<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:creativeCommons="http://backend.userland.com/creativeCommonsRssModule" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Writing, Wishing</title>
	
	<link>http://www.writingwishing.com</link>
	<description>Writer. Mother. Wish Maker. Memory Keeper.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 10:17:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/mamawantsthis/ovRG" /><feedburner:info uri="mamawantsthis/ovrg" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</creativeCommons:license><image><link>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</link><url>http://creativecommons.org/images/public/somerights20.gif</url><title>Some Rights Reserved</title></image><feedburner:emailServiceId>mamawantsthis/ovRG</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>Sticky</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~3/Y9z2_MVD0B8/</link>
		<comments>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/sticky/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 02:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alison</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toddler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.writingwishing.com/?p=6359</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sticky. Darker than I thought. So much. My shirt, his pajama top, speckled with it. Beginning to dry, on my hand. Wet, my shirt is wet, his tears soaking into my shoulder, his pain becoming mine. Calm. Calm. Calm. Where is he? My husband? There. Come over, now. Take him. I&#8217;m taking a look. His [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Sticky. Darker than I thought. So much. My shirt, his pajama top, speckled with it. Beginning to dry, on my hand. Wet, my shirt is wet, his tears soaking into my shoulder, his pain becoming mine.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Calm. Calm. Calm. Where is he? My husband? There. Come over, now.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Take him. I&#8217;m taking a look.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">His hair, now matted. Sticky. A mess. A bloody mess.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I can&#8217;t really see how bad it is, but there&#8217;s a lot of blood.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Doctor? </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Yes. Now. Let&#8217;s go.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Still calm.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He&#8217;s quiet now. Conscious. Wide-eyed. I shush him, hold him in my arms.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The bright light of the doctor&#8217;s office down the road is a rude shock. It&#8217;s a quiet night, but not for long.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Sticky. My hands are still sticky. My son&#8217;s blood, now dried on my hands, but fresh from his head, still pouring out. Screams as four grown men try to restrain him.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Flurry of activity, I have to walk out for a minute to catch my breath. I need to be calm.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">No, no, no. Screams. My boy pleads with his eyes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It&#8217;s a failure. The doctor gives up, the tiny tube of glue still in his gloved hand, my son finally unwrapped from the blanket, my arms taking its place.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>We tried, he moved too much, the blood was hiding the cut, we had to keep cleaning, then tried the glue. Every time he moved, we had to clean again. And again. The wound is small, it doesn&#8217;t seem that way because of the blood.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">No kidding, doctor.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">My 2 year old is calm, his father now holding him, taking him outside for some fresh air.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">So, doctor, what do we do?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Keep pressure on the cut until the bleed stops, give him some painkillers.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">That&#8217;s it?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>That&#8217;s it. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">We head home, my hand on a piece of bandage, holding it to his head. It&#8217;s soaked.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He&#8217;s tired now. Does not want to leave my side. I lay him down on my bed, holding him close. His quiet breathing assures me he&#8217;s okay, he&#8217;s still breathing, he&#8217;s okay, despite the blood on his pajama top, and on my now-dry hands.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">So much. So dark. So sticky.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">My heartbeat finally slows to normal, matching his even breathing.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I don&#8217;t sleep a wink that night.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>My oldest, then 2 years old (January 2012), fell off the couch one night, hitting his head on the way down, on the coffee table&#8217;s edge. He was fine the next day, probably with a killer headache, but otherwise back to his toddler self. My uncle, a doctor, saw him later that day and assured me that head wounds almost always look worse than they are, because of the massive bleeding. In our case, fortunately, that was true. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>This is the second post I wrote as part of an exercise, using sensory details as a starting point, from <a href="http://katehopper.com" target="_blank">Kate Hopper</a>&#8216;s book, Use Your Words: A Writing Guide for Mothers. If you haven&#8217;t read it, I highly recommend that you do.</em></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~4/Y9z2_MVD0B8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/sticky/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/sticky/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>In The Morning</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~3/g6aKclb22B0/</link>
		<comments>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/in-the-morning/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 02:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alison</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Scrumplet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.writingwishing.com/?p=6324</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Small, sticky, slightly salty hands assault my senses, followed quickly by his distinctive good morning yelp. It&#8217;s usually still dark so I can vaguely make out his small figure next to me, sitting up, wide awake &#8211; my opposite. He senses that I&#8217;m awake and snuggles close, wanting his morning feed. I stroke his head, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Small, sticky, slightly salty hands assault my senses, followed quickly by his distinctive good morning yelp. It&#8217;s usually still dark so I can vaguely make out his small figure next to me, sitting up, wide awake &#8211; my opposite.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He senses that I&#8217;m awake and snuggles close, wanting his morning feed. I stroke his head, soft hair smelling like sweat and milk. When he finishes, he rolls over onto his belly and in one smooth movement, pushes up to sit. He&#8217;s looking for my phone, the familiar light of it starts his day.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He starts crawling over to the edge of the bed, phone in hand. I can&#8217;t see his face, but I know his expression. Cheeky, small smile and eyes full of mischief. I move, feeling like an elephant, and grab the phone before it leaves his hand. Too late.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I heave his familiar weight onto my left arm, his right hand pinching my flesh, and lower him into the crib he left in the middle of the night.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Piercing screams hit my ears, really waking me up. His protests cut short when I hand him a book, some toys. I take my 3-minute shower and get dressed. He is &#8216;talking&#8217;, lips forming around the easy p&#8217;s and d&#8217;s. I can just see his arms, still chubby with the classic baby rolls, chucking things out of the crib.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He&#8217;s calling me now, a baby voice indistinguishable to others, unique to my ears. I go. His arms are outstretched as soon as he hears my footsteps, little legs perfectly stable as he stands. His big smile shows 8 teeth (eight!), his eyes crinkle upward slightly. He looks nothing like me, and everything like me.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It&#8217;s difficult to change him now, he doesn&#8217;t stop moving. Sitting up, he suddenly lunges forward, hands going for the current object of desire &#8211; my glasses one day, a bottle of moisturizer the next. I struggle to slip the romper over his ever-growing head, his busy arms and legs protesting the whole time.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He expertly picks up a small square of french toast with his thumb and finger, and eats it quickly, then promptly grabs a fistful of his breakfast. He shoves it all into his mouth, ignoring my protests, then spits half of them out. He eats like a squirrel, softening the food, one cheek bulging, and slowly swallows it bit by bit.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">His head turns quickly as he hears his older brother stirring in his room. He looks at me, and points a chubby and still impossibly tiny finger towards his brother&#8217;s room.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">There is no question who the boss is around here, in the morning.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/11-month-old-baby.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-6350" alt="11 month old baby" src="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/11-month-old-baby.jpg" width="464" height="699" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>This post is a writing exercise from <a href="http://www.katehopper.com/" target="_blank">Kate Hopper</a>&#8216;s book, <strong>Use Your Words: A Writing Guide for Mothers</strong>, to sketch a character in detail. I highly recommend it for all writing mothers. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>What are your mornings like?</strong></em></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>My weekly article at Everyday Family this week is about<a href="http://www.everydayfamily.com/blog/4-reasons-play-dates-are-important/" target="_blank"> play dates &#8211; for moms AND kids</a>. Would love a read and/ or share, thank you and see you there!</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~4/g6aKclb22B0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/in-the-morning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/in-the-morning/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>On Writing</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~3/dL1382416m0/</link>
		<comments>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/on-writing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 02:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alison</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.writingwishing.com/?p=6318</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This post is inspired by Jennie of A Lady In France. It came in an ordinary-looking envelope, white, I think. My name and address scrawled on the front, confirming that its contents, were indeed mine. I&#8217;d never won anything in my life (nothing I really wanted, like these cassette tapes!), and this was exciting. My [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Maya-Angelou-quote.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6331" alt="There is no greater agony than bearing an untold story inside you." src="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Maya-Angelou-quote.jpg" width="468" height="468" /></a>This post is inspired by <a href="http://aladyinfrance.com/2013/04/04/about-writing/" target="_blank">Jennie of A Lady In France.</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It came in an ordinary-looking envelope, white, I think. My name and address scrawled on the front, confirming that its contents, were indeed mine. I&#8217;d never won anything in my life (nothing I really wanted, like these cassette tapes!), and this was exciting.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">My first I-really-wanted-this-prize came from a poem I submitted to a local radio station, who read it on air. I was 15 or 16, and I may have missed part of the reading of my not-very-good-poem about a bird and a tree, when it aired. The details of the poem is lost, I don&#8217;t have a copy, nor do I remember any of it, except that it wasn&#8217;t very long, and it was the first time I sent my writing out into the world.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It was also the last time, for a very long time. I still wrote &#8211; more bad poetry, song lyrics, angst-filled journal entries about boys and all the things teenagers worried about, which seem so trivial now, all kept private, read by no one. I had dreams of becoming a journalist only because I really, really wanted to meet *Tom Cruise in person. Not because I thought I could make a living out of writing or that I loved words.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">My love for words was never spoken, nor was it realized. I didn&#8217;t stop and think, &#8220;Ooh, I really enjoy writing, I should do it all the time.&#8221; No, it was something I did. Just as I played the piano, or chased my sister around the house, or ate breakfast.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">None of the writing I did when I was 18 to 35 meant anything. Thoughtful analysis of Shakespeare and Jane Austen in college, critiques of film techniques and theorizing of criminal sociology in university. Press releases, biographies, newsletters, proposals, advertorials, advertising copy, reports in a 10-year career.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I was given a &#8216;My Baby&#8217;s Coming&#8217; journal when I was pregnant in 2009. After two entries, where I scrawled out &#8220;It&#8217;s a Boy!&#8221; and &#8216;My back hurts&#8221;, it&#8217;s empty, save for the weekly weight and belly circumference measurements.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I did not write about my feelings of impending motherhood, or how I thought my life would change. I did not write about how I thought I&#8217;d mother my son, or how I feared parenthood would change my marriage. I did not write about my son&#8217;s first year, where I went through a rollercoaster of emotions. I did not write about the first month where everyday I felt like I was dying little by little inside. I did not write about the first smile, the first step, the first tooth, the first anything. I did not write about my relationship with my husband, how it nearly broke us, and strengthened us. I did not write about the deep love and the breathtaking depths of feelings that motherhood brings.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I took many pictures and videos, but I wrote nothing.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Even when I started to blog, I had no intentions of writing about mothering.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">However, and unexpectedly, my words have a life of their own. They spill out onto the pages, my fingers typing furiously, my mind whirling with ALL THE THINGS I need to write now before I forget.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The words have continued to come, and with them, a rush of emotions I did not expect, a burden of memories from my own childhood and feelings about my mother, bubbling to the surface. Scars of wounds I never knew were there, are itching to be scratched, urging me to break through skin and bleed words.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I am afraid to scratch some of those scars. I feel like I&#8217;m tentatively emerging as a mother who writes, who hesitate to say, &#8220;I am a writer&#8221;, and who is unsure whether some stories are meant to be told.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I am no longer that teenager who sent our her words so eagerly, in exchange for some cassette tapes.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">What I am, is a mother who wants to tell her stories, to capture the stories of her children until they&#8217;re old enough to write their own, to still time for a little while with her words.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I hope I&#8217;m doing that well.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>* I no longer love Tom Cruise.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>BlogHer &#8217;13 has opened submissions and voting for Voices of The Year (VOTY), and I have a few posts there that I would love a vote for. If you could take a couple of minutes to do so, I&#8217;ll love you forever and ever. Thank YOU. My posts are about <a href="http://www.blogher.com/about-blogging" target="_blank">blogging</a>, <a href="http://www.blogher.com/are-you-judging-me" target="_blank">mothers judging other mothers</a>, i<a href="http://www.blogher.com/intrinsic-goodness" target="_blank">ntrinsic goodness of people</a>, <a href="http://www.blogher.com/raising-boys-girl-way-0" target="_blank">raising boys, the girl way</a>, and this post <a href="http://www.blogher.com/writing-27" target="_blank">about writing</a>.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~4/dL1382416m0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/on-writing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>87</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/on-writing/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Old School Blogging: The Marriage Edition</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~3/dygBwQSfkyM/</link>
		<comments>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/old-school-blogging-marriage-edition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 02:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alison</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Husband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Link Up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marriage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.writingwishing.com/?p=6301</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Old School Blogging is back! Elaine and Heather had such a great time with this last month (as did all of us, including me, who missed the linkup by mere hours, oops), that they&#8217;re doing this again (thanks ladies, it sure helps with the writer&#8217;s block). This month is all about marriage, babies and bliss. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Old School Blogging is back! <a href="http://www.misselaineouslife.com/2013/04/old-school-blogging-april.html" target="_blank">Elaine</a> and <a href="http://thetamom.com" target="_blank">Heather</a> had such a great time with this last month (as did all of us, including me, who missed the linkup by mere hours, oops), that they&#8217;re doing this again (thanks ladies, it sure helps with the writer&#8217;s block).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This month is all about marriage, babies and bliss. Here we go.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. How did your husband pop the big question?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong></strong>Well, whaddya know? I wrote about <a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/2011/05/how-we-came-to-be/" target="_blank">how we got engaged</a> a while back. It involved a carrot and a cat. That&#8217;s not a euphemism. You have to read it to believe it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. What are the three most surprising things about married life?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong></strong>One, little things do matter. Like, putting the dirty cup into the sink rather than on the counter tells me you listened when I <del>nagged</del> asked nicely. Two, how much work it is (as my wise friend <a href="http://twocannoli.com" target="_blank">Kristin</a> says, love is a verb). Three, how well we&#8217;ve both adapted to it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. How did you find out you were pregnant for the first time?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I knew I was pregnant before I &#8216;found out&#8217;. I waited until I was a day late, bought a pregnancy test kit, and did the test that night. I saw the two lines, went to my husband (who did not know I was doing the test), and said, hey, we&#8217;re going to be parents! He looked at me and said, &#8220;Really? You&#8217;re sure?&#8221; Stick waved again, and he did some kind of weird shooting gesture with sound effects, and winked at me. True story.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. How did you choose your first baby&#8217;s name?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">We were at a bookstore, and I was flicking through a baby name book. I was 8 weeks pregnant, and just knew that it was a boy. We stopped at a random page, saw the name, and knew it would be our son&#8217;s name.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. Describe where you see yourself 10 years from now&#8230;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Blogging about how the teenage/ tween years are killing me! &lt;insert smiley face&gt; &lt;insert tears&gt;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>6. Describe how you find bliss either by using words or images.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Bliss can be found in the laughter of my children, in a hot cup of coffee, in the arms of my husband, in the writing that I do, in the anticipation of a cupcake (or ice cream), in the words of friends, in the feel of toes buried in the warm sand, in a clean house, in the pages of a book, and in the quiet of the night.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Now tag 5 of your bloggy friends!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I&#8217;d love to read about your engagement, marriage, babies and bliss &#8211; Alexa of <a href="http://noholdingback1212.com" target="_blank">No Holding Back</a>, Alma of <a href="http://almaboheme.blogspot.com" target="_blank">Alma Boheme</a>, Kim of <a href="http://toodarnhappy.com" target="_blank">Too Darn Happy</a>, Leslie of<a href="http://www.pampersplaydatesparties.com/" target="_blank"> Pampers, Playdates &amp; Parties</a> and Tamara of <a href="http://tamaralikecamera.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">Tamara Camera Blog</a>! Anyone else who&#8217;d like to play, please do, let me know and link up with <a href="http://www.misselaineouslife.com/2013/04/old-school-blogging-april.html" target="_blank">Elaine!</a></p>
<p><center><a href="http://www.misselaineouslife.com" target="_blank"><img alt="" src="http://i1235.photobucket.com/albums/ff437/elainea1/OSBimage125.jpg" border="0" /></a></center>&nbsp;</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~4/dygBwQSfkyM" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/old-school-blogging-marriage-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>75</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/old-school-blogging-marriage-edition/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Parenting Theories</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~3/vharbFRsVb8/</link>
		<comments>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/parenting-theories/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 02:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alison</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.writingwishing.com/?p=6291</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Uh oh. Another blog post about parenting. Is this one going to tout the fabulous French way, where French children don&#8217;t throw public tantrums? Ooh, wait, is it going to be about the Asian way of parenting &#8211; practice piano for 6 hours or you&#8217;ll never succeed! No, no, it must be about breastfeeding &#8211; [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/John-Wilmot-quote-about-raising-children.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-6296" alt="Before children, I had six theories about raising children; now, I have six children and no theories." src="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/John-Wilmot-quote-about-raising-children.jpg" width="672" height="420" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Uh oh. Another blog post about parenting. Is this one going to tout the fabulous French way, where French children don&#8217;t throw public tantrums?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Ooh, wait, is it going to be about the Asian way of parenting &#8211; practice piano for 6 hours or you&#8217;ll never succeed!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">No, no, it must be about breastfeeding &#8211; let&#8217;s throw in a controversial title like, if you don&#8217;t support breastfeeding in public, you don&#8217;t support breastfeeding (actual title of an article).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Perhaps a view on attachment parenting? Helicopter parenting? Just feed them chicken fingers parenting? <a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/2012/08/my-parenting-style-is-best-described-as-flying-by-the-seat-of-my-pants/" target="_blank">Fly by the seat of your pants parenting</a>?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">No, this is none of that.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I am not a parenting expert. I don&#8217;t have any theories on how to parent your child successfully. I don&#8217;t have any brilliant ideas on sleep training, discipline, talking to children about big life issues like death or equality. I can&#8217;t offer any advice on potty training.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Everything that I&#8217;ve shared here or <a href="http://www.everydayfamily.com/blog/authors/alison-lee/" target="_blank">elsewhere</a> about any aspects of parenting, is based on my experience and my experience alone. I am not an expert in parenting, but I am an expert on my own children.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I can&#8217;t tell you that breastfeeding is the only way to go. I can only tell you that I nursed both my children (and still breastfeeding one), and that&#8217;s what worked for us (and my boys hate the bottle).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I can&#8217;t give you tips on sleep training. I can tell you that we had to employ different tactics at different stages to get our 3 year old to sleep on his own, through the night. I can tell you that transitioning the baby to the cot to sleep on his own has only worked for naps, and the reason is because I&#8217;m not in the room with him, sleeping and breathing mere feet away.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I can&#8217;t tell you a lot about feeding kids. I can tell you about our struggles with our 3 year old and his picky eating, and how we&#8217;re trying various ways to get him to try new things. Occasionally, I can even share some tried-and-tested toddler-friendly recipes with you.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I can&#8217;t tell you what is good for your child. I can&#8217;t tell you what &#8216;method&#8217; you should employ. I can&#8217;t tell you to get off your iPhone or your laptop. I can&#8217;t tell you to stop letting your children watch television. I can&#8217;t tell you how to discipline your children when they&#8217;re running around in a restaurant. I can&#8217;t tell you how to manage tantrums. I can&#8217;t tell you how to raise your kids.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">All I can tell you is this.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Parenting is hard (what a cliche, but for a reason).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Parenting is something you go in thinking you know everything, only to find out you know nothing.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Parenting is different for everyone, with many similarities.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Parenting is not something that can be taught, that has a winning formula, that in adopting one &#8216;way&#8217;, will ensure you succeed.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Parenting is not just about the parents, it&#8217;s about the children. How you find your way as a parent, has a lot to do with the temperament and personality of your child.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Parenting is a maze, a convoluted mass of ideas, theories, techniques, suggestions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Parenting is scary, and exhilarating.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It&#8217;s hard enough to do this thing, without being judged, without reading yet another sanctimonious article about how we are doing it wrong, without being badgered about this versus that, without being divided into camps.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I don&#8217;t want to read another article about breastfeeding in public, or whether mothers should stay home or not. I don&#8217;t want to read yet another post from a non-parent about how we should parent. We all do what we have to for our children, for ourselves. My way is no better or worse than yours.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I do want to read articles about parents sharing their experiences, good and bad. I want to read posts from parents telling me how challenging and beautiful it is. I want to read articles about triumph and love, and yes, even heartbreak and grief. I want to read mothers&#8217; and fathers&#8217; hearts, and their truth.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Parenting: It is <strong>Heart</strong>, and<strong> Truth</strong>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Linking up with <a href="http://thingsicantsay.com/2013/04/pour-your-heart-out-speaking-up.html" target="_blank">Shell&#8217;s Pour Your Heart Out.</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>What do you think about blog posts/ articles about parenting theories?</strong></em></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>This is not a theory, but it is a post about <a href="http://www.everydayfamily.com/blog/7-tips-for-flying-solo-with-a-baby/" target="_blank">what I learned when travelling solo with a baby</a>. Come check it out, my post at Everyday Family.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~4/vharbFRsVb8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/parenting-theories/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>110</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/parenting-theories/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>My Body Spoke Up</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~3/J2ndVhS_GyA/</link>
		<comments>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/my-body-spoke-up/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alison</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life's Lessons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.writingwishing.com/?p=6277</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week, I believe I survived on adrenaline, chai, my children&#8217;s hugs and kisses, and occasional meals. I wrote a bunch of stuff here, I wrote a bunch of stuff elsewhere, and my 2nd blog anniversary came to pass (I could do some links here but I&#8217;m lazy). I was on Twitter and Facebook talking [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week, I believe I survived on adrenaline, chai, my children&#8217;s hugs and kisses, and occasional meals.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I wrote a bunch of stuff here, I wrote a bunch of stuff elsewhere, and my 2nd blog anniversary came to pass (I could do some links here but I&#8217;m lazy). I was on Twitter and Facebook talking about Peeps (what are they and why the fascination, I asked?), and in the middle of all that, I did a lot of solo parenting during the week.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">So it was to no one&#8217;s surprise (well, aside from me), that on Saturday morning, I could barely get out of bed. No matter how little sleep I get, I can usually leap out of bed, straight into the shower. Not this day, no. I had a baby crawling all over me, playing with my phone (and probably calling a bunch of people at 6.30 a.m., I am sorry), and I could not get my sorry behind out of bed.</p>
<div id="attachment_6282" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Babies.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-6282 " alt="Two babies" src="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Babies.jpg" width="640" height="480" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Random picture of babies &#8211; aren&#8217;t they adorable?</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Eventually, I managed to crawl out, get both children up, dressed and breakfasted, and promptly lay in a useless heap on the couch, still in my stinky pajamas where I stayed for a good while, keeping one eye open on the boys.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">When 9 o&#8217;clock rolled around and I survived a shower, I told my husband that I was feeling sick, although I couldn&#8217;t explain where I hurt, why I felt like crap, I just felt fatigued and nauseous (no, I am not pregnant). For possibly the first time in my life, I listened to him when he ordered me to rest for the day.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I slept from 2.00 to 7.00 p.m., waking up intermittently to feed the baby, and diaper changes while my beloved made decisions for me throughout the day. Children carted off to their grandparents, dinner was pizza and bedtime for me was 10.00 p.m. (after ice cream because ice cream makes everything better).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">On Sunday, I woke up at 7.00, feeling (slightly) human again.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Turns out, I was probably just sleep-deprived.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Huh.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">There is no moral to this story. Because last night, I went to bed at my usual hour, and this morning, I was up at 6.30 again. I have a full to-do list, lots of ideas for the blog and my writing, many books to read, and children to play with.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Until the next collapse-into-heap-moment, I&#8217;ll just chug along until my body speaks up again.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>When was the last time you took an afternoon nap?</strong></em></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>In a great twist of irony, I have <a href="http://www.everydayfamily.com/blog/10-sanity-saving-ideas-for-first-year-moms/" target="_blank">a post on Everyday Family advocating 10 ways to save your sanity as a first-year mom</a> &#8211; well, for any mom really. I need to take my own advice.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>I also have a winner for the <a href="http://littlelovemedia.com/blogger-services" target="_blank">blog evaluation from Little Love Media</a> thanks to my 2nd blog birthday &#8211; congratulations <a href="http://lovelifesurf.com" target="_blank">Christine of Love, Life, Surf</a>, an email is on its way!</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~4/J2ndVhS_GyA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/my-body-spoke-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>80</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/04/my-body-spoke-up/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Two Blogging Years</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~3/_cEwjbx39hk/</link>
		<comments>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/two-blogging-years/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alison</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogiversary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.writingwishing.com/?p=6261</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yes, it&#8217;s me again. I feel like I&#8217;ve been in your face a lot this week (and I have, with this post about social media suicide going viral, writing about my mother issues, then suggesting fun ways to remember your baby&#8217;s first year), but I couldn&#8217;t go today without posting. Because today is my second blog [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Yes, it&#8217;s me again. I feel like I&#8217;ve been in your face a lot this week (and I have, with this post about <a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/how-to-kill-your-brand-and-business-with-a-few-facebook-updates/" target="_blank">social media suicide</a> going viral, <a href="http://www.scarymommy.com/my-mother/" target="_blank">writing about my mother issues</a>, then <a href="http://www.everydayfamily.com/blog/3-creative-ways-to-remember-your-babys-first-year/" target="_blank">suggesting fun ways to remember your baby&#8217;s first year</a>), but I couldn&#8217;t go today without posting.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Because today is my second blog anniversary (Blogiversary? Blogeversary? Blogversary?).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Two-year-blogging-anniversary.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6267" alt="Two year blogging anniversary" src="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Two-year-blogging-anniversary.jpg" width="603" height="403" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Two blogging years feels like the equivalent of 5 human years. I feel like I&#8217;ve been doing this for way longer than 24 months, written more than 500 or so posts, and spent way more than a gazillion hours on social media (oh wait, I <em>have</em> spent more than a gazillion hours on social media).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This date, two years ago, I started a blog on a whim, using a name I no longer use, which my husband helpfully pointed out recently, &#8220;sounds like a p*rn site&#8221; (why didn&#8217;t you tell me then, Husband?!). I had no idea what I was getting into, nor did I stick with my original idea for a blog (that lasted about two days).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I can&#8217;t imagine not blogging (and not writing posts without using parentheses &#8211; this post will have a record number of them, just sayin&#8217;). The thought of not writing, not talking to you, not knowing what you were up to, not getting my words out somehow? Unimaginable.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I won&#8217;t get soppy on you, I will just say, thank you. Thank you to each of you who have taken the time to read, to comment, to share, to be there, to talk, to commiserate, to assure, to love. Thank you for your friendship, thank you for making the last two years so much richer for me in so many ways.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">What&#8217;s a blog anniversary without a present?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Instead of gift cards or spa treatments or jewelry (I haven&#8217;t blogged long enough, or maybe smart enough, to make enough money for that, sorry), I thought I&#8217;ll give away a <a href="http://littlelovemedia.com/blogger-services" target="_blank">blog evaluation from Little Love Media</a>. If you don&#8217;t need one, maybe you can give it away to a bloggy friend if you win it? No fancy Rafflecopter widgets, or mandatory entries to like my Facebook page, or follow me everywhere. You just have to leave a comment telling me why YOU are awesome, and I&#8217;ll pick a winner with a handy plugin.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>Giveaway is open to all, worldwide, from March 29 to April 1 (closes 9.00 a.m. Eastern). You may only enter once. Winners will be picked using And The Winner Is&#8230;.</strong></em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Have a lovely weekend! And tell me one awesome thing about yourself.</em></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~4/_cEwjbx39hk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/two-blogging-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/two-blogging-years/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>My Now, Your Future</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~3/eZihA5z6Km8/</link>
		<comments>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/my-now-your-future/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 02:58:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alison</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.writingwishing.com/?p=6249</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear boys, You are growing up in the era of social media, over-sharing and the &#8220;Me, Me, Me&#8221; culture. This is both exhilarating and frightening. Exhilarating because your (almost) entire childhood will be captured. Every small, silly, momentous event in your lives will be recorded right here, on Facebook, Instagram, Twitter and who-knows-what-else-in-the-future. Frightening because your [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Dear boys,</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You are growing up in the era of social media, over-sharing and the &#8220;Me, Me, Me&#8221; culture. This is both exhilarating and frightening.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Exhilarating because your (almost) entire childhood will be captured. Every small, silly, momentous event in your lives will be recorded right here, on Facebook, Instagram, Twitter and who-knows-what-else-in-the-future.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Frightening because your (almost) entire childhood will be captured. Every small, silly, momentous event in your lives will be recorded right here, on Facebook, Instagram, Twitter and who-knows-what-else-in-the-future.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You see, nothing is really erased when you put something out there in the digital world. You can take things down, delete frantically, or just hope that by virtue of the crushing enormity of information out there, certain things will just be buried (like a picture of kids on the potty &#8211; not that I&#8217;ve ever, or will ever do that to you).</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">When you grow up, and apply for jobs, you will likely be Googled (that&#8217;s the faith I have in Google, it will still be around 20 years from now). Do I want your potential boss to see you frolicking in the pool? Will it hurt your chances if I dress you in a bee suit? Will they think differently of you if they knew you had a speech delay when you were 3? Will they hold it against you if your parents are politically inclined one way or the other? Will they like you more because they saw that at age 5, you were a champion reader? Will they decide on whether you&#8217;re a good fit or not because your mother blogged and occasionally dropped the F-bomb? Will you be judged in any way because of your digital footprint, most of which in your young life, you had no say over?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I don&#8217;t know.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I certainly hope that you can hold your own as young men. That we, your parents, have instilled the right values in you. I hope that your personalities will shine through on their own, and that any digital history of you, will just be a small reflection of you as a whole. I want to believe that everything we&#8217;re doing now, online and offline, is considered, measured, well thought out, and nothing that any of us will regret.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">We will all be be judged in life. I just hope you won&#8217;t be because of what we did online.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Love, Mama</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>This post was inspired by <a href="http://socialmediatoday.com/kendallmorris/1324386/warning-your-facebook-posts-may-be-harmful-your-childs-future" target="_blank">this article I read on Social Media Today</a>, where the author warned that what we put online now, can affect our children in the future. It has made me think long and hard about my social media behavior. It&#8217;s not just about me. </em></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>The amazing Jill Smokler of Scary Mommy has once again allowed me to pour my heart out on her gorgeous site. Today,<a href="http://www.scarymommy.com/my-mother/" target="_blank"> I wrote about my mother</a>. It was hard because it&#8217;s not flattering to her. But it&#8217;s an important post, so it would be so wonderful if you could read it. Thank you.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Speaking of futures and children, I wrote a post about <a href="http://www.everydayfamily.com/blog/3-creative-ways-to-remember-your-babys-first-year/" target="_blank">3 fun ways to remember your baby&#8217;s first year</a> at Everyday Family. Would love for you to read it! Thank you.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~4/eZihA5z6Km8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/my-now-your-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>83</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/my-now-your-future/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Handle Rejection (Or How Not To Curl Up In A Fetal Position And Eat Copious Amounts Of Chocolate)</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~3/BGf2jxy-tRI/</link>
		<comments>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/how-to-handle-rejection/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alison</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[List]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.writingwishing.com/?p=6212</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s hard to be a writer. It&#8217;s harder to be a writer who wants to make money from writing. And it&#8217;s really, really hard to put yourself out there and ask for a writing job. You plan the perfect pitch in your head. You run it by a few trusted people. You write and rewrite [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">It&#8217;s hard to be a writer. It&#8217;s harder to be a writer who wants to make money from writing. And it&#8217;s really, really hard to put yourself out there and ask for a writing job.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You plan the perfect pitch in your head. You run it by a few trusted people. You write and rewrite your pitch. You sit on it for a few days to make sure that it feels right. You send your pitch and you wait.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">And wait.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You hear nothing back after a week, so you do the right thing and send a polite follow up email.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">And you get this &#8211; &#8220;Thank you for your submission, but it&#8217;s not the right fit for us.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Period. The end. No other explanation. You look at the rest of their site and think that what you were offering was <em>absolutely the perfect fit. </em>You doubt yourself. You suffer a blow to your confidence. Again. You shout, &#8220;Can&#8217;t I catch a freaking break??&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You will want to curl up in a fetal position and eat copious amounts of chocolate (or whatever &#8216;bad&#8217; food makes you feel better). Don&#8217;t. There are better ways to handle rejection.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Pity-party-drawing.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6218" alt="Pity party drawing" src="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Pity-party-drawing.jpg" width="509" height="687" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">1. Cry. Yes, let it out. You&#8217;ll feel a smidgen better. Just a smidgen. You&#8217;ll still want to hit something.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">2. Hit something. Preferably something inanimate, but soft. Like a pillow. Yes, hit a pillow.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">3. Swear. Loudly and profusely. Preferably out of the earshot of children.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">4. Tell someone. Like I did. (&#8220;I was *splutter* rejected *sob*. Why *sob* would *sob* they *sob* not *sob* l-l-l-o-v-e me *sob*?)</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">5. Tell two more people. Preferably one who will say, &#8220;I never liked &lt;the rejector&gt; anyway, and I like them even less now!&#8221;. Then ask her to marry you.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">6. Eat chocolate. But sitting up. Not curled up in a fetal position.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">7. Bake something, preferably something you are really good at, so as to feel a sense of achievement. Make sure your family members get a slice so they can tell you how awesome you are.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">8. Do something you love. Like, watch TV. What?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">9. Write a post about how to handle rejection. Inject some humor into it because you really need to laugh.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">10. Go out there and try again. Someone will think YOU are awesome and the right fit. Also? Be grateful for the opportunities that have come your way.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>How do you handle rejection? If you&#8217;ve never been rejected, don&#8217;t tell me, heh.</strong></em></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~4/BGf2jxy-tRI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/how-to-handle-rejection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>112</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/how-to-handle-rejection/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Kill Your Brand and Business With A Few Facebook Updates</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~3/Kvi1XJTUPos/</link>
		<comments>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/how-to-kill-your-brand-and-business-with-a-few-facebook-updates/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 02:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alison</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Le Deux Garcons social media disaster]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.writingwishing.com/?p=6222</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You&#8217;d think in this day and age of social media, Community Managers of Facebook Pages for businesses would be trained and savvy. Because if they were, they wouldn&#8217;t call their customers &#8220;bitches&#8221; and tell someone who posted a complaint on their wall, that it&#8217;d &#8220;kill&#8221; them to have customers like these. Couple that with a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">You&#8217;d think in this day and age of social media, Community Managers of Facebook Pages for businesses would be trained and savvy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Because if they were, they wouldn&#8217;t call their customers &#8220;bitches&#8221; and tell someone who posted a complaint on their wall, that it&#8217;d &#8220;kill&#8221; them to have customers like these. Couple that with a poor grasp of the English language, and you have an almost laughable social media disaster, as evidenced by Le Deux Garcons, a bakery (or as they call themselves, a patisserie) based in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">{In Sarcasm Font} Here&#8217;s how you kill your brand and business in a few simple steps:</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">1. When a customer has a valid complaint, and a helpful suggestion to improve customer service, tell them to buy their desserts elsewhere. For dramatic flair, tell your customer it&#8217;d kill you to have to serve people like her. Oh, and insult the French while you&#8217;re at it.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Le-Deux-Garcon-FB-update.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6235" alt="Le Deux Garcons FB wall status" src="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Le-Deux-Garcon-FB-update.jpg" width="634" height="626" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">2. Following that exchange, tell your customers that you can manage without their patronage because you can &#8220;afford to.&#8221; Use the word &#8220;whatever&#8221; when possible, to emphasize how little you care.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Le-Deux-Garcons-update-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6237" alt="Le Deux Garcons FB wall status 2" src="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Le-Deux-Garcons-update-1.jpg" width="595" height="378" /></a></p>
<p>3. Delete the wall status above. But only after it&#8217;s been screen grabbed.</p>
<p>4. Proceed to call your customers &#8220;bitches&#8221;.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Le-Deux-Garcons-FB-update-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-6236" alt="Le Deux Garcons calls customers bitches" src="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Le-Deux-Garcons-FB-update-2.jpg" width="672" height="426" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">5. Delete the wall post above and pretend nothing happened, while everyone in Kuala Lumpur spreads word that your bakery is not worth visiting, unless you want to be called a bitch and served up a side of attitude.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As of this writing (March 24, Sunday morning), Le Deux Garcons has not responded to this unfolding disaster in any way. Their <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Les-Deux-Garcons/190072754350375" target="_blank">Facebook page</a>&#8216;s last update is over two months old. The non-recommendations are rolling in, with folks saying they will never, ever step foot into that store again.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Not once have they apologized for the poor service the original poster complained about, nor their rude responses to their customers.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Le Deux Garcons, I think you need to hire a social media consultant and/ or a PR team to clean up your social media mess. Good luck.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Update #1: Le Deux Garcons posted this apology (which sounds very template, or is it just me?) at 1.00 p.m. on 24 March. From the comments, it doesn&#8217;t look like it made much difference, with customers calling for a more sincere approach.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Le-Deux-Garcons-update-Sun.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6240" alt="Le Deux Garcons apology" src="http://www.writingwishing.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Le-Deux-Garcons-update-Sun.jpg" width="585" height="788" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Update #2: The largest local newspaper covered this &#8220;brouhaha&#8221; as they called it, quoting the owner Ben Yeong as saying that the apology above is sufficient, and that&#8217;s that. He also insisted that the remarks above were written by a &#8220;staff member&#8221;. So, Mr. Yeong, your shop assistants are allowed to login to your business&#8217;s Facebook account? Or worse, do you have a social media manager who is clearly clueless? My take? Mr. Ben Yeong is the perpetrator.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>I will be following this as it unfolds further, and post updates when they happen.</strong></em></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mamawantsthis/ovRG/~4/Kvi1XJTUPos" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/how-to-kill-your-brand-and-business-with-a-few-facebook-updates/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>98</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.writingwishing.com/2013/03/how-to-kill-your-brand-and-business-with-a-few-facebook-updates/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss>
