<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Like a sponge</title>
	
	<link>http://www.likeasponge.nl</link>
	<description>Soak up Dutch</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 10:24:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/LikeASponge" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="likeasponge" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">LikeASponge</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>All-consuming consumpties</title>
		<link>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2671</link>
		<comments>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2671#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 10:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Marianne</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Other stuff]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2671</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It was the annual gymuitvoering here in the village last weekend. My mum went to see Shakespeare&#8217;s Richard III (as opposed to anyone else&#8217;s Richard III &#8211; Kabouter Plop&#8217;s maybe?) the other week. The gymuitvoering lasted longer. Daughter was taking part, in the gymuitvoering that is, and I&#8217;d been roped in to help. The English [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><div id="attachment_2672" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><a href="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Summer-holiday-2010-005.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2672  " alt="A polite notice" src="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Summer-holiday-2010-005-450x600.jpg" width="450" height="600" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A polite notice</p></div>
<p>It was the annual gymuitvoering here in the village last weekend. My mum went to see Shakespeare&#8217;s Richard III (as opposed to anyone else&#8217;s Richard III &#8211; Kabouter Plop&#8217;s maybe?) the other week.</p>
<p>The gymuitvoering lasted longer.</p>
<p>Daughter was taking part, in the gymuitvoering that is, and I&#8217;d been roped in to help. The English equivalent of a gymuitvoering is a gym display.</p>
<p>I used to take part in gym displays as a child, but they were usually about half an hour of jumping around at the local flower show before everyone went off to judge the biggest onions and best Victoria Sponge. They certainly weren&#8217;t Shakespearean in length.</p>
<p>My job at the gymuitvoering was to keep the children quiet for the 2 hours and 55 minutes that they were sitting on the bench waiting for it to be their turn, and to round them up and make sure they were ready when it was their turn.</p>
<p>This earned me free entrance and a consumptiebon.</p>
<p>&#8216;Conceptiebon?&#8217; said Son when he saw it. &#8216;What&#8217;s a conceptiebon?&#8217; When Husband and I had picked ourselves up off the floor we explained that it was a <em>consumptie</em>bon and not a <em>conceptie</em>bon. &#8216;What&#8217;s conceptie then?&#8217; asked Son, which, it&#8217;s nice to imagine that we live life like a musical, had us breaking into song:</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="375" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/umyl-wWRkJ4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>It also had me asking Husband if there is an equivalent of the birds and the bees is in Dutch. &#8216;De vogeltjes en de bijtjes,&#8217; he said. I looked it up because his Dutch has been besmet by us. It should be de bloemetjes en de bijtjes.</p>
<p>After we&#8217;d established that there was no such thing as a conceptiebon, we turned to what the consumptiebon is: a refreshment voucher. Because a consumptie is a refreshment.</p>
<p>At the swimming pool the same day a notice on the wall cautioned something like &#8216;het nuttigen van eigen consumpties is niet toegestaan.&#8217; It had me thinking about how consumption in English used to signify TB (TBC in Dutch), and how consume has its wild side in the sense of devour, as in a fire that consumes a building.</p>
<p>But at the same time consume also means to ingest, which I suppose is devouring too, and this is where the Dutch consumptie comes from. But where the Dutch consumptie means the food and drinks themselves, the English consumption means the process of ingesting the food and drinks, the consumption of consumpties, as it were.</p>
<p>Te Dutch and the English have travelled a different path to end up at the same destination: a word that signifies food and drinks. The Dutch has created the noun consumptie from the verb consumeren, which signifies the process of ingesting, whereas the English has created the noun refreshment from the verb refresh, which signifies restoring.</p>
<p>So the Dutch consumptie focuses on the act whereas the English refreshment on its effect. But they both label the same thing: food and drinks.</p>
<p>And both languages still use notices such as &#8216;het nuttigen van eigen consumpties is niet toegestaan&#8217; or &#8216;only refreshments purchased at xxx may be consumed on the premises&#8217;. Prim notices that speak in a voice from the past from the walls of swimming-pool cafes, soft-play areas and the like. It&#8217;s a bit like listening to a news reel from the 1950s.</p>
<p>And I haven&#8217;t even gone into the newer meaning of consumer or consument, someone who buys stuff. It&#8217;s rather apt to see that consumerism comes from devouring.</p>
<p>I used my consumptiebon for a beer in the interval at the gymuithouding, as it should be called. I needed it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?feed=rss2&amp;p=2671</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrate your victories! Forget your defeats!</title>
		<link>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2651</link>
		<comments>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2651#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 11:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Marianne</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Living in Holland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2651</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Try asking a Dutch person if they&#8217;ve ever heard of Chatham and chances are they will have done. Ask a British person and chances are they won&#8217;t. I tried it out on the Dutch person next to me at a recent circle of doom. And on myself. The Dutch person had vaguely heard of it. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><a href="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/chatham2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2662 " alt="chatham2" src="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/chatham2-500x375.jpg" width="400" height="300" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">
<p>Try asking a Dutch person if they&#8217;ve ever heard of Chatham and chances are they will have done. Ask a British person and chances are they won&#8217;t.</p>
<p>I tried it out on the Dutch person next to me at a recent circle of doom. And on myself. The Dutch person had vaguely heard of it. I hadn&#8217;t until I watched the Helden op Zee episode of <a href="http://www.uitzendinggemist.nl/programmas/9044-de-gouden-eeuw">De Gouden Eeuw.</a> Theory proven therefore.*</p>
<p>The weird thing is that Chatham is in England. So why do Dutch people know about it? Is there a really good campsite there? Do they make good liquorice? Is it gezellig? Do they have circles of doom?</p>
<p>The answer to all of the above is no. Or at least it&#8217;s not why it&#8217;s famous in the Netherlands. They know it because, just like Nieuwpoort, it&#8217;s the scene of a great Dutch victory.</p>
<p>So if you say Chatham to a Dutch person it&#8217;s a bit like saying Waterloo to a British person (although if the British person is a child they&#8217;ll snigger first because you said loo). Even if they don&#8217;t know much about it they&#8217;ll know that it was the scene of something great for their nation.</p>
<p>Maybe Anouk should sing a song about Chatham for the Eurovision Song Contest this year. Although Chatham is a bit difficult to rhyme. Can only think of twat. Beat the British twat-hams at Chatham sha la la, ting a ling, doo be doo?</p>
<p>Back to the history lesson. The British historian in De Gouden Eeuw makes the point that countries tend to remember their victories and forget their defeats. They also downplay other countries&#8217; victories. So the same Chatham event is known as &#8216;de Slag bij de Medway&#8217; in Dutch and the &#8216;Raid on the Medway&#8217; in English. A battle for the Dutch but a mere raid for the English.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s like how if your country wins the Eurovision Song Contest it matters a lot whereas if you lose you forget about it fast. In times of European peace the Eurovision Song Contest and football have consequently become our battles and raids.</p>
<p>The story behind Chatham is a cunning Dutch plan to wreak revenge on the British attack on the Dutch fleet in 1666 and plundering of the islands of Vlieland and Terschelling.</p>
<p>Without, ahem, going into too much detail, it all being too painful being one of the British twat-hams at Chatham and all that and having to live with Dutch people who still seem to think it is alright to show off about this victory but don&#8217;t seem to remember that we won the Eurovision Song Contest with Bucks Fizz once, the Dutch fleet, led by Michiel de Ruyter, sailed to Britain to take the British military base at Chatham and do a spot of camping.</p>
<p>They sailed down the River Medway to Chatham where they attacked the British fleet and managed to sink lots of ships, set fire to others, set fire and sink others again and sink and set fire to yet others again.</p>
<p>They also managed to capture the flagship (vlaggenschip in Dutch) of the British fleet, the HMS Royal Charles, and tow it back to the Netherlands as a war trophy.</p>
<p>The stern carving is still on display at the Rijksmuseum, although Prince Willem Alexander did return temporarily to the UK last year for an <a href="http://www.rmg.co.uk/visit/events/royal-river">exhibition </a>at the Maritime Museum in Greenwich under much pomp and inner gloating.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>* Although I am willing to accept that I might just be very ignorant</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?feed=rss2&amp;p=2651</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prague: it’s just like Drenthe</title>
		<link>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2649</link>
		<comments>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2649#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 10:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Marianne</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Other stuff]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2649</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Son&#8217;s friend recently went to Prague. His impression was that &#8216;het is net Drenthe. Maar met meer geschiedenis&#8217;.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>Son&#8217;s friend recently went to Prague. His impression was that &#8216;het is net Drenthe. Maar met meer geschiedenis&#8217;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?feed=rss2&amp;p=2649</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Expecting gezeur</title>
		<link>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2646</link>
		<comments>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2646#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 14:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Marianne</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Living in Holland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2646</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Daughter has a tummy bug, and has spend the last few days vomiting. As Son&#8217;s bruised arm doesn&#8217;t yet allow him to cycle to school, I took him to school in the car yesterday, which meant taking the sick machine too. On the way back home in the afternoon we realised we&#8217;d forgotten the sick [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>Daughter has a tummy bug, and has spend the last few days vomiting. As Son&#8217;s bruised arm doesn&#8217;t yet allow him to cycle to school, I took him to school in the car yesterday, which meant taking the sick machine too.</p>
<p>On the way back home in the afternoon we realised we&#8217;d forgotten the sick bucket when daughter cried out, &#8216;I&#8217;m going to be sick.&#8217;</p>
<p>Like a suburban James Bond I pulled over, jumped out of the car, rushed round to Daughter&#8217;s side of the car, grabbed her and held her over some grass. (Not quick enough, however, to save the interior of the car from a soaking. My car doesn&#8217;t need ejector seats; it needs an automatic sick bucket. Or ejector seats for sick producers).</p>
<p>I had stopped was outside the village graveyard. During the action I was expecting an oude zeur to pop up – maybe out of a grave – and tell me off for letting Daughter vomit on the verge outside the graveyard. Sacrilegious. Tut, tut, tut.</p>
<p>Surprisingly, it didn&#8217;t happen. But it did remind me of one of my favourite zeur moments, in retrospect at least. It involved a very-heavily pregnant me (something like 39 weeks and 6 days) who had decided we desperately needed new tumblers in case our kraamvisite decided they wanted iets fris rather than a lekker bakje koffie.</p>
<p>So there I stood outside the Hema with two carrier bags each containing a set of glasses. I had just hung a bag on each side of the handlebar of my bike – how&#8217;s that for Dutch going to 40 weeks and carrying on cycling too – and was backing the bike out from between all the other bikes when I managed to knock over a bike.</p>
<p>Normally I am very law-abiding and would have picked up the other bike. However, this time what with the pregnant inability to bend over compounded by the two bags of glasses hanging on my bike handlebars, being antisocial seemed like the only option.</p>
<p>Unlike our graveyard moment, this time there was an oude zeur at hand, and she was quick to let me know how bad I was. She&#8217;d gone before I could even explain the heavily pregnant/bags of glasses conundrum and ask her for help.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?feed=rss2&amp;p=2646</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Avoiding speaking other languages</title>
		<link>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2638</link>
		<comments>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2638#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 10:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Marianne</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Language learning]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2638</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Whilst on holiday in the Belgian Ardennes the other week – another tick on the list of Dutch things to do – we ended up in France one day, a bit excited at having so many countries within reach: Belgium, France, Germany and Luxembourg! Seeing as one of the subjects of my degree was French, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>Whilst on holiday in the Belgian Ardennes the other week – another tick on the list of Dutch things to do – we ended up in France one day, a bit excited at having so many countries within reach: Belgium, France, Germany and Luxembourg!</p>
<p>Seeing as one of the subjects of my degree was French, I should have relished the thought of being able to speak some French. Instead, as the kids got excited at the prospect of French cheese, quails, skinned rabbits, lobsters, cockles and oysters in the supermarket part of me said no way, no way, no way, because we were staying in a holiday cottage and the idea of holidays is that you don&#8217;t have to cook and certainly not rabbit, lobster and quail.</p>
<p>However, it was also due to reluctance at having to ask for French cheese, quails, skinned rabbits, lobsters, cockles and oysters.</p>
<p>Husband and I live up to the stereotypes of the Dutch people being good at languages and the British being crap at them. This isn&#8217;t because he&#8217;s any better at languages than me, honestly, but simply because he doesn&#8217;t mind having a go. And to be fair to myself doing the above in Dutch would not be a problem.</p>
<p>Husband was soon stepping into the breach and ordering smelly cheese like there was no tomorrow (although he too drew the line at quails, skinned rabbits, lobsters, cockles and oysters).</p>
<p>The next day had me taking a more Dutch approach. Son slipped in the snow in the woods. Suspecting a broken arm we raced to the A&amp;E department of the nearest hospital in a Belgian town.</p>
<p>This time it was me who marched up to the reception and spoke French. I might chicken out of skinned rabbits but injured children are a different kettle of fish.</p>
<p>(Luckily Son&#8217;s arm wasn&#8217;t broken or fractured, which had Son bursting into tears for the first time since the initial fall because he wanted a plaster cast and six weeks of not having to write at school.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?feed=rss2&amp;p=2638</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Battle of Nieuwpoort</title>
		<link>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2580</link>
		<comments>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2580#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 10:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Marianne</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Living in Holland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2580</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On our way back from the UK at Christmas we drove past a sign in northern Belgium saying Nieuwpoort. &#8216;De Slag bij Nieuwpoort!&#8217; Husband exclaimed. The rest of the car didn&#8217;t share his enthusiasm. De Slag bij Nieuwpoort is one of those things you learn at school here. Having learnt about other things at school, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>On our way back from the UK at Christmas we drove past a sign in northern Belgium saying Nieuwpoort. &#8216;De Slag bij Nieuwpoort!&#8217; Husband exclaimed. The rest of the car didn&#8217;t share his enthusiasm.</p>
<p>De Slag bij Nieuwpoort is one of those things you learn at school here. Having learnt about other things at school, I decided to find out what it was all about.</p>
<p>The story begins with kapers (privateers), or zeerovers as they&#8217;re called on <a href="http://www.innl.nl/page/288/nl">this site</a>. The difference is significant, because a kaper had permission in the form of a kaperbrief (letter of marque) from a country to plunder and pillage, a <a href="http://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaper">piraterij-vergunning</a> (pirate permit), as it says here. <a href="http://www.historynet.com/francis-drakes-raids-on-spanish-colonial-ports-netted-tons-of-loot.htm">Francis Drake</a> was therefore a privateer, to the English at least, because he had a letter of marque from Queen Elizabeth I.</p>
<div id="attachment_2628" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 316px"><a href="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/kaperbrief.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2628" alt="kaperbrief" src="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/kaperbrief.jpg" width="306" height="306" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A kaper graduation ceremony</p></div>
<p>A zeerover, however, is another name for a pirate, as is boekanier (like the English buccaneer it comes from the French boucanier, &#8216;one who dries and smokes meat on a boucan, a barbecue&#8230;&#8217;*) The Chambers Dictionary of Etymology also mentions &#8216;sea rovers&#8217; in connection with buccaneers, a term I&#8217;ve never heard before.**</p>
<div id="attachment_2631" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 316px"><a href="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/zeerovers.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2631" alt="zeerovers" src="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/zeerovers.jpg" width="306" height="306" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Zeerovers, piraten or boekaniers</p></div>
<p>The Battle of Nieuwpoort was fought because kapers from the ports of Duinkerken and Nieuwpoort, which were in the hands of the Spanish – this was during the Eighty Years&#8217; War between the Dutch and the Spanish – had a piracy permit from the high admiralty in Brussels to plunder passing ships. The Dutch Republic wasn&#8217;t pleased because this meant its ships being attacked.</p>
<p>It therefore decided to send in an Oranje.</p>
<p>Maurits van Oranje was dispatched in 1600 to what is now Belgium, and he and his troops faced the Spanish in the dunes of Nieuwpoort in what is known as the Slag bij Nieuwpoort. Despite being fewer in numbers the Dutch army managed to win the battle and beat the Spanish army.***</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>* Chambers Dictionary of Etymology</p>
<p>** Incidentally, there is an obsolete meaning of the verb rove, to roam, which is &#8216;to sail as pirates, roam the seas as rovers&#8217; and a rover is a sea robber or pirate. These come from the Dutch rover, robber.</p>
<p>*** Despite winning the battle they didn&#8217;t manage to seize Nieuwpoort and the kapers continued their attacks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?feed=rss2&amp;p=2580</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Right to language lessons in native language</title>
		<link>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2607</link>
		<comments>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2607#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 12:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Marianne</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Living in Holland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2607</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A Turkish workers&#8217; organisation, HTIB, is taking the Dutch state to court over the right of Turkish children to language lessons in Turkish at school. Their lawyer appeared on Pauw en Witteman the other night and his argument was that the Netherlands has signed treaties – he didn&#8217;t specify which ones – that guarantee children [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><iframe src="http://media.vara.nl/player.php?id=215279" height="270" width="480" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>A Turkish workers&#8217; organisation, HTIB, is taking the Dutch state to court over the right of Turkish children to language lessons in Turkish at school.</p>
<p>Their lawyer appeared on Pauw en Witteman the other night and his argument was that the Netherlands has signed treaties – he didn&#8217;t specify which ones – that guarantee children the right to their native language.</p>
<p>One of the treaties could be the Convention on the Rights of the Child, Article 30 of which states: &#8216;Minority or indigenous children have the right to learn about and practice their own culture, language and religion.&#8217;</p>
<p>The above version was from the <a href="http://www.unicef.org/crc/">UNICEF</a> site but the link is no longer working. I can&#8217;t seem to find the text on the UN site but have just found another version on the <a href="http://www.crin.org/docs/resources/treaties/uncrc.asp">CRIN </a>site, which, interestingly enough, words it differently (my italics):</p>
<p>&#8216;In those States in which ethnic, religious or linguistic minorities or persons of indigenous origin exist, a child belonging to such a minority or who is indigenous <em>shall not be denied the right,</em> in community with other members of his or her group, to enjoy his or her own culture, to profess and practise his or her own religion, or to use his or her own language.&#8217;</p>
<p>The CRIN version, even more so than the UNICEF version, says that the child mustn&#8217;t be prevented from access to its culture, language and religion, but doesn&#8217;t say anything about the state having to teach the child these.</p>
<p>The Dutch Ministry of Education, Culture and Science is taking this line as well, if a piece in <a href="http://www.elsevier.nl/Nederland/nieuws/2013/2/Vereniging-eist-Turkse-taalles-op-Nederlandse-scholen-1182762W/?cmpid=NLC|elsevier_dagelijks|2013-02-25|Vereniging_eist_Turkse_taalles_op_Nederlandse_scholen">Elsevier</a> is to be believed.</p>
<p>However, without knowing the treaties the organisation is referring to and which text actually applies, it&#8217;s difficult to say whether the right to language lessons is actually enshrined in treaties.</p>
<p>I agree with the teacher in the above piece that it would be unfeasible to implement this for all children with a native language other than Dutch.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?feed=rss2&amp;p=2607</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Must try this</title>
		<link>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2602</link>
		<comments>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2602#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 13:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Marianne</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Living in Holland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2602</guid>
		<description />
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><a href="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/mager.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2603" alt="mager" src="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/mager-500x500.jpg" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?feed=rss2&amp;p=2602</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Historically inaccurate potatoes</title>
		<link>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2589</link>
		<comments>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2589#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 12:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Marianne</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Living in Holland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2589</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have a radar for historically inaccurate potatoes. So when the girl in Girl with a Pearl Earring by Tracy Chevalier mentions boiling her cap with potato peelings to keep it stiff, my radar immediately sights it. I irritate even myself by looking up when the painting Girl with a Pearl Earring is from: 1665. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><div id="attachment_2595" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 280px"><a href="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/potato.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2595" title="A potato" alt="potato" src="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/potato-450x600.jpg" width="270" height="360" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A potato</p></div>
<p>I have a radar for historically inaccurate potatoes. So when the girl in Girl with a Pearl Earring by Tracy Chevalier mentions boiling her cap with potato peelings to keep it stiff, my radar immediately sights it. I irritate even myself by looking up when the painting Girl with a Pearl Earring is from: 1665. Would potatoes have been common enough then to be boiling your cap in them?</p>
<div id="attachment_2599" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 280px"><a href="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/inaccurate-potato.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2599 " alt="A historically inaccurate potato" src="http://www.likeasponge.nl/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/inaccurate-potato-450x600.jpg" width="270" height="360" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A historically inaccurate potato</p></div>
<p>A recent article on stamppot in the NRC Handelsblad mentioned how even though hutspot is all about potatoes, the hutspot that the Spanish left behind when they scarpered lifting the seige of Leiden in 1574 wouldn&#8217;t have contained potatoes. The potato had only just been introduced in the Netherlands so it would probably have contained parsnips instead. The potato, said the writer, only became customary fare somewhere in the eighteenth century.</p>
<p>My radar&#8217;s next possible example of historically inaccurate potatoes was in The Thousand Autumns of Jacob de Zoet by David Mitchell. The potato pops up in a character&#8217;s childhood reminiscence of how he and the gardener roasted a potato on a fire in the garden in 1757. Would the potato have been the peasant food it certainly was a century later when Van Gogh painted the Potato Eaters? My radar and I decided we should let this one go.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?feed=rss2&amp;p=2589</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Queens, plums and potatoes</title>
		<link>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2577</link>
		<comments>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2577#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 12:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Marianne</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning Dutch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Living in Holland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.likeasponge.nl/?p=2577</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With Queen Beatrix&#8217;s abdication yesterday and continuing the theme of potatoes, I recently discovered that whereas a British queen speaks with a plum in her mouth a Dutch one speaks with a hot potato in her throat (praten met een hete aardappel in de keel).]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>With Queen Beatrix&#8217;s abdication yesterday and continuing the theme of potatoes, I recently discovered that whereas a British queen speaks with a plum in her mouth a Dutch one speaks with a hot potato in her throat (praten met een hete aardappel in de keel).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.likeasponge.nl/?feed=rss2&amp;p=2577</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
