<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Police: Dad Kills Son While Cleaning Gun</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/christopher-stanlane-kills-son_n_2952944.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2952944</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T03:53:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T05:54:01Z</updated>
    
    <summary>FAIRMONT, N.C. -- Authorities say a 10-year-old boy was killed in North Carolina when he was shot by his father while the parent cleaned a...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/david-moye/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;FAIRMONT, N.C. -- Authorities say a 10-year-old boy was killed in North Carolina when he was shot by his father while the parent cleaned a shotgun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robeson County deputies say 34-year-old Christopher Stanlane was on the couch in his Fairmont home wiping down the gun around 4 p.m. Sunday when it fired.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Investigators say the boy was sitting in front of his father watching television and was struck in the head. Paramedic declared him dead at the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No charges have been filed, and deputies are still investigating the shooting.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055642/thumbs/s-CHRISTOPHER-STANLANE-JR-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Emily Hecht-McGowan: A Letter to My Baby Girl</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emily-hechtmcgowan/what-marriage-equality-me_b_2948752.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2948752</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T01:56:05Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T01:56:10Z</updated>
    
    <summary>We didn't marry for "rights" or "benefits." We married for the same reasons that most people do -- both gay and straight. Because we loved each other, we wanted to stand up in front of our friends and family and make a lifelong commitment to one another and we aspired to build a family together.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Emily Hecht-McGowan</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emily-hechtmcgowan/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;We have reached an incredibly historic moment in the movement for LGBT equality. Today, the U.S. Supreme Court began hearing two pivotal gay rights cases: on Proposition 8, the referendum that stripped away same-sex couples' right to marry in California, and the "Defense of Marriage" Act (DOMA),the law that requires the federal government to discriminate against married same-sex couples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been an advocate for the LGBT community for many years. I've worked on the repeal of "Don't Ask, Don't Tell" and DOMA. I've fought for safer schools for our kids, for employment non-discrimination, and to protect families with LGBT parents. But my perspective on these issues fundamentally changed when my wife Sharon and I became parents. I hope our 6-month-old daughter, Sadie, will never know how her family was treated unequally by most states and the federal government just because she has two mommies. But I imagine that someday Sadie will come to Sharon and me, and ask us to explain what all of the fuss was about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've written her a letter with what I want to tell her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Sadie,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's what the fuss is about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Mom and Mommy were married on June 5, 2010, our marriage was not legal in most places.  Because it was important to us that our marriage be a legal one, we traveled to Boston (along with your grandparents, aunties, uncles, and all of Mom and Mommy's friends), where they allowed gay and lesbian couples to marry, to have our wedding. We didn't marry for "rights" or "benefits." We married for the same reasons that most people do -- both gay and straight. Because we loved each other, we wanted to stand up in front of our friends and family and make a lifelong commitment to one another and we aspired to build a family together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That dream of a family came true on October 2, 2012, the day you were born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because you have two mommies, it took a little extra help and a little longer to bring you into the world. But there has never been a child who was more anticipated or planned for, and certainly none that is more loved than you. You are such a wonderful little girl, with a light and a spirit and a smile that just illuminate a room. You bring so much joy into our lives, each and every day.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom and I are teaching you to be compassionate, and to stand up for what you believe in. To tell the truth, and to treat others with respect. And we want the same things for you that most parents want for their children -- to feel loved, safe, and supported. We want you to always be surrounded by loving friends and family, and to grow into a happy, confident, thriving adult with a strong sense of self and purpose. And we hope that someday you, too, will have a family of your own. No matter what path you choose, your mommies will always be here to love you, support you and cheer you on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, there are some people who don't think that you should have two mommies. The opponents of marriage equality have made sweeping statements and assumptions about the quality of your life, and the lives of all children raised by gay and lesbian couples. They've argued that Mom and I are not good parents, and that families with biological ties to each other are somehow superior to other kinds of families. There are many reasons why these arguments are offensive and ludicrous, but at the most basic level they simply ignore the reality of today's American family -- the reality of OUR family. We are a nation of blended and multi-generational families, adoptive and foster families, families headed by single parents, divorced parents and unmarried parents. And yes, some families have a mommy and a daddy, some have two mommies, and some have two daddies. So while opponents of marriage equality attempt to render families like ours invisible, &lt;a href="http://www.familyequality.org/equal_family_blog/2013/03/13/1571/new_data_on_lgbt_families" target="_hplink"&gt;new information&lt;/a&gt; tells us that there are many more of our families than we originally thought, and that our numbers will only continue to grow.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps what's even more infuriating is that some people have made judgments about the worth of our family, and have professed to speak on your behalf without ever taking the time to actually get to know you or our family and learn about our experiences. At 6 months old, you're too young to speak for yourself -- although with two lawyers for mothers, my guess is that you have already formed some strong opinions on this topic! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I had the opportunity to work on the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/steve-majors/voices-of-children_b_2791942.html" target="_hplink"&gt;"Children's Voices" amicus brief&lt;/a&gt;, I jumped at the chance to give you and hundreds of thousands of children like you a voice in this critical discussion. The brief, filed by Family Equality Council and our partner organizations, attempts to paint for the Justices an accurate picture of what families headed by gay and lesbian couples truly look like. The voices and stories of the children whose lives and families are at the heart of the DOMA and Prop 8 cases are too often absent, or simply dismissed as unimportant. Because you and children like you are among those most directly impacted by marriage equality, you are uniquely qualified to speak about how your families function and how your parents' exclusion from marriage impacts your lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The young people who speak out in this brief are truly remarkable, and capture so much of what I think you would say, if you could communicate your feelings to the Court today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are your role models -- the &lt;a href="http://www.familyequality.org/get_involved/outspoken/" target="_hplink"&gt;Outspoken Generation&lt;/a&gt;. They are speaking out for what they believe in; they are telling the truth. They are standing up for their families and are demanding that they be respected and valued, just the same as everyone else. These young people are my heroes -- because they are standing up for YOU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time you read this letter, we will know the Court's rulings. But today, on the cusp of this historic moment, while it's impossible to predict the outcomes, there are a few things I do know for certain. We are at a tipping point in the fight for equality. Last November, marriage was on the ballot in four different states -- and for the first time ever, equality won in every instance. Support for marriage equality nationwide is at &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-fix/wp/2013/03/18/gay-marriage-support-hits-new-high-in-post-abc-poll/" target="_hplink"&gt;unprecedented levels&lt;/a&gt;. And we now live in a world where any serious candidate for President of the United States will have to openly and unabashedly support the freedom for all Americans to marry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no going backwards. The momentum is on the side of equality, and every single day we are one step closer to a world where all you will ever know about this fight is what you will read in your history books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this explains what all of the fuss was about.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love you with all my heart,&lt;br /&gt;
Mommy&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1032458/thumbs/s-LGBT-IMMIGRANTS-UNITED-STATES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Prince's Heartwarming Letter To A Young Fan Is All Kinds Of Sweet</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/prince-letter-to-young-fan_n_2951112.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2951112</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T22:36:53Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T22:27:32Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Get ready for some serious '80s nostalgia. In June 1984, a young Prince fan named Annalisa Masters wrote Prince a letter just after his sixth...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Hayley Hudson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/hayley-hudson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Get ready for some serious '80s nostalgia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In June 1984, a young Prince fan named Annalisa Masters wrote Prince a letter just after his sixth album &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LYUvCStLYJI" target="_hplink"&gt;Purple Rain&lt;/a&gt; came out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's unclear what exactly Masters wrote, but whatever it was touched Prince so deeply that he responded with a very sweet letter. Until recently it was &lt;a href="http://www.lettersofnote.com/2011/11/i-was-2-busy-listening-2-grass-grow.html" target="_hplink"&gt;on display&lt;/a&gt; at the Hard Rock Cafe in Minneapolis, according to Letters of Note, who originally posted it online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Story continues after photo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="prince letter to young fan" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055294/thumbs/o-PRINCE-LETTER-TO-YOUNG-FAN-570.jpg?15" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The letter reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Dearest Annalisa,

&lt;p&gt;It is so nice of 2 write me. I don't always have time 2 reply but your letters surely brighten my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You're so sweet. I'm glad you're my friend. If u dig the video, wait until u see the movie. I'm very proud of it. I hope u are 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on making thru jr. high. I'm sure u did better than I. I wasn't much on school. I was 2 busy listening 2 the grass grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank u again 4 writing me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until I hear from u,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prince&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He seems totally down to earth -- a side effect of listening to grass grow, maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;H/T BuzzFeed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055294/thumbs/s-PRINCE-LETTER-TO-YOUNG-FAN-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Alyssa Silva: For My Brother</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/alyssa-silva/for-my-brother_b_2951276.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2951276</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T21:39:42Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T21:39:46Z</updated>
    
    <summary>One September afternoon, I was receiving an albuterol treatment to keep my lungs expanded and free from infection. Suddenly, there was a knock at our door: It was a police officer to tell my mom Adam had been hit by a truck while riding his bike.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Alyssa Silva</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/alyssa-silva/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My name is Alyssa Silva and I am a 22-year-old aspiring writer. When I was five-months- old, I was diagnosed with a disease called Spinal Muscular Atrophy. It is a debilitating disease that causes severe muscle weakness and affects my overall physical well-being. However, this doesn't stop me from living my life to its fullest. I started a blog in hopes of spreading awareness on my disease by sharing my personal stories with everyone. I hope that my posts will educate others on what living with this disease is like and inspire those who find themselves in difficult situations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd like to dedicate this post to someone who has always believed in me throughout the years. Whether I'm sick in the hospital, need someone to take me to school, or just want someone to talk to, this person is there for me no matter the circumstance. I'm not sure what I did to deserve such a special guy, but I'm so grateful for having him in my life. This one goes out to my best friend and brother, Adam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By all means, Adam and I have your typical older brother/little sister relationship. We laugh, we argue, we get along, we fight; you know -- the usual sibling "stuff." More often than not, Adam finds some clever way to poke fun at me, and I always find myself using a less-than-witty remark as my comeback. It's a little annoying, but hey, that's what big brothers are for, right? Nevertheless, in addition to the traditional relationship the two of us share, Adam has given me nothing but the love and strength I need to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-25-ScreenShot20130325at5.06.37PM.png" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-25-ScreenShot20130325at5.06.37PM.png" width="295" height="290" style="float: left; margin:10px"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just the other day my mom was telling me a story from when Adam and I were very young. It was right after Christmas and I was extremely sick, which only meant one thing: My parents were packing up our necessities and getting ready for a three-week hospital stay. My mom walked into my brother's room around 11 o'clock at night, hours after she had tucked him in, and found him in the corner crying. When asking what was wrong, Adam replied with, "I don't want my baby sister to go to the hospital. I want Santa to take all my presents back if that means making her all better. I just want my sister to stay home. That's all I want for Christmas!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn't help but chuckle when I first heard this story. Because, seriously, how cute is that? Then, I realized Adam has been this way all along. Okay, so maybe we haven't found him in a corner crying and asking Santa to take his toys back since that night. But, to this day, Adam has always done everything in his power to make sure I'm happy and healthy. From holding my hand during those daunting doctors' appointments to canceling his plans to take care of me, he has given me every reason to believe that he really is the best brother ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 12 years ago, the tables were turned and for the first time in my life, I was worried sick over Adam. One September afternoon, I was receiving an albuterol treatment to keep my lungs expanded and free from infection, something I used to do on a daily basis. Suddenly, there was a knock at our door and my mom rushed to open it. It was a police officer to tell my mom Adam had been hit by a truck while riding his bike. The prognosis didn't look too promising, and the police officer escorted my mom to the hospital before it was going to be too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first three days Adam was on life support, and the doctors had very little hope he would pull through. He had fractured his femur and skull in several places and had internal bleeding. As hard as it was, my parents were told to say their goodbyes in case he wouldn't make it through the night. Although the news was grim, we all held on to our strong faith in hopes of Adam seeing better days. Night after night he fought for his life, and slowly began getting stronger as time progressed. He ended up spending two weeks in the hospital and a few years gaining his stamina back. Adam was one of the lucky ones, and I can't even begin to think about what my life would have been like without him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam, you're braver than most people I know. Not only have you gone through your own hardships, but you have always stayed by my side through my adversities as well. You've showed me what it means to have courage, especially during those days when giving up seems like the only option. Thank you for doing all that you do to help mom and dad out with my needs. Thank you for encouraging me to start this blog. And, most importantly, thank you for being my number one fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-25-ScreenShot20130325at5.06.46PM.png" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-25-ScreenShot20130325at5.06.46PM.png" width="309" height="310" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This post &lt;a href="http://alyssaksilva.wordpress.com/2013/02/03/for-my-brother/" target="_hplink"&gt;originally appeared&lt;/a&gt; on Alyssa's WordPress blog. To read more of her work, &lt;a href="http://alyssaksilva.wordpress.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055388/thumbs/s-ALYSSA-SILVA-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Do Parents Spend More Time Teaching Boys Or Girls?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/2013/03/25/girls-and-learning_n_2949117.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2949117</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T21:25:16Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T21:25:17Z</updated>
    
    <summary>If you're trying to keep up with the latest headlines on gender equality and parenting, it's hard to tell if Canada is really having a...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Claire Sibonney</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/claire-sibonney/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;If you're trying to keep up with the latest headlines on gender equality and parenting, it's hard to tell if &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/saman-ahsan/how-do-we-empower-girls-in-canada_b_2918035.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Canada is really having a girl crisis,&lt;/a&gt; or if girls are more empowered than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While girls clearly have never had more education opportunities, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/saman-ahsan/how-do-we-empower-girls-in-canada_b_2918035.html" target="_hplink"&gt;they still face enormous struggles, particularly when it comes to self esteem. &lt;/a&gt; And there are signs that girls still have a long way to go in shattering the glass ceiling in the workplace, whether or not you agree with&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/monique-svazlian-cpcc-acc/truly-leaning-in_b_2909452.html" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg's "Lean In" ideas about feminism&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a recent working paper by two Canadian economics professors concludes that for preschool kids in Canada, the United States and United Kingdom, it is &lt;a href="http://faculty.arts.ubc.ca/kmilligan/research/papers/baker-milligan-boygirl.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;girls — not boys — who receive more teaching time from their parents.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study's authors,  University of Toronto's Michael Baker and University of British Columbia's Kevin Milligan, noted that in all three countries, parents spent more time teaching their daughters across the board, including reading, telling stories, singing songs, drawing, and teaching new words and letters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only activity that was spread more evenly between boys and girls was teaching numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an interview with the Toronto Star, the authors say that spending equal learning time with boys and girls &lt;a href="http://www.thestar.com/life/parent/2013/03/25/parents_spend_more_learning_time_with_young_daughters_than_sons_study.html" target="_hplink"&gt;could reduce the Canadian kindergarten achievement gender gap by up to a third&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conclusions were even true for fraternal girl-and-boy twins in cases where parents were determined to treat both children similarly. And it looks like the reason is simply because girls are easier to teach and "more rewarding" and they tend not to wiggle and squirm as much as boys do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"This finding is consistent with a story in which boys are less rewarding to teach, and parents are more willing to persevere with boys once they are not responsible for their care throughout the day," say Baker and Milligan in the report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit of more time learning with parents is that it may embed certain behavior patterns that children need to do well in school, &lt;a href="http://www.ccl-cca.ca/ccl/Reports/OtherReports/201104GenderReport.html" target="_hplink"&gt;and may be a reason that boys are falling behind academically&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their study was a follow-up to a previous report that showed boys actually received more parental time than girls because their dads spend more time with them. However, the evidence that &lt;a href="http://www.nber.org/digest/oct04/w10281.html" target="_hplink"&gt;fathers may prefer sons&lt;/a&gt; didn't seem to apply with children under the age or five or six.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lesson for parents here? We all know little boys can be more of a handful than little girls, but that doesn't mean it's okay for parents to spend less time nurturing them. (That includes you too, Kate Middleton, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/2013/03/17/kate-middleton-baby_n_2895951.html" target="_hplink"&gt; since you say you want a baby boy&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is alright, however, to explore &lt;a href="http://www.eduguide.org/library/viewarticle/1511/" target="_hplink"&gt;how girls and boys have different learning styles&lt;/a&gt; when you're trying to educate your preschooler. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1054501/thumbs/s-THE-GENDER-GAP-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>14 Ways To De-Stress When Your Ex Has the Kids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/divorce-stress_n_2950800.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2950800</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T21:14:43Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T21:17:46Z</updated>
    
    <summary>One surprising silver-lining to divorce? Having time to yourself when your ex has the kids. You miss them, of course, but once you've adjusted to...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;One surprising silver-lining to divorce? Having time to yourself when your ex has the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You miss them, of course, but once you've adjusted to the quiet -- and the complete lack of Nick Jr. on your TV -- that uninterrupted "me time" can be exactly what you need after a long week of soccer practices, doctor's appointments and carpooling to school. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just ask HuffPost Divorce readers. From morning yoga classes, to well-earned naps, click through the slideshow below to see how our readers de-stress when the ex has the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--287666--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055206/thumbs/s-NAP-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Mike Julianelle: Why I Don't Care If Strangers Mistake My Son For A Girl</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mike-julianelle/gender-neutral_b_2832070.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2832070</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T20:08:22Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T20:08:29Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It's not our job as parents to decide who our son will be; it's our job to help him become the best version of that person he can.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Mike Julianelle</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mike-julianelle/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;My son is over 2 years old now and &lt;a href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/03/28/sweeney-toddler/" title="Sweeney Toddler" &gt;he's never had his hair cut&lt;/a&gt;. His hair is quite long and very curly, and as a result strangers occasionally mistake him for a girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first ten times it happened, I was annoyed. But eventually it got me thinking: &lt;em&gt;Would my son make a good-looking girl? And how would my life be different if I had a daughter instead of a son?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to the first question is an unequivocal YES. He would be a beautiful little girl. He has perfect skin, gorgeous hair and absurdly long eyelashes. Pretty sure he'd be walking runways, if he were a she.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second question is more complicated. I only have the one kid, so obviously I've only done the son thing. But even without having a daughter, I'm pretty sure the early stages of raising a girl aren't all that different from the early stages of raising a boy. The first few months are a total wash (literally -- you'll be doing laundry NONSTOP for the first year, at least). Once the personality starts to emerge, it starts out pretty gender neutral and likely remains that way until about the year-and-a-half mark. That was when my son started doing more boy-centric stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He's barely over 2 and he's just now really getting into cars and trains and playing catch, etc. But he also &lt;a href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/08/31/overstuffed/" title="Overstuffed" &gt;loves his stuffed animals&lt;/a&gt; and plays with my wife's makeup brush and occasionally wraps things around his neck, like a boa. So while he's been gravitating towards more stereotypically male interests, there's still a bit of overlap. Which is totally fine -- he's 2! And my wife and I try not to stifle any instinct he may have, one way or the other. He'll figure himself out, eventually, and we're not going to stand in his way. After all, &lt;a href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/09/18/stay-at-home-cad/" title="Stay-at-home Cad" &gt;I'm at home all day&lt;/a&gt;, so what right do I have to limit his choices?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when he seemed to really enjoy a friend's play kitchen, despite objections from some traditionalists in our circle, we got him one. And when he wants to play catch with his little football, we let him. Maybe he likes trucks and fire engines more than the average girl, but it also seems like he likes to dance more than the average boy. Parents seem to agree that boys are dirtier and more rambunctious, which may be true; my son is certainly a bit of a spaz these days. And he &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; usually pretty filthy. But he also HATES when his hands get dirty, whether it's from eating or playing in the sand or picking his nose, and begs us to clean them off immediately. I'm not actually sure if that's a gender-based thing or just common sense. Sticky hands are nasty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TV shows and music he likes are pretty gender neutral too, or so I assume. Every kid likes Elmo, right? And "Yo Gabba Gabba" is pretty devoid of any gender signifiers, unless you want to have a discussion about the geometry of Moono. I do not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really feel like the only thing that would be significantly different about having a 2-year-old daughter would be the clothes she would wear, and that wardrobe would be largely be under my wife's control (and full of dresses and hats and sparkly things). I'd also guess that a little girl might be more into princesses than superheroes, but &lt;a href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/06/07/just-one-of-the-guys-geeks/" &gt;that needn't be the case&lt;/a&gt;. To be honest, I'd make damn sure my daughter liked Superman, regardless of whether she liked Cinderella too. The same way my wife is going to make sure my son enjoys musicals, even though "Die Hard" might end up being his favorite movie. These things needn't be mutually exclusive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really don't care about our child's gender; we just want it to be happy. If that means veering outside the lines of stupid, often arbitrary gender assignations, so be it. It's not our job as parents to decide who our son will be; it's our job to help him become the best version of that person he can. So he'll get exposure to a whole world of interests, regardless of what gender they're typically associated with, and then he'll get to choose what he likes best, without judgment. Odds are it will be a mix of boy stuff &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; girl stuff. And if strangers want to keep mistaking him for a girl, that's their problem. Hopefully we'll instill in him enough self-confidence to be himself, regardless of what a still-largely-traditional world may think.&lt;p&gt;We won't go so far as &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/11/28/daughter-raised-as-boy_n_2204575.html" &gt;denying his gender&lt;/a&gt;, or pretending he's something he's not. We'll let him decide for himself, somewhere down the line. But we will probably get him a haircut soon. He looks like a mad scientist when he wakes up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-25-genderneutral3.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-25-genderneutral3.jpg" width="450" height="601" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/12/12/gender-neutral/" target="_hplink"&gt;This post originally appeared on Dad and Buried. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055116/thumbs/s-MIKEJULIANELLE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Babble.com: My Daughter's Awkward Question That I Wasn't Ready To Answer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/babblecom/how-not-to-talk-about-boys_b_2917942.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2917942</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T19:59:05Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T20:57:41Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The ability to talk about boys with my daughter will definitely come in handy soon. We're going to be at "that age" in no time. I don't know if me being gay is going to make it easier for her to confide in me, but if it does, great.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Babble.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/babblecom/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Seth Taylor for &lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/babble-voices/dad-overboard-seth-taylor/2013/03/11/how-to-not-talk-about-boys/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||032013||HowtoNotTalkAboutBoysWithMyDaughter|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;Babble.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, my daughter and I are hanging out at home. As we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day, she was at her mom's house. While she was there, she watched "The Avengers" for the first time. I'm all excited to hear what she thought of it, card-carrying nerd that I am. I've been trying to get her to watch it for months. She'd previously resisted, saying she thought it might be too intense or scary for her "age group." Her words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm thrilled we can now talk about how supremely, galactically cool the movie is. "So was I right?" I ask eagerly. "Was it awesome? Was it the best superhero movie ever?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never one to concede easily, she says, "Yeeeaaaa."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"No," I say, "I need more. I need you to admit it was completely amazing."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Fine," she says, "I admit it. It was cool."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Score for Dad. "See?" I say, basking in the moment. "I told you you'd like it. I never steer you wrong when it comes to movies. Right? Right?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I know, I know," she admits. (But not without an eye roll.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then she says, with a fresh spark in her voice: "One thing's for sure, though. Captain America is totally HOT."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/babble-voices/dad-overboard-seth-taylor/2013/02/05/are-you-there-god-its-me-margarets-dad/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||032013||HowtoNotTalkAboutBoysWithMyDaughter|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;Related: My daughter's about to hit puberty -- help!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time she's called a movie star hot. (See: &lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/babble-voices/dad-overboard-seth-taylor/2013/02/05/are-you-there-god-its-me-margarets-dad/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||032013||HowtoNotTalkAboutBoysWithMyDaughter|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;Peeta&lt;/a&gt;.) I've gotten used to it, although I still get a little squinchy every time she says it, and have to suppress the urge to say "NO NO NO YOU ARE ELEVEN THERE IS NO HOTNESS FOR AT LEAST THREE MORE YEARS YOU ARE FORBIDDEN TO HAVE HUMAN GIRL EMOTIONS BEGONE TO YOUR IVORY TOWER AND SSSHHHHH."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the truth is, she's definitely of the age when puppy crushes begin. It's time. And it's ok. Besides, I don't think "hot" is a sexualized term for her yet. It's just the language she's speaking, courtesy of middle school. Her friends call guys hot all the time. (Only famous guys, though. So far, they still think the boys at the school are gross. Thank God.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it's fine that she thinks Captain America is "hot." No problem. I'm good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then she says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Daddy, do you think Captain America is hot?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Screeeeeeeeeeeech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I ... um ... well ... what?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I said, do you think he's hot?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"How's that again?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Do. You. Think. Captain. America. Is. Ho-"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"So sorry, I can't hear you."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Yes you can!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Sorry, the reception is bad."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'm right in front of you! Just tell me if you think that guy is-"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'm going through a tunnel."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"DAD!" She's looking at me expectantly, no intention of letting me off the hook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, Mr. Super Well-Adjusted Gay Dad. What to do here? It feels like an extremely awkward (albeit predictable) moment, and it would be so even if she was asking me to assess a woman. Is it extra-bonus weird because we're talking about a guy's Hotness Quotient? Should it be weird just because it's the first time she's asked such a question, requiring a gay man's response?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderate honesty is the way to go, I decide. So I say, "I suppose he's a handsome guy, yes."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pretty bland response from me, I know. But it's enough to make her crack a huge grin. I can tell she a) knows I'm officially uncomfortable talking about this with her, and b) loves it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You know what's great about having a gay dad?" she  says then, "We get to talk about boys together!" And then she laughs and goes into the kitchen to get a snack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another one of those Dad situations I'm actually glad for. The more we talk, the more comfortable everything becomes. I'm a fan of it, the talking. The ability to talk about boys with my daughter will definitely come in handy soon. We're going to be at "that age" in no time. I don't know if me being gay is going to make it easier for her to confide in me, but if it does, great. If she can talk to me candidly about how much she likes Captain America, maybe she'll feel comfortable talking about a guy in her class that she likes, when the time comes. And maybe she'll be comfortable asking me questions about the guy that I like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in due time. I'll be ready for it when it matters. But for now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, Daughter. No. We won't be talking about boys together. Not quite yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now go to your room until you're 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/babble-voices/ellen-seidman-1000-perplexing-things-about-parenthood/2012/08/07/11-mistakes-parents-make-even-the-perfect-ones/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||032013||HowtoNotTalkAboutBoysWithMyDaughter|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;For 11 mistakes all parents make (even the perfect ones!), visit Babble!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE ON BABBLE:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/dad/if-you-want-to-date-my-daughter-you-must-follow-these-rules-part-1/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||032013||HowtoNotTalkAboutBoysWithMyDaughter|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;10 "dad rules" for dating my teenage daughter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/strollerderby/2012/08/12/10-sex-questions-from-seventh-graders-that-most-adults-probably-cant-answer-honestly-anyway/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||032013||HowtoNotTalkAboutBoysWithMyDaughter|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;10 sex questions from seventh graders that adults can't answer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/kid/the-7-worst-things-you-can-say-to-your-child/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||032013||HowtoNotTalkAboutBoysWithMyDaughter|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;7 things you should NEVER say to a kid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/mom/parent-humor-mom-secrets-kids-dont-know/parent-humor-mom-secrets-kids-dont-know-1/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||032013||HowtoNotTalkAboutBoysWithMyDaughter|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;The 10 biggest lies parents tell their kids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055171/thumbs/s-FATHER-DAUGHER-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Rev. Richard L. Killmer: Putting Kids In Solitary Confinement: A Cruel And Unwise Decision</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rev-richard-l-killmer/putting-kids-in-solitary-confinement-a-cruel-and-unwise-decision_b_2949966.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2949966</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T19:41:30Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T22:03:48Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I want a future community for my grandchildren which is marked by health and wholeness. By working to end the practice of the solitary confinement of youth, I hope to contribute to that kind of community.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Rev. Richard L. Killmer</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rev-richard-l-killmer/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Veteran news anchor Ted Koppel ended his &lt;a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/video/rock-center/51298950#51298950" target="_hplink"&gt;piece on kids locked away in solitary confinement on Rock Center with Brian Williams&lt;/a&gt; this past Friday by describing the practice as a "&lt;a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/video/rock-center/51298950#51299099" target="_hplink"&gt;national disgrace&lt;/a&gt;."  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The religious community shares in Koppel's sentiment. People of faith are particularly concerned about youth in solitary confinement in youth facilities and adult prisons. As a Presbyterian minister and as a grandfather, I believe the solitary confinement of youth is both wrong and counterproductive. In many states, children under 18 years old and "youthful offenders" under 24 are held in solitary confinement in adult prisons. The long-term psychological and developmental impacts of solitary confinement upon children are particularly devastating, resulting in hallucinations, paranoia, and increased rates of self-mutilation and suicide.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citing CIA studies into the impact of prolonged solitary confinement, psychologist Dr. Stuart Grassian described the results of solitary as "&lt;a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/video/rock-center/51298950#51299099" target="_hplink"&gt;permanent impairment&lt;/a&gt;."  If indeed 95 percent of the youth currently held in such debilitating conditions of isolation in U.S. prisons and jails will at some point return home to our communities, we all have a shared stake in their condition.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that all human beings have been given inherent dignity and worth. Solitary confinement degrades those gifts. My faith teaches that human beings thrive in community and consequently, denying human beings the community they need is unacceptable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem of solitary confinement extends beyond youth in the system. The United States has become a world leader in incarceration and in holding prisoners in prolonged solitary confinement. With just five percent of the world's population, the United States holds 25 percent of the world's prison population and the vast majority of all prisoners held in long-term solitary confinement. According to the Bureau of Justice Statistics, over 80,000 people in the U.S. criminal justice system are held in some form of isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the many faith traditions that comprise the &lt;a href="http://www.nrcat.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;National Religious Campaign Against Torture&lt;/a&gt;, all recognize the inherent dignity of each human being, and the particular importance of protecting the health and growth of children. We believe that prolonged solitary confinement denies the essential human need for community and profoundly disrupts the developmental progress of youth, and must be brought to an &lt;a href="http://www.nrcat.org/torture-in-us-prisons/statement" target="_hplink"&gt;end&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a story in the Book of Isaiah in which the prophet tells King Hezekiah that his children will be taken into exile in Assyria. The king responds by saying, "At least there will be peace in my day." Like King Hezekiah, short-sighted decisions may give a sense of security now by hiding the reality and the long-term impacts of placing young people in solitary confinement. By placing young people in solitary who will be released having experienced the horrors of such conditions, our society is failing our young people and the communities to which they will one day return. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is good news: Many states throughout the United States are awakening to the need for the practice of placing youth in solitary confinement to end. A number of bills have been introduced in states including Florida, California, Montana and Texas to limit or eliminate the use of juvenile solitary confinement. Campaigns are growing around the country to bring this abusive practice to an end.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Florida, a state that holds more young people under age 18 in adult state prisons than any other state, a bill (SB 812) has been introduced which includes provisions that strictly limit the use of solitary confinement of both children under 18 years old and youthful offenders under 24. Currently, there is no prohibition in state law or Florida Department of Corrections policy or regulation against holding young people in solitary confinement in Florida prisons and jails. &lt;a href="http://www.nrcat.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;The National Religious Campaign Against Torture &lt;/a&gt;is working hard to support this bill as well as similar ones in California and other states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want a future community for my grandchildren which is marked by health and wholeness. By working to end the practice of the solitary confinement of youth, I hope to contribute to that kind of community.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055178/thumbs/s-SOLITARY-CONFINEMENT-mini.jpg?10" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Victoria's Secret 'Bright Young Things' Slogan Has Parents In Tizzy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/victorias-secret-bright-young-things_n_2950691.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2950691</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T19:36:37Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T20:33:12Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Parents -- specifically parents with blogs -- are in a tizzy over Victoria's Secret's alleged new "tween line" aimed at young girls. News starting circulating...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ellie-krupnick/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Parents -- specifically parents with blogs -- are in a tizzy over &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/victorias-secret/" target="_hplink"&gt;Victoria's Secret's&lt;/a&gt; alleged new "tween line" aimed at young girls. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News starting circulating over the past few weeks that the lingerie mega-store was expanding its offerings with &lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/victorias-secret-teen-ads-2013-3" target="_hplink"&gt;a line called Bright Young Things&lt;/a&gt;, a collection that would target the tween demographic &lt;a href="http://www.today.com/video/today/51113907#51113907" target="_hplink"&gt;supposedly worth "$335 billion of spending power,"&lt;/a&gt; according to retail analyst Hitha Prabhakar. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news sparked inevitable uproar from parents like Evan Dolive, who penned &lt;a href="http://evandolive.com/2013/03/22/a-letter-to-victorias-secret-from-a-father/" target="_hplink"&gt;an open letter to Victoria's Secret on his personal blog.&lt;/a&gt; "I don’t want my daughter to ever think that to be popular or even attractive she has to have emblazon words on her bottom," he wrote. &lt;a href="http://phdsandpigtails.com/2013/03/23/victorias-secret-bright-young-things-age-compression/" target="_hplink"&gt;Another blogger echoed the senimtent&lt;/a&gt;, writing that Bright Young Things "furthers a trend of sexualizing girls younger and younger." The Victoria's Secret Facebook page &lt;a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/amyodell/backlash-mounts-against-victorias-secrets-sexy-teen-underwea" target="_hplink"&gt;started overflowing with angry comments&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is Victoria's Secret really coming for your 12-year-old? Click over to VictoriasSecret.com and you'll find no sign of a separate Bright Young Things collection. It appears that &lt;a href="http://www.victoriassecret.com/pink/spring-break" target="_hplink"&gt;Bright Young Things is a new Spring Break-themed tagline for PINK&lt;/a&gt;, Victoria's Secret's more youthful counterpart. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lingerie brand founded PINK, its younger spin-off, in 2002 with the explicit aim of targeting 15-to-22 year olds. The brightly colored sweats, bras, tank tops and undies have proven immensely popular among the high school set, but often for even younger girls in middle school too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is no plan to target middle schoolers explicitly, as Bright Young Things is not a new collection as reported. A PINK spokesperson told us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;In response to questions we recently received, Victoria’s Secret PINK is a brand for college-aged women. Despite recent rumors, we have no plans to introduce a collection for younger women. "Bright Young Things" was a slogan used in conjunction with the college spring break tradition.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Victoria's Secret has not, then, adopted a new policy to target younger girls than it already does. But that doesn't change the fact that PINK has and continues to target teens, whose preferences tend to rub off on tweens. It also doesn't change the fact that PINK's offerings for spring 2013 include &lt;a href="http://www.victoriassecret.com/pink/panties/lace-back-cheekster-panty-pink?ProductID=94055&amp;CatalogueType=OLS" target="_hplink"&gt;underwear with the word "Wild" across the butt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.victoriassecret.com/pink/spring-break/beach-blanket-pink?ProductID=108255&amp;CatalogueType=OLS" target="_hplink"&gt;a beach towel with the phrase "Kiss Me."&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it is those kind of saucy messages that have parents' panties in a twist, so to speak. And it's not nearly the first time Victoria's Secret has angered its customers with some controversial products (see &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/09/24/victorias-secret-geisha-outfit-photos_n_1909366.html" target="_hplink"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/04/pink-loves-consent-underw_n_2239534.html" target="_hplink"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/11/08/karlie-kloss-victorias-secret-headdress-fashion-show_n_2091958.html" target="_hplink"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think PINK needs to change their approach and tone down the cheeky teen messaging, or are parents overreacting? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See PINK's new Spring Break-themed video:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="570" height="321" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/FUS5ScGvcCw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="victorias secret bright young things" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055160/thumbs/o-VICTORIAS-SECRET-BRIGHT-YOUNG-THINGS-570.jpg?15" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fashion brands just can't stay out of the headlines:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--240278--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want more? Be sure to check out HuffPost Style on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/huffpoststyle" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/HuffPostStyle" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffpoststyle.tumblr.com" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffpoststyle/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; and Instagram at @HuffPostStyle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
--&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Do you have a style story idea or tips? Email us at stylesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055160/thumbs/s-VICTORIAS-SECRET-BRIGHT-YOUNG-THINGS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Energy Drinks May Be Riskier For Some Hearts More Than Others</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/energy-drinks-heart-risk_n_2950486.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2950486</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T19:04:48Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T19:08:02Z</updated>
    
    <summary> By Erin Hicks In a new analysis of possible harmful effects of energy drinks on the heart, researchers have found that the drinks may...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Amanda L. Chan</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/amanda-l-chan/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.everydayhealth.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;&lt;img alt="2012-07-16-eh_logo.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2012-07-16-eh_logo.jpg" width="150" height="45" style="float: right; margin:10px"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Erin Hicks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a new analysis of possible harmful effects of energy drinks on the heart, researchers have found that the drinks may increase blood pressure and disturb your heart’s natural rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientists at the University of the Pacific in Stockton, Calif., analyzed data from seven previously published studies looking at the effect of energy drinks on heart health. The pooled studies included healthy participants 18 to 45 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In their analysis, researchers looked at data on QT interval — the time it takes for the heart's electrical wave to reset before the next beat, as measured using EKG — in 93 people who had just consumed one to three cans of energy drinks. When it's prolonged, QT interval can cause seriously irregular heartbeats or even sudden cardiac death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;More from Everyday Health:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.everydayhealth.com/rheumatoid-arthritis/delayed-release-pills-ra-sleep-9113.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;Delayed-Release Pills Could Save Rheumatoid Arthritis Patients Some Shuteye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.everydayhealth.com/type-2-diabetes/as-diabetes-rates-soar-national-prevention-strategy-emerges.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;As Diabetes Rates Soar, a National Prevention Strategy Emerges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.everydayhealth.com/type-1-diabetes/0322/global-surge-in-type-1-diabetes-still-an-enigma.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;Global Surge in Type 1 Diabetes Still an Enigma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Researchers found the average QT interval was 10 milliseconds longer for those who had consumed energy drinks than for those who had not. Doctors are generally concerned if patients experience 30 added milliseconds in their QT interval from baseline, according to a press release on the study, but any time QT intervals are prolonged it could put you at heart risk, according to Stephen Green, MD, a cardiologist at North Shore University Hospital in Long Island, N.Y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers also found that systolic blood pressure, the top number in a blood pressure reading, increased an average of 3.5 points in a pool of 132 participants who had consumed energy drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Regulation for Energy Drinks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another recent study, published in the Journal of the American Medical Association, reviewed possible risks associated with the levels of caffeine in most energy drinks, and they also reviewed the practice of combining energy drinks with alcohol. Mixing alcohol with energy drinks, they concluded, can lead to risky sexual behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last October, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) received reports of five deaths linked to Monster Energy, a popular energy drink that contains 160 mg of caffeine per 16-ounce can. In November, FDA received reports of 13 deaths over the past four years possibly linked to 5-Hour Energy, an energy shot that contains caffeine and vitamin B12, among other energy boosters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One issue with energy drinks, said Green, is that they aren’t regulated, so there's not much data on their effects on people with certain medical problems or for those taking other drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, Dr. Green said, “We don’t know what’s causing the prolonged QT intervals."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you have something you consider a drug, it has to go through a trial and prove safety and efficacy, and then it has to go through the FDA" approval process,  said Green, who believes that if energy drinks were a prescription medicine, there would be a warning on the label.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Herbal foods, vitamins or supplements haven’t really been tested. Whether it’s an energy drink or a supplement or a weight-loss pill, none of these things have really been tested,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue with energy drinks is that, unlike a cup of coffee, they usually contain other active ingredients that the average user may not be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Some of these energy drinks have more than caffeine in them — they are full of other herbs or supplements," said Green. So it's hard for doctors to know when they see possible effects of an energy drink on a patient, which, if any, ingredient in the drink may be causing the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The problem here with energy drinks is there is no screening. It's just sitting there on the market, and if you’re predisposed to having a prolonged QT for whatever reason, whether you know it or not, it could put you at risk for a serious cardiac event,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Energy Drinks: Uncertain Risks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Green explained that some people may be at more risk than others when they have energy drinks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you’re young, say 22, and don’t have high blood pressure or other medical problems, you may have three double espressos or a Monster energy drink and nothing will probably happen to you,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"But if you have a history of heart palpitations and drink caffeine or an energy drink, you’ll probably have more heart palpitations because that’s what it does.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also warns that just because you've had energy drinks in the past without incident, that doesn't mean you won’t have a problem in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Say you’re taking cough medicine because you have a cold and then you drink an energy drink. That’s a combination you’ve never tried before with energy drinks, and we don’t know what could happen,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s like cocaine — you can take it for years and not have a problem, but then take it once and you could have a major problem,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottom line: "If you don’t have any health problems you know of and aren’t on any medication, an energy drink here and there probably won't hurt you. But if you’re on medication, have high blood pressure, or a history of heart palpitations, energy drinks might not be for you,” Green said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"&lt;a href="http://www.everydayhealth.com/heart-health/energy-drinks-riskier-for-some-hearts-more-than-others-1955.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;Energy Drinks: Riskier for Some Hearts More Than Others&lt;/a&gt;" originally appeared on Everyday Health.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055042/thumbs/s-ENERGY-DRINKS-HEART-mini.jpg?13" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Early Math Skills Add Up (And Hold Back Americans)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/math-skills-first-grade-number-sense_n_2950383.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2950383</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T18:47:01Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T08:39:10Z</updated>
    
    <summary>WASHINGTON &amp;mdash; We know a lot about how babies learn to talk, and youngsters learn to read. Now scientists are unraveling the earliest building blocks...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/william-mcguinness/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON &amp;mdash; We know a lot about how babies learn to talk, and youngsters learn to read. Now scientists are unraveling the earliest building blocks of math &amp;ndash; and what children know about numbers as they begin first grade seems to play a big role in how well they do everyday calculations later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The findings have specialists considering steps that parents might take to spur math abilities, just like they do to try to raise a good reader.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;This isn't only about trying to improve the nation's math scores and attract kids to become engineers. It's far more basic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider: How rapidly can you calculate a tip? Do the fractions to double a recipe? Know how many quarters and dimes the cashier should hand back as your change?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 1 in 5 adults in the U.S. lacks the math competence expected of a middle-schooler, meaning they have trouble with those ordinary tasks and aren't qualified for many of today's jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's not just, can you do well in school? It's how well can you do in your life," says Dr. Kathy Mann Koepke of the National Institutes of Health, which is funding much of this research into math cognition. "We are in the midst of math all the time."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new study shows trouble can start early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University of Missouri researchers tested 180 seventh-graders. Those who lagged behind their peers in a test of core math skills needed to function as adults were the same kids who'd had the least number sense or fluency way back when they started first grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The gap they started with, they don't close it," says Dr. David Geary, a cognitive psychologist who leads the study that is tracking children from kindergarten to high school in the Columbia, Mo., school system. "They're not catching up" to the kids who started ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If first grade sounds pretty young to be predicting math ability, well, no one expects tots to be scribbling sums. But this number sense, or what Geary more precisely terms "number system knowledge," turns out to be a fundamental skill that students continually build on, much more than the simple ability to count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What's involved? Understanding that numbers represent different quantities &amp;ndash; that three dots is the same as the numeral "3" or the word "three." Grasping magnitude &amp;ndash; that 23 is bigger than 17.  Getting the concept that numbers can be broken into parts &amp;ndash; that 5 is the same as 2 and 3, or 4 and 1. Showing on a number line that the difference between 10 and 12 is the same as the difference between 20 and 22.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Factors such as IQ and attention span didn't explain why some first-graders did better than others. Now Geary is studying if something that youngsters learn in preschool offers an advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's other evidence that math matters early in life. Numerous studies with young babies and a variety of animals show that a related ability &amp;ndash; to estimate numbers without counting &amp;ndash; is intuitive, sort of hard-wired in the brain, says Mann Koepke, of NIH's National Institute of Child Health and Human Development. That's the ability that lets you choose the shortest grocery check-out line at a glance, or that guides a bird to the bush with the most berries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number system knowledge is more sophisticated, and the Missouri study shows children who start elementary school without those concepts "seem to struggle enormously," says Mann Koepke, who wasn't part of that research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While schools tend to focus on math problems around third grade, and math learning disabilities often are diagnosed by fifth grade, the new findings suggest "the need to intervene is much earlier than we ever used to think," she adds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exactly how to intervene still is being studied, sure to be a topic when NIH brings experts together this spring to assess what's known about math cognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Geary sees a strong parallel with reading. Scientists have long known that preschoolers who know the names of letters and can better distinguish what sounds those letters make go on to read more easily. So parents today are advised to read to their children from birth, and many youngsters' books use rhyming to focus on sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise for math, "kids need to know number words" early on, he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NIH's Mann Koepke agrees, and offers some tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Don't teach your toddler to count solely by reciting numbers. Attach numbers to a noun &amp;ndash; "Here are five crayons: One crayon, two crayons..." or say "I need to buy two yogurts" as you pick them from the store shelf &amp;ndash; so they'll absorb the quantity concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Talk about distance: How many steps to your ball? The swing is farther away; it takes more steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Describe shapes: The ellipse is round like a circle but flatter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_As they grow, show children how math is part of daily life, as you make change, or measure ingredients, or decide how soon to leave for a destination 10 miles away,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We should be talking to our children about magnitude, numbers, distance, shapes as soon as they're born," she contends. "More than likely, this is a positive influence on their brain function."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;___&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDITOR'S NOTE &amp;ndash; Lauran Neergaard covers health and medical issues for The Associated Press in Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055040/thumbs/s-MATH-SKILLS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Much Screen Time Is Too Much?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/less-or-more-parents-grapple-with-kids-screen-time-limits_n_2950284.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2950284</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T18:30:28Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T18:46:26Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The American Academy of Pediatrics discourages use of electronic media by kids under age 2 and recommends older kids be limited to one to two...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Today Moms </name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nina-zipkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;The American Academy of Pediatrics &lt;a href="http://www.healthychildren.org/english/family-life/media/pages/Where-We-Stand-TV-Viewing-Time.aspx?nfstatus=401&amp;nftoken=00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000&amp;nfstatusdescription=ERROR%3a+No+local+token" target="_hplink"&gt;discourages&lt;/a&gt; use of electronic media by kids under age 2 and recommends older kids be limited to one to two hours of educational programming daily. That may make intuitive sense to any parent who has watched a kid grow slack-jawed in front of the tube or beg for just five more minutes on the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1054967/thumbs/s-LESS-OR-MORE-PARENTS-GRAPPLE-WITH-KIDS-SCREEN-TI-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Rabbi Danya Ruttenberg: The Four Children Of American Judaism</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rabbi-danya-ruttenberg/the-four-children-of-american-judaism_b_2925869.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2925869</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T18:24:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T18:24:49Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The four children of Passover -- the wise child, the wicked child, the simple child and the one who does not know how to ask -- get a lot of play this time of year. They're profound blueprints for the spiritual journey. In fact, they could be understood as stages in the religious growth of many American Jews.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Rabbi Danya Ruttenberg</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rabbi-danya-ruttenberg/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;The four children of Passover -- the wise child, the wicked child, the simple child and the one who does not know how to ask -- get a lot of play this time of year.  And for good reason: They're profound blueprints for the spiritual journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, they could be understood as stages in the religious growth of many American Jews.  That is, we move from silence to basic speech, then into seeking meaning and, eventually, into an integrated, engaged wisdom. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The child who does not know how to ask may reflect the ways in which we started our Jewish education. Most American Jews did not grow up in an observant home, did not even know that there were questions that could be asked of Jewish life and practice.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after getting through the process of Hebrew school, or through the bar mitzvah process, many Jews have glimpsed only the most fundamental basics.  And since, for most American Jews, that's where Jewish education stops, that's where too many adults wind up remaining in their Jewish thinking. Children are, perhaps appropriately, taught a childlike version of Judaism. But frankly, many corners of liberal Jewish education don't try to reach much further than that, or give 13-year-olds the tools to see that there's more depth to be had when they make it over the horizon. Many Jewish adults can, like the simple child, ask, at best, the most basic of questions: "What is this?"  The answer the simple child is given is correspondingly general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this model, the "wicked" child is not "bad"; rather, the wicked child is seeking understanding -- taking a step back, to be sure, but still engaged in the process, still asking questions.  The "wicked" child pushes beyond the Hebrew school level, asking, "What is this service to you?" The basics aren't enough anymore--now it's time to seek meaning.  It's the move from a kid's way of thinking about Judaism to an adult understanding, to something more sophisticated, something important and deep.  Since he doesn't doesn't have that sense of spiritual relevance for himself, he asks, "what is this to you?"  In the traditional text, he's excoriated for separating himself from the community, but this is actually a pretty common phenomenon, at least these days.  If you've never known your religious tradition to be personally meaningful, you might ask someone for whom it is what it is that they seem to see that you don't (yet).  What do you see?  For those who grew up in an observant home, this is the time that they start to ask what it means to be Jewish on their own terms, and may step back for a moment -- either intellectually or more formally -- to put some distance between themselves and their families' observance of the tradition in order to better understand it on their own terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's only then, once there's a sense of personal meaning, that a person might be willing to ask about the "testimonies, statues and laws," as the wise child does. That is, for Jews who haven't grown up with a ritually engaged relationship to the tradition, it's often only after there's an understanding that all of this stuff is much more meaningful and personally impactful than previously suspected (or learned) that the actual performance of Jewish ritual life becomes more interesting.  If I know that it's actually meaningful and not a bunch of empty gestures for no reason, I'm more likely to want to know how I can do it.  And for those who grew up ritually engaged, this often looks like a time of renewed excitement and commitment to Jewish religious practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the thing is, this isn't a one-time process.  In an engaged, fully awake Jewish life, we may find ourselves becoming silent, simple, searching and wise again and again and again, and our understandings of meaning and practice growing and changing all the time.  The most important thing is to be brave enough to start asking in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050200/thumbs/s-THE-FOUR-CHILDREN-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jon Summers: What SCOTUS Can Learn From Our Sleepless Nights</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jon-summers/what-scotus-can-learn-from-our-sleepless-nights_b_2935269.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2935269</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T18:16:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T18:21:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary>People didn't ask us if we, as two men, were prepared to raise a child, and they didn't warn us about the importance of making sure our son has female influences (he does). They simply congratulated us and warned us to "kiss sleep goodbye." It's time for our laws to catch up with our culture.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jon Summers</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jon-summers/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;"I can't believe I'm already doing this," I said to myself as I opened the top drawer of a dresser that we have only had for a month.  But it was time.  Alexander is 3 months old, and the "newborn" clothes are no longer a match for his rapidly growing, 13-pound body. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This rite of passage for new parents is as old as time, and every parent reacts to it differently.  Kyle, who was in the living room with the baby as I was doing this, seemed to take it in stride. For me it was a slightly more emotional journey as I separated the clothes into two piles: the "definitely keep" pile and the "probably-should-get-rid-of-this-but-probably-won't" heap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The "definitely keep" pile is priceless. It's the monkey sleeper and bear hat that Alexander was wearing the day we walked into the hospital room and met him for the first time. The striped onesie that he wore the day we took him home. The frog sleeper that his birth mom gave him as a gift so that she could share with him her love of frogs, the same outfit that he wore on her first visit on the day after Christmas, which was also the day after she signed the adoption papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took in every element of each item: how it looked, felt and smelled.  Memories flooded my brain. The raw excitement in Kyle's eyes as we walked into the hospital room. The immeasurable combination of love and fear that we felt the day we drove him home.  The beauty that is the love that has surrounded this child from the 40 weeks leading up to his birth that has only continued to grow ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and memories of a few sleepless nights.  Fortunately we knew those were coming. In fact, it seemed that the favorite bit of "advice" that people gave us as we prepared to become parents was "say goodbye to sleep" and "sleep in now."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a couple who did an extensive amount of paperwork, met multiple times with social workers, took a class and waited for a year, Kyle and I repeatedly joked to each other, "Do people really think we haven't thought of that?"  But as we took more time to think about it, we realized that what people were doing was trying to connect in the best way they knew how, by talking about a common experience that all parents endure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What our ad hoc advisors didn't know, however, was that for Kyle and me, the sleepless nights had already begun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I described in &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jon-summers/how-this-sonogram-changed-our-life_b_2681478.html" target="_hplink"&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt;, our son's birth mother chose Kyle and me two months before she was expected to give birth.  It was a blessing, but it also added stress.  While we had two months to celebrate and prepare, we also had two months to worry, something that turned out to be a particularly strong talent of mine.  Having met our birth mom, we were genuinely (and still are) concerned for her and her family; we love her and wanted her to be well. We worried about the baby: Will he be healthy? And we worried about what it would be like if our birth mother changed her mind. She never indicated that she would, but it was still a possibility, and we were already in love with the baby growing inside her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That anxiety produced more sleepless nights than anything since Alexander was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, our baby is actually a great sleeper. Our 15-year-old dog wakes us up more than he does. But even on those nights when he wakes us up, we feel blessed, because it's another opportunity to look into the eyes of this little boy whom we love so, so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm sure most parents feel the same, because whether you're gay or straight, and whether your child is adopted or biologically yours, there are certain things that our families all have in common.  And on a human level, all we want to do is connect -- even if it means offering up the most basic advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I've learned something else as I reflect on these warnings: Our country's culture is ahead of our laws.  People didn't ask us if we, as two men, were prepared to raise a child, and they didn't warn us about the importance of making sure our son has female influences (he does). Those seemed to be non-issues to even our most conservative acquaintances, friends and family members, who simply congratulated us and warned us to "kiss sleep goodbye." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's time for our laws to catch up with our culture, and the Supreme Court has an opportunity to make this happen as it prepares to hear oral arguments in two marriage-equality cases. The justices should not ignore the &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/21/health/american-academy-of-pediatrics-backs-gay-marriage.html?_r=1&amp;" target="_hplink"&gt;input of the American Academy of Pediatrics&lt;/a&gt;, which says that marriage equality helps kids. And they should support families like ours, because we love our kids and are just as sleep-deprived as they are.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1013321/thumbs/s-SUPREME-COURT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
