<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Alyson Schafer: What to Tell Your Kids About the Boston Marathon Bombing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/alyson-schafer/talking-to-kids-boston-marathon_b_3090945.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3090945</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T12:45:54Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T12:06:23Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The bombings at the finish line of the Boston Marathon has rocked the nation. Many children overheard their parents talking about it, or caught a glance of the news coverage. How does a parent effectively discuss the event of today? I have a few suggestions, based on some psychological tenants to help guide you.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Alyson Schafer</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/alyson-schafer/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;The bombings at the finish line of the Boston Marathon has rocked the nation. Many children overheard their parents talking about it, or caught a glance of the news coverage. If the car radio was on during the drive home from school you may not have even considered the little ears in the back seat were tuning in too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does a parent effectively discuss the event of today? I have a few suggestions, based on some psychological tenants to help guide you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Young Children Don't Need to Know World News&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Young children don't need to know world news. Their world is their home life and that's big enough! Parents need to create barriers to media and filter information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may think that your nine-month-old is too young to understand what you are watching on the news, but research shows youngsters are impacted by upset facial expressions and other stressful visual images that accompany the news. Best practices: turn off the tube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of TV and radio, read the media coverage giving updates on the progress of the investigation via feeds and online updates. That protects your child vicarious trauma from accidental news consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Clarify Misunderstandings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your child likely heard something about the events of today, ask them what they understood happened. Be sure they explain using their own words. You may be surprised to hear what they put together in their own minds. It gives you an opportunity to correct their misunderstandings. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Mommy, I don't want you running in your race next weekend in case you get hit by a bomb too." Expect questions of this type. Your job will be to explain that this explosion was a freak incident and that we are all safe. This event was upsetting because it was so rare and random. Explain that while we are sad it happened, it's not worth spending one ounce of energy worrying about its ever happening again. The police are looking for who ever did this and they will be found and put in jail where they can't do this again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your Emotions Are Educational Too&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your child looks to you to see how you are reacting in order to make their own assessment of how frightening the day's events where. If you are very upset and anxious, you are broadcasting that the situation is severe and scary. If you have an empathetic disposition, your children will likely adopt that emotional stance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Re-Instill a Sense of Safety&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your child's world view that life is safe and predictable may have been shattered today. We must re-assure our children that the world is still a safe place. To do that, discuss the positives; such as how responsive the police and president where. How the people in the crowd pitched in to help one another. Maintain your own family routines, and be additionally calm, caring and warm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. No Lies -- But Be Selective in The Amount of Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because children need to feel safe, they need to believe their parents wouldn't deceive them. It's important to always model being truthful in our interactions with others. In fact, being truthful sends a message of confidence in their ability to handle life. When we lie, we are basically giving the child a vote of non-confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Decide How Much To Pass Along&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adapt the amount of information you are sharing by age appropriateness and your child's needs by moving from the broadest of brushstrokes to the finest of details. Here are three such examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We are all very upset because today there was a big explosion that hurt a lot of people" might be enough for a preschooler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Today a bomb went off near the finish line of a big running race and lots of people had to be taken to the hospital and three even died."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Today at the Boston Marathon there were two simultaneous bomb explosions along the route towards the finish line. Lots of people were hurt, and three have died (including an eight-year-old). The police are investigating who perpetrated this crime. It's a terrible tragedy since it was innocent civilians who were targeted."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Help Children Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your child is upset or moved by the events of today, invite them to channel their emotions into thinking of constructive ways to be helpful. Perhaps they want to write a card, send a letter, hold a vigil, say a few words, or a prayer, light a candle, place flowers somewhere symbolic, donate money from their piggy bank, or anything else that moves the child to make meaning and to regain a sense of control of their own life and emotions through actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be days of news still ahead. I hope you feel more confident in how you'll&lt;br /&gt;
broach this subject with your children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--292040--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--LIVEBLOG--1685--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1088561/thumbs/s-BOSTON-MARATHON-BOMBS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jayson Lusk: 8 Reasons You SHOULDN'T Buy Organic</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jayson-lusk/post_4620_b_3046545.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3046545</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T12:10:49Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T12:11:04Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Everywhere you turn, you hear "organic is healthier", "organic is greener", or "you absolutely MUST buy organic." It's not a question of whether we want to eat healthy, environmentally friendly food - who doesn't want that?</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jayson Lusk</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jayson-lusk/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Everywhere you turn, you hear "organic is healthier", "organic is greener", or "you absolutely MUST buy organic." It's not a question of whether we want to eat healthy, environmentally friendly food -- who doesn't want that? The question is whether organic lives up to the hype and whether it's worth it to pay a hefty premium. One of the problems with organic is that few shoppers know what the term really means, and they project onto the nebulous word all their hopes and dreams of good eating. Despite what many believe, organic doesn't mean food from small farms, produced without pesticides, or grown in the USA. There are a few advantages to eating organic but there are some drawbacks too. If you're rich enough and well-informed on the issues, then I say go for it. But, if you're not so sure whether organic lives up to all it is promised to be, here are a few reasons to re-think doubling your grocery bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jayson Lusk is the author of the new book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Food-Police-Well-Fed-Manifesto/dp/0307987035" target="_hplink"&gt;The Food Police: A Well-Fed Manifesto About the Politics of Your Plate. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--291001--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1078398/thumbs/s-BUYING-ORGANIC-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Brad Harrington: The Boston Marathon: Clinging to a Lifelong Love</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brad-harrington/the-boston-marathon-cling_b_3090721.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3090721</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T10:57:22Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T12:11:12Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I remember my father lifting me up so I could look straight down as the elite runners finished. That April day in the 1960's, my love affair with the Boston Marathon began.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brad Harrington</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brad-harrington/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I spent much of yesterday in shock and disbelief. As the story and images of the tragedy of the Boston Marathon unfolded, I found myself clinging to a lifelong love, and to an eight-year-old victim who lost his life because he was taken to see that event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was on a beautiful spring day nearly a half-century ago that my father decided to take our family to see two of Boston's great hallmarks. I was not yet ten. The Prudential Tower had recently been completed and was the tallest building in the world outside of New York at that time. On its 50th floor was the &lt;a href="http://www.prudentialcenter.com/tourism_local/shop_detail.php?id=64" target="_hplink"&gt;Prudential Skywalk&lt;/a&gt;, which offered breathtaking views of the Hub. From one side, you could literally look into Fenway Park and see the Red Sox in action, from another, view Boston's historic Beacon Hill area and Boston Harbor beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that day, my late father wanted us to see more than the views of our beautiful capitol city. He wanted us to have a bird's eye view of its most iconic athletic event, &lt;a href="http://www.baa.org" target="_hplink"&gt;the Boston Marathon&lt;/a&gt;. Back then the finish line was a few hundred yards from its present location and directly in front of "the Pru." My father knew that from the Skywalk you would truly have a bird's eye view of the finish of the great race 500 feet below. I remember him lifting me up so I could look straight down as the elite runners finished. That April day in the 1960's, my love affair with the Boston Marathon began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout college and graduate school, to my days living in Brookline and now my time at Boston College, I have gone to many marathons. For a number of years, I lived just one block from the race's route. My roommate and I would host a party after spending hours at the Marathon shouting almost non-stop encouragement to the runners. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember the days when hometown hero Bill Rodgers dominated the race and helped raise the popularity of running to an unprecedented level. I remember many occasions when the roar of the crowd signaled the approach of the legendary Johnny Kelley as he continued on his miraculous record-breaking streak completing more than 60 Boston Marathons. In the '70's and early '80's, sightings of the first woman runner were always moments of particular excitement. I even clearly remember being at the marathon in 1980 when "she who shall not be named" jumped into the race near its end to steal the winner's wreath from the true victor, the one who should have been remembered, Canadian runner Jacqueline Gareau. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of us who love the Marathon remember the heroic efforts of so many early wheelchair participants, who struggled through 26.2 miles using standard wheelchairs, not the aerodynamic ones we see today.  And of course we remember &lt;a href="http://www.teamhoyt.com" target="_hplink"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Hoyt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, as father Dick pushed son Rick in a wheelchair to &lt;u&gt;30&lt;/u&gt; Boston finishes, always in extraordinary completion times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was one of many who most enjoyed cheering for the also-rans. The ones whose times were slow, whose outfits were unique, who didn't possess a runner's physique. They were the ones who ran more on guts than on athletic ability. They were us. They were fulfilling a dream I held for many years to run Boston. If I never competed, I could at least offer my unbridled enthusiasm to those who ran for charity, or for fun, or for the opportunity to participate in one of the only great sporting events on earth that allows less than super athletes the chance to compete with the world's best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patriots%27_Day" target="_hplink"&gt;Patriots' Day&lt;/a&gt;, that uniquely Massachusetts holiday, is more than just the race. There's the re-enactment of the first battle of the Revolutionary War that was originally fought on April 19, 1775. Thousands awake in the middle of the night and stand for hours in the dark to see this historic re-enactment on Lexington Green that begins at dawn and is over in a matter of minutes. Our beloved Red Sox play a morning game allowing members of &lt;em&gt;Red Sox Nation &lt;/em&gt;to exit Fenway in time to engage in the day's festivities. After the elite runners pass, fans, volunteers, and family members stay on to offer encouragement to those less elite runners who need it most. It is the women of Wellesley College cheering en masse, the crowds that line Heartbreak Hill on the slow, difficult rise to Boston College, and the thousands of gatherings and cookouts, large and small, that celebrate our beginning of spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At every Marathon I have attended I have felt blessed to be a Bostonian. In spite of the many difficulties that any major city faces, there was one day every year when Beantown and its surrounding neighbors came together to celebrate our history, our city, our day, our race and, above all, the triumph of the human spirit. I pray that spirit will help us transcend this terrible moment. It's hard to lose the innocence of a lifelong love and harder still to grasp the magnitude of all that's been lost because of this unforgiveable act. And hardest of all to think about an eight-year-old boy, on the first day of a lifelong love affair that would end before it was realized.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1088316/thumbs/s-ELITE-WOMEN-START-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Advice From Mr. Rogers We Really Need Right Now</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/mr-rogers-look-for-the-helpers_n_3088716.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3088716</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T02:00:16Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T04:20:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>In the wake of today's explosions at the Boston marathon, many parents are again struggling with how to explain tragic events to children. Sadly, we've...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Farah L. Miller</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/farah-l-miller/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;In the wake of today's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/boston-explosion-news_n_3088615.html" target="_hplink"&gt;explosions at the Boston marathon&lt;/a&gt;, many parents are again struggling with &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/2012/12/16/167399094/tragedy-and-children-what-to-discuss" target="_hplink"&gt;how to explain tragic events to children&lt;/a&gt;. Sadly, we've grappled with this same question all too recently. After &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/parents-sandy-hook" target="_hplink"&gt;December's shooting at Sandy Hook Elementary School,&lt;/a&gt; we &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/17/mister-rogers-helpers-quote_n_2318793.html" target="_hplink"&gt;shared the following&lt;/a&gt; quote from &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mister-Rogers-Parenting-Book-Understand/dp/076241345X" target="_hplink"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mister Rogers Parenting Book&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which had &lt;a href="http://www.pbs.org/newshour/rundown/2012/12/fred-rogers-post-goes-viral.html" target="_hplink"&gt;gone viral&lt;/a&gt; and was particularly comforting.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When I was a boy and I would see scary things in the news, my mother would say to me, '&lt;a href="http://www.fredrogers.org/FRC/par-tragic-events.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Look for the helpers. You will always find people who are helping&lt;/a&gt;." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given Monday's events in Boston, we wanted to highlight his words as well as the below video --  which includes Mister Rogers's practical advice for parents dealing scary events in the news -- again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/17/mister-rogers-helpers-quote_n_2318793.html" target="_hplink"&gt;&lt;img alt="mister rogers helpers quote" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/908244/thumbs/o-MISTER-ROGERS-HELPERS-QUOTE-570.jpg?6" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For moms and dads looking for more guidance from experts, the Fred Rogers Company website includes a &lt;a href="http://www.fci.org/new-site/par-tragic-events.html" target="_hplink"&gt;list of useful tips&lt;/a&gt;, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do your best to keep the television off, or at least limit how much your child sees of any news event.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Try to keep yourself calm. Your presence can help your child feel more secure.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Give your child extra comfort and physical affection, like hugs or snuggling up together with a favorite book. Physical comfort goes a long way towards providing inner security. That closeness can nourish you, too.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fredrogers.org/FRC/par-tragic-events.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Click over to The Fred Rogers Company site to read more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WATCH:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="570" height="428" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/LZbXM3Kzd7o?wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOW YOU CAN BE A HELPER&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/help-boston-marathon-victims_n_3087183.html" target="_hplink"&gt;HuffPost Impact has a list of where to donate or help the victims in Boston here &lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1088457/thumbs/s-MR-ROGERS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Bettina Elias Siegel: An Interview with Melanie Warner of Pandora's Lunchbox</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/bettina-elias-siegel/pandoras-lunchbox_b_3085974.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3085974</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T22:12:42Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T22:12:53Z</updated>
    
    <summary>"On occasions when they ask why they can't have Cheetos, Froot Loops or yogurt in a tube I tell them it's because these things aren't real food. They taste good, but they don't help their bodies grow strong or give them big muscles."</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Bettina Elias Siegel</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/bettina-elias-siegel/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;As someone who &lt;a href="http://thelunchtray.com" target="_hplink"&gt;writes regularly about food&lt;/a&gt; and who worked as an advertising/regulatory lawyer for one of the world's largest food conglomerates, I didn't think there was a lot that could surprise me about the processed food industry. Then I picked up Melanie Warner's new book, &lt;em&gt;Pandora's Lunchbox&lt;/em&gt;, and was agog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the Vitamin D in your milk -- even your organic milk -- likely comes from Australian sheep wool that's been heavily processed in China?  Or that, of the 5,000 additives in our food supply today, and of the additional 3,750 "food contact substances" that might also migrate into our food during processing, only half have been subject to any kind of published toxicology studies?  Or that an early crusader for food safety, Harvey Wiley, had a cadre of volunteers called the "Poison Squad" who would ingest questionable ingredients like borax and sulfuric acid to determine their potential for harm?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melanie Warner is a freelance writer whose work has appeared in numerous publications, including &lt;em&gt;Fortune&lt;/em&gt;, CBSnews.com and the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;.  I used to follow her CBS blog regularly and have long admired her incisive coverage of the food industry. Melanie was kind enough to let me interview her about &lt;em&gt;Pandora's Lunchbox&lt;/em&gt; and, given &lt;a href="http://thelunchtray.com" target="_hplink"&gt;my interest in kids and food&lt;/a&gt;, I was particularly interested in how her findings have affected her as a parent of two boys:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You obviously were well-informed about the processed food industry before researching &lt;em&gt;Pandora's Lunchbox&lt;/em&gt;, so I'm wondering: Was there anything you learned about food processing or additives that still totally shocked you?  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was surprised to encounter so many people within the industry who don't eat the products they help produce. They are cooking much of their own food -- many of them say they love to cook - and shopping at farmer's markets and Whole Foods. They don't buy soda or Gatorade for their kids, and they eat fast food only when they have to, such as when traveling. One food scientist excitedly told me about the huge garden she plants every year; another explained that he makes his own yogurt. It's a strange dichotomy and many of these industry veterans acknowledge the existence of two food systems operating in America -- one where educated people in the upper incomes eat wholesome, fresh food and the one where everyone else consumes a steady stream of unhealthy, highly processed fare. The problem is that, on a collective level, all of these food scientists and company executives are helping to perpetuate this inequality, instead of working to expand access to fresh, real food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another surprising finding was just how porous our system of food additive regulation is. It's amazing to realize that, for most new food ingredients, there are no actual FDA requirements for safety testing. And what's worse, there are an estimated 1,000 additives the agency doesn't even know about -- substances that ingredient companies have just started selling. This lack of oversight also leads to a situation where you have a substance like BHA, which is a probable carcinogen according to the Health and Human Services Department, being added to commonly-consumed products like Tang, McDonald's sausages and breakfast steak sandwiches and DiGiorno pepperoni pizza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You write about your philosophy with respect to processed foods and your own children, concluding that "I'd rather not take the chance -- especially when there are so many alternatives. I'd rather feed them processed foods without chemical preservatives and ingredients that leave tongues Smurf-blue..."  Many parents feel the same way, but are challenged by the opportunities in our kids' day to eat chemical-filled junk food outside the home, like the bright blue sports drink and processed chips handed out at the soccer game. How do you handle these instances with your own kids? Do you urge them not to partake?  Or do you just roll with it, on the theory that their overall diet is not highly processed?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am fortunate to live in the abnormally healthy enclave of Boulder, Colorado, where blue drinks and cupcakes with industrial chemicals are not the norm. When my kids do encounter Flamin' Hot Doritos, soda, fast food and candy, I often just roll with it and let them have fun. But if junk food were to be the norm, greeting us at every soccer game and social occasion as I know is the case for so many parents, I would be figuring out ways to make sure our kids don't overconsume it, teaching them that it's an occasional indulgence, not a normal, acceptable way of eating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don't know how old your sons are, but are you planning to talk (or have you talked) to them about some of your findings in the book?  What's the message you want to impart to your kids about processed food and food additives?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our sons are six and four, and so to them mommy's new book is very boring. It's just a dense jumble of words, no fun pictures. When I speak to them generally about food, I try to point out foods that are healthy and have some fun with asking them questions about where food comes from and how it's grown. On occasions when they ask why they can't have Cheetos, Froot Loops or yogurt in a tube I tell them it's because these things aren't real food. They taste good, but they don't help their bodies grow strong or give them big muscles (that seems to work with little boys). I suspect at some point down the road I'll get a lot more pushback on this and more questions. Maybe then I'll give them the gory details about how some of their favorite processed foods are made and what all the various ingredients are, and then see if they still have an appetite for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As you probably know, two food bloggers are asking Kraft to drop two petroleum-based yellow food dyes from its mac-n-cheese product and they've garnered &lt;a href="https://www.change.org/kraftyellow"&gt;280,000 petition signatures&lt;/a&gt; in support of their effort. So far, however, Kraft seems to be holding firm. So what do you think about this episode? Given the lax oversight at FDA with respect to food additives, what's the best way to bring about change? If this petition effort ultimately fails, do you think there's anything an individual can do besides just choosing natural products?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is a mistake on Kraft's part. The company is probably digging in its heels due to some combination of cost concerns and a fear that they will lose customers were the signature bright orange appearance of their mac &amp;amp; cheese to change even a little. I think Kraft is missing an opportunity to stand out from the crowd and respond to what is clearly a shifting tide in consumer sentiment. These types of concerns are not going away. So far, the company has responded to the petition by saying that they already offer mac &amp;amp; cheese varieties without artificial food colorings. But the other day when I went to my local King Soopers (owned by the Kroger chain), six of eight Kraft varieties contained food dyes -- and this in Boulder where you might think people would appreciate the more natural offerings. Also, the prefabbed mac &amp;amp; cheese so many restaurants serve (Applebee's, IHOP, Bob Evans, etc.) happens to be the original Kraft variety with food dyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for ways to bring about change, we shouldn't underestimate the power we have as customers to force the food companies, and indeed our entire food system, to change through what we choose to buy. Kids should be another big area of focus. Getting elementary and middle school aged kids to understand the concept of healthy food represents one of our best chances for changing our toxic food environment. Kids are naturally curious about nearly everything and food is no exception. Encourage schools to plant a garden so that kids learn all foods originate in the soil, not the shelves at the supermarket. We also need to find ways to teach kids basic cooking skills since many of them are not learning this at home. There quite a lot of tools out there for education, such as &lt;a href="http://www.turnthetidefoundation.org/unjunkyourself.htm"&gt;these extremely watchable videos&lt;/a&gt; encouraging kids to "un-junk" themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One thing about your book that struck me (and with which I wholeheartedly agree) is that you don't expect profit-driven food giants like PepsiCo, Kraft and ConAgra to change their ways. You recognize that they're for-profit companies and are unlikely to be the agents of change some food reformers hope them to be. That said, do you support any kind of legislative curbs on their activities? For example, do you think they should be barred from directly advertising unhealthy foods to children?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do.This would offer a tremendous leg up for parents, many of whom really can't get through the supermarket or drive by McDonald's without their kids nagging at them. I've seen my kids gravitate toward a bag or box with Sponge Bob or a colorful animal on it, even though they have no idea what's even in it. They don't care; they just want it. There was &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-505123_162-44041154/junk-food-armageddon-feds-may-impose-strict-nutrition-standards-on-items-marketed-to-kids/"&gt;an amazing document&lt;/a&gt; written in 2010 by a joint committee of officials and scientists from the FTC, FDA, USDA and CDC. It set strict nutrition guidelines for what could be marketed to kids. The rules were so well written that they would have eliminated most of what's geared towards kids today, which is, by and large, sugary, nutritionally devoid junk. Naturally, the food industry howled in protest and the guidelines, which were voluntary by the way, quietly disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your book ends on a hopeful note, advocating a return to simple home cooking, but you also recognize that many Americans lack even basic cooking skills. It seems unlikely that our cash-strapped, standardized-testing-focused public schools can assume this role, and there aren't nearly enough non-profits like &lt;a href="http://cookingmatters.org/"&gt;Cooking Matters&lt;/a&gt; to reach the people who need them. So how do we bring Americans back into the kitchen?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to start thinking about how to allocate resources to the important job of changing the way America eats, especially our kids. Perhaps food and cooking education are something a soda tax could fund, much in the way tobacco taxes have financed effective anti-smoking ad campaigns. Soda taxes are inevitable; it's just a question of when. They make sense because they would discourage consumption of what is arguably the worst item in our diets, something linked to obesity and diabetes. Moreover, they send a cultural message about things that should be consumed carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not a gourmet cook, nor am I even a foodie. But I find the act of preparing my own food -- even if it's just simple meals like a grilled chicken salad or spaghetti and meatballs -- to be enormously rewarding, both in terms of our family's physical and emotional well-being. So many subtle yet deep family bonds are forged around the dinner table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything else you'd like to share with readers about processed food?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's important not to get too strident about all this. Processed food can have its role in our lives and there's nothing wrong with some junk food indulgences. Food is meant to be enjoyed. My hope is that we move toward a place where more and more Americans start to grasp the profound pleasures of eating fresh, healthy food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more by Bettina Elias Siegel, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/bettina-elias-siegel/" target="_hplink"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more on personal health, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/personal-health/" target="_hplink"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1088234/thumbs/s-PANDORAS-LUNCHBOOK-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>NBC Sets Summer Schedule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/nbc-summer-shows-premiere-dates_n_3087651.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3087651</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T22:08:31Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T22:08:35Z</updated>
    
    <summary>NBC has announced its new summer 2013 schedule. "Save Me," which was ordered to series in May 2012, will debut on Thursday, May 23 with...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Chris Harnick</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/chris-harnick/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;NBC has announced its new summer 2013 schedule. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Save Me," which was ordered to series in May 2012, will debut on Thursday, May 23 with two episodes, beginning at 8 p.m. ET. The series stars Heche as a woman who suffers a near-death experience and undergoes a spiritual awakening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Camp," which comes from from Liz Heldens ("Friday Night Lights") and Peter Elkoff ("Gossip Girl"), will premiere on Wednesday, July 10 at 10 p.m. ET. The series is set at Little Otter Family Camp and follows Rachel Griffiths as a divorced camp director who is in search of a fresh start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the reality category, "Get Out Alive With Bear Grylls" premieres on Monday, July 8 at 9 p.m. ET. The show features 10 teams of two surviving on New Zealand's South Island. Also, "American Ninja Warrior" returns with a two-hour special on Monday, July 1 at 8 p.m. ET. The show, which features contestants competing in obstacle courses, moves to Mondays at 8 p.m. ET on July 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"America's Got Talent" returns for Season 8 on Tuesday, June 4 at 9 p.m. ET and begins its two-night a week run on Wednesday, July 10 at 9 p.m. ET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--280226--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1088205/thumbs/s-NBC-SUMMER-PREMIERE-DATES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Twesigye Jackson Kaguri: Fathers Need To Step Up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/twesigye-jackson-kaguri/fathers-need-to-step-up_b_3081732.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3081732</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T21:46:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T21:47:10Z</updated>
    
    <summary>As I watched my sons being born, I knew our generation must be a generation to take on the responsibility of fatherhood. We need to care about women giving birth to the next generation. We need to be involved with our children from the moment they take their first breath.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Twesigye Jackson Kaguri</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/twesigye-jackson-kaguri/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;As Mother's Day approaches, I hope we go beyond showering our mothers with gifts. I hope we realize that every child needs two parents, bonded strongly with the child, showing him/her as much love and affection as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I are expecting twins any time now. We also have two sons; one is 10 years old and the other is 15 months. I was honored to be present when my sons were born, to cut their umbilical cords and look them in the eyes after birth. I still remember waking up that first day and finding my wife holding our newborn baby. What a great feeling and an exciting time it was for mom, child and dad. And shouldn't it be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American men love to see their newborn babies and hold them, but parenthood is often relegated to women in many parts of the world. I was born in Nyakagyezi, Uganda, a village where men do not see their wives give birth. My father left the village as soon as my mother said she was feeling labor pains. She birthed all five of her children in a mud daub house with dirt floors. There was no doctor or even a nurse to help her, only a local woman who acted as midwife. I grew up knowing many of women who delivered babies, and even knew the one who cut my cord. To this day, she still happily reminds me and all my friends of our births. What a great memory to share. But it is a memory many men do not experience. It was a memory my father never shared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my wife and I ready for the C-section she will have in one day, I think about other women who have no husband to support them when they give birth. I think of the story a woman named Rosemary in Nyakagyezi. Rosemary was born and raised in the same village as me. She never went to school, and was expected to work hard for her parents.  Like other women in her village, she married at a young age to a local man and got pregnant right away. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As her pregnancy progressed, Rosemary discovered that her husband had no interest in her pregnancy or the coming child. She was ashamed to tell anyone she was expecting a baby, but as she neared nine months, she confided in her mother. When the time to give birth came, she did not tell anyone. She birthed her own baby, cut the cord, wrapped her daughter in a dirty cloth and went back to sleep. In the morning, her husband woke up and left the house without noticing Rosemary had had a baby. She repeated this same exercise six times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another Mexican woman left alone in her home, &lt;a href="http://usatoday30.usatoday.com/news/health/2004-04-07-self-caesarean_x.htm" target="_hplink"&gt;gave herself a C-section&lt;/a&gt; to save her baby when her labor stopped progressing. Can you imagine? No help, no friends, no nothing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my mother confided in me how she had delivered all five children, I couldn't help but wonder why men are not at their wives' side during this time? What is wrong with them that they neglect their wives in their time of need, and their children at the time of birth? Could this be a reason why many of us have no close relationships with our fathers? We are rejected as soon as we are conceived, abandoned at birth and live life loving our mothers and caring for them beyond expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I watched my sons being born, I knew our generation must be a generation to take on the responsibility of fatherhood. We need to care about women giving birth to the next generation. We need to be involved with our children from the moment they take their first breath. We need to step up and be the fathers we should be.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1088193/thumbs/s-FATHERHOOD-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Daniel Vahab: Online Petition Against Disney's Sexist Avengers T-Shirts Gets Nearly 6,000 Signatures</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/daniel-vahab/online-petition-against-disneys-sexist-avenegers-t-shirt_b_3081976.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3081976</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T21:29:10Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T21:29:15Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A recent Change.org online petition to get the Disney Store to "stop selling sexist Avengers T-shirts" has received nearly 6,000 signatures. The shirts in question include one for boys that reads, "Be a Hero," and one for girls that reads, "I Need a Hero."</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Daniel Vahab</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/daniel-vahab/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;A recent Change.org &lt;a href="https://www.change.org/petitions/stop-selling-sexist-avengers-t-shirts-disneystore-women-can-be-heroes-too-notbuyingit" target="_hplink"&gt;online petition&lt;/a&gt; to get the Disney Store to "stop selling sexist Avengers T-shirts" has received nearly 6,000 signatures. The goal, as of this writing, is to receive an additional 1,617 signatures. The petition will send a letter signed by its many signatures to the Disney Store executives. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
The superhero t-shirts in question include one for boys that reads, "Be a Hero," and one for girls that reads, "I Need a Hero," the juxtaposition of which has recently led many to criticize them as spreading a message that girls can't be heroes themselves; that hero roles are for men only and girls need to be saved by male heroes. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
As the petition states, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;We believe that women can be heroes too, and as one of the most recognizable children's brands in the world, it's especially important that Disney takes responsibility for the messages they deliver to our youngest and most vulnerable.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Said one signer of the petition: 
 
&lt;blockquote&gt;My daughter LOVES superheroes, in particular she loves the Avengers. She doesn't need a superhero... What she needs is for corporations to stop telling her that because of her gender she couldn't possibly BE the superhero herself. Please think through the messages you send to our daughters.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 
Much to the maker of the shirts surprise, women are heroes just as much as men. Consider just a few prominent examples in U.S. history: civil rights activist Rosa Parks, whose act of refusing to give up her seat to a white person sparked the Montgomery Bus Boycott; Harriet Tubman, whose Underground Railroad operation helped countless slaves escape to freedom; Susan B. Anthony, whose efforts helped secure women's right to vote; Molly Pitcher, who risked her life to bring water to soldiers in the Revolutionary War; and the unnamed and named women soldiers who pretended to be men so that they, too, could fight in battle for their country; and so many others.

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And the irony here as &lt;a href="http://badassdigest.com/2013/04/12/hey-marvel-these-avengers-shirts-suck/" target="_hplink"&gt;one blogger pointed out,&lt;/a&gt; is that the Avengers are coed heroes. According to &lt;a href="http://marvel.com/universe/Wasp" target="_hplink"&gt;Marvel's website,&lt;/a&gt; the Wasp female, yes female, superhero character's powers include expanding or shrinking in size exponentially, as well as flying with wings and the ability to "fire blasts of energy."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not needing a hero herself, Marvel's website notes a heroic defeat in which Wasp alone defeats the Magician character. The Magician character, by the way, was male.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And disregarding the discriminatory factor of it, one wonders whether it is even age-appropriate to have a shirt that reads, "I Need a Hero," catered toward little girls. Because the implication could also relate to a higher maturity level as many hero fairy tales relate to the girl finding her prince, her lover-savior. Does a young girl really comprehend that or should she have to comprehend that? &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Were all those involved in the making and promotion of the t-shirts just that ignorant to have missed the sexist implications? Did they think there wouldn't be backlash? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine this: Do you think the CEO of Disney, who walked into a Disney Store with his daughter, would buy a shirt for her that reads "Be a Hero" or "I Need a Hero" if he wanted her to be a future leader? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say money talks. But, so does bad press and enough ticked-off customers. So, by refusing to purchase said t-shirts and getting the word out, Disney, you better recognize -- we will not tolerate sexist t-shirts.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Indeed, perhaps Disney should make a series of t-shirts on famous women heroes in history, like those mentioned above. Or, better yet, develop a whole set of new women superheroes from them. Certainly they deserve that status.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1082736/thumbs/s-AVENGERS-BOY-SHIRT-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Grieving Mom Makes Beautiful Request In Son's Honor</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/chasing-rainbows-gavin-leong_n_3085603.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3085603</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T21:18:30Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T03:18:37Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Kate Leong’s virtual circle is mourning with her today, as she prepares to bury her 5-year-old son. Leong has documented Gavin's life and battle with...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Lisa Belkin</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-belkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Kate Leong’s virtual circle is mourning with her today, as she prepares to bury her 5-year-old son. Leong has documented Gavin's life and battle with cerebral palsy on her blog &lt;a href="http://www.kateleong.com" target="_hplink"&gt;Chasing Rainbows&lt;/a&gt; since his birth, making strangers feel like family as they’ve followed along online. So when she shared the news of his death on Facebook Sunday night, her &lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/babble-voices/ellen-seidman-1000-perplexing-things-about-parenthood/2013/04/15/when-a-child-dies-facebook-becomes-faithbook/" target="_hplink"&gt;heartbreak  became theirs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate and her husband Ed fought hard to become parents -- Kate suffered through 13 miscarriages and one stillbirth over the years. Gavin was the older of their two sons. Although he was always medically fragile, the crisis that would kill him came out of the blue: Gavin woke up one morning with a stuffed nose and by nightfall was hospitalized with a raging fever, suffering seizures and heart attacks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it became clear that the situation was dire, Kate put&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/chasingrainbowsblog" target="_hplink"&gt; a request on her Facebook page yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, an answer to the flood of readers who’d been reaching out to say “what can we do.” It was her birthday, she wrote, and this was her wish: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I'm asking you to help someone... document it with words and or a photo... and place it on the &lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/chasingrainbowsblog " target="_hplink"&gt;Chasing Rainbows Facebook Page&lt;/a&gt;. Then be sure to check the page often to get inspired by the outpouring of love. Here are some great ideas for you... Find a special needs classroom in your community. These are usually low funded and always looking for donations. Perhaps you have toys your kids don't play with anymore that could be used in the classroom or during therapy. Random crayons that are laying around. I know we always needed rug gripper to place under Gavin's behind when he sat - that's a good need. Do you know a special needs Mom in your neighborhood? Church? School? Tell her you'd like to make dinner for her family. What night would work? Then tell her the only requirement is they have to give a "cheers toast" to Gavin during dinner. Help someone struggling to unload groceries into their car in the rain. Donate clothes to a women's shelter. Check with your local children's hospital for volunteer opportunities - even if it's just for two hours of your life. Save all of your magazines and bring a big stash to your local hospital. You have no idea how helpful that is to parents who spend days, weeks or months (as I did when Gavin was a baby) sitting in their child's hospital room. These are just some ideas... be creative! And think of Gavin when you do it. Share his story with the person you are blessing. Tell them that Gavin Leong changed the world with little acts of courage, determination and a sweet smile... without ever saying a word. And then ask them to pay it forward to honor his legacy. This would be the best birthday gift you could give me. There is no time frame - you could post something today or a year from now or five years from now. Thank you for helping me to honor my amazing little boy. And feel free to share this anywhere you want! 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All day readers answered with their plans to honor that wish. Kate and Ed, who had decided to take Gavin off life-support and donate his organs, responded with photos of them holding their son for the last time. Late in the evening, Kate shared &lt;a href=" http://www.kateleong.com/2013/04/gavin-david-leong.html#.UWtt8IletR6" target="_hplink"&gt; that Gavin was gone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday,  Kate posted that Gavin's liver would go to a 3-year-old boy in Texas. "We can just picture his parents' excitement!" she wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We at HuffPost Parents send our deepest condolences to the Leong family. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-04-15-gavin3.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-04-15-gavin3.jpg" width="350" height="525" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo courtesy of &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/chasingrainbowsblog" target="_hplink"&gt;Chasing Rainbows' Facebook Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1087788/thumbs/s-GAVIN-LEONG-NOTFORREUSE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Parents Around The World Describe Their Kids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/how-parents-around-the-world-_n_3087330.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3087330</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T20:46:57Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T21:50:41Z</updated>
    
    <summary>If you ask American moms, we are raising a nation of baby Einsteins. Here's what one parent had to say about the intelligence of her...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Atlantic </name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/teri-dangelo/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;If you ask American moms, we are raising a nation of baby Einsteins. Here's what one parent had to say about the intelligence of her 3-year-old, which was apparent to her from the very first moments of her life:&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1088070/thumbs/s-HOW-PARENTS-DESCRIBE-THEIR-KIDS-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Liz O&amp;#146Donnell: Work-Life Balance Does Exist, But It's Not What You Think It is</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/liz-orsquo/work-life-balance_b_3081884.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3081884</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T20:37:48Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T20:37:54Z</updated>
    
    <summary>My life, like the lives of so many of the 23 million working mothers in this country, is a constant series of choices -- weighing the pros and cons of every decision I make.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Liz O&amp;#146Donnell</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/liz-orsquo/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;"There's no such thing as work-life balance. Can we please stop talking about balance?" From &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/04/06/sheryl-sandberg_n_1409061.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Sheryl Sandberg&lt;/a&gt; to the women I meet in my day-to-day life, it seems that lately, I hear these comments a lot. And I disagree. For a working mother, it's all about balance. And we need to talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, we need to define our terms. The Merriam-Webster dictionary lists nine different definitions of balance. If you take the narrow definition when you think work-life -- that it's "stability produced by even distribution of weight on each side of the vertical axis," then absolutely, it's a fantasy. But if you define balance as, "weight or force of one side in excess of another," "a means of judging or deciding," or even, "mental and emotional steadiness," then you realize a working mother's whole life is about balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the time we open our eyes in the morning until the time we fall asleep at night, working women are balancing competing priorities, constantly weighing everything we do against everything else we should be doing. Take the decisions I made in one 24-hour period last week:&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Should I sleep in or exercise? Exercise or catch up on email? Take the kids to school or actually get to work on time? Research home health aides for my parents or mentor a younger coworker during my lunch hour? Book a trip to corporate headquarters for some critical face time or dial in to the meeting so I can be home to help with homework? Go to a networking event or to my daughter's soccer game? Stay until the end of the game or go to the PTO meeting? Volunteer with a political campaign on the weekend or visit my aging parents? Go to my parent's house or do yard work? Meet a friend for a glass of wine or stay home with my husband? Do laundry or go to bed? Catch up on emails or go to sleep? Lie awake and stress about my to-dos or get up and cross things off the list?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My life, like the lives of so many of the 23 million working mothers in this country, is a constant series of choices -- weighing the pros and cons of every decision I make. Sure, a few of those choices are a luxury of privilege -- like whether or not to volunteer -- but most are based on pure necessity, like how to provide financially for my family and still have time to be present in their lives. That's the balancing act, and it's constant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I subscribe wholeheartedly to the idea work life needs to be a parenting discussion, not a woman-only discussion, but women are especially susceptible to the pressures of trying, not merely to have it all, but to do it all. For starters, we face inherent challenges and biases in the workforce that require us to seriously consider how we show up and how we do or don't access flex options. Second, even if we intellectually reject the media-created idea of the superwoman who brings home the bacon, fries it up in a pan, eats the bacon, but doesn't let it affect her midsection, on another level, the idea of having it all is ingrained in our psyche. We are surrounded by images of having it all, climbing the corporate ladder and being the perfect mother. Even Sandberg with her eye-opening discussion of the challenges women face at work is an image of perfection: C-level executive, caring wife and mother, well-spoken, well-coiffed, well-dressed. And doing it all? Well, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/07/12/more-than-half-american-women-breadwinners_n_1668140.html" target="_hplink"&gt;women are breadwinners in fifty percent of U.S. households&lt;/a&gt;, and do on average, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/liz-orsquo/women-work-life-balance_b_2527179.html" target="_hplink"&gt;fifty percent more household chores&lt;/a&gt; than men do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we better define our terms and we acknowledge that work-life balance is about so much more than the basic question, "can you have a successful career and a thriving family life?" we start to understand just how relevant and critical the balance discussion is. To say we're trying to balance work and family is incomplete. We're balancing every decision, every day, against a whole list of competing priorities. Until we, along with our employers, our spouses and our communities understand that, we won't create the truly useful and relevant workplace policies and social structures like family leave policies, eldercare services, flex workplaces and extended-day school programs, that will support working women. There is such a thing as work-life balance, and too often, the weight or force of one side is in excess of another.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1034696/thumbs/s-WORKLIFE-BALANCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Why I Had Trouble Letting Go Of My Single Mother Title</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/why-i-was-reluctant-to-le_n_3087180.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3087180</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T20:25:48Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T20:24:35Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Angie and I were playing hide-and-seek at the playground on a Wednesday afternoon when three helicopters starting circling overhead, a sure sign of trouble in...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>www.rolereboot.org</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Angie and I were playing hide-and-seek at the playground on a Wednesday afternoon when three helicopters starting circling overhead, a sure sign of trouble in our neck of northern Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1087993/thumbs/s-MOM-DAUGHTER-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Rob Watson: Did You Hear The Joke About The Homophobes Who Wanted To Put Their 16-Year-Old Lesbian Daughter Up For Adoption?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rob-watson/did-you-hear-the-joke-about-the-homophobes-who-wanted-to-put-up-their-16-year-old-lesbian-daughter-for-adoption_b_3071555.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3071555</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T20:23:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T20:27:28Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The satirical article described the mindset of a homophobic couple who, upon learning that their daughter is gay, sought to put her up for adoption. Those who believed the story did so because, even though the story is fake, the mindset it describes is painfully and horrifically real.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Rob Watson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rob-watson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Jokes are supposed to be funny.  They always start with a setup and then build to a crescendo where the plot twists and the listener bursts out laughing.    Last week a "joke" went viral, but no one was left laughing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The "joke" was a piece titled "&lt;a href="http://tysonbowersiii.com/parents-put-16-year-old-daughter-up-for-adoption-after-learning-she-is-gay/" target="_hplink"&gt;PARENTS PUT 16 YEAR OLD DAUGHTER UP FOR ADOPTION AFTER LEARNING SHE IS GAY&lt;/a&gt;."  It came from a site called Memoirs of DEACON Tyson Bowers III and had previous iterations on The Daily Bleach and Christwire.  The site it came from featured other "credible" pieces such as "KENTUCKY MAN SUES MOTHER FOR NOT ABORTING HIM," "DANGERS OF PRIDE WEEK," "STUDY: LESBIANS MORE LIKELY TO EAT FISH," "AFRICAN AMERICAN SCIENTIST INVENT SYNTHETIC WATERMELON" and "GAYS BUILDING SECRET PENILE SHAPED RESORT ISLAND."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The piece was written as humor -- satire -- but none of the 72,000 who shared it took it that way.  They believed it to be real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who could blame them?  The article described the mindset of a homophobic couple from "Southern Carolina" who, upon learning that their daughter is gay, sought to put her up for adoption.  Those who believed the story did so because, even though the story is fake, the mindset it describes is painfully and horrifically real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story sped through Facebook, and many people posted it, in most cases temporarily, only to take it down again, apologizing for having fallen for the hoax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most heart-wrenching thing to observe was the sweet souls who were willing to step up to help.  Numerous people sought more information because they were actively looking to adopt the abandoned teen in question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some news for them, and for those of you who cared about the 16-year-old girl in the fake story: She exists.  The story was bogus, the situation was a lie, but she is the truth.  She is 16 and 15 and 14.  She is lesbian, she is gay, she is bisexual and she is transgender.  Her parents did not try to adopt her out; they simply kicked her out of the house and slammed the door behind her.  She is our homeless LGBT youth.  And not only does she exist, but she accounts for up to 40 percent of all homeless teens, even though only some 3 to 10 percent of all teens are LGBT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writer Cathy Kristofferson researched and wrote &lt;a href="http://oblogdeeoblogda.me/2013/01/01/the-ongoing-plight-of-homeless-queer-youth/" target="_hplink"&gt;an important piece&lt;/a&gt; in which she paints an accurate and urgent portrait of the LGBT homeless teen.  Of the disproportionate rate, she states:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Simple.  Youth who come out to their parents are rejected by those parents at a rate of 50%, with 26% immediately thrown out of the house to become instantly homeless and many following soon after as a result of the physical and verbal abuse that ensues after their declaration.  Empowered by the gains in equality and acceptance with the heightened visibility the adult gay community has welcomed of late, youth are emboldened to come out at ever-younger ages while still reliant on parents who are a flip of the coin away from rejecting them.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Simple factors of 4 tell the story of parental rejection and its effect on queer youth homelessness:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;2 out of 4 will be rejected by their parents when they come out&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;1 out of 4 will be kicked out by their parents when they come out&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;3 out of 4 homeless queer youth will say parent objections to their orientation led to their homelessness&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Youth homelessness is bad enough on its own but being queer further compounds the difficulties.  Devastating statistics like 62% of queer homeless youth attempt suicide only begin to tell the story of the additional hardship endured when compared with their heterosexual counterparts.  Queer youth experiencing homelessness are:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;3 times more likely to commit suicide, and 8 times more likely due to parental rejection&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;3 times more likely to turn to prostitution and survival sex&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;6 times higher incidents of mental health and substance abuse issues&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;7 times more likely to experience sexual violence at a much higher risk of victimization by rape, robbery and assault&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, yes, there was an article passed around the other day, and thousands were rightly outraged and cared.  The article was a fraud, bur your feelings and mine were not.  We need to focus not on the tomfoolery of the Internet but on the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;, the reason behind our feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; is that there are real kids out there who need not only our indignation but our action.  Last Christmas I suggested &lt;a href="http://evolequals.com/2012/12/21/a-five-point-plan-to-creating-the-best-christmas/" target="_hplink"&gt;reaching out to them&lt;/a&gt; in the spirit of the season.  Now I am suggesting it in the spirit of what is right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wanted to adopt the 16-year-old in the story, find the real her and adopt her.  If you wanted to send money, start a program or get involved, please do it.  If you felt passion, please channel that passion into action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we don't, then the unreal story becomes real.  It becomes an allegory for the progressive community who chose to adopt out its youth in need.  We are better than that.  Let's not have the next viral story be ours.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1088001/thumbs/s-HOMELESS-LGBT-YOUTH-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Marla Murasko: Did the TSA Harrass Us Because of Our Special Needs Son?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marla-murasko/did-the-tsa-harrass-us-because-of-our-special-needs-son_b_3085495.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3085495</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T20:22:06Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T20:22:11Z</updated>
    
    <summary>My husband and I have traveled many places with our son, who is 7 years old and diagnosed with Down syndrome. We have traveled through many airports and have always followed the TSA policies. However, on this one particular day, we encountered rude and unpleasant harassment.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Marla Murasko</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marla-murasko/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is it that with the travel industry struggling as much as it is, the TSA makes traveling worse for travelers by making the process of going through security checkpoints so uncomfortable and degrading?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband and I are frequent flyers, and have traveled many places with our son, who is 7 years old and diagnosed with Down syndrome. We have traveled through many airports and have always followed the TSA policies. However, on this one particular day, we encountered such a rude and unpleasant display of harassment from a TSA Supervisor in the Houston airport that I wrote a letter to the TSA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were returning from Spring break in Mexico and just cleared customs. We put all our carry-on bags on the security belt, as well as our shoes, my husband's hat and belt and the small cooler pack that contained my son's "empty" medicine bottle, which was clearly labeled. The bottle was empty because we brought just enough for our trip. It also contained two Capri Sun water packs and one Dananimal Yogurt drink. Which, if you take a look at those yogurt shakes, was only 3.1 fluid ounces. As it reads in the TSA policies for "&lt;a href="http://www.tsa.gov/traveler-information/3-1-1-carry-ons" target="_hplink"&gt;3-1-1 for Carry-Ons&lt;/a&gt; 3.4 ounce (100ml) bottle or less (by volume) is acceptable, so still within guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time was no different from any other time we have traveled. We clearly were upfront with the agents, explaining that this is what we had in the cooler bag, our son has special needs and we have a note from the TSA (that we received from an earlier incident five years ago in Newark) and a doctor's note explaining his special diet.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What's interesting is that there is no set policy that is carried out by TSA agents across the board for all the airports. What I mean by that is that we have encountered TSA agents who didn't even open the bag; some who told us you are allowed liquids and medicines by the TSA and never looked inside; and some who want to scan the liquids. My husband and I have no problem with them doing that, we understand that it's their job. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we were told that they needed to go through all of our bags because the iPads were standing upright in the bag. We have never heard of this rule in all of our times traveling. So, instead of going through those bags and rechecking them, as they said they were going to, they decided to pull my husband aside to do a pat down. But this was after he checked the one yogurt drink we had in the bag, and didn't look at anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, we explained that we have documentation from the TSA, but no one wanted to acknowledge or even look at the documentation; they just proceeded to pat my husband down.  At this point, my husband and I were clearly upset. But, what made matters worse is that the TSA Supervisor who was standing right there had the audacity to say to us "if you just be quiet, it will go a lot faster." Seriously, is this how the TSA trains their employees to treat passengers? I was absolutely appalled at his comment.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, my husband was so upset that he began shaking because he felt that he was being disrespected during the pat down. He even said to the supervisor: "he's pulling my pants down," and the arrogant supervisor said "well hold them up." I turned to him and said, "You just told him to put his arms out to the side, which do you want?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me quote what the TSA policies read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Our current policies and procedures focus on ensuring that all passengers, regardless of their personal situations and needs, are treated equally and with dignity, respect and courtesy they deserve.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither my husband and I believe that this was an act of dignity or respect, what do you think?  It even got to the point where I then said to the supervisor, "look how you are upsetting my son," because at this point, he was clearly shaken seeing his father getting patted down and harassed.  He is smart enough to know the issue was about his drinks, that all he kept saying was "I'm sorry, I'm sorry!"  This is absolutely the most despicable and insensitive thing I have ever seen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a family traveling with a child with special needs, we have enough to deal without having a TSA employee -- a supervisor, no less -- upset my son right before we get on a flight. This was an absolute misuse of power. He stood there with his blue shirt on and little badge that said TSA and abused his power of authority by harassing an innocent family with a special needs son.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But hold on, this gets even worse. Would you like to know what his response was to me? He looked right at me and said, "if I don't shut up, he was going to get law enforcement." Instead of apologizing or trying to make the situation better, he wants to call the police on me because I told him he was upsetting my son? &lt;strong&gt;Really?&lt;/strong&gt; This is outrageous!  This was the worse my husband and I have ever been treated at an airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reading the TSA website, I quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Many airports have lanes specifically for use by passengers with disabilities and medical conditions or those traveling with young children. While passengers still may need to wait in line if they use these lanes, the lines often are much shorter and the wait time generally is less. A passenger can ask to be directed to one of these lanes when checking in with his or her airline or once he or she has reached the general line used by passengers. Use of these lanes is not limited to passengers who have physical disabilities. Passengers with cognitive and psychological disabilities that make it difficult to wait in line are also allowed to use these lanes.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not know this but will be asking for this in the future. Hopefully, those agents will better know how to handle a family with a special needs child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I am so upset,  I proceed to tell the supervisor that I was going to be writing a letter to the TSA telling them of the actions carried out by their employees. Well, as anyone who was wrongfully mistreated, you ask for the person's name who is mistreating and harassing you. So, I asked him "what is your name?" His response: "I'm the Supervisor." I stated "that is not what I asked you, I asked for your name." He again responded "he was the supervisor." At this point, I said to him "Do we have an issue here, what is your name?" He then finally told me his name. I also looked around to see if there was any information that would tell me at what checkpoint I was at. I thought that with that information, his name, date and time they could identify who it was.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hope is that the TSA make this person go through more training on how to handle families with special needs children, have him go through some sensitivity training and take his level of Supervisor away until he shows he knows how to handle that responsibility.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Have you been in a similar situation with a TSA agent? Do you feel this was harassment?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1025538/thumbs/s-TSA-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Lisa M. Dietlin: Making a Difference: The World of Giving - April Is Autism Awareness Month</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-m-dietlin/autism-awareness-month_b_3086864.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3086864</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T20:15:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T20:15:18Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Did you know that autism is the fastest-growing developmental disorder but is also the most underfunded? This April marks Autism Awareness Month, an entire month devoted to raising awareness about this disease.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Lisa M. Dietlin</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-m-dietlin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Did you know that autism is the &lt;a href="http://www.autismspeaks.org/what-autism/facts-about-autism" target="_hplink"&gt;fastest-growing&lt;/a&gt; developmental disorder but is also the most &lt;a href="http://nationalautismassociation.org/resources/autism-fact-sheet/" target="_hplink"&gt;underfunded&lt;/a&gt;?  This April marks Autism Awareness Month, an entire month devoted to raising awareness about this disease.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href="http://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2012/p0329_autism_disorder.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Centers for Disease Control and Prevention&lt;/a&gt; one in every 88 children is diagnosed with some form of autism -- &lt;a href="http://www.autismspeaks.org/what-autism" target="_hplink"&gt;1 in 54 boys and 1 in 252 girls&lt;/a&gt;, meaning boys are five times more likely to be diagnosed with autism than girls.  Some feel this disease is growing at an epidemic rate as &lt;a href="http://www.baylor.edu/soe/index.php?id=66053" target="_hplink"&gt;every 20 minutes&lt;/a&gt; someone is diagnosed with autism.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autism is growing at a rate of &lt;a href="http://www.autism-society.org/about-autism/facts-and-statistics.html" target="_hplink"&gt;10 to 17 percent&lt;/a&gt; annually with children.  Many adults with autism find it difficult or impossible to relate to other people in a meaningful way, many show restrictive and/or repetitive patterns of behavior or body movements and often have some degree of mental retardation.  This is also one of the most expensive disorders, having a lifetime cost of approximately &lt;a href="http://www.autism-society.org/about-autism/facts-and-statistics.html" target="_hplink"&gt;$3.2 million&lt;/a&gt; per person and $60,000 per year for a family with an autistic family member.  To be sure, there are people who will say the numbers are too overwhelming and that little, if anything, can be done to help change the course of this rampant disorder.  I would argue there is a lot that you, the reader, can do and know that will cause a change to occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you should be aware there are numerous nonprofit organizations as well as individuals working to make sure schools, research and other related services are available to those affected by autism.  &lt;a href="http://www.autismspeaks.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;Autism Speaks&lt;/a&gt; was founded in 2005 by grandparents who had a grandchild with autism.  Their friend, Bernie Marcus, donated $25 million to launch the organization which focuses on funding research, preventative measures, treatments and ultimately a cure as well as a host of other services.  They advocate on behalf of those affected with autism as well as their families.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://chicago.easterseals.com/site/PageServer?pagename=ILCH_homepage" target="_hplink"&gt;Easter Seals Metropolitan Chicago&lt;/a&gt; is a leader of providing services to those with disabilities including autism.  Their Therapeutic School and Center for Autism Research is one of the first in the country to specifically focus on autism research.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://autismallianceofmichigan.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;The Autism Alliance of Michigan&lt;/a&gt; was founded in 2010 and is doing amazing work.  &lt;a href="http://www.msuspartans.com/sports/m-baskbl/mtt/ianni_anthony00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Anthony Ianni,&lt;/a&gt; a former Michigan State University basketball player who has autism, is one of its spokespeople sharing his story about achieving his lifelong goals.  A high school friend of mine named Scott is a retired police officer.  He leads the effort to educate other police officers throughout Michigan and other areas of the country about how to work with autistic individuals who might be witnesses to a crime or even the alleged perpetrator.  Scott educates them on how to interact with individuals affected by autism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two additional nonprofit organizations focused on autism in various areas include the &lt;a href="www.autism-society.org" target="_hplink"&gt;Autism Society&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="www.tacanow.org" target="_hplink"&gt;TACA &lt;/a&gt;(which stands for &lt;u&gt;T&lt;/u&gt;alk &lt;u&gt;A&lt;/u&gt;bout &lt;u&gt;C&lt;/u&gt;uring &lt;u&gt;A&lt;/u&gt;utism).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many retail stores dedicate resources and raise money to help those affected by disabilities.  For example, this year &lt;a href="http://www.buildabear.com/shopping/" target="_hplink"&gt;Build-A-Bear Workshop&lt;/a&gt; is offering an &lt;a href="http://www.autismspeaks.org/about-us/press-releases/build-bear-workshop-offers-unique-piece-support-autism-speaks" target="_hplink"&gt;Autism Speaks bear&lt;/a&gt;.  With each bear purchased, some of the proceeds are given directly to Autism Speaks.  The &lt;a href="http://www.dominicks.com/IFL/Grocery/Home" target="_hplink"&gt;Dominick's&lt;/a&gt; grocery store chain, through its parent company's foundation, &lt;a href="http://www.safewayfoundation.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;the Safeway Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, is committed to raising dollars for people with disabilities in the month of April.  They ask their customers when they are checking out if they would like to make a donation to help people with disabilities.  Their employees give back, too!  According to their website, last year they gave more than $9.2 million to nonprofits that provide services to those with disabilities including autism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celebrities are involved in helping raise dollars and awareness for this disease including Tina Fey, Stephen Colbert, Tony Braxton, Dan Marino, Adam Sandler, Adian Quinn, Doug Flutie and many more some of whom have children that have been diagnosed including Jenny McCarthy and Joe Mantegna. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenny McCarthy has used her own personal story of autism to provide help and hope for families around the world by establishing &lt;a href="www.generationrescue.org" target="_hplink"&gt;Generation Rescue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Mantegna, Chicago-born actor and one of the stars of the CBS hit show &lt;em&gt;Criminal Minds&lt;/em&gt;, is the national spokesperson for Easter Seals Metropolitan Chicago, as his daughter is affected by autism. Check out what he has to say about autism and this school &lt;a href="http://chicago.easterseals.com/site/PageServer?pagename=ILCH_joe_mantegna_talks_about_the_new_school_videos" target="_hplink"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many things that you can be doing to be Making A Difference (M.A.D.) for an important cause.  Here are five (5) tips which will help you to be aware of how to support those affected by autism:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.	Learn more about all aspects of autism and the spectrum; a simple search on the Internet will provide a wealth of information.  As a reference point, autism is a term to describe five (5) neurological disorders, often referred to as Autism Spectrum Disorder.  These include autistic disorder, Rett syndrome, childhood disintegrative disorder, pervasive developmental disorder -- not otherwise specified (PDD-NOS) and Asperger syndrome.  &lt;br /&gt;
2.	Offer to help a family who has a child with this disease; make a meal, have a conversation, offer to visit... any of these gestures plus simply being available as a resource can and will make a difference&lt;br /&gt;
3.	Make a financial donation to a nonprofit organization that works to help children and their families affected by autism&lt;br /&gt;
4.	Volunteer at a nonprofit organization doing work in autism&lt;br /&gt;
5.	Offer to babysit for a family who has an autistic child.  Give them a few hours to do their grocery shopping, go to a movie, dinner, etc. with knowing their child is in safe keeping  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus Tip: shop!  Many stores offer a portion of the purchase price of an item or allow you to make a donation.  Be mindful this month about where you shop and choose vendors that are associated with helping those affected by autism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we really think about it, all of us probably know individuals and families affected by autism.  By working together as a community as well as funding the research and facilities that provide help, we will be able to deal with this disease that affects so many in our community.  If we all do something, we will be Making A Difference!  What will you do to be M.A.D. today for those affected by autism?&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1066525/thumbs/s-AUTISM-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
