<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Robin M. Masheb: When Religion and Dieting Collide: What Did You Give Up for Lent?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/robin-m-masheb/body-image_b_2978191.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2978191</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T12:33:14Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T12:47:42Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Maybe what we need to give up for Lent isn't a forbidden food, but the Fat Talk instead. Eating is indeed a sacred practice. As is the speech we use to feed our minds.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Robin M. Masheb</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/robin-m-masheb/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;What did you give up for Lent? Chocolate or ice cream? Or perhaps some other high-fat, high-sugar, and relatively high-calorie "forbidden food?" For overweight people struggling with eating disorders, an important aspect of treatment involves incorporating small amounts of "forbidden foods" into one's diet on a regular basis. The rationale is to break the cycle of being "on a diet" or "off a diet." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite having this knowledge, when religious holidays with dietary restrictions or associations come around (it can be Yom Kippur for Jews or Ramadan for Muslims), patients are eager to give up something like chocolate or to fast for a holiday. All too often, underlying the religious practice of self-discipline is the thinking that this is a good way to lose weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our class on Psychopathology and Pastoral Care at Yale Divinity School, we happened to be discussing eating disorders, and the contrast between our country's obesity crisis and the pressure to conform to the "thin ideal." A student asked how we could help young people, particularly girls, develop a healthy body image in an environment where two-thirds of our country is overweight and everyone idealizes women who wear a size two. In the context of this environment, how can one make a difference? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important aspect of this conversation is the identity and self-image parents help to create for their child. Do you focus on your daughter's appearance and weight, or do you compliment her character and achievements -- in your own mind, to her, and around other people? Is the way you build the identity of your son different than the way you do this with your daughter? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there is the matter of &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RKPaxD61lwo"&gt;Fat Talk&lt;/a&gt;. Does your child hear you comment to yourself, "I feel so fat?" Or perhaps you ask your partner or child, "Do I look fat in this?" Fat Talk isn't about your shape or weight. Rather, Fat Talk is a demeaning way we talk about ourselves or others. Why do we do this? There is a false notion that berating oneself with this talk will be motivating. Nothing could be further from the truth. Fat Talk shames. It leads to inertia and impedes efforts to eat right and exercise more. Fat Talk is neither therapeutic nor pastoral. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we put a stop to Fat Talk and poor body image, and build better identities and self-images for our children? Try consciously correcting yourself when you hear Fat Talk in your mind, or when you say it out loud, especially in front of your kids. Avoid comparing your body with others. Instead, offer a prayer of thanksgiving for the skin you are in. If you feel down about being overweight, try going for a walk and enjoying being outside. Remind yourself of your importance to your family and community, and to the meaning of your work. Think about health and wellbeing, rather than thinness, as the goal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is hard to buck the media messages that continually assault our sense of wellbeing with idealized images of models and mannequins who appear to be suffering from anorexia nervosa. So in addition to being mindful about the way that we talk to our kids, we also have to speak out publicly and try to clear up this cultural confusion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's what a 14-year-old named &lt;a href="http://theviralmedialab.org/5631/2012/10/dont-photoshop-my-story-an-interview-with-julia-bluhm/"&gt;Julia Bluhm&lt;/a&gt;, a member of the First Congregational Church of Waterville, Maine, did. As a dancer, Julia Bluhm became concerned about eating disorders. This led her to work with others to start a petition to &lt;i&gt;Seventeen&lt;/i&gt;, asking the magazine to stop photo-shopping pictures of girls. The idea was to start showing pictures of real girls in their natural beauty. The campaign was a success, with 86,000 people signing the petition. Then &lt;i&gt;Seventeen&lt;/i&gt; agreed to publish one unaltered photo spread each month. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How we frame things matters. It was the scientist among us, the psychologist, who told the divinity school class we needed to think about eating as a sacred practice. Sacred because it is the means of how we live, how we exist in our bodies. What if religious leaders started preaching this kind of mindfulness? What if we spoke more about well-being and less about looks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to try to change the cultural conversation, starting with the way we talk to ourselves, to our children, to congregations, and in the public square. When religion and dieting collide, we need to think more deeply about our lives, our goals, and our values. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe what we need to give up for Lent isn't a forbidden food, but the Fat Talk instead. Eating is indeed a sacred practice. As is the speech we use to feed our minds. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robin M. Masheb, Ph.D. is Associate Director for the Program for Obesity, Weight and Eating Research, and an Assistant Professor, in the Department of Psychiatry at the Yale School of Medicine. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mary Clark Moschella, Ph.D. is the Roger J. Squire Professor of Pastoral Care and Counseling at Yale Divinity School.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061844/thumbs/s-BODY-IMAGE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Did Kim Kardashian Reveal The Sex Of Her Baby?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/kim-kardashian-reveal-sex-baby-video_n_2977127.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2977127</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T07:15:08Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T10:00:54Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Did Kim Kardashian inadvertently reveal the sex of her baby with Kanye West during her appearance on "The Tonight Show." It's not certain, but Jay...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Hughes</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jason-hughes/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Did &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/402311/kim-kardashian-gives-in-to-first-pregnancy-craving-of-in-n-out-burger-and-fries" target="_hplink"&gt;Kim Kardashian&lt;/a&gt; inadvertently reveal the sex of her baby with &lt;a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/arts-entertainment/music/news/kanye-west-the-rapper-who-wouldbe-god-8553905.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Kanye West&lt;/a&gt; during her appearance on "&lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/life/tv/2013/03/28/bianco-news-and-views-tonight-show/2025549/" target="_hplink"&gt;The Tonight Show&lt;/a&gt;." It's not certain, but &lt;a href="http://insidetv.ew.com/2013/03/28/jay-leno-hits-seven-week-high-in-viewers/" target="_hplink"&gt;Jay Leno&lt;/a&gt; seems to think she may have by dropping a possible name she was considering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It happened when they addressed the &lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/entertainment/gossip/la-et-mg-kim-kardashian-kanye-west-baby-name-20130322,0,6489927.story" target="_hplink"&gt;rumors they're considering the name North&lt;/a&gt; -- thus dubbing the baby North West. Kardashian denied these rumors, but suggested something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You know what name I do like, but it probably won’t be on? I do like, because it kind of goes with North, I like Easton. Easton West. I think that’s cute."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Now Easton would be a boy’s name, correct?” Leno asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You never know," Kardashian said. She did say that Easton probably wouldn't be the name, either. Maybe because it is a boy's name and the &lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/news/kim-kardashian-kanye-west-expecting-a-baby-girl-2013232" target="_hplink"&gt;rumor is that she and Kanye are expecting a little girl&lt;/a&gt;. She's not due until the summer, so fans will just have to wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, fans can track the pregnancy on Kardashian's Instagram page where she seems to be posting everything that's happening with the pregnancy &lt;em&gt;except &lt;/em&gt;the gender of the baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Catch Kim Kardashian on "&lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/400824/kourtney-kim-take-miami-recap-is-kim-killing-kanye-s-style-cred" target="_hplink"&gt;Kourtney &amp; Kim Take Miami&lt;/a&gt;," Sundays at 9 p.m. ET on E! "The Tonight Show with Jay Leno" airs every weeknight at 11:35 p.m. ET on NBC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TV Replay scours the vast television landscape to find the most interesting, amusing, and, on a good day, amazing moments, and delivers them right to your browser.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061716/thumbs/s-LENO-KIM-KARDASHIAN-130328-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'Wife Swap': One Family Walks Off The Show</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/wife-swap-couple-walks-off-show-video_n_2976915.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2976915</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T05:15:29Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T09:47:40Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The culture clash was even more extreme on the latest episode of "Wife Swap." Producers had to know there was going to be the potential...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Hughes</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jason-hughes/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;The culture clash was even more extreme on the latest episode of "&lt;a href="http://www.uproxx.com/tv/2013/03/noted-whistleblower-coolio-now-says-his-celebrity-wife-swap-appearance-was-a-sham/" target="_hplink"&gt;Wife Swap&lt;/a&gt;." Producers had to know there was going to be the potential for serious ramifications by swapping a proud Christian Republican family with a polyamorous one. Gina Louden found it too much when she swapped into the Envy family -- a husband, wife and girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gina, a Tea Party activist and political pundit, couldn't even make it through the week, abandoning the show to check into a hotel. Then, against the rules of the show, she contacted her husband, John.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Hey, honey. We’re definitely dealing with dark forces here," John told her. He'd been preaching against the Envy lifestyle to Angela, the wife he inherited for the show, to the point he was traumatizing her. Gina, on the other hand, had been trying to convince Chris to step up and not expect the women to wait on him hand and foot. She felt that the girlfriend was an innocent victim in the relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that phone call, the Loudons were not seen from again in the episode, marking the first time a family did not make the roundtable discussion at the end of the hour. Celeb Dirty Laundry &lt;a href="http://www.celebdirtylaundry.com/2013/celebrity-wife-swap-recap-32813-gina-loudon-and-angela-envy-swap-lives/" target="_hplink"&gt;blamed both families for their communication breakdowns&lt;/a&gt;, making it "more dramatic than usual." Still, the Envy family did embrace some of the things they learned from Gina. Presumably, the Loudons did not embrace anything they learned from Angela.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See which cultures mix it up next time on "Wife Swap," Thursdays at 8 p.m. ET on ABC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TV Replay scours the vast television landscape to find the most interesting, amusing, and, on a good day, amazing moments, and delivers them right to your browser.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061706/thumbs/s-WIFE-SWAP-TEA-PARTY-130328-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Mitt Romney: My Grandchildren 'Are Just Darling Little Infants'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/mitt-romney-grandchildren_n_2976261.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2976261</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T03:48:33Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T05:10:32Z</updated>
    
    <summary>With his 2012 presidential campaign in the rear-view mirror, former Massachusetts Gov. Mitt Romney (R) now has more time to spend with his family. At...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/chris-gentilviso/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;With his 2012 presidential campaign in the rear-view mirror, former &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/11/07/mitt-romney-election-results-2012_n_2036422.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Massachusetts Gov. Mitt Romney (R)&lt;/a&gt; now has more time to spend with his family. At the top of his list of stories -- the grandeur of his grandchildren's names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was one of the main topics he addressed in a &lt;a href="http://www.dennismillerradio.com/b/A-Lot-of-Energy/695532222038379258.html" target="_hplink"&gt;radio interview with Dennis Miller&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday, as he prepared to celebrate his 44th wedding anniversary with wife, Ann Romney, on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Forty-four great years," Romney remarked. "Amazingly, 21 grandchildren right now. I think it’s 21, it could be 22," he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the interview, Miller joked: "Now listen, I don't know if they've even told you this, but you've had two more grandchildren since this interview started," drawing laughter from Romney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The last few months ago, we had twins come in, and you can't believe what they're named," Romney said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"What?" Miller asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Winston and Eleanor," Romney replied, drawing a chuckle from Miller. "I mean, it's going back the glorious days of the 30s and 40s I guess. But these are just darling little infants, and to have such big names on them is really something."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Romney later elaborated on how mystified he was by the children's names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"When I heard Winston and Eleanor I thought 'it sounds like two English bulldogs.' But they're adorable children. And you know, I don't know what it is about twins. There's something that just melts your heart to see them together in the same little crib, connecting with one another. It really is beautiful."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/28/mitt-romney-2012-campaign_n_2786093.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Romney did his first interview&lt;/a&gt; since November's election loss, opening up about how much of a "roller coaster" ride the 2012 campaign was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We were on a roller coaster, exciting and thrilling, ups and downs," Romney told Fox News' Chris Wallace. "But the ride ends. And then you get off. And it's not like, oh, can't we be on a roller coaster the rest of our life? It's like, no, the ride's over."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061602/thumbs/s-MITT-ROMNEY-GRANDCHILDREN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: Teacher Criticized For Saying 'Vagina' Speaks Out</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/tim-mcdaniel-idaho-teache_n_2975643.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2975643</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T00:53:21Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T00:53:28Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Parents in Dietrich, Idaho, say the word "vagina" has no place in a 10th grade science class, according to news website MagicValley.com. We talk with...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>HuffPost Live</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/john-stephens/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Parents in Dietrich, Idaho, say the word "vagina" has no place in a 10th grade science class, according to news website MagicValley.com. We talk with the teacher being investigated for teaching human anatomy in Sex Ed class.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061562/thumbs/s-TIM-MCDANIEL-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The 'Grey's Anatomy' You Don't Want To Miss</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/sarah-chalke-kawasakis-disease-greys-anatomy_n_2975040.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2975040</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T23:22:10Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T00:03:24Z</updated>
    
    <summary>This week's "Grey's Anatomy" is the episode fans have been waiting for, but not because of some twisted love triangle or Save Seattle Grace drama....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jaimie Etkin</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jaimie-etkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;This week's "Grey's Anatomy" is the episode fans have been waiting for, but not because of some twisted love triangle or Save Seattle Grace drama. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah Chalke, best known for her earlier roles on "Roseanne" and "Scrubs," guest stars to tell her very personal and "mind-blowing" story, according to &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/greys-anatomy-april-matthew-japril-sarah-drew_n_2925257.html" target="_hplink"&gt;"Grey's" star Sarah Drew&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/402252/sarah-chalke-s-very-personal-grey-s-anatomy-episode-inspired-by-son-s-deadly-disease" target="_hplink"&gt;Chalke opens up to The Huffington Post about her now-three-year-old son Charlie's battle with Kawasaki's disease&lt;/a&gt;, an autoimmune disease that is largely seen in children under the age of five. Find out why &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sarahchalke" target="_hplink"&gt;she decided to bring her harrowing Kawasaki's experience to "Grey's Anatomy,"&lt;/a&gt; the one in a million opportunity she had on set and why parents need to know "that it's OK to fight" for their children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's a really incredible, moving and heart-wrenching story to tell on the show," Drew told The Huffington Post earlier of Chalke's episode. "It's really amazing. I'm so excited to see it."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you decide to tell your story on "Grey's Anatomy" and why now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It was pretty scary actually. [Laughs.] Now is a good time in the sense that it took me a bit of time to be ready to talk about it and it was a big decision to talk about it. Because I obviously wish that it was something that happened to me that I was talking about -- it complicates things, I think, when it involves your kid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked a lot about it and, at the end of the day, in the balance of things, once you go through something like that, you can't not figure out every single way that you can help another parent or another kid who might be going through what we did. For me, the biggest goal was to raise awareness because it's something that doesn't have a lot of visibility -- nobody knows about it. We didn't know about it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a treatment. There's this ticking clock. There's a 10-day window that you have to get this treatment in to save your kid's heart. It's called IVIG. So through an IV drip for 12 hours, they give kids a protein solution that's made from human blood. It takes 10,000 blood donors to create a batch and out of that batch, a lot of kids will get treated. Each kid is getting the benefit of the immunity from 10,000 donors and what that does is it reduces inflammation in the body. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's this great website called &lt;a href="http://KDFoundation.org" target="_hplink"&gt;KDFoundation.org&lt;/a&gt; and that's the website that "Grey's" actually let me do a PSA for at the end of the episode. That's the website that saved my son because it's the website that I kept going back to and just reading the symptoms that are so clearly listed and [my son] had all of them. We fought really hard to get him diagnosed and he got the treatment on Day 10.5. It was late and thank God, he's OK. And I think that's what has allowed me to feel like I can try and do this. But I was really scared when we were doing it. [Laughs.] &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What has been really cool since then is the response from parents that I've had already, even before the episode has aired. There were parents that were as lucky as us and parents that were not as lucky as us who've written to me. But this is such a unique way to get parents to see the visual symptoms because it's basically high fever and then everything goes red. There's the red, bloodshot eyes and the red lips and the red tongue and the red throat and the red hands and feet and then the last symptom is the peeling of the skin on the fingers, but that happens often once the diagnosis is missed. Charlie's was actually on Day 9 and that's like a telltale sign and can kind of help the diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you always want to &lt;a href="http://blogs.babycenter.com/celebrities/sarah-chalke-son-real-life-illness-03282013-greys-anatomy/" target="_hplink"&gt;play the mom to the child with Kawasaki's&lt;/a&gt; in the episode or did you just want to bring the story to Shonda Rhimes and have someone else play her?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It was interesting. I knew that I wanted to do this and I told the creators of "Grey's Anatomy" about our experience and they said, "We want to do this and we want you to play the mom." [It wasn't] my story, but just a &lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/entertainment/sarah-chalke-brings-her-story-to-greys-anatomy-spoilers/" target="_hplink"&gt;Kawasaki's storyline&lt;/a&gt; inspired by ours. And I said, "Can I sleep on that?" [Laughs.] Because I knew it was going to be tough. Then I emailed them two hours later and said, "No, absolutely. I want to do this. I want to play the mom." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was nervous about what that was going to be like, to play the mom, but it was interesting what ended up happening. My first day of shooting, I had this anxiety, like, "I hope I'm going to be OK when I hold a kid who's made up to look like Charlie did at that time." And I get this email from my Kawasaki's doctor, Dr. Jane Burns, who is one of the leading researchers in the world on Kawasaki's. And she got an email from the mother of another one of her patients who had been cast to play my son. They cast triplets in case one kid is tired or something, but one of the triplets had had KD a year before. It was wild because what are the chances of that happening? It's like zero. Casting didn't even know when they cast this little guy! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most of your scenes are with Ellen Pompeo, who plays Meredith, and Camilla Luddington, who plays Jo. Are they as doctors helpful and compassionate or do they dismiss what your character is saying she thinks her son has?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You know, the episode is called "Can't Fight This Feeling" and there's so many different &lt;a href="http://celebritybabies.people.com/2013/03/28/greys-anatomy-sarah-chalke-kawasaki-disease/" target="_hplink"&gt;Kawasaki's experiences&lt;/a&gt;. Every parent has a different journey, but it's a very common experience for people to feel like, "My kid's just really sick. I don't know what's wrong, but it's something bigger than a virus. They're not themselves. They're limp in my arms. It's just something more than this. I can't help but have this feeling that something's wrong." What I loved about the way the writers wrote the episode is that I feel like it's a message to parents -- not only, "Please look out for these symptoms for KD and if you ever come across them, go get it checked out or bring Kawasaki's up to your doctor," but I felt like it also gives the message to parents, "Fight for your kid. Whether it's KD or something else, get a second, third, fourth or fifth opinion. Don't be scared to ask questions. Don't be scared to go back. Don't be scared to get an extra test." You will never look back and regret doing those things. I feel like it's just a message to parents that it's OK to fight and to advocate for your kids.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's the full episode description for "Can't Fight This Feeling" below:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;A gas tanker explodes on a Seattle highway, causing multiple injuries -- including paramedic Matthew; Meredith and Jo help a frantic mother (Sarah Chalke) whose child is suffering from a mysterious illness; and Owen bonds with a young boy whose parents are in critical condition. Meanwhile true colors are revealed when Alex is forced to work with Jo's boyfriend on an ailing patient.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Watch Sarah Chalke's portrayal of the Kawasaki's disease storyline on "Grey's Anatomy," airing Thursday, March 28 at 9 p.m. ET on ABC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--288098--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061512/thumbs/s-SARAH-CHALKE-KAWASAKIS-DISEASE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Lea Lion: How I Became The Mom Who Gave Birth In A Parking Lot</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lea-lion/a-parking-lot-birth-story_b_2832173.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2832173</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T22:48:50Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T23:06:10Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I held onto the wall and the banister as I slowly made my way down the stairs. I held onto my very worried-looking mother as I walked out of the front door. Then I held onto the porch railing as another contraction rocked through me. My only thought was: Must get to car.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Lea Lion</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lea-lion/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;If you are a woman of childbearing age in Los Angeles, you may have heard of me. I often get introduced at baby showers as, "My friend who gave birth in a parking lot." Having a baby in a parking lot is not what I thought I would become known for, but it was one of the best experiences of my life and, luckily, I love telling -- and retelling -- my birth story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A watched pot never boils. At three days past my due date with my second child, I knew what it felt like to be the pot. Every time I came downstairs -- in the morning, after a midday nap, before dinner -- my in-laws, who were in town for the birth, observed, "Still no baby?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still no baby. The skin on my belly was stretched past capacity. There were fine fissures in a perfect circle around where my bellybutton used to be. I wasn't about to pop. I had popped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The waiting was wearing on my in-laws too -- they decided to take the ferry to Catalina Island. In their absence, my parents moved into the guest room to continue the vigil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried walking and yoga and sex to bring on labor. (Well, we tried to try sex.) Still no baby. There was nothing left to do except ride mini-trains, my then 2-year-old's latest obsession, so off we went to Descanso Gardens, where I carried my basketball-shaped belly around the koi ponds and across the wooden footbridges of the cherry blossom-strewn Japanese garden. Still no baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ordered steaming bowls of soup at our favorite noodle shop on Sunset Blvd. Still no baby. But then as I squeezed myself in behind the steering wheel to drive home, I felt a cramp coming on like a gentle wave. I didn't tell anybody. I knew if I told my parents, the watched pot phenomenon would intensify and, besides, I knew from my first birth that I still had a long journey ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At home, my husband and I watched a movie - no idea which one though -- I was too busy concentrating on the wave-like sensation that rolled through my belly every half hour. "The babe is on the way," I announced to my husband.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got into bed and fell asleep, but then at 2:00 a.m., I was up again, so I read a few birth stories from "Spiritual Midwifery" by Ina May Gaskin, to get in the baby-having mood. The waves were stronger now -- coming about every 20 minutes -- but still far from the all-encompassing contractions that I remembered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my first birth, I walked around for most of the 19-hour labor. This time, when I felt a contraction coming on, I would leap out of bed and start circling our Oriental rug only to have the wave fade away without ever reaching the crescendo of my memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At sunrise, after hours of mellow waves, I had two body-rocking contractions in a row. The intensity of giving birth came rushing back to me. I remembered, in the middle of active labor, thinking about how easy running a marathon must be in comparison. This time, I just thought, &lt;em&gt;I am never doing this again.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there was no turning back. I got into my favorite birthing position -- standing with my arms wrapped around my husband's neck -- and moaned. "We have to go to the hospital," I told him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just then, my 2-year-old woke up. My husband scooped him up and brought him downstairs to his grandparents. I went into the bathroom and sat down on the toilet. A contraction crashed through me. I could feel the baby's head crown and then, as the contraction subsided, it got sucked back into the birth canal. "We have to go!" I yelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I held onto the wall and the banister as I slowly made my way down the stairs. I held onto my very worried-looking mother as I walked out of the front door. Then I held onto the porch railing as another contraction rocked through me. My only thought was: Must get to car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no way I could sit down. Every time I had a contraction, the baby's head would emerge a little bit more. So I kneeled backwards in the passenger seat and held onto the leather headrest. I moaned. My husband called our obstetrician on speakerphone. After hearing me in the background, our always laid-back, joke-cracking doc sounded serious, "Head straight to the hospital. I'm on my way."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an unseasonably cool and rainy April morning. Typically, it takes 20 minutes to drive from our home in Echo Park to the hospital in Beverly Hills, but Beverly Boulevard was being repaved and traffic was backed up. My husband drove into maze-like streets of Hancock Park. In the brief moments between contractions, I noticed raindrops on the car window and naked tree limbs overhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we pulled into the hospital parking lot. "I have to get out of here. I have to get out of here," I repeated over and over. My husband jumped out, opened my door and started getting our bags out of the trunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing at last, I had another contraction. I reached my hand down and felt the top of the baby's head. "Ofer, I'm having the baby." I took off my underwear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Lea, we're here. The elevators are right over there."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"No, I mean right now. Feel." I grabbed his hand and pulled it up between my legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Oh my God!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband dropped down onto his knees. He dropped the car keys. He didn't have time to drop the bags that were slung over his chest. I stood with my hands on my thighs. My husband was behind me. One more push and the baby's head popped out. Then my water broke and a huge splash of fluid drenched my husband, the baby and the parking lot floor. I felt the baby's body slide out -- fast, really fast -- into my husband's open hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the baby was out, I tried to take a step forward, but the umbilical cord yanked me back into place. Immediately, the baby started to cry. When we heard his cries, a wave of relief washed over us. "Hi baby," "Oh my God," "Hi baby," we chanted again and again. It was cold and damp and I gathered the long skirt of my dress to wrap around him. My husband hugged him close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parking lot -- one of the busiest in L.A. -- was deserted. Minutes passed. Eventually, I saw a parking lot attendant in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"911! Emergency!" I yelled. "We just had a baby!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parking guy looked over at us, looked away, looked back and then turned around and ran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn't get it -- where did he go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he reappeared, I yelled again, "We just had a baby!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More minutes passed. Then, the elevator doors opened and three nurses came running out into the parking lot, each pushing a wheelchair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was pandemonium. Nurses shouting. Wheelchairs flying. Baby crying. What was going on? &lt;em&gt;Why were there so many wheelchairs?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Pass the baby to me," one of the nurses instructed my husband. She held out her arms, urging him to hand the baby through my legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; "I'm not passing my baby anywhere," he replied. "Are you crazy?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before she had a chance to answer, our doctor arrived, took charge and started yelling at the bumbling nurses. "Where are my clamps? Where are blankets? Why are there so many wheelchairs?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had been discovered, but we still had to figure out how to get from the parking lot up to the maternity ward. My husband was still behind me holding the baby and the baby and I were still attached by umbilical cord. There was only one thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Lea, do you think you could swing your leg over my head and turn around?" my husband asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After giving birth? No problem. I did a fan kick over my husband's head and with the cord now in front of me, sat down in one of the wheelchairs. My husband handed the baby to me and I got my first full on look at my new baby boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went up to the maternity floor in a blissful, post-birth bubble. But once we got there, it was chaos again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dozens of doctors and nurses and hospital administrators squeezed into our delivery room, obscuring the panoramic view of the Hollywood Hills out of the floor-to-ceiling window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I delivered the placenta in one easy push. I breastfed my new baby. The nurses took the baby over to the scale and weighed him. It was business as usual -- except that no one seemed to be able to figure out how to check us  -- a mother &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a baby --  into the maternity ward. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Has this ever happened here before?" I asked a friendly nurse as she took my blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Honey," she said, shaking her head 'no' and laughing, "this is Beverly Hills."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-07-kobeandofer1" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-07-kobeandofer1" width="550" height="413" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061506/thumbs/s-LEA-LION-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>GalTime: 10 Famous Mother/Child Duos</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/galtime/10-famous-motherchild-duo_b_2964713.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2964713</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T22:39:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T22:40:02Z</updated>
    
    <summary>To show just how greatly a mother's influence can shape her child, here's a list of ten famous people throughout history who matched the great successes their mothers had already achieved.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>GalTime</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/galtime/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LauraSeldon" target="_hplink"&gt;Laura Seldon&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href="http://www.GalTime.com" target="_hplink"&gt;GalTime.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ralph Waldo Emerson once said, "Men are what their mothers made them." The same goes for women, who typically grow up to become similar to their mothers -- no matter how hard they resist! There's something about a mother's love and care that can't help but shape us into the unique person we will eventually grow to become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Whoever is the primary care giver has more significance than others when it comes to a child's development," says Sil Reynolds, therapist, mother-daughter workshop leader and co-author of the book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mothering-Daughtering-Keeping-Strong-Through/dp/1604078855" target="_hplink"&gt;Mothering and Daughtering: Keeping Your Bond Strong Through the Teen Years&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (which she wrote with her own daughter). "Since the primary care giver is usually the mother, she will have a more significant influence on her child's development than others."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.goodtherapy.org/pandora-maclean-hoover-therapist.php" target="_hplink"&gt;Pandora MacLean-Hoover&lt;/a&gt;, a Licensed Independent Clinical Social Worker in Newburyport, Mass., echoes that comment. "Mothers are theoretically considered 'primary love objects' because they often are the adult with whom a child first bonds," she says. "Appreciating and understanding who influenced us and how, throughout our lifetime, is central to how we think about ourselves."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To show just how greatly a mother's influence can shape her child, here's a list of ten famous people throughout history who matched the great successes their mothers had already achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Mary Wollstonecraft (1759 - 1797) and Daughter Mary Shelley (1797 - 1851)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mary Wollstonecraft was a famed British writer, philosopher and advocate of women's rights. Her daughter, Mary Shelley was an English writer, best known for writing the &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Marie Curie (1867 - 1934) and Daughter Irene Joliot-Curie (1897 - 1956)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marie Curie was a Polish physicist and chemist, working mainly in France, who is famous for her pioneering research on radioactivity. Her daughter, Irene Joliot-Curie, pursued her mother's work and went on to jointly win a Nobel Prize for chemistry in 1935 (with her husband, Frédéric Joliot-Curie) for discovering artificial radioactivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Josephine Baker (1906 - 1975) and Son Jean-Claude Baker (b. 1944)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josephine Baker was an American-born French dancer, singer, and actress. She adopted Jean-Claude Baker in 1958 after she met him while he worked as a bellhop in Paris at the age of 14. Following in his adopted mother's footsteps, his career has included being a model, nightclub owner and recording artist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Judy Garland (1922 - 1969) and Liza Minnelli (b. 1946)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judy Garland was an actress, singer and vaudevillian. Adored by audiences around the world for her role in &lt;em&gt;The Wizard of Oz&lt;/em&gt;, she was once described by Fred Astaire as "the greatest entertainer who ever lived." Her daughter, Liza Minnelli, is a famous performer as well. She has won four Tony Awards, an Oscar and a special "Legends" Grammy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Gloria Vanderbilt (b. 1924) and Son Anderson Cooper (b. 1967)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Born in 1924, Gloria Laura Vanderbilt is an American heiress, actress and clothing designer best known for her designer blue jeans. She is a member of the prominent Vanderbilt family of New York and the mother of CNN's Anderson Cooper. Cooper, who is 45, hosts his own show on the network, &lt;em&gt;Anderson Cooper 360°.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis (1929 - 1994) and Children John F. Kennedy, Jr. (1960 - 1999) and Caroline Kennedy (b. 1957)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacqueline ("Jackie") Bouvier Kennedy Onassis was First Lady and wife of the 35th President of the United States, John F. Kennedy. She was also mother to four children, including John F. Kennedy, Jr., who was a well-known American socialite, magazine publisher and lawyer who tragically died in 1999. Caroline Kennedy is a famed American author and attorney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Tippi Hedren (b. 1930) and Daughter Melanie Griffith (b. 1957)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathalie Kay "Tippi" Hedren is an actress and former fashion model. She is known for her roles in the Alfred Hitchcock films &lt;em&gt;The Birds&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Marnie.&lt;/em&gt; Her daughter, Melanie Griffith, is an Academy Award nominated actress and Golden Globe winner for her performance in the 1988 film, &lt;em&gt;Working Girl.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Debbie Reynolds (b. 1932) and Daughter Carrie Fisher (b. 1956)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Debbie Reynolds is a famous actress, singer and dancer who starred in &lt;em&gt;Singin' in the Rain&lt;/em&gt; in 1952, which made her a major star. Her daughter, Carrie Fisher, is also an actress. Fisher starred in the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; trilogy in the late '70s and early '80s as Princess Leia. However, Fisher is also famous for her work as a novelist and screenwriter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Blythe Danner (b. 1943) and Daughter Gwyneth Paltrow (b. 1972)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although she has been acting since the early '70s, Blythe Danner's best-known recent films include the 2000 comedy &lt;em&gt;Meet the Parents,&lt;/em&gt; and its sequels, &lt;em&gt;Meet the Fockers&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Little Fockers&lt;/em&gt;. Her daughter, Gwyneth Paltrow, has garnered worldwide recognition as an actress as well. She won an Academy Award for Best Actress in 1998 for her performance in &lt;em&gt;Shakespeare in Love&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Goldie Hawn (b. 1945) and Daughter Kate Hudson (b. 1979)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goldie Hawn is an actress, film director, producer and occasional singer. Known for her roles in &lt;em&gt;Rowan &amp; Martin's Laugh-In&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Private Benjamin&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Overboard&lt;/em&gt;, she also won an Academy Award in 1969 for her role in the movie &lt;em&gt;Cactus Flower&lt;/em&gt;. Her daughter, Kate Hudson, is also an award-winning actress. She rose to fame in 2001 after winning a Golden Globe and receiving several nominations, including a nomination for an Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress, for her role in &lt;em&gt;Almost Famous.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More from &lt;a href="http://www.GalTime.com:" target="_hplink"&gt;GalTime.com:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://galtime.com/article/parenting/49717/28272/confessions-bad-moms-why-were-still-good" target="_hplink"&gt;Confessions of 'Bad Mom's and Why We're Still Good &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://galtime.com/article/parenting/21097/54532/boys-body-image-4-affirming-messages-parents" target="_hplink"&gt;Boys &amp; Body Image: 4 Affirming Messages from Parents &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://galtime.com/article/parenting/21097/49307/what-your-kids-learn-your-marriage" target="_hplink"&gt;What Your Kids Learn From Your Marriage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://galtime.com/promotion/54680/gerber-life-bring-dreams-life-video-contest" target="_hplink"&gt;Enter to Win Gerber Life's "Bring Dreams to Life" Video Contest &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LauraSeldon" target="_hplink"&gt;Laura Seldon&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and journalist living in Los Angeles. She has written for Guess Inc., Rock The Vote, and JDate.com. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LauraSeldon" target="_hplink"&gt;Follow her on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for fun and interesting updates on how to live your best life yet!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061473/thumbs/s-GLORIA-VANDERBILT-ANDERSON-COOPER-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>15 Steps To De-Stress School Mornings</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/de-stress-school-mornings_n_2932268.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2932268</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T22:24:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T22:24:47Z</updated>
    
    <summary>This post is part of Stress-Less Parenting Club's new workshop. Check out previous posts here, and if you haven’t signed up yet, go to the...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Teri DAngelo</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/teri-dangelo/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is part of Stress-Less Parenting Club's new workshop. Check out &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/stress-less-parenting" target="_hplink"&gt;previous posts here&lt;/a&gt;, and if you haven’t signed up yet, go to the purple box on the right side of this page to receive our weekly newsletter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can't wear that sundress to school -- it's too cold outside! Put on something warmer! Where are your shoes? Your hair looks like a rat's nest! Where's your backpack? Oh no, we're out of cold cuts for sandwiches! Where did I put that permission form for the school trip to the zoo? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School mornings can easily turn into complete fiascos. One little thing can throw off the whole morning.  Christine Koh and Asha Dornfest, the leaders of our second Stress-Less Parenting workshop, emphasize in their new book &lt;em&gt;Minimalist Parenting&lt;/em&gt; the importance of having predictable routines to "streamline they rhythm of the school day." As &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/asha-dornfest/minimalist-parenting_b_2956088.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Asha writes in her new blog post&lt;/a&gt;, "the more I was able to create simple, repeatable routines for myself and the kids, the more time-efficient we all became. Everything, from getting ready for school to packing lunches to managing the after-school backpack explosion and weeknight cooking, got easier and took less time (which meant more time to relax)."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this week's workshop, Christine and Asha offer their best advice for starting school mornings off right:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve found that the best “getting ready for school” routine begins the night before. Think of it as setting up the dominoes before the effortless knockdown in the morning. As your kids get older, hand the elements of the routine over to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* Lay Out Clothes&lt;br /&gt;
* Detangle Hair&lt;br /&gt;
* Get a Head Start on Lunch Packing&lt;br /&gt;
* Line Up Backpacks and Lunch Bags&lt;br /&gt;
* Run and Empty the Dishwasher&lt;br /&gt;
* Set Out the Breakfast Dishes&lt;br /&gt;
* Sign Permission Slips, Gather Milk Money, Etc&lt;br /&gt;
* Get After-School Necessities Together&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keys to a mostly successful morning launch are to &lt;em&gt;have a plan&lt;/em&gt; and to &lt;em&gt;stay calm. &lt;/em&gt; Getting sucked into the drama and cranky morning moods escalates the bad feelings all around. Try to project cool conﬁdence (pretend if you must) -- hopefully, the kids will take your behavior cues. How the plan actually looks is up to you and your situation. Variables include the presence of other helpful (and awake) adults, the number and ages of your kids, whether or not you’re getting ready for work at the same time, distance to school, and general “morning person” temperaments. Keep in mind that no routine is perfect out of the gate -- routines are meant to be tweaked. No matter how your routine shapes up, the more you model “ﬁrst we do this, and then we do that,” the sooner your kids will do it themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wake Up Earlier Than Your Kids&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Try to get up at least 10 minutes before the kids do. Not only do you  deserve some alone time with your coffee, you’ll feel more in control  when the action begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encourage Your Kids to Use an Alarm Clock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Get an alarm clock for each of your kids and begin using it, no matter their ages. The sooner kids get used to waking themselves, the easier everyone’s mornings will go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swap Morning Wake Ups&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If your kids have different wake-up times, swap which parent gets up ﬁrst each morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Say Yes to Breakfast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A good breakfast is a must for a productive school day, and it’s a nice time to connect before everyone goes their separate ways. Even late sleepers and those with tiny morning appetites need to eat, so try to make breakfast a priority. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preview the Day With Your Kids&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Get in the habit of previewing the day with your kids to remind them about upcoming events and tasks, and to get them in the habit of planning ahead. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set Time “Signposts”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Try to break the morning routine into its natural “shifts” -- for example, breakfast, getting dressed, brushing hair and teeth, heading out the door. The shifts will be unique to your speciﬁc routine. Next, attach times to each shift, such as “breakfast is ﬁnished at 8 a.m.” Kids can better pace themselves when they’re aware of their progress through the routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End on a High Note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No matter how the morning goes down, try to end with a positive send-off. You’re working on building habits, and there will be good days and bad days. In the grand scheme of things, progress counts more than straight-line success. Besides, no one will remember the tardy passes in a few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THIS WEEK'S CHALLENGE&lt;/strong&gt;
Pinpoint the things that typically make school mornings stressful for you, and discuss with your partner and children how you can handle them better. Try integrating some of Christine and Asha's tips into your routine and let us know in the comments how it goes.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q&amp;A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the toughest parts of school mornings for you? What have you done in your house to make them go smoother? As you think about this week's challenge, we also invite you to leave your thoughts and tricks in the comments or to tweet them to us @HuffPostParents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excerpted with permission from Minimalist Parenting: Enjoy Modern Family Life More by Doing Less by Christine Koh and Asha Dornfest (Bibliomotion, March 2013).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051260/thumbs/s-SCHOOL-MORNINGS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>School District Bans Dodgeball, Citing Bullying Concerns</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/school-dodgeball-ban-windham-new-hampshire_n_2973792.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2973792</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T22:18:11Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T22:22:38Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Students attending Windham schools in New Hampshire, won't be dodging balls during gym class anymore. The school district voted to ban dodgeball and other "human...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/sara-gates/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Students attending Windham schools in New Hampshire, won't be dodging balls during gym class anymore. The &lt;a href="http://www.unionleader.com/article/20130327/NEWS04/130329184" target="_hplink"&gt;school district voted to ban dodgeball&lt;/a&gt; and other "human target" sports in a recent 4-1 decision, according to multiple sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windham Patch reports that &lt;a href="http://windham.patch.com/articles/school-board-axes-dodgeball-games-from-curriculum" target="_hplink"&gt;school officials launched an inquiry&lt;/a&gt; into the physically aggressive activities after a parent complained. Ultimately, administrators cited bullying concerns for the reason to prohibit students from playing dodgeball and similar games during school hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We spend a lot of time making sure our kids are violence free," Windham Superintendent Henry LaBranche &lt;a href="http://www.eagletribune.com/latestnews/x1121363328/Windham-school-officials-drop-dodgeball" target="_hplink"&gt;told the Eagle-Tribune&lt;/a&gt;. "Here we have games where we use children as targets. That seems to be counter to what we are trying to accomplish with our anti-bullying campaign."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The school district's decision to ban dodgeball actually falls in line with the National Association for Sport and Physical Education's recommendation. Following the release of "&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0364725/" target="_hplink"&gt;DodgeBall: A True Underdog Story&lt;/a&gt;," the nonprofit association, which &lt;a href="http://www.aahperd.org/naspe/standards/peps.cfm" target="_hplink"&gt;sets standards for school sports&lt;/a&gt;, announced that it does not approve of &lt;a href="http://www.aahperd.org/naspe/standards/upload/Position-on-Dodgeball-in-PE-2006.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;dodgeball as an appropriate activity for K-12 students&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The association pointed out that not all students are able to participate equally, since some of the players who require more physical activity are typically eliminated first. Targeting of "weaker" students was also cited as a concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Windham school board has referenced similar reasons to defend its decision, not everyone is on board with the newly enacted ban. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I think it’s ridiculous,” local parent Lesa Meuller, who has two boys ages 9 and 12, told Windham Patch. "I’ve never heard of anyone &lt;a href="http://windham.patch.com/articles/dodgeball-debate-continues-in-windham" target="_hplink"&gt;getting hurt playing dodgeball&lt;/a&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether dodgeball is an appropriate sport for school children has been a topic of discussion among school administrators for more than a decade. As a 2001 New York Times story notes, schools across the nation have moved to &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2001/05/06/us/increasingly-schools-move-to-restrict-dodgeball.html" target="_hplink"&gt;restrict or limit the aggressive activity&lt;/a&gt;, and, in some cases, officially ban the sport.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061127/thumbs/s-SCHOOL-DODGEBALL-BAN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Asha Dornfest: Putting School Year Activities Into Perspective </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/asha-dornfest/minimalist-parenting_b_2956088.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2956088</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T22:17:47Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T22:58:24Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There are serious logistics involved when your children are in school. What with the lunches and the clothes and the papers and the pickups and the drop-offs and the homework and the social and extracurricular activities and the vacation schedules (not to mention the volunteering)...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Asha Dornfest</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/asha-dornfest/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is part of &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/stress-less-parenting" target="_hplink"&gt;Stress-Less Parenting Club's second workshop&lt;/a&gt;. Asha Dornfest and Christine Koh, co-authors of Minimalist Parenting, are sharing their best advice on simplifying family life. Here, Asha discusses strategies for managing the school year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I don't know why, but it feels like I have less time now that they're in school all day."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next-door neighbor said this, and my mental response was &lt;em&gt;whaaaaa? &lt;/em&gt;Her three children were a few years older than mine, which I assumed meant she was living the relaxed life of a Mother With School-Aged Children. My oldest was a preschooler and my youngest was a baby at the time, and I was still in direct contact with plenty of poop, snot and tears. Two kids in school sounded like a resort vacation to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My neighbor's a hard-working, community-involved mom, so I didn't imagine she was lounging around eating artisan truffles and playing Angry Birds. But surely, with 9 a.m. to 3 p.m. covered by the public school system, she had more time, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn't until my kids were in school that I understood what she meant. There are serious logistics involved when your children are in school. What with the lunches and the clothes and the papers and the pickups and the drop-offs and the homework and the social and extracurricular activities and the vacation schedules (not to mention the volunteering)... it's a lot of overhead to manage. Especially if you work part- or full-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while, yes, you do have more child-free time during the day once your kids are in school, that time (plus the busy hours after school) can get complicated pretty quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you keep life relaxed and sane once your kids go to school? For me, the answer evolved as my kids got older. But it began with identifying my priorities. For example, I work during the school hours, so I decided early on not to feel guilty about forgoing regular classroom volunteer time. My absence in the classroom had another benefit for my kids: It helped them embrace school as "their" place and encouraged their independence. (That's just my kids; I know many parents who derive great satisfaction from school volunteering, and many kids who love seeing their parents during the school day.) For me, chaperoning field trips is the perfect way to pitch in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I structured before- and after-school time with routines. This took a long time and much trial-and-error because I'm not a naturally systematic person. But the more I was able to create simple, repeatable routines for myself and the kids, the more time-efficient we all became. Everything, from getting ready for school to packing lunches to managing the after-school backpack explosion and weeknight cooking, got easier and took less time (which meant more time to relax).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we limited after-school activities. Again, this is a personal choice based on my family's temperament. While some kids are passionate athletes or thrive with a busy afternoon schedule, mine don't, so we kept extracurriculars limited to one per kid. There have been years when one or both kids had no after-school activities. This means our afternoons have a certain openness to them. My husband or I have time to cook dinner (depending on who's free), my kids have the flexibility to choose how to entertain themselves, and there's time for their homework and chores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's more to it, of course, and our balance shifts every year. My oldest is now in middle school, so our expectations about his independent work are much higher. We expect him to manage and organize his homework and get it done mostly by himself. We're always available to help him through organizational and academic rough spots, but he knows that his work (and his grades) are his responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still have our share of complications and scheduling collisions, but for the most part, it's working well for all of us. The most important thing, I think, is that it's working for us. Your family's school-year choices may be different, but the bottom line is that they're your choices to make. If school days feel uncomfortably busy for you, ask yourself what you might edit so there's more room for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;If you haven't signed up for Stress-Less Parenting yet, go to the purple box on the right side of this page to receive our weekly newsletter.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051260/thumbs/s-SCHOOL-MORNINGS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Tracey Stewart: Spring Clean Your Freezer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tracey-stewart/spring-clean-your-freezer_b_2973677.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2973677</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T21:47:18Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T21:47:24Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Is it really cheaper to buy boxed frozen foods than to buy ingredients in bulk and prepare meals for the freezer yourself? You may pay a little more initially, but you will get more meals out of your purchase in the long run.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Tracey Stewart</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tracey-stewart/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;While working on a cooking piece one day, Chef Aida Koski went into my freezer for some ice and suddenly let out a loud gasp. I thought she had come across the dead bird my daughter was saving for the Spring when she could hold a proper funeral... but that wasn't it at all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Tracey, what's all this frozen food about?" she asked. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick to go on the defense I responded, "Well Miss Fancypants Chef, I am tired, constantly on the run, unable to handle too much of my children's whining about when dinner will be ready, and not the skilled chef that you are! So judge all you want but sometimes there's no other choice. And besides, all that frozen food is organic and gluten free -- so what's so bad about that?!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aida took my face in her hands and lovingly said, "I am going to help you. I know you need frozen foods sometimes, but you definitely don't need all of the preservatives and chemicals that come with them. Neither do your children. It's time to un-process your freezer." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's nice when mommies get mommied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Do We Need to Consider When Un-Processing Our Freezers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Take a look at the boxed items in your freezer. Do you know all of the ingredients listed, or can you even pronounce them all? You should know what it is that you are eating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shelf Life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If a product has a long shelf life or extended expiration date, it might be best to avoid it. Who knows what they have put in the food to make it last so long?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Claims of Natural Benefits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
"Natural flavoring" or "natural coloring" does not necessarily mean natural. It may refer to a completely obscure product in your food, just as good at producing the flavor or color needed for that product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expenses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Is it really cheaper to buy boxed frozen foods than to buy ingredients in bulk and prepare meals for the freezer yourself? You may pay a little more initially, but you will get more meals out of your purchase in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Space&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Can your freezer really fit that many boxes? They seem to take up a lot of room and often have lots of unnecessary extra packaging. Flat ziplock bags packed yourself may be more space efficient and decrease all of that clutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleaning Your Freezer and Starting Fresh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aida explained the facts and proceeded to give me some easy recipes to make the change not only for my frozen foods, but for EVERYTHING! Now, when there's time, I set aside a free Sunday afternoon to cook like a mofo. My fridge is stocked for weeks with good, healthy food that's ready in minutes, and I feel better about what I'm serving my kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took the four most common "boxed foods" found in homes with kids, and decided to share Aida's recipes with you to begin the un-processing process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-28-ChickenTenders.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-28-ChickenTenders.jpg" width="400" height="400" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo credit: Lisel Ashlock, Creative Director for Moomah the Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;a href="http://moomah.com/themagazine/gluten-free-chicken-tenders" target="_hplink"&gt;chicken tenders&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://moomah.com/themagazine/gluten-free-fish-sticks" target="_hplink"&gt;fish sticks&lt;/a&gt; take less than ten minutes to prepare, package and throw in the freezer. What's better is that they also only take ten minutes to cook when you need them. Aida has even provided the ingredients for some low fat sauces, in case you really want to step it up and get fancy! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-28-FishSticks.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-28-FishSticks.jpg" width="400" height="400" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo credit: Lisel Ashlock, Creative Director for Moomah the Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;a href="http://moomah.com/themagazine/gluten-free-macncheese" target="_hplink"&gt;macaroni and cheese&lt;/a&gt; is so simple and so unbelievably delicious that you will never turn back to boxed pasta again. Best thing about it? You will totally fool your kids into eating vegetables in this dish -- they will not have a clue that the orange they see is not just delicious cheese, but is infused with butternut squash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-28-MacnCheese.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-28-MacnCheese.jpg" width="400" height="400" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo credit: Lisel Ashlock, Creative Director for Moomah the Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finally, it's dessert time and your kids (and you!) are going to go crazy for the &lt;a href="http://moomah.com/themagazine/fruit-pops" target="_hplink"&gt;yummy yogurt popsicles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-28-IMG_0639.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-28-IMG_0639.jpg" width="400" height="400" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo credit: Lisel Ashlock, Creative Director for Moomah the Magazine&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good news is that all of these recipes are GLUTEN-FREE... not that your kids will ever know it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://moomah.com/themagazine/unprocess-your-freezer/" target="_hplink"&gt;Get Spring Cleaning now with all of these delicious recipes now at Moomah the Magazine.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Girl Told She'd Never Walk Again Takes First Steps Since Being Shot</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/thusha-kamaleswaran-paralyzed-shot-walks_n_2973840.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2973840</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T21:24:06Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T21:24:08Z</updated>
    
    <summary>They told her she'd never walk again, but a young girl from south London wouldn't take "no" for an answer. In an exclusive interview with...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kavitha-a-davidson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;They told her she'd never walk again, but a young girl from south London wouldn't take "no" for an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an exclusive interview with the Mirror, &lt;a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/thusha-kamaleswaran-gang-shooting-victim-1781370" target="_hplink"&gt;seven-year-old Thusha Kamaleswaran&lt;/a&gt; proudly revealed that she has taken her first steps since being shot in a store in south London two years ago. Using the help of a harness and treadmill, she defied previous prognoses, determined to get out of her wheelchair on her own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I want to dance around and play basketball with my friends," &lt;a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/thusha-kamaleswaran-gang-shooting-victim-1781370" target="_hplink"&gt;Thusha told the Mirror&lt;/a&gt;. "I want to travel around the world, too."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March 2011, &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-london-19718249" target="_hplink"&gt;Thusha was caught in the crossfire&lt;/a&gt; of a gang fight that broke out in her uncle's store. A stray bullet landed in her spine, stopping her heart twice and paralyzing her from the waist down. According to the BBC, after a year of surgeries and extended hospital stays, doctors gave her a slim chance of ever walking again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shooting of the then-five-year-old sparked an outpouring of support. The detectives who worked on her case set up a &lt;a href="http://www.thushafund.co.uk/" target="_hplink"&gt;trust to help cover her medical expenses&lt;/a&gt;, participating in fundraising challenges that have &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2012/09/24/police-raise-200000-for-f_n_1909289.html" target="_hplink"&gt;raised at least £185,000&lt;/a&gt;, the Press Association reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after she returned home from the hospital in May 2012, ITV &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2012/04/05/thusha-kamaleswaran-six-year-old-shot-stockwell_n_1406060.html" target="_hplink"&gt;caught up with Thusha and her family.&lt;/a&gt; The girl's family had made the conscious decision not to tell her the doctors' grim prognosis in order to keep the girl's hope alive. In the heartbreaking segment above, Thusha spoke of her desire to dance again and return to school, not knowing just how slim a chance she had at ever standing on her own two feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps being kept in the dark about her condition aided Thusha in her recovery. Ever optimistic, she has been undergoing &lt;a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/thusha-kamaleswaran-gang-shooting-victim-1781370" target="_hplink"&gt;intense physiotherapy&lt;/a&gt; for the past two years and performs hours of rehabilitation exercises every day, the Mirror reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Thusha never gives up, she works so hard," her older brother, Thushan, &lt;a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/thusha-kamaleswaran-gang-shooting-victim-1781370" target="_hplink"&gt;told the Mirror&lt;/a&gt;. "Nothing will stop her from achieving her goal."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061353/thumbs/s-THUSHA-KAMALESWARAN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>What A Drawer Full Of Mementos Reminds Me About My Daughter's Short Life</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/mourning-loss-of-a-child_n_2964416.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2964416</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T21:20:57Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T21:26:32Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Written by Suzanne Leigh for Brain, Child Months before my elder daughter was diagnosed with a malignant brain tumor, I started leaving brief handwritten notes...</summary>
    <author>
        <name/>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/teri-dangelo/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.brainchildmag.com/2013/03/message-in-a-lunchbox/" target="_hplink"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Suzanne Leigh for Brain, Child &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Months before my elder daughter was diagnosed with a malignant brain tumor, I started leaving brief handwritten notes at the bottom of her lunchbox. “I love you, Sweetheart, and I can’t wait to see you after school!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I retrieved her lunchbox after school, the note remained seemingly untouched along with remnants of a sandwich, tangerine peel and uneaten baby carrots. My lusty 7-year-old was in too much of a hurry to eat her lunch and join her friends for tag or tetherball than to respond to a message from mom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Periodically I continued the lunchbox notes. Someday, I told myself, Natasha would grow up and remember those tender messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At age 10, when Natasha’s brain tumor had started to metastasize and her prognosis was very poor, she started to respond to my lunchbox messages. “I love you SO much and I miss you so much. You are my best friend,” she wrote on the back of my own message to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her message was painful in its poignancy. I knew her closeness to me correlated to the severity of her diagnosis. In the last two years of her life while her healthy peers would accept a perfunctory kiss at best at school pick-up time, Natasha would put both arms around my neck. While they campaigned for weekend slumber parties with BFFs and mom-free time at the mall, my fragile child always wanted her parents close by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Natasha started writing letters to her parents, younger sister and other loved ones. These were fervent declarations of devotion, often accompanied by moody watercolors of rainbows, angels, vivid pastels of wild animals or warm family portraits with dad’s arms encircling the three of us. In hindsight those letter and pictures were her way of telling us that she knew her life was limited and she was grateful to those that she loved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A week after Natasha had passed away, I realized that I had never written her a letter. It was overdue.  I wrote of emotions that were too intense, too cumbersome for her to have heard when she was alive. I told her about the day she was born when I had placed my cheek on her soft head and whispered: My heart beats for you, Natasha. I told her that I had never experienced real fear until I had become her mother. (Sure I had been scared, but ultimately the worst that could happen was that I would die. As a mother, losing that precious new life incited far greater fear.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told her that I’d have done anything, anything to have saved her life. That I had wished so hard that the brain tumor bullet had hit me, instead of her; that my own rude health disgusted rather than delighted me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I told her that she had taught me to love without limits and that my infinite love for her would carry me through the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I placed the letter in a drawer where I keep her mementos. Inside is a manila envelope containing the golden brown wavy hair she had lost following full brain radiation. In another envelope is the blonde hair she’d lost two years previously due to chemo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Story continues below)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;img alt="notforreuse" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1058840/original.jpg" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
At times I am drawn magnetically to these two envelopes; their contents cause anguish, but they are a tangible part of her that I get to keep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deeper in this drawer are other emblems of her life:  her letter to Santa (“Please may I have an American Girl doll for Christmas. I hope you are doing well and are not too cold”). And a letter to the tooth fairy requesting that she wake her up so they can talk.  There are journal entries recounting happy carefree times, princess birthday parties, trick or treating and beach vacations with friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mourn Natasha, I am learning that when the pain is acute, I need to focus on those items at the bottom of the drawer. They reflect the time before we entered Cancerland and the all-too-short period before she recurred, when the word “cure” would be tentatively mentioned. I need to remember that while her brief life is defined by disease, it is also defined by joy and innocence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My surviving daughter is 8. A year ago, I started to leave messages in lunchbox. “I hope you are having a good time,” I wrote. “I can’t wait to see you after school.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I picked up Marissa, the message was still there, along with the detritus of her lunch. “Did you read my message?” I asked. “Yes, but I was too busy to reply.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that my surviving child with her pink cheeks and flawless health history will always be too busy to reply to the messages in her lunchbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to read more thought-provoking essays? &lt;a href="http://www.brainchildmag.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to Brain, Child: The Magazine for Thinking Mothers and see why we’ve been receiving awards for literary excellence since 2000.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1058823/thumbs/s-NOTFORREUSE-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>9 Things You Need To Survive Your Split</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/divorce-care-package_n_2973446.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2973446</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T21:16:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T00:56:34Z</updated>
    
    <summary>If there's ever a time you need a little distraction in your life, it's during the divorce process. That's why we launched our Divorce Care...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If there's ever a time you need a little distraction in your life, it's during the divorce process. That's why we launched our &lt;strong&gt;Divorce Care Package&lt;/strong&gt; series. With each post, we'll show you what things -- books, movies, recipes -- helped others relieve stress in the midst of divorce, in the hopes that a few of their picks will serve you well, too. Want to share what got you through your divorce? Email us at &lt;a href="mailto:divorce@huffingtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;divorce@huffingtonpost.com&lt;/a&gt; or tweet &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPost Divorce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can a woman depend on to get her through a divorce? According to &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jennifer-ball/" target="_hplink"&gt;HuffPost blogger Jennifer Ball,&lt;/a&gt; it's simple: a good dog, the love of your kids, Nora Ephron's highly relatable work -- &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;this guy: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="jon hamm" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061090/thumbs/h-JON-HAMM-320x320.jpg?6" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sigh. Yeah, we get that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, Ball, who blogs regularly about post-split life at &lt;a href="http://happyhausfrau.blogspot.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;The Happy Hausfrau&lt;/a&gt;, shares how each item helped her get through her divorce. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--288756--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061247/thumbs/s-KIDART-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
