<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>These Piñata Eggs Hold A Fun Easter Surprise</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/easter-ideas-pinata-eggs_n_2945141.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2945141</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T12:38:27Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T12:38:30Z</updated>
    
    <summary>We can't think of a better way to spend the holiday!</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rain-embuscado/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;We love to put a new spin on holiday traditions. Like our &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/19/easter-ideas-alternative-egg-designs_n_2901928.html" target="_hplink"&gt;egg decorating designs&lt;/a&gt;, for example, which are fun alternatives to the usual dyeing method. So when we came across a fun activity that replaces the standard hunt, we were absolutely thrilled. Today's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/easter-2013" target="_hplink"&gt;Easter idea&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://asubtlerevelry.com" target="_hplink"&gt;A Subtle Revelry&lt;/a&gt; shows us how &lt;a href="http://asubtlerevelry.com/pinata-eggs" target="_hplink"&gt;to make egg piñatas&lt;/a&gt; that are just as fun to put together as they are to smash. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="easter ideas" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053953/thumbs/a-EASTER-IDEAS-640x468.jpg?15" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="http://asubtlerevelry.com/pinata-eggs" target="_hplink"&gt;A Subtle Revelry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our favorite part? These pretty decorations are filled with confetti which makes for a beautiful explosion of color when they are busted open. To learn how to make this simple craft, head on over to &lt;a href="http://asubtlerevelry.com/pinata-eggs" target="_hplink"&gt;A Subtle Revelry's website&lt;/a&gt;. And if you want even more &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/easter-2013" target="_hplink"&gt;Easter ideas&lt;/a&gt;, check out our our board on &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/easter-at-home/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--286961--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have a home story idea or tip? Email us at homesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053953/thumbs/s-EASTER-IDEAS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: 66 Inspirational Quotes About Marriage Equality</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/gay-marriage-quotes_n_2947825.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2947825</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T12:37:54Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T12:41:00Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Two cases will go before the Supreme Court regarding the legality of same-sex marriage in the United States, one on March 26 and the other...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Noah Michelson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/noah-michelson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Two cases will go before the Supreme Court regarding the legality of same-sex marriage in the United States, one on March 26 and the other the following day, March 27.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, the Justices will hear arguments involving Proposition 8, the legislation which made gay marriage illegal in California in 2008. And on Wednesday, the Court will consider the constitutionality of the Defense of Marriage Act, which was signed into law in 1996 and federally defines marriage as the legal union of one man and one woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've seen an incredible amount of progress on the marriage equality front in the last 10 years -- including a huge push that came in just the last few months when same-sex marriage was made legal in Washington, Maryland and Maine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we nervously watch and wait to see how the Supreme Court rules on these two historic cases, we thought now was a good time to showcase some inspiring quotes about the fight for marriage equality. We've chosen 66 great quotes from queer people and their allies and featured them in the slideshow below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a favorite quote that isn't featured? Tell us in the comments section, along with your thoughts on what you think is going to happen regarding the Prop 8 and DOMA cases.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1054004/thumbs/s-GAY-MARRIAGE-QUOTES-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Mom Of The Month: Lawyer LaShann DeArcy Hall</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/lashann-dearcy-hall_n_2935489.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2935489</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T12:23:22Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T12:16:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary> “Mommy? What are we going to do today?” Jayden Hall asks her mother, lawyer LaShann DeArcy Hall, some variation of this question every weekend...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Cumberbatch Anderson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-anderson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="matermealogo2" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/660021/original.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mommy? What are we going to do today?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jayden Hall asks her mother, lawyer LaShann DeArcy Hall, some variation of this question every weekend morning. The 5-year-old keeps a tight schedule that rivals some adults, dashing from her kindergarten class at Chapin School on the Upper East Side to dance lessons, swim classes, and play dates around the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No stranger to a packed schedule herself, DeArcy Hall relishes in being able to say, “Today, we’re just going to relax.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of counsel at Morrison Foerster, one of New York City’s most respected law firms, relaxation isn’t something DeArcy Hall gets to do a whole lot of, she admits. There are the untold hours spent working on commercial and civil litigation trials, acting primarily as a defense lawyer for a number of Fortune 500 companies. Last fall she was appointed as a commissioner for the New York State Joint Commission on Public Ethics, adding to her role as a commissioner of the New York City Taxi &amp; Limousine Commission, to which she was appointed by Mayor Michael Bloomberg. And somehow DeArcy Hall also fits in pro bono work, as well as championing diversity in the legal world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At the end of the day, it’s stressful, we work long hours, but I am doing what I love to do,” DeArcy Hall says. “I get to have a career that is the career I would choose for myself, and it’s not just one that I’m doing because I have to.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly enough it’s a career she wasn’t quite sure she wanted to pursue. Her other option may surprise you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more of &lt;a href="http://www.matermea.com/#/lashann/4574763539" target="_hplink"&gt;LaShann's story&lt;/a&gt; and meet these other fabulous mothers at &lt;a href="http://www.matermea.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;matermea.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052254/thumbs/s-LASHANN-DEARCY-HALL-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Most Awesome Thing You'll See Today</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/bear-meets-kid-wearing-bear-costume_n_2945386.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2945386</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T11:59:28Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T11:59:32Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There isn't much to say about this magical moment at the Minnesota Zoo. Maybe this little one was so excited to see the "Russia's Grizzly...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Timothy Stenovec</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/timothy-stenovec/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;There isn't much to say about this magical moment at the Minnesota Zoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe this little one was so excited to see the "Russia's Grizzly Coast" exhibit at the zoo that he or she wanted to dress up like a bear? Maybe he or she wears this everyday? Maybe the kid is actually a bear? Who knows? We just know that it's awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reddit community certainly loved it; the photo was posted on Saturday and &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/1av0bg/bear_meets_kid_in_bear_costume/" target="_hplink"&gt;has garnered nearly 800 comments&lt;/a&gt;, many of them from people sharing their own experiences at the zoo. &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/1av0bg/bear_meets_kid_in_bear_costume/c910k0v" target="_hplink"&gt;In costume&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it was going viral over the weekend, the photo isn't new, as &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/1av0bg/bear_meets_kid_in_bear_costume/c910ol6" target="_hplink"&gt;one Redditor pointed out&lt;/a&gt;. It was posted to the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MNZoo" target="_hplink"&gt;Minnesota Zoo's Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10151210909533788&amp;set=a.143699433787.112370.136257148787&amp;type=1&amp;theater" target="_hplink"&gt;most recently in October&lt;/a&gt; to promote the zoo's "HallZOOween" event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enjoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/kBLu68z"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/kBLu68z.jpg" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt; 

        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053592/thumbs/s-BEAR-MEETS-KID-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Best Airports For Kids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/the-10-best-airports-for-kids_n_2932795.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2932795</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T11:50:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T11:50:53Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Traveling is, in and of itself, no easy feat. So, adding little ones into the equation is enough to make a family want to stay...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Rebecca Dolan</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rebeccadolan/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Traveling is, in and of itself, no easy feat. So, adding little ones into the equation is enough to make a family want to stay home. We know that there are &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-belkin/the-importance-of-family-_b_2421149.html" target="_hplink"&gt;many important reasons to travel as a family&lt;/a&gt;, and some would say that &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/barbara-adam/traveling-with-kids-the-t_b_1375419.html" target="_hplink"&gt;the time is always right to do so&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the process a bit easier, the folks at travelnerd.com compiled a ranking of &lt;a href="http://www.travelnerd.com/blog/2013/travelnerd-study-worst-airports-kids/" target="_hplink"&gt;the best and worst U.S. airports for kids&lt;/a&gt;. The list is based on the number of nurseries and play areas available at each airport. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the top 10 airports for kids below. For the 10 worst, hop on over to &lt;a href="http://www.travelnerd.com/blog/2013/travelnerd-study-worst-airports-kids/" target="_hplink"&gt;travelnerd's website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For even more on traveling with kids, check out our &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tamar-lowell/traveling-with-kids-tips_b_2326259.html" target="_hplink"&gt;10 sanity-saving tips&lt;/a&gt; and advice on &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/susan-stiffelman/travel-tips_b_2160457.html" target="_hplink"&gt;how to travel with kids without falling apart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051306/thumbs/s-BEST-AIRPORTS-FOR-KIDS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Linda Joy Myers, Ph. D.: How My Life Finally Came Full Circle</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/linda-joy-myers-ph-d/parenthood-full-circle_b_2918269.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2918269</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T11:50:08Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T12:05:33Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I come from a legacy of mothers who left their mark upon me, etching profound disturbances, carving hollows of loss. I was determined to be different, but there's something about wounding deep below the surface that's not easy to escape. I knew when I was nine that my mother and grandmother were not what I wanted to be, but the webs they wove caught me anyway.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Linda Joy Myers, Ph. D.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/linda-joy-myers-ph-d/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I come from a legacy of mothers who left their mark upon me, etching profound disturbances, carving hollows of loss. I was determined to be different, but there's something about wounding deep below the surface that's not easy to escape. I knew when I was nine that my mother and grandmother were not what I wanted to be, but the webs they wove caught me anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's easy to see them in my mind, my mother and grandmother, each of them always with a dreamy look in their eyes. In their photographs they exemplify another era, the thirties and forties, vintage glamour with perfect makeup and sleek silk dresses. My grandmother wore a boa flung over her shoulder when she graced the Captain's table on ships to England. The idealized image of their glamour is the way I prefer to see them, but the truth was that they could be as terrifying as a lightning storm, the thunder of their rage and anger that would only end with their deaths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wildness would blow in whenever my mother arrived on the train from Chicago to visit us, having left me to be raised by her mother when I was four. I lived with my grandmother in Oklahoma, where we'd moved when I was six, my small body pressed by the insistent plains wind. The wind and great space of the plains incited a longing that never had words, etching me with a feeling that to this day comes upon me when I land in the Midwest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a yearly ritual as I grew up, I'd stand by the tracks at the Perry, Oklahoma, train station, watching the great white eye of the train hover in the silvery horizon, suspended in time and space. The train would burst into the station like an out-of-control animal, and time would stop when a striking woman with dark hair and eyes, her heels clicking on the bricks, approached me and my already-simmering grandmother. The held breath of the moment wouldn't erupt until later when we arrived at the small frame house -- mother and daughter circling around each other, seeming to be searching for the best place to strike. Gray cigarette smoke filled the house and the sound of their voices rose to the ceiling as I tried to think of a way to stop them. But how do you stop a storm?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passionate to understand my mothers, I soaked up history as I lay in a featherbed with my great-grandmother Blanche. I was eight and she was 80. Born in 1873, she seemed to know the history of everything. Her teeth in a jar by the bed, she told me about baking bread in a wood cook stove, feeding a gang of harvesters, growing a garden and canning for winter. "I married your Gram's father on a snowy New Year's Day 1894," she told me. "Two months later he died." She fell silent then, and in that moment I understood the dark moods that fell over my grandmother. "Poor thing, your Mam Jo'tine was left behind when she was a baby. Never was right, Lulu off galavanting with her fancy clothes."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She shook her head, her grey curls rasping on the pillow. I understood then the tense moments as the train approached, the smoky storms when mother visited us -- their history trailing behind them. I became a sleuth, trying to understand what happened and how could it be changed. The seeds had been sown for my life path: psychological sleuth, therapist, and ultimately writer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'll never be like them," we all say about our families, but the power of patterning rubs grooves into our psyches -- we're shaped by childhood no matter how much we try to break out of it. It's fair to say that growing up without my parents shaped my inner psyche, despite the smile I put on my face to greet the world and how I'd try to cover up my shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After three marriages -- which I came to understand were based on the unresolved issues of abandonment by both parents -- I was a single parent of three children, including a daughter. Sometimes I would be overtaken by memories of loss, grief and anger while I wrestled with how to be a different kind of mother. Through therapy and the compassionate confrontations by someone who could see the "me" hidden in the mess of family history, I began to wake up to my life. My therapist told me to write about what happened, to capture the stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later I became a therapist, and continued to try to understand my legacy. I learned to practice awareness, to sit with uncomfortable feelings. I had always believed that if my grandmother and mother could see beyond the hurts, if they could only listen and tune into each other, they would find peace. But 10 years before Gram died, she paid Mother several thousand dollars to never return, and they never saw each other again. When Gram was buried in the Iowa cemetery, I made a pact with myself: I will NOT allow such a terrible ending with my mother when the time comes, no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through writing my memoir, Don't Call Me Mother, I found my voice, along with new ways to see my wounded mothers. I wrote a story about my grandmother as a 20-year-old girl whose first baby was stillborn, tuning into her grief, wanting to learn more about her as a young woman. By stepping into her shoes, I found compassion for who she was, and who she was trying to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched genealogical records about my mother's early years -- I wanted to know when her mother left, and what happened to her as a little girl. I wanted to know how my mother could deny to all her friends that she had a daughter and grandchildren -- a wound that would be cut anew each year. I kept trying to get her to see how smart I was, that I was a valuable person, that my children were beautiful, but she scuttled us through back hallways the few times I brought the children to visit her in Chicago, and on her deathbed she screamed, "Don't you dare tell them you're my daughter."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I kept the promise I'd made to myself so long ago. I was with Mother at her bedside in the last few days of her life, when the brain tumor no longer allowed her to speak, our hands grasping, tears flowing for both of us. In that moment forgiveness flooded my heart as I saw all my mothers -- my great-grandmother Blanche, and Gram -- floating near us, well-intentioned but broken. At my mother's death, the curse lifted from my body, leaving me freer than I'd ever felt before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got home to be with my daughter, for a moment it seemed that I was getting to know her for the first time, able to see her more clearly, as if I'd always seen her through the fogged lenses of my own brokenness. But despite any promises to myself about being a different kind of mother, somehow I'd been unable to see anything but her wrong choices, her faults. One day, consumed in anger about something, I just stopped, suddenly seeing myself from the outside in, seeing my grandmother yelling at my mother. There it was -- the pattern I had promised myself I'd break -- being played out despite how sure I was that I could be different from them. It felt like an engine out of control inside me, so powerful was the urge to criticize her. I stopped shouting -- something kicked in and I stood, confused, angry and curious. How could I change what was happening? I had to do it now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched inside me for the love I knew I had for my daughter. I had to dig down past the fears her behavior engendered in me, and my own guilt for all I had done wrong: not enough boundaries -- I'd been overcontrolled, so I'd become lenient, which was supposed to be better. And yet it was anything but. There was guilt, too, a lot of it for being so absent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remembered her birth -- the amazing moment of awe when she came out of my body, a little girl who was passionate, who had her own will, who had a voice. A girl who hugged and kissed, a girl who wanted to be with me, though I didn't quite know how to be with her completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"This is my daughter," I reminded myself, "and she needs me to find my way to her, to accept her." I asked myself how I could love her even if I disapproved of her. How could I speak with her in a way that would allow a gap between what I didn't like and what might be possible --unlike what Gram and mother did? I began to practice this, like a meditation, controlling my disapproval, and as I did, it became easier between us, though we had many more moments of struggle as we created a new kind of relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she married a man who was good to her, who came from a large affectionate Italian family, she settled into learning her own way to be a woman and eventually a mother, which meant staying at home with the children more, making cupcakes for birthdays -- things I didn't do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her daughter has my middle name, Joy, and I was there when she uncurled out of her mother's body. Six-year-old Zoe and I have a special bond. Hearing her tell me how special it is to have me stay with them makes me feel that I belong with a family for the first time. And when the three of us curl up together on the couch, my daughter's dark eyes gleam with contentment.  There are times when she looks like my mother; her hands are my mother's hands. Sometimes she catches a look on my face and says, "I know this is special for you, Mom."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes during these moments, I gaze at them, seeing beyond the present moment, seeing my beautiful Gram and Mother at an earlier time, when life stretched out with hope that things could be different. How I wish they could have had such simple joy as I have now. When Zoe, Amanda and I scratch each other's backs or hold hands, my body soaks up the visceral proof that I did it -- I broke the pattern, and my reward is to be blissed out in their embraces, all of us freed from the shackles of the past, free to be simply happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="border-bottom:solid 1px;text-transform:uppercase;font-size:10px;font-weight:bold;font-family:sans-serif;"&gt;Earlier on Huff/Post50:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--232745--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051613/thumbs/s-PARENTHOOD-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'Revenge': Mason Treadwell Has Victoria Bombshell</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/revenge-mason-treadwell-victoria-secret-video_n_2946675.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2946675</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T07:15:21Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T10:38:14Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It turns out everybody's in the revenge game on "Revenge." Emily's former foster brother -- back when she was Amanda -- was all about getting...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jason-hughes/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;It turns out everybody's in the revenge game on "&lt;a href="http://tvrecaps.ew.com/recap/revenge-season-2-episode-17/" target="_hplink"&gt;Revenge&lt;/a&gt;." Emily's former foster brother -- back when she was Amanda -- was all about getting a very public revenge on the foster mother who abused and tortured all of the children in her care. He was even willing to exploit the Graysons to do so, though making an enemy of them may not be the wisest choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But just as one foster child was folding out of the story, an unexpected new one cropped up. It was during a chat with Mason Treadwell in prison. It turned out that her foster mother had sold all of David Clarke's unread letters to his daughter Amanda to Mason. Understandably, Emily wanted to know what they said, as Mason insisted they burned in that little fire she set at his place. He could be lying about that, but it does give him a tiny bit of leverage over her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mason did reveal something very intriguing, though. Victoria Grayson had another son, and that child wound up in the foster care system. "I imagine you’ll exploit this fresh little morsel with your usual flair?" Mason said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You can’t even begin to imagine," Emily responded with a smile. "&lt;a href="http://www.buddytv.com/articles/revenge/post-3-49625.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;Emily's evil smile at this little nugget of information&lt;/a&gt; is a beauty to behold," wrote Buddy TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celebuzz was excited about &lt;a href="http://www.celebuzz.com/2013-03-25/revenge-recap-fires-and-foster-care-secrets/" target="_hplink"&gt;the story potential with Victoria's mystery child&lt;/a&gt;. They wrote, "Let’s hope he has Daniel’s smile but his mother’s cunning. In fact, let’s hope he’s been planning his own Revenge plan all this time. That would certainly spice things up!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find out who's plotting against who as "Revenge" rolls on, Sundays at 9 p.m. ET on ABC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053715/thumbs/s-REVENGE-MASON-SECRET-130324-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Onion Slams Dems For Backing Off Assault Weapons</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/24/the-onion-calls-democrats-cowering-sack-of-shit_n_2945073.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2945073</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-24T19:14:19Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T10:06:39Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The Onion probably won't be apologizing for this one any time soon. In its latest week in review, the satirical news outlet jabbed Democrats for...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Carol Hartsell</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/carol-hartsell/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;The Onion probably won't be &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/25/the-onion-apologizes-for-quvenzhane-wallis-oscar-tweet_n_2759400.html" target="_hplink"&gt;apologizing&lt;/a&gt; for this one any time soon.  In its latest &lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/video/proud-time-to-be-a-cowering-sack-of-shit-as-democr,31778/" target="_hplink"&gt;week in review&lt;/a&gt;, the satirical news outlet jabbed Democrats for &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/19/obama-gun-reform_n_2909590.html" target="_hplink"&gt;caving on the assault weapons ban&lt;/a&gt; in its gun control package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It is once again a proud time to be a cowering sack of shit," the fake report proclaims. It goes on to mockingly praise Dems for failing to "stand up for comprehensive gun control legislation that could save thousands of innocent lives."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the NSFW clip above and let us know what you think. Do Democrats deserve all the criticism they can get for not pursuing the ban?&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053477/thumbs/s-THEONIONDEMOCRATSCOWERING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>A Royal Response To Mom's Plea To Clean The Bathroom</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/24/my-mom-told-me-to-clean-t_n_2944577.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2944577</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-24T17:22:09Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-24T17:22:11Z</updated>
    
    <summary>This is what happened when one Redditor's mom said to "clean the bathroom like the Queen of England is visiting." Bloody brilliant. (via Imgur and...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Elizabeth Perle</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/elizabeth-perle/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;This is what happened when &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/1awke8/my_mom_told_me_to_clean_the_bathroom_like_the/" target="_hplink"&gt;one Redditor's&lt;/a&gt; mom said to "clean the bathroom like the Queen of England is visiting." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bloody brilliant.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;iframe class="imgur-album" width="100%" height="550" frameborder="0" src="http://imgur.com/a/hwi1W/embed"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(via&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/a/hwi1W" target="_hplink"&gt; Imgur&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://TastefullyOffensive.tumblr.com" target="_hplink"&gt;TastefullyOffensive.tumblr.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053395/thumbs/s-BATHROOMQUEEN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>What You're Losing If You Don't Unplug</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/24/your-phone-vs-your-heart_n_2944370.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2944370</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-24T16:08:19Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-24T16:08:19Z</updated>
    
    <summary>CAN you remember the last time you were in a public space in America and didn’t notice that half the people around you were bent...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The New York Times</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-mustich/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;CAN you remember the last time you were in a public space in America and didn’t notice that half the people around you were bent over a digital screen, thumbing a connection to somewhere else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us are well aware of the convenience that instant electronic access provides. Less has been said about the costs. Research that my colleagues and I have just completed, to be published in a forthcoming issue of Psychological Science, suggests that one measurable toll may be on our biological capacity to connect with other people.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053359/thumbs/s-UNPLUGGING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>PHOTO: Jessica Simpson's Pregnant Look Is Gorgeous</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/24/jessica-simpsons-pregnant-outfit-photo_n_2944228.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2944228</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-24T14:45:32Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-24T15:27:33Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Talk about a family affair: Jessica Simpson showed off a gorgeous pregnant look Saturday at a mall in Charlotte, N.C., accompanied by sister Ashlee Simpson,...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Youyoung Lee</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/youyoung-lee/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Talk about a family affair: Jessica Simpson showed off a gorgeous pregnant look Saturday at a mall in Charlotte, N.C., accompanied by sister Ashlee Simpson, fiancé Eric Johnson and daughter Maxwell. The 32-year-old"Fashion Star" judge wore a floor-length burgundy dress from her eponymous label and a smart-fitting black jacket that complemented her visibly growing baby bump. (You taking notes, Kim Kardashian?) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The expecting mom made news recently when she &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/07/jessica-simpson-baby-gender-video_n_2826447.html" target="_hplink"&gt;accidentally the gender of her second child&lt;/a&gt; on "Jimmy Kimmel Live!". "I never knew a wiener could actually make me nauseous," she said. "Well, I guess I just told the whole world that I’m having a boy!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="jessica simpson pregnant" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053313/thumbs/o-JESSICA-SIMPSON-PREGNANT-570.jpg?5" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="jessica simpson" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053327/thumbs/o-JESSICA-SIMPSON-570.jpg?2" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053313/thumbs/s-JESSICA-SIMPSON-PREGNANT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Melissa Sher: The Parenting Advice I Wish I'd Heard Sooner</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/melissa-sher/never-ever-ever-getting-back-together_b_2906756.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2906756</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-24T14:43:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-24T14:43:52Z</updated>
    
    <summary>"Remember, you're still you." That was the parenting advice I heard given to a mother-to-be last week. I loved it. It was perfect. I wished someone had told it to me when I was a new mom.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Melissa Sher</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/melissa-sher/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;"Remember, you're still you." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was the parenting advice I heard given to a mother-to-be last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You're still you."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved it. It was perfect. I wished someone had told it to me when I was a new mom. Because in the early days of being a parent, it's easy to forget. And in the not-so-early days of being a parent, it's easy to forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eight years ago when I came home from the hospital with my brand-spanking-new son, I did not remember, "You're still you." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the time you could say, "Push! Push! One more big push!" I became someone else. I became somebody's mother and life was different. There was the lack of sleep. And lack of showering. There was the new way I ate my meals while standing up. There was the new baby who did not always act -- shocker! -- like a bundle of joy. There was having almost no time &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; myself but having too much time &lt;em&gt;by&lt;/em&gt; myself. There was even my new vocation: all-you-can-eat milk buffet. And, sure, every buffet is all-you-can-eat but you get the point. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My old life and I were a Taylor Swift song. We were never, ever, ever getting back together. I'd go to the bank to deposit a check and by the time I bobbed my way to the front of the line with my son tucked into the Baby Bjorn, I'd forget why I was there. I would go to dinner with friends and struggle to say something interesting and non-baby related. I'd once been a movie buff but watched the Oscars and fell asleep before the award for Best Picture was given out. (OK, I don't blame myself for that one. How hard is it to find a decent host for a show watched by a gazillion people?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weeks passed. Months passed. I'm really sorry to say this but years passed. And then, one day and two kids more, I felt like myself again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here's the catch: feeling like myself again didn't mean that I was the same person I was before I had kids. I was not. I had changed. Just like I changed when I started high school and college and the day I discovered tweezing my eyebrows. Because we're all constantly changing. And, when we become parents we change a whole hell of a lot. As Taylor Swift once sang, you can't step into the same river twice. (Are you sure she didn't sing that? Well, she should. Those would be great breakup lyrics.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even though I've changed since becoming a mother, I feel like myself once again. But better. I'm more patient. I'm calmer. I'm less selfish. I appreciate the little things more. A lot more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the happiest moments I can remember was because of the little things. It was spring, and I was taking my three kids to Dairy Queen. On the drive, I turned up the volume on the radio and sang along. (It was not a Taylor Swift song but don't you wish -- for continuity -- that it had been?) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I love you more today than yesterday, but not as much as tomorrow." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sang loud. I sang as loud as I could. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I love you more today than yesterday. But darling not as much as tomorrow." And as I was driving in my -- yep -- minivan, I thought about how true the lyrics were when it came to my children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so happy on that drive. The weather was beautiful. And so were my kids. And so was life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, two of my three kids started begging me to stop singing. And the only reason my third didn't is because he was a baby and didn't yet talk. "Stop singing! Stop! Stop singing, Mommy!" &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turned out that they too were just being themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053266/thumbs/s-PARENTING-ADVICE-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Can You Guess What These Garlands Are Made From? </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/24/easter-ideas-diy-paper-egg-garland_n_2933455.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2933455</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-24T14:40:33Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-24T14:42:29Z</updated>
    
    <summary>They add just the right pop of Easter colors.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rain-embuscado/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Finding unique and inspiring decorations for any holiday can be a bit of a challenge, especially when we find that the  store-bought variety are a little tired. So why not make some decorations of your own? Today's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/easter-2013" target="_hplink"&gt;Easter idea&lt;/a&gt;, which was designed by &lt;a href="http://www.modernparentsmessykids.com" target="_hplink"&gt;Modern Parents Messy Kids&lt;/a&gt;, is the perfect project to dress up your home for the upcoming festivities. Their &lt;a href="http://www.modernparentsmessykids.com/2011/03/diy-paint-chip-easter-garland.html" target="_hplink"&gt;DIY paint chip Easter garland&lt;/a&gt; also serves as a brilliant repurposing idea for all those leftover samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="easter ideas" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053275/thumbs/s-EASTER-IDEAS-large640.jpg?15" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.modernparentsmessykids.com/2011/03/diy-paint-chip-easter-garland.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Photo by Modern Parents Messy Kids &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from how easy this beautiful craft is to make, we're huge fans of the idea that the color combinations we can use to make our eggs are virtually endless. For more photos and details about making this craft, be sure to head over to &lt;a href="http://www.modernparentsmessykids.com/2011/03/diy-paint-chip-easter-garland.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Modern Parents, Messy Kids' website&lt;/a&gt;. And if you want even more &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/easter-2013" target="_hplink"&gt;Easter ideas&lt;/a&gt;, check out our our board on &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/easter-at-home/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--286961--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have a home story idea or tip? Email us at homesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053275/thumbs/s-EASTER-IDEAS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Prevent These From Becoming Super Gross</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/24/kitchen-sponges-cleaning-tip_n_2939441.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2939441</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-24T14:28:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-24T14:48:01Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There's no denying that after a while, kitchen sponges can become pretty nasty. Because they're always wet, germs tend to build up and before you...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/michelle-manetti/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;There's no denying that after a while, kitchen sponges can become pretty nasty. Because they're always wet, &lt;a href="https://brightnest.com/posts/kitchen-sponge-vs-toilet-seat-which-has-more-germs" target="_hplink"&gt;germs tend to build up&lt;/a&gt; and before you know it, they've become moldy and smelly. But one Reddit user found a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/cleaning" target="_hplink"&gt;cleaning tip&lt;/a&gt; you can try to help &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/DIY/comments/fj60u/the_simplest_diy_i_ever_did_so_proud_of_myself/" target="_hplink"&gt;keep sponges dry and mildew-free&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Churnopol uploaded a photo of the scrubber attached to an office binder clip. This device holds the sponge upright, preventing it from sitting in water and allowing it to air dry pretty fast. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/5F2Ar"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/5F2Ar.jpg" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Photo by &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/DIY/comments/fj60u/the_simplest_diy_i_ever_did_so_proud_of_myself/" target="_hplink"&gt;churnopol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is definitely a clever way to help keep sponges from becoming gross and unusable. And if you're looking to &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/09/19/how-to-clean-and-deodorize-a-sponge_n_1897114.html" target="_hplink"&gt;really clean and deodorize one of your own&lt;/a&gt;, you can soak it in lemon juice and water. Then, place it in the microwave for about one minute, and that should do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through our slideshow to see more unique cleaning tips. And be sure to &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/DIY/comments/fj60u/the_simplest_diy_i_ever_did_so_proud_of_myself/" target="_hplink"&gt;head over to Reddit&lt;/a&gt; for more information. &lt;a href="http://lifehacker.com/5768098/keep-your-kitchen-sponges-dry-and-grime+free-with-binder-clips" target="_hplink"&gt;Hat tip to Life Hacker&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--259485--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have a home story idea or tip? Email us at homesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053286/thumbs/s-CLEANING-TIP-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Parenting.com: Helping My Daughter Find Her Own Voice</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/parentingcom/finding-her-own-voice_b_2915939.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2915939</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-24T14:09:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-24T14:09:39Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Implementation of assistive tech can be thwarted by the most basic and heartbreaking of obstacles: the desire to be like everyone else.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Parenting.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/parentingcom/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Robert Rummel-Hudson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National Public Radio&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/health/2013/03/11/173816690/new-voices-for-the-voiceless-synthetic-speech-gets-an-upgrade" target="_hplink"&gt; recently broadcast &lt;/a&gt;a story about Samantha Grimaldo, a 17-year-old girl with Perisylvian syndrome, another name for the &lt;a href="http://www.parenting.com/blogs/special-needs-blog/robert-rummel-hudson/special-needs-parenting-schuyler?src=syn&amp;dom=HuffPo" target="_hplink"&gt;same neurological disorder &lt;/a&gt;that my daughter Schuyler was born with. The similarities don't end there; indeed, as my wife pointed out, Schuyler and Samantha even look eerily alike. But it is in the manifestation of their disorder where they have the most in common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samantha Grimaldo is unable to speak, at least in a manner that is generally understandable. To communicate, she uses speech technology very similar to Schuyler's. For years, they actually used the same dedicated speech device; my daughter recognized it immediately in the photo. Now, like Schuyler, she uses an iPad to produce spoken language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And like Schuyler, she doesn't like using the voice if she can avoid doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plus: &lt;a href="http://www.parenting.com/blogs/special-needs-blog/special-needs-schuyler?src=syn&amp;dom=HuffPo" target="_hplink"&gt;Meet Schuyler, Monster Slayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of their reasons are similar. In the interview, Samantha describes the voice as "weird" and "older." Schuyler has often said that using her speech device causes other people to look at her strangely. Samantha and Schuyler are self-conscious about using their speech devices. Both teenaged girls have difficulty squaring the alien voices that emerge from their technological helpers with their own sense of identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's one of the dirty secrets of assistive voice technology. There are a million good reasons to use it, and the innovations advance remarkably every day. But as one noted assistive tech innovator pointed out to me as we sat in an exhibition hall full of the latest technology, "Every piece of assistive tech equipment in this room says the same thing to the casual observer. It says 'I have a disability.'" &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plus: &lt;a href="http://www.parenting.com/blogs/special-needs-blog/special-needs-parenting-schuyler?src=syn&amp;dom=HuffPo" target="_hplink"&gt;The Difference of Special Needs Children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementation of assistive tech can be thwarted by the most basic and heartbreaking of obstacles: the desire to be like everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NPR story follows Northeastern University speech scientist Rupal Patel as she works to develop an electronic voice to replace the generic ones on Samantha's iPad, a new voice based on the actual sounds that Samantha produces naturally. The voices that currently exist are actually pretty diverse. If you're imagining the sound of Stephen Hawking's electronic voice or the computer that gives you the time and temperature over the phone, you might be surprised at what's out there. But the fact remains that no matter which voice modules Samantha or Schuyler select, they're not their own. And they know it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plus: &lt;a href="http://www.parenting.com/blogs/special-needs-blog/brian-braiker/blind-boy-cane?src=syn&amp;dom=HuffPo" target="_hplink"&gt;The Bravest Steps for One Boy with Special Needs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might seem like a simple thing. It is perhaps the simplest of issues in the complex world of synthetic speech prosthesis. But for users, particularly those who can hear the pitch and tone of their own voices but are unable to produce usable speech, it is a frustrating and deeply personal issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One morning a few years ago, Schuyler pulled me aside and told me that she wanted to change the voice on her speech device. "I want big girl voice," she said in her device's vaguely robotic child's voice. And so we spent the better part of an hour going through the choices available to her, picking one and then tweaking the pitch and the speed with which it spoke. Meticulously, carefully and with much consideration, we found what was going to pass for her voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, I hope she finds it for real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="2013-03-21-schulyer4.jpeg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-21-schulyer4.jpeg" width="300" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;More from Parenting.com:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.parenting.com/gallery/best-childrens-museums?src=syn&amp;dom=HuffPo" target="_hplink"&gt;The Best Children's Museums in the Country&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.parenting.com/gallery/10-toys-great-for-kids-with-special-needs?src=syn&amp;dom=HuffPo" target="_hplink"&gt;10 Great Toys for Kids with Special Needs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.parenting.com/blogs/special-needs-blog/laura-parenting/autism-health-care?src=syn&amp;dom=HuffPo" target="_hplink"&gt;One Mom's Fight for Autism Health Coverage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049358/thumbs/s-FINDING-HER-VOICE-NOTFORREUSE-mini.jpg?12" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
