<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>B.C. Girl Saved By Heroic Chihuahua</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/2013/03/26/chihuahua-saves-chilliwack-girl-pit-bull-jenna-desrochers_n_2960086.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>2000571415</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T03:24:47Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T03:29:53Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A four-year-old Chihuahua came to the rescue of an eight-year-old Chilliwack girl after a neighbour's pit bull attacked her and began biting her face. Jenna...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>CBC</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ziann-lum/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;A four-year-old Chihuahua came to the rescue of an eight-year-old Chilliwack girl after a neighbour's pit bull attacked her and began biting her face.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Jenna Desrochers was outside in a backyard last Tuesday at around 5 p.m. PT when the neighbour's pit bull broke free from its enclosure and went after her.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Soon after, her grandmother's Chihuahua came to the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Anne Marie Desrochers, Jenna's grandmother, says the pit bull knocked Jenna down and began biting her face. Honey, a four-year-old Chihuahua, then came to the rescue by drawing the attacking dog away.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;"The pit bull took Jenna down at the knees, that's what the owner had told me, and basically went for her face."&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;"Then, the Chihuahua was around...The pit bull ran for the Chihuaua. She was distracted enough," Desrochers said.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The owner then managed to grab a hold of the pit bull's collar, and brought the dog inside.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Jenna was badly hurt and needed hours of surgery and hundreds of stitches, but her grandmother says it could have been much worse.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;After a discussion between the families, the neighbour agreed that the pit bull should be put down.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057640/thumbs/s-CHIHUAHUA-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: One Little Girl Plus 14 Dogs Means Pure Joy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/14-german-shepherds_n_2958691.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2958691</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T23:27:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T23:18:12Z</updated>
    
    <summary>We'd like to introduce you to 5-year-old Pernille from Norway. She's the queen of her own kingdom of floppy-eared, bushy tailed German Shepherds from the...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Mohini Kundu</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mohini-kundu/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;We'd like to introduce you to 5-year-old Pernille from Norway. She's the queen of her own kingdom of floppy-eared, bushy tailed German Shepherds from the breeders at &lt;a href="http://www.finika.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Kennel Finika&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here she is with 14 (yep, count 'em) of the kennel's finest at her command. Could anything look more like paradise than a little girl frolicking with dogs in a forest? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/kennel.finika" target="_hplink"&gt;the kennel's Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for more photos of puppies, prize-winning pooches and little Pernille with her pals. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H/T &lt;a href="http://now.msn.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;msnNOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057343/thumbs/s-14-GERMAN-SHEPARDS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Arianna Huffington: Disconnect: A New Movie Sounds the Alarm About Our Hyper-Connected Lives</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/arianna-huffington/disconnect-movie_b_2958875.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2958875</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T23:15:07Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T23:22:38Z</updated>
    
    <summary>In the 1840s, Benjamin Disraeli, still a long way from being prime minister, wanted to wake people up to the plight of the British working class. The alarm he sounded wasn't delivered in a speech, a pamphlet, or an article -- but in a novel, Sybil, published in 1845. Ever since I read Sybil when I was at Cambridge, I've loved thinkers and writers who use storytelling to reach people and get us to act. And so it was that I found myself moderating a panel discussion last week with the director and two cast members of a movie that uses storytelling to wake us up to one of the biggest problems of our modern age: the effect that being "connected" to technology 24/7 is having on our ability to connect with our lives, ourselves, and the people we love. Like so many people, this is something I struggle with on a regular basis. That's why Disconnect struck a nerve.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Arianna Huffington</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/arianna-huffington/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;In the 1840s, Benjamin Disraeli, still a long way from being prime minister, wanted to wake people up to the plight of the British working class -- and move them to act. The alarm he sounded wasn't delivered in a speech, a pamphlet, or an article -- but in a novel, &lt;em&gt;Sybil&lt;/em&gt;, published in 1845. It had the desired effect -- raising awareness, provoking outrage, and leading to the passage of several fundamental social reforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disraeli knew that one of the most effective ways to touch people is through narrative -- putting flesh and blood on raw facts and data. Ever since I read &lt;em&gt;Sybil&lt;/em&gt; when I was at Cambridge, I've loved thinkers and writers and gadflies who use storytelling to reach people and get us to act. Of course, since Disraeli's time, other powerful ways of telling those stories have emerged -- including movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so it was that I found myself moderating a panel discussion last week with the director and two cast members (Frank Grillo and Marc Jacobs -- yes, &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; Marc Jacobs!) of a movie that uses storytelling to wake us up to one of the biggest problems of our modern age: the effect that being "connected" to technology 24/7 is having on our ability to connect with our lives, ourselves and the people we love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film, written by Andrew Stern and directed by Henry-Alex Rubin, is called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://disconnectthemovie.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Disconnect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, and when it opens on April 12 I urge everybody to go see it. I found &lt;em&gt;Disconnect&lt;/em&gt; incredibly compelling -- a perfect use of storytelling to vividly dramatize an issue that permeates our lives to such an extent that it's hard to even see. As well as Frank Grillo and Marc Jacobs, the cast includes Jason Bateman, Hope Davis, Paula Patton, Alexander Skarsgård, and Michael Nyqvist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disconnect&lt;/em&gt; -- I'll try to avoid spoilers -- interweaves three stories, each involving characters whose lives have reached a crisis exacerbated by their dependence on technology at the expense of real human connection. There's a couple that has recently lost a baby. Instead of grieving together, they turn away from each other, and lose themselves in online distractions. There are two boys who use the power of social media to take advantage of another boy's loneliness and isolation -- itself partly caused by his father's obsession with work and email. And there's a woman reporter who becomes involved with a 18-year-old webcam porn performer who lives in a house run by a porn kingpin played by Jacobs. Now do you want to see it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stories become more and more enmeshed and finally come together in a gripping ending. In each instance, it takes a crisis to shake the characters up. &lt;em&gt;Disconnect&lt;/em&gt; shows how easy it is to allow technology to lure us into a somnambulist life, gradually being pulled away from a sense of who we are and what really matters. At one point, the father, played by Jason Bateman, huddles with his wife, played by Hope Davis, and his daughter, played by Hayley Ramm, and looks at his son, played by Jonah Bobo, and says, "Everything I love is in this room." And yet that's certainly not how he had been living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's easy to get seduced by technology. As Henry-Alex Rubin said during our Q&amp;A, many people use the Internet as medication, to dull pain and disappointments. One thing leads to another and, before you know it, you're missing your own life. Before the screening, Marc Jacobs told me that he'd banished all technology from his bedroom and has a low tolerance for it at dinners. "You have friends over for dinner and they're on their BlackBerrys and iPhones all the time, and you think, 'Why are you even here?'" And in fact, it was the sight of people around the dinner table emailing and texting that inspired Andrew Stern to write &lt;em&gt;Disconnect&lt;/em&gt; in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href="http://www.mit.edu/~sturkle/" target="_hplink"&gt;Sherry Turkle&lt;/a&gt;, a professor at MIT and author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Alone-Together-Expect-Technology-Other/dp/0465031463" target="_hplink"&gt;Alone Together: Why We Expect More from Technology and Less from Each Other&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, pointed out in a &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/sherry_turkle_alone_together.html" target="_hplink"&gt;TEDTalk&lt;/a&gt;: "People want to be with each other, but also elsewhere -- connected to all the different places they want to be."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turkle explains that technology exploits our loneliness and our fear of the hard work and messiness of intimacy. "From social networks to sociable robots, we're designing technologies that will give us the illusion of companionship without the demands of friendship," she says. As a result, "we slip into thinking that always being connected is going to make us feel less alone," but "actually it's the opposite that's true."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even worse, it's not just that overuse of social technology can make us feel lonelier and more disconnected, there's now scientific evidence that it can actually diminish our capacity to really connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barbara Fredrickson is a professor of psychology at the University of North Carolina and the author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Love-2-0-Supreme-Everything-ebook/dp/B008BM0LMG" target="_hplink"&gt;Love 2.0: How Our Supreme Emotion Affects Everything We Feel, Think, Do, and Become&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. She explains how, in the same way that leading a sedentary life changes our bodies, our online habits can actually rewire our brains. "Experiences leave imprints on our neural pathways," she &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/24/opinion/sunday/your-phone-vs-your-heart.html" target="_hplink"&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt;. "Any habit molds the very structure of your brain in ways that strengthen your proclivity for that habit."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, she says, your answer to questions like "how much time do you typically spend with others?" and "when you do, how connected and attuned to them do you feel?" can in fact "reveal our biological capacity to connect." And, the research shows, by changing the ways you connect, you can change your capacity to connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She cites a study that showed that meditators who were taught a practice aimed at increasing their "warmth and tenderness toward themselves and others" were able to increase their vagal tone, which is part of our cardiovascular system. And she notes that other research has shown that "by increasing people's vagal tone, we increase their capacity for connection, friendship and empathy." In short, she writes, "the more attuned to others you become, the healthier you become, and vice versa."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, "Your heart's capacity for friendship also obeys the biological law of 'use it or lose it.' If you don't regularly exercise your ability to connect face to face," she writes, "you'll eventually find yourself lacking some of the basic biological capacity to do so."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while we may think we are using technology to connect, we are actually diminishing our capacity to really connect. We're machines that are built to seek out connection, so it's no wonder we are drawn to technology that seems to offer easy connections. It's not unlike the proposition that diet soft drinks may actually lead to gaining weight. "Some studies suggest that when our taste buds sense sweetness, the body expects a calorie load to accompany it," dietician Cheryl Forberg &lt;a href="http://news.menshealth.com/the-truth-about-diet-soda/2011/07/07/" target="_hplink"&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Men's Health&lt;/em&gt;. "When that doesn't happen, it may cause us to overeat because we crave the energy rush our body was expecting."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at HuffPost, we are taking steps both editorially and personally to course-correct and help our community end our addiction to technology. Last year, our Executive Lifestyle Editor, Lori Leibovich, announced to her young children that she was going on a "&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lori-leibovich/moms-electronic-diet_b_2010645.html" target="_hplink"&gt;digital diet&lt;/a&gt;" while on summer vacation. "If you see me doing anything on my iPhone besides taking pictures," she told them, "take it away from me." Her kids were thrilled. How did it go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;There were moments when I felt existentially lost ... But it also felt exhilarating to use my hands for digging tunnels in the sand and turning the pages of a novel instead of just for tapping away on a screen. For the first time in I don't know how long, I was really seeing my kids. And they were relishing being seen.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, as Henry-Alex Rubin said during the Q&amp;A, it's not like people weren't lonely and isolated in the past. But the Internet and social media amplify everything, including isolation. And while we're surfing the web, it's easy to ignore that we might also be surfing through our lives. Nothing against surfing, but it's by definition staying on the surface, which is great for surfing and terrible for life. The writer and cartoonist Alan Saunders, in a line later used in a John Lennon lyric, once &lt;a href="http://quoteinvestigator.com/2012/05/06/other-plans/" target="_hplink"&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; that "life is what happens to us while we are making other plans." And now we have technology that's really, really great at helping us make plans -- for experiences that we're not fully present for when they actually happen because we're so busy making more plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like so many people, this is something I struggle with on a regular basis. That's why &lt;em&gt;Disconnect&lt;/em&gt; struck a nerve. Through the unique stories it so masterfully tells, it speaks to some universal truths about one of humanity's core traits -- our desire to connect. And, I should add, there is absolutely nothing didactic about the film. "I didn't approach this with any sort of theory or polemic," Henry-Alex Rubin &lt;a href="http://www.style.com/stylefile/2013/03/plugged-in-but-disconnected/" target="_hplink"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; in the Q&amp;A. "I just wanted to make things as real as possible. I approached it like a documentary."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a modern &lt;em&gt;Sybil&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Disconnect&lt;/em&gt; sounds the alarm through fiction and drama about some very dark realities and deep truths.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How To Win Over Your Stepkids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/stepparent-advice-how-to_n_2951878.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2951878</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T22:38:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T22:39:32Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It's a rare stepparent who hasn't tried, in their own way, to win over their stepkids. Whether it was snapping up two Justin Bieber concert...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;It's a rare stepparent who hasn't tried, in their own way, to win over their stepkids. Whether it was snapping up two Justin Bieber concert tickets or attempting to bond over hot wings during a stepsons-only guy's night out, it's hard to resist trying to fast-track a solid relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as any member of a blended family can tell you, relationships can't be forced. So how can you stop stressing over winning over your step-kids -- and actually get them to like you? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recenty asked five experts (and HuffPost bloggers) to share with us the three things they think stepparents need to know to create a healthy, unhurried relationship with their stepkids. Click through the slideshow below to read their advice, then &lt;a href="mailto:divorce@huffingtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or tweet &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPostDivorce&lt;/a&gt; the three things &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think new stepparents need to know to forge a better relationship with their spouse's kids. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--288355--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055534/thumbs/s-STEPPARENT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>PHOTO: The Cutest Smiling Elephant</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/smiling-baby-elephant-photo_n_2958657.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2958657</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T22:28:01Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T22:28:02Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Not only are baby elephants incredibly cute, but they seem to have way too much fun with whatever they're doing. Even if it's not playing...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>James Gerken</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/james-gerken/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Not only are baby &lt;a href="http://huffingtonpost.com/news/elephants" target="_hplink"&gt;elephants&lt;/a&gt; incredibly cute, but they seem to have way too much fun with whatever they're doing. Even if it's not &lt;a href="http://screen.yahoo.com/baby-elephant-plays-ocean-231138164.html" target="_hplink"&gt;playing in the ocean&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bu_E2f0mQmI" target="_hplink"&gt;rolling in mud&lt;/a&gt;, this particular elephant really likes his stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Story continues below photo.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/N4jynEM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/N4jynEM.jpg" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The photo above has received &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/aww/comments/1b0lpk/smiling_elephants_are_the_cutest/" target="_hplink"&gt;thousands of up votes on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, generating comments like, "I haz grass," and, "The world needs more elephants."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, many members of this species are threatened. A &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/06/cites-report-elephants-africa-poaching_n_2818638.html" target="_hplink"&gt;2013 report from the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species&lt;/a&gt; (CITES) found that, "Globally, illegal ivory trade activity has more than doubled since 2007." A recent documentary &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/27/battle-for-the-elephants_n_2768184.html" target="_hplink"&gt;followed the ivory trade from East Africa to Southeast Asia&lt;/a&gt;, revealing how local corruption in Africa and insatiable Chinese demand for ivory is pushing elephants closer to extinction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) Red List of Threatened Species currently &lt;a href="http://www.iucnredlist.org/details/12392/0" target="_hplink"&gt;lists African Elephants&lt;/a&gt; (Loxodonta africana) as "vulnerable."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057472/thumbs/s-SMILING-BABY-ELEPHANT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Katherine Stone: The Day My Spanx Stuck Out at CNN</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/katherine-stone/the-day-my-spanx-stuck-ou_1_b_2958769.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2958769</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T22:11:49Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T22:11:58Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I've been wearing a dress that is too short and shows at least two inches of the control-top area of my support hose, all the way around. Three hundred and sixty degrees of Spanx. I just walked all around CNN with my control-tops sticking out.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Katherine Stone</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/katherine-stone/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I got the message while I was sitting at my desk, looking forward to a full Friday with no conference calls or meetings. Nothing to do but focus on writing and answering emails. Would you like to be on HLN TV today to talk about postpartum depression?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to that is always, "Of course!" because I'll take any mass media opportunity to give moms better information about the most common complication of childbirth, even if it means missing out on the luxury of a rare uninterrupted day of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was 10:00 a.m. and they needed me there by 11:00 a.m. I live an hour away from CNN Center in Atlanta, so I was going to have to run out of the house in five minutes flat. This was a bit of a problem, given that I was in sweats and hadn't washed my face. I had taken a shower the night before and gone to bed with my hair wet, too busy to deal with it because I was on my own with the kids. So there I am with no makeup and hair sticking out all over the place and I have five minutes. I was grateful they agreed to do my hair and makeup when I arrived, so the goal was to get on an outfit and go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you appear on television, you're supposed to wear something that looks at least semi-professional and is a solid color. I walked into my closet and realized pretty much everything I own is black. Or grey. I thought, "Screw it!" and threw on the first black dress I saw hanging, put on some deodorant, wrangled on my Spanx, and ran out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got to CNN, the lovely ladies in hair and makeup went to work on me. Not just one person, mind you, but three of them. Three. When everyone else in hair and makeup has one person working on them and you have three, that's a bit concerning. Plus, I've gained some weight and some wrinkles as of late, and then there's the completely undignified and enraging mid-40s acne thing going on, so I'm feeling very self-conscious these days. The poor makeup artist applied foundation, and then more foundation, and then more foundation. And then she started using contouring makeup like a boss to make it look like I have cheekbones instead of jowls. I started sinking lower and lower into the chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They did the best they could do and I was finally presentable and off I went to the studio. Where I sat. And sat. And watched the ENTIRE SHOW happening live before me without ever going on. I got bumped, and let me say there's something about being bumped that makes you feel all sad panda and unworthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was grateful, however, that the host of HLN's "Raising America" that day, Christi Paul, decided to do a quick after-the-show show with me on PPD. Good. Yay. All is not lost. I do the interview, hop back in the car and race home so I can change before it's time to pick the kids up from the bus stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrive, I walk into my bathroom and see myself in the mirror. This is when I realize that I've been wearing a dress that is too short and shows at least two inches of the control-top area of my support hose, all the way around. Three hundred and sixty degrees of Spanx. I just walked all around CNN with my control-tops sticking out, for the entire world to see, and no one said anything. Not one word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that day, HLN sends me a link of the after-the-show segment I did, which is now up on their website for the world to see. In it, for some reason unbeknownst to me, my right ear plays a starring role. The entire time I'm speaking, the viewer is looking at my profile, where my hair has decided to part and feature my ear on full display, like I'm some sort of &lt;a href="http://www.hlntv.com/video/2013/03/14/postpartum-progress-realities" target="_hplink"&gt;elfin mother's advocate.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only did I just spend my entire day not going on TV, not only am I wearing five pounds of makeup, and not only did I show everyone MY ASS all day long, but my ear decided to upstage me and be the star of the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've got it all together, ladies. All. Together.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/775954/thumbs/s-SPANX-mini.jpg?10" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Look Who Will Be At This Year's White House Easter Egg Roll!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/easter-egg-roll-guests-_n_2958313.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2958313</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T22:03:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T22:03:38Z</updated>
    
    <summary>WASHINGTON -- The White House Easter Egg Roll has announced the 2013 guest list. Over fifty iconic real and fictional characters will bring joy and...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brandon Wetherbee</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brandon-wetherbee/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON -- The &lt;a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2013/03/25/white-house-announces-special-guest-costume-characters-easter-egg-roll-d" target="_hplink"&gt;White House Easter Egg Roll has announced the 2013 guest list&lt;/a&gt;. Over fifty iconic real and fictional characters will bring joy and cheer in a sometimes-costumed form to &lt;a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/eastereggroll" target="_hplink"&gt;nearly 35,000 children and parents on April 1&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click through the slideshow to see the 50+ real and costumed characters that will be on the White House lawn:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--288448--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The release of the guest list is one more hint that the roll really will go on. As recently as March 19 &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/19/white-house-easter-egg-roll-sequester_n_2908785.html" target="_hplink"&gt;White House press secretary Jay Carney was still reassuring the public that, regardless of the sequester-related cancellation of White House tours&lt;/a&gt;, this tradition wouldn't be axed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not you have tickets to the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/15/white-house-easter-egg-roll-2013_n_2697305.html" target="_hplink"&gt;long sold-out event&lt;/a&gt;, you can watch a live stream of Monday's event and purchase &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/11/white-house-easter-eggs_n_2853223.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Bo Obama approved commemorative eggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And speaking of Bo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt; var src_url="https://spshared.5min.com/Scripts/PlayerSeed.js?playList=517720292&amp;height=411&amp;width=570&amp;sid=577&amp;origin=SOLR&amp;relatedMode=2&amp;relatedBottomHeight=60&amp;companionPos=&amp;hasCompanion=false&amp;autoStart=false&amp;colorPallet=%23FFEB00&amp;videoControlDisplayColor=%23191919&amp;shuffle=0&amp;isAP=1"; src_url += "&amp;onVideoDataLoaded=HPTrack.Vid.DL&amp;onTimeUpdate=HPTrack.Vid.TC"; if (typeof(commercial_video) == "object") { src_url += "&amp;siteSection="+commercial_video.site_and_category; if (commercial_video.package) { src_url += "&amp;sponsorship="+commercial_video.package;  } } document.write('&lt;scr' + 'ipt type="text/javascript" src="'+src_url+'"&gt;&lt;/scr' + 'ipt&gt;');&lt;/script&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057396/thumbs/s-WHITE-HOUSE-EASTER-EGG-ROLL-GUESTS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'Scary,' 'Graphic' Text Messages Sent To Fifth-Graders</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/elementary-students-text-messages-new-jersey_n_2958245.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2958245</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T21:53:42Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T22:03:01Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Text messages sent to students at Somerville Elementary School in Ridgewood, N.J., threaten to kill them if they don't forward the texts to a certain...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Tyler Kingkade</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tyler-kingkade/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Text messages sent to students at Somerville Elementary School in Ridgewood, N.J., threaten to kill them if they don't forward the texts to a certain number of people, &lt;a href="http://www.nj.com/bergen/index.ssf/2013/03/text_messages_circulating_at_elementary_school_prompts_new_warning_from_ridgewood_officials_report_s.html" target="_hplink"&gt;according to local media reports&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somerville students in the &lt;a href="http://www.northjersey.com/news/Ridgewood_district_warns_school_of_scary_text_messages_circulating.html" target="_hplink"&gt;fourth and fifth grades received these digital chain letters&lt;/a&gt; on their cellphones in recent weeks, The Record in North Jersey reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorna Oates-Santos, the&lt;a href="http://ridgewood.patch.com/articles/scary-graphic-text-message-circulates-at-ridgewood-elementary-school" target="_hplink"&gt; school's principal, sent a letter to parents on March 19 warning that the text message&lt;/a&gt; "is rather scary, quite graphic and inappropriate." (The entire message can be read below.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It is clear that this message was not created by a student at our school; rather, it comes from the Internet and is spreading like wildfire," &lt;a href="https://editorial.huffingtonpost.com/tmp/2958245_94.html?preview=yes" target="_hplink"&gt;Oates-Santos wrote to parents, according to the Ridgewood Patch&lt;/a&gt;. "Our students, however, are involved in forwarding the message and writing about it." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oates-Santos &lt;a href="http://ridgewood.patch.com/articles/scary-graphic-text-message-circulates-at-ridgewood-elementary-school" target="_hplink"&gt;encouraged parents to discuss best practices with their children&lt;/a&gt; for using social media and digital communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I know those things are fake, so I just deleted it and didn't worry about it," Somerville fifth-grader Lucy Kaczmarski&lt;a href="http://newyork.cbslocal.com/2013/03/21/nj-elementary-students-receive-threatening-chain-letter-style-text-message/" target="_hplink"&gt; told WCBS.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucy is right, and a quick scan of the Internet will bring up posts including this exact chain message from &lt;a href="http://breakthechainletters.blogspot.com/2011/10/teddy-chain-letter-smashed.html" target="_hplink"&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pastebin.com/df8hXLxR" target="_hplink"&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://toasterdemon.newgrounds.com/news/post/22947" target="_hplink"&gt;2007&lt;/a&gt;. But the news also brought up a question about whether it's appropriate for fourth- and fifth-graders to have their own cellphones in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WCBS &lt;a href="http://newyork.cbslocal.com/2013/03/21/nj-elementary-students-receive-threatening-chain-letter-style-text-message/" target="_hplink"&gt;quoted an anonymous&lt;/a&gt; parent suggesting the 10-year-olds were too young to have personal cellphones, and the Ridgewood Patch &lt;a href="http://ridgewood.patch.com/articles/poll-what-age-should-kids-have-smartphones" target="_hplink"&gt;put it to a vote&lt;/a&gt;. So what do you think?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;HH--236POLL--10481--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The messages circulated among students are pasted below (&lt;a href="http://ridgewood.patch.com/articles/read-the-scary-text-ridgewood-kids-have-received?national=patch&amp;ncid=edlinkuspatc00000006" target="_hplink"&gt;via Ridgewood Patch&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Hi, I am Teddy. Once you read this you cannot get out. Finish reading this until it is done! As I said, I am Teddy. I am 7 years old. I have no eyes and blood all over my face. I am dead. If you don't send this to at least 12 people I will come to your house at midnight and I'll hide under your bed. When you're asleep, I'll kill you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't believe me? Case 1: Patty Buckles Got this e-mail. She doesn't believe in chain letters. Well, Foolish Patty. She was sleeping when her TV started flickering on and off. Now she's not with us anymore. Ha ha patty, Ha ha! You don't want to be like Patty, do you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Case 2: George M. Simon Hates chain mail, but he didn't want to die that night. He sent it to 4 people. Not good enough George. Now, George is in a coma, we don't know if he'll ever wake up. Ha ha George, Ha ha! Now, do you want to be like George?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Case 3: Valarie Tyler She got this letter. Another chain letter she thought. Only had 7 people to send to. Well, That night when she was having a shower she saw bloody Mary in the mirror. It was the BIGGEST fright of her life. Valarie is scarred for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Case 4: Derek Minse This is the final case I'll tell you about. Well, Derek was a smart person. He sent it to 12 people. Later that day, he found a $100.00 bill on the ground. He was premoted to head officer at his job and his girlfriend said yes to his purposal. Now, Katie and him are living happily ever after.The have 2 beautiful children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send this to at least 12 people or you'll face the consequences. 0 people- You will die tonight 1-6 people- you will be injured 7-11 people- you will get the biggest fright of your life 12 and over- you are safe and will have good fortune! Do What Teddy Says!!!! Hurry, you must send to 12 people before midnight no send backs Sorry!! I had to!&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057316/thumbs/s-SCARY-TEXT-MESSAGES-SOMERVILLE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: Comedian Tackles New Fatherhood In Web Show</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/being-a-dad-show-john-ramsey_n_2924220.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2924220</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T21:50:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T22:55:41Z</updated>
    
    <summary>"You've gotta know your audience," John Ramsey explains to his collaborator, Mike Macrae, in the second episode of "Being A Dad," his new web comedy...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Emma Mustich</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-mustich/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;"You've gotta know your audience," &lt;a href="http://www.johnramseycomedy.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;John Ramsey&lt;/a&gt; explains to his collaborator, Mike Macrae, in the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kho9PdA6seo&amp;list=PLnbsPAGTUNTzEiN_I5cYmQygRhERYm9_R" target="_hplink"&gt;second episode&lt;/a&gt; of "Being A Dad," his new web comedy show about fatherhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comedian and former lawyer, who lives in Austin, Texas, is trying to explain that his cheesy impersonations of Arnold Schwarzenegger, Austin Powers and Bill Cosby aren't "hack" if they make little kids laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But he hopes babies and toddlers won't be the only ones amused. The web show he just launched -- produced by &lt;a href="http://humordy.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;HUMORdy&lt;/a&gt; -- is aimed at his fellow new parents (Ramsey and his wife have a 16-month-old son, Jack, whom we meet in the second video, and are expecting another baby boy this summer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ramsey sees the series as a way to "kill three birds with one stone -- spend time with my son, continue producing comedy, and process some of things that being a dad has me thinking about," he told HuffPost over email, adding: "I never wanted to do any material based on real life, but now it's all I think about -- so I don't have much choice.  Just another thing being a dad has changed."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the series' &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Uq687oCo09k&amp;list=PLnbsPAGTUNTzEiN_I5cYmQygRhERYm9_R" target="_hplink"&gt;first episode&lt;/a&gt;, Ramsey's Diaper Genie comes to life in the middle of the night, offering encouragement to the new dad (who's so exhausted he mistakes a hammer for his own baby).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Ramsey told HuffPost that bedtime is indeed one of the things that makes him appreciate parenting's paradoxes -- and comedy value -- the most: "Like when it's 7:30 and you're just dying for your kid to go to bed, like 'he's being such a nightmare right now.' And then he finally  goes to sleep, and at 7:35, you're like, 'I miss him. He's so cute it's unbelievable.'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Watch the complete second episode of "Being A Dad" above, and see Episode One, "Diaper Genie," here:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="570" height="321" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Uq687oCo09k" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057239/thumbs/s-BEING-A-DAD-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Is Putting Your Children First Bad For Marriage?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/marriage-problems_n_2957477.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2957477</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T21:35:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T21:10:13Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Do good moms make bad wives? That's the charged question blogger Jackie Morgan MacDougall asked Tuesday in a HuffPost Divorce blog on the need for...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Do good moms make bad wives? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's the charged question blogger Jackie Morgan MacDougall asked Tuesday in a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jackie-morgan-macdougall/7-tips-to-save-your-marri_b_2909724.html" target="_hplink"&gt;HuffPost Divorce blog&lt;/a&gt; on the need for parents to prioritize their marriages to stave off divorce. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'm not saying to neglect the kids, but they won't exactly suffer by seeing their parents put each other at the top of the list, instead serving as relationship role models," MacDougall wrote. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MacDougall is hardly the first person to make the case for putting your spouse before your kids. Author and mother-of-four Ayelet Waldman &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-solod-warren/whos-your-bad-mother-ayel_b_195824.html" target="_hplink"&gt;famously elicited boos&lt;/a&gt; from an "Oprah" show audience for admitting that she &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2005/03/27/fashion/27love.html?_r=0" target="_hplink"&gt;loved her husband more than her own kids&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to know what our readers thought, so with MacDougall's piece in mind, we posed this question to our &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce?ref=tn_tnmn" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; communities: Is putting your children first bad for a marriage? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the slideshow below to read their responses, then head to the comments to weigh in with your thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--288519--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1056945/thumbs/s-MARRIAGE-PROBLEMS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Nichole Thomas: What I Teach My Daughters When They Watch Me Eat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nichole-thomas/mindful-eating_b_2957268.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2957268</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T21:22:30Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T21:22:37Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Sure, we know our children learn things by watching us, but they are also developing a perspective on life. They are starting to develop mental constructs about what is OK and what's not, and that is a really great thing.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nichole Thomas</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nichole-thomas/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;The other day my daughter Imani asked me what I was eating. It was a simple enough question, but after I answered her she continued to watch me. She followed with a couple more questions,  but the conversation that followed was what really made me smile. Kids can teach us some amazing things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Mommy, what are those green things?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Asparagus," I replied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"And what is the pink stuff?" &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's smoked salmon, with olive oil, and capers."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Why do you eat so slow?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I was beginning to laugh because she had her entire face in my plate, and her nose was glistening from the olive oil that rolled off of the my asparagus and landed on her face. She smiled, and wiped it with her finger and ate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Ummmmmm, that looks good!! May I have some?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Sure," I said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we sat together and ate smoked salmon; grilled asparagus with cracked black pepper, Himalayan pink salt, lemon zest, and parsley; and two chunks of crusty gluten-free baguettes. As I watched my 5-year-old take in the sights and smells of our Mediterranean feast, I noticed that she started watching everything I did. The way I dredged my bread through the oil. The number of capers I added to a bite of salmon. The size bite I took. (She even took some food off of her fork with her fingers to match mine, so cute!) Then I saw her get it! Her little "aha!" moment, as Ms. Oprah Winfrey calls it.  The lightbulb went off in her head and she slowed down. She began to take deep breaths in between each bite, and developed her own rhythm. She started to do something I just learned to do in my early 30s, she found pleasure in her meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat together, talking, laughing, eating, and sharing something pretty special. So then I wanted to see if she felt any different. I asked her how her food was? What she tasted, and what it tasted like? If she liked capers by themselves, or only with the smoked salmon? How she liked the lemon zest on the asparagus? Whether she like the bread crusty and hot, or softened with the olive oil? What her favorite colors were on the plate? She discovered her own tastes, and things she liked. It was also empowering for her to see how easily I made a yummy lunch, in no time, that tasted so good. She saw that eating and spending time with me was just as much fun as sitting down and watching a 30-minute TV show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But just to be clear, she wasn't the only one that learned a lot that day. I learned that every time I think about grabbing something -- even though it's made at home, but I rush it down to get to that next call, or meeting -- I'm doing my body a disservice. When I think I don't have 30 to 40 minutes to spend with my munchkins "right now"  because the day has gotten away from me, I need to reassess the day! I learned that &lt;em&gt;pleasure&lt;/em&gt; isn't a bad word! I learned that developing a healthy relationship with food isn't just important for me to maintain a healthy weight and fight disease, but because my baby girls need to see better habits in order to develop their own. It was almost like sitting in front of my 5-year-old self. An "aha!" moment for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, we know our children learn things by watching us, but they are also developing a perspective on life. They are starting to develop mental constructs about what is OK and what's not, and that is a really great thing. So the next time you have some time to spend with your family, friends, and loved ones, really try to give them &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;! For however long that is, commit yourself, enjoy yourself, and take in all the pleasures the moment has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recipe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smoked Salmon with Asparagus and Capers on a Toasted Baguette&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3-4 slices of smoked salmon&lt;br /&gt;
2 tablespoons of capers&lt;br /&gt;
1 bundle of asparagus, washed, dried&lt;br /&gt;
1 baking sheet&lt;br /&gt;
1 gluten free baguette&lt;br /&gt;
2 tablespoons EVOO  (Thanks, Rachael Ray, typing that all the time is a bit annoying!)&lt;br /&gt;
The zest of half a lemon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Instructions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 375*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place cleaned and dried asparagus on a baking sheet, drizzle with olive oil, and top with lemon zest, parsley, salt and cracked black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bake for 8-10 minutes, or until fork tender&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toast baguette slices until crispy and golden brown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place smoked salmon, asparagus, and toasted baguette slices on your favorite plate, drizzle with a little more EVOO, and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XO,&lt;br /&gt;
Nichole~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more by Nichole Thomas, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nichole-thomas"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more on wellness, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/wellness"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057320/thumbs/s-MINDFUL-EATING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'Emaciated' Boy, 4, Spent 5 Days With Dead Mother</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/nj-police-emaciated-boy-f_n_2958452.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2958452</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T21:10:16Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T21:50:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>UNION, N.J. -- Police in northern New Jersey found an emaciated 4-year-old boy in an apartment Tuesday morning with the body of his mother, who...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/david-moye/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;UNION, N.J. -- Police in northern New Jersey found an emaciated 4-year-old boy in an apartment Tuesday morning with the body of his mother, who appeared to have been dead about five days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy told police he tried to get food from the refrigerator but couldn't open the door, Union Police Director Daniel Zieser said. The boy also had rubbed lotion on his mother in an apparent attempt to help her, leaving behind his handprints, Zieser said.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;"He made a statement to the officer that `There's plenty of food in the refrigerator, but I couldn't open the door,'" Zieser told New York radio station WCBS. "So that's kind of sad that nobody checked on him, no family members. It's sad, very sad."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discovery was made Tuesday after a maintenance worker reported a bad odor coming from the apartment. The door was ajar but locked with a chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once police forced their way in, they found the woman's body in a bedroom. The county medical examiner was conducting an autopsy to determine the time and cause of death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman wasn't being identified until relatives could be notified. Police don't suspect foul play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy was taken to a hospital for treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057384/thumbs/s-EMACIATED-BOY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Robin Farr: Postpartum Rage is Common in New Mothers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/robin-farr/postpartum-rage-new-mothers_b_2958346.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2958346</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T20:59:48Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T23:51:37Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Imagine a time you totally lost your temper. When you were so consumed by anger you felt it as a physical thing, adrenaline racing through your body and blocking out all rational thought. When your first instinct, as though it were primal, was to throw something so it would shatter into a thousand pieces and break whatever spell had overtaken you.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Robin Farr</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/robin-farr/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;One of the most common search terms that brings people to my blog is "postpartum rage" or some variation of it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Rage at husband." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Rage after pregnancy."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Postpartum depression rage."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Sleep deprivation and rage."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Rage after having a baby."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You'll notice that all of these search terms include rage. Not anger, not just depression, but rage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These mothers are NOT alone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dictionary.com definition of rage contains five entries for rage as a noun and every one of them includes a mention of violence. I wish I could say that's not really accurate when it comes to the feelings of rage these women are searching for answers to when they turn to Google and end up on my blog, but I can't. I know, and these women find me, because I wrote about it. I experienced it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the dictionary definition, most of these mothers are not violent. They don't hit their children (or their husbands). They are not child abusers. What they are is women suffering from a very common illness that affects, by some estimates, up to 20 per cent of new mothers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my experience with postpartum rage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a time you totally lost your temper. When you were so consumed by anger you felt it as a physical thing, adrenaline racing through your body and blocking out all rational thought. When your first instinct, as though it were primal, was to throw something so it would shatter into a thousand pieces and break whatever spell had overtaken you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's what it felt like for me for much of my son's first 2 1/2 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was desperately sleep deprived. I had no patience. Anger was my constant companion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It raised its ugly head when I had spent hours trying to get him to sleep only to have him immediately wake up screaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It brought me to tears when he woke up every half hour at night and I was so tired I wanted to die and had no idea how I was ever going to get through the night, never mind the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It added to the exhaustion of trying to cope with and comfort a fussy baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It made me want to yell and scream. Sometimes I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It left me feeling without hope when he smiled and cooed and all I could think was that having a baby had been a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For months the inside of my head was screaming because I was so angry and I didn't know what to do about it. I couldn't throw the baby against the wall or out the window, though the physical urge to do so consumed me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent many days worrying I would hit him and yet at the same time was sure I wouldn't. Except one time I did. It was light - just a smack against his thigh on a really bad day when I had nothing left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It made him cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stood there in horror. And then I scooped him up and held him to me and cried with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even then, I didn't know what was wrong with me. And I didn't ask for help because I was so scared to admit what was going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It simmered beneath the surface all the time, a bubbling pot of anger that threatened, every day, to spill over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I couldn't take it I would summon my loudest inside-my-head voice and swear - at the universe, at his crying, at mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I swore at my inability to cope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I swore at battling the same things, day after day after day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I swore out loud some days, to myself, through my sobs, as my tears ran over my words and the guilt and misery and hopelessness that came with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt massively ripped off in my experience as a new mother. I still resent it. It still makes me cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might judge me for this story. You might tell me I'm a bad mother who should never have had a baby, and who certainly shouldn't have had another after experiencing this. But here's the thing: I'm not a bad mother. I was sick and, because it's not talked about, I didn't know it and I didn't get help soon enough. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postpartum depression doesn't get nearly enough attention. And when it does, it's often the wrong sort of attention, complete with hyperbole and inaccuracy, as Katherine Stone wrote about in her HuffPost piece "It's Time For Everyone To Get The Facts About Postpartum Depression." And this lack of straight facts that leads new mothers to search the web when they're feeling rage after having a baby instead of asking someone for help. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since sharing my story on my blog, I've come to realize just how common postpartum rage is. We don't talk about it enough, but I'm trying to help change that. So come on, let's talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Etan Thomas: Celebrities Inspire a Fatherhood Movement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/etan-thomas/fatherhood-movement_b_2958236.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2958236</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T20:59:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T20:59:36Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I wanted the young people in attendance to know that the while there are many negative statistics about the outcomes for families headed by a single parent, that should not stop any one of them from reaching their potential.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Etan Thomas</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/etan-thomas/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Since the release of my book &lt;em&gt;Fatherhood Rising To The Ultimate Challenge&lt;/em&gt; last year, I have traveled the country to encourage young people who they can be anything they want to be in life no matter what their circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It always amazes me how much hearing that message from an athlete or rapper or actor they recognize resonates with them. It's the reason why I started a fatherhood movement and connected with a wide a range of men to give personal accounts about responsibility, triumphs, struggles and what it takes for young people to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fatherhood movement has been rapidly growing. What's reaffirming to me is that the young men who we encounter want to do something with their lives -- they want to make the right decisions, they want to have an impact on the world. They just are looking for guidance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That fact is sometimes lost on many who still see young people as the scourge of society. But at a recent fatherhood panel during the NBA All Star Weekend -- which featured Pastors Joel Osteen and Carl Lentz, as well as current and former NBA stars Dwyane Wade, Allan Houston and Michael Redd -- I was encouraged that so many young people are craving the answers to life's challenges. Moderated by CNN's Soledad O'Brien and held at the Lakewood Church in Houston, the panel attracted thousands. I stayed afterwards talking to people young and old for about two hours as I signed books and took pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, an unfortunate reality is that these types of events are usually not covered by the mainstream media. It seems that mainstream media outlets only want to focus on the negative things that athletes do, not the life affirming things many of us engage in daily. It's not something plastered on the front of the morning newspapers. But had any of these athletes done anything negative, that sure would have been a top story. That's why we have to hold the media accountable to show a balance of positive stories because young people are watching.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/61283790" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/61283790"&gt;NBA All Star Weekend Fatherhood Panel&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/user13878476"&gt;j amezqua&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com"&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the young people who attended the event were from single family households. Each panelist discussed fatherhood from a different perspective. But I wanted the young people to know that the while there are many negative statistics about the outcomes for families headed by a single parent, that should not stop any one of them from reaching their potential.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what all of us told the young people who day is that they keep following their dreams no matter what their situation or circumstances. Will there be obstacles? Yes. Will it be easy? Absolutely not. But there are too many examples of men who were able to be successful and make the right decisions who came from so-called "broken homes."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes the statistics are alarming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the U.S. Census Bureau in November, 2009, there are approximately 13.7 million single parents in the United States today, and those parents are responsible for raising &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/61283790" target="_blank"&gt;21.8 million children&lt;/a&gt; (approximately 26 percent).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although having a single parent household may not be the most favorable situation, it is reality for a quarter of all kids in America today. Why shower them with negative statistics and lower their expectations and possibilities in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one can deny that the statistics are &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/61283790" target="_blank"&gt;alarming&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*63 percent of youth suicides are from fatherless homes (U.S. Dept. Of Health/Census) -- five times the average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*90 percent of all homeless and runaway children are from fatherless homes -- 32 times the average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*85 percent of all children who show behavior disorders come from fatherless homes -- 20 times the average. (Center for Disease Control)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*80 percent of rapists with anger problems come from fatherless homes -- 14 times the average. (Justice and Behavior, Vol 14, p. 403-26)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*71 percent of all high school dropouts come from fatherless homes -- Nine times the average. (National Principals Association Report)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*75 percent of all adolescent patients in chemical abuse centers come from fatherless homes -- 10 times the average. (Rainbows for All God's Children)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*70 percent of youths in state-operated institutions come from fatherless homes -- 9 times the average. (U.S. Dept. of Justice, Sept. 1988)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*85 percent of all youths in prison come from fatherless homes -- 20 times the average. (Fulton Co. Dept. of Correction)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, young people need to be encouraged that they can be anything their hearts desire to be no matter what their situation or circumstance is. Will there be obstacles? Yes. Will it be easy? Absolutely not. But there are too many examples of men who were able to be successful and make the right decisions who came from so-called "broken homes." Most notably, President Barack Obama. That's not to say that he didn't still feel the pain and anger of not having his father there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Obama described in &lt;em&gt;Dreams of My Father&lt;/em&gt; his impression when he met his wife's family for the first time as 'the vision of domestic bliss.' He continued to say&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Upon seeing the joy of the Robinson house, for someone like me who had barely known his father, who had spent much of his life traveling from place to place, his bloodline scattered to the forewinds, the home that Fraizer and Marian Robinson had built for themselves stirred a longing for stability, a sense of place that I had not realized was there.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is seen by his words how deep the feeling for a father can remain in the heart of someone years after they have reached adulthood. It can affect their lives and their future. President Obama is also the perfect example of someone who has been able to be successful despite that missing connection in their lives. It is possible. We have to be very careful of discouraging young people before they even begin on their journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the eve of Father's Day Weekend in 2009 at a White House Town Hall, the president made these powerful and inspirational statements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I say this as someone who grew up without a father in my life. I had a heroic mom and wonderful grandparents who helped raise me and my sister, and it is because of them that I am able to stand here today. But despite all their extraordinary love and attention, that didn't mean that I didn't feel my father's absence. That's something that leaves a hole in a child's heart...

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Some of the young men who are here today might have their own concerns one day about being a dad. Some of you may be worried that if you didn't have a father, that you may not know how to be one when your turn comes. Some of you might even use that as an excuse to say well, if my dad wasn't around, why should I be. Let's be clear, because your own father wasn't there for you is no excuse for you to be absent also. It's all the more reason to be present. There is no rule that says you have to repeat your father's mistakes. Just the opposite. You have an obligation to break the cycle and to learn from those mistakes. To rise up where your own fathers fell short and to do better with your own children. That's what I try to do in my life. When my daughters were born I made a pledge to them and myself that I would do everything I could to give them the things I didn't have. And I decided that if I could be one thing in life, it would be to be a good father. I haven't always known exactly how to do that. I've made my share of mistakes. I had to ask a lot of questions. But I have also learned from men that I admire.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's why panels like this are so important. Young people need to hear words of encouragement similar to this from the people who have their attention. I applaud the work that Allan Houston is doing with his foundation and Dwyane Wade is doing with his book &lt;em&gt;A Father First&lt;/em&gt;, and want to continue to combine efforts with them an all men who are willing to use their voice, celebrity, and passion to have a positive impact. Not because any of us believe we are some fatherhood experts who have all the answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reason for writing this book and putting together these panels across the country and joining with the efforts of these powerful men is to inspire an entire young generation who are growing up without fathers in their homes. The statistics say that 1 in 4 kids -- black, white, brown, yellow; all American kids -- are growing up without a father in their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal with this book is to use the stories of these men from Tony Dungy to Dr. Cornell West from Ice Cube to Talib Kweli, Roland Martin and John King from CNN, Arn Tellem, Mumia Abul Jamal, Ed Gordon, Chris Paul, Allan Houston,Will Downing, Coach John Thompson, Grant Hill, Derek Fisher and Billy Hunter to Derrick Coleman, Pastor John K Jenkins,, David Aldridge and Stuart Scott, Dave Zirin and John Carlos to Tito Puente Jr. to Damian Marley to Yao Ming from Kevin Durant to Michael Moore, Congressman Elijah Cummings and Howard Dean to Chuck D, Kareem Abdul Jabbar to Taye Diggs to Tony Hawk , Andre Agassi, and Al Sharpton, Kevin Powell, Lamman Rucker, Styles P, Russ Parr, and Isaiah Washington. Al Horford, Joe Johnson, Baron Davis, Joakim Noah, and Malcolm Jamal Warner to inspire them to believe that they can make it and be successful in life. To show them the beauty of fatherhood, not from a shaking my finger at them standpoint. They get enough of that from adults. But from the sharing of other's experiences. None of us are fatherhood experts, I don't even think there is any such thing, but we can all learn from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as an appointee to President Obama's Fatherhood Initiative, I am going to continue this Fatherhood Movement and continue to have panels and town hall discussions in different cities across the nation. All in an effort to inspire an entire generation to believe in themselves no matter what negativity, statistics, or discouragement they are being bombarded with. This is the book and movement I wish I and so many young men and women who came from single parent households had when we were growing up. The stories of these men and most notably President Obama, would have encouraged a lot of people that I grew up with. My overall goal is to inspire an entire generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A condensed version of this &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/therootdc/post/pastor-joel-osteen-dwayne-wade-allan-houston-michael-redd-soledad-obrien-and-etan-thomas-participate-in-a-fatherhood-panel-to-inspire-young-people-to-reach-for-their-dreams/2013/03/20/3cd5d1b6-9168-11e2-9abd-e4c5c9dc5e90_blog.html" target="_hplink"&gt;article originally ran in The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057260/thumbs/s-ETAN-THOMAS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Tamar Abrams: A Farewell Letter, Unread</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tamar-abrams/a-farewell-letter-unread_b_2949282.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2949282</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T20:51:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T20:51:17Z</updated>
    
    <summary>One day in September 2000, I sat down and penned a letter to my then-7-year-old daughter. When I was finished filling two pages of lined paper, I sealed them in an envelope upon which I wrote, "For Hannah -- to be opened only in the event of my death."</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Tamar Abrams</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tamar-abrams/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;One day in September 2000, I sat down and penned a letter to my then-7-year-old daughter. When I was finished filling two pages of lined paper, I sealed them in an envelope upon which I wrote, "For Hannah -- to be opened only in the event of my death." My daughter is now a second-year college student who will head to Brussels in the fall for an internship at the European Union Parliament. We have made it through the awkward preteen years, the sometimes prickly teen years and the early phases of untangling our complex interdependence. My worries about raising her as a single mother have largely dissipated and she is emerging from childhood as a fiercely opinionated, loving and smart young woman. Most shocking is the speed with which she has blossomed from a skinny little girl into a confident and stunningly beautiful woman.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Which brings me back to that letter. What were the thoughts and ideas I felt were the most important legacy of our life together so many years ago? I had forgotten about the letter until recently, and it took an hour of searching through files in the garage before I found it. (Which makes me wonder how I expected anyone else to locate it if I had in fact died!)&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
The letter begins, "My darling Hannah Lily, if you are reading this, it is because I've died. I am so sorry. My greatest sorrow in life was the knowledge that you would lose me one day." I can only imagine my mood as I was writing that, though I no longer recall any incident that was the catalyst for the letter. It was still a year before our world was jangled by 9/11.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
The first page of the letter is mostly about me, so I guess I wasn't very adept at thinking about what my child would most want to read in the event of my death. "You are my greatest accomplishment, my greatest joy. Nothing else even comes close. You have brought me happiness beyond my greatest imagining and showed me what all-consuming love feels like." I continued, "When you were very young, I would tell you every night, 'I love you forever and for always.' That is true. Wherever I am now, I am still loving you fiercely. "&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
I don't recall ever understanding the transiency of life until I gave birth. Having total responsibility for a fragile baby gave me the sense that every bus, every insect, every virus was a potential killer. It took all my self-control to allow my daughter to play in the mud, to cross a street by herself (after looking both ways several times and with a crossing guard present) and eventually, to get her driver's license. And at some point I worried less about her mortality and more about mine. That may have been the point at which I sat down with a ballpoint pen and wrote her a letter that she has never seen.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
"Rely on your faith and your religion," I exhorted. "Raising you as a Jew was not a default decision on my part. Judaism will provide you with answers, comfort and fellowship. There is a God. You pray to God every night. Do not doubt that your prayers are heard, if not always granted."&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Shortly after Hannah became a bat mitzvah at 13, she announced she no longer believed in God or wanted to continue her religious studies. I was devastated. It was less about the actual religious aspects and more about simply having faith in something and being connected to all of her ancestors. As with many other aspects of parenting, patience was my friend. Her first year at college, she called to say she was planning to celebrate the High Holy Days at Hillel House, and visited Israel last summer. The seed of religion was planted and occasionally watered. I trust that she will someday introduce her own children to God and prayer.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
"You will never be alone. You have the gifts and skills to lead a rich, happy life. Use them. You are smart in so many ways and have a huge reserve of compassion and warmth. Don't waste these. Don't waste time on regret or grief. Life is so fleeting. Plunge in with joy!"&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Hannah's ability to gracefully and purposefully walk through life has expanded and contracted, similar to the paths of most children. There have been enormous highs and dreadful lows. As much as I would love to relive most of her childhood, I doubt I could be coaxed back to her middle school years -- nor could she. Some passages of childhood are best lived only once, and quickly. But she has shown time and again that she is full of compassion and love. She is a woman who will undoubtedly have enduring romance and friendships for all of her days.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
"I told you when you were 4 to follow these rules: Never lie. Be kind. Never deliberately hurt another person. Let these rules guide you. But also sing! Play! Dance! Be grateful!" It is so gratifying to know that the most important life lessons of her preschool days continue to guide her. I laugh, though, to recall that when she was 4, she was forbidden to say the words "stupid" or "shut up." At the time, those seemed like the very worst bits of language that I could imagine. I had no idea what I was in for!&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Because I have trouble remembering where I left the car keys, I have no memory of where I was when I wrote this letter or what I was thinking. But I would wager big money that by the time I reached the final paragraph, I was weeping. I know I am now. What words does a mother end such a letter with? How do you bid farewell, even as an intellectual exercise? At the time, I wouldn't have known all the joy and richness of the next 13 years or that the letter would be buried under paperwork in a file labeled "Banking" during the course of two moves. I am so glad it is handwritten, though. Computers are a godsend but they steal from us the visceral connection of putting words on paper.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
My handwriting in the letter is careful. There are no crossed-out words or misspellings. Perhaps I had first written a rough draft? The letters are carefully slanted in that way only left-handed people can manage. Words are underlined, exclamation points are bright slashes on the paper. The second page was ripped from a notebook carelessly, so that the top left corner is missing. In these two pages I had hoped to convey my love, my hope, my continuing presence in the life of the daughter who I adored. It seems now to be such a small effort, not nearly up to the task for which it was designed. I wonder who I thought would give her the letter. Did I expect my words to provide immediate comfort or to sustain her over the decades to come? Was it designed as a talisman, a salve, a prayer?&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Rereading it now, I am so glad I wrote it and of course so glad she has never read it. But the surprising thing is that, if I were to write a similar letter today, it would say almost all the same things. Although we live in a much more dangerous world today than we did in 2000, it is not advising caution that is important in such letters, but insisting that a child live fully and joyfully. I suppose I will put the letter back in the envelope and reseal it this afternoon. And this time I will put it someplace easier to locate. If I reread it in another 13 years, perhaps it will be while babysitting my grandchildren. And when they ask me why I'm crying, I'll tell them it's because a mother's love endures.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
The letter to my precious Hannah ends with this paragraph: "I love you from another place as I loved you when I was by your side. When you feel the wind against your cheek, that is me sending you my kisses. I thank you for giving me life. I adore you. I embrace you. And I expect you to live a long, rich and happy life. Always -- your Mom."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-26-hanandtam.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-26-hanandtam.jpg" width="720" height="540" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057221/thumbs/s-TAMAR-ABRAMS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
