<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>New Baby For B.C. Model, Jeremy Renner</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/2013/03/30/sonni-pacheco-jeremy-renner-baby-girl-vancouver_n_2982784.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2982784</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T05:01:15Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T05:27:24Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Sonni Pacheco, a model who grew up in B.C., and Oscar-nominated actor Jeremy Renner are the proud parents of a baby girl. Ava Berlin Renner...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post B.C.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/andree-lau/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/2013/01/24/sonni-pacheco-jeremy-renner-baby-mother-vancouver_n_2539585.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Sonni Pacheco&lt;/a&gt;, a model who grew up in B.C., and Oscar-nominated actor Jeremy Renner are the proud parents of a baby girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/news/jeremy-renner-names-baby-daughter-ava-berlin-2013293" target="_hplink"&gt;Ava Berlin Renner&lt;/a&gt; was born on Thursday at seven pounds, Renner's representative confirmed to several media outlets, including Us Weekly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They are beyond thrilled," the rep said of the parents, according to the L.A. Times. "&lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/entertainment/gossip/la-et-mg-jeremy-renner-baby-girl-ex-girlfriend-report-20130329,0,6558453.story" target="_hplink"&gt;Mother and daughter&lt;/a&gt; are doing great."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pacheco, 22, is a lingerie model and was a spokeswoman for Monster Energy Drinks. She was born and raised in Pitt Meadows, B.C., outside of Vancouver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday's official statement also made clear that Pacheco is Renner's girlfriend, after &lt;a href="http://www.nationalenquirer.com/celebrity/jeremy-renners-baby-mama-male-roomie" target="_hplink"&gt;earlier reports that the couple had split up&lt;/a&gt; but were living together during the pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.laineygossip.com/Jeremy-Renner-on-Letterman-met-baby-mother-in-Vancouver/25733" target="_hplink"&gt;couple met in Vancouver&lt;/a&gt; when Renner was working on "Mission Impossible: Ghost Protocol," said Lainey Gossip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Renner, 44, was nominated for Academy Awards for his roles in "The Hurt Locker" in 2008 and "The Town" in 2010. He most recently starred in the "Bourne Legacy" and "Hansel and Gretel: Witch Hunters."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063178/thumbs/s-SONNI-PACHECO-JEREMY-RENNER-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Aletha Maybank, M.D., MPH: Time for Your Check-up!: How to Get the Most Out of Your Doctor's Visit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/aletha-maybank-md-mph/doctors-office-advice_b_2982086.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2982086</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T01:01:16Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T01:01:30Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A visit to the doctor's office can be overwhelming for many of us. There is so much to remember for an appointment slot that may only last for 15 minutes. But it doesn't have to be stressful.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Aletha Maybank, M.D., MPH</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/aletha-maybank-md-mph/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;A visit to the doctor's office can be overwhelming for many of us. There is so much to remember for an appointment slot that may only last for 15 minutes. But it doesn't have to be stressful. Having good health is partly dependent on effectively navigating the health system and learning how to better advocate for our families and ourselves. In the medical field, we call this being health literate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health literacy is the ability to get, process, and understand health information and services and to use that information to make appropriate and better choices about your health and medical care. Here are some steps within your power to start making the system work for you and to get the most out of your and your family's doctor's visit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In between Visits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;bull; Keep a medical journal, more commonly known as a personal health record (pHr) for each family member.  If you are comfortable with using Internet and mobile technology, there are many programs and apps that now support creating an electronic pHr.  Speak with your health professional regarding their preference on which one to use.   If you don't want to use the Internet or mobile technology, buy a notebook and simply write. The things to record are 1) any symptoms that happen including the time and day they appear and what makes the symptoms better or worse; 2) home test results such as temperature checks, glucose levels, blood pressure monitoring, etc.; 3) questions that come to mind that you want to remember to ask during the visit; 4) a list of medications taken including prescription, over-the-counter, and herbal medicines; 5) notes on new allergies to any medicines or foods; 6) a list of all your doctors or health professionals along with their specialty&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull; Talk with family members (parents, siblings, grandparents, etc.) to fully know your family health history.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull; Do your best to keep all appointments.  The timing of appointments is especially important for children.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;During the Visit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;bull; Bring you or your family member's personal health record or journal to the visit.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull; If it is a child's visit, a trusted adult should accompany the child.  Even for adults, it can be helpful to bring someone with you that you trust can communicate on your behalf in case you are ill, as well as help write down notes from the visit.  Taking someone with you is important especially if there is a language barrier or difficulty reading or understanding material given to you.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull; Ask the doctor to tell you your vital numbers and lab results. Write them down -- weight, height, blood pressure, and other important test and lab results.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull; Write down new medicines and their doses.  For children, keep your own record of immunizations or shots your child received.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull; Ask all questions that you may have. You have a right to do so no matter the question. Don't be embarrassed to ask questions.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull; Make sure you clearly understand any answers, diagnoses, and treatment plans provided to you. One of the best ways to demonstrate if you understand is for you to repeat what the doctor told you.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull; Do not hesitate to provide feedback to the doctor about the visit -- what you think did not go well and what did go well. It is always helpful to hear how you think we are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1048367/thumbs/s-HEALTH-CARE-mini.jpg?1" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: The Touching Gift Inside This Box</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/gabriel-wison-harry-potter-gifts_n_2980665.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2980665</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T22:37:13Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T22:37:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The package may have been delivered by the U.S.P.S. instead of an owl -- but for its recipient, it was nothing short of magical. A...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Emma Mustich</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-mustich/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;The package may have been delivered by the U.S.P.S. instead of an owl -- but for its recipient, it was nothing short of magical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 9-year-old boy named Gabe, who suffers from an autoimmune disease on the &lt;a href="http://intramural.nimh.nih.gov/pdn/web.htm" target="_hplink"&gt;PANDAS&lt;/a&gt; spectrum, received a box full of goodies from Universal Orlando's &lt;a href="https://www.universalorlando.com/harrypotter/" target="_hplink"&gt;Wizarding World Of Harry Potter&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday. It was a gift from Redditor &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/user/TheAdster" target="_hplink"&gt;TheAdster&lt;/a&gt;, who &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/1b84bg/my_son_who_has_an_autoimmune_disease_got_this_in/c94huln?context=3" target="_hplink"&gt;wasn't aware of the boy's medical condition&lt;/a&gt;, but knew the boy's mother via the social sharing site. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started nine days ago, with a discussion of the novelty shops at Orlando's Potter-themed park. Gabe's mother, who goes by pandas_mom , said her family found the stores too small and crowded on a recent trip to Universal -- so TheAdster &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/1aloxx/hey_harry_potter_fans_here_are_the_plans_for_your/c8z1pne" target="_hplink"&gt;offered to send&lt;/a&gt; souvenirs, including the &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/1aloxx/hey_harry_potter_fans_here_are_the_plans_for_your/c8yxdws" target="_hplink"&gt;chocolate frogs&lt;/a&gt;, Gabe had wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After receiving the package, pandas_mom &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/1b84bg/my_son_who_has_an_autoimmune_disease_got_this_in/" target="_hplink"&gt;posted photos of Gabe's reaction&lt;/a&gt; to Reddit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Story continues below gallery)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;iframe class="imgur-album" width="100%" height="550" frameborder="0" src="http://imgur.com/a/nbTrP/embed"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
She wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I cannot say how much getting this box today meant to my son. He has had a really difficult couple of months with his disease. His immune system is depressed, he had a seizure last month, his other symptoms have him miserable and angry, unable to make it through a day without tears and frustrations. It breaks our hearts. Today was especially difficult. My husband has been in the hospital for the last couple days, and really ill for days before that, and the loss of routine was hard on him. ... So to go on a late night run to the mailbox, and having the fun and suprise of a package addressed from "HOGWARTS SCHOOL" I just can't tell you. He grinned from ear to ear. ... You are my hero tonight, /u/TheAdster !&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the story and photos started making waves, other Redditors pitched in to take TheAdster's generosity one big step further, starting &lt;a href="http://www.giveforward.com/fundraiser/g452/gabesarmy" target="_hplink"&gt;a fundraising page for Gabe&lt;/a&gt; under the name Gabe's Army.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For his part, TheAdster &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/1b84bg/my_son_who_has_an_autoimmune_disease_got_this_in/c94inb1" target="_hplink"&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt;, "Sometimes in life things are all about timing -- when to say something, when not to say something, when to do something, etc. and when things aren't going so well sometimes it just takes a small notch of positivity to swing momentum the other way...."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062624/thumbs/s-BOX-FROM-HOGWARTS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>My Proudest Moment As A Stepparent</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/stepparents_n_2981073.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2981073</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T22:32:09Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T23:20:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Every stepparent remembers the moment they finally earned their stepkids' seal of approval. It's a meaningful moment -- as any stepparent can tell you, a...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Every stepparent remembers the moment they finally earned their stepkids' seal of approval. It's a meaningful moment -- as any stepparent can tell you, a stepchild's trust can be hard won, sometimes taking years and years to gain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/1b8qa9/as_a_stepdad_of_3_this_was_my_proudest_moment_to/" target="_hplink"&gt;Redditor Jedi_Hog shared his shiningest moment&lt;/a&gt; as a stepparent -- in meme form. Take a look here: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-29-ScreenShot20130329at3.02.26PM.png" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-29-ScreenShot20130329at3.02.26PM.png" width="398" height="402" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.quickmeme.com/meme/3tkwcq/" target="_hplink"&gt;quickmeme.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stepdad's success story won over Reddit, with fellow stepparents and stepkids weighing in with their personal stories in the comments. We were especially touched by Redditor MorganaLeFaye's &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/1b8qa9/as_a_stepdad_of_3_this_was_my_proudest_moment_to/" target="_hplink"&gt;sweet tribute to her stepdad: &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;My dad is the man who raised me. I met him when I was four.

&lt;p&gt;He's the one that put the band-aids on skinned knees and went to my school plays even though he really didn't want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He's the one who got very awkward whenever I would cry because he really didn't know what to do to fix me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He's the man who went to McDonalds or Taco Bell when my mom was working late and he was put in charge of "making us a healthy, well balanced dinner."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is the man who hooked the stereo speakers up to the TV when I was very young and turned our living room into a movie theater so we could watch Jurassic Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is the man who walked me down the aisle and cried on my wedding day as he told me how beautiful I looked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He may not be genetically related to me, but he is in every sense my father.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to extend the love by asking our readers to share their proudest moments as stepparents. Click through the slideshow below for some of our favorite responses, then head to the comments and tell us about your best stepparent stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--289220--HH&gt;`&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063084/thumbs/s-STEPPARENTING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Heartbreaking Photo Shows 8-Year-Old Syrian 'Rebel' With Cigarette, Gun</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/8-year-old-syrian-rebel-ahmed-heartbreaking-photo_n_2981437.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2981437</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T22:20:42Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T22:24:08Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It's a picture that is both haunting and heartbreaking. Dressed in red, an 8-year-old Syrian boy identified as Ahmed stares into the camera of American-born...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/meredith-bennettsmith/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;It's a picture that is both haunting and heartbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dressed in red, an 8-year-old Syrian boy identified as Ahmed stares into the camera of American-born photojournalist Sebastiano Tomada Piccolomini. The child's face is partially obscured by the smoke of a lit cigarette, and his small frame is dwarfed by the assault rifle slung around his shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Story continues below)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="8 year old syrian rebel" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062291/thumbs/o-8-YEAR-OLD-SYRIAN-REBEL-900.jpg?6" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt;Ahmed, the 8-year-old son of a FSA fighter, stands in front of a barricade were he assists his FSA comrades in the neighborhood of Salahadeen one of Aleppo's front lines. Aleppo, Syria, on March 27 2013. (Sebastiano Tomada / Sipa USA)&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Piccolomini's pint-sized "rebel" exemplifies the growing tragedy in Aleppo, a city on the front lines of Syria's ongoing civil war. The photographer has been documenting the &lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/world/photo-essay-native-new-yorker-sebastiano-tomada-piccolomini-face-ongoing-conflict-engulfing-syria-article-1.1300104" target="_hplink"&gt;struggle of the Free Syrian Army fighters&lt;/a&gt; for a series called "The Things They Carry," the New York Daily News reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the country's commercial center, Aleppo is currently divided by between soldiers loyal to President Bashar Assad and the rebel forces who oppose him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to German filmmaker Marcel Mettelsiefen, &lt;a href="http://www.channel4.com/news/syrias-descent-the-agony-of-aleppos-children" target="_hplink"&gt;conditions in the city border on unbearable&lt;/a&gt;, with only 30 doctors and nurses caring for hundreds of thousands of civilians. The New York Times reports that &lt;a href="http://latitude.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/03/29/the-stalemate-in-syria/" target="_hplink"&gt;rebel areas lack electricity, water, or any sort of economic stability.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the &lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/02/12/us-syria-crisis-un-idUSBRE91B19C20130212" target="_hplink"&gt;fighting broke out in Syria&lt;/a&gt; more than two years ago, the United Nations estimates that more than 70,000 people have been killed, Reuters notes.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062291/thumbs/s-8-YEAR-OLD-SYRIAN-REBEL-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Still 'Hangin'!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/holly-robinson-still-sees_n_2981383.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2981383</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T21:53:10Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T21:53:14Z</updated>
    
    <summary>"Hangin' With Mr. Cooper" may be a distant, yet fond memory for many fans of ABC's T.G.I.F. lineup, but the series' former stars Holly Robinson...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Leigh Weingus</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/leigh-weingus/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;"Hangin' With Mr. Cooper" may be a distant, yet fond memory for many fans of ABC's T.G.I.F. lineup, but the series' former stars Holly Robinson Peete and Mark Curry are still ... well, hangin'. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While filling in for Billy Bush as a guest host on Access Hollywood Live this week, Peete said she and Curry see each other all the time because their kids are in the same class. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"When you do a TV series with someone for five or six years, you either never want to see that person again or they're a permanent member of your family," Peete said. "The irony is that Mark's daughter and my son are in the same class so I hang with Mr. Cooper every day."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Hangin' With Mr. Cooper" aired from 1992 to 1997 and centered on single high-school teacher and coach Mr. Cooper (Curry), a man who got through every situation life threw his way with humor, including living with two female roommates, one being Peete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you surprised Peete and Curry still hang out?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--245349--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062974/thumbs/s-HOLLY-ROBINSON-PEETE-HANGIN-WITH-MR-COOPER-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Glenn D. Braunstein, M.D.: Let's Junk Junk-Food Advertising to Kids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/glenn-d-braunstein-md/junk-food-advertising-to-kids_b_2973238.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2973238</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T21:42:14Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T21:42:22Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The average toddler sees nearly three fast-food advertisements every day. And research shows that children younger than eight years old are not capable of understanding the intent of advertising and typically accept claims as fact. Television and print are only part of the problem.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Glenn D. Braunstein, M.D.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/glenn-d-braunstein-md/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;No matter how often you've warned your kids that you're not buying any junk food at the grocery store, they still badger you relentlessly. Many times, they win, because they have a smiling, laughing SpongeBob SquarePants backing them up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a virtual treasure trove of products emblazoned with SpongeBob and other characters enticing kids up and down every aisle, from boxes of Popsicles, Kraft Macaroni and Cheese and Yoplait Go-Gurt &amp;#8212; a single serving of which contains a fair portion of the total daily allowance of sugar recommended by the &lt;a href="http://life.familyeducation.com/nutritional-information/obesity/64270.html?page=1&amp;amp;detoured=1" target="_blank"&gt;American Heart Association&lt;/a&gt; for children. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to junk food, advertisers are outgunning well-intentioned parents, who know all too well it's tough going against the likes of SpongeBob, Dora or even LeBron James.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a recent report from the &lt;a href="http://www.ftc.gov/opa/2012/12/foodmarketing.shtm" target="_blank"&gt;Federal Trade Commission&lt;/a&gt;, food and beverage companies spent $1.8 billion marketing directly to children and teens in 2009. That may be a 15 percent decrease from the $2.1 billion spent in 2006, but that doesn't mean advertisers are getting softer. They're getting savvier. Interactive game websites for kids, Internet advertising, and product placement in movies, video games and &lt;a href="http://opinionator.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/01/05/why-do-stars-think-its-o-k-to-sell-soda/" target="_blank"&gt;TV shows&lt;/a&gt; are their new pathways. Coke cups accessorize the judges' table on &lt;em&gt;American Idol&lt;/em&gt;, while on the &amp;quot;X Factor,&amp;quot; folks have gone with Pepsi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast-food restaurants, which spent $4.2 billion on marketing in 2009, are likewise exploiting new opportunities, including banner ads on mobile websites, smartphone applications, and text messaging ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Campaigns aimed at kids operate on what the industry calls &amp;quot;pester power.&amp;quot; And boy, does it work. The average toddler sees nearly three fast-food advertisements every day; kids ages 6-11 view three-and-a-half ads; and teenagers, nearly five, according to a study by Yale's &lt;a href="http://news.yale.edu/2010/11/08/fast-food-restaurants-dish-unhealthy-marketing-youth-researchers-release-unprecedented-re" target="_blank"&gt;Rudd Center for Food Policy &amp;amp; Obesity&lt;/a&gt;. As a result, 40 percent of children between ages two and 11 ask to go to McDonald's at least once a week, according to the Rudd Center research. Fifteen percent of preschoolers ask daily. In the end, 84 percent of parents say they acquiesced and had taken their kids, ages two to 11, to a fast-food restaurant at least once in the past week.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's no small wonder that more than a third of &lt;a href="http://www.cdc.gov/healthyyouth/obesity/facts.htm" target="_blank"&gt;kids and teens&lt;/a&gt; today are overweight or obese and are being diagnosed with adult conditions like Type 2 diabetes. &lt;a href="http://thorax.bmj.com/content/early/2013/01/03/thoraxjnl-2012-202285" target="_blank"&gt;Recent research&lt;/a&gt; also suggests there may be a link between eating too much junk and an increased risk for asthma, severe eczema and rhinitis, a condition with allergy-like symptoms &amp;#8212; runny nose and itchy, watery eyes. The study found children and young teens who ate fast food three or more times a week were significantly more likely to have these problems. Researchers speculate that may be because fast food is high in saturated fatty acids, trans fatty acids, sodium, carbohydrates and sugar, and contains preservatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Marketing any product directly to young children is devious, but marketing those that contribute to a dangerous and preventable health epidemic should be banned. It makes no sense to wage programs like Michelle Obama's &lt;a href="http://www.letsmove.gov/" target="_blank"&gt;&amp;quot;Let's Move&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; or public-service announcements touting fruit and vegetable consumption while allowing junk-food giants to trumpet their contradictory message, armed with bigger budgets, celebrity endorsements, licensed characters and far greater exposure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://pediatrics.aappublications.org/content/118/6/2563.full" target="_blank"&gt;Research&lt;/a&gt; shows that children younger than eight years old are not cognitively and psychologically capable of understanding the intent of advertising and typically accept claims as fact. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, ads designed to promote healthy foods among kids can lose their potency when viewed in the same sitting as &lt;a href="http://www.apa.org/pubs/info/reports/advertising-children.aspx?item=2" target="_blank"&gt;commercials&lt;/a&gt; for junk food. We also know that eating habits developed in childhood can last a lifetime, which, of course, is why advertisers are so eager to snag costumers young. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's disappointing that stars like Pepsi spokes-celebrities LeBron James and the boy band One Direction are willing to sell their images to push empty calories to kids, especially since they, along with popular licensed characters, are such persuasive sales tools. In a &lt;a href="http://www.aap.org/en-us/about-the-aap/aap-press-room/Pages/Using-Cartoon-Characters-to-Market-Junk-Food.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt;, 40 children from age four to six were given three pairs of identical foods (graham crackers, gummy fruit snacks and carrots) packaged either with or without a popular cartoon character. After tasting both items in each pair, they were asked which tasted better. Overwhelmingly, the item that featured a cartoon character on the package was selected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.apa.org/monitor/jun04/protecting.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;American Psychological Association&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://pediatrics.aappublications.org/content/118/6/2563.full?sid=4c1d90cc-5eaf-4fb9-8b98-8504121da6c5" target="_blank"&gt;American Academy of Pediatrics&lt;/a&gt; recommend restricting child-directed advertising. Yet junk-food peddlers have managed to persuade lawmakers to let them &lt;a href="http://www.yaleruddcenter.org/what_we_do.aspx?id=25" target="_blank"&gt;regulate themselves&lt;/a&gt;. Can't you just hear SpongeBob laughing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late 1970s, the &lt;a href="http://ftc.gov/os/comments/foodmktgtokids-pra/526194-00005.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Federal Trade Commission&lt;/a&gt; thoroughly studied the issue and agreed that advertising to children younger than age six was unfair and deceptive. It proposed restrictions on TV commercials for kids. But the proposal was dropped because of political opposition and some difficulty over deciding how rules should be implemented. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of countries have managed to impose restrictions. Sweden and Norway don't allow advertising targeted to children younger than 12. Greece forbids toy advertising before 10 p.m. In Denmark and Belgium, child-directed advertising is significantly restricted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The province of &lt;a href="http://works.bepress.com/kathy_baylis/33/" target="_blank"&gt;Quebec&lt;/a&gt; in Canada banned fast-food advertising to children in television and print in 1978. As a result, fast-food sales have declined by an estimated 13 percent, and the childhood obesity rate in Quebec is significantly lower than the national average. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increasingly, though, television and print are only part of the problem. Eighty percent of kids under age five use the Internet weekly, and 60 percent of kids three and younger watch videos online. Check out the bookmarks on your child's computer, and you may be surprised to find interactive commercials masquerading as game sites, such as &lt;a href="http://www.bkcrown.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Burger King's BKCrown.com&lt;/a&gt;, McDonald's &lt;a href="http://www.happymeal.com/en_US/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;HappyMeal.com&lt;/a&gt;, Trix Cereal's &lt;a href="http://www.sillyrabbit.com/" target="_blank"&gt;sillyrabbit.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.gummibear.com/" target="_blank"&gt;gummibear.com&lt;/a&gt;. Websites also are frequently promoted on product packaging, sometimes directing kids there to find quiz answers or enter contests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, only baby steps have been made. &lt;i&gt;Monsters Inc.&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Toy Story&lt;/i&gt; fruit snacks notwithstanding, &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/06/05/business/media/in-nutrition-initiative-disney-to-restrict-advertising.html?pagewanted=all" target="_blank"&gt;Walt Disney Co&lt;/a&gt;. last year announced it would restrict advertisements on its various media outlets of foods that don't meet certain nutritional requirements. The new rules start in 2015, after existing contracts expire. This follows a 2006 initiative in which the house of mouse opted to phase out promotion of junk food to kids and at its theme parks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos also go to &lt;a href="http://www.bevnet.com/news/2013/moms-organic-market-eliminates-products-marketed-to-children" target="_blank"&gt;MOM's&lt;/a&gt; Organic Market, the 10-store chain in the Washington-Baltimore area that announced it was dropping all products with packaging that features licensed children's characters, including Dora the Explorer frozen soybeans and Elmo juice boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a start, but we need to finish the job, banning junk-food and fast-food peddlers from targeting kids who haven't even learned to tie their shoes. Until then, I urge parents to keep computers and televisions out of children's rooms and in a spot where you can see what's happening. Continue to preach the importance of healthy eating habits and, above all, hang tough in the grocery store. Don't let SpongeBob have the last laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1000582/thumbs/s-JUNK-FOOD-mini.jpg?5" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Matthew Broderick's New TV Role</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/matthew-broderick-cbs-pilot-tad-quill_n_2981569.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2981569</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T21:36:33Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T22:03:38Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Matthew Broderick has signed on to play the lead in CBS' multicamera comedy pilot from Tad Quill, according to Deadline. A veteran film and theater...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Laura Prudom</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/laura-prudom/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.deadline.com/2013/03/matthew-broderick-to-topline-cbs-tad-quill-comedy-pilot/" target="_hplink"&gt;Matthew Broderick has signed on to play the lead in CBS' multicamera comedy pilot from Tad Quill&lt;/a&gt;, according to Deadline. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A veteran film and theater actor who rarely does TV, Broderick will play Jack, "a recently widowed father who raises his 12-year old son while jumping back into the dating pool," in the pilot from CBS Television Studios. He reportedly took the role after a meeting with Quill and a "lengthy courtship" from the producers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Broderick's most notable movies include "Ferris Bueller's Day Off," "Glory" and "The Lion King." He has recently made guest appearances on "Modern Family" and "30 Rock," but if the pilot makes it to series, it will be Broderick's first lead TV role. Quill previously produced "Scrubs" and "Spin City."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deadline also notes that the Quill project was initially conceived and ordered to pilot three years ago, but was put on hold because the network and producers struggled to cast Broderick's role. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think Broderick sounds like a good fit for a CBS comedy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--235502--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063055/thumbs/s-MATTHEW-BRODERICK-CBS-PILOT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>What Your Kids Should Know About The Newest National Monuments</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/table-talk-new-national-monuments_n_2978941.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2978941</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T21:24:30Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T21:24:31Z</updated>
    
    <summary>This week's Family Dinner Table Talk, from HuffPost and The Family Dinner book: Over 100 years ago, President Theodore Roosevelt made Devils Tower in Wyoming...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nina Zipkin</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nina-zipkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This week's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tag/family-dinner-download" target="_hplink"&gt;Family Dinner Table Talk&lt;/a&gt;, from HuffPost and The Family Dinner book:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 100 years ago, President Theodore Roosevelt made &lt;a href="http://www.nps.gov/deto/index.htm" target="_hplink"&gt;Devils Tower&lt;/a&gt; in Wyoming America’s first national monument. &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/obama-national-monuments_n_2933014.html" target="_hplink"&gt;This week&lt;/a&gt;, President Obama added five more locations to the long list of venerated national landmarks that already includes Mount Rushmore, The Gateway Arch and the Statue of Liberty. The new sites are the &lt;a href="http://articles.baltimoresun.com/2013-03-26/news/bs-ed-tubman-20130326_1_harriet-tubman-black-woman-first-black-mayor" target="_hplink"&gt;Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Monument&lt;/a&gt; in Maryland; the &lt;a href="http://www.nps.gov/chyo/index.htm" target="_hplink"&gt;Charles Young Buffalo Soldiers National Monument&lt;/a&gt; in Ohio; the &lt;a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2013/03/25/presidential-proclamation-r-o-grande-del-norte-national-monument" target="_hplink"&gt;Rio Grande del Norte National Monument&lt;/a&gt; in New Mexico, the &lt;a href="http://blog.seattlepi.com/seattlepolitics/2013/03/25/obama-makes-it-legal-on-san-juan-islands-national-monument/ " target="_hplink"&gt;San Juan Islands National Monument&lt;/a&gt; in Washington state, and &lt;a href="http://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/2013/03/130326-delaware-first-state-national-monument-science-nation/" target="_hplink"&gt;First State National Monument&lt;/a&gt; in Delaware.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Tonight, let’s talk about the importance of preserving our natural sites and resources -- and honoring our country’s history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions for discussion&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have you ever visited any national monuments?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which national monuments would you most like to visit in the future?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we preserving enough? Is there anything in your town you hope will stay the same for the next hundred years?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;In her cookbook, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Family-Dinner-Great-Ways-Connect/dp/0446565466" target="_hplink"&gt;The Family Dinner&lt;/a&gt;, Laurie David talks about the importance of families making a ritual of sitting down to dinner together, and how &lt;a href="http://thefamilydinnerbook.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;family dinners&lt;/a&gt; offer a great opportunity for meaningful discussions about the day's news. "Dinner," she says, "is as much about digestible conversation as it is about delicious food."&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;We couldn't agree more. So HuffPost has &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/arianna-huffington/introducing-huffpost-fami_b_779610.html" target="_hplink"&gt;joined with Laurie&lt;/a&gt; and every Friday afternoon, just in time for dinner, our editors highlight one of the most compelling news stories of the week -- stories that will spark a lively discussion among the whole family.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062970/thumbs/s-NATIONAL-MONUMENTS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Purple Fig: That Mom Losing Patience With Her Son? Don't Judge Her</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/the-purple-fig/judgy-moms_b_2973476.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2973476</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T21:04:03Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T21:47:09Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When I became a mother five years ago I naively assumed that having a child meant a woman had grown up. Gone would be the petty insecurities, comparisons and judgements that women so cruelly share during the teenage years and beyond. I was wrong.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Purple Fig</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/the-purple-fig/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;When I became a mother five years ago I naively assumed that having a child meant a woman had grown up. Gone would be the petty insecurities, comparisons and judgements that women so cruelly share during the teenage years and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two children, two cities and many play dates and hours at the park later, I've made some wonderful mom friends. I've also been blown away by the cattiness and cruelty of some women who are permanently suspended in a junior high, mean-girls mindset, even with their own children watching and listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sidelong glances, whispers and blatant online bullying I've seen encouraged me to start a conversation with a group of my own mom friends. The stories each woman told me were sometimes hard to believe but they are all true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom you shun at the park because she's single and living with her parents? Don't judge her. She's going to university full-time to create a good life for her son. In the blink of an eye you could be her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://thepurplefig.com" target="_hplink"&gt;Check out more from The Purple Fig&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom who is losing her patience with a screaming child in the grocery store line-up? She had two hours of sleep last night because her children are sick and teething. Don't roll your eyes at her. Help her out. You will be her one day, guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom who puts her five-year-old in diapers at night? Don't judge her. Her child has a severe illness. Sleep is far more important than night time potty training. She also has to pour salt on her child's food to help with kidney function so don't judge her for that either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom that picked up McDonald's for her child on the way home? Don't judge her -- 99 per cent of the time she feeds her child good food. She's tired. She's had a long day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom who took a nap when you were visiting and didn't cook you supper? Don't judge her. She's suffering from a postpartum mood disorder and is just trying to cope and care for her children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom who lets her kids sleep in her bed? Don't judge her. She's creating security and comfort that will last a lifetime. She knows little-kid-snuggles only last for a little while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom who stopped breastfeeding too soon? Remember when you told her how sad it was that her child would get sick and die on formula? Remember when you told her that she and her baby wouldn't bond? Are you for real? She had thrush, was on two different meds to increase her milk supply and had multiple lactation consultants. It didn't work. She moved on and you should too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom who is still breastfeeding when her child is two? She's happy. Her child is happy. Leave them alone and stop staring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom who is too rushed to say hello at preschool drop-off? Her son has a life-threatening illness. She is so focused on his care that she doesn't even see you. Don't judge her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom who can't get her children to sleep well? She's tried everything. She's read all the books and gone to the seminars. You may be an expert on your own four children but you know nothing about her two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom you judged because she had a C-section while you had a natural birth? Even though you told her she didn't try hard enough and is a failure, she's pretty grateful that her child is alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom who is too easy on her kids and lets them get away with too much? She grew up afraid of a parent and refuses to repeat the pattern in her own family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom who had too many kids too close together? Don't judge her. Her children are happy and loved. On the other hand, don't judge the mom who only had one child either. You don't know the reasoning behind it and it's none of your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom who looks after her children 24/7 and (gasp!) doesn't work outside of the home? Maybe she actually likes it. Maybe she's doing what is best for her kids. She may even blog about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom who struggled with infertility for years and finally got pregnant with IVF? Don't judge her. You have no idea of the thoughts and pain that go into such an experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are rarely as they seem. I've grown a pretty thick skin when it comes to being judged by others for my parenting decisions. I do my best to accept that everyone makes different decisions for their families. Could you do the same? Most of us are our own worst critics anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, it's not about us. It's about our children. Let's cut each other some slack. We're supposed to be the grown-ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;By Ann Sorgard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://thepurplefig.com" target="_hplink"&gt;The Purple Fig&lt;/a&gt; is a community where women share personal and relatable stories; no ego, no shame. We're about life, love and all of the stuff that makes us yearn, squirm, and giggle. These stories make up the authentic and intriguing journey of a woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sign up for&lt;strong&gt; The Purple Fig newsletter&lt;/strong&gt; issued every Monday: &lt;a href="http://eepurl.com/rXSh1" target="_hplink"&gt;http://eepurl.com/rXSh1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See more from The Purple Fig&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://thepurplefig.com"target="_hplink"&gt;http://thepurplefig.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;On Facebook: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/thepurplefigmag" target="_hplink"&gt;http://www.facebook.com/thepurplefigmag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;On Twitter:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/thepurplefigmag"target="_hplink"&gt;http://twitter.com/thepurplefigmag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062716/thumbs/s-GOSSIP-MOMS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Federal Judge To Rule On Morning-After Pill For Teens</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/morning-after-pill-teenagers_n_2980942.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2980942</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T20:59:10Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T01:21:34Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A U.S. district court judge is expected to issue a ruling in the next few days on whether the Food and Drug Administration should make...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Laura Bassett</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/laura-bassett/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;A U.S. district court judge is expected to issue a ruling in the next few days on whether the Food and Drug Administration should make emergency contraception available over the counter for all women and girls of child-bearing potential. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. Health and Human Services Secretary Kathleen Sebelius &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/12/14/plan-b-birth-control-morning-after-pill-obama_n_1148769.html" target="_hplink"&gt;upset women's health advocates&lt;/a&gt; in December 2011 when she &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/12/07/plan-b-over-the-counter_n_1134284.html" target="_hplink"&gt;overruled an FDA recommendation &lt;/a&gt;that the Plan B One-step, or the morning-after pill, be sold over the counter without age restrictions. Currently, the pill is only available behind the counter to women 17 years and older, or with a prescription for those who are younger. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following Sebelius' controversial decision, the FDA rejected a citizens' petition filed by the Center for Reproductive Rights to lift the age restrictions on all levonorgestrel-based emergency contraception and sell it on regular pharmacy shelves. The group then challenged Sebelius and the FDA in a U.S. district court, arguing that both decisions were based on politics rather than the sound recommendations of the scientific and medical communities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Politics has completely interfered with the process," said Janet Crepps, senior counsel for CRR. "The medical people within FDA said there was enough evidence to allow emergency contraception to be made available completely over the counter without restrictions, but [Sebelius] came back and said there was insufficient evidence to support making it available to younger minors. If you look at the reasoning, it doesn't hold up."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sebelius and the FDA, who are being jointly represented by attorneys from the U.S. Justice Department, argued in court that Sebelius' decision to overrule the FDA recommendation was based on a lack of scientific evidence demonstrating that girls younger than 17 can effectively and safely use the morning-after pill on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FDA did not immediately respond to calls for comment. A representative for HHS referred HuffPost to a &lt;a href="http://www.hhs.gov/news/press/2011pres/12/20111207a.html" target="_hplink"&gt;2011 press release that coincided with Sebelius' decision&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. District Court Judge Edward Korman is expected to decide within the next week whether to uphold the restrictions on emergency contraception, to lower the age restriction but keep the drug behind the counter at pharmacies, or to ask the FDA to remove the age limit completely and sell the pill over the counter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctors and women's health advocates largely disagree with Sebelius' decision and believe that putting any barriers between teenagers and contraception does more harm than good. Emergency contraception must be taken within 72 hours of sexual intercourse in order to be effective, and requiring girls under the age of 17 to obtain a prescription for it could prevent them from being able to take it in time. Moreover, young adolescents and low-income women may not have the government-issued ID required to obtain the pill from a pharmacist behind the counter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We have the highest teen pregnancy and unplanned pregnancy rate in the developed world," said Tracey Wilkinson, a pediatrician and fellow with Physicians for Reproductive Health. "The way we currently access contraception is not effective enough to change that. Most teens use condoms as their main form of birth control, which isn't very effective if they don't use them consistently or the condom breaks. They need access in a timely manner to an alternative form of birth control." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilkinson said the morning-after pill is the hormonal equivalent to about four regular birth control pills and that parents should not be concerned at all about the medication's safety. "I would tell parents that a bottle of Tylenol is much more dangerous than emergency contraception," she said. "If you take an overdose of Tylenol, you can cause irreversible liver damage, but those risks are not present with emergency contraception."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062900/thumbs/s-MORNING-AFTER-PILL-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>This Teen Built A Biofuel Lab... In Her Bedroom! (VIDEO)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/sara-volz-17-year-old-mak_n_2979408.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2979408</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T20:41:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T20:49:20Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Take a look under most teens' beds and you're likely to find old socks, some dust bunnies or maybe a secret diary that's meant to...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Taylor Trudon</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/taylor-trudon/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Take a look under most teens' beds and you're likely to find old socks, some dust bunnies or maybe a secret diary that's meant to be kept hidden from prying eyes (a.k.a. your annoying little brother). But for 17-year-old Sara Volz, instead of using the space under her bed to collect dust, it's home to her &lt;a href="http://news.yahoo.com/video/gma-teen-scientists-amazing-breakthrough-080000284.html" target="_hplink"&gt;groundbreaking algae biofuel lab&lt;/a&gt;. Yup, that's right: Volz grows algae under her bed, allowing her to spearhead cutting-edge research -- and win a $100,000 scholarship in the process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volz, the 2013 Intel Science Talent Search winner who beat out 1,700 other nationwide whiz kids, is taking algae to a new level. She &lt;a href="http://news.yahoo.com/video/gma-teen-scientists-amazing-breakthrough-080000284.html" target="_hplink"&gt;explained to ABC News&lt;/a&gt; that the natural oils produced by algae can be converted into biofuels, which can be used in diesel engines. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's great because it means you're not relying on petroleum-based fuels. You're not relying on fossil fuels," Volz said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that this isn't necessarily economically feasible, but Volz may have found a way to work around this hurdle. Using the resources of her lab-based bedroom -- decorated with green algae-filled beakers and microscopes -- Volz is working to make biofuels ultimately more cost efficient by increasing the natural oil production of the algae through &lt;a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/technology/futureoftech/whiz-kid-grows-algae-under-her-bed-wins-intel-science-1C8835461" target="_hplink"&gt;"artificial selection."&lt;/a&gt; The teen even admitted to adjusting her sleep schedule to accommodate her work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, the science star (and captain of her school's Science Bowl team) &lt;a href="http://grist.org/list/awesome-17-year-old-geek-wins-100000-for-her-bedroom-biofuel-lab/" target="_hplink"&gt;will be taking her talents&lt;/a&gt; to the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, where she'll begin college in the fall. While it's unclear if Volz will be moving her algae  into her college dorm room, we can't wait to see what she does next (but we hope it involves more sleep!).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;object id="flashObj" width="402" height="286" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=9,0,47,0"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&amp;isUI=1" /&gt;&lt;param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /&gt;&lt;param name="flashVars" value="videoId=2223987627001&amp;playerID=1995251661001&amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAqwZd9wk~,X1Exj3sUi-3G45_fNGdn-gUaDz11r4TZ&amp;domain=embed&amp;dynamicStreaming=true" /&gt;&lt;param name="base" value="http://admin.brightcove.com" /&gt;&lt;param name="seamlesstabbing" value="false" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="swLiveConnect" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;embed src="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&amp;isUI=1" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" flashVars="videoId=2223987627001&amp;playerID=1995251661001&amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAqwZd9wk~,X1Exj3sUi-3G45_fNGdn-gUaDz11r4TZ&amp;domain=embed&amp;dynamicStreaming=true" base="http://admin.brightcove.com" name="flashObj" width="402" height="286" seamlesstabbing="false" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowFullScreen="true" allowScriptAccess="always" swLiveConnect="true" pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[h/t &lt;a href="http://news.yahoo.com/video/gma-teen-scientists-amazing-breakthrough-080000284.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Yahoo! News&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062676/thumbs/s-SARA-VOLZ-ALGAE-BIOFUEL-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>McDonald's Nutritionist: Our Food Is Healthy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/mcdonalds-nutrition_n_2980991.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2980991</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T20:37:28Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T20:37:29Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Just days before a study from the Center for Science in the Public Interest lambasted fast food restaurants for the nutritional failures of their children's...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rachel-tepper/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Just days before a study from the Center for Science in the Public Interest &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/kids-meals-fail-nutrition-test_n_2969810.html" target="_hplink"&gt;lambasted fast food restaurants for the nutritional failures of their children's meals&lt;/a&gt;, McDonald's director of nutrition, Cindy Goody, &lt;a href="http://www.sltrib.com/sltrib/entertainment2/56057810-223/mcdonald-nutrition-eat-calories.html.csp?page=1" target="_hplink"&gt;defended the chain's menu offerings as healthy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We're making nutrition more mainstream at McDonald's today," Goody told The Salt Lake Tribune on Tuesday. She noted that in the past few years, McDonald's has added oatmeal dishes, chicken sandwiches with buns that boast 8 grams of whole grains and a new Happy Meal with apples and a smaller portion of fries. Chocolate milk, once 1 percent fat, is now fat-free. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"All of that came from careful listening to moms in particular and recognizing people are becoming more mindful about what they're putting in their mouth," she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goody went on to declare that processed food could "absolutely" be healthy, offering up examples from her own diet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I'm a mom of a 2-year-old and I gained the prerequisite [sic] 30 pounds and I was able to lose all that baby weight. I don't have a fast metabolism and I eat at McDonald's once or twice a day. Really. Plus I work out the recommended 5 hours a week. I may eat an Egg McMuffin and apples. My new thing is to have either a hamburger or a double hamburger, no cheese, two bags of apple slices and an oatmeal cookie and still keeping it under 600 calories.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goody spoke to the Tribune as part of McDonald's promotion of its new McWrap line. Earlier this week, Advertising Age wrote about an internal McDonald's memo that &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/mcdonalds-chicken-mcwrap-subway-buster_n_2950605.html" target="_hplink"&gt;referred to the McWrap has a "Subway buster"&lt;/a&gt;; McDonald's hopes to chip away at its rival's popularity with millennial customers. Depending on whether one chooses grilled or deep-fried chicken, the wraps range from 360 to 600 calories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Center for Science in the Public Interest study, Subway's eight children's offerings are &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/kids-meals-fail-nutrition-test_n_2969810.html" target="_hplink"&gt;exceptions to the usual fast food fare for kids&lt;/a&gt;. All met the center's nutrition criteria; kid-sized subs at Subway come with apple slices; and low-fat milk or bottled water is offered in place of soda.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062795/thumbs/s-MCDONALDS-NUTRITIONIST-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: These Babies Are NOT Impressed With The Easter Bunny</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/babies-not-impressed-easter-bunny_n_2979970.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2979970</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T20:15:23Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T20:30:36Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Santa could have warned the Easter Bunny about this situation. When it comes time to pose for photos with real-life holiday icons, kids are less...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Samakow</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-samakow/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/03/kids-on-santas-lap-pictures_n_2213268.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Santa could have warned&lt;/a&gt; the Easter Bunny about this situation. When it comes time to pose for photos with real-life holiday icons, kids are less than enthusiastic. But those not-quite-perfect shots are inevitably adorable and way more entertaining than expected. We asked the &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/huffpostparents" target="_hplink"&gt;HuffPost Parents Facebook community&lt;/a&gt; to submit Easter photos -- and have not been disappointed with the cuteness/hilarity pouring into our inboxes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it's your turn! Check out the gallery below, then send a photo of your little ones and the Easter Bunny to &lt;a href="mailto:parents@huffingtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;parents@huffingtonpost.com&lt;/a&gt; or by pressing "add a slide" below. (And yes, smiling kids are welcome too.)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062422/thumbs/s-BABIES-KIDS-EASTER-BUNNY-PHOTOS-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Liz Joynt Sandberg: Primal Whimper</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/liz-joynt-sandberg/primal-whimper_b_2973740.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2973740</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T20:12:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T20:12:22Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The babysitter tells me that Ida was missing me a lot. I awkwardly fork over a handful of cash. I've been in charge of a kid who just wanted to be with her parents, too. I've also been the kid who wanted to be with her parents. Now I'm the mother who was missed. It's hard.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Liz Joynt Sandberg</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/liz-joynt-sandberg/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;It's just that I've been gone all day. Doing things like rehearsing &lt;a href="http://chicagoimprovfestival.org/events/1-deep-just-ben-and-liz-joynt-sandberg/" target="_hplink"&gt;the piece that premieres in less than two weeks&lt;/a&gt;, and then having a meeting to plan doing a better job of writing on the Internet. Good things -- things that I really like. But things that still take it out of me. My brain is fried to the point that I doubt my ability to properly read a recipe. Dinner is going to be dicey.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I love the babysitter. She's my favorite. But when I get home, she tells me that Ida had a hard time today -- was missing me a lot. I awkwardly fork over a handful of cash to the beloved babysitter, feeling a little bad for her because I've been there. I've been in charge of a kid who just wanted to be with her parents before and it's hard. I've been the kid who wanted to be with her parents before, too. Now I'm the mother who was missed, and who will pay. Maybe just cash this time, maybe more. I know this thing inside and out. It's hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's hard that the second beloved babysitter is out the door. Ida, having reached her edge, throws a magnum fit. It's hard when someone who was allegedly desperate for you punches you in the face. It's hard to know how to parent desperation. It's hard to be the parent you want to be in the face of biological freak-out. It's moments like this when the terror of "forever, no matter what" sets in. A full-on mother-daughter double freak-out where all psychic bases are covered (but it just looks like any other hug, really). It's like a way less fun, somehow even more insane Laser Floyd show in your brain. Except it's your life. You know you won't always feel this way. You know she won't either. But that awareness is like a fart in a whirlwind when you're both feeling so decimated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, all I can think to say to Ida when we reach this point of meltdown is, "It's hard to be 3. It's hard to be a mother. We're having a hard time." Sometimes, this is what it looks like to do our best. When there is no "out" and only "through," telling the truth of our stripped-down reality is the best I can do. Sometimes, we are having a hard time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I woke up dreading telling Ida that it was another babysitter day -- that I'd be gone a lot again. I thought about skipping my class (and thereby having to drop out of the program I'm in, which in that moment, felt like equal parts failure and sweet relief. You know, the usual). But as I walked in my bare feet, being very quiet as I crept past Ida's closed bedroom door on my way to the bathroom, I overheard her talking to her stuffed sheep. "Sheep, I know it's hard to be Sheep. I always come back, Sheep. I have projects to do like school and dancing and going to Pump It Up." And for whatever weird reason, it got a little easier. Somehow, knowing that Ida had an understanding (weird, and Sheep-specific as it may be) of my being gone -- of how it feels to be me -- was a huge comfort. And then, of course, came the awesome realization that I gave that to her. Just by saying "sometimes it's hard to be 3," she knew that I care about how it feels to be her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're really doing it. We're a family. Hard as it can be in all these small ways sometimes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-29-LizJoyntSandberg.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-29-LizJoyntSandberg.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-29-LizJoyntSandberg-thumb.jpg" width="500" height="666" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post originally appeared in &lt;a href="http://www.rebelliousmagazine.com/_blog/PLUCK/post/Primal_Whimper/" target="_hplink"&gt;Rebellious Magazine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062820/thumbs/s-LIZ-JOYNT-SANDBERG-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
