<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jamie McGonnigal: Husband Threatens Custody Suit After Ex-wife Befriends 'Known Homosexual'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jamie-mcgonnigal/custody-suit-ex-wife-gay-friend_b_2926903.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2926903</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T22:16:01Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T22:16:09Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Kelly's friend Chris has no record of being a child predator, or really any criminal record whatsoever, but the lawyer's letter also threatens to pursue criminal proceedings against him merely for babysitting Kelly's son.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jamie McGonnigal</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jamie-mcgonnigal/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Here's one for the books. A Roman Catholic father in Maryland has asked his lawyer, Paul C. Sullivan, to pen one of the most horrific pieces of undeniable bigotry that I have seen in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ed Taylor and Kelly Robertson were married, had two sons and then divorced (as has been known to happen). Kelly was awarded custody of the children, with visitation rights for Ed. Since then, it seems that Kelly has become friends with a gay man, Chris. Kelly has since remarried, and she sometimes asks Chris to babysit her kids (as has been known to happen).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, that's not OK with ultra-Catholic Ed. The following letter was sent to Kelly with regard to her parenting. In the letter, Paul Sullivan engages in a homophobic tirade ignorantly linking being gay with being a child predator, claiming that by having a gay person around the house, Kelly is "encouraging a homosexual lifestyle," and threatening investigations and custody trials should Kelly not reverse the child's dangerous course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the lawyer and father have been in communication with the sheriff, the county commissioners, the vice principal and the guidance counselor of the middle school that Kelly's son attends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelly's friend Chris has no record of being a child predator, or really any criminal record whatsoever, but the lawyer's letter also threatens to pursue criminal proceedings against him merely for babysitting Kelly's son.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this were 1950, I might understand some of the homophobic and vitriolic things being claimed here by Paul Sullivan, but it's 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the full text of the letter, followed by images of it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Dear Mrs. XXXXXX
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;I have been retained by Mr. XXX again to address parenting issues related to your two (2) sons. As you know, there has been considerable difficulty recently related to your refusal to support and encourage the children's Roman Catholic faith and certain biblical precepts related to lifestyle choices. It appears as if you are encouraging a homosexual lifestyle for the children and allowing your eldest, XXXX at age 13 to be placed in an environment where he could, and likely would, be exposed to a child predator.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;As you know this case was previously assigned to Judge Kenneth long who is currently the administrative judge for the Washington County Circuit Court in Hagerstown. In the event you continue the destructive parenting that encourages XXXX' exploration of decadent choices in behavior, we will have no alternative but to file to obtain sole legal custody and sole physical custody of both children. We have been in communication with Sheriff XXXX, the vice principal of XXXX Middle School, the guidance counselor at XXXX Middle School and the president of the XXXX County Commissioners, seeking their assistance and support in helping XXXX change the path which you seem to be encouraging.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;It may be necessary for us to file a CINA petition, because the actions taken at his school related to detention do not seem to be having any corrective effect. This child appears to be out of control because of your refusal to co-parent with Mr. XXXX on Saturday, March 16th at 8:30 PM as ordered by the court. It is our understanding that you allowed XXXX to stay overnight at the home of a known homosexual whose probable intentions related to XXXX are suspect. Further investigation may lead to the request for criminal charges against that individual due to XXXX minority.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;We're attempting to obtain additional assistance to help XXXX abate the current course you have encouraged him to travel. You seem not to understand the eventual adverse consequences that may occur for XXXX and which could adversely affect him for a lifetime.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;If, however, you would be taking the position in court that you are not encouraging XXXX in the way it is believed you are, and are in fact unable to adequately discipline XXXX or institute and enforce parental boundaries that are needed, you certainly have the option to enter into a consent decree allowing Mr. XXXX to have sole legal and sole physical custody of the children so that he will have the authority, within the bounds of law, to take the corrective action needed to safeguard the best interests of the children.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Please do not hesitate to contact me if you have any questions concerning this matter. If you are agreeable to the entry of a consent order as suggested above, please call me at your earliest convenience and I will prepare it for your review and signature.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Thank you and kindest regards,
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Very truly yours,
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Paul C. Sullivan&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHOTOS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-21-392930_10200966632633571_559762508_n.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-21-392930_10200966632633571_559762508_n.jpg" width="600" height="825" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-21-580977_10200966632793575_1531958428_n.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-21-580977_10200966632793575_1531958428_n.jpg" width="600" height="825" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Some further research and a conversation with Kelly has brought some more information to light. It turns out that Ed has released some videos about his wife, "&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JUbOhjSUXzw" target="_hplink"&gt;The Drug Slut&lt;/a&gt;," and it turns out that their son's "behavior problems" include getting detention for talking in class and simply not wanting to participate in the extreme dogma that his father tries to force upon him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ed's organization, Maryland's Fathers Rights League, is also known for lobbying against the &lt;a href="http://wn.com/righteous_anger_of_exiled_fathers,_the_only_sane_response" target="_hplink"&gt;Violence Against Women Act&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050342/thumbs/s-EDTAYLORCUSTODYSUITLETTER-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Eva Glettner: An Extra Chromosome of Awesome</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/eva-glettner/an-extra-chromosome-of-aw_b_2926340.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2926340</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T22:14:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T22:14:19Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Today is 3/21 which is an important number because people with Down Syndrome have an extra copy (for a grand total of three) of the twenty-first chromosome. My brother, Jacob, owns that extra chromosome. No, seriously. He tells it who's boss.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Eva Glettner</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/eva-glettner/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Today is &lt;a href="http://www.worlddownsyndromeday.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;World Down Syndrome Day&lt;/a&gt;. This is a real thing. The United Nations General Assembly says so, and the date is quite significant. Today is 3/21 which is an important number because people with Down Syndrome have an extra copy (for a grand total of three) of the twenty-first chromosome. My brother, Jacob, owns that extra chromosome. No, seriously. He tells it who's boss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mother has always made that very clear. We were never embarrassed by Jacob's differences, because that is part of what makes him so special. If kids would ever comment on Jacob's appearance, us siblings would always jump in and say "and that's what makes him awesome." As a child, he had the most enviable blonde and curly hair. My mom would joke "it's that extra chromosome at work."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirty years ago, my parents were up against a different world. Down Syndrome was something that was whispered and not discussed. That would NOT work in our family. My parents became Jacob's advocates and never settled for less than the best. Jacob was enrolled in so many different types of therapies not to change him, but to make him thrive. And thrive he does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He can't walk down the street without saying "hi" to at least one person that he knows. Because while everyone else is too busy being busy, Jacob looks around and says "hi" or some form of "hey there, good buddy." Everyone is Jacob's buddy. This extra chromosome is on to something here. Jacob is beyond special. He recognizes the importance of friendship and values these relationships. He is always the first person to post a "Happy Birthday" on a friend's Facebook page or message me at night to tell me "You are a great mom, sister friend." People need to hear positive praise. We live in a society that forgets that being mean isn't something to be coveted. His messages make my evening. Sometimes they make my week. I love being both his sister and his friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacob reminds people what is really important. Most of the time it isn't at all what they thought. It's the value of a community. Jacob has been embraced by this community. But he's really lucky. My parents are tenacious and adamant that "good enough" is never enough for Jacob. He is entitled to the best that life has to offer. My parents advocated for him when they thought that his education was subpar, a bus route too long, or extracurricular activities that weren't inclusive enough or at all. They paved the way, but now Jacob has mowed down that route in search of the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People thought that Jacob wouldn't be toilet trained, would never learn to read, write or swim. How wrong they all were. He's a social media maven. Take that, naysayers. #tenaciousJAKE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Jacob &lt;a href="www.huffingtonpost.com/eva-glettner/down-syndrome_b_2489374.html" target="_hplink"&gt;finally got his driver's permit.&lt;/a&gt; And he only had one mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050335/thumbs/s-DOWN-SYNDROME-DAY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Charity Curley Mathews: Out With Plastic, In With Porcelain: Why I Replaced the Kids' Dishes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/charity-curley-mathews/out-with-plastic-in-with-_b_2916417.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2916417</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T21:56:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T21:56:48Z</updated>
    
    <summary>As a mom who blogs about cooking for kids, there are two things that I keep reading about: an inspiring Montessori approach to eating, and weird news stories about BPA. That's why I decided to pack up the plastic dishes this week. The new ones are glass (gulp), porcelain (double gulp) and metal (actually, no gulp).</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Charity Curley Mathews</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/charity-curley-mathews/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;The time has come. As a mom who &lt;a href="http://foodlets.com" target="_hplink"&gt;blogs about cooking for kids&lt;/a&gt;, there are two things that I keep reading about: an inspiring &lt;a href="http://livingmontessorinow.com/2011/09/12/montessori-monday-table-setting/" target="_hplink"&gt;Montessori approach&lt;/a&gt; to eating, and &lt;a href="http://www.lifelinescreening.com/health-updates/healthy-you/healthy-cooking/foods-might-serve-up-high-levels-of-chemicals-found-in-plastics.aspx?SourceCd=LETT-928" target="_hplink"&gt;weird news stories about BPA&lt;/a&gt;. That's why I decided to pack up the plastic dishes this week. The new ones are glass (gulp), porcelain (double gulp) and metal (actually, no gulp). They're designed to &lt;a href="http://foodlets.com/2012/09/25/5-ways-to-teach-toddlers-table-manners/" target="_hplink"&gt;teach little kids good eating habits&lt;/a&gt;, without exposing them to chemicals along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montessori is pretty popular here in the U.S. (and indeed all the Montessori preschools in our part of North Carolina are full), and this approach to eating involves giving even the littlest kids real glasses, plates and utensils so they can truly learn how to master them. The logic goes like this: If a plastic glass falls off the table and doesn't break, the consequences are fewer than they would be with glass. I'll say!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's not for the faint of heart though. A friend of mine who lives in Amsterdam sent his daughter to a local Montessori preschool and cringed when he told us about visiting for lunch one day. "They all use glasses, real glasses, and set the table themselves. Everyone's wearing a little apron. Sure enough, a cup crashes on the floor about five seconds after we get there, and there's glass everywhere. But they just clean it right up and carry on." He thought it was really stressful, and I don't blame him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it's also about trust. Audrey Butters says in her blog &lt;a href="http://iheartmontessori.wordpress.com/2012/11/20/setting-the-table-products-we-love/" target="_hplink"&gt;I heart Montessori&lt;/a&gt;, "Real plates, bowls and glasses portray to the child 'You are trusted' and build confidence." Along those lines, our kids love doing everything that Mom and Dad do, even more than they like drinking out of a monkey-shaped sippy cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually like our new cups which are just little 3.25 oz. juice glasses and best of all, they're quite sturdy. We have three very small people (3 1/2, 2 years and 9 months, though he's got help) drinking out of them, spilling them and picking them up off the floor again. So far, nary a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plain white plates are also a hit, though I suspect easier to shatter. That's okay though. They're also less expensive (picked up at World Market) and that's one of the tenants of the Montessori approach at home. Use real stuff, but buy it inexpensively, even from a garage sale, so replacements are easy on the wallet. I also like white because replacements always match (at least well enough) and we can dress things up elsewhere with place mats, napkins and tablecloths. Also, no one has to cry over who has the pink bowl ever again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there are hand-me-downs. The kids' "new" bowls are dipping bowls purchased from Pier 1 about 10 years ago, for a couple bucks each. And last, we've stocked the kids' cupboard with forks and spoons from our regular utensil collection -- they use the salad forks and dessert spoons. It's actually the stainless steel set that we registered for in our wedding almost five years ago now, but they're so sturdy and there are so many of them that it's a perfect way to actually USE our stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One more thing about the kids' cupboard: it's awesome. Even ours who are 3 1/2 and 2-years-old can set the table, and feel really proud about it. Those are two things I'd like to foster from here on out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But best of all, everything the kids are eating from now is toxin-free. Plastic gear is easy to clean and amazingly durable, but these news stories about how dangerous plastic is for kids just aren't going away. So the dishes will have to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-21-charitycurleymatthews.jpeg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-21-charitycurleymatthews.jpeg" width="600" height="400" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050285/thumbs/s-REAL-PLATES-KIDS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>masalamommas: How Single Parents Can Keep Their Kids Safe From Bullying</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/masalamommas/children-of-divorce-and-bullying_b_2925338.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2925338</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T21:38:05Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T21:36:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary>All across the country, we're hearing and seeing incidents that involve bullying at an alarming rate. As a parent of children coming from a hostile environment, like divorce, I have a fairly different set of responsibilities in addition to the traditional safe-guarding of our children.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>masalamommas</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/masalamommas/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;All across the country, we're hearing and seeing incidents that involve bullying at an alarming rate. We read and hear stories of triumphant celebrations of situations that are brought to light by victims as they overcome the oppression. Sadly, with that are heartbreaking stories of those that succumbed to the power play between them and the bully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I needed to confront this monster face to face myself as one of my sons informed me of an episode that took place with him. I have never had to face this before as their dad handled such conflicts. My first reaction was to march to this other child's home who dared to think he could dominate, hurt and threaten MY son! Common sense prevailed and the thought was just that...a thought. It's heartbreaking to one day realize that there is something, someone in existence that's playing a role in preventing you from protecting your children. Nothing makes a parent feel more powerless and helpless than the inability to keep their children safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is bullying? "Bullying is unwanted, aggressive behaviour among school aged children that involves a real or perceived power imbalance. The behaviour is repeated, or has the potential to be repeated, over time. &lt;a href="http://www.stopbullying.gov" target="_hplink"&gt;Bullying&lt;/a&gt; includes actions such as making threats, spreading rumours, attacking someone physically or verbally, and excluding someone from a group on purpose. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been quite a bit of "how to" and "what to do" propaganda in circulation in light of recent events. Yes, I agree that bullying is unnecessary, preventable and without a doubt tragic. I also agree that there are certain steps that both a parent and the child must take in order for the acts to be contained and stopped! I can sit here and tell you that as a parent, I DID those very things that all agencies, websites, counsellors and advocates tell a parent that they are "supposed" to do. That worked fine when my kids were little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens when they become teenagers and are now caught up in the peer pressure of "Don't Be a Snitch"? What happens when the stigma of "snitching" on peers overwhelms your child's instincts to trust the system? Why is it so difficult for so many teens to follow the guidelines that were instilled in them from a very young age? "Snitching" happens to be a term common among teens and is something I've been dealing with recently. It segregates them from the accepted group...the one that stands out...the one that is now a target to be bullied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BLOG CONTINUES AFTER SLIDESHOW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--222925--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It's one thing when they're able to come home and talk to dad about this. What now that dad isn't around, and mom is the one you rely on? The simplest of solutions was counter intimidation. In spite of all that we're taught, the reality and my experience has been that an alpha personality needs to make themselves present in a way that basically shows the opponent -- hey, don't mess with me! I realize that is counter-intuitive to everything we are taught on how to handle such conflicts"? In a classic textbook scenario, yes, I would 100 per cent follow the steps on how to resolve this conflict:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    1) Walk away from the situation&lt;br /&gt;
    2) Notify the yard duty and/or teacher&lt;br /&gt;
    3) Inform the parents&lt;br /&gt;
    4) Escalate to Principal if needed&lt;br /&gt;
    5) Mediate with parents of other child(ren) if necessary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a recent article in&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/claire-n-barnes-ma/divorce-children-and-bull_b_1916756.html" target="_hplink"&gt; the Huffington Post&lt;/a&gt;, children who are upset or withdrawn because their parents have separated -- especially if they've had to move and change communities or schools -- are quickly identified by bullies as easy marks."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a parent of children coming from a &lt;a href="http://masalamommas.com/2012/01/03/im-getting-divorce-single-moms-journey/" target="_hplink"&gt;hostile&lt;/a&gt; environment, I have a fairly different set of responsibilities in addition to the traditional safe-guarding of our children. We have to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a)  Establish a rapport and a relationship with teachers &amp; school authorities that are very open and candid. They are our allies, our ears, and our eyes in an extremely vulnerable and sensitive time of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b)  Establish trust and open communication with your child in the event that an unfortunate incident (be it bullying or something else) occurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c) Don't react -- Remember, your teen is feeling the emotions 100 times more magnified than you are. They're the ones LIVING the hell day to day. Be sensitive to them and the situation. Most importantly, LISTEN to them.&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;br /&gt;
d)  Make yourself available -- it's easy to get lost in your own drama. Make them a priority. Think back to when you were their age and put yourself in their shoes. All they want is for you to listen and understand them.&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
e) Actions speak louder than words. Show, not just tell them that they are a priority. Don't assume that they know what's on your and their mind. Ask, probe and Yes... be nosy! Resistance today is welcomed tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;f)  Instil in them early on that they are not alone! It's easy as a teen to find an excuse to isolate yourself. Be a nag, be inquisitive -- do it lovingly, stay involved in their day-to-day life.&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;
g) Be there for them. As clichéd as this sounds -- BE THERE! Refer to my post on &lt;a href="http://masalamommas.com/2012/07/17/flying-solo-column-from-single-moms-perspective/" target="_hplink"&gt;"Let's Go for A Drive"&lt;/a&gt; When they open the door to communicating with you, nothing else should take priority! Listen, talk, verbalize, communicate and connect with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are not guaranteed rules or techniques for helping to curtail bullies. They are however guides to establishing trust and understanding within your family dynamics that have worked for me and my two sons, that may prevent and help a situation that could have otherwise let to tragedy or destruction. As a parent who values and prides in a good relationship with her adolescent children, I cannot stress to you enough the importance of establishing trust, transparency and communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Vaishali Sharda &lt;br /&gt;
Follow Vaishali on Twitter&lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/v4vaishali" target="_hplink"&gt; @v4vaishali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about Vaishali's story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://masalamommas.com/2012/01/03/im-getting-divorce-single-moms-journey/" target="_hplink"&gt;I'm Getting a Divorce&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://masalamommas.com/2012/06/04/flying-solo-whats-name/" target="_hplink"&gt;Getting Your Identity Back After Divorce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://masalamommas.com/2012/09/03/flying-solo-real-talk-challenging-subjects-with-kids/" target="_hplink"&gt;Talking Through Challenging Subjects With Kids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/771886/thumbs/s-BULLYING-NIOS-ESCUELA-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>6 Time Management Tricks For Parents</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/time-management-for-parents_n_2875834.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2875834</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T19:32:05Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T19:52:52Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It's no secret that time takes on a whole new dimension once you're a parent. What was once a 15-minute run to the drug store...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Teri DAngelo</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/teri-dangelo/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;It's no secret that time takes on a whole new dimension once you're a parent. What was once a 15-minute run to the drug store now takes an hour --- and that's if luck's on your side and and there's no diaper blowout or tantrum (or whatever kind of incident typically throws things off for you these days). Some days it feels like there's just &lt;em&gt;no time left&lt;/em&gt; once you've checked all the boxes of daily family life, even if you only managed to check the most basic ones, like making sure everyone is clean (enough) and had some semblance of dinner. When you add a birthday party or a piano lesson or a soccer practice or all of the above to the schedule, the juggling act gets all the more intricate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's why we're so excited to announce that Christine Koh and Asha Dornfest, bloggers and authors of the new book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.minimalistparenting.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Minimalist Parenting,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are joining us to lead our second &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/stress-less-parenting/" target="_hplink"&gt;Stress-Less Parenting&lt;/a&gt; workshop. They say the key to enjoying family life more is to "step off the modern parenting treadmill." As &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/asha-dornfest/minimalist-parenting-stress-less_b_2907525.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Asha writes in her first blog post&lt;/a&gt;, "You -- and only you -- get to decide what's important to your family. Not the modern culture of 'more' and 'faster.' Not the experts. Not even your mother. You choose what your family considers valuable, enriching and fun."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the things that we &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; need to get done, effective time management is key. So for Week One of this workshop, Christine and Asha offer six tips to help parents stay on track. Read them here and get their first challenge, then please give them a warm welcome in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIME MANAGEMENT TRICKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t Fall into the Multitasking Trap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We get that there’s only so much interruption you can control (you can’t exactly push the mute button on a toddler). But as much as you  can, sharpen your focus. Turn off your e-mail, silence your phone, close Facebook and Twitter, and focus on the task at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tackle Your Hardest Thing First&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We all have those nagging to-do items ... some require focused time (e.g., generating a budget) whereas others come with emotional weight (e.g., a difﬁcult phone call you need to make). Either way, procrastinating depletes your energy -- every time your eyes hit that to-do list item and you don’t address it, it slows your momentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try this: start with the most onerous item on your to-do list. Often, you’ll ﬁnd that the task did not actually take that long, and you’re immediately feeling freer and ready to rock the rest of your day because that burden is lifted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schedule “Serendipity Space”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When you’re caught up in the routine of everyday life, it’s easy to forget that you’re modeling for your kids how to structure their time. Consider “padding” your activities with periods of quiet -- “serendipity space” -- where there is nothing to do and nowhere to go. That way, you can take advantage of the in-the-moment opportunities for puddle jumping or couch-cuddling that tend to get lost when there’s always someplace to be ﬁve minutes ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Advantage of “In-Between Minutes”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The more you use your calendar, the more you’ll notice little snatches of time throughout your day that are too short for anything substantial, but are perfect for one- to ﬁve-minute tasks and/or distraction breaks. The secret is to have those little tasks queued up in your to-do list so you can take advantage of the in-between minutes. Good “in-between” tasks include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Making phone calls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Checking social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responding to email &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing self-care tasks that fall by the wayside (e.g., nail ﬁling, stretching)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tidying up, even a single drawer or surface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sorting the mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filing papers (or, better, shredding and recycling them)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking ahead in your calendar and to-do list to see where you could beneﬁt from a little planning (for example, noting a birthday the following week so you remember to put a card on your shopping list)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tweak Your Scheduling Style&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We all continue to evolve in our relationships and realize new things about one another; sometimes these differences come to bear when the system reaches pressure points. Be open to tweaking your scheduling style, either to reach a compromise or to improve life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pause Before Saying Yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Don’t say yes to things you and your family don’t want to do. Obligation is a difﬁcult beast to battle, but really, what’s worse: declining an invite or task, or gritting your teeth and muddling through with “I don’t want to do this” mojo? Beyond the basic things you must do, reserve your energy for the things that make you feel happy and excited. No excuses necessary. Simply respond with “Thank you for asking/inviting us, but we’re unable to do it/attend.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THIS WEEK'S CHALLENGE&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put this week's tricks into immediate practice, we're challenging all of you to say no to at least one invite or task you don't want to do but might otherwise accept out of obligation or fear you'd disappoint someone. It could be a task your child's school is asking you to volunteer for, a "made-up" &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kristen-howerton/can-we-bring-the-holidays_b_2903040.html" target="_hplink"&gt;holiday that you just don't think merits a whole bunch of hooplah&lt;/a&gt; or an evening activity that requires a babysitter when you'd really rather be home in bed. The only requirement is that you take time you would like for yourself back. &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q&amp;A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Tell us -- what are your best time management strategies as a parent? How do you take advantage of "in-between minutes"? As you think about this week's challenge, we also invite you to leave your thoughts and tricks in the comments or to tweet them to us &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/HuffPostParents" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPostParents&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excerpted with permission from Minimalist Parenting: Enjoy Modern Family Life More by Doing Less by Christine Koh and Asha Dornfest (Bibliomotion, March 2013).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1048080/thumbs/s-TIMEMANAGEMENT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Asha Dornfest: Why Parents Need To Think Differently About Time</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/asha-dornfest/minimalist-parenting-stress-less_b_2907525.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2907525</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T19:29:26Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T20:16:12Z</updated>
    
    <summary>You -- and only you -- get to decide what's important to your family. Not the modern culture of "more" and "faster." Not the experts. Not even your mother. You choose what your family considers valuable, enriching and fun.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Asha Dornfest</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/asha-dornfest/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is part of &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/stress-less-parenting" target="_hplink"&gt;Stress-Less Parenting Club's second workshop&lt;/a&gt;. Asha Dornfest and Christine Koh, co-authors of Minimalist Parenting, are sharing their best advice on simplifying family life. Here, Asha explains how that begins with good time management.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a reason time management is the first major topic we talk about in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.minimalistparenting.com/the-book/" target="_hplink"&gt;Minimalist Parenting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Based on what we're hearing from parents -- and what we experience ourselves -- finding, managing and saving time is one of the biggest challenges of modern parenting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look: when you can't count on a full night's sleep and your schedule revolves around someone else's meals and nap times, it's just not possible to get as much done as before you had kids. But even as your kids get older and you regain a semblance of control over your time, it's easy to let it get eaten up with activities and obligations, not to mention the "shoulds."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"I should sign my kid up for soccer now, before it gets too competitive and he misses his chance."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We should probably invite the whole class to the birthday party, even though the thought of supervising 35 7-year-olds makes me want to scream."&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
"I'm so tired when I get home from work, but I should be making more interesting meals for dinner."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parenting can push your guilt button. These are your children, and you want to do your best by them. But we'd like to challenge your assumptions about what "good parents" are doing and invite you to think differently about your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A core premise of &lt;em&gt;Minimalist Parenting&lt;/em&gt; is that you -- and only you -- get to decide what's important to your family. Not the modern culture of "more" and "faster." Not the experts. Not even your mother. &lt;em&gt;You&lt;/em&gt; choose what your family considers valuable, enriching and fun. Once you zero in on your values, you can prioritize making space in your schedule for what's important by reducing or clearing out the stuff that doesn't matter so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds simple, right? But the logistics get fraught when you're operating with the assumption that &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; has to be done perfectly and it has to be done by you. Even non-perfectionists writing books about simplifying life get caught in this trap! When we were in the thick of writing &lt;em&gt;Minimalist Parenting&lt;/em&gt;, I agonized over getting healthy dinners on the table. My usual routine of looking through my cookbooks, planning meals, shopping and cooking wasn't meshing with the increased work demands of writing a book. It wasn't until I lowered the bar on the variety of our weeknight meals that I realized "healthy dinner" could be a combination of repeatable meals, store-bought shortcuts (like a rotisserie chicken) and weekend leftovers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example: after-school activities. I care about my daughter's health, development and social life as much as the next mom, so when she was younger, I figured I should get her involved in sports or music lessons. Right? Everyone else in her class seemed to be running from one activity to another, and I had a vague sense that being "well-rounded" would help her in the future. But she never clamored to join the soccer team, and I certainly wasn't clamoring to drive her to practice twice a week and games on the weekend. I had to give myself a confidence pep talk when I made the choice to prioritize open time, relaxation and unhurried room for chores, homework and spontaneous play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are just a couple examples; yours are sure to be different. The key is to know there are many "right" ways to prioritize your time and declutter your schedule, as long as you're navigating based on your values rather then on guilt or insecurity.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Beyond the things you must do, reserve your time and energy for the things that are important and fun for &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; family. Think of saying no as a way of saying yes to joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Want to put Asha's advice into practice? Check out her and Christine's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/time-management-for-parents_n_2875834.html?utm_hp_ref=stress-less-parenting" target="_hplink"&gt;first workshop here&lt;/a&gt; and participate in this week's challenge. If you haven't signed up for Stress-Less Parenting yet, go to the purple box on the right side of this page to receive our weekly newsletter.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1044971/thumbs/s-STRESS-LESS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Marchesa Designer Reveals Her Secrets To Creating Gorgeous Gowns</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/marchesa-georgina-chapman_n_2925547.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2925547</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T19:14:23Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T19:19:18Z</updated>
    
    <summary>For Marchesa designer Georgina Chapman, being pregnant has changed her design process completely. Chapman, who debuted Marchesa's fall 2013 bridal collection in October, told CultureMap...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Erin Migdol</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/erin-migdol/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;For Marchesa designer Georgina Chapman, being pregnant has changed her design process completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chapman, who debuted &lt;a href="http://www.brides.com/wedding-dresses-style/bridal-runway-shows/2012/10/new-marchesa-wedding-dresses-2013-fall#slide=1" target="_hplink"&gt;Marchesa's fall 2013 bridal collection&lt;/a&gt; in October, told CultureMap Houston Thursday that she has felt an &lt;a href="http://houston.culturemap.com/newsdetail/03-21-13-marchesas-georgina-chapman-talks-wedding-gownsi-project-runwayi-and-her-oscar-creation/" target="_hplink"&gt;"incredible rush of creativity" while pregnant&lt;/a&gt; (she's &lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/news/georgina-chapman-pregnant-with-second-child-2012112" target="_hplink"&gt;expecting her second child&lt;/a&gt; with her husband, studio executive Harvey Weinstein, any day). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I am dramatic in my design approach to begin with, but when I’m pregnant, I tend to unleash even more of that fantastical thinking," she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She also revealed that she never designs bridal gowns with trends in mind, preferring instead to focus on inspiration, mood and the overall silhouette. The Marchesa aesthetic of feminine touches, dramatic flair and attention to detail are applied to both her red carpet and bridal gowns, she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I think about everything from structure, style and fabrics, to how the gown will look in photos and the style of wedding," Chapman said. "We do work with themes in our bridal collections, but they are subtle. We have in the past played with ideas of floral lace, romantic fairy tales, and modern adaptations of historical references."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chaman and Weinstein, who married in 2007, &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/367727/harvey-weinstein-and-georgina-chapman-expecting-second-child" target="_hplink"&gt;welcomed their first child in 2010&lt;/a&gt;. Check out Marchesa's &lt;a href="http://blogs.phillymag.com/bridal_bulletin/2012/10/22/marchesas-fall-2013-bridal-collection-philadelphia-elizabeth-johns/" target="_hplink"&gt;fall 2013 bridal collection here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click through the slideshow below to see the top fall 2013 bridal trends.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--256786--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Weddings on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostWeddings" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/HuffPostWedding" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffpostwedding/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049757/thumbs/s-MARCHESA-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: 5 Messages That Will Move You On World Down Syndrome Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/world-down-syndrome-day_n_2924867.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2924867</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T19:10:56Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T19:10:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>On World Down Syndrome Day, advocates across the globe come together to push for more inclusion, demonstrate what it really means to live with Down...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/eleanor-goldberg/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href="http://www.worlddownsyndromeday.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;World Down Syndrome Day&lt;/a&gt;, advocates across the globe come together to push for more inclusion, demonstrate what it really means to live with Down syndrome and show just how capable people with the condition are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the UN devotes a single day to celebrating people with Down syndrome, those living with it are constant breathing examples every day of what it means to face down an obstacle, no matter what society says, and overcome it in order to lead incredibly fulfilling lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out five inspiring stories below that will at first melt your heart and then likely forever change the way you look at people with Down syndrome. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re not OK with the R-word&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="john stephens" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049739/thumbs/o-JOHN-STEPHENS-570.jpg?12" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Activists were enraged after &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/10/23/ann-coulter-obama-retard_n_2004828.html " target="_hplink"&gt;Ann Coulter called Barack Obama a "retard" &lt;/a&gt;on Twitter after the final presidential debate in October. But &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/10/24/ann-coulter-retard-john-franklin-stephens-special-olympics-open-letter_n_2008538.html" target="_hplink"&gt;John Franklin Stephens&lt;/a&gt;, a Special Olympics athlete and ambassador, decided to turn the use of the derogatory term into a beautiful awareness moment when he wrote an open letter to the pundit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Come on Ms. Coulter, you aren’t dumb and you aren’t shallow. So why are you continually using a word like the R-word as an insult?” &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/10/24/ann-coulter-retard-john-franklin-stephens-special-olympics-open-letter_n_2008538.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Stephens, 30, wrote.&lt;/a&gt; "Ms. Coulter, you, and society, need to learn that being compared to people like me should be considered a badge of honor. "No one overcomes more than we do and still loves life so much." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read Stephens’ letter in its entirety &lt;a href="http://specialolympicsblog.wordpress.com/2012/10/23/an-open-letter-to-ann-coulter/" target="_hplink"&gt;here. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We actually just have an extra chromosome &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="down syndrome tshirt" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1015779/thumbs/o-DOWN-SYNDROME-TSHIRT-570.jpg?6" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This T-shirt speaks for itself, but when &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/19ffn7/my_best_friends_brother/" target="_hplink"&gt;Redditor GimpBizket &lt;/a&gt;uploaded the picture of his best friend's brother, he added another heartwarming sentiment: "Regardless of his condition he loves his independence. He understands there are certain things he can not do on his own but appreciates it when he is given the opportunity to." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We dream big&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="lauren potter" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049821/thumbs/o-LAUREN-POTTER-570.jpg?7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lauren-potter/world-down-symdrome-day_b_1352900.html" target="_hplink"&gt;“Glee” star Lauren Potter&lt;/a&gt; decided she wanted to be an actress, she also decided in that moment to listen only to those people who encouraged her to pursue her dream, she wrote in a blog for HuffPost last year. Potter landed a spot in a film, plays a cheerleader on a hit show and advocates for people with intellectual disabilities with Best Buddies, the Special Olympics, The Arc and President Obama’s Committee for People with Intellectual Disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am still going to school to learn more about life,” &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lauren-potter/world-down-symdrome-day_b_1352900.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Potter wrote&lt;/a&gt;, “about living more independently, about making good decisions, and most importantly... TO NEVER EVER GIVE UP MY DREAMS!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read Lauren Potter’s blog post &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lauren-potter/world-down-symdrome-day_b_1352900.html" target="_hplink"&gt;here. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re incredibly gifted &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/2w4dISU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/2w4dISU.jpg" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In just 18 photographs, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/10/24/grace-and-josh-curley-spr_n_2006952.html#slide=1677816" target="_hplink"&gt;Grace Curley and her brother, Josh&lt;/a&gt; showed the world what it really means to have Down syndrome. It means he’s smart, funny, loving, helpful and while some say he has a disability, Grace says he has the amazing “ability to love unconditionally, be non-judgmental.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See Grace and Josh’s entire photo slideshow &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/10/24/grace-and-josh-curley-spr_n_2006952.html#slide=1677816" target="_hplink"&gt;here. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re just like any other kid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/tSJ4MNT"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/tSJ4MNT.jpg" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/03/29/ace-girl-explains-why-brother-archie-down-syndrome-just-like-any-other-kid_n_1386641.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Ace Eicher’s family adopted her little brother,&lt;/a&gt; who has Down syndrome, from Bulgaria, she was thrilled. Ace and Archie do just about everything together – jump on beds, eat ice cream and play in the park -- which is why it’s hard for the little girl to understand why people think her brother is “different,” she said in a video her family made in honor of World Down Syndrome Day last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m just happy he’s my brother,” &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/03/29/ace-girl-explains-why-brother-archie-down-syndrome-just-like-any-other-kid_n_1386641.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Ace said in her video. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Watch Ace and Archie’s video &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=cZ_i3yioHlo#at=96" target="_hplink"&gt;here. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049681/thumbs/s-WORLD-DOWN-SYNDROME-DAY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Accurate Are Recent Reports About Black Teens And Abortion?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/abortion-rates-black-teens_n_2925427.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2925427</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T19:10:35Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T19:10:40Z</updated>
    
    <summary>While the debate over New York City's wildly criticized teen pregnancy prevention campaign rages on, a recent study conducted by the Guttmacher Institute may offer...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Cumberbatch Anderson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-anderson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;While the debate over New York City's wildly criticized &lt;a href="http://www.nyc.gov/html/hra/html/programs/teen_pregnancy_campaign.shtml" target="_hplink"&gt;teen pregnancy prevention campaign&lt;/a&gt; rages on, a recent study conducted by the Guttmacher Institute may offer support to proponents of the PSA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="http://www.guttmacher.org/pubs/USTPtrendsState08.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;the Institute's state-by-state study of abortion rates among teens&lt;/a&gt;, black teenagers between 15 and 19 years old have an abortion rate of 41 per 1,000 women, more than twice the national average of 18 per 1,000. In comparison, white teenagers have an abortion rate of 10 per 1,000 women, which means that African-American teenagers are having abortions at a rate that is about four times higher than that of their white counterparts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In New York, the state with the highest abortion rate in the country, the situation is even more grim, with pregnancies among black teens -- excluding miscarriages -- resulting in abortion 67 percent of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as convincing as the stats may be to those like New York Mayor Michael Bloomberg, whose tenure has served as a testing ground for aggressive public health campaigns like the recent teen pregnancy prevention PSAs, others say there's no way to accurately measure how many abortions happen each year. The reason: &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/explainer/2013/03/chinese_abortion_data_how_do_researchers_like_the_guttmacher_institute_count.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Researchers' methods of tracking abortions are complicated, Slate.com's L.V. Anderson says&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the United States, for example, where the CDC collects data from state health agencies, though those agencies aren't required to report abortion numbers to the CDC. According to Anderson:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The CDC encourages agencies to ask abortion providers for the woman’s age, gestational stage, race, ethnicity, abortion type, the woman’s marital status, and the woman’s previous abortions and births, but not every state collects all this information, and some states (California, Delaware, Maryland, and New Hampshire) don’t report abortions to the CDC at all. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anderson does point to the Guttmacher Institute, however, where efforts to collect more-complete data include approaching every known abortion facility nationwide while also taking governmental tallies into consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in &lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/OTUS/states-banned-abortions/story?id=18703520#.UUtLMVufG0A" target="_hplink"&gt;places where abortion is illegal&lt;/a&gt;, obtaining accurate figures remains a challenge, Anderson goes on to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the U.S., &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/wp/2013/01/31/all-states-except-oregon-now-limit-abortion-access/" target="_hplink"&gt;all but one state has layered on restrictions to 1973's Roe vs. Wade decision&lt;/a&gt;, ultimately limiting access to abortions for many women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, there has not been a study that has found the direct cause for the high abortion rate among black teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some abortion rights opponents, like the &lt;a href="http://www.blackprolifecoalition.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;National Black Pro-Life Coalition&lt;/a&gt;, an organization seeking to reduce the number of abortions among black teenagers, claim &lt;a href="http://" target="_hplink"&gt;easy access to abortions is the culprit &lt;/a&gt; and that abortion providers like Planned Parenthood deliberately place their abortion facilities in areas with large minority populations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others, like Rachel Jones, a senior research associate at the Guttmacher Institute, say the cause may be far simpler. She noted that poverty and a lack of attention given to teenagers at high risk for teen pregnancy could be potential causes for the high abortion rates among African-American teens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s no definitive research that’s actually been able to answer that question. We just do know that African-American women, including African-American teenagers, just have more pregnancies,” &lt;a href="http://dailycaller.com/2013/03/14/african-american-teen-abortion-rates-reach-twice-national-average-study-finds/#ixzz2OCVU6j00" target="_hplink"&gt;Jones told The Daily Caller&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049828/thumbs/s-ABORTION-RATES-BLACK-TEENS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Stir: 11 Things Never To Say To Breastfeeding Moms</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/the-stir/11-things-never-to-say-to_b_2906958.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2906958</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T19:07:20Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T19:07:58Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Here are 11 things never to say to a breastfeeding mother.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Stir</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/the-stir/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by &lt;a href="http://thestir.cafemom.com/blogger/8/michele_zipp" target="_hplink"&gt;Michele Zipp&lt;/a&gt; for CafeMom's blog, &lt;a href="http://thestir.cafemom.com/baby/152622/11_things_never_to_say" target="_hplink"&gt;The Stir&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People say mean things. We all know this and perhaps have been hurt by the words of others. It's especially hurtful when people say mean things when you are doing something good -- like breastfeeding. It's like wonder food for babies and it's proven to be beneficial for toddlers. It's liquid gold -- the best meal mama could ever prepare. And yet people say mean things about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Womanly Art of Breastfeeding 8th Edition features a list of things people should never say to breastfeeding moms. Things like "He's just using you for a pacifier," "You look like a cow attached to that pump," and "Maybe your milk isn't good enough." Ouch. I thought of more of these remarks, sadly inspired by things that were said to me and my friends. Here are 11 things never to say to a breastfeeding mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. You're still breastfeeding? When people say this with a tone of shock and disgust, it's hurtful. Why are other people so concerned with how long a mama nurses her child?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. Breastfeeding is going to ruin your boobs. Mine look awesome and I breastfed twins into toddlerhood, thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. I just don't get why anyone would breastfeed a toddler. When this is said to a new mother, it could make her feel uncomfortable because she may very well plan on breastfeeding into toddlerhood. Or maybe she hasn't planned on it but it will just naturally happen. Again, why are other people so concerned with how long a mama nurses her child? Why can't people just be supportive of something good?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. You could always just give baby formula. This is like saying to a happy newlywed that instead of choosing John to be her husband, she could always get a divorce and choose Rick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. Ugh. Ugh to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6. That's obscene! Can't you go to the bathroom to do that? No, it's not. No, I can't. I'm here. Baby's hungry. I'm not going to let him enjoy his meal in a dirty bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7. Breasts are sexual. I wouldn't put them in my baby's mouth. Perhaps people who say this need therapy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8. Your breasts should belong to your husband, not your baby. Apparently these people never heard of sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9. Oh the baby is weaning? Thank goodness! You must be so happy to not have to do that anymore! Actually, it may be a difficult time for mama. Weaning isn't always a happy thing. And &lt;em&gt;that &lt;/em&gt;-- breastfeeding -- is an incredible bonding experience as well, and a comfort, and there are happy hormones released. The end of that can be a sad time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10. Your sex life won't exist if you breastfeed because your baby will always be attached to you. I think some breastfeeding moms just have to get more creative when it comes to sex. Heck don't all new parents? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11. Oh, you're one of those moms (with an eye roll). A first reaction may be to get annoyed, but we shouldn't. We should smile and say, Yes, yes I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have any of these things been said to you? What else would you add?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More from &lt;em&gt;The Stir&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thestir.cafemom.com/baby/150630/5_things_never_to_say" target="_hplink"&gt;5 Things Never to Say to a Lesbian Mom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thestir.cafemom.com/toddler/130297/5_things_never_to_say" target="_hplink"&gt;8 Things Never to Say to a Mom of an Only Child&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thestir.cafemom.com/baby/594/5_things_never_to_say" target="_hplink"&gt;5 Things Never to Say to an Adoptive Parent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thestir.cafemom.com/pregnancy/128550/20_things_you_should_never" target="_hplink"&gt;20 Things You Should Never Say to a Pregnant Woman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049831/thumbs/s-BREASTFEEDING-MOMS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>PHOTOS: Seraphina Affleck's Haircut Is Definitely Going To Make Suri Cruise Jealous</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/seraphina-afflecks-haircut-suri-cruise-photos_n_2925583.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2925583</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T19:02:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T19:23:55Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Ben Affleck and Jennifer Garner's daughter Seraphina doesn't have as much fashion cred as, say, a Suri Cruise or a Harper Beckham. But it looks...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rebecca-adams/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/ben-affleck" target="_hplink"&gt;Ben Affleck&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/jennifer-garner" target="_hplink"&gt;Jennifer Garner&lt;/a&gt;'s daughter Seraphina doesn't have as much fashion cred as, say, a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/suri-cruise" target="_hplink"&gt;Suri Cruise&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/harper-beckham" target="_hplink"&gt;Harper Beckham&lt;/a&gt;. But it looks like the 4-year-old is really upping her style game: She just got a super chic haircut. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's right, the younger of the two Affleck sisters debuted her new blunt bob while clutching a coffee cup during an Los Angeles outing with Daddy yesterday. Our first reaction? This is just too cute. Our second reaction? Suri's going to be &lt;em&gt;pissed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you remember, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/katie-holmes" target="_hplink"&gt;Katie Holmes&lt;/a&gt;' little one rocked a very similar cropped look back in 2009 (it was actually just the in-between style after &lt;a href="http://www.popsugar.com/Stolen-Kisses-Matching-Haircuts-Cruises-Milan-850614" target="_hplink"&gt;her mommy-and-me cut&lt;/a&gt; grew out, but whatever). Sure, Seraphina's &lt;a href="http://hollywoodlife.com/2010/09/16/awww-seraphina-affleck-wants-to-be-just-like-mom/" target="_hplink"&gt;worn some cool sunglasses &lt;/a&gt;and even &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/celebritybabies/gallery/0,,20455216,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;rocked colored denim&lt;/a&gt; in the past. But don't you think Suri -- specifically, &lt;a href="http://surisburnbook.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Suri's Burn Book&lt;/a&gt; -- might take issue with the lack of originality here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, &lt;em&gt;we're&lt;/em&gt; totally cool with the homage. What's wrong with having another well-coiffed little lady in Hollywood?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seraphina's new cropped 'do:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="seraphina affleck haircut" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049718/thumbs/o-SERAPHINA-AFFLECK-HAIRCUT-570.jpg?15" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suri rocking the blunt bob in 2009:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="seraphina affleck haircut" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049726/thumbs/o-SERAPHINA-AFFLECK-HAIRCUT-570.jpg?3" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See more stylish celebrity offspring!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--219242--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want more? Be sure to check out HuffPost Style on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/huffpoststyle" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/HuffPostStyle" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffpoststyle.tumblr.com" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffpoststyle/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; and Instagram at @HuffPostStyle.&lt;br /&gt;
--&lt;br /&gt;
Do you have a style story idea or tip? Email us at stylesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049718/thumbs/s-SERAPHINA-AFFLECK-HAIRCUT-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>3-Year-Olds Know To Share, But Don't</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/kids-and-sharing_n_2925415.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2925415</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T18:52:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T18:52:48Z</updated>
    
    <summary>By: Tia Ghose, LiveScience Staff Writer Published: 03/20/2013 06:07 PM EDT on LiveScience Tots as young as 3 believe it's important to share. But when...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Samakow</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-samakow/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;By: Tia Ghose, LiveScience Staff Writer &lt;br /&gt;
Published: 03/20/2013 06:07 PM EDT on LiveScience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Tots as young as 3 believe it's important to share. But when sparkly stickers enter the picture, the young ones get greedy, new research finds.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The results, published today (March 20) in the journal &lt;a href="http://dx.plos.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0059510"&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/a&gt;, suggest that children already understand and agree with fairness principles by age 3, but don't actually live by those precepts until older ages. The study also suggests a lack of &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/15821-cookie-test-control.html"&gt;impulse control&lt;/a&gt; or a failure of willpower can't explain the trend, as might be expected.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;These little kids are really clear: Yeah, you should split things equally when everyone is equally deserving. But when given a chance to do that, they tend to hoard things,&amp;quot; said study co-author Craig Smith, a developmental psychologist at the University of Michigan at Ann Arbor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Stickers!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Several studies in the past have shown that toddlers are bad at sharing. In a classic experiment called the &lt;a href="http://www.myhealthnewsdaily.com/2320-selfish-kids-immature-brain-blame.html"&gt;dictator game&lt;/a&gt;, 3-year-olds typically dole out less than half of their stickers to another child, often giving none. Separately, studies have suggested that even &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/16460-babies-grasp-fairness-sharing.html"&gt;babies have a sense of fairness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; To see how those differing beliefs and actions interact, Smith and his colleagues gave 3-to-8-year-old children four stickers each and told the kids they could share any number with another child of the same gender. The youngest children were more selfish, while older kids allocated stickers more fairly. [&lt;a href=" http://www.livescience.com/14144-parenting-tips-compassion-esteem.html"&gt;5 Ways to Foster Self-Compassion in Your Child&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Beforehand, the researchers also asked the children questions about what people should do in similar situations, and both age groups of children agreed that people should split the stickers evenly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; That led the researchers to wonder why younger children's ideals diverged so dramatically from their actual behaviors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Can't help themselves?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Under one possible explanation, children planned to share, but lost their &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/23899-twist-on-marshmallow-test-shows-environment-affects-self-control.html"&gt;willpower&lt;/a&gt; as soon as they got their hands on the sparkly prizes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; But when researchers asked children to predict how they would share stickers, they accurately forecasted their behavior.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;They have this bizarre sense of self-awareness, like, 'I know I'm going to hoard this,'&amp;quot; Smith told LiveScience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; That suggests the children's selfishness (at least in this task) did not come from a lack of impulse control.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Researchers also tested the idea that children expected other kids to hoard stickers, so they might as well, too. But most children expected other kids to share fairly, ruling out &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/24183-ancient-cynics-shortcut-to-happiness.html"&gt;cynicism&lt;/a&gt; as the explanation for the observed selfishness.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Children also knew that rules of fairness applied to themselves as well as others.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; After hoarding stickers, younger children felt quite &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/23844-self-interest-decision.html"&gt;happy with their selfishness&lt;/a&gt;, whereas older children felt more ambivalent after doing the same.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Unanswered question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The findings are impressive, because they tie together children's beliefs and actions, said Felix Warneken, a developmental psychologist at Harvard University, who was not involved in the study.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;What's striking is that there's this &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/2054-oddly-hypocrisy-rooted-high-morals.html"&gt;hypocrisy&lt;/a&gt; between what should be done and what they actually do,&amp;quot; Warneken told LiveScience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It's still not clear exactly why little children's beliefs and actions differ so dramatically, but it may be part of the developmental process, Warneken said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Still, that doesn't mean &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/10068-selfishness-benefit-society.html"&gt;youngsters' selfishness&lt;/a&gt; is unchangeable. In collective cultures, in which sharing is a necessity in life, children tend to act fairly in sharing tasks at an earlier age, Smith said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;Follow Tia Ghose on Twitter &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/tiaghose"&gt;@tiaghose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Follow&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;LiveScience &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter/livescience" title="http://twitter.com/#!/livescience"&gt;@livescience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/#!/livescience" title="http://www.facebook.com/#!/livescience"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&amp; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/101164570444913213957/posts"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Original article on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/28073-greedy-children-believe-fairness.html"&gt;LiveScience.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/17894-10-scientific-parenting-tips.html'&gt;10 Scientific Tips For Raising Happy Kids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/12932-11-facts-parent-baby-brain.html'&gt;11 Facts Every Parent Should Know About Their Baby's Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/14343-amazing-brainy-baby-abilities.html'&gt;That's Incredible! 9 Brainy Baby Abilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; Copyright 2013 LiveScience, a TechMediaNetwork company. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. ]]&gt; &lt;/content&gt; &lt;/article&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049817/thumbs/s-TODDLERS-NOT-SHARING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Survey Reveals Surprising Facts About LGBT Students In New York Schools </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/glsen-2011-school-climate-new-york-_n_2925652.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2925652</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T18:42:57Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T18:44:47Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The state of New York may have a comparatively liberal attitude towards its lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender (LGBT) residents. But a new poll suggests...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Curtis M. Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/curtis-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;The state of New York may have a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/07/23/new-york-gay-marriage-fir_n_1694561.html" target="_hplink"&gt;comparatively liberal attitude&lt;/a&gt; towards its lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender (LGBT) residents. But a new poll suggests that generally tolerant mindset may not extend to the state's school system. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.glsen.org/cgi-bin/iowa/all/home/index.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Gay, Lesbian &amp; Straight Education Network&lt;/a&gt; (GLSEN) released its "&lt;a href="http://www.glsen.org/binary-data/GLSEN_ATTACHMENTS/file/000/002/2178-2.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;School Climate in New York&lt;/a&gt;" report, which aims to provide a "snapshot" of the educational environment for LGBT students in New York state's middle and high schools.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report, which looked at 2011 statistics, found that about nine out of 10 LGBT students polled said they regularly heard classmates make negative remarks about how someone expressed their gender, such as comments about someone not acting "feminine" or "masculine" enough. Meanwhile, one out of every five LGBT students said they were physically harassed, and about one in 10 said they had been physically assaulted, based on their sexual orientation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“While we have seen some progress nationally in the 14 years since we started our National School Climate Survey, much work remains to ensure that all New York schools are safe and affirming environments for LGBT students,” Dr. Eliza Byard, GLSEN’s Executive Director, said in a press release. “We look forward to working with our New York Chapter partners to ensure that every LGBT student has equal access to a quality education.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GLSEN's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/09/05/glsen-national-school-climate-survey-lgbt-students-_n_1856508.html" target="_hplink"&gt;2011 National School Climate Survey&lt;/a&gt;, which was released in September 2012, found that six out of 10 LGBT teens said they felt unsafe at school, while 82 percent of that same group say they've been verbally harassed because of their sexual orientation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view the full "School Climate In New York" report &lt;a href="http://www.glsen.org/binary-data/GLSEN_ATTACHMENTS/file/000/002/2178-2.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at some select findings from the report in the slideshow below: &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049748/thumbs/s-GLSEN-SCHOOL-CLIMATE-NEW-YORK-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Dad Gets Daughter's Cremated Remains After 26 Years Apart</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/jerry-wolf-reunited-with-_n_2925864.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2925864</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T18:31:36Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T19:52:19Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A man has been reunited with the ashes of his baby daughter more than 25 years after she died, thanks to a chance encounter and...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kim Bellware</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kim-bellware/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;A man has been reunited with the ashes of his baby daughter more than 25 years after she died, thanks to a chance encounter and the work of a coroner's office in the Chicago metro area. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1987, Jerry Wolf's 2-month-old daughter, Shawna, died of Sudden Infant Death Syndrome in his Carpentersville, Ill. home, but the Sun-Times reports he and his then-wife were young, broke and living in Florida less than a year later. &lt;a href="http://beaconnews.suntimes.com/18993990-417/dad-reunited-with-babys-remains-after-26-years.html" target="_hplink"&gt;As a result, the couple was somehow never connected with their daughter's cremains. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was by chance that Wolf's mother, who still resides in Carpentersville, &lt;a href="http://chicago.cbslocal.com/2013/03/08/kane-county-coroner-has-unclaimed-cremains-of-47-people/" target="_hplink"&gt; saw a story about unclaimed remains with the Kane County Coroner's office&lt;/a&gt; and recognized her grandaughter's name among those listed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She immediately called Wolf to tell him his daughter had been found, prompting Wolf drove from his home in Wisconsin the very next day to pick up the urn. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I couldn’t wait. I had to have her back again with her family, Wolf told the Sun-Times. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in March, &lt;a href="http://www.countyofkane.org/Pages/commDisp.aspx?focusID=94" target="_hplink"&gt;Kane County Coroner Rob Russell sought to find relatives of the 47 people&lt;/a&gt; whose remains were still with his office. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://articles.chicagotribune.com/2013-03-08/news/chi-kane-county-unclaimed-remains-20130308_1_relatives-coroner-russell" target="_hplink"&gt;“Either we’ve run into dead ends, or the next of kin just doesn’t want them,” &lt;/a&gt;Russell told the Tribune at the time. “We can’t force them to do it. Some can’t afford to bury (the remains). Some of them just don’t want them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remains ended up with the coroner from a variety of sources. In the case of Wolf's daughter, her ashes had been in a storage locker that was sold. According to the list of unclaimed remains, some ashes were with other police departments, and &lt;a href="http://www.countyofkane.org/Documents/Focus%20on%20the%20County/CREMAINS%20IN%20STORAGE.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;several were found inside a Gold Medal Flour tin at a Goodwill store in South Elgin, Ill. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russell told the Tribune several cremains of babies came from mothers who wouldn't even acknowledge their pregnancies. The oldest identified remains belong to a woman who died in 1952. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coroner's office will continue to store the remains if they go unclaimed. Wolf, meanwhile, said the discovery has given him closure at last. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"My life is complete.”&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049835/thumbs/s-JERRY-WOLF-REUNITED-WITH-DAUGHTER-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Abi Cotler: Five Ways to Better Appreciate Your Kids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/abi-cotler-oroarty/five-ways-to-appreciate-y_b_2879259.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2879259</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T18:06:04Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T21:01:58Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A week or so after Newton, I found myself marveling at the size of my three-year-old's smooth little fingers as I dried them in a public bathroom. This slow, sublime, moment was very different than the usual rush to get out of there before someone else needed to come in.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Abi Cotler</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/abi-cotler-oroarty/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-19-IMG_4712.JPG"&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-19-IMG_4712.JPG" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-19-IMG_4712-thumb.JPG" width="608" height="400" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Newtown school shootings many parents found themselves hugging their children more, being more patient with them, finding more time to get down on their level and play. Similarly, a friend of mine recently made big changes to her life after the sudden death of a four-year-old in her hometown who was a playmate to her own children. She began a new routine including more time for herself and her body. Also her appreciation for everything about her children grew. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's a basic human truth that most of us don't stay in such a state of appreciation when not in the face of tragedy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A week or so after Newtown, I found myself marveling at the size of my three-year-old's smooth little fingers as I dried them in a public bathroom. This slow, sublime, moment was very different than the usual rush to get out of there before someone else needed to come in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often wish that state could last forever and have wondered what I might do to improve my appreciation of the days (and nights) I have with my toddler and her six-year old sister.  Recently I've tested out different suggestions from various reading and the web. Below is a list of what's worked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• &lt;strong&gt;Put Some Love Into It:&lt;/strong&gt;  One time I was making my daughter's cumbersome bed for what felt like the fifteenth day in a row when she was having trouble with nighttime accidents. Testy as can be, I suddenly found myself thinking that if I put all the love I had for her into making the bed, I would feel so much better. Instantly, I forgot that I had a graduate degree, a neck ache, and a long list of things to do that day, and I felt transcendent -- some would say closer to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when you find yourself cursing the eighth disgusting mess you've dealt with that day already, try putting all your love for your family into it and see if it doesn't help let some light into the gloom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•&lt;strong&gt;Turn Off:&lt;/strong&gt; Turning off your phone, especially if it's 'smart', is one of the easiest ways for most of us to significantly bump up our attention and focus on the present. I notice that even if I put the phone on vibrate, or in another room, I find myself checking it when I see my kids are otherwise occupied. When it is all the way powered down, I get it through my skull that there's no reason to go through turning it back on just to get distracted -- what's important is right in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•&lt;strong&gt;Gratitude Journal: &lt;/strong&gt; I used to keep an Oprah style gratitude journal, so I went back to that, leaving it by my bedside lamp to help me remember before lights out. In it, I try to list at least five specific things that happened that day with my kids that I'm grateful for. I try to keep to specifics because the broad generalities, like: my kids are generally healthy and happy, are easy to come up with, but it's the actual daily events that I'm more interested in, like: my daughter read her little sister an entire book three times today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•&lt;strong&gt;Post-it Up: &lt;/strong&gt; Jot down a few ideas about what it is you're trying to accomplish here -- set the intention. Then create little reminders on note cards or post-its (best invention ever, thank you Romi and Michele!) and place the reminders around your house. Next to the bathroom mirror and by the laundry machine are good places to post. Right now, there's a purple post-it in my bathroom that reads, "Enjoy every little breath."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•&lt;strong&gt;Planned Neglect:&lt;/strong&gt; I once asked an octogenarian artist how he managed to produce so much art over the years. He told me about something he called "planned neglect." He said that he had to force himself to ignore some of the household chores that needed to get done every single day in order to prioritize his art. All these years later, nothing bad has happened to him as a result of letting laundry and dishes pile up -- and the work he had to show for this seemed stunningly fulfilling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find one of the biggest challenges to staying present with my kids are of the demands of the home, and being home with two little wrecking crews create so many of those demands, don't they? But lately I've been trying to lower the standard of what I need to have done each day in order to feel that I'm taking care of my home (believe me, the bar wasn't stunningly high to begin with). Sometimes breakfast dishes don't get done until I'm cooking dinner. Sometimes the house isn't all the way picked up at the end of the day. Becoming more relaxed about domesticity has really helped me not feel like I need to constantly pull away from the present moment, whatever it holds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual when I cavalierly hand out parenting advice, I caution anyone who heeds it to go easy. Try starting with just one of these things above and then perhaps switch to another if it doesn't do the trick for you. The last thing we want to do is worry too much about not appreciating our kids enough, because nothing makes you feel unappreciative like that kind of guilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you've already faced personal tragedy to a great degree, perhaps you don't need these techniques. But I hope we can all start trying to live in a world where you don't need to face down death to appreciate life. Life, after all, is the name of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049688/thumbs/s-GRATITUDE-KIDS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
