<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Camera Found In High School Bathroom</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/camera-found-in-maryland-high-school-bathroom_n_2930453.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>newscred-5335800384fa835e26a87ecb9f5e8e8a</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T13:36:52Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T13:36:54Z</updated>
    
    <summary>An Anne Arundel County police officer has been placed on administrative leave after an investigation indicated he placed a camera in a boys bathroom at...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Baltimore Sun</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/arin-greenwood/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;An Anne Arundel County police officer has been placed on administrative leave after an investigation indicated he placed a camera in a boys bathroom at Glen Burnie High School, police said Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A student found what appeared to be a camera about 10:20 a.m. Wednesday and told an assistant principal about it around noon, saying he felt uncomfortable using the restroom, officials said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera was turned over to police, who said their investigation revealed that a 14-year veteran of the department, most recently assigned to the Special Services Bureau, had installed the camera without police or school officials knowing. Both agencies said Thursday that it wasn't their device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The officer, who was not named by police, was placed on paid administrative leave with his police powers suspended, a routine practice during an investigation, police said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We have not recovered any images or recordings," said police Lt. T.J. Smith, adding that it did not appear any images were stored in the camera. However, he said, "it appears capable of video."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether the camera had been transmitting to a remote location, whether it could capture sound and how long it was in the bathroom on the first floor of the school's media building are part of the investigation, Smith said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police said they are consulting with prosecutors regarding the case. Deputy prosecutor Thomas J. Fleckenstein said he could not speak about the investigation, but in general, visual surveillance in a bathroom could be investigated for possible prurient interest -- akin to a peeping Tom -- and audio recordings can be investigated for potential wiretap violations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an email letter sent to students' parents Thursday and also posted on the school's website, Principal Vickie Plitt said searches for additional cameras on Wednesday and Thursday turned up nothing. The school system has security cameras, but they are in public places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Obviously, this is a very troubling situation," she wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Principals at other schools are certainly aware of this situation," said county schools spokesman Bob Mosier. "We don't have any evidence of this turning up at any other school."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera was located on the bathroom ceiling and was in plain sight, leaving open the question of whether someone would make it so obviously visible if the idea was to surreptitiously catch images, or if the goal might have been to deter problem behavior in the restroom. Police said those questions are part of the investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;andrea.siegel@baltsun.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;twitter.com/andsiegel ___&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="nc_footer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;(c)2013 The Baltimore Sun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit The Baltimore Sun at &lt;a href="http://www.baltimoresun.com"&gt;www.baltimoresun.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributed by MCT Information Services&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src="http://pixel.newscred.com/px.gif?key=YXJ0aWNsZT01MzM1ODAwMzg0ZmE4MzVlMjZhODdlY2I5ZjVlOGU4YSZvd25lcj0zNDQ5NjhiY2NjN2VmZjJhNDYzYTk2ZjA3YzVmYTQ2NSZub25jZT05YWFmMzgwNS04ZTM2LTQzYzQtOTYyMS1hNjFhMTNjMThmYmUmcHVibGlzaGVyPTA4YzIwOWI5YTg3MzA2ZjRiZjkyNjAwYTQ0ZDIxMTlm" alt="" height="1" width="1" class="nc_pixel"/&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051004/thumbs/s-CAMERA-FOUND-IN-SCHOOL-BATHROOM-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Coalition Pushes Back Against School Closings</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/chicago-teachers-union-school-closings_n_2931851.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2931851</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T13:16:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T13:26:08Z</updated>
    
    <summary>CHICAGO -- Chicago Public Schools officials ended months of speculation when they released the list of 54 schools the city plans to close, but the...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tyler-kingkade/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;CHICAGO -- Chicago Public Schools officials ended months of speculation when they released the list of 54 schools the city plans to close, but the pushback against Mayor Rahm Emanuel and his schools chief is likely just starting to ramp up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As word of the schools on the long-awaited closings list trickled out Thursday, parents, teachers and community members &amp;ndash; some furious, some in tears &amp;ndash; vowed to fight the closings. One group took a bus of people to protest in front of the homes of school board members, and some parents spoke of a lawsuit. The Chicago Teachers Union already had scheduled a mass protest march through downtown for next week.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;"We are the City of Big Shoulders and so we intend to put up a fight," union President Karen Lewis said. "We don't know if we can win, but if you don't fight, you will never win at all."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emanuel and schools CEO Barbara Byrd-Bennett say the closures are necessary because too many Chicago Public School buildings are half-empty, with 403,000 students in a system that has seats for more than 500,000. But opponents say the closures will further erode troubled neighborhoods and endanger students who may have to cross gang boundaries to attend school. The schools slated for closure are all elementary schools and are overwhelmingly black and in low-income neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 30,000 students will be affected by the plan, with about half that number moving into new schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CPS officials say money being spent to keep underused schools open could be better used to educate students elsewhere as the district deals with a $1 billion budget deficit. The district says it will invest money to improve schools that are welcoming new students. The funds will be used to add better technology, air conditioning, tutoring services, increased security and other services. CPS says it also will ensure every school has a library and that students no longer are learning in dilapidated buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We know this is going to be difficult, but we believe it's the right thing to do," said CPS spokeswoman Becky Carroll. "I'm sure any parent would stand up and say they want a better education for their child. And in order for that to happen, we have to do this and move on."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carroll said public hearings will be scheduled over the next two months, and CPS officials will meet one-on-one and in small groups with parents to make sure they understand what's happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chicago officials have moved to close schools in the past, but never anywhere near the number designated at one time by the Emanuel administration. Former Mayor Richard M. Daley's administration spread school closings over a number of years. CPS, the nation's third-largest school district, now has 681 schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chicago is among several major U.S. cities, including Philadelphia, Washington and Detroit, to use mass school closures to reduce costs and offset declining enrollment. Detroit has closed more than 130 schools since 2005, including more than 40 in 2010 alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue has again pitted Emanuel against the Chicago Teachers Union, whose 26,000 members went on strike early in the school year, idling students for seven days. Chicago aldermen and other lawmakers also have blasted the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the critics is Eular Hatchett, who lives in the violence-plagued neighborhood of North Lawndale and walks her 13-year-old nephew DaVontay Horace to school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Our parents know about this area," she said. "They don't know about those other areas. If they send him way north or way south, I'm not going to do that. It's too dangerous."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because some schools have more than one building, a total of 61 structures will be closed. In addition to the closures, students at 11 other schools will be "co-located" with existing schools. Six schools have been targeted for academic interventions known as "turnaround."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of the 54 schools are in overwhelmingly black neighborhoods that have lost residents in recent years. The city's black population dropped 17 percent in the last census as African-Americans moved out to the suburbs and elsewhere. The other few schools are majority Hispanic or mixed black and Hispanic. Overall, 91 percent of Chicago public school students are minorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CPS says the plan will save the district $560 million over 10 years in capital costs and an additional $43 million per year in operating costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;District officials said they couldn't calculate how many teachers will be laid off as a result of the cuts because school leaders will make decisions about their own budgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosemary Maurello, a teacher at Lafayette Elementary, said she's worried about where her students will end up after that school closes. As a tenured teacher, the contract allows her to follow her students to their new school, but she wonders whether some of them will opt to go to other schools instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The district has plans for community organizations to help students get to their new locations safely, but Maurello wonders how long that will last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I truly believe that it's going to be chaos," she said.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051001/thumbs/s-CHICAGO-TEACHERS-UNION-SCHOOL-CLOSINGS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Easiest Way To Add Holiday Flair To Your Table</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/easter-ideas-bunny-centerpiece_n_2925324.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2925324</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T12:51:34Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T12:51:34Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Bring a touch of the Easter spirit into every room.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rain-embuscado/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Easter is only a week away, and if you're expecting family or friends over to celebrate the occasion, you'll probably want to add some holiday flair. To help you set up the perfect tablescape for your get-together, today's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/easter-ideas-egg-hunt-bags_n_2917237.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Easter idea&lt;/a&gt; is by &lt;a href="http://www.craftyscrappyhappy.net" target="_hplink"&gt;Crafty Scrappy Happy&lt;/a&gt;, who shows us how to pull together a quick and adorable &lt;a href="http://www.craftyscrappyhappy.net/2013/03/a-simple-easter-decor-diy.html" target="_hplink"&gt;DIY bunny centerpiece&lt;/a&gt; that anchors the dining room table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="easter ideas" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050930/thumbs/a-EASTER-IDEAS-640x468.jpg?11" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="http://www.craftyscrappyhappy.net/2013/03/a-simple-easter-decor-diy.html"&gt;Crafty Scrappy Happy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This craft turns simple accessories that you probably have around the house into festive decorations. And the best part? You can keep them around even after the Easter season is over and enjoy them all spring. For full instructions, head on over to &lt;a href="http://www.craftyscrappyhappy.net/2013/03/a-simple-easter-decor-diy.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Crafty Scrappy Happy's website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--286961--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you want even more &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/easter-2013" target="_hplink"&gt;Easter ideas&lt;/a&gt;, check out our our board on &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/easter-at-home/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050930/thumbs/s-EASTER-IDEAS-mini.jpg?11" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>This Is Your Kid's Brain On A Touchscreen</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/this-is-your-kids-brain-o_n_2931678.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2931678</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T12:50:06Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T12:55:01Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Young children--even toddlers--are spending more and more time with digital technology. What will it mean for their development?...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Atlantic</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dino-grandoni/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Young children--even toddlers--are spending more and more time with digital technology. What will it mean for their development?&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050942/thumbs/s-CHILD-IPAD-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Hessie Jones: Teaching Our Kids Not to Treat the Internet as a Private Diary</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/hessie-jones/teens-oversharing-internet_b_2923694.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2923694</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T12:37:23Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T12:37:48Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I get that kids need an outlet to vent. I get that kids need to be with others who understand what they're going through. But this world of social has created an environment that eventually strings them along a path to a point where the very information they created can be their greatest demise.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Hessie Jones</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/hessie-jones/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I stumbled onto Tumblr the other day and I browsed the content. It was mostly teen content, reblogs of jokes, inspiring sayings and images, weird videos etc. Most of it seemed harmless enough but once I dug deeper I became more disturbed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One girl wrote of the pressure she felt to perfect. Skinny, straight As, s star athlete. She also wrote about being the daughter of divorced parents: a strict father, an alcoholic mother and living with a brother battling Type 1 Diabetes. Another wrote dark poetry about her thoughts of suicide, broken friendships and relationships. More often than not, for every post there were at least 30 "notes." On Tumblr, these notes are "likes" or "reblogs" and sometimes comments. This &lt;a href="http://www.agencypost.com/smells-like-teen-spirit-schooling-marketers-on-tumblr/" target="_hplink"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; conveys the essence of why teens are on Tumblr:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;These teens come to Tumblr to learn and discuss subjects outside of the classroom, the locker room, the hallway and social events. Stories of divorce. Stories of depression and pain. Stories they wouldn't tell to anyone.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quietly shook my head as I wrote this post on Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-21-content.png" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-21-content.png" width="464" height="267" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It occurred to me after reading a post from my friend &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jkcallas" target="_hplink"&gt;Jure Klepic&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jure-klepic/bang-with-friends-app_b_2900671.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Will Bang With Friends Bring Klout to its Climax&lt;/a&gt;, that companies continue to manipulate the vulnerabilities of adolescence and entice them to disclose "far too personal" information on the web. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Need for Validation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came another article, "&lt;a href="http://www.mercurynews.com/business/ci_22817076/students-tell-all-anonymous-facebook-confession-pages" target="_hplink"&gt;Students Tell All on Anonymous Facebook Pages&lt;/a&gt;." The confessions are curated by students, and unofficially links the content to certain universities. The content you find on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Confessions-Of-A-Uni-Student/439249686139430?fref=ts" target="_hplink"&gt;Confessions of a Uni Student&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook range from tame and rueful to very raunchy and downright mean. The article, however, goes on to claim, that this is a "confession craze captivating teenagers and 20-somethings -- but alarms teachers, law enforcement officers and counsellors."  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My daughter uses Tumblr. She is well aware of the dangers of over-disclosure and unfortunately has had some early experience that put her at the centre of some online bullying. Why she uses Tumblr is very much the reason why many teens go there. As one anonymous user indicated &lt;a href="http://www.agencypost.com/smells-like-teen-spirit-schooling-marketers-on-tumblr/" target="_hplink" target="_hplink"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I like the idea of my voice being heard somewhere where people care, so I make it heard in an environment with users who will curiously read what I have to say solely out of interest. Doing so brings me a sort of joy, that people care or agree with the things I say, that I really can't get anywhere else.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get that kids need an outlet to vent. I get that kids need to be with others who understand what they're going through. I get that kids need validation but this world of social has created an environment that eventually strings them along a path to a point where the very information they created can be their greatest demise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/marci-warhaftnadler/" target="_hplink"&gt;Marci Warhaft-Nadler&lt;/a&gt;, founder of &lt;a href="http://fitvsfiction.com/Fit_vs_Fiction/Welcome.html" target="_hplink"&gt;FitVsFiction&lt;/a&gt; had this to say when I showed her the Facebook Confessions article, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-21-marci1.png" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-21-marci1.png" width="458" height="237" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-21-marci2.png" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-21-marci2.png" width="448" height="230" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kids Don't Care or Are they Unaware of the Need for Privacy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My kids have grown up with the Internet. It's their source of entertainment, information and communication. They don't know how to live without it. When I was younger, all my thoughts were kept in my private diary. My mother would kill to find out what I wrote within those pages. I kept a lot of that to myself and on occasion I would tell a close friend, if I needed to. These days that diary has been replaced by a public message board that can't necessarily be erased. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read somewhere that it's not that kids don't care. Like, all of us experience, it's that the consequences of their action are separated from the action itself. So, while I indulge in my favourite french fries with a nice dose of salt, I don't think about how that impacts my health later in life. If I smoke a pack of cigarettes now, does that mean that I'm going to get lung cancer in later years? We all, to some extent, live for &lt;em&gt;today&lt;/em&gt;. From this perspective it's no wonder why teens do what they do. They just have different mechanisms now to speak their mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook Trains Us to Disclose for the Almighty Dollar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world of social media has allowed platforms like Facebook and Twitter to play on the human need for reinforcement and validation. It's game mechanics for "Likes" and "Comments" are those bits of validation that satisfies. In a way, Facebook is training all who use Facebook, to disclose more information about us. The more we embroider the account of our daily lives, the more social reinforcement we receive. We satisfy our own needs. In turn, Facebook accumulates more information that continuously stitches together a tighter and richer view of who we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a marketer and these rich profiles are what we, as marketers, crave. We want to know more about you so we can connect with you and sell you stuff. And we are willing to pay Facebook more if the information we get in return makes it easier to sell our products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a mother as well so I see both sides of the coin. Big data is a huge topic these days. Everyone talks about its merits and the amount of insight we can glean from the billions of actions and post on social networks, mobile devices on a daily basis. While it has it merits there has to be controls. We need to ask the question, "Why do you need to know this?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We Need to Arm the Next Generation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet has yet to grow up. As it quickly evolves we have to somehow get it to a place that preserves our relationships and our information and our secrets. We need to teach our kids to be aware of their privacy settings. We need to arm them with the knowledge of information that's collected from cookies, their cell phones, from RFID. They need to know about phishing and identity theft. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href="http://writingya.blogspot.ca/2012/03/on-privacy-from-ongoing-ted-talks.html" target="_hplink"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; on Writingya. It's poignant and it says it all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The problem is that we have not created a privacy culture on the Internet that we can live with. We created the wrong one. What I think about is: What is intimacy without privacy? What is a democracy without privacy?...Technology makes people stupid. It can blind you to what your underlying values are and need to be. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next generation needs to know their privacy rights. They need to fight for them...much more than we are doing today. More than anything, they need to be increasingly aware of the consequences of their actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--262232--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050215/thumbs/s-TEENS-INTERNET-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Marlo Thomas: Brighten Up For Spring: 25 Easy Ways to Improve Your Life</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marlo-thomas/25-ways-to-improve-your-life_b_2908808.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2908808</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T12:29:26Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T13:22:02Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Anyone who knows me will tell you that I love when things are organized. When I first moved in with my husband and his teenage boys, I actually color-coded their towels.  It worked! And my desk is an organizational work of art -- pens over there, paperwork over here and a typed to-do list just to be sure I get it all done.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Marlo Thomas</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marlo-thomas/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows me will tell you that I love when things are organized. When I first moved in with my husband and his teenage boys, I actually color-coded their towels.  It worked! And my desk is an organizational work of art -- pens over there, paperwork over here and a typed to-do list just to be sure I get it all done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when it comes to spring cleaning - I not only take it literally, I actually enjoy it. I dive into the cleaning part with relish -- clearing out my closets, tossing old magazines, de-cluttering the clutter -- but I also use this annual ritual to shake off the winter doldrums, take stock and get motivated. To me, spring cleaning is about more than just dusty windows and crammed bookshelves. It's an opportunity to look at the other parts of my life and contemplate how they can change, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; A life coach we recently had on " Mondays With Marlo"  told me that the best way to get out of a rut is to just change one thing. That's it. Just start with &lt;em&gt;one &lt;/em&gt;thing. It can be as simple as buying your morning coffee at a different coffee shop.  And then you make another change. You might try waking up an hour earlier or start reading a new book. It's not so much &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you change, but &lt;em&gt;that &lt;/em&gt;you change something. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as the changes start adding up, you find that your life is slowly starting to change . Small changes can bring about larger changes, and as you improve your life on a daily basis you'll find you become more engaged, more enthusiastic and more outgoing.  Something new is happening. And that really is what spring is about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now that spring has sprung, we've put together a few suggestions to get you started. Try one or try them all. As the old Chinese proverb goes, "The longest journey begins with the first step."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--287377--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1045374/thumbs/s-SPRING-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Drew Barrymore Can't Stop Gushing About Baby Olive</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/drew-barrymore-gushing-olive-fallon-video_n_2930787.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2930787</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T11:15:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T11:32:04Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Drew Barrymore carried the glow of new motherhood with her to "Late Night." She was all smiles during her chat with Jimmy Fallon, where she...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Hughes</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jason-hughes/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/entertainment/drew-barrymore-has-advice-for-you-just-ask/" target="_hplink"&gt;Drew Barrymore&lt;/a&gt; carried the glow of new motherhood with her to "&lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/399938/jimmy-fallon-makes-light-of-tonight-show-rumors-on-late-night-talks-jay-leno-takeover-to-gq" target="_hplink"&gt;Late Night&lt;/a&gt;." She was all smiles during her chat with &lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/tv-movies/exclusive-tentative-state-budget-jimmy-fallon-tax-credit-article-1.1295513" target="_hplink"&gt;Jimmy Fallon&lt;/a&gt;, where she gushed about her baby girl, Olive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fallon asked whether he could show a home movie of Olive that Barrymore had sent him. When he did, it showed that Olive is glowing with as much joy as her mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I mean, come on. It just makes you happy," Fallon said of Olive smiling and laughing in the clip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Barrymore, Olive is a fan of "Late Night" as well, or at least its host. "She loves Jimmy by the way," Barrymore said. "She gets like very coquettish deer eyes with him."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barrymore's new mother glow carries over into her new line of cosmetics as well. &lt;a href="http://www.walmart.com/browse/beauty/flower-cosmetics/1085666_1007040_1101184/" target="_hplink"&gt;Flower is available exclusively at Wal-Mart&lt;/a&gt;. Olive is available exclusively at Drew Barrymore's home, but fans will always have her joyous laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tune in to "Late Night with Jimmy Fallon" every weeknight at 12:37 a.m. ET on NBC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TV Replay scours the vast television landscape to find the most interesting, amusing, and, on a good day, amazing moments, and delivers them right to your browser.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050745/thumbs/s-FALLON-DREW-BARRYMORE-130321-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kimmel Wants To Be Cast As Ellen Pompeo's Baby On 'Grey's Anatomy'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/ellen-pompeo-kimmel-cast-baby-video_n_2930679.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2930679</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T10:45:35Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T13:09:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Jimmy Kimmel had a very unusual "Grey's Anatomy" casting proposition for Ellen Pompeo. Her character Meredith Grey is pregnant on the long-running hospital drama, and...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Hughes</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jason-hughes/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.deadline.com/2013/03/jimmy-kimmel-on-tonight-show-rumors-fallon-perfect-sense-video/" target="_hplink"&gt;Jimmy Kimmel&lt;/a&gt; had a very unusual "Grey's Anatomy" casting proposition for &lt;a href="http://perezhilton.com/2013-03-15-ellen-pompeo-chris-ivery-kiss-restaurant-el-lay-sighting-greys-anatomy-saliva-cute" target="_hplink"&gt;Ellen Pompeo&lt;/a&gt;. Her character Meredith Grey is pregnant on the long-running hospital drama, and Kimmel would like to play the baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Does that mean we get to cuddle?" Pompeo asked him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We’ll do a lot more than just that. I mean you can change me and everything," Kimmel said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pompeo did feel they should draw the line at breastfeeding, but Kimmel insisted. "Yes, there is! Oh yes! I have to be healthy!" he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pompeo said that her husband and Kimmel's fiancee might have a problem with that. So it's not looking good for Kimmel as Meredith Grey's baby on "Grey's Anatomy." And it so could have been. Meredith just found out this week that &lt;a href="http://tvrecaps.ew.com/recap/greys-anatomy-season-9-episode-18/" target="_hplink"&gt;she'll be having a baby boy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fans can look forward to the baby's delivery by tuning in to "Grey's Anatomy" every Thursday at 9 p.m. ET on ABC. "Jimmy Kimmel Live" airs weeknights at 11:35 p.m. ET on ABC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TV Replay scours the vast television landscape to find the most interesting, amusing, and, on a good day, amazing moments, and delivers them right to your browser.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050742/thumbs/s-KIMMEL-ELLEN-POMPEO-130321-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'Grey's Anatomy': Is Meredith Having A Boy Or A Girl?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/greys-anatomy-baby-boy-girl-video_n_2929863.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2929863</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T08:45:01Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T10:23:06Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Meredith was stressing out about her baby on "Grey's Anatomy" -- again! She seemed convinced that everything that could go wrong absolutely would go wrong....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Hughes</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jason-hughes/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Meredith was stressing out about her baby on "&lt;a href="http://tvrecaps.ew.com/recap/greys-anatomy-season-9-episode-18/" target="_hplink"&gt;Grey's Anatomy&lt;/a&gt;" -- again! She seemed convinced that everything that could go wrong absolutely would go wrong. So Derek tried to put her mind at ease with an ultrasound. In doing so, they learned something pretty major.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"just take a look and then we’ll know," Derek said as the ultrasound of a healthy baby started to reveal itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Nine, ten," Meredith counted. So everything was okay. "Eleven," she added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"That’s not a finger," Derek said. That's right, it was going to be a boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We think it's safe to say this will be &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/400286/best-tv-moments-glee-s-breakup-the-vampire-diaries-surprise-hookup-and-more" target="_hplink"&gt;one of TV's cutest babies ever&lt;/a&gt;, no?” E! Online wrote. Hollywood Life was excited about the &lt;a href="http://hollywoodlife.com/2013/03/21/greys-anatomy-meredith-baby-girl-gender-season-9-episode-18-recap/" target="_hplink"&gt;news of their "McBoy"&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So everything is going smoothly for now with Meredith's baby on "Grey's Anatomy," Thursdays at 9 p.m. ET on ABC. Will it stay that way?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TV Replay scours the vast television landscape to find the most interesting, amusing, and, on a good day, amazing moments, and delivers them right to your browser.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050627/thumbs/s-GREYS-BABY-BOY-130321-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'Wife Swap': Vegas Party Girl Vs. Off-The-Grid Christian</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/wife-swap-vegas-party-girl-off-the-grid-video_n_2929873.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2929873</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T05:15:27Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T09:28:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It was a culture shock for sure during the season premiere of "Wife Swap." Marissa was a big-time party girl from Las Vegas nicknamed Big...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jason-hughes/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;It was a culture shock for sure during the season premiere of "&lt;a href="http://www.stltoday.com/lifestyles/columns/joe-holleman/former-stl-tea-party-pols-starring-in-wife-swap/article_4b4b9044-063b-5fa6-a00a-b61dc0f8904b.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Wife Swap&lt;/a&gt;." Marissa was a big-time party girl from Las Vegas nicknamed Big Juicy. She was switching places with Angela, a Christian minimalist. To say that neither was quite prepared for their new lifestyle would be an understatement. And they didn't seem too excited about the opportunity, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I have never been to Las Vegas. I have a pretty negative connotation," Angela admitted. "Sin City? So, I’m not really excited about that."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big Juicy was freaking out as well, "No! No! Are you serious?" she asked "Those people are Amish!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, they weren't Amish, but they did live a minimalist lifestyle with no electricity. It was very rustic and of the earth, and Marissa was definitely out of her element. SheKnows noted the struggles of both women, writing, "Angela has no clue what a manny is and &lt;a href="http://realitytvmagazine.sheknows.com/2013/03/21/wife-swap-recap-party-versus-poultry/" target="_hplink"&gt;Marissa is struggling with killing and eating animals&lt;/a&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angela was horrified about Marissa's gay friend who also served as their manny, as were her kids when Marissa talked about him. But while Marissa admitted to falling in love with Angela's kids -- she helped them loosen up and have a little fun -- Angela was less receptive to Marissa or her lifestyle. She did, though, agree to let her kids play video games for ten minutes a day, while Marissa had her manny move out so she could spend more time with her son herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See new non-celebrities on "Wife Swap," Thursdays at 8 p.m. ET on ABC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TV Replay scours the vast television landscape to find the most interesting, amusing, and, on a good day, amazing moments, and delivers them right to your browser.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050629/thumbs/s-WIFE-SWAP-CHRISTIAN-130321-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Taste Test: Reese's And Mounds Ice Cream Eggs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/reeses-mounds-ice-cream_n_2926662.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2926662</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T03:02:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T03:02:42Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Hint: they're made of ice cream.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Rebecca Orchant</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rebecca-orchant/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;"You know what is better than candy? Ice cream that tastes like candy," said one of our tasters. The ice cream in question? Reese's Peanut Butter Cup and Mounds Ice Cream Eggs from &lt;a href="http://www.goodhumor.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Good Humor&lt;/a&gt;. To be fair, these products are not really new. Good Humor has been making the candy bar flavored ice creams for some time. But... they shaped them like Easter eggs, you guys. So we took the excuse to &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/taste-tests" target="_hplink"&gt;taste test&lt;/a&gt; them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These limited edition shapes will be in grocery stores around the nation during Easter season (so, we hope, now?). Here's what our tasters thought of each flavor: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reese's Peanut Butter Cup Ice Cream Eggs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;img alt="reeses ice cream eggs" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050125/thumbs/o-REESES-ICE-CREAM-EGGS-570.jpg?5" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, we agreed that these tasted like what would happen if you stuck an over-sized Reese's Peanut Butter cup in the freezer -- delicious, but not really ground-breaking. Don't get us wrong, we would eat five or six if there were no dietary/social consequences to that kind of behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mounds Ice Cream Egg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="mounds ice cream egg" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050136/thumbs/o-MOUNDS-ICE-CREAM-EGG-570.jpg?1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One taster said, "You know what candy sucks? Mounds. You know what ice cream candy does not suck? Mounds."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we don't all necessarily agree that Mounds is a sub-par candy bar, we did agree nearly unanimously that this ice cream bar rules. One taster went so far as to call it "refreshing." One called it "perfection." While the coconut in a traditional Mounds bar can be a bit overwhelming at times, it is the perfect counterpoint to the creamy vanilla ice cream and chocolate in this bar -- err, egg. Whatever. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any chocolate-covered ice cream bar, the chocolate broke as soon as you took a bite and made a mess. One taster thought these might benefit from a stick to hold them with. The rest of us like getting messy when we eat ice cream. &lt;strong&gt;What candy bar do you wish would get turned into ice cream? Let us know in the comments!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As always, this taste test is in no way sponsored or influenced by the brands included.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to read more from HuffPost Taste? Follow us on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffposttaste" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/HuffPostTaste" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposttaste/" target="_blank"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://huffposttaste.tumblr.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050165/thumbs/s-REESES-MOUNDS-ICE-CREAM-mini.jpg?30" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: You Want To Listen To This 7-Year-Old's Message</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/hunter-pro-sandcastle-builder_n_2928260.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2928260</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T02:32:29Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T02:23:29Z</updated>
    
    <summary>In honor of World Water Day tomorrow, People Water has released its cutest ad to date. The water provider's video stars a very wise 7-year-old...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Mohini Kundu</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mohini-kundu/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;In honor of &lt;a href="http://www.unwater.org/water-cooperation-2013/home/en/" target="_hplink"&gt;World Water Day&lt;/a&gt; tomorrow, &lt;a href="http://www.peoplewater.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;People Water&lt;/a&gt; has released its cutest ad to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The water provider's video stars a very wise 7-year-old named 'Hunter' who talks about his life as a professional sandcastle builder and makes you wish you'd chased your dreams a little harder. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"What is life without passion?" he asks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But his real message is about the 4,320 kids that die each day because they don't have access to clean water. People Water wants to change that. For every bottle of water they sell, the company's Drop for Drop program will donate an equivalent amount of clean water to a person in need. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're not sure how much of this ad -- and Hunter -- are a joke, but it doesn't matter. Because he made our hearts sing and reminded us to try and make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H/T: &lt;a href="http://now.msn.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Msn Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050468/thumbs/s-HUNTER-PRO-SANDCASTLE-BUILDER-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: 3rd Grader Asks Chris Christie Tough Question</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/chris-christie-2016-ellen-gallagher_n_2928363.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2928363</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T00:39:41Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T00:43:43Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A little more than four months removed from the 2012 election, speculation has continued to swirl about the possibility of New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/chris-gentilviso/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;A little more than four months removed from the 2012 election, speculation has continued to swirl about the possibility of &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/chris-christie-2016" target="_hplink"&gt;New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie (R)&lt;/a&gt; running for president.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href="http://politicalticker.blogs.cnn.com/2013/03/21/video-third-grader-asks-christie-to-run-for-president/" target="_hplink"&gt;inquisitive third grader&lt;/a&gt; became the latest to join the conversation on Thursday. At a town hall in Manasquan, New Jersey, &lt;a href="http://videos.nj.com/star-ledger/2013/03/a_girl_wonders_if_gov_christie.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Ellen Gallagher&lt;/a&gt; asked Christie if a 2016 bid was in the cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You've done a great job here in New Jersey and I was wondering if you were thinking about running for president," the girl said in footage obtained by &lt;a href="http://newjersey.news12.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;News 12&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question drew immediate laughter from the child and applause from the crowd. Christie cracked a smile, and quipped "do you work for MSNBC?", before telling the girl that he was focused on his job as New Jersey governor right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href="http://www.nj.com/news/index.ssf/2013/03/sandy_recovery_topic_of_christ.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Newark Star-Ledger&lt;/a&gt;, Christie was doing just that on Thursday. Manasquan is a Jersey Shore borough ravaged by Hurricane Sandy, and the gathering addressed how residents should rebuild in light of the storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in January, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/07/chris-christie-2016_n_2424738.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Christie was emphatic to the Star-Ledger&lt;/a&gt; that if he chose to run in 2016, he would be more ready. But he also stressed that his current focus was on a 2013 reelection bid for the role of New Jersey governor -- a commitment that would bump into the next election cycle. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Life is life; you never know what it’s going to confront you with," he told the paper in January. "But I’m asking for four years and I intend to serve four years."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050488/thumbs/s-CHRIS-CHRISTIE-2016-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kate Perino: Adult Daughter Of Gay Dads Speaks Out On Why Marriage Equality Matters</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kate-perino/speaking-out-sarah-gogin-adult-daughter-of-gay-dads-on-why-marriage-equality-matters_b_2918481.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2918481</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T23:48:01Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T23:51:18Z</updated>
    
    <summary>On March 26 and 27 the Supreme Court will address a common question: Should all Americans have the freedom to marry the person they love? The children being raised by LGBT parents are in an excellent position to answer that question -- and they are speaking out.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kate Perino</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kate-perino/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;On March 26 and 27 the Supreme Court will hear arguments in the DOMA and Proposition 8 cases. The decisions in both cases will address a common question: Should all Americans have the freedom to marry the person they love?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The children being raised by LGBT parents are in an excellent position to answer that question -- and across the United States they are speaking out. The Family Equality Council and our coalition partners have filed a "&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/steve-majors/voices-of-children_b_2791942.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Children's Voices&lt;/a&gt;" &lt;em&gt;amicus curiae&lt;/em&gt; brief asking the Supreme Court to consider what these young people have to say about their families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah Gogin lives in California and is one of the &lt;em&gt;amici&lt;/em&gt; in the "Children's Voices" brief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-20-GoginMcPhersonfamily.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-20-GoginMcPhersonfamily.jpg" width="600" height="451" /&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo courtesy of Sarah Gogin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
"We're a pretty traditional 'untraditional' family," she muses. The traditions that mean the most to her family? Beginning when she was young, Sarah and her parents had "Friday Night at the Movies," ordering pizza and watching a classic film together every week. Sarah credits this time with her fathers with endowing her with a lifelong appreciation of black-and-white films and, she jokes, "a great sense of fashion!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The McPherson-Gogin family is Irish, Italian and Catholic, which means "big celebrations at Christmas and Easter," and "of course, a lot of food." Religion, she adds, "is a very important part of my family's life." So is their connection to their community. They have "a lot of San Francisco pride," and, Sarah adds, her Pop has become a mentor for many of her friends and classmates over the years. In the "Children's Voices" Supreme Court brief, Sarah describes how her Dad "became assistant soccer coach and one of the key members of the [high school] Athletic Board," while her Pop "became the first male president of the Mother's Board."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get there, though, Sarah's dads had to put a great deal of time and thought into finding an open, supportive school environment. In order to educate their daugher at a Catholic school, they had to go outside their local parish because of what Sarah calls "this tension ... sort of beating around the bush because of my family background, but not always saying outright, 'We won't accept Sarah.'" The end result, she says, was absolutely worth it: "tons of faculty and family support across the board." Her friends and their parents felt comfortable asking questions about Sarah's family, even challenging ones like, "How are you going to teach her to be a woman?" Her dads' response, Sarah says, was always, "Just like any other parent." "They raised me to be a contributor to society," she explains. "They would tell people, 'We're teaching our daughter to be a responsible, loving, successful adult.'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a teen, Sarah says, "I became the fourth-generation McPherson-Gogin to attend St. Ignatius College Preparatory." While she had the typical ups and downs of adolescence, Sarah also confronted homophobia. "Going down the hall," she remembers, "you could hear people saying 'fag,' 'queer,' and even if it wasn't directed at me, it still affected me." The lessons Sarah learned at home helped her confront prejudice and negativity with action and compassion. As she describes it, "My parents have taught me you can either learn from a bad situation or you can run from it. They've taught me to keep moving; remember the past but keep going forward."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Sarah did. She started reaching out, teaching people about her family, and at age 16 she was featured in the COLAGE documentary &lt;a href="http://www.familyequality.org/get_informed/childrens_voices_brief/#COLAGE" target="_hplink"&gt;&lt;em&gt;In My Shoes: Stories of Youth With LGBT Parents&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Although Sarah's high school would not allow a gay-straight alliance (GSA), she helped create a Safe Spaces Club that hosted an annual Day of Silence, along with a number of speakers and other programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Sarah had to give some advice to young people with LGBT parents, she would say, "Don't give up. Don't be afraid. I think a lot of times kids get scared of what other kids might do if they say their parents are gay. And, yeah, times are gonna get rough, but you have to be strong about who you are and who your family is."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah attributes a lot of her personal strength and conviction to her upbringing. Her parents taught her "some great lessons about building relationships" and "to stand up for myself and not change just because someone else wants you to." As she describes the challenges her fathers have faced and overcome through the decades, it's clear that Sarah's heritage has inspired her to live her own life with determination and authenticity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now Sarah has sent a message to the Supreme Court, telling her family's story alongside other &lt;a href="http://www.familyequality.org/get_involved/outspoken/" target="_hplink"&gt;outspoken youth&lt;/a&gt;. She sums it up: "My parents must have done something right to get to this point. They have worked so hard, through so much adversity, to reach this point where they are successful and happy. Why would you have anything against them being married in the eyes of law?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the court agrees with her, Sarah says, it will be "a time to celebrate everything we've been through to reach this point, and the good to come." But regardless, in Sarah's own words, "my family is the same as yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We love the same, hurt the same. We are the same as you."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050456/thumbs/s-GOGINMCPHERSONFAMILYPERSONAL-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>New Development In Caleb Gordley Shooting </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/neighbor-who-killed-virginia-teen_n_2927702.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2927702</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T22:57:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T22:57:45Z</updated>
    
    <summary>STERLING, Va. -- Police say a homeowner fired a warning shot before fatally shooting a 16-year-old neighbor who drunkenly entered the wrong home by mistake....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brandon-wetherbee/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;STERLING, Va. -- Police say a homeowner fired a warning shot before fatally shooting a 16-year-old neighbor who drunkenly entered the wrong home by mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Loudoun County Sheriff's Office said Thursday that Caleb Gordley of Sterling died from a gunshot to the back of his shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Caleb died Sunday morning. His family said he sneaked out of the house Saturday night and went drinking with friends. Walking home, he mistakenly entered a similar home two doors down from his own by crawling through a back window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheriff's office said Thursday that the homeowner gave verbal warnings and fired a warning shot, but Caleb continued up the stairs. Caleb was shot in the back after passing the homeowner in a hallway and walking toward a bedroom where others were located.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050405/thumbs/s-NEIGHBOR-WHO-KILLED-VIRGINIA-TEEN-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
