<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Dr. Patricia Fitzgerald: Is Your Stress Response Stuck In The 'On' Position?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-patricia-fitzgerald/stress-response_b_2964036.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2964036</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T12:58:36Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T12:58:45Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The survival instinct designed to give us tools to fight or flee has turned on us. Now that it is on inappropriately, this response can have the opposite effect. Instead of saving our lives, it can contribute to insomnia, depression, panic attacks, and a host of other health concerns.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Dr. Patricia Fitzgerald</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-patricia-fitzgerald/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Most of us live in a world with so much comfort compared to our ancestors.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Want that double latte with 2 percent milk? Skim? How about almond milk? Maybe soy?&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Can't remember who was the 16th president of the United States? Don't waste time trying to jog your memory or discuss with friends. You can find the answer in seconds by, you guessed it, Googling it.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Lonely? Don't forget, you have hundreds of Facebook friends to reach out to. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Is the room a little chilly? Turn up the heat. A little too hot? Get the A/C going.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
In the mood for a green sweater with black buttons? Don't spend time going from store to store looking endlessly through racks. Google will search for you.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Hungry? Don't worry about what the local harvest has yielded this month. You can choose from Thai, Italian, Japanese, raw, cooked, and everything in between -- most of which can be delivered to your door in less than an hour.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
You might have flashbacks to when you were growing up, and you'd come home from school to the scent of what was being prepared for dinner. You might be smelling the food for hours, feeling hungry, and guess what -- you had to, dare I say, wait!&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
In a culture with more creature comforts, paradoxically we experience more impatience, discomfort, anxiety, and depression. We have amazing tools for virtual connection within the digital space, yet we can still feel isolated.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Do you find yourself checking emails and texts every few minutes? Do you get stressed if you don't get a quick reply? And, God forbid, how do you feel if you are in a place with no cell signal for very long? Have you ever left your phone at home or at the office accidentally? Did you feel unsettled until you and your device were reunited?&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Do you feel like you are hypervigilant, always on alert? Without realizing it, you may be activating the fight-or-flight mechanism.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
But wait a minute, there is nothing to fight or to flee from. The fact that you can't get a cell signal might feel stressful, but it's not serious, right? So why the fight-or-flight response?&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Dr. Marc Schoen, author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Your-Survival-Instinct-Killing-ebook/dp/B008BM4LHM" target="_hplink"&gt;Your Survival Instinct is Killing You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, believes that our tolerance for discomfort is at an all time high. Our fight-or-flight instinct, the survival instinct, is stuck in the on position. We react to circumstances as if we were in life-threatening danger.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
The title &lt;em&gt;Your Survival Instinct Is Killing You&lt;/em&gt; perfectly describes this paradox: The survival instinct designed to give us tools to fight or flee has turned on us. Now that it is on inappropriately, this response can have the opposite effect. Instead of saving our lives, it can contribute to insomnia, depression, panic attacks, and a host of other health concerns. Instead of being a life-preserver, it can wreak havoc on our health, performance, and quality of life.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
It seems like the more we expect comfort, the less we can tolerate being uncomfortable, which is often experienced as impatience. I can remember when I had dial-up Internet. I was used to the time needed for a site to load. And it didn't feel particularly stressful, as the newness of the Internet trumped any possible frustration. Although, as we see with technological progress, as things get faster, we often feel like it can't be fast enough.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Dr. Schoen believes that as our need for instant gratification increases, we are becoming more impatient and addicted to the constant stimulation. The more "sped up" we are, we develop a lower threshold for tolerating discomfort. In those moments of poor discomfort management, we activate the fight or flight response.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Dr. Schoen proposes that the management of discomfort is the single most important skill for the 21st century. We need to handle discomfort without activating the stress response so we can have increased performance, health, and quality of life.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Sounds like a good idea, but how do we actually find that "off" switch? How can we stop feeling "wired and tired" and chronically stressed?&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
I met up with Dr. Schoen to learn more about this fascinating insight regarding our stress response, our increasing discomfort, and to learn how we can transform this discomfort and impatience into peace of mind:&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/X1RIRv-c7Io" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;For more by Dr. Patricia Fitzgerald, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-patricia-fitzgerald"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more on stress, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/stress"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Margaret Wheeler Johnson: 'Office Moms' Aren't New, But They Say A Lot About What We Need At Work</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/margaret-wheeler-johnson/office-moms-arent-new-but_b_2970376.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2970376</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T11:58:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T12:36:23Z</updated>
    
    <summary>She forms close personal relationships with mostly younger women in the office, and she is especially present in mostly female workplaces. She makes sure there are lots and lots of cupcakes. And she represents what a lot of offices could use more of.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Margaret Wheeler Johnson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/margaret-wheeler-johnson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;On Tuesday the Wall Street Journal published an article by Katie Rosenman reporting the emergence of the "&lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887324789504578384360255204892.html" target="_hplink"&gt;office mom&lt;/a&gt;" -- the woman "asserting herself as the matriarch of the office family."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is often the case with trend stories, the office mom is not actually a new thing. There have been nurturing female figures in offices since women were first allowed to work as secretaries. Yet a conversation about office moms is relevant in this particular cultural moment when we are already talking so much about who women are and should be at work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosenman describes the office mom as the workplace equivalent of the room mother or school nurse -- an almost always female supplier of tissues and advice, the person who knows who has a cold and who is going through a breakup, the shoulder to cry on at the office. She forms close personal relationships with mostly younger women in the office, and she is especially present -- sometimes in numbers -- in mostly female workplaces. She makes sure there are lots and lots of cupcakes. And she represents what a lot of offices could use more of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a danger in highlighting a phenomenon like this of making the apparent domain of the office mom -- companies with a large number of women on staff -- seem like centers of frivolity, where employees are more focused on finding someone to take care of them than they are on the bottom line. &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887324789504578384360255204892.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Rosenman's description of those workplaces&lt;/a&gt; and the confiding and nurturing that goes on there certainly doesn't fit into a traditionally masculine every-man-for-himself work environment, where you get ahead by trusting no one and looking to the leadership less for advice than for a sign of who you can most easily replace. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And those who appreciate power women Sheryl Sandberg and Marissa Mayer's refusal to put the personal before the professional may not appreciate this focus on senior women's nurturing skills at the office rather than their professional contributions, which Rosenman doesn't touch on much in the piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But singling out the "office mom" is important for two reasons. First, so much media coverage of women's professional lives either &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/roomfordebate/2013/03/20/shery-sandberg-says-lean-in-but-is-that-really-the-way-to-lead" target="_hplink"&gt;questions their ability to lead&lt;/a&gt; -- as the New York Times' Room for Debate did last week --- or &lt;a href="http://www.thegrindstone.com/2012/06/06/office-politics/i-quit-my-job-because-of-mean-girls-4-true-stories-412/" target="_hplink"&gt;how terrible they supposedly are to each other&lt;/a&gt;.  The "office mom" as Rosenman describes her goes out of her way to be supportive of female colleagues and is a leader in the sense that she helps keep valuable employees happy and healthy. Lori Richmond, creative director of XO, told the Journal, "I'm not worried about being seen as too soft or not tough enough," says Ms. Richmond, a 36-year-old mother of two. "Nurturing valuable employees is critical."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, Rosenman's description of office moms and their relationships with colleagues highlights the fact that female employees do often form close personal bonds at work -- and that's a valuable thing. Sure, a relationship between a junior employee and her superior can't be the kind of friendship she has with people outside her professional life, but pretending that employees don't form friendships with their coworkers is like pretending that office romances don't happen. It's very hard to keep a boss-employee or even mentor-mentee relationship at the office entirely work-focused. Since &lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/life-style/health/gene-explain-women-talk-men-study-article-1.1269957" target="_hplink"&gt;women talk more than men&lt;/a&gt;, I would argue that it's even harder for women, and not necessarily beneficial. Which company would you rather spend 8 to 12 hours every day working for: the one where you interact with colleagues you genuinely care about, resulting in a steady flow of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oxytocin" target="_hplink"&gt;oxytocin&lt;/a&gt; and reliable opinions on how to get through those times when life throws you under the bus, or the one where people who barely know you and have no personal investment in you? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Rosenman paints a picture of the kind of environment some predominantly female workplace have made a reality -- one where you are trusted to get the job done but someone lets you know they care if you are getting enough sleep, if your relationship is on the rocks, if you get home safely. It's a messier way to do business -- family, after all, can get messy, and very, very personal -- but one that more mixed gender workplaces and predominantly male companies might enjoy and benefit from if they tried it. I'm looking forward to the trend piece on the office dad.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059888/thumbs/s-OFFICE-MOM-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>John Green Contributes To Book About Teen Cancer Victim</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/john-green-book-esther-grace-earl_n_2970100.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2970100</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T11:47:20Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T11:57:31Z</updated>
    
    <summary>NEW YORK &amp;mdash; Young adult author John Green has written an introduction for a book about the teen cancer victim to whom he dedicated his...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/zoe-triska/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;NEW YORK &amp;mdash; Young adult author John Green has written an introduction for a book about the teen cancer victim to whom he dedicated his best-selling novel "The Fault in Our Stars."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penguin Young Readers Group announced Thursday that it will publish "This Star Won't Go Out: The Life and Words of Esther Grace Earl" in early 2014. Along with Green's introduction, the book will compile writings and sketches by the girl from Quincy, Mass., known for the YouTube video journal about her terminal illness.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Esther died in 2010 at 16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Green and J.K. Rowling were among her admirers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is named for the foundation started in Esther's memory, "This Star Won't Go Out." Penguin will donate to the foundation, which aids families with children who have cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;___&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foundation: &lt;a href="http://www.tswgo.org"&gt;http://www.tswgo.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059833/thumbs/s-JOHN-GREEN-BOOK-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'Real World: Portland': Children Of Alcoholic Dads Unite</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/the-real-world-portland-alcoholic-dads-video_n_2969186.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2969186</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T07:15:09Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T10:04:48Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It's been a long time since "The Real World" first entered our lives, and a lot has changed in that time. Reality television has become...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Hughes</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jason-hughes/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;It's been a long time since "&lt;a href="http://www.avclub.com/articles/bondage-butts-and-burlesque,95383/" target="_hplink"&gt;The Real World&lt;/a&gt;" first entered our lives, and a lot has changed in that time. Reality television has become a dominant genre, and "The Real World" has evolved to match their more sensational approach. "&lt;a href="http://remotecontrol.mtv.com/2013/03/27/real-world-butt-ranking-anastasia/" target="_hplink"&gt;The Real World: Portland&lt;/a&gt;" looks to continue that tradition of conflict, wild behavior and general rowdiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the premiere, though, it was all about meeting new people and finding common ground to establish their relationships. For Anastasia and Avery, their common ground proved rather unusual. Things started off normally enough, with both learning that they're from Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I don’t have, like, a father in my life," Anastasia said. Neither did Avery. But then came the kicker. "My real dad is, like, an alcoholic," revealed Anastasia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"So is mine! High five! Yes!” Avery said excitedly. And they actually high-fived over alcoholic fathers. Poor Jordan was dejected with no alcoholic father back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the promo alone, The Stir decided they wouldn't be tuning in, writing that "&lt;a href="http://thestir.cafemom.com/entertainment/153137/mtvs_real_world_portland_is" target="_hplink"&gt;'The Real World' is virtually indistinguishable from 'Jersey Shore.'&lt;/a&gt;" The Washington Times agreed, wondering &lt;a href="http://communities.washingtontimes.com/neighborhood/tv-den/2013/mar/27/tv-tonight-season-28-real-world-invades-portland-m/" target="_hplink"&gt;what happened to the show&lt;/a&gt;. "When ‘The Real World’ first aired way back in 1992 it was applauded for its exploration of contemporary problems familiar to its core audience," they wrote. "These days ...  the cast is nudged towards conflict and encouraged to air their grievances about fellow housemates."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"The Real World" may have lost its soul, but it hasn't lost its audience or appeal. "The Real World: Portland" continues on Wednesdays at 10 p.m. ET on MTV.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TV Replay scours the vast television landscape to find the most interesting, amusing, and, on a good day, amazing moments, and delivers them right to your browser.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059682/thumbs/s-REAL-WORLD-PORTLAND-130327-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Shelley Whelpton: Catching Up With the Times</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/shelley-whelpton/scotus-gay-marriage_b_2967674.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2967674</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T01:11:02Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T01:11:14Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I am a Canadian woman who has been married to an American woman for sixteen years. My two sons have been raised in a world where having two moms is totally normal -- and wonderful.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Shelley Whelpton</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/shelley-whelpton/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;My 10-year-old son and I went to the steps of the Supreme Court this morning to soak up this historic moment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a Canadian woman who has been married to an American woman for sixteen years. We had a commitment ceremony in Maine. We have been legally married in San Francisco (and then this marriage was annulled by the courts), in Canada (this marriage stands) and, with the recent Washington, D.C. City Council decision, our marriage in Canada is now recognized in the District. So, we're now married, but not for the purposes of U.S. citizenship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My two sons have been raised in a world where having two moms is totally normal -- and wonderful. They understand that the law has somehow not kept pace with the times -- they get this when I have to separate from my family and go through a different line at U.S. customs. And they understand that the courts now have a chance to catch up with the times. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first signs that we saw this morning were "Death Penalty 4 Fags" and "Obama Go to Hell." We walked through and past the pro-DOMA picketers to pick up American flags, a DOMA Project "Binational Couples Fight for Equality" sign and join the more numerous and celebratory pro-gay marriage supporters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, my son was subdued, taking it all in. There were not many DOMA advocates there, but they were doing their utmost to command attention. Once over being a little stunned, he started asking questions: "Why are (DOMA supporters) so mean about this and how can they be allowed to use words like 'hell'?" My son has strong sensibilities about the use of profanity. In his judgment, the police officers all around us should have insisted that the "Obama Go to Hell" sign come down. He noticed their commercially-produced signs (our side had homemade, hand-scrawled signs) and wondered who would agree to produce these kinds of hateful signs in the first place. Giving it all more thought, he asked why these supporters of DOMA care so much about this issue, saying "it really won't matter for their lives" and if DOMA is overturned, "so many more people in America will be happy."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we started to leave the steps of the Supreme Court and were approaching supporters of DOMA, I asked my son if we should walk through or around the group. He was quick and clear in his response, "Let's walk through them." As we waited for the light to turn, steps away from a gay couple kissing in front of the "Death Penalty 4 Fags" sign, my son made a point (subtly) of turning around our "Binational Couples" sign to face DOMA supporters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was inspired by my son this morning. I was inclined to walk around, rather than through, the group of DOMA advocates. I have hope that kids in this country are growing up with the sensibility and clarity and conviction of my 10-year-old. And, in the meantime, it would be great if we can all catch up with them.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059257/thumbs/s-SUPREME-COURT-GAY-MARRIAGE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: Miracle Baby Weighed In At Over 15 Pounds</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/baby-george-king_n_2967517.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2967517</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T00:47:25Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T11:57:14Z</updated>
    
    <summary>An expecting British couple got a surprise during delivery six weeks ago: their baby was a very big boy. Baby George King was born weighing...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Peter Finocchiaro</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/peter-finocchiaro/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;An expecting British couple got a surprise during delivery six weeks ago: their baby was a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; big boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baby George King was born weighing 15 pounds, 7 ounces. According to &lt;a href="http://www.christianpost.com/news/baby-born-15-pounds-7-ounces-2nd-biggest-baby-born-naturally-in-uk-history-photo-video-92766/" target="_hplink"&gt;some reports&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://shine.yahoo.com/parenting/george-king-of-england--born-weighing-over-15-pounds--is-one-big-baby-212724847.html" target="_hplink"&gt;he's the second largest baby ever delivered vaginally&lt;/a&gt; in the United Kingdom.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctors were caught off guard by George's size, which caused frightening complications. George's mother Jade told the BBC that during delivery, &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-bristol-21952025" target="_hplink"&gt;the baby's shoulders got stuck&lt;/a&gt;, depriving him of oxygen for five minutes and reducing his chance of survival to 10 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"That's when, sort of, everything kicked off, really," Jade said. "There were about 20-odd doctors in the room. That's when it got really scary."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="http://shine.yahoo.com/parenting/george-king-of-england--born-weighing-over-15-pounds--is-one-big-baby-212724847.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Yahoo! Shine&lt;/a&gt;, doctors don't know why baby George was so big. Last year, when &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/04/14/crista-hebel-12-pound-preemie_n_1424881.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Michigan mom Crista Hebel gave birth to a 12-pound preemie&lt;/a&gt;, Dr. Shieva Ghofrany, an OBGYN with Stamford Hospital told The Huffington Post that &lt;a href="http://www.aafp.org/afp/2001/0115/p302.html" target="_hplink"&gt;fetal macrosomia&lt;/a&gt; -- defined as a birth weight of more than 8.8 pounds -– can be directly attributed to maternal obesity and diabetes. But she clarified that those are not the only factors, pointing out that in the last five to six years, "babies have definitely been coming out bigger." Other factors contributing to rise of heavy newborns could be similar to the r&lt;a href="http://api.viglink.com/api/click?format=go&amp;key=32baf9faf91103bc2a7aa19ce37d8c0d&amp;loc=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.huffingtonpost.com%2F2012%2F04%2F14%2Fcrista-hebel-12-pound-preemie_n_1424881.html&amp;v=1&amp;libid=1364435789973&amp;out=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2F2012%2F04%2F01%2Fmagazine%2Fpuberty-before-age-10-a-new-normal.html%3Fpagewanted%3Dall&amp;ref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com%2F&amp;title=Crista%20Hebel%2C%20Mom%2C%20Gives%20Birth%20To%2012-Pound%20Preemie%20Baby&amp;txt=unexplained%20reason%20girls%20are%20going%20through%20puberty%20earlier&amp;jsonp=vglnk_jsonp_13644370327883" target="_hplink"&gt;easons posited for why girls are going through puberty earlier&lt;/a&gt; -– contaminants in food or hormones in meats, for example. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Ghofrany acknowledged that bigger babies might look cute, but said the trend is dangerous given that they are much harder to deliver. As Brooklyn-based midwife Miriam Schwarzschild told Yahoo! Shine, fetal macrosomia can contribute to post-birth hemorrhaging, and other risks include "enlarged organs, a fractured clavicle, and, like in George's case, oxygen deprivation." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schwarzschild also said she found it "bizarre" that the the King's doctors were so surprised by baby George's size. "You estimate the fetal weight, always," she said. "I mean, you didn't ever feel her or talk to her or measure her? That doesn't make any sense."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George was kept in the hospital for four-and-a-half weeks after his birth, and doctors have kept an eye out for any lingering negative effects. The prognosis so far has been good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"He's a little miracle," Mom said. "Well, big miracle, really."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While big babies may be on the rise, the Guinness Book of World Records says the heaviest baby ever born weighed in at 23 pounds, born to &lt;a href="http://www.metro.co.uk/news/world/743025-biggest-baby-shock-for-diabetic-mother" target="_hplink"&gt;Anna Bates in 1879&lt;/a&gt;. No other newborn has tipped that scale yet, but here are seven who have come close.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059442/thumbs/s-GEORGE-KING-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Christine Carter, PhD: I Don't Care How Big the Market Is, Those Are My Daughters</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/christine-carter-phd/those-are-my-daughters_b_2964296.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2964296</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T23:36:11Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T23:36:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Between the cotton candy colors, bright toys and Beiber-fever, it is obvious to me why Victoria's Secret appeals to the bat mitzvah set.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Christine Carter, PhD</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/christine-carter-phd/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Our 12-year-olds think thong underwear makes them cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two 6th grade girls in my daughter's class recently got in a snit in the locker room after PE. Apparently, one girl (let's call her Janet) was wearing boy shorts with "love" emblazoned across the bottom. She claimed these ultra-cool undies came from Victoria's Secret. The other girl said she'd gotten the very same underwear from Target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were fighting about status: Did Janet have bragging rights? Or was she upgrading her Target underwear to Victoria's Secret sexiness "to get attention," as my daughter thinks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These girls are 12 years old. Why are they arguing about this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in the thick of raising daughters. In addition to my own girls, among my circle of closest friends there are a dozen daughters whose backs I'm personally trying to protect. Because I love these girls and see how vulnerable they are, the locker-room argument about Victoria's Secret underwear makes my blood boil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have heard that Victoria's Secret came out blatently targeting teens and tweeners at their fashion show a few months ago: They hired pre-teen idol Justin Beiber to perform while supermodels dressed up as little girl's toys strutted around him. Literally AS the toys: one was a bike with pink streamer handles, another a pinwheel -- &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1lMh2z9mp5g"&gt;watch the video&lt;/a&gt; and see for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WATCH: Victoria's Secret Fashion Show&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/1lMh2z9mp5g" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between the cotton candy colors, bright toys and Beiber-fever, it is obvious to me why Victoria's Secret appeals to the bat mitzvah set. For spring break, Victoria's Secret launched the "Bright Young Things" campaign to appeal to young teens, according to Victoria Secret CFO Stuart Burgdoerfer. "When somebody's 15 or 16 years old, what do they want to be?" Burgdoerfer quipped &lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/victorias-secrets-pink-line-successes-2013-2"&gt;at a conference&lt;/a&gt;. "They want to be older, and they want to be cool like the girl in college, and that's part of the magic of what we do."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advertising and marketing does work like magic. That is what is so scary. This is what Victoria's Secret is teaching our daughters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1) Slutty is status.&lt;/strong&gt; One of the brain changes that occurs during adolescence is a heightened attention to social hierarchy. Teens and tweeners &lt;a href="http://www.christinecarter.com/community/blog/2012/12/what-teens-need/"&gt;begin taking risks in order to gain social status&lt;/a&gt; (like lying about where your underwear comes from). The interesting thing about this is that they tend to take the risks in the areas that their peers will recognize as status: for the drama geeks, getting a big a part in a play is status. For the "in-crowd," partying is status. And for the fashionistas (and the Justin Beiber fanatics, and tweeners that look up to college kids), risqué style is now equated with status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(2) There is only one type of body that is acceptable.&lt;/strong&gt; When they put supermodels in high heels, little girl costumes and bubble gum underwear on stage with Justin Beiber, they create an impossible ideal for our girls to emulate, which in turn makes them feel inadequate. Consider these statistics from the University of Washington's &lt;a href="http://depts.washington.edu/thmedia/view.cgi?section=bodyimage&amp;amp;page=fastfacts"&gt;Teen Health and the Media&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a study of fifth graders, both girls and boys told researchers they were dissatisfied with their own bodies after watching a music video by Britney Spears or a clip from the TV show "Friends."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;53% of American girls are "unhappy with their bodies." &lt;strong&gt;This reaches 78% by the time girls reach seventeen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a survey of girls 9 and 10 years old, 40% have tried to lose weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our daughters go through puberty- - a time of intense body changes -- their attention to body image is heightened. These biological and developmental changes are, in turn, amplified further by advertising. They don't call it neuromarketing for nothing: when advertising sends our girls messages about what their changing bodies should look like -- and it isn't what they do look like -- the ad causes a &lt;a href="http://www.christinecarter.com/community/blog/2012/12/are-we-wired-to-want-stuff/"&gt;dopamine rush&lt;/a&gt; in our daughters' brains that, in turn, creates intense desire for what is being advertised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't know about you, but I don't want my daughters to think of their ideal selves as uber-sexy barbie-dolls with "call me" on their panties, and I don't want them to feel inadequate compared to this brightly-colored exemplar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(3) Boys should objectify girls.&lt;/strong&gt; When I saw that fashion show I couldn't help but think of the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/02/steubenville-high-school-joke-rape-targeted-anonymous-video_n_2398479.html"&gt;Steubenville gang rape&lt;/a&gt;, in which a teen girl was so blatantly objectified she was used as a sex toy and dragged, unconscious, from party to party. Where do boys learn that girls are objects, accessories for their entertainment? Look no further than the media, &lt;a href="http://player.vimeo.com/video/18985647"&gt;where objectified women are the norm rather than the exception&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WATCH: &lt;em&gt;Miss Representation&lt;/em&gt; Trailer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/18985647" frameborder="0" width="400" height="300"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The media's influence is so great that &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/ejsp.1890/abstract;jsessionid=1BB618BCD8E0BCE3C29A797293C9AB7E.d04t03?deniedAccessCustomisedMessage=&amp;amp;userIsAuthenticated=false"&gt;a new study&lt;/a&gt; from the European Journal of Social Psychology shows that our brains tend to process photos of regular, everyday women as a collection of sexualized body parts, while our brains process a photos of men as whole people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want my girls to have boyfriends that see them for the whole people that they are, boys who treat them as individuals, not objects or a bunch of sexualized body parts. I want my girls to have meaningful intimate relationships. When they are ready to be sexually active, I want them to feel loved and cherished by their sexual partners and empowered by their sexuality -- not used and discarded like last year's Christmas present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do know that Victoria's Secret is not our only, or even our biggest, problem. Dozens of other companies taunt our youth with hyper-sexualized images -- the tween market is worth "$335 billion of spending power," retail analyst &lt;a href="http://www.today.com/video/today/51113907#51113907"&gt;Hitha Prabhaker&lt;/a&gt; told the TODAY show Tuesday morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large consumer products companies, with their gazillion-dollar marketing budgets, are influencing our kids in profound ways. As parents, we can protect them by not letting them watch commercials and by not letting them shop in (or, frankly, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/victoriassecret/posts/10151544123529090"&gt;even near&lt;/a&gt;) stores like Victoria's Secret. We can -- and should -- &lt;a href="http://evandolive.com/2013/03/22/a-letter-to-victorias-secret-from-a-father/"&gt;write letters&lt;/a&gt; and hope that our righteous anger goes viral on Facebook. But honestly, these tactics feel profoundly inadequate compared to the marketing machines that we face. Can we win a war by boycotting the companies that hurt kids, or by simply hiding our children from the enemy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I'm also open to other ideas if you've got them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;© 2013 Christine Carter, Ph.D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christine Carter, Ph.D., is a sociologist and happiness expert at UC Berkeley's &lt;a href="http://greatergood.berkeley.edu/"&gt;Greater Good Science Center&lt;/a&gt; and the author of &lt;a href="http://www.raisinghappiness.com/book/about-the-book/"&gt;Raising Happiness&lt;/a&gt;. She coaches and teaches &lt;a href="http://www.raisinghappiness.com/classes/class-catalog/"&gt;online classes&lt;/a&gt; in order to help people bring more joy into their lives, and she writes an award-winning &lt;a href="http://www.christinecarter.com/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; for parents and couples.  Find Raising Happiness on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DrChristineCarter"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or sign up for free &lt;a href="http://www.christinecarter.com/free-updates/"&gt;Happiness Tips&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/847699/thumbs/s-VICTORIAS-SECRET-HURRICANE-SANDY-mini.jpg?12" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Larry Magid: It's Time for Adults to Stop Bullying Kids and Each Other</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/larry-magid/we-hear-a-lot-about-kids_b_2967092.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2967092</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T23:11:56Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:16:24Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There are lots of ways to define bullying and not all experts agree with this definition, but the closest one that we have to an "official" one is aggressive behavior that is intentional and that involves an imbalance of power. Most often, it is repeated over time."</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Larry Magid</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/larry-magid/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;We hear a lot about kids bullying* other kids and it is indeed a problem. But what about adults bullying other adults, or adults bullying kids?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True, bullying is a problem among youth. The National Center for Education Statistics &lt;a href="http://nces.ed.gov/pubs2012/2012314.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;reported &lt;/a&gt;that in 2009,  28 percent of 12 through 18 year old kids were "bullied by traditional means at school" while six percent were "bullied by electronic means anywhere." There are of course other studies with other statistics, but just about all agree that it's a problem that affects a significant minority -- but not most -- of tweens and teens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it's also a problem for a signification percentage of adults and there are, sadly, cases of adults bullying children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adult-on-Adult Bullying&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="http://www.workplacebullying.org/wbiresearch/2010-wbi-national-survey/" target="_hplink"&gt;2010 study&lt;/a&gt; commissioned by the &lt;a href="http://www.workplacebullying.org/front-page/" target="_hplink"&gt;Workplace Bullying Institute&lt;/a&gt; and conducted by Zogby International found that more than a third (35 percent) "have experienced bullying firsthand." Other surveys differ but it's pretty clear that millions of adults have experienced verbal abuse, offensive conduct and sabotage of their work, according to the Institute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also plenty of bullying within families and couples. According to the National Domestic Violence Hotline, a 2006 Harris poll, found that "approximately 33 million or 15 percent of all U.S. adults, admit that they were a victim of domestic violence." Among all adults, 39 percent said they had experienced some type of abuse such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Called bad names (31 percent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushing, slapping, choking or hitting (21 percent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public humiliation (19 percent )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping away from friends or family (13 percent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threatening your family (10 percent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forcing you to have sexual intercourse without consent (9 percent)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: Harris Interactive: &lt;a href="http://www.ncdsv.org/images/Over33MillionAdultsClaimtobeVictimDV.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;Over Thirty Million Adults Claim to be Victims of Domestic Violence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Military bullying&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bullying is also a &lt;a href="http://www.army.mil/article/85308/" target="_hplink"&gt;problem in the military&lt;/a&gt;. Dr. Rene Robichaux, the Army's Social Work program manager was quoted by Army News Service that "hazing often occurs in 'elite' military units, and that much of it is psychological and directed at newcomers." That article also pointed out that "Bullies can also be found higher up in the ranks. Although leaders are supposed to look out for the welfare of their Soldiers, they are sometimes the ones who do the bullying." The armed services are actively engaged in anti-bullying campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Police Harassment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Police harassment is often a form of bullying and it can be adult-to-adult or adult-to-child. In 2010, according to the Cato Institute's &lt;a href="http://www.policemisconduct.net/2010-q3-national-police-misconduct-statistical-report/" target="_hplink"&gt;National Police Misconduct Reporting Project&lt;/a&gt;, there were 3,814 unique reports of police misconduct involving 4,966 sworn law enforcement officers. Of these, 25 percent involved excessive force and 10.4 percet were sexual misconduct. It's important to note that fewer than one percent of police officers (992 for each 100,000 officers) were involved in this misconduct. It's anecdotal and it doesn't always constitute bullying, but I've heard many reports of teens -- including my own son -- being harassed or teased by police officers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Politicians &amp; pundits too&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don't forget the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/larry-magid/are-adults-on-tv-role-mod_b_527124.html" target="_hplink"&gt;bullies you see on TV&lt;/a&gt;, whether they be politicians making derogatory comments about their opponents, pundits making mean or caustic comments, or adults bullying each other in sitcoms and other shows. I expect politicians to conduct vigorous campaigns but why can't they agree not to lie or degrade their opponents. For good and bad, public figures are role models and some are modeling bad behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adults bullying children&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been out in public -- say at a grocery store or restaurant -- and seen an adult being abusive to a child? I've seen parents yell at kids for no apparent reason. I've seen parents swat kids and I've seen plenty of cases where parents and other adults were just rude to kids. I experienced it myself when I was in school. I had a gym teacher who regularly harassed and belittled me and other kids who he thought were too slow, too fat or too gay. If you don't believe me, buy a copy of &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Warrens-Words-Commentary-Social-Justice/dp/0985098651" target="_hplink"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Warren's Words: Smart Commentary on Social Justice&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It was written by my elementary, middle school and high school friend and schoolmate &lt;a href="http://www.warrenblumenfeld.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Warren Blumenfeld&lt;/a&gt;, who documented some of this from his perspective as a gay teenager who -- at the time -- hadn't yet come out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a paper, &lt;a href="http://www.backoffbully.com/PDF%20files/BullyingTeachers.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;Teachers Who Bully Students: A Hidden Trauma&lt;/a&gt;, Stuart Twemlow and colleagues found that 70.4 percent of teachers asked said that they knew of "isolated cases" of teachers bullying students. 17.6 percent said it happened frequently and 40.2 percent admitted to having bullied a student at least once. In fairness, this was a very small study with only 116 responses from teachers from seven urban U.S. elementary schools. I wouldn't generalize this data to apply to all teachers, but even if the percentages turn out to be much lower, it's still a cause for concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*Definition of bullying&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of ways to define bullying and not all experts agree with this definition, but the closest one that we have to an "official" definition comes from the Olweus Bullying Prevent Program that defines bullying as "aggressive behavior that is intentional and that involves an imbalance of power. Most often, it is repeated over time."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nancy Willard, founder of &lt;a href="http://EmbraceCivility.org," target="_hplink"&gt;EmbraceCivility.org,&lt;/a&gt; defines student bullying as "hurtful act or acts that have caused severe distress, and are pervasive or persistent, and have caused physical harm to the student or his or her property, or significant interference with the students' educational opportunities."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: Little Girl's Evil Laughter Is The Best Thing Caught On Film</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/little-girl-dog-walking-troll_n_2965661.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2965661</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T23:10:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T03:34:28Z</updated>
    
    <summary>What's cuter than a mini-prankster with the most adorable evil laughter ever caught on film? Quite possibly nothing else. How else do you explain the...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Mohini Kundu</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mohini-kundu/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;What's cuter than a mini-prankster with the most adorable evil laughter ever caught on film? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite possibly nothing else. How else do you explain the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=rO2CJ6JuA1g" target="_hplink"&gt;over half-million views in a single day&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't worry -- no pets were harmed in the making of this video. Dad Jason Adams was able to grab his daughter's furry partner in crime before he got too far. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H/T &lt;a href="http://now.msn.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;msnNOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1058993/thumbs/s-LITTLE-GIRL-DOG-WALKING-TROLL-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>John Edwards' Daughter On Dad's Affair: 'I Was Devastated'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/cate-edwards-john-edwards-affair_n_2966760.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2966760</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T23:04:08Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T23:29:25Z</updated>
    
    <summary>John Edwards' eldest daughter is speaking out for the first time since her father's trial over alleged campaign finance violations. In an interview set to...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/chris-gentilviso/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;John Edwards' eldest daughter is speaking out for the first time since her &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/05/31/john-edwards-trial_n_1561041.html" target="_hplink"&gt;father's trial&lt;/a&gt; over alleged campaign finance violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an interview set to air Friday on NBC's "Today" and "Rock Center with Brian Williams," &lt;a href="http://todaynews.today.com/_news/2013/03/27/17488488-john-edwards-eldest-daughter-i-was-mad-devastated-about-affair?lite" target="_hplink"&gt;Cate Edwards opens up&lt;/a&gt; about her feelings when she found out about her dad's affair with Rielle Hunter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I guess he and my mom decided that that was, you know, how it needed to be done," she told NBC. "So yeah, I was devastated. And I was disappointed. I mean, these are my parents."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last May, John Edwards' campaign finance case was &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/05/31/john-edwards-trial-mistrial_n_1560562.html" target="_hplink"&gt;declared a mistrial&lt;/a&gt; when jurors were unable to pinpoint if he used donors' money to mask his pregnant mistress. The trial did lift Edwards' affair with Hunter into the public eye -- relations that took place while his wife, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2010/12/07/elizabeth-edwards-dead_n_793416.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Elizabeth Edwards&lt;/a&gt;, was ill with cancer. She died in December 2010 at age 61.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I don't think God's through with me," Edwards said after the mistrial. "I really believe he thinks there's still some good things I can do."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hunter published a tell-all book that was released in June, entitled &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/06/17/rielle-hunter-memoir_n_1604239.html" target="_hplink"&gt;"What Really Happened: John Edwards, Our Daughter and Me."&lt;/a&gt; Among the topics addressed were Hunter's views on Edwards' parenting of their daughter, Quinn, as well as his thoughts during his trial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Associated Press:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Days before his indictment Hunter asked: "So if you went to jail, what kind of jail would it be? One of those country clubs?"

&lt;p&gt;"He said, 'Yeah.'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"'Where?'" she asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"'Probably Virginia.'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"So Quinn and I will move to Virginia. Virginia is a great state."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only low-security federal prison in Virginia is in Petersburg, where former Washington, D.C., mayor Marion Barry once served time.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059465/thumbs/s-CATE-EDWARDS-JOHN-EDWARDS-AFFAIR-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Andy Braner: Tweet, Text, or Talk? Decisions for a New Way of Living</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/andy-braner/tweet-text-or-talk-decisi_b_2964256.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2964256</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T22:52:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T22:53:00Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I'm finding more and more teenagers don't have "hang out places" anymore, they've found their tribe of friends on social media and smart phones. Looking someone in the eye is a foreign concept for a new generation of emerging adults.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Andy Braner</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/andy-braner/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I asked a group of students last week, "How many friends do you have on Facebook?"  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One boy answered, "I have 1,200 friends on Facebook."  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Really?"  I asked in amazement.  I couldn't recall a time in my youth where I would ever have over three to four friends.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"How many of those friends, if they called you, would you answer and talk with?" I asked, fishing for an answer about how many people he really connects with apart from social media. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
"Maybe 20," He answered with a big smile confirming his own sense of popularity.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Of those 20, how many of those friends would actually come over to your house when you're world is falling apart, and just know you needed them?"I pushed further.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Maybe 2?"  He answered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew right then, the definition of friendship has been replaced. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
I'm finding more and more teenagers don't have "hang out places" anymore, they've found their tribe of friends on social media and smart phones. Looking someone in the eye is a foreign concept for a new generation of emerging adults.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wonder...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without creating a 'demon in the cell phone' attitude, what is really happening to us as humans?  I'm reminded of the Pixar movie &lt;em&gt;Wall-E&lt;/em&gt;, where the robot is whisked away to the floating city in outer space where the humans hang out. The ship is full of overweight social misfits who actually talk to one another side by side over a computer screen.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the majority of audiences, we watched that movie and found it ridiculous that someone wouldn't just lean over and talk to their friend sitting right beside them, but I'm watching our teens evolve into just those people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I was talking with a group of students and I asked, 'Where do you guys go to just have fun?" And the look on their eyes told me all I needed to know.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever tried to explain a particular concept to someone and see the 'deer in the headlights' look?  It was as if I asked these English-speaking natives a question in Arabic. They had no idea what I was talking about.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We don't go anywhere with a group. We hang out on our phones. Why would I go somewhere to hang out when I can carry &lt;strong&gt;everyone&lt;/strong&gt; with me in my back pocket?"  as he held up his iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world has changed.  We have decisions to make as parents. Are we going to continue to promote relationships over a computer screen, OR, are we going to intervene and raise a generation that sees the world around them in reality?  The friendships made on Facebook, Twitter, and Google+ are awesome, and I don't want to diminish the value of living in a technological world.  But in the same breath, my follow up question is simple: When are we going to provide outlets for our students to engage in face to face relationships?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had dinner last night with my 14-year-old son, and he told me about a book he was reading.  Mind you, this book wasn't on any school list, it was a book he decided to pick up at our local book store that taught him about global events. He took 20 minutes to share with me about the nature of having 160 countries all interacting together socially, economically, and relationally.  He defined the U.S. relationships with the East, and began to articulate Middle East politics as it relates to U.S. foreign service.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left our dinner as one of the most proud moments of my time as a dad. I have a son who is reading, developing conceptual ideas on his own, and articulating those ideas with his father as he speaks coherently about global issues, to my face.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my parent friends out there: Although the world on social media is useful, don't forget we have to help our kids enter the real world. They need to learn how to draw from their own experiences to talk to people face to face. They need to engage with people and learn proper body language when dealing with hard issues. And for the sake of their future relationships, we need to help them navigate emotional trauma apart from simply texting back and forth.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the convenience of technology, but I don't know if my wife is satisfied with simply texting my love back and forth. I think there comes a time when we have to look deep into one another's eyes, and show our spouses how much they really mean to us.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I for one, am proud of our team at KIVU who are dedicated to providing a place where teens can learn the art of being human.  We are committed to mentoring students in a technological free zone so they can still live in technology but when called upon they can exist in real time human interactions.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strange isn't it?  The world has shifted so much in the last decade, being human is now an art form?&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059452/thumbs/s-TEENS-SOCIAL-MEDIA-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Problem With Saying 'Stay-At-Home Mom'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/we-need-a-new-word-for-sahm_n_2966251.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2966251</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T22:40:52Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T22:41:07Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The childhood rhyme is wrong, of course -- words CAN always hurt you. They have power, and pack a punch, which is why we spend...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Lisa Belkin</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-belkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;The childhood rhyme is wrong, of course -- words CAN always hurt you. They have power, and pack a punch, which is why we spend so much time parsing and dissecting them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica Grose does some particularly pointed desconstructing over on Double X this week, asking &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/xx_factor/2013/03/26/housewife_homemaker_or_stay_at_home_mom_what_should_we_call_women_who_don.html " target="_hplink"&gt;“Why Do We Call Them ‘Stay-at-Home-Moms?’ There Must Be A Better Term.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She starts, as one should, with the history of that term. As with so many descriptors that become laden with connotation -- first Negro, then Black, then African-American, for instance -- this one started as a replacement for one that had itself become outdated and insulting. First there were housewives, then homemakers. Only in the early 1990s, when women rightly objected to both of those because they made raising children more about the home than the kids, &lt;a href="http://query.nytimes.com/search/sitesearch/#/%22stay+at+home+mom%22/since1851/allresults/1/allauthors/oldest/" target="_hplink"&gt;did the term stay-at-home-mother enter the language&lt;/a&gt;. And now many of us think that sounds like a slap, too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you write about parenting, you quickly learn that there is no way to describe mothers and their relationship with the paid workforce that doesn’t insult someone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay-at-home mother? &lt;em&gt;“Makes me sound like a shut-in!” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working mother? &lt;em&gt;“Don’t ALL mothers work!” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-working mother? &lt;em&gt;“Really? You think I’m eating bonbons?” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full-time mother? &lt;em&gt;“What, you think because I have a job I am only a mother part of the time?!” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s ignore for a moment the excellent point that we never seem to feel the need to modify “fathers” with “working” and focus instead on whether it is time to change what we call mothers who do or do not receive a paycheck. Because what we call them simultaneously reflects and alters the way we perceive them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with the current options -- working mom (let’s call her WM) and stay-at-home-mom (SAHM) -- is that they create a paradigm that is black and white, polar opposites. As MORE editor Leslie Jane Seymour &lt;a href="http://www.more.com/reinvention-money/careers/mommy-wars-peace-accords" target="_hplink"&gt;wrote recently&lt;/a&gt; of the time she asked, as a brand-new mother at a PTA open house, whether she might join both the club for SAHMs AND the one for WMs, “Oh no, you need to choose.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in real life few of us are all one acronym or the other. I have rarely met a SAHM who was not at one point fully engaged in the workforce and who did not have plans to reenter at some future point. And I know very few WMs who have not changed the way they work to adapt to the changing rhythms and responsibilities of children. Women who are “at home” are also running small businesses or local charities or school fundraisers. Women who are “at work” are leaving early, or arriving late, or working after children are in bed, or arranging part-time, flex-time and telecommuting schedules. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, New York Magazine held Kelly Makino up as the poster person for SAHMs -- &lt;a href="http://nymag.com/news/features/retro-wife-2013-3/" target="_hplink"&gt;“the Retro Wife,”&lt;/a&gt; she was called on the cover -- and yet, in an interview with me and Nancy Redd on HuffPostLive, she said that she is hardly an example of all-or-nothing. (You can watch the clip below and read the &lt;a href="http://jezebel.com/5991961/women-profiled-in-feminist-housewives-piece-say-new-york-misquoted-and-misrepresented-t" target="_hplink"&gt;piece in Jezebel&lt;/a&gt; in which Makino told Tracie Egan Morrissey the same.) Though she no longer is paid as a social worker, for instance, she uses her training in her work with a 600-family co-op that helps parents “pool time and resources.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If women are not either/or, this/not that, why then is our language so binary? And how do we change that? Or, more specifically, what do we change it TO? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would suggest that a replacement term has to meet two criteria. First, that it apply to men as well as women. Second, that it include those who are parents and those who are not. Our social ideal should be a work/life paradigm where everyone shapes a career that includes times where we work full-throttle and times when we ratchet back, and our words should be consistent with that. They should embrace the sense of ebb and flow, more and less that are the truth of most of our lives, rather than the stop and start, one or the other, that are unrealistically divisive. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already have options out there. Sylvia Ann Hewlett, whose recent change of her company’s name from the Center for Work-Life Policy to the &lt;a href="http://www.worklifepolicy.org/index.php/pageID/23" target="_hplink"&gt;Center for Talent Innovation&lt;/a&gt; reflects that broadened perspective, uses the analogy of a highway, with on-ramps and off-ramps. Cathy Benko of Deloitte uses &lt;a href="http://www.deloitte.com/us/talent/mcc" target="_hplink"&gt;the image of a lattice&lt;/a&gt; rather than a ladder, allowing for zigs and zags. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And perhaps the answer will turn out to be Sheryl Sandberg’s recent contribution, that of &lt;a href="www.http://leanin.org" target="_hplink"&gt;Leaning In and Leaning Back&lt;/a&gt; -- as in “I’m leaning back in my career for the moment and leaning in more at home.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the word, it’s past time we find one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggestions? Leave yours in the comments or tweet them to &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/HuffPostParents" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPostParents&lt;/a&gt; and we'll collect them in a slideshow here. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059403/thumbs/s-STAYATHOMEMOM-mini.jpg?17" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Don Meyer, Ph.D.: Because I Said So</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/don-meyer-phd/because-i-said-so_1_b_2962815.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2962815</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T22:22:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T22:23:00Z</updated>
    
    <summary>In his book Ken Jennings has compiled "125 of the nagging Mom and Dad-isms that we all grew up with." To the best of his ability he has researched them and renders a verdict of "True" or "False." For some of them he acknowledges that the truth is not absolute.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Don Meyer, Ph.D.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/don-meyer-phd/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"Don't drink coffee until you are 20-years-old or you won't grow up to be tall and strong."&lt;/em&gt; -- Barbara Meyer (my mother)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps Ken Jennings is best known for being the record holder for winnings on Jeopardy ($2.52 million).  But now he has written his third book titled &lt;em&gt;Because I Said So; The Truth Behind the Myths, Tales and Warnings Every Generation Passes Down to Its Kids&lt;/em&gt; (2012).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his book Jennings has compiled "125 of the nagging Mom and Dad-isms that we all grew up with."  To the best of his ability he has researched them and renders a verdict of "True" or "False."  For some of them he acknowledges that the truth is not absolute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will not find in this book propositions that cannot be tested scientifically by doctors, research, etc.  For example, whether watching too much TV is harmful is still widely debated even after being around for 60 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennings also gathers what he calls "parental nagging" from other cultures.  In Korea, they aren't allowed to sleep with an electric fan in their rooms because a fan, they are told, will somehow asphyxiate them while they sleep.  Filipino children are told not to wear red when it's stormy, because red clothing attracts lightening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who of us has not heard our parents say things like this:  wait an hour after eating to swim; if you cross your eyes they may stay that way; don't go out into the cold because you might get sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennings does cite studies showing that cold, wet feet might help cause a cold and hot chicken soup can fight one.  I was surprised when we were in Finland a few years ago, however, that mothers there regularly place their babies outside on the porch in bitter cold weather.  Yes, they do bundle them up but they want them to breathe fresh, cold air.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting examples Jennings gives in his book involves lollipops.  He describes the time his young son, Dylan, came running around a corner with a grape Tootsie Pop in his mouth.  "'Whoa, slow down!' I said.  'What if you tripped and fell on your face?  The lollipop stick would get jammed right through the roof of your mouth!'  Dylan's eyes got wide, 'Could that really happen?'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennings admits he had no idea.  His mother told him that repeatedly while growing up and now he was repeating it.  In his words, "What do you do when a nine-year-old calls your bluff?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He did check with his mother to back him up and she said she had no idea. She said, "That's what Grandma used to tell us." His mother went on to say she thought it may have come from some novel.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I was horrified," Jennings writes. "A fact I confidently passed along to my trusting children turned out to be a third-hand rumor confirmed only by a novelist... What else had I inadvertently been misleading them about?"  I know he must be smiling when he says, "That's the dirty secrets of parenting:  It's a big game of telephone stretching back through the centuries and delivering garbled, well-intended medieval bromides to the present.  Possible misinformation like the lollipop thing never gets corrected; it just goes into hibernation for a few decades and then jumps out to snare a new generation, like a 17-year-old cicada."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So is there really danger in sitting too close to the TV or eating toothpaste or sneezing with your eyes open or even running with scissors?  If you must know the answer, this book will help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what about my mother's counsel, "No coffee 'til you're 20 or you won't grow up to be tall and strong."  Actually, I didn't drink coffee until I was 20.  But since I stand about five feet seven inches, I have always wondered how tall I would be if I had drunk coffee before I was 20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	   &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Dr. Don Meyer is President of&lt;br /&gt;
Valley Forge Christian College, Phoenixville, PA&lt;br /&gt;
Responses can be emailed to president@vfcc.edu&lt;br /&gt;
Official page:  Facebook.com/DrDonMeyer&lt;br /&gt;
Originally published with The Phoenix, www.phoenixvillenews.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059411/thumbs/s-KEN-JENNINGS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Dr. Jim Taylor: Teach Your Wired Children About Healthy Relationships</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-jim-taylor/teach-your-wired-children_b_2958331.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2958331</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T22:18:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T22:19:04Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There is a place for children to have online relationships, but they are no substitute for the depth and breadth of flesh-and-blood relationships where your children are able to fully connect with other people and completely experience the meaning, satisfaction and joy of human relationships.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Dr. Jim Taylor</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-jim-taylor/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Technology, such as the Internet, smartphones and social media, can have great benefits in helping your children form and maintain relationships. At the same time, if not used with limits and guidance by your children, such use may prevent them from developing the essential relationship qualities and skills that have allowed us to make real connections and build real relationships for ages. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is certainly a place for children to have online relationships, but they are no substitute for the depth and breadth of flesh-and-blood relationships where your children are able to fully connect with other people and completely experience the meaning, satisfaction and joy of deep human relationships. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, children's (and adults') real relationships can be untidy, with hurt feelings, anger, frustration and disappointment. But relationships are like two sides of the same coin; children can't experience the beauty of relationships -- love,  comfort and excitement -- without also being willing to accept its occasional blood, sweat and tears. I challenge anyone who can show me that online relationships can provide that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To raise children capable of having healthy relationships in this world that is so dominated by popular culture and technology, you must be wel- informed and deliberate about your children's exposure to both. Of course, the most basic way to prevent popular culture and technology from having an undue and unhealthy influence over your children's relationships is to set limits on their exposure. You should establish clear expectations about the quality of the popular culture that your children are allowed to experience and the type and quantity of technology they are permitted to use. Just as importantly, you must create appropriate consequences to add "bite" the expectations you set in the event of inevitable transgressions on the part of your children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another obvious preventive measure is to educate your children about the messages they're getting from popular culture and technology. The more informed your children are about those messages, the less vulnerable they will be to those messages. As they get older, they will be able to make deliberate choices about what aspects of popular culture they expose themselves to and what technology they use. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of this education involves talking to your children about the unrealistic messages that popular culture conveys to them about relationships, for example, that love can be found in a matter of weeks (think The Bachelor) or that physical appearance is a healthy foundation for relationships (think Gossip Girls). You can also show them the differences between online and offline relationships, particularly what is missing from the former and present in the latter, for example, facial expressions, body language, and other nonverbal cues (notwithstanding Skype and other video chatting), voice inflection (notwithstanding phone calls), touch, and smell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you can't just play defense against popular culture and technology. In fact, to raise children who are capable of healthy relationships in this digital age, teaching your children about healthy relationships may be your most important way to help them resist the unhealthy messages from popular culture and technology and ensure that they are capable of developing healthy relationships. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good place to start in teaching your children about healthy relationships is in your relationship with your spouse. Let me say this clearly. There is no greater influence on how your children come to see relationships than your relationship with your "other half." From a very early age, your relationship -- good, bad or ugly -- likely becomes the template on which their future relationships are based. If you can show your children from an early age how a healthy relationship works, filled with respect, caring and empathy, simply through your daily relationship with your spouse, you will instill in them a positive view of relationships that will be resistant to those that they receive from popular culture (this, of course, is more of a challenge for divorced couples or single parents). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, when you model the healthy use of technology as a tool for strengthening relationships, you provide your children with another template that will encourage the dominance of offline relationships, teach them how to use technology to foster healthy relationships and make them less vulnerable to the allure of online relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most powerful way to override the inevitable messages your children will receive from popular culture and technology about relationships is to give your children the most quantity and quality of unmediated (meaning direct) social experiences on which they can build the competence, confidence, and comfort to develop healthy relationships throughout their lives. These encounters can include the spectrum of relationships including family, friends, educational, athletic, cultural and spiritual. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This depth and breadth of flesh-and-blood relationships will also give your children the ability to compare those relationships and online relationships and, hopefully, see that the latter can't hold a candle to the former. The more ways in which your children can experience the richness of offline relationships, the more they will come to value them and not be drawn to those gained through popular culture and technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to maximizing your children's in-the-moment appreciation for face-to-face relationships, you can also actively teach them essential relationship skills. Early exposure to social skills and the basics of relationships, for example, saying hello and goodbye and please and thank you, shaking hands and looking others in the eye, as well as compassion and concern for others, will prevent your children from avoiding real relationships due to doubt, shyness or social discomfort and give them the competence and confidence to want to explore further unmediated relationships. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to give your children direct experience in relationships and the tools to build self-assurance in your children's relationship capabilities. You also want to instill in them a skeptical attitude toward the messages they get about relationships from popular culture and technology. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you accomplish these goals, you give your children a true gift, namely, they will see for themselves that real-life relationships are far more rewarding than those found online and they will make sure these relationships take precedence over the virtual kind. And that is a gift that will keep on giving throughout their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1015688/thumbs/s-SCREEN-SENSE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kristin Shaw: Dear Future Daughter-in-Law</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kristin-shaw/dear-future-daughterinlaw_b_2960379.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2960379</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T21:51:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T21:52:05Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I will love you as my own daughter, if you will let me. If you're close to your mom, I am not going to try to replace her; you don't need two moms. You might, however, be interested in having a mother-in-law who might be a friend. All you have to do is ask.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kristin Shaw</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kristin-shaw/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I'm one of the lucky ones; I adore my husband's mother. She is loving, and kind, and thoughtful.  She doesn't pry. She doesn't judge. She doesn't tell me what to do and how to do it. She spoils me, in fact. Before you write me off and think I'm just bragging, dear daughter-in-law-to-be (or son-in-law, should that be the case) let me tell you this: as the mother of a boy, I am observing and learning much about the way I want to be as a mother-in-law. &lt;em&gt;Your&lt;/em&gt; mother-in-law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conversations with many a girlfriend, I've listened to the laments of daughters-in-law who struggle with mothers-in-law who have hurt their feelings with passive-aggressive (or flat-out rude) words, or purposely give their grandchildren something to eat that they weren't supposed to, or constantly tell them how to run their household. I've seen the eye rolls, the long sighs and the "she's coming to visit, God help me" refrains.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mother and my father both called each others' mothers "Mom." It sounded natural from both sides, even though both loved their own mothers dearly. I don't have any expectations; you can call me Kristin. You can call me Nonna, if you have children. Just please don't call me anything that you would call your worst enemy.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of children, I promise that I won't ask you when you're going to start having them. If you have one, I won't ask you when you'll have the second one or tell you that you CAN'T POSSIBLY HAVE JUST ONE CHILD GOOD GOD WOMAN HOW CAN YOU DO THAT TO HIM? Because someone actually said that to me and it really pissed me off.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may spoil your kids a little bit, if you'll let me, but I won't feed them chocolate if you tell me not to. I promise to take their allergies very seriously, and I won't let them watch TV all day. I'll happily babysit! If you choose to cry-it-out or not cry-it-out, breastfeed or bottle feed, pacifier or no pacifier, cloth or disposable diaper, I support your decision. Lord knows that plenty of other people will give you their opinion when you're a parent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, I know how this works. In order to stay close to my son, I need to stay close to the one to whom he gives his heart.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it's not just that. I will love you as my own daughter, if you will let me. If you're close to your mom, I am not going to try to replace her; you don't need two moms. You might, however, be interested in having a mother-in-law who might be a friend. A friend with whom you enjoy spending time and maybe even learning something, if you ask. All you have to do is ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I'm going to ask you right now, wherever you are, to give me a chance. Don't believe that all mothers-in-law are like the evil stepmothers of old Disney. Don't think that I don't want you in our lives or that I'll be in the way. Don't believe that we are in a competition. If my son has fallen in love with you, then you must be very special. We are on the same team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, dear daughter-in-law, that I'm scared of losing my son forever. Unfortunately, I know a few men who have shut their mothers out at the urging of a new spouse, leaving their mothers heartbroken. I can barely speak the words as I try not to imagine what that might be like for a mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one time, I thought that maybe having a boy was the easier route through life, avoiding the drama we girls seem to generate as teenagers. However, I'm realizing how much more difficult it may be to let them go as they grow older, because they jump out of the nest with both feet, willing themselves to fly even before their feathers are fully formed. They feel the pressure to be MEN and they propel themselves forward, and away from their families... as far as they need to go to find themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to tell you about my son's &lt;a href="http://www.twocannoli.com/2012/07/you-will-cry.html" target="_hplink"&gt;childhood&lt;/a&gt;, and what it was like to hold him and rock him to sleep at night. I want to laugh with you about the funny things he said as a preschooler and show you his &lt;a href="http://www.twocannoli.com/2012/09/the-moment-we-met.html" target="_hplink"&gt;baby pictures&lt;/a&gt;. I hope to share with you his triumphs and dreams from when he was a child, and fill in the blanks on any of the stories he has told you from his mama's perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not here to stand in your way. I'm here to spoil you, and listen to you and help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like my mother-in-law does for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-27-KristinShaw.JPG"&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-27-KristinShaw.JPG" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-27-KristinShaw-thumb.JPG" width="500" height="374" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059350/thumbs/s-KRISTIN-SHAW-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
