<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Beyonce Would Respond To The 'Mommy Wars'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/how-might-diva-feminist-b_n_2939446.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2939446</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T13:53:41Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T13:55:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>She might not address the issues facing women head on, but we can still look to her vague proclamations for insight. As the inspiration for...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>BuzzFeed SHIFT</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-gray/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She might not address the issues facing women head on, but we can still look to her vague proclamations for insight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the inspiration for the Atlantic's "All the Single Ladies," you must believe, Beyonce, that the role of women in society is changing in fundamentally significant ways.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1042654/thumbs/s-BEYONCE-NEW-SINGLE-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Amanda Bynes' Family Concerned About Her Well-Being</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/amanda-bynes-family-concerned_n_2939246.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2939246</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T13:43:40Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T13:43:50Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Amanda Bynes' family is reportedly thinking about bringing her back to Los Angeles. The troubled 26-year-old's bizarre behavior has her loved ones concerned and they're...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Leigh Blickley</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/leigh-blickley/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Amanda Bynes' family is reportedly thinking about bringing her back to Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The troubled 26-year-old's bizarre behavior &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/400714/source-amanda-bynes-family-is-concerned-for-her-well-being" target="_hplink"&gt;has her loved ones concerned and they're ready to intervene&lt;/a&gt;, according to E! News.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="amanda bynes family" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052721/thumbs/o-AMANDA-BYNES-FAMILY-570.jpg?3" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since moving to New York from L.A., Bynes has been acting strangely, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/tweets-of-the-week-amanda-bynes-drake_n_2935539.html" target="_hplink"&gt;posting weird pictures on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; -- umm, that cheek piercing? -- as well as &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/amanda-bynes-drake-vagina_n_2929248.html?utm_hp_ref=celebrity" target="_hplink"&gt;raunchy and inappropriate tweets&lt;/a&gt;. A source close to the star tells E! that &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/400714/source-amanda-bynes-family-is-concerned-for-her-well-being" target="_hplink"&gt;her family is "concerned for her welfare"&lt;/a&gt; and want her to move closer to them so that they can keep an eye on her. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, she refuses to leave the Big Apple. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The source adds that Bynes family is hopeful that everything is going to be OK, but that they're ready to step in if needed. Well, considering her recent run-ins with police and out-of-control solo outings, it appears it's time to intervene. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please don't take paparazzi pictures of me I like taking my own!&lt;a href="http://t.co/Jw2XOcywvT" title="http://twitpic.com/cbn57a"&gt;twitpic.com/cbn57a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Amanda Bynes (@AmandaBynes) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AmandaBynes/status/312696457633357824"&gt;March 15, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052723/thumbs/s-AMANDA-BYNES-FAMILY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Gay British Teen Dies After Being Set On Fire At Birthday Party </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/steven-simpson-gay-teen-burned-birthday-_n_2939092.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2939092</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T13:41:07Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T13:41:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A young British man has been convicted of manslaughter after killing a gay teen by setting him on fire. The BBC reports that 20-year-old Jordan...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Curtis M. Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/curtis-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;A young British man has been convicted of manslaughter after killing a gay teen by setting him on fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BBC reports that 20-year-old Jordan Sheard has been sentenced to three and a half years in jail for &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-21887535" target="_hplink"&gt;the death of Steven Simpson&lt;/a&gt; after pleading guilty to manslaughter charges. Simpson, 18, died one day after sustaining "significant burns" in June 2012, according to the report. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simpson had Asperger's syndrome, a speech impairment and epilepsy, &lt;a href="http://www.yorkshirepost.co.uk/news/at-a-glance/general-news/teen-dies-at-his-birthday-party-after-friend-covers-him-with-tanning-oil-and-sets-him-alight-1-5519548" target="_hplink"&gt;the Yorkshire Post noted&lt;/a&gt;. The teen had reportedly been dared to strip down to his underpants before being doused in tanning oil, after which Sheard set him aflame at the party. Other reports said that &lt;a href="http://news.ninemsn.com.au/world/2013/03/22/10/32/teen-set-alight-at-birthday-party" target="_hplink"&gt;anti-gay messages&lt;/a&gt;, including "gay boy" and "I love d*ck," had been found scrawled across Simpson's body. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detective Sean Middleton described Simpson to the BBC as "a very caring and likeable young man" and a "generous spirit was taken advantage of and a single thoughtless act resulted in his death."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of local lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender (LGBT) rights advocates said they believed Sheard's prison term to be too lenient, but prosecuting attorney Tim Warburton &lt;a href="http://www.thestar.co.uk/news/local/barnsley-teen-burned-to-death-on-his-18th-birthday-1-5521116" target="_hplink"&gt;nonetheless told The Star&lt;/a&gt; that the sentence was "within the range of what would be expected had it been considered a hate crime," and that it would not be appealed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"This was a cruel case of bullying based on Steven’s sexuality and disability," Warburton is quoted as saying. "While we accept Jordan did not intend to kill Steven, his actions did lead to his death." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Sheard's attorney said his client had been "deeply and significantly affected by what he has done and the tragic consequences that ensued," which describing Simpson's death as a "stupid prank that went wrong in a bad way," &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2297053/Yob-killed-autistic-gay-teenager-Steven-Simpson-setting-18th-birthday-party.html" target="_hplink"&gt;the Daily Mail noted&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052373/thumbs/s-STEVEN-SIMPSON-GAY-TEEN-BURNED-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Loren Ridinger: Learning to Let Your Children Go</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/loren-ridinger/learning-to-let-your-chil_b_2921073.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2921073</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T13:14:59Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T13:15:02Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Watching your child grow into an independent individual is an incredible experience filled with highs and lows.  And once their grown, it's even more of a challenge to step back and let your child make their own decisions.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Loren Ridinger</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/loren-ridinger/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;It's been a flurry of activity around our house for the last few months. My daughter, Amber, will likely be married by the time you read this post, and to be honest -- the wedding planning was a bittersweet ride. Of course we are so happy for her, we love Duane so much that it is easy to feel confident about her future. I love being a mom. And, the past years have been so incredible to watch my little baby grow into a gorgeous, independent woman. But as a mom, it's tough. Sometimes I just want to scoop my little baby back up and sing her to sleep. Helping her plan her wedding was a beautiful process -- of course I wanted it to be the day of her dreams. But it's milestones like this that make it even more difficult for me to let her go. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you decide to have a baby, it's a huge decision. During the months of pregnancy and even throughout the first years of her life, I worried all the time. Am I a good mom? Is Amber a happy baby? Do other people think I am a good mom? Am I making the right decisions as a parent? The questions and uncertainties go on and on. Being a new mom, there's nothing else to compare the experience to -- it's completely unchartered territory. And it's terrifying and exhilarating all at once. All the while you're filled with overwhelming love. A love so strong and intense, sometimes you just have to laugh while other times you just have to cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most parents, we want nothing but the best for our children. The best education, we want them to be happy and confident, we don't want them to suffer over anything -- as seeing them in any pain is certainly more painful to us as parents. I still want to give my daughter everything I didn't have and more. I want her life to be filled with joy and success and I never want her to worry.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she was just a baby, I remember thinking about the day she would find her prince and be married. I remember the moment perfectly, staring at her in her little bed and thinking how I just wanted her to stay little and need me forever. Throughout the years, I recall doing everything I could to keep her close, to protect her and for her to still need me as her mom. I am sure that was challenging for her because like most parents, we can be overwhelming (especially me) while trying to keep them little when all they want to do is spread their wings and fly.  It's just as tough now as she heads out to have a family of her own. I am so happy for both of them, but at the same time, I have to admit, I have been a bit melancholy. I finally figured it out while recalling all the memories, looking at all her baby pictures and listening to wedding songs for her dance with her dad -- you never stop being a mom. Whether your child is five or fifty, they are always going to be your baby and their age just doesn't matter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching your child grow into an independent individual is an incredible experience filled with highs and lows. Helping to guide and mold your child while teaching them to function in a world full of challenges is a big task with big ideals. And once their grown, it's even more of a challenge to step back and let your child make their own decisions.  But it's okay to feel this way. The love for our children is unconditional. There is nothing else like it, sometimes it hurts but it is still the greatest love of all.  I am always going to be her mom and she will always be my baby -- even in my perfect and not-so-perfect moments. Like a caterpillar, she has grown and turned into a beautiful butterfly. She is ready to spread her wings and fly.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is her time to shine.  Fly baby -- Fly.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052705/thumbs/s-MOTHER-DAUGHTER-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Passover Seder Won't Be Complete Without This DIY Afikoman Bag</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/passover-ideas-afikoman-bag_n_2931925.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2931925</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T13:07:40Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T13:06:56Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The kids will have a blast searching for this crafty sack. </summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rain-embuscado/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Tomorrow marks the start of Passover, and to help you prepare for the occasion, today's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/craft-of-the-day" target="_hplink"&gt;Craft Of The Day&lt;/a&gt; features a project by &lt;a href="http://secret-agent-josephine.com/blog/" target="_hplink"&gt;Secret Agent Josephine&lt;/a&gt; which was featured on &lt;a href="http://theshiksa.com" target="_hplink"&gt;The Shiksa In The Kitchen's blog&lt;/a&gt;. The blogger shows us a fun and no-sew way &lt;a href="http://theshiksa.com/2012/04/01/family-fun-afikoman-bag/" target="_hplink"&gt;to make a DIY Afikoman bag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="passover ideas" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052420/thumbs/a-PASSOVER-IDEAS-640x468.jpg?15" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="http://secret-agent-josephine.com/blog/" target="_hplink"&gt;Brenda Ponnay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No seder can be complete without the search for this matzoh holder. And since it's such a fun and important part of celebrating, why not make this case really special? Plus, it's super easy and the blogger shows you two different versions, so you can chose your favorite style.  For full instructions, head over to &lt;a href="http://theshiksa.com/2012/04/01/family-fun-afikoman-bag/" target="_hplink"&gt;The Shiksa in the Kitchen's website&lt;/a&gt;. And if you're on the hunt for even more great ideas, be sure to check out our &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/craft-of-the-day" target="_hplink"&gt;Craft Of The Day&lt;/a&gt; slideshow below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEPOLLAJAX--193347--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have a home story idea or tip? Email us at homesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052420/thumbs/s-PASSOVER-IDEAS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>8 Ways To Create A Restful, Cozy Reading Nook </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/create-reading-nook_n_2933462.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2933462</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T13:04:01Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T13:03:31Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There are few things more relaxing than spending a Sunday afternoon at home and curling up with a good book -- so why not create...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/carolyn-gregoire/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;There are few things more relaxing than spending a Sunday afternoon at home and curling up with a good book -- so why not create a cozy area just for this purpose for your family to enjoy? A reading nook can also be the perfect way to transform an awkward corner, windowsill or loft space into a warm, comfortable area for a little R&amp;R. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it's for kids or grown-ups, these cozy, well-lit reading spots will set a peaceful tone in any room, and they're surprisingly easy to set up. If you're thinking about adding one to your home, click through the slideshow below for eight  tranquil and restful design ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell us: Do you have a reading nook in your home? Would you ever add one to your living room or playroom? Share your thoughts in the comments or tweet &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPostHome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--287873--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have a home story idea or tip? Email us at homesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051835/thumbs/s-READING-NOOK-IDEAS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: Little Boy Saves Cat From Bullies</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/wendell-overton-saves-cat-bullies_n_2936222.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2936222</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T01:17:30Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T01:20:33Z</updated>
    
    <summary>This is Jackson the cat. He lives in North Carolina. Last week, a group of kids approached Jackson, threw him into the air, ran over...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Hayley Hudson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/hayley-hudson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;This is Jackson the cat. He lives in North Carolina.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="wendell overton 4" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052444/thumbs/o-WENDELL-OVERTON-4-570.jpg?5" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, a group of kids approached Jackson, &lt;a href="http://www.examiner.com/article/10-year-old-boy-north-carolina-rescues-cat-being-tortured-by-bullies" target="_hplink"&gt;threw him into the air&lt;/a&gt;, ran over him with their bikes and squirted energy drinks in his face. The bullies reportedly varied in age from 5 to 13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But 10-year-old Wendell Overton saved the day. According to a Wednesday post on the Outer Banks SPCA's Facebook page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="wendell overton 3" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052440/thumbs/o-WENDELL-OVERTON-3-570.jpg?5" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Wendell Overton, 10, of Manteo made the world a better place on March 12. Jackson the cat was being tortured by a group of boys. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10151830043083298&amp;set=a.10150999268118298.543082.116792203297&amp;type=1&amp;theater" target="_hplink"&gt;Courageous Wendell rescued Jackson&lt;/a&gt; and took him home to his mother, who called the Outer Banks SPCA. Jackson is doing great and will be available for adoption soon! Thank you, Wendell, for being so brave and doing the right thing!&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overton &lt;a href="http://www.wvec.com/news/Manteo-youngster-praised-for-saving-cat-from-abuse--197808781.html" target="_hplink"&gt;had seen the black-and-white cat&lt;/a&gt; in the neighborhood before, WVEC reported. On the day of the attack he became worried that his injuries were serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"He said 'Mom, &lt;a href="http://www.wvec.com/news/Manteo-youngster-praised-for-saving-cat-from-abuse--197808781.html" target="_hplink"&gt;this cat is going to die&lt;/a&gt;. We need to save it,'" his mother said in the video above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story generated a flurry of attention for Jackson and Overton. Shortly after the photo went online, the SPCA posted an update:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;WOW! Words cannot express how moved we are by &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10151829057283298&amp;set=a.152917373297.144372.116792203297&amp;type=1&amp;theater" target="_hplink"&gt;the overwhelming response to Wendell's story&lt;/a&gt;. We wanted to give everyone an update on Jackson, the cat saved by Wendell's compassion and bravery. He is recovering well, resting comfortably, eating like a king and will be looking for a new home soon! &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tons of cards and letters poured in praising Wendell's bravery. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XOXO.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="wendell overton 6" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052447/thumbs/o-WENDELL-OVERTON-6-570.jpg?5" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;H/T: &lt;a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/10-year-old-heroically-saves-cat-from-bullies" target="_hplink"&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052436/thumbs/s-WENDELL-OVERTON-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Heidi Murkoff: How Pregnancy Has Changed Since I Was Pregnant</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/heidi-murkoff/pregnancy-has-changed_b_2931161.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2931161</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T23:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T18:40:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Childcare is more likely to be divided more equitably between parents too. Many of our mums commented that their partners are more involved than their dads were when they were growing up - and others noted that the shift towards greater sharing of the baby care workload is inevitable, given that most mums (as dads) are juggling parenthood with a career.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Heidi Murkoff</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/heidi-murkoff/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;It all started with a surprise -the happiest kind of surprise, but the most life-changing, too:  what they call in the business (for lack of a more technical term) an 'oops' pregnancy.  Erik and I got married, and three months later - oops, I was pregnant.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was my first reaction joy? Excitement? Nausea? A heady combination of all three?  No - it was more along the lines of...panic.  My mind reeled, my stomach churned with all the questions, all the worries - all the thoughts of gin-and-tonics, coffees, and assorted medications I'd unwittingly shared with my well-under-age embryo before discovering she existed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If knowledge is powerful - and I believe it is, especially empowering when you're pregnant - I was definitely running on empty.  Back in the days when pregnancy information came from a handful of books, an occasional newspaper article or well-meaning but misinformed mother-in-law, auntie, neighbour, or friend)- answers to my questions and reassurance for my concerns weren't easy to come by.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I became a mum on a mission - a mission to help expectant parents sleep better at night than Erik and I had.  And literally two hours before I went into labour with Emma, I delivered the proposal for What to Expect When You're Expecting.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pregnancy hasn't changed all that much in the 30 years since (it's still about 9 months long, you're still queasy and bloated and constipated) and neither have babies (they still don't come with instructions, they spend a good chunk of their days and nights crying, they still smell amazing). But the way expectant and new mums and dads experience their pregnancies has evolved - and how they access the information, the support, the empowerment that they crave has changed...a lot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And today, there's an app for that. Make that, hundreds of apps, so parents can tap into information on the go.  Message boards, Twitter and Facebook all allow mums to swap insights, experiences, and baby bump photo with other mums. Personally, I've exchanged posts and tweets with mums and dads from one end of the earth to the other - Cairo to Istanbul, London to Sydney and Singapore to South Africa. And if there's one message that resonates in each: no matter what a parent's socioeconomic, racial, religious, cultural, or geographical differences, the bond we share is so much greater than what divides us and at the end of the day - we all want what's best for our babies.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what's trending among UK parents?  Hashtag: technology. Pregnancy apps mean that information and support are always at your fingertips, no matter where you are.  In a survey of 1,000 British mums we conducted for the launch of WhatToExpect.co.uk, we found (and no surprise here) that 45% of mums in the UK count apps as one of their most valuable resources during pregnancy.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And mum's the word on social media, too.  It takes a mum to "get" a mum - and nobody knows this better than social networking mums.  Today's mums can cast a wide social net - making hundreds, thousands, even millions of virtual fellow mum friends who are going through the same experience at the same time - through sites like WhatToExpect.co.uk. Just knowing that you're not alone in what you're feeling  (whether it's a seemingly random pregnancy symptom or frustration over a baby who won't take "sleep" for an answer) doesn't necessarily make those feelings go away - but it helps you cope with them so much more effectively.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What else is trending among UK families? Dads. Our survey showed that mums, while still doing the lioness's share of parenting, aren't going it alone anymore - at least when it comes to all the many choices expectant and new parents have to make. In fact, 79% of couples say they share parenting decisions, compared to the 43% of respondents who feel their own parents did back in the day.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Childcare is more likely to be divided more equitably between parents too. Many of our mums commented that their partners are more involved than their dads were when they were growing up - and others noted that the shift towards greater sharing of the baby care workload is inevitable, given that most mums (as dads) are juggling parenthood with a career.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm often asked whether becoming a mum (or a dad) is different today than it was when my sweet little oops, Emma, made her way into the world - and into my tentative arms.  Different today, now that Emma has her arms full of her first baby Lennox (still managing, of course, to use her one-handed iPhone skills to keep in touch with her WhatToExpect mama friends).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different? In many ways. The same? In many more.  Challenging and life-changing...mind-blowing and heart-melting...frustrating and fulfilling...exasperating and exhilarating...in other words, the hardest job we'll ever love? Without a doubt.       &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;www.whattoexpect.co.uk&lt;br /&gt;
@WhatToExpectUK&lt;br /&gt;
Facebook - What to Expect UK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://pinterest.com/ukwhattoexpect/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/674948/thumbs/s-PREGNANCY-mini.jpg?4" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: Put Together This Centerpiece In Minutes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/easter-ideas-flower-arrangements_n_2926331.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2926331</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T22:13:10Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T22:14:10Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Pretty cool, huh?</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rain-embuscado/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;If you haven't already noticed, we've started preparing for Easter festivities early this month. From &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/04/05/easter-craft-ideas-easter-egg-vase_n_1406740.html" target="_hplink"&gt;experimenting with centerpieces&lt;/a&gt; for the dining room table to experimenting with &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/19/easter-ideas-alternative-egg-designs_n_2901928.html" target="_hplink"&gt;alternative design ideas for the traditional egg&lt;/a&gt;, we've got quite a few projects on our plate. But one of the most important aspects of the holiday meal is the centerpiece. And a classic one can be made with lovely seasonal flowers, like colorful tulips. And who better to teach us how to put together a stunning arrangement than Martha Stewart? And this one has a cute twist! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the video above to learn how you can make a bouquet of egg-like flowers just like Martha, and click through our  photos of our own version of the craft. And if you want even more &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/easter-2013" target="_hplink"&gt;Easter ideas&lt;/a&gt;, check out our our board on &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/easter-at-home/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEPOLLAJAX--219180--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have a home story idea or tip? Email us at homesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052304/thumbs/s-EASTER-IDEAS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Poster Contest Celebrating Fossil Fuels Triggers Heated Energy Debate In Utah</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/fossil-fuel-poster-contest-earth-day-utah-energy-debate_n_2933673.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2933673</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T21:51:34Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T22:06:28Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A controversial, state-sponsored pro-fossil fuels Earth Day poster contest for children has triggered a heated and divisive debate about Utah's reliance on non-renewable energy resources....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Dominique Mosbergen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dominique-mosbergen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;A controversial, state-sponsored &lt;a href="http://fs.ogm.utah.gov/PUB/DOGM/Earth_Day/EarthDayPosterContest-OfficialRules2013.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;pro-fossil fuels Earth Day poster contest&lt;/a&gt; for children has triggered a heated and divisive debate about Utah's reliance on non-renewable energy resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The debate has revealed a much more complicated struggle -- fueled by politics, big business, and a concern for the environment -- that is now being waged to determine the future of Utah's energy resources and environmental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organized by Utah's &lt;a href="http://linux1.ogm.utah.gov/WebStuff/wwwroot/division/tabs.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Division of Oil, Gas and Mining&lt;/a&gt; and sponsored by the Society of Petroleum Engineers, the 2013 Earth Day poster contest's theme was "&lt;a href="http://fs.ogm.utah.gov/PUB/DOGM/Earth_Day/EarthDayPosterContest-OfficialRules2013.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;Where would WE be without oil, gas and mining?&lt;/a&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contest was open to Utah students in grades K-6, and according to the &lt;a href="http://fs.ogm.utah.gov/PUB/DOGM/Earth_Day/EarthDayPosterContest-OfficialRules2013.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;informational pamphlet&lt;/a&gt; provided to principals and teachers, the first objective of the competition was to "improve students’ and the public’s awareness of the important role that oil, gas, and mining play in our everyday lives." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deadline was March 20. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Story continues below)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="utah" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051678/original.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Credit: &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=453552048036014&amp;set=a.341805365877350.76846.122708411120381&amp;type=1&amp;theater" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook/Utah Division of Oil, Gas and Mining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim Springer, the Division of Oil, Gas and Mining's Public Information Officer, told The Huffington Post that this was the second year the contest had been held. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Informational pamphlets for the contest were given out to all Utah schools, but it was then up to the discretion of the schools themselves as to whether or not they would participate, he said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked if he thought the poster contest was in any way problematic, Springer said teaching children about fossil fuels is important because they're an indispensable part of modern life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Fossil fuels are not going to go away anytime soon. Alternative forms of energy are great and continue to be explored, but they're not going to be able to meet our [global] demand in the future," he said. "Even around Earth Day, we need to think about the responsible development of oil, natural gas [and other fossil fuels]. Without them, we don't have the economy, we don't have jobs, we don't have modern society."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the poster contest has apparently remained under the radar since its inception, over the last few weeks, a wave of indignation has been swelling as parents, activists and concerned citizens alike have voiced their shock and outrage at the competition's premise. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, a parent of an elementary school student in Farmington, Utah, wrote a &lt;a href="http://www.sltrib.com/sltrib/opinion/55992432-82/gas-oil-mining-petroleum.html.csp" target="_hplink"&gt;letter to the editor of the Salt Lake Tribune&lt;/a&gt; expressing his exasperation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I’m furious," wrote Colby Poulson, whose son was provided materials for the contest by his teachers. "Why is the state backing an &lt;a href="http://www.sltrib.com/sltrib/opinion/55992432-82/gas-oil-mining-petroleum.html.csp" target="_hplink"&gt;"Earth Day" contest that celebrates fossil fuels&lt;/a&gt;, while completely ignoring the adverse effects that their use and extraction can too often have on our air quality, water quality, public lands and the other organisms we share the world with?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Poulson's letter was published, a movement against the poster competition began to rally. And now, pushing back against the original contest, the grassroots environmental advocacy group &lt;a href="http://blog.utahmomsforcleanair.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;Utah Moms for Clean Air&lt;/a&gt; has organized an &lt;a href="http://www.sltrib.com/sltrib/news/56037216-78/contest-utah-poster-clean.html.csp" target="_hplink"&gt;alternative competition&lt;/a&gt; of its own. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also open to students in grades K-6, the counter-contest's theme is "&lt;a href="http://blog.utahmomsforcleanair.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;Explore the Economic, Environmental and Health Costs of Fossil Fuels on Utah&lt;/a&gt;." The deadline for the contest is April 19. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I was horrified and dumbfounded when I heard about the [Division of Oil, Gas and Mining's] contest," Cherise Udell, the group's founder, told The Huffington Post over the phone on Thursday. "So I took my outrage and turned it into a Jon Stewart-style skewering."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Utah is a laughing stock of the nation, if not the world, for the absurdity of promoting a fossil fuel contest for Earth Day," she continued. "We need to show the world that not everyone in Utah is on board with this. We're getting back some of our dignity, dignity for our state."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a follow-up conversation with Udell on Friday, she said that Utah Gov. Gary Herbert, who &lt;a href="http://fs.ogm.utah.gov/pub/MINES/MINERALS/OGMAMREarthDayPosterContestWinnersPR0412.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;endorsed the Division of Oil, Gas and Mining's poster contest last year&lt;/a&gt;, had refused to endorse the Utah Moms' competition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's a blatant bias that's totally inappropriate," she said, adding that she feels let down by the state's leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poster contest has cast a spotlight on a pressing and continuing debate about energy resources in Utah -- a state that is heavily reliant on nonrenewable fossil fuels and that some environmental activists say is in the pocket of Big Coal and the fossil fuel industry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's certainly safe to say that Utah is the most fossil fuel-dependent state in the nation," Matt Pacenza, Policy Director of &lt;a href="http://healutah.org/who/aboutus" target="_hplink"&gt;HEAL Utah&lt;/a&gt;, an environmental organization that has for years pushed back against the state's nuclear energy program and that advocates for sustainable energy production and use, told HuffPost. "There is almost no renewable electricity made in Utah that's used in Utah."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coal, petroleum and natural gas account for 98 percent of Utah’s energy consumption, according to a 2011 &lt;a href="http://epubs.utah.edu/index.php/HJP/article/viewFile/499/365" target="_hplink"&gt;report about Utah's energy issues&lt;/a&gt; published in the Hinckley Journal of Politics. Coal itself, described as a "&lt;a href="http://epubs.utah.edu/index.php/HJP/article/viewFile/499/365" target="_hplink"&gt;backbone&lt;/a&gt;" of Utah's economy, supplies almost half of the energy consumed in the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utah's dependence on fossil fuels, such as oil and coal, has been a central factor in the state's worsening pollution problem. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the New York Times reported in February, &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/24/us/utah-a-nature-lovers-haven-is-plagued-by-dirty-air.html?_r=0" target="_hplink"&gt;air pollution in and around the state's capital&lt;/a&gt; has become so bad in the last few months that it has "prompted warnings from local doctors, spawned protests at the State Capitol and [has] led to a variety of legislative proposals in the hopes of confronting the problem before it gets worse." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://epubs.utah.edu/index.php/HJP/article/viewFile/499/365" target="_hplink"&gt;Fracking for natural gas&lt;/a&gt; (an industry that is fast becoming a "key sector Utah’s economy, valued at over 2.6 billion dollars in 2008") is also potentially a problem for the state, said author Caroline Gleich in her Hinckley Journal report.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"[T]he state is failing its residents, present and future," she wrote. "This failure is from a lack of preparation, planning, and oversight for future energy production and consumption, and overall ignorance of adverse environmental impacts from Utah’s current energy portfolio."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environmentalists say that one of the most distressing things about the current energy situation in Utah is that the state actually has a huge potential for producing renewable energy, such as wind and solar power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, in a &lt;a href="http://healutah.org/files/TheBluePrintFINAL_medRes.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;2010 study commissioned by HEAL Utah&lt;/a&gt;, it was found that "careful development of Utah’s abundant renewable energy resources can provide a technically sound, economically feasible, and reliable long-term strategy to meet Utah’s growing energy needs through the middle of this century." The state's wind, solar, and geothermal resources could fulfill &lt;a href="http://healutah.org/files/TheBluePrintFINAL_medRes.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;almost 100 percent of Utah's energy needs&lt;/a&gt;, the study concluded. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terry Marasco of the Utah Clean Air Alliance said that, ultimately, the state-sponsored poster contest has revealed a deep-rooted imbalance in Utah -- an imbalance that has pitted the people who are pro-renewables and those who are pro-fossils against one another, rather than promoting dialogue and cooperation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Utah has such a huge reserve of gas, shale, coal, tar sand, etc. and it's become a 'let's burn, let's get the income' kind of state. [The state's leadership] is careful not to tread on the toes of the fossil industries -- huge amounts of income come from that," Marasco, who's also a member of Utah Moms for Clean Air, told HuffPost. "The thing is, it's not that we want [fossil fuel production] to stop altogether, it's more a question of how to make it cleaner and to mitigate it so that health risks and costs are reduced dramatically."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the poster contest, which Marasco called "insidious," he said the problem was not just that the competition was aimed at children who are "very vulnerable" and whose "belief systems are just beginning," but that it didn't provide a balanced perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It implants in children the idea that this stuff is okay. It doesn't include the down side of these things -- like, my grandmother might die two years sooner, or I might get asthma. That's the balance that's missing in Utah," he said. "We need to show the balance and what the real cost [of fossil fuels] is and then kids can make their own decisions."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051890/thumbs/s-FOSSIL-FUEL-POSTER-CONTEST-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Hearing Delayed For Irish Nanny Accused Of Beating Child To Death</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/aisling-mccarthy-brady_n_2935682.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2935682</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T21:45:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T22:00:47Z</updated>
    
    <summary>MEDFORD, Mass. -- As an attorney protested a $500,000 bail set for an Irish nanny accused of beating a Massachusetts infant who later died, prosecutors...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/david-moye/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;MEDFORD, Mass. -- As an attorney protested a $500,000 bail set for an Irish nanny accused of beating a Massachusetts infant who later died, prosecutors said Friday they "fully and firmly" expect to bring more serious charges against her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Middlesex County prosecutors said a state medical examiner needs more time to complete an autopsy on Rehma Sabir of Cambridge, who was hospitalized with severe head injuries on Jan. 14 &amp;ndash; her first birthday &amp;ndash; and died two days later.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Aisling McCarthy Brady, 34, of Quincy was charged with assault and battery on a child causing substantial bodily injury. Prosecutors said at the time that Brady could be charged with murder once an autopsy on the baby is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Brady's lawyer, Melinda Thompson, asked a judge in Cambridge District Court to reduce her bail, saying prosecutors have kept her in jail for more than two months despite not filing a murder charge against her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"There is an innocent person sitting in jail," Thompson said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assistant District Attorney Patrick Fitzgerald said the case involves "substantial and complex medical issues" and the state medical examiner needs more time before making a final ruling on the cause of death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Based on all the evidence within our present knowledge and possession, we fully and firmly expect to upgrade charges," Fitzgerald wrote in court documents filed Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immigration officials have said Brady is in the United States illegally and placed a detainer on her after she was arrested. She arrived from Ireland in 2002 under a tourist program and was only authorized to stay 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judge Roanne Sragow denied Thompson's request to review Brady's bail, saying Thompson would have to bring her request to the judge who originally set the bail or take her request to Superior Court. Sragow agreed to a request from prosecutors to delay a probable cause hearing until April 22.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the hearing, Thompson said she believes prosecutors rushed to charge Brady.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"She's terrified. She's devastated. She's in jail for something she didn't do, and she's having a really hard time," Thompson said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baby's parents, Nada Siddiqui and Sameer Sabir, told police Aisling had been their nanny for about six months, caring for the baby while they worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the court filing, Fitzgerald said preliminary findings by the child protection team at Children's Hospital in Boston indicate the baby's "injuries and subsequent death were a result of non-accidental abusive head trauma."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fitzgerald said that since then, prosecutors have found evidence of "extensive internal head injuries" on Jan. 14, while she was in the sole care of Brady.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fitzgerald wrote that medical experts believe her injuries "are consistent with abusive head trauma caused by an intentional violent shaking or impact trauma." But he said additional microscopic examination of the girl's brain and eyes "are necessary to conduct a complete and thorough investigation into the cause and manner of Rehma's death."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fitzgerald said the final autopsy report is expected to be completed within four weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052354/thumbs/s-AISLING-MCCARTHY-BRADY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Mary L. Pulido, Ph.D.: Social Media Gone Awry: Tips for Teens to Stay Safe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mary-l-pulido-phd/social-media-gone-awry-ti_b_2923603.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2923603</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T21:25:15Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T21:25:20Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Here are a few tips to keep your teen safe when using the Internet and other web-based technologies. If you think it's an awkward conversation; you can hand them this blog to read.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Mary L. Pulido, Ph.D.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mary-l-pulido-phd/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Anyone who is a parent today did not grow up with the generation of technology that teens are using to capture and document a tremendous amount of their lives on social media.  The good, the bad and the ugly is being recorded and shared -- as we recently saw again in the horrific rape case in Steubenville, Ohio.  I recommend that parents have a conversation with their children about safety when using different forms of social media -- from Facebook to texting and anything in between. Today, the culture seems to promote that "anything goes" in regards to self-expression.  There needs to be a conversation about what is appropriate behavior and what actions could have huge repercussions that damage their reputation -- and are harmful to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April is National Child Abuse Prevention Month -- a time to recognize that we each can play a part in promoting the social and emotional well-being of children and families in communities. Let's start by protecting our own children from the dangers that lurk in the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few tips to keep your teen safe when using the Internet and other web-based technologies.  If you think it's an awkward conversation; you can hand them this blog to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Be smart about what you post on the Web.  It is a lot more public than it seems.  Protect your space.  Use privacy settings and don't just randomly accept everyone's request as a friend.  Do a bit of investigating to find out more about them first.  It's recommended that you don't use your real name or give out too much personal information on your Facebook page or other social media sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Clean up your profile.  Take anything embarrassing, too personal or any photos that show you doing something illegal (drinking, drugs) off of your page.  Those photos of you dancing with a beer bottle in your hand, are not going to look good when you are applying for college. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Provocative and sexy names and pictures can draw attention from people you don't want in your life, particularly online predators. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Posting or sending sexy photos of yourself (sexting) can get you into big trouble with the law.  If you are underage, they may be considered child pornography, a serious crime. Never take an image of yourself that you wouldn't want your parents, teachers, or your employers to see.  Think twice or three times before you post.  You can't take it back and it's out there forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	You have no control over where the photos are sent once you send them. The image that you meant for your boyfriend or girlfriend can be sent to their friends, and their friends and their friends.  If you forward a sexual photo of someone underage, you are as responsible as the original sender.  You could face child pornography charges, go to jail, and be legally required to register as a sex offender. You could also be asked to leave a sports team, be humiliated in public, or lose educational opportunities and have legal problems.  Here is a &lt;a href="http://www.nsteens.org/Videos/InformationTravels" target="_hplink"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; from the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (2 minutes), where teens discuss the dangers of online posting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Report any nude pictures that you receive on your cell phone to an adult that you trust.  Do not delete the message; get your parents or your guardian, your teacher or school counselor involved immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Be careful what you download or look at. Some images are extreme, and once you see it -- it's in your mind forever.  This is particularly true for violent and/or pornographic images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Adults who talk to you about sex online are committing a crime. So are adults who meet underage teens for sex.  Some teens may think it's fun but it is serious trouble and best to report it to the police. You can also make a report by clicking &lt;a href="http://www.cybertipline.com." target="_hplink"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Be careful if you go in person to meet someone in person that you met on the Internet. You may think you know them well, but you don't. Tell your parents or someone you trust before you go. Don't go alone, bring a friend. Always meet in a public place. Make sure you have your cell phone and an exit plan. Here is a another &lt;a href="http://www.nsteens.org/Videos/SurvivorDiaries" target="_hplink"&gt;video clip &lt;/a&gt;(2.40 minutes) where teens talk about bad experiences they had when meeting someone in person who they met online. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The New York Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children (NYSPCC), the world's first child protection agency, will hold their annual Spring Luncheon on Thursday, April 18, 2013 at The Pierre Hotel in New York City. The afternoon will feature a keynote address by child advocate, Elizabeth Smart. To learn more, please contact the Special Events office at 212 233 5500 ext 216 or email info@nyspcc.org.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1038910/thumbs/s-FACEBOOK-HASHTAG-mini.jpg?9" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: How A Miniature Horse Is Helping This Boy With Special Needs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/zaiden-beattie-miniature-horse_n_2935187.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2935187</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T21:19:02Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T13:54:06Z</updated>
    
    <summary>ANCHORAGE, Alaska -- A young miniature horse in sneakers is helping a 4-year-old special needs child at an Anchorage public elementary school. Zoe, a black...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-mustich/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;ANCHORAGE, Alaska -- A young miniature horse in sneakers is helping a 4-year-old special needs child at an Anchorage public elementary school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zoe, a black mare, is a service animal for preschooler Zaiden Beattie at Russian Jack Elementary School. It's the only service horse in an Alaska school - and after multiple online searches, the only service horse Principal Elizabeth Hornbuckle could find at any school in the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zaiden is one of 300 children in the U.S. diagnosed with A-T, or ataxia-telangiectasia, a genetic disorder that progressively robs children of their ability to coordinate movement such as walking. Zaiden's mother, Lesley Zacharias, a professional horse trainer, is teaching Zoe to help Zaiden walk steadily until the disease inevitably shackles him to a wheelchair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"He moves around a lot better and has more energy if he's got a hand on someone, either holding someone's hand or a hand on something," Zacharias said. "My personal goal is first grade with a pony instead of a walker."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The head of the 10-month-old horse only rises to an adult's waist and is almost irresistible to touch, though training protocols call for her to be petted on the neck, not the face, and only when given permission. Zoe is calm but playful, eager to play or work, and lets her owners know it by nuzzling their hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sturdy, 150-pound animal began making appearances in Zaiden's preschool classroom in January. Early training began with socialization - exposure to crowds and loud noises such as the school's fire alarm. Now she's learning tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"She's providing balance and mobility, and she's learning how to pick things up and eventually hand things to him," Zacharias said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zacharias describes Zaiden's balance as "good to wobbly."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"He trips a fair amount. He falls down a fair amount," she said. "Some days, by the time he gets off the school bus, his legs look like they're going to give out."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people with the disease are in a wheelchair by the age of 16. A-T also causes immune system problems and a high rate of cancer, and patients generally die in their 20s, according to the National Cancer Institute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's progressive. Fatal. Basically he's going to lose his brain cells in his cerebellum, so he'll just continually lose motor skill ability," Zacharias said. "But intellectually, he's going to be there the whole time."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. Department of Justice regulations that took effect in March 2011 recognized miniature horses as service animals under the Americans with Disabilities Act, and Zacharias became determined to find one to extend her son's mobility. Her partner, Joel Beattie, was skeptical, she said, but one by one, obstacles fell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She couldn't find a baby horse but did locate a pregnant mare in Minnesota that had been used as a therapy horse for children with disabilities. Nine-year-old Gwendolyn was trucked to Washington then transported by ferry and van to Anchorage by Zacharias' sister. Zoe was born in the family's garage in May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their long-time landlord surprised them and said, yes, Zaiden could have a service horse inside their rented house. A friend, Deb Turner, became a surrogate mother to the little horses, talking neighbors into letting Gwendolyn and Zoe graze on their lawns. A professional seamstress who repairs backpacks for an REI store made a custom harness for Zoe with handholds that Zaiden can grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even before Zoe was born, educators at the elementary school helped solve problems such as how to keep the horse from sliding on the hard school floors. Hornbuckle, the principal, found the answer with an online search. She learned another miniature horse owner bought shoes at a Build-A-Bear Workshop store. Zoe now has eight sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people want to know if Zoe is housebroken. The horse has defecated just twice inside the school, including once "on cue" at a staff meeting after Hornbuckle said accidents were likely to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zaiden's teacher, Cynthia Temple, said people in the school district have offered her sympathy for having to tolerate a horse in her classroom. She said it was an easy call because it makes Zaiden's life better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"My goal as a teacher for all the kids is independence, regardless of their needs," Temple said. "For Zaiden, an independent thing was putting on his coat, which was big feat, and using the zipper. Now Zoe is part of how Zaiden is going to function, walking and getting up from his chair, those little things that I can already see."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The law gives Zaiden the right to walk with his horse into restaurants and stores, but Zacharias has been cautious about public appearances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I want it to be appreciated, not just allowed," she said. "I feel a heavy responsibility in being an advocate not just for my son's condition but also for miniature horses and for service animals."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She's keeping a record of her family's experience, perhaps as a guide for others in her family's situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It would be neat to look back and have some legacy to leave when Zaiden is gone," she said. "To have something and say, yes, this happened and it was really difficult, but look at what we were able to create out of it, and none of that would have happened if it weren't for this situation."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052149/thumbs/s-ZAIDEN-BEATTIE-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: How Much Should We Worry About Our Kids' Screen Time?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/touch-screen-generation_n_2932434.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2932434</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T21:12:56Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T21:34:09Z</updated>
    
    <summary>How will your kids' use of technology affect their development? Does the time your toddler spends playing with your iPad or smartphone do more harm...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Nina Zipkin</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nina-zipkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;How will your kids' use of technology affect their development?  Does the time your toddler spends playing with your iPad or smartphone do more harm than good? How much should parents worry about their kids' screen time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanna Rosin, senior editor at The Atlantic, appeared on HuffPost Live to discuss some of the questions she explores in her recent article “&lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2013/04/the-touch-screen-generation/309250/ " target="_hplink"&gt;The Touch Screen Generation.&lt;/a&gt;”  She wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;... as technology becomes ubiquitous in our lives, American parents are becoming more, not less, wary of what it might be doing to their children. Technological competence and sophistication have not, for parents, translated into comfort and ease. They have merely created yet another sphere that parents feel they have to navigate in exactly the right way.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining Rosin on HuffPost Live were three other parents, HuffPost Parents Managing Editor Farah Miller, &lt;a href="http://www.duckduckmoose.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;app&lt;/a&gt; developer Caroline Hu Flexer and child psychiatrist Dr. Michael Anderson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the comments, HuffPost Live Producer Nkechi Nneji asked, “How much of this is parents feeling guilt?” She wondered if moms and dads were worried that technology was only a temporary fix -- “a band-aid” that would only come back to haunt them later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosin, whose adorable 4-year-old son Gideon sat on her lap as she spoke, said guilt is only part of the dilemma for parents. “They feel like, oh my gosh, my kids have to be really good at technology, but …if I give them the wrong technology, or too much technology, I’m going to ruin them. It’s in the anxious box as opposed to the smart decisions box." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miller noted that the blank “screen look” that appears on kids' faces when they are deeply engaged in screens troubles her. “When I see my daughter watching 'Doc McStuffins,' which is the one of the moment…I can’t even get her attention. Whereas with other games it’s kind of like they’re still there.  I think that’s where it’s not just guilt. I think there is something, you can sense when your kid isn’t quite where you want them to be.”&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051564/thumbs/s-TOUCH-SCREEN-GENERATION-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Glennon Melton: Sister Warriors Create A Miracle</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/glennon-melton/sister-warriors-create-miracle-_b_2933740.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2933740</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T21:00:34Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T21:33:55Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I left before the woman behind me in line knew I had paid for her things.  A few minutes later I saw her climb into the driver's seat of her car, put her head in her hands, and weep.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Glennon Melton</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/glennon-melton/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Please read this message and then re-read it and re-re-read it. Allow what happened at this Maryland grocery store yesterday to sink down deep into your bones and remind you that always and forever  - the Truth Is Love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--PHOTO--SISTER-WARRIORS--1052227--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**********************&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear G:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is Nicholas' birthday. I went grocery shopping deliberately in a low income part of town, and bought the person's groceries behind me as a birthday present to me and my big boy (inspired by Monkee See - Monkee Do).  I left before the woman behind me in line knew I had paid for her things.  A few minutes later I saw her climb into the driver's seat of her car, put her head in her hands, and weep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so nervous trying to explain to the cashier what I wanted to do that I left my phone in the store. When I went back to get it, that same cashier told me that the woman behind me had been buying all of that food for a domestic violence shelter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Sisters Warriors. Amazing and Full of Grace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love, Meghan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;************************&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've read this story twenty times now. I've got the movie in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can SEE that woman finding out her groceries were paid in full. I can see her eyes and heart try to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder...why was she working at a domestic violence shelter? Had her life been touched by violence? Was she healing herself by healing others?  Was she trying to prove to herself that despite every shred of evidence to the contrary - Love Wins? And was she paying for all of those groceries herself? Could she afford them, or did she take a leap of faith? Did Meghan catch her before she hit the ground?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yesterday, is it possible that God lead Meghan to THAT grocery store in THAT moment because God wanted this warrior to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am watching. I love you. Trust me and trust your sisters. SERVE your sisters. Expect miracles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever God's message was- it seems to have been received. Weeping in her car. Healing, I think. Experiencing a real life miracle - as a direct result of serving her sisters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALL OF US - Warriors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meghan - for not just feeling but DOING compassion. For being brave and different and bold with her love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sister behind her.  Creating and receiving a miracle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The warriors in the shelter, working towards the life they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cashier who witnessed the whole miracle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Sister Warriors. Amazing and Full of Grace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of them. All of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Friday, Love Warriors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://momastery.com/blog/" target="_hplink"&gt;Find more at www.momastery.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052227/thumbs/s-SISTER-WARRIORS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
