<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Orange Rhino: 10 Things I Learned When I Stopped Yelling At My Kids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/the-orange-rhino/10-things-i-learned-when-i-stopped-yelling_b_2886161.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2886161</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T20:57:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T20:58:06Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I always have an audience -- my four boys are always watching me and THEY are the audience that matters most; they are the ones I want to show just how loving, patient and "yell-free" I can be.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Orange Rhino</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/the-orange-rhino/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;January 20, 2012. I will never forget that date. Thinking I was home alone with my four boys, then ages 5 and under, my handyman caught me in a full on, red in the face, body shaking, throat throbbing scream so bad that all my boys burst into tears. I was mortified. Mortified! And so sad; this was not the mom I had ever dreamed I would be! The next day I decided enough was enough and I promised my boys I would go 365 days straight without yelling. Soon thereafter I discovered that rhinos are calm animals that charge when provoked; I was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; a rhino (I even have lots of stretch marks and saggy body parts to prove it.) I just charged with my words instead of a horn. I quickly started calling myself The Orange Rhino as a reminder to no longer yell, but instead to be calm like a rhino and warm like the color orange. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I proudly share that I am officially an Orange Rhino! I haven't charged with my words in over 400 days thanks to many things I learned this past year. Here are the top 10 things that I learned but trust me, there are many many more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Yelling isn't the only thing I haven't done in over a year.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also haven't gone to bed with a gut-wrenching pit in my stomach because I felt like the worst mom ever. I haven't bawled to my husband that I yelled again and again. And I haven't heard my sons scream, "You're the meanest, worstest, mommy in the whole world, I don't love you anymore!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. My kids are my most important audience.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I had my "no more yelling epiphany," I realized that I don't yell in the presence of others because I want them to believe I am a loving and patient mom. The truth is, I already was that way... but rarely when I was alone, just always when I was in public with an audience to judge me. This is so backwards! I always have an audience -- my four boys are always watching me and THEY are the audience that matters most; they are the ones I want to show just how loving, patient and "yell-free" I can be. I want my boys to judge me and proclaim, "My mommy is the bestest mommy ever!" I remember this whenever I am home and thinking I can't keep it together; obviously I can... I do it out and about all the time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Kids are kids -- and not just kids, but people too.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like me, my kids have good days and bad days. Some days they are pleasant and sweet and listen really well; other days they are grumpy and difficult. By the way, I am always sweet and never difficult. Always. Ha! And like all kids, my boys are loud at times, they refuse to put their shoes on, and they color on the wall, especially if it is covered in brand new wallpaper that mommy loves. So, yeah, I need to watch my expectations and remember that my boys are kids: they are still learning, still growing, and still figuring out how to handle waking up on the wrong side of the bed. When they "make mistakes" I need to remember that not only does yelling not help, but like me, they don't like to be yelled at!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. I can't always control my kids' actions, but I can always control my reaction. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can try my hardest to follow all the parenting tricks of the trade for well-disciplined children, but since my kids are just kids, they sometimes won't do what I want. I can decide if I want to scream "Pick up your Legos!" when they don't listen or if I want to walk away for a second, regain composure by doing some jumping jacks, and then return with a new approach. P.S. Walking away and taking a breather can actually get the Legos picked up faster than yelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Yelling doesn't work.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were numerous times when I wanted to quit my Orange Rhino Challenge, when I thought yelling would just be easier than finding deep breaths and creative alternatives to yelling. But I knew better. Early on, I learned that yelling simply doesn't work, that it just makes things spiral out of control and it makes it hard for my boys to hear what I want them to learn. How can they clearly hear me "say" "Hurry up, get your backpacks, your shoes, your jackets, don't touch each other, go faster, you can do it yourself!" when it's all a garbled, loud mix of intimidating orders that are making them cry?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. By yelling you might miss out on life-changing moments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One night I heard footsteps coming downstairs well after bedtime. Although infuriated that my "me-time" was interrupted, I remained calm and returned said child to bed. As I tucked him in he said "Mommy, will you love me if I go to heaven first, because if you go first, I will still love you. In fact, I will always love you." Tears still come to my eyes just writing that. I can guarantee if I had yelled "GET BACK IN BED!" we never would have had that sweet, very important conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Two words you should always remember are "at least."&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not going to say not yelling is "easy peasy," but getting creative with alternatives certainly made it easier and more doable. And after yelling into the toilet, beating my chest like a gorilla, singing Lalala, Lalala it's Elmo's world, and using orange napkins at mealtime as a reminder of my promise, it certainly got a heck of a lot easier. Sure, I feel silly at times doing these things, but they keep me from losing it. So do my new favorite words: "at least."  These two small words give me great perspective and remind me to chill out. I use them readily in any annoying but not yell worthy kid situation. "He just dropped an entire jug of milk on the floor... at least it wasn't glass and at least he was trying to help!" I also use them readily when I want to give up:"'Okay, this is hard but &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; there are only three hours until bedtime, not 12."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Often times, I am the problem, not my kids.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The break-up line, "It's not you, it's me" rings uncomfortably true when learning not to yell.  I quickly realized that oftentimes I wanted to yell because I had a fight with my husband, I was overwhelmed by my to-do list, I was tired or it was that time of the month, not because the kids were behaving "badly." I also quickly realized that acknowledging my personal triggers by saying out loud: "Orange Rhino, you have wicked PMS and need chocolate, you aren't mad at the kids, don't yell" works really well to keep yells at bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Taking care of me helps me to not yell.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was always great at taking care of others; I was not, however, always good at taking care of myself until now. Once I realized that personal triggers like feeling overweight, feeling disconnected from friends, and feeling exhausted set me up to yell, I started taking care of me. I started going to bed earlier, prioritizing exercise, trying to call one friend a day and most importantly, I started telling myself it's OK to not be perfect. Taking care of me not only helps me not yell, but it also makes me happier, more relaxed, and more loving. Ah, the benefits of not yelling extend far beyond parenting! There is no doubt that I am in a better parenting AND personal place now that I don't yell. Just to name a few unexpected benefits of not yelling: I do more random acts of kindness, I handle stressful situations more gracefully, and I communicate more lovingly with my husband.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Not yelling feels phenomenal for everyone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have stopped yelling, not only do I feel happier and calmer, I also feel lighter. I go to bed guilt-free (except for the extra cookie I ate that day, oops) and wake up more confident that I can parent with greater understanding of my kids, my needs, and how to be more loving and patient. And I am pretty sure my kids feel happier and calmer too. I know everyone wants to read, "I stopped yelling and not only do I feel great, but also my kids are now calmer AND perfectly behaved." Well, they aren't. They are still kids. But, yes tantrums are shorter and some are completely avoided. Now that I am calmer, I can think more rationally to resolve potential problems before meltdown mania.  But forget perfectly behaved kids for a second. My kids are most definitely more loving towards me, and now tell me quite often "I love you Orange Rhino mommy!" and that feels more than awesome, it feels phenomenal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To get started on your own journey to yell less and love more one moment at a time, read:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://theorangerhino.com/12-steps-to-stop-yelling-at-your-kid/" target="_hplink"&gt;12 Steps to Stop Yelling At Your Kids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://theorangerhino.com/alternatives-to-yelling/" target="_hplink"&gt;Orange Rhino Alternatives to Yelling &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053029/thumbs/s-ORANGE-RHINO-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Funniest Tweets From Parents This Week </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/best-parenting-tweets_n_2927266.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2927266</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T20:45:52Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T20:46:37Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Here on HuffPost Parents, we talk often about the challenges associated with raising kids in a high-tech world. (We have a whole page dedicated to...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Samakow</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-samakow/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Here on HuffPost Parents, we talk often about the challenges associated with raising kids in a high-tech world. (&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/parents-families-tech" target="_hplink"&gt;We have a whole page dedicated to the subject.&lt;/a&gt;) And while the intersection of family and tech certainly warrants serious discussion, sometimes we also have to laugh at what it means to grow up in a world where there's an app for everything. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/marriedwtoddler/status/314774765099446273" target="_hplink"&gt;Rhiana Maidenberg did a good job pointing out the funny&lt;/a&gt; this week on Twitter. "While reading the 3 yo a book this morning, 'Mommy, press pause. I need to go pee pee. #DigitalToddlers," she wrote. Another mom had a similar experience when &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lifecoachfit/status/314753522358951936" target="_hplink"&gt;her 4-year-old told her she loved people with iPads&lt;/a&gt;. Exclusively? We're not sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many more of our favorite tweeters looked at the light side of parenting this week. Click through the gallery below to see our favorites and be sure to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostParents" target="_hplink"&gt;follow @HuffPostParents&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053024/thumbs/s-TWEETS-OF-THE-WEEK-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Barbara Greenberg: Why You May Not Want to Let Your Middle Schoolers Date</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/barbara-greenberg/why-you-may-not-want-to-l_b_2931111.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2931111</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T20:12:09Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T20:12:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A recent study from the University of Georgia conducted by Pamela Orpinas and colleagues and published in the Journal of Research on Adolescence suggests that the answer may be no.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Barbara Greenberg</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/barbara-greenberg/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;A recent &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jora.12029/abstract" target="_hplink"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Georgia conducted by Pamela Orpinas and colleagues and published in the Journal of Research on Adolescence suggests that the answer may be no. Perhaps middle school and dating should be mutually exclusive. In their very carefully conducted study Orpinas and colleagues followed the same group of 624 kids as they traveled from 6th grade to their senior year of high school. I love these studies that follow the same group of kids over time. It really gives us an opportunity to see how earlier behaviors in life are associated with later behaviors. In my mind, this is the best sort of research that there is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The findings were at the very least quite alarming and you may want to read on to find out why. The students who began dating early, in middle school that is, were significantly more likely to eventually drop out of school, have worse study skills and to use marijuana and alcohol in high school than their later dating peers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to tell you that the results of this study do not surprise me. There are several possible explanations of why early dating may lead to other subsequent problematic behaviors. It may be that the early daters are greater risk takers in general. On the other hand, dating is hard and complicated for individuals of any age so these young middle schoolers may be particularly ill-equipped to deal with dating, break-ups and all of the emotional complications associated with intimate relationships. Another possibility is that these early daters get distracted at an early age, develop a habit of always being in a relationship and lose focus on how to handle all aspects of life in a healthy manner. The most likely explanation for why early dating is associated with later difficulties is likely to be a confluence of the factors I mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents need to be aware of the relationship between early dating and subsequent problems and help their kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My suggestions include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Watching your kids and making sure that their emotional lives aren't centered exclusively around dating relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. Creating opportunities for your middle schoolers to get their affiliative needs met from a variety of sources including friends, family etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. Teach them how to deal with stress effectively so they learn to deal with all of life's stressors including relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. Know that developing good study habits is crucial and help them with this aspect of school,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AND&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. Try to help them develop a balanced life.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053005/thumbs/s-MIDDLE-SCHOOLERS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Judith Greenberg, Ph.D.: The 'Do You Know?' Test</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/judith-greenberg-phd/oh-i-know-i-know_b_2919835.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2919835</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T17:46:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T17:47:01Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Do you know where your parents met? The story of your birth? Can you recite a tale of suffering from you ancestral archives? It turns out that possessing those answers may help you develop resilience.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Judith Greenberg, Ph.D.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/judith-greenberg-phd/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Do you know where your parents met? The story of your birth? Can you recite a tale of suffering from you ancestral archives? It turns out that possessing those answers may help you develop resilience. A recent &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; article &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/17/fashion/the-family-stories-that-bind-us-this-life.html?smid=fb-share&amp;_r=0" target="_hplink"&gt;proposes&lt;/a&gt; that knowing family stories helps people, especially children, face life's challenges. Doctors Duke and Fivush asked children 20 questions and found that sharing family narratives yields greater health and happiness. By this standard, I should be a paragon of health and happiness.  I write about family narratives on a daily basis as I work on a memoir about the trans-generational transmission of trauma. As I tell the story of two cousins during the Holocaust, I focus on how we hear and pass along stories of family suffering. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it's a relief to hear that despite the burdens such learning may carry, passing along family narratives yields benefits. WNYC's host Brian Leher &lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/bl/2013/mar/19/open-phones-knowing-your-family-story/" target="_hplink"&gt;asked callers&lt;/a&gt; to respond to the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;' story.  Callers disclosed conflicts about sharing aspects of narratives.  Some were not sure how to tell past encounters with tragedy and violence. One mother described the difficulty of telling her child how he was born in New York on 9/11.  Another wasn't sure how much of her own exposure to violence in Bosnia to share with her children. I was reminded of the struggle experienced by some trauma survivors. Some parents kept their painful pasts secret in order to try to protect their children.  In her wonderful book, &lt;em&gt;After Long Silence,&lt;/em&gt; Helen Fremont tells about being raised a Roman Catholic only to discover as an adult that her parents were actually Jews whose families had been killed in the Holocaust.  Her parents had suffered so much tragedy that they came to believe in the false narrative they had told to survive, a history that erased their Jewish roots. As Fremont shows, family secrets can create their own forms of pain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other callers discussed conflicts around narrating birth stories. A Catholic mother confided that she grapples with how to disclose the fact that her first child was conceived out of wedlock.  Brian Leher started his program with a clip by parents who adopted a child after finding him in the subway. They turned their family history into a children's book and read it repeatedly to their son, who eventually took pride in recognizing that the story was his own. That child shared his adoption book in kindergarten and it, in turn, helped other adopted children in his class.  Whether our parents or caregivers share our genes or not, we join together through our shared narratives. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Sophocles and the Greeks (and Freud) knew, stories of origin fascinate, bewilder and haunt us.  What if Jocasta and Laius simply told Oedipus the prophecy about his birth? If they understood the value of sharing family narratives could Oedipus have avoided his tragic fate? Fortunately, the puzzle of origins that most of us must solve is not nearly as shocking as the revelations in&lt;em&gt; Oedipus Rex.&lt;/em&gt;  That said, secrets persist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My family is full of writers and talkers.  Nevertheless, dramatic family secrets were unlocked during my childhood.   I can't post all of the details here, but they revolved around topics discussed on Leher's radio show.  In two cases, the parents thought that hiding the truth of origins and birth from their children would protect them. I consider both to have backfired.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the case I unlocked, I remain mute.  But as for the other, cousins were adopted but never told.  The extended family outside of than the children themselves knew about the adoption.  Only as adults did these cousins piece together the story.  One of these cousins had brown eyes while both of his parents had blue eyes - a genetic impossibility. Do I need to explain the sense of betrayal when he discovered his "birth story"? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lest you get the wrong impression, my family does tell plenty of shared stories.  When I read about the "Do You Know" test, my first response was, "Yes! I know, already!  I know!" I tease my mother when she tells stories from her past.  When she begins to recite one from her repertoire, I call out, "Here comes #702!" Even at age 46, I can be an annoying daughter.  I could write a novel about my father's dramatic childhood, full of the names of his terrible teachers who hated his Commie-leanings, or the boy with whom he surprised my aunt while wearing an Air Raid Warden's helmet and goggles, or the time he caught a bank robber (for real!).  I know so many details of my mother's history that sometimes I have a hard time separating my own story from hers.   (Mother-daughter issues -- lines between us can become blurry in my mind.)  My memoir answers the question, "Where did your parents meet?" I describe how my father and his grad school pals pre-arranged a sighting of my mother. Hannah Arendt was speaking at Mandell Hall at the University of Chicago on her controversial "Eichmann in Jerusalem" and the culpability of the &lt;em&gt;Judenrat&lt;/em&gt; in the Holocaust.  My father arranged for one friend to accompany my mother to the lecture while he and another friend went to the lecture so he could check her out.  My dad liked what he saw.  The story makes me feel happy and strangely connected to Hannah Arendt.  If the Holocaust slips into virtually every blog post I write, then perhaps it's due to this part of my family narrative. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I lose all of my readers with too many family stories, I close with a reflection on the value of sharing these narratives with an extended family.  Every summer my husband, kids, and I travel to Cape Cod with my parents, brothers, and their families.  Inevitably, with siblings, cousins, in-laws, spouses, parents, and children, some strife ensues.  There's always a point at which I am about to declare: "not next year!"  And then I realize that despite family conflicts, we join together for the deepest belly laughs I have all year, such as when we tease my mother for reading &lt;em&gt;Never Again: Echoes of the Holocaust As Understood Through Film&lt;/em&gt; while relaxing at the beach. From competitive kids lunging at one another with mini golf clubs to sharing perfect wave rides on boogie boards, we create new chapters of our family narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1031660/thumbs/s-CHILDREN-EXERCISE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Dr. Peggy Drexler: Girl Power -- But at What Cost?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/peggy-drexler/girl-powerbut-at-what-cos_b_2939881.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2939881</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T15:41:30Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T15:41:33Z</updated>
    
    <summary>While girl power, the movement that began in the early 90s, has aimed to empower many young girls to be ambitious, assertive, and self-reliant, that girl power as interpreted on TV and in film is slowly but surely seeping into our streets as something more sinister.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Dr. Peggy Drexler</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/peggy-drexler/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;In the final, hyper-violent scene of the movie &lt;em&gt;Kick-Ass, Hit-Girl&lt;/em&gt;, a 10-year-old vigilante in a purple wig played by Chloe Grace Moretz takes down more than a dozen armed men using two shot guns and a variety of exotic fighting techniques. As Joan Jett's "Bad Reputation" plays in the background, Hit-Girl shoots many of the men in the head, at close range.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kick-Ass, of course, centered on Hit-Girl, and this scene is just the culmination of a few hours' worth of others just like it. But these scenes, or these characters, are not particularly rare -- or even, these days, extreme. Pick any action movie, and chances are good there will be at least one scene in which a woman beats up a man (and, of course, looks good doing it). In most cases, there will be a lot of back flips involved. Sometimes, there will be multiple men. The good news here is that women are being cast as tough characters and superheroes as often as men. But the bad news may be the dangerous message all this woman-imparted violence is sending to young girls. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the National Center for Mental Health Promotion and Youth Violence Prevention, schools and communities have experienced a rise in aggression, delinquency, and bullying among girls and young women in recent years. From 1991 to 2000, arrests of girls increased more (or decreased less) than arrests of boys for most types of violent offenses, while a national student survey revealed that "33 percent of female students reported being bullied at school compared to 30 percent of male students." In 2009, the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration found that one in four adolescent girls has been the perpetrator of, or has participated in, a violent act in the past year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could pop culture have anything to do with it? Surely. While girl power, the movement that began in the early 90s, has aimed to empower many young girls to be ambitious, assertive, and self-reliant, that girl power as interpreted on TV and in film is slowly but surely seeping into our streets as something more sinister. Films like &lt;em&gt;Sucker Punch&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Haywire&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;The Dark Knight Rises&lt;/em&gt;, with Anne Hathaway's vengeful Catwoman (in form-fitting suit, naturally), feature hyper-violent women toeing the line between feminism and fetishism. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; recently reported that &lt;em&gt;Kick-Ass 2 Prelude: Hit-Girl,&lt;/em&gt; debuted on the graphic books hardcover best-seller list at number four, while violent vixens represent some of the most popular video game characters, including Lara Croft and &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt;'s Sonya Blade. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, last week's &lt;em&gt;New York Post &lt;/em&gt;featured the story of a Bronx elementary school teacher who starred in a bloody B-movie, &lt;em&gt;Gang Girl&lt;/em&gt;, as a thug who deals drugs, rapes, and murders. According to the &lt;em&gt;Post&lt;/em&gt;, violent incidents have spiked at her school. Female rage is in, and the Mean Girl has officially been replaced by the murderous one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which makes the case that girl power violence is really no better than the old, and long-derided, Tom vs. Jerry sort of TV violence fed to kids -- especially when so many of those characters, at their core, serve to fulfill some male fantasy of the sexy little killer. But the answer isn't to direct girls exclusively to movies that feature women as princesses and sweethearts. Until we have more films that portray women as bold and unafraid -- and nobody's object -- it's parents' job to have frank conversations with girls about the difference between fantasy and reality, and what to draw from the feminine heroes they're seeing more and more of. According to &lt;em&gt;Children Now,&lt;/em&gt; research shows that children, especially those between the ages of eight and 12, want their parents to talk with them about violence, and that those who have early conversations about tough subjects are more likely to continue turning to their parents as they become teens. Some ways to start: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitor their intake.&lt;/strong&gt; You're not going to be able to shield your child from all violence in pop culture. But you can limit it, and help minimize the risk that she becomes desensitized to it. Minimize the fictional depictions, and use real life violence as a conversation starter. Watching the outcomes of real world violence on TV, or reading about it together in the news, can be a good opportunity to talk with children about the consequences of such acts of violence. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host movie post-mortems.&lt;/strong&gt; Kids feel better when they talk about their feelings. After a movie or TV show that may have seemed violent -- upsetting or not -- ask your daughter her thoughts. Let her know the show seemed scary to you, too -- that she isn't alone -- and then reassure her that what she saw on TV was just make-believe. Play video games together and then talk about them after. If anything you've seen together on screen disturbs you, tell her why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demystify the cool factor. &lt;/strong&gt;Badass women in film may seem cool, and in some ways they are. But instead of celebrating these women for the ass they can kick, encourage girls to look up to them for their strength of character -- and in the meantime find them other models of female strength in movies that don't rely on violence. Talk about the importance of being strong and standing up for one's self, but that in real life that doesn't mean acting aggressive (or violent). It also doesn't require wearing skintight clothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reassure them of their safety. &lt;/strong&gt;An overexposure to violence can cause kids to become anxious and fearful. She'll wonder if she's safe -- and she'll wonder if she needs to act like the girls she sees on TV in order to stay safe. Be supportive and reassuring, and let girls know that safety does not follow acts of violence. Talk to them about how in real life, guns and knives hurt and kill people. Get them to say it back to you -- again, and again.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052842/thumbs/s-GIRL-POWER-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Was Transgender Teacher Being Harassed Prior To Her Death?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/lucy-meadows-transgender-death-media-_n_2939728.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2939728</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T14:51:28Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T14:51:55Z</updated>
    
    <summary>New speculation is surrounding the death of a British primary school teacher who came out to her students as a transgender woman last year. Jane...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Curtis M. Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/curtis-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;New speculation is surrounding the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/lucy-meadows-transgender-teacher-dead_n_2932670.html" target="_hplink"&gt;death of a British primary school teacher&lt;/a&gt; who came out to her students as a transgender woman last year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jane Fae, a writer specializing in transgender issues, claims to have been given access to emails sent by Lucy Meadows, who was found dead at her Accrington, Lancashire home on March 19, &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/22/lucy-meadows-press-harassment" target="_hplink"&gt;The Guardian is reporting&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a March 22 &lt;a href="http://www.newstatesman.com/2013/03/press-regulation-freedom-speech-and-death-lucy-meadows" target="_hplink"&gt;column for the New Statesman&lt;/a&gt;, Fae described the content of Meadows' emails as follows: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;"She talks of her good luck in having a supportive head. But the stress of her situation is also visible. She complains bitterly of how she must leave her house by the back door, and arrive at school very early, or very late, in order to avoid the press pack.

&lt;p&gt;She talks of the press offering other parents money for a picture of her; of how in the end they simply lifted an old picture from the Facebook pages of her brother and sister without permission."&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily Mail writer Richard Littlejohn, who Fae says has been described in various press reports as "a bully" and "a murderer," has also come under significant fire since the news of Meadows' death broke. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A petition calling for Littlejohn to be fired from the Daily Mail has since been launched, pointing to an earlier article he penned on the Meadows' case which featured the headline, "He's not only in the wrong body... he's in the wrong job." That article has since been removed from the Mail's website, &lt;a href="http://action.sumofus.org/a/daily-mail-littlejohn-lucy-meadows/?sub=pr" target="_hplink"&gt;according to the petition&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Throughout the article, Littlejohn repeatedly referred to Lucy as 'he,' and claimed that getting gender reassignment surgery showed that she didn't care for the children she taught," petition organizers write. "The Daily Mail may thrive on controversy to sell its tabloid papers, but even it knows it went too far this time." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some believe Meadows now killed herself, though The Guardian stresses that the precise circumstances of her death have still not been made clear. On March 21, the publication reported that &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/22/transgender-teacher-found-dead-accrington" target="_hplink"&gt;police were not treating the death&lt;/a&gt; as suspicious. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meadows, 32, had been teaching at Accrington's St. Mary Magdalen's School before announcing &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/20/nathan-upton-lucy-meadows-transgender-church-of-england-primary-school_n_2332095.html" target="_hplink"&gt;she was transgender in a letter &lt;/a&gt;sent to her students' parents shortly before the holiday break. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Mr. Upton has recently made a significant change in his life and will be transitioning to live as a woman," the letter read in part. "After the Christmas break, she will return to work as Miss Meadows." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A statement &lt;a href="http://www.theboltonnews.co.uk/news/northwest/10116784._Sir__will_become__Miss__at_Accrington_school/" target="_hplink"&gt;cited by The Bolton News&lt;/a&gt; quoted Meadows as saying at the time, "This has been a long and difficult journey for me, and it was certainly not an easy decision to make." After thanking colleagues for their support, she added, "I'd now ask for my privacy to be respected so that I can continue with my job, which I'm committed to and which I enjoy very much."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052794/thumbs/s-TRANSGENDER-TEACHER-DEATH-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>7 'Happy' Things That Can Totally Stress Us Out (And How To Deal)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/10-happy-life-events-that_n_2761433.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2761433</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T14:24:13Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T14:24:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It's an unfortunate paradox that many of life's most momentous occasions are both the best of times and the worst of times. The events that...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/carolyn-gregoire/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;It's an unfortunate paradox that many of life's most momentous occasions are both the best of times and the worst of times. The events that should be some of the most joyful -– getting married, having kids, taking time off work to travel abroad –- can also be the most stress-inducing. Whether it’s the pressure of planning a major event or the anxiety of trying to live up to our own expectations of how happy we &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be, once-joyful milestones can easily devolve into anxiety-filled occasions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it may seem counter-intuitive for happiness to cause panic, anything that disrupts our daily routine and normal modes of interaction can cause a stress reaction. The body's stress response can be set off by any event that triggers a &lt;a href="http://www.webmd.com/balance/stress-management/stress-management-causes-of-stress" target="_hplink"&gt;significant emotional response&lt;/a&gt;, throwing off our physical and mental equilibrium -- thereby making a wedding practically as stressful as a divorce and a tropical vacation more anxiety-filled than a hectic week in the office. Click through the slideshow below for 10 pivotal life events that commonly cause stress -- and ways to ways to bring the joy back into your most memorable milestones.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052589/thumbs/s-HAPPY-LIFE-EVENTS-STRESS-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Marshall P. Duke: The Stories That Bind Us: What Are the Twenty Questions?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marshall-p-duke/the-stories-that-bind-us-_b_2918975.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2918975</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T14:09:36Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T14:09:38Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The major criterion for inclusion in this set of questions was that they test knowledge of things that children could not possibly have learned first hand.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Marshall P. Duke</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marshall-p-duke/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Since the publication on Sunday, March 17 of Bruce Feiler's &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;  column entitled "&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/17/fashion/the-family-stories-that-bind-us-this-life.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=0" target="_hplink"&gt;This Life: The Stories that Bind us&lt;/a&gt;," Robyn Fivush and I have received a large number of requests for what he referred to as the "Do You Know Scale" (DYK).  The DYK comprises 20 questions seeking knowledge about family history.  The major criterion for inclusion in this set of questions was that they test knowledge of things that children could not possibly have learned first hand, either because they happened before the children were born or they involved family members that were less familiar to them than parents and grandparents.  Given this limitation, the children who knew the information would therefore have had to receive it from others through stories, writings or other indirect sources.  As was mentioned by Bruce Feiler, in our research, higher scores on the DYK scale were associated with higher levels of self-esteem, an internal locus of control ( a belief in one's own capacity to control what happens to him or her), better family functioning, lower levels of anxiety, fewer behavioral problems, and better chances for good outcomes if a child faces educational or emotional/behavioral difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write this blog post because many people have written and asked us to send them the list of twenty DYK questions so they can be sure their children know what our test children knew.  However, correlation is not causation. Simply knowing the answers to questions will not produce the good outcomes described above. The good outcomes as well as the knowledge of family history that the children possessed were all the result of something else.  We have written about this "something else" in several publications and I quote from one of those publications here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; "If simply knowing family history could make for better states of well-being, some might propose (confusing correlation with causation) that we simply teach children various facts about their families and they will become stronger. Clearly, this approach would not work! Rather, it is our belief that knowledge of family history reflects certain processes that exist in families whose members know their histories. One such process is the communication of family information across generations; important questions about this process would include "Who is passing this information?" and "When is this information transmitted?" In our study of family stories at the Emory University Family Narratives Project funded by the Sloan Foundation, we found that family stories seem to be transferred by mothers and grandmothers more often than not and that the information was typically passed during family dinners, family vacations, family holidays, and the  like. Other data indicated that these very same regular family dinners, yearly vacations, and holiday celebrations occur more frequently in families that have high levels of cohesiveness and that they contribute to the development of a strong sense of what we have called the intergenerational self.  It is this intergenerational self and the personal strength and moral guidance that seem to derive from it that are associated with increased resilience, better adjustment, and improved chances of good clinical and educational outcomes." --  &lt;em&gt; [Duke, M.P., Lazarus, A., &amp; Fivush, R.  (2008).  Knowledge of family history as a clinically useful index of psychological well-being and prognosis: A brief report.  Psychotherapy Theory, Research, Practice, Training, 45, 268-272.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The 20 items of the DYK scale are provided below. However, please remember that these are only a representative sample of the kinds of questions that kids should be able to answer. You can make up others. The main criterion, as mentioned above, is that the questions are about things that the children could not have learned on their own or experienced directly.  Each family will have different stories and different key moments and memories that are shared.  It is not the &lt;em&gt;content&lt;/em&gt; of what is known that is the critical factor, but the &lt;em&gt;process&lt;/em&gt; by which these things came to be known.  This process is, in our opinion, the causational factor.  In order to hear family stories, people need to sit down with one another and not be distracted.  Some people have to talk and some have to listen. The stories need to be told over and over and the times of sitting together need to be multiple and occur over many years.  The most convenient times traditionally have been family dinners, family trips in the car, vacations, birthday gatherings, etc.  As Bruce Feiler notes, however, given the complexities of modern family life families can also sit and talk over a snack after school or before everyone goes off to work, or at any other time that they can focus on each other.  These gatherings -- short or long -- are at the heart of the process by which the intergenerational stories can be told and learned and through which children can grow stronger and healthier.   No quick fix.  No simply learning the answers to the questions.  Just coming from a family in which the opportunities to learn family history and to create a family narrative are regular, multiple, predictable and &lt;em&gt;inviolable&lt;/em&gt;. As Bruce Feiler implores in his book, &lt;em&gt;" The Secrets of Happy Families"&lt;/em&gt;: Talk. A lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;                                      The Do You Know Scale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please answer the following questions by circling "Y" for "yes" or "N" for "no." Even if you know the information we are asking about, you don't need to write it down. We just wish to know if you know the information. &lt;br /&gt;
1.	Do you know how your parents met?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
2.	Do you know where your mother grew up?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
3.	Do you know where your father grew up?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
4.	Do you know where some of your grandparents grew up?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
5.	Do you know where some of your grandparents met?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
6.	Do you know where your parents were married?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
7.	Do you know what went on when you were being born?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
8.	Do you know the source of your name?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
9.	Do you know some things about what happened when your brothers or sisters were being  born?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
10.	Do you know which person in your family you look most like?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
11.	Do you know which person in the family you act most like?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
12.	Do you know some of the illnesses and injuries that your parents experienced when they were younger?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
13.	Do you know some of the lessons that your parents learned from good or bad experiences?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
14.	Do you know some things that happened to your mom or dad when they were in school?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
15.	Do you know the national background of your family (such as English, German, Russian, etc)?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
16.	Do you know some of the jobs that your parents had when they were young?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
17.	Do you know some awards that your parents received when they were young?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
18.	Do you know the names of the schools that your mom went to?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
19.	Do you know the names of the schools that your dad went to?Y N&lt;br /&gt;
20.	Do you know about a relative whose face "froze" in a grumpy position because he or she did not smile enough?Y N&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Score: Total number answered Y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important Note : About that last question! Fifteen percent of our sample actually answered "Yes!"   This is because the stories that families tell are not always "true."  More often than not they are told in order to teach a lesson or help with a physical or emotional hurt.  As such, they may be modified as needed.  The accuracy of the stories is not really critical.  In fact, there are often disagreements among family members about what really happened!  These disagreements then become part of the family narrative.  Not to worry!&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1024500/thumbs/s-KIDS-COMPUTERS-mini.jpg?9" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Beyonce Would Respond To The 'Mommy Wars'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/how-might-diva-feminist-b_n_2939446.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2939446</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T13:53:41Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T13:55:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>She might not address the issues facing women head on, but we can still look to her vague proclamations for insight. As the inspiration for...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>BuzzFeed SHIFT</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-gray/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She might not address the issues facing women head on, but we can still look to her vague proclamations for insight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the inspiration for the Atlantic's "All the Single Ladies," you must believe, Beyonce, that the role of women in society is changing in fundamentally significant ways.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1042654/thumbs/s-BEYONCE-NEW-SINGLE-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Amanda Bynes' Family Concerned About Her Well-Being</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/amanda-bynes-family-concerned_n_2939246.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2939246</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T13:43:40Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T13:43:50Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Amanda Bynes' family is reportedly thinking about bringing her back to Los Angeles. The troubled 26-year-old's bizarre behavior has her loved ones concerned and they're...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Leigh Blickley</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/leigh-blickley/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Amanda Bynes' family is reportedly thinking about bringing her back to Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The troubled 26-year-old's bizarre behavior &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/400714/source-amanda-bynes-family-is-concerned-for-her-well-being" target="_hplink"&gt;has her loved ones concerned and they're ready to intervene&lt;/a&gt;, according to E! News.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="amanda bynes family" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052721/thumbs/o-AMANDA-BYNES-FAMILY-570.jpg?3" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since moving to New York from L.A., Bynes has been acting strangely, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/tweets-of-the-week-amanda-bynes-drake_n_2935539.html" target="_hplink"&gt;posting weird pictures on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; -- umm, that cheek piercing? -- as well as &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/amanda-bynes-drake-vagina_n_2929248.html?utm_hp_ref=celebrity" target="_hplink"&gt;raunchy and inappropriate tweets&lt;/a&gt;. A source close to the star tells E! that &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/400714/source-amanda-bynes-family-is-concerned-for-her-well-being" target="_hplink"&gt;her family is "concerned for her welfare"&lt;/a&gt; and want her to move closer to them so that they can keep an eye on her. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, she refuses to leave the Big Apple. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The source adds that Bynes family is hopeful that everything is going to be OK, but that they're ready to step in if needed. Well, considering her recent run-ins with police and out-of-control solo outings, it appears it's time to intervene. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please don't take paparazzi pictures of me I like taking my own!&lt;a href="http://t.co/Jw2XOcywvT" title="http://twitpic.com/cbn57a"&gt;twitpic.com/cbn57a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Amanda Bynes (@AmandaBynes) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AmandaBynes/status/312696457633357824"&gt;March 15, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052723/thumbs/s-AMANDA-BYNES-FAMILY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Gay British Teen Dies After Being Set On Fire At Birthday Party </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/steven-simpson-gay-teen-burned-birthday-_n_2939092.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2939092</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T13:41:07Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T21:40:27Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A young British man has been convicted of manslaughter after killing a gay teen by setting him on fire. The BBC reports that 20-year-old Jordan...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Curtis M. Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/curtis-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;A young British man has been convicted of manslaughter after killing a gay teen by setting him on fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BBC reports that 20-year-old Jordan Sheard has been sentenced to three and a half years in jail for &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-21887535" target="_hplink"&gt;the death of Steven Simpson&lt;/a&gt; after pleading guilty to manslaughter charges. Simpson, 18, died one day after sustaining "significant burns" in June 2012, according to the report. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simpson had Asperger's syndrome, a speech impairment and epilepsy, &lt;a href="http://www.yorkshirepost.co.uk/news/at-a-glance/general-news/teen-dies-at-his-birthday-party-after-friend-covers-him-with-tanning-oil-and-sets-him-alight-1-5519548" target="_hplink"&gt;the Yorkshire Post noted&lt;/a&gt;. The teen had reportedly been dared to strip down to his underpants before being doused in tanning oil, after which Sheard set him aflame at the party. Other reports said that &lt;a href="http://news.ninemsn.com.au/world/2013/03/22/10/32/teen-set-alight-at-birthday-party" target="_hplink"&gt;anti-gay messages&lt;/a&gt;, including "gay boy" and "I love d*ck," had been found scrawled across Simpson's body. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detective Sean Middleton described Simpson to the BBC as "a very caring and likeable young man" and a "generous spirit was taken advantage of and a single thoughtless act resulted in his death."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of local lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender (LGBT) rights advocates said they believed Sheard's prison term to be too lenient, but prosecuting attorney Tim Warburton &lt;a href="http://www.thestar.co.uk/news/local/barnsley-teen-burned-to-death-on-his-18th-birthday-1-5521116" target="_hplink"&gt;nonetheless told The Star&lt;/a&gt; that the sentence was "within the range of what would be expected had it been considered a hate crime," and that it would not be appealed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"This was a cruel case of bullying based on Steven’s sexuality and disability," Warburton is quoted as saying. "While we accept Jordan did not intend to kill Steven, his actions did lead to his death." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Sheard's attorney said his client had been "deeply and significantly affected by what he has done and the tragic consequences that ensued," which describing Simpson's death as a "stupid prank that went wrong in a bad way," &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2297053/Yob-killed-autistic-gay-teenager-Steven-Simpson-setting-18th-birthday-party.html" target="_hplink"&gt;the Daily Mail noted&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052373/thumbs/s-STEVEN-SIMPSON-GAY-TEEN-BURNED-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Loren Ridinger: Learning to Let Your Children Go</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/loren-ridinger/learning-to-let-your-chil_b_2921073.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2921073</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T13:14:59Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T13:15:02Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Watching your child grow into an independent individual is an incredible experience filled with highs and lows.  And once their grown, it's even more of a challenge to step back and let your child make their own decisions.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Loren Ridinger</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/loren-ridinger/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;It's been a flurry of activity around our house for the last few months. My daughter, Amber, will likely be married by the time you read this post, and to be honest -- the wedding planning was a bittersweet ride. Of course we are so happy for her, we love Duane so much that it is easy to feel confident about her future. I love being a mom. And, the past years have been so incredible to watch my little baby grow into a gorgeous, independent woman. But as a mom, it's tough. Sometimes I just want to scoop my little baby back up and sing her to sleep. Helping her plan her wedding was a beautiful process -- of course I wanted it to be the day of her dreams. But it's milestones like this that make it even more difficult for me to let her go. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you decide to have a baby, it's a huge decision. During the months of pregnancy and even throughout the first years of her life, I worried all the time. Am I a good mom? Is Amber a happy baby? Do other people think I am a good mom? Am I making the right decisions as a parent? The questions and uncertainties go on and on. Being a new mom, there's nothing else to compare the experience to -- it's completely unchartered territory. And it's terrifying and exhilarating all at once. All the while you're filled with overwhelming love. A love so strong and intense, sometimes you just have to laugh while other times you just have to cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most parents, we want nothing but the best for our children. The best education, we want them to be happy and confident, we don't want them to suffer over anything -- as seeing them in any pain is certainly more painful to us as parents. I still want to give my daughter everything I didn't have and more. I want her life to be filled with joy and success and I never want her to worry.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she was just a baby, I remember thinking about the day she would find her prince and be married. I remember the moment perfectly, staring at her in her little bed and thinking how I just wanted her to stay little and need me forever. Throughout the years, I recall doing everything I could to keep her close, to protect her and for her to still need me as her mom. I am sure that was challenging for her because like most parents, we can be overwhelming (especially me) while trying to keep them little when all they want to do is spread their wings and fly.  It's just as tough now as she heads out to have a family of her own. I am so happy for both of them, but at the same time, I have to admit, I have been a bit melancholy. I finally figured it out while recalling all the memories, looking at all her baby pictures and listening to wedding songs for her dance with her dad -- you never stop being a mom. Whether your child is five or fifty, they are always going to be your baby and their age just doesn't matter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching your child grow into an independent individual is an incredible experience filled with highs and lows. Helping to guide and mold your child while teaching them to function in a world full of challenges is a big task with big ideals. And once their grown, it's even more of a challenge to step back and let your child make their own decisions.  But it's okay to feel this way. The love for our children is unconditional. There is nothing else like it, sometimes it hurts but it is still the greatest love of all.  I am always going to be her mom and she will always be my baby -- even in my perfect and not-so-perfect moments. Like a caterpillar, she has grown and turned into a beautiful butterfly. She is ready to spread her wings and fly.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is her time to shine.  Fly baby -- Fly.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052705/thumbs/s-MOTHER-DAUGHTER-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Passover Seder Won't Be Complete Without This DIY Afikoman Bag</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/passover-ideas-afikoman-bag_n_2931925.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2931925</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T13:07:40Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T13:06:56Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The kids will have a blast searching for this crafty sack. </summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rain-embuscado/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Tomorrow marks the start of Passover, and to help you prepare for the occasion, today's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/craft-of-the-day" target="_hplink"&gt;Craft Of The Day&lt;/a&gt; features a project by &lt;a href="http://secret-agent-josephine.com/blog/" target="_hplink"&gt;Secret Agent Josephine&lt;/a&gt; which was featured on &lt;a href="http://theshiksa.com" target="_hplink"&gt;The Shiksa In The Kitchen's blog&lt;/a&gt;. The blogger shows us a fun and no-sew way &lt;a href="http://theshiksa.com/2012/04/01/family-fun-afikoman-bag/" target="_hplink"&gt;to make a DIY Afikoman bag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="passover ideas" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052420/thumbs/a-PASSOVER-IDEAS-640x468.jpg?15" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="http://secret-agent-josephine.com/blog/" target="_hplink"&gt;Brenda Ponnay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No seder can be complete without the search for this matzoh holder. And since it's such a fun and important part of celebrating, why not make this case really special? Plus, it's super easy and the blogger shows you two different versions, so you can chose your favorite style.  For full instructions, head over to &lt;a href="http://theshiksa.com/2012/04/01/family-fun-afikoman-bag/" target="_hplink"&gt;The Shiksa in the Kitchen's website&lt;/a&gt;. And if you're on the hunt for even more great ideas, be sure to check out our &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/craft-of-the-day" target="_hplink"&gt;Craft Of The Day&lt;/a&gt; slideshow below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEPOLLAJAX--193347--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have a home story idea or tip? Email us at homesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052420/thumbs/s-PASSOVER-IDEAS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>8 Ways To Create A Restful, Cozy Reading Nook </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/create-reading-nook_n_2933462.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2933462</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T13:04:01Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-24T03:41:37Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There are few things more relaxing than spending a Sunday afternoon at home and curling up with a good book -- so why not create...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/carolyn-gregoire/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;There are few things more relaxing than spending a Sunday afternoon at home and curling up with a good book -- so why not create a cozy area just for this purpose for your family to enjoy? A reading nook can also be the perfect way to transform an awkward corner, windowsill or loft space into a warm, comfortable area for a little R&amp;R. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it's for kids or grown-ups, these cozy, well-lit reading spots will set a peaceful tone in any room, and they're surprisingly easy to set up. If you're thinking about adding one to your home, click through the slideshow below for eight  tranquil and restful design ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell us: Do you have a reading nook in your home? Would you ever add one to your living room or playroom? Share your thoughts in the comments or tweet &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPostHome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--287873--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have a home story idea or tip? Email us at homesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051835/thumbs/s-READING-NOOK-IDEAS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: Little Boy Saves Cat From Bullies</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/wendell-overton-saves-cat-bullies_n_2936222.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2936222</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T01:17:30Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T01:20:33Z</updated>
    
    <summary>This is Jackson the cat. He lives in North Carolina. Last week, a group of kids approached Jackson, threw him into the air, ran over...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Hayley Hudson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/hayley-hudson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;This is Jackson the cat. He lives in North Carolina.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="wendell overton 4" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052444/thumbs/o-WENDELL-OVERTON-4-570.jpg?5" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, a group of kids approached Jackson, &lt;a href="http://www.examiner.com/article/10-year-old-boy-north-carolina-rescues-cat-being-tortured-by-bullies" target="_hplink"&gt;threw him into the air&lt;/a&gt;, ran over him with their bikes and squirted energy drinks in his face. The bullies reportedly varied in age from 5 to 13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But 10-year-old Wendell Overton saved the day. According to a Wednesday post on the Outer Banks SPCA's Facebook page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="wendell overton 3" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052440/thumbs/o-WENDELL-OVERTON-3-570.jpg?5" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Wendell Overton, 10, of Manteo made the world a better place on March 12. Jackson the cat was being tortured by a group of boys. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10151830043083298&amp;set=a.10150999268118298.543082.116792203297&amp;type=1&amp;theater" target="_hplink"&gt;Courageous Wendell rescued Jackson&lt;/a&gt; and took him home to his mother, who called the Outer Banks SPCA. Jackson is doing great and will be available for adoption soon! Thank you, Wendell, for being so brave and doing the right thing!&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overton &lt;a href="http://www.wvec.com/news/Manteo-youngster-praised-for-saving-cat-from-abuse--197808781.html" target="_hplink"&gt;had seen the black-and-white cat&lt;/a&gt; in the neighborhood before, WVEC reported. On the day of the attack he became worried that his injuries were serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"He said 'Mom, &lt;a href="http://www.wvec.com/news/Manteo-youngster-praised-for-saving-cat-from-abuse--197808781.html" target="_hplink"&gt;this cat is going to die&lt;/a&gt;. We need to save it,'" his mother said in the video above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story generated a flurry of attention for Jackson and Overton. Shortly after the photo went online, the SPCA posted an update:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;WOW! Words cannot express how moved we are by &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10151829057283298&amp;set=a.152917373297.144372.116792203297&amp;type=1&amp;theater" target="_hplink"&gt;the overwhelming response to Wendell's story&lt;/a&gt;. We wanted to give everyone an update on Jackson, the cat saved by Wendell's compassion and bravery. He is recovering well, resting comfortably, eating like a king and will be looking for a new home soon! &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tons of cards and letters poured in praising Wendell's bravery. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XOXO.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="wendell overton 6" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052447/thumbs/o-WENDELL-OVERTON-6-570.jpg?5" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;H/T: &lt;a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/10-year-old-heroically-saves-cat-from-bullies" target="_hplink"&gt;BuzzFeed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052436/thumbs/s-WENDELL-OVERTON-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
