<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Will This Be The Worst Allergy Season Ever?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/31/2013-allergy-season-could_n_2989655.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2989655</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-31T22:03:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T22:26:05Z</updated>
    
    <summary>From Marlene Cimons, Climate Nexus: Marlene Cimons writes for Climate Nexus, a nonprofit that aims to tell the climate story in innovative ways that raise awareness...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Leader</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-leader/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/28320-climate-change-allergies.html" target="_hplink"&gt;From Marlene Cimons, Climate Nexus:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marlene Cimons writes for &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://climatenexus.org/"&gt;Climate Nexus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, a nonprofit that aims to tell the climate story in innovative ways that raise awareness of, dispel misinformation about, and showcase solutions to climate change and energy issues in the United States.  She&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; contributed this article to LiveScience's &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/topics/expert-voices-op-ed-and-insights/"&gt;Expert Voices: Op-Ed &amp; Insights&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This spring could be the most miserable one ever for those of us with allergies, and we can blame it on climate change. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People in the Northeast, in particular, will be among the hardest hit in the aftermath of &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/24380-hurricane-sandy-status-data.html"&gt;Hurricane Sandy&lt;/a&gt; and this winter's record-setting blizzard, both of which dumped massive amounts of precipitation over the region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;[This] promises a robust allergy season,'' said Leonard Bielory, an allergy and immunology specialist with the Rutgers &lt;a href="http://www.cep.rutgers.edu/site/"&gt;Center for Environmental Prediction&lt;/a&gt; in New Jersey, a state which suffered widespread destruction from Sandy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The first airborne tree pollen has been measured in recent days, and while the count is still low, some allergy sufferers are showing comparatively severe symptoms,'' he added. &amp;quot;I expect more tree pollen than ever to be released this spring, and the reaction to the early pollen to be unusually strong.''&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The planet is getting warmer, and human behavior is responsible. The changing climate has brought early spring, late-ending fall, and large amounts of rain and snow.  All of that, combined with historically high levels of carbon dioxide in the air, nourishes the trees and plants that make pollen, and encourages more fungal growth, such as mold, and the release of spores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be paying a wretched price in the coming months for the behavior fueling the explosion of pollen, which are the tiny reproductive cells found in trees, weeds, plants and grasses.  By all accounts, there will be more pollen this year than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The trees are going to burst in the next week or two, and we will get a burst of pollen higher than in past years,'' said Bielory, who predicts that pollen counts will increase by 30 percent by 2020 and, &amp;quot;in a perfect test-tube world, will double by 2040 because of climate change.'' [&lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/24659-pollen-counts-rise-global-warming.html"&gt;Study: Pollen Counts To More Than Double By 2040&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most trees release their pollen in the early spring, while grasses do so in late spring and early summer. Ragweed makes its pollen in the late summer and early fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And pollen production is only part of the impact that &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/11350-top-10-surprising-results-global-warming.html"&gt;global warming&lt;/a&gt; is going to have on allergies and asthma — and our health overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In areas of the country experiencing prolonged heat and drought, dust will worsen air pollution, exacerbating asthma and other respiratory diseases. In other regions, climate change will affect the insect population — their stings and bites can provoke fatal allergic reactions in sensitive individuals — as well as the proliferation of such vines as poison ivy. Poison ivy thrives with increased carbon dioxide, and as a result, now makes a far more potent urushiol — the oil that causes poison-ivy-triggered rashes — than in the past. [&lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/23026-global-warming-changing-world.html"&gt;8 Ways Global Warming Is Already Changing the World&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current evidence also suggests that climate change will increase the concentration of ground-level ozone, particularly in Northeastern, Midwestern and Western cities, causing an increase in respiratory diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, if you have allergies or asthma, climate change is going to make you a lot sicker now and in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cdc.gov/healthcommunication/toolstemplates/entertainmented/tips/allergies.html"&gt;Allergic diseases&lt;/a&gt; are the sixth leading cause of chronic disease in the United States, with an annual cost of $18 billion, according to the federal Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. More than 50 million Americans suffer from allergies annually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.myhealthnewsdaily.com/1060-asthma-drug-omalizumab-prevents-seasonal-allergies-asthma-attacks-.html"&gt;Asthma afflicts about 20 million Americans&lt;/a&gt;, and is rising around the world, according to the CDC. Moreover, some public health experts regard the global increase of asthma as an early health effect of climate change, and a harbinger of more health dangers to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18774380"&gt;one study&lt;/a&gt; published in the Journal of Allergy and Clinical Immunology called climate change &amp;quot;potentially the largest global threat to human health ever encountered,'' predicting more injury, disease and death from natural disasters, heat waves, infections and widespread malnutrition, as well as more allergic and air-pollution illnesses and death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are lucky enough to be free from allergies, don't make the mistake of dismissing them as nothing more than a minor annoyance. Allergies can have a serious impact on the quality of life, and in some circumstances — a bee sting, for example, or if they trigger an asthma attack — they can kill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This is not just a matter of having a runny nose,'' said Jeffrey Demain, director of the &lt;a href="http://www.allergyalaska.com"&gt;Allergy, Asthma and Immunology Center of Alaska&lt;/a&gt;.  &amp;quot;Allergies affect the ability to go to work and go to school, and they affect school and work performance. They interfere with playing sports, social opportunities, how well you sleep, your relationships and your overall general happiness.''&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average, someone with allergic disorders experiences a quality of life 35 percent less than the general population, Demain said. &amp;quot;It really is quite dramatic,'' he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allergies occur when the body's immune system overreacts to a substance that generally doesn't bother other people. The allergens can prompt sneezing, coughing, watery eyes and itching. In the years between 1970 and 2000, allergic rhinitis among Americans has risen from 10 percent to 30 percent, which correlates to similar increases in positive allergy skin-test results, according to Bielory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most experts believe the impact of climate change on allergic diseases will vary by region, depending on latitude, altitude, rainfall and storms, land-use patterns, urbanization, transportation and energy production. Drought, for example, will contribute to increasing air pollution, while heavy rain will wash the pollution away, but encourage the growth of mold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bielory and his colleagues, &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3053965/"&gt;reporting in a 2011 study&lt;/a&gt;, showed that the ragweed-pollen season has become longer in northern areas of the country in recent years, and points to climate change as the reason this is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We drew a line from Texas to Canada,'' he explained. &amp;quot;The pollen count duration remained the same in Texas, but changed as you moved north. Even though you are heading north to Canada, the pollen started earlier and ended later — and it should have been shortening. This was due to earlier springs and the later onset of fall. Frost wasn't occurring as early as it used to, so ragweed was pollinating later.''&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pollen levels per plant are increasing as a result of escalating concentrations of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere, and the plants themselves are growing bigger, experts say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The increased pollen is probably a way for the plant to adapt,'' said Demain, who also is an associate clinical professor at the University of Washington. &amp;quot;They become larger and produce much more pollen. More people are going to develop asthma and allergies, and it's going to be severe.''&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stopping human activities that contribute to climate change might help future generations avoid these risks, but the rest of us — like the plants themselves — will have to adapt. We also can hope for a new medical breakthrough that will turn off the allergic response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, stay inside and keep your windows closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The views expressed are those of the author and do not necessarily reflect the views of the publisher.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/26413-freakiest-medical-conditions.html'&gt;The 9 Most Bizarre Medical Conditions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/11350-top-10-surprising-results-global-warming.html'&gt;Top 10 Surprising Results of Global Warming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.myhealthnewsdaily.com/952-nine-weirdest-allergies-110215.html'&gt;The 9 Weirdest Allergies Explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Copyright 2013 &lt;a href="http://LiveScience.com" target="_hplink"&gt;LiveScience&lt;/a&gt;, a TechMediaNetwork company. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1064050/thumbs/s-2013-ALLERGY-SEASON-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>No Baby Shower For Kate Middleton?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/31/kate-middleton-baby-shower_n_2989093.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2989093</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-31T17:52:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T17:54:15Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Despite all of the murmurings of a baby shower for Kate Middleton, royal experts are saying that the event is quite unlikely. According to Victoria...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rebecca-adams/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Despite all of the murmurings of a baby shower for &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/kate-middleton" target="_hplink"&gt;Kate Middleton&lt;/a&gt;, royal experts are saying that the event is quite unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Victoria Arbiter, ABC News Royal Expert, &lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/Travel/kate-middleton-baby-shower/story?id=18838126#.UVhubqs6U5g" target="_hplink"&gt;the Duchess of Cambridge will most likely eschew a big to-do&lt;/a&gt; because of the "added pressure that [she and Prince William] are clearly very wealthy, and a lavish baby shower would be seen as highly inappropriate. There's nothing they can't go out and buy themselves."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until now, the general consensus among rumor mill contributors has been that &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/pippa-middleton" target="_hplink"&gt;Pippa Middleton&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href="http://hollywoodlife.com/2013/03/27/kate-middleton-baby-shower-plans-pippa-middleton/" target="_hplink"&gt;planning a "down-to-earth" baby shower for the duchess&lt;/a&gt;, complete with wine, beer and a possible appearance by &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/queen-elizabeth-ii" target="_hplink"&gt;Queen Elizabeth II&lt;/a&gt;. Arbiter even conceded that there is a slight chance that Pips will put together a very small event, but she doesn't think there's a chance the queen would show up (and we have to agree).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baby showers aren't customary in the UK, so we have some advice for Pippa &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; she's planning a gathering: &lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/pictures/inside-kourtney-kardashians-baby-shower-2012295/22779" target="_hplink"&gt;Take a tip from Kourtney Kardashian&lt;/a&gt; and include yummy sweets like chocolate chip cake, cotton candy and strawberry shakes on your shower menu in lieu of your &lt;a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/foodanddrink/9653014/Pippa-Middleton-Im-a-real-foodie-kidneys-oysters-mussels-liver...-I-eat-it-all.html" target="_hplink"&gt;trademark pigeon breasts and pig cheeks&lt;/a&gt;. Just a tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, all of these theories are only educated guesses. Who &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; knows what Kate will do to fête her bun in the oven? We're not 100 percent convinced in either direction, but what do you think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See more Kate Middleton:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--250608--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want more? Be sure to check out HuffPost Style on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/huffpoststyle" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/HuffPostStyle" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffpoststyle.tumblr.com" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffpoststyle/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; and Instagram at @HuffPostStyle.&lt;br /&gt;
--&lt;br /&gt;
Do you have a style story idea or tip? Email us at stylesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063958/thumbs/s-KATE-MIDDLETON-BABY-SHOWER-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Police: Deadbeat Dad Literally Tries To Crawl Away From Paying Child Support</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/31/steven-jones-child-suppor_n_2989111.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2989111</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-31T17:30:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T17:52:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Police say a deadbeat dad from the Chicago suburb of Maywood was found literally trying to crawl away from making child support payments. Cops were...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kim Bellware</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kim-bellware/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Police say a deadbeat dad from the Chicago suburb of Maywood was found literally trying to crawl away from making child support payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chicagotribune.com/news/local/breaking/chi-man-who-owes-70k-in-child-support-caught-hiding-in-basement-20130329,0,4058247.story" target="_hplink"&gt;Cops were trying to execute a child support warrant for 36-year-old Steven Jones&lt;/a&gt; who the Tribune reports owes more than $70,000 in past-due payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deputies went to the 900 block of South 5th Avenue in Bellwood about 9:30 p.m. Thursday, &lt;a href="http://www.nbcchicago.com/news/local/Dad-Tries-to-Crawl-Away-from-Police-Owes-Thousands-in-Child-Support-200787641.html?_osource=SocialFlowTwt_CHBrand#ixzz2P8EM0v2p" target="_hplink"&gt;after they learned Jones worked as a tax preparer there&lt;/a&gt;, the Associated Press reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cook County Sheriff Tom Dart said after failing to answer the door, Jones spotted the officers who say they saw the man "drop to the floor and crawl downstairs."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://chicago.cbslocal.com/2013/03/29/police-deadbeat-dad-crawled-down-stairs-to-avoid-arrest/" target="_hplink"&gt;Jones was arrested on the child support warrant when officers found him hiding in the basement&lt;/a&gt;, the Sun-Times reports. He was also charged with obstruction of service of process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jones received a $30,000 I-Bond for obstruction Friday at the Maywood Courthouse, as well as a $2,000 C-bond for the child support warrant.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063959/thumbs/s-STEVEN-JONES-CHILD-SUPPORT-MAYWOOD-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kourtney Volunteers To Be Khloe's Surrogate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/31/kourtney-kardashian-khloe-kardashian-surrogate_n_2988860.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2988860</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-31T16:00:26Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T16:01:19Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Kourtney Kardashian has two kids and Kim's expecting her first baby, but their married sister Khloe is still struggling to get pregnant. Well, that's when...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Leigh Blickley</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/leigh-blickley/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Kourtney Kardashian has two kids and Kim's expecting her first baby, but their married sister Khloe is still struggling to get pregnant. Well, that's when sisterly love comes in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/shows/kourtney_and_kim_take_miami" target="_hplink"&gt;In tonight's episode of "Kourtney &amp; Kim Take Miami,"&lt;/a&gt; Kourtney reveals that &lt;a href="http://www.celebuzz.com/2013-03-29/kourtney-to-khloe-ill-be-your-surrogate/" target="_hplink"&gt;she's considering carrying a child for Khloe and her husband Lamar Odom&lt;/a&gt;, since her 28-year-old sister is having trouble conceiving on her own. Khloe has been open about her battle with infertility, confessing on the show that she doesn't ovulate and is also taking pills to thicken her uterus lining. "If that doesn't get thicker," she explains, "then I cannot carry a baby."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a sneak peek at the episode, Kourtney asks her baby daddy and longtime boyfriend Scott Disick &lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/entertainment/news/kourtney-kardashian-considers-being-khloe-kardashians-surrogate-2013313" target="_hplink"&gt;what he thinks about her being a gestational carrier&lt;/a&gt; for Khloe and Lamar. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I wanted to ask you your thoughts on me being a surogate for Khloe. How would that make you feel?" Kourtney, 33, asks Scott, who smirks at the question. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You're telling me you want to get pregnant, carry a child and give it to Khloe?" he asks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It would be her child with Lamar," Kourtney explains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, &lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/entertainment/news/kourtney-kardashian-considers-being-khloe-kardashians-surrogate-2013313" target="_hplink"&gt;Scott can't seem to wrap his head around the idea&lt;/a&gt;, saying, "That's weird. Why wouldn't you adopt a kid in need?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kourtney tries to tell Scott that Khloe and Lamar most likely want a "blood child" ... and he fires back. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You don't just go putting babies in other sisters because you can .... This is not a normal conversation to come home with! It's too much for me. This is freaking me out!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Nothing is happening," Kourtney reassures him. "I was just having a conversation."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the end, it's Scott who realizes that it might actually be a good thing for Khloe. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I want her to be happy and I feel like she wants a kid so bad," &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/shows/kourtney_and_kim_take_miami/news/402840/kourtney-kardashian-offers-to-be-surrogate-for-khlo-kardashian-odom-in-kourtney-kim-take-miami-finale-watch-now" target="_hplink"&gt;Scott tells Kourtney later in the episode&lt;/a&gt;. "I take back some of the things I said to you thinking you were crazy about carrying her child. I still think it's a huge decision, but I understand why you'd want to do that for your family."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not so fast though, Kourtney. It sounds like Khloe is not into the idea: "You would push my baby out of your vag[ina]?! ... Ewww." &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063887/thumbs/s-KOURTNEY-KARDASHIAN-KHLOE-KARDASHIAN-SURROGATE-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: State Trooper's Dedication to Newtown Family Is Forever</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/31/eddie-vayan_n_2974550.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2974550</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-31T15:07:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T15:13:32Z</updated>
    
    <summary>One state trooper has become the greatest source of support to a Newtown family affected by the Sandy Hook shooting. On the day of the...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Mohini Kundu</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mohini-kundu/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;One state trooper has become the greatest source of support to a Newtown family affected by the Sandy Hook shooting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the day of the tragic shootings, each family was assigned a Connecticut state trooper to act as its guardian through the ordeal. In the three months since, trooper Eddie Vayan has continued to honor his duty to the Hubbard family who lost their little girl Catherine on that December morning. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-18563_162-57576672/a-guardian-angel-helps-family-heal-in-the-aftermath-of-newtown/" target="_hplink"&gt;CBS interviewed the Hubbard family&lt;/a&gt; and the faithful officer who has supported them from day one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's the kindness in him that goes far beyond what anybody could ever expect," mother Jenny Hubbard said in the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vayan and his fellow troopers were instructed to protect the families' privacy and help them out in any way possible. "I'm here for whatever you need. I'm not going to leave your side," Eddie recalls telling the Hubbards when they met. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trooper stayed with Jenny Hubbard and her son Freddy as news of Catherine's passing was confirmed. He also spared the parents from having to identify their daughter by doing it himself with the help of a photo. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Freddy asked him if he would stand by Catherine's casket, after the wake in full uniform and he did," father Matthew Hubbard told CBS. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vayan has since become like a big brother to Freddy, and his continued protection was a great comfort to the family when it came time to send their son back to school. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Vayan, his friendship with the Hubbard family will last for many years to come. "December 14th, 2012 is the worst day of my life, the most tragic day of my life, but being part of the Hubbards' has been &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-18563_162-57576672/a-guardian-angel-helps-family-heal-in-the-aftermath-of-newtown/" target="_hplink"&gt;the most honorable time of my life&lt;/a&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061311/thumbs/s-NEWTOWN-TROOPER-HEALS-HUBBARD-FAMILY-mini.jpg?19" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Emily Mendell: Why Sundays Are So Special To Me Right Now</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emily-mendell/suddenly-sunday_b_2988610.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2988610</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-31T14:44:01Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T14:47:30Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I realized that I may have reached a place in my life where this time could easily be my favorite part of the week. Sunday nights are the gift of pause, a deep breath, a comforting ritual in which we abide, often without noticing.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Emily Mendell</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emily-mendell/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Early last Sunday evening, I sat in my home office writing, paying a few bills, and taking inventory of the week ahead. We had just finished dinner as a family; Dave had prepared lamb shanks and the house still smelled rich and savory from a full day of braising. Once the dishwasher was loaded, we all retreated to our own spaces and obligations. Noah was in his room, strumming on his guitar, the riffs playfully ambling down the hallway into earshot.  Chase tackled the tail ends of his math homework at the kitchen table. Dave tapped away on his computer, preparing for the coming week of parent-teacher conferences.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
I took a quick break from my tasks at hand to check my Twitter feed, where I found a number of people lamenting the existence of Sunday nights. They shared how much they loathed this particular time, sentiments we have all heard and felt many times before.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Sunday nights are the end to an "all too short" weekend. Sunday nights are heavy in anticipation of the drudgery, stress, chaos, and toil of the impending work and school week. Come Sunday night, time has run out on all the chores and tasks you promised you would get to at some point, but never did. Sunday nights are all about surrendering to the fact that you do not control your own destiny, because here comes Monday whether you like it or not.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Yup. Roger that.I get it.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
But as I sat at my desk with a great deal of empathy for these Sunday-night-tortured Twitter people, I realized that I may have reached a place in my life where this time could easily be my favorite part of the week. It wasn't always this way, but Sunday nights have become a spiritual oasis where my family centers itself before flinging headlong into the tumultuous schedule that we honor Mondays through Fridays. Sunday nights are the gift of pause, a deep breath, a comforting ritual in which we abide, often without noticing.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
On Sundays we are given permission to eat dinner early, sometimes as early as 4:00 p.m. We have time to set the table, carefully folding napkins and laying down flatware, rather than throwing some pasta into a bowl and announcing that "everyone is responsible for their own utensils and drinks." There are no activities on Sunday night, no rushing to get to lessons, or board meetings or school events. Yet, it is still officially a school night so the boys are relegated to our home and presumably a reasonable bedtime. All of this mandatory togetherness is understood, and, without a word, embraced by all of us. We putter around, cross paths in the hallways, and move through the evening with an easiness that is elusive on all other nights when our schedules propel us in umpteen different, urgent directions. On Sunday nights, we return to ourselves and to each other.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Years ago when my grandmother was still living, Sunday nights were reserved for extended family dinners. We would assemble at someone's home -- my sister's, brother's or mine, taking turns hosting, sometimes cooking or ordering take out, but always together for the sake of Mom-Mom. We don't get together as regularly now that she is gone, but the essence of "family" still prevails for Sunday nights. Our open door policy -- one which happily welcomes anyone into our home on any night of the week -- is not outright negated, but it isn't honored either. Not on Sunday.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Of course, these evenings of Zen were not possible when the boys were little. There was much more house work to be done, baths to be given, stories to be read, and earlier bedtimes which cut Sunday nights short, trying to fit it all in before the requisite melt down, which by the way wasn't always my children's. The drum beat was relentless back then, even on Sundays. But the boys have grown and our family rhythm has changed. And suddenly, Sunday nights have become this lovely little interlude.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
I realize I may be in the eye of the Sunday night hating storm. Years from now, Sunday nights may be the time the boys return to college so I reserve my right to return to loathing this time. But for now, it's an opportunity to be present, in the here and now, and choose not to fret about the days ahead. Instead, we connect and disperse to get done what needs to get done -- perhaps alone -- but under the same roof with the same unspoken understanding that we are exactly where we belong.Together.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063828/thumbs/s-WOMAN-DRINKING-COFFEE-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>What To Do When The Easter Bunny Leaves A Mess</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/31/clean-up-easter-grass_n_2984725.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2984725</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-31T13:32:11Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T13:32:12Z</updated>
    
    <summary>And you're left with all that stubborn grass.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/michelle-manetti/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;If you and your family were paid a visit by the Easter Bunny, chances are you got a basket filled with goodies. It's also likely that your home is now covered in that plastic grass, which looks cute, but makes a mess. For some reason, like tinsel, it's pretty hard to vacuum up, so we went searching around to find the &lt;a href="http://www.mamapedia.com/article/i-hate-easter-grass" target="_hplink"&gt;best way to clean up Easter grass&lt;/a&gt;-- but it wasn't easy. But our friends over at Real Simple had a great trick that shows us &lt;a href="http://www.realsimple.com/home-organizing/new-uses-for-old-things/lint-roller-as-glitter-pick-up-00000000043325/index.html" target="_hplink"&gt;how to clean up glitter&lt;/a&gt;, and we think it'll come in handy after all the chocolate is eaten and the eggs are cracked open. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply take a lint roller and wipe it along the covered surfaces. The tool should easily pick up any straggling pieces and the area will look as good as new. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also try &lt;a href="http://www.casasugar.com/Tip-Cleaning-Up-Christmas-Tree-Needles-From-Carpet-12462858" target="_hplink"&gt;Pop Sugar's trick&lt;/a&gt; of wrapping a piece of duct tape around your hand -- sticky side exposed. Then, pat the messy spots with the adhesive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these ideas will definitely do the trick by saving you a lot of time (and frustration) during Easter clean up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through our slideshow to see other great cleaning and organizing tricks. And be sure to head over to Real Simple and Pop Sugar for more information. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--259485--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have a home story idea or tip? Email us at homesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063425/thumbs/s-CLEAN-UP-EASTER-GRASS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Susan Patton: Why I Told Female Princeton Students To Find A Husband</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/susan-patton/why-i-told-female-princeton-students-to-find-a-husband_b_2988154.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2988154</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-31T13:13:50Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T13:14:34Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The extreme reaction to my letter is astonishing. Honestly, it was intended as little more than honest advice from a Jewish mother.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Susan Patton</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/susan-patton/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Since publishing a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nina-bahadur/susan-patton-daily-princetonian-find-a-husband-princeton_b_2979789.html?utm_hp_ref=women&amp;ir=Women?utm_hp_ref=women&amp;ir=Women" target="_hplink"&gt;letter to the editor in the &lt;em&gt;Daily Princetonian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Friday, some people have asked me to clarify whether I intended it to be read as satire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My letter was serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sincerely feel that too much focus has been placed on encouraging young women only to achieve professionally. I understand that this can be seen as retrogressive, but for those women who aspire to what used to be thought of as a traditional life with home and family, there is almost no ink addressing personal fulfillment outside of the workplace. Specifically, finding lifelong friends and the right partner with whom to share a life and raise a family.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I understand that all women don't want marriage (to men or other women) and or children, but for those that do, identifying the right partner is critical. One of the criteria by which I am defining the right partner is someone with shared educational and intellectual appreciation. Yes, that can be found after college and outside of Princeton, but the concentration of outstanding men (and women) will never be greater than it is as a student. I wanted to encourage the wonderful young women on Princeton's campus to take advantage of this while they can. From a sheer numbers perspective, the odds will never be as good again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The popularity of Nikki Mueller's video (&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YDhf9qwiA34" target="_hplink"&gt;I Went to Princeton, Bitch&lt;/a&gt;) comically attests to the difficulty Princeton women face from men who are threatened by their academic credentials. It doesn't address how unsatisfying it is for exceptionally well educated women to be with men who are not their intellectual equal. I am divorced. I did not marry a Princeton man. I wish I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://nymag.com/thecut/2013/03/princeton-mom-to-all-students-find-a-husband.html" target="_hplink"&gt;extreme reaction to my letter&lt;/a&gt; is astonishing. Honestly, it was intended as little more than honest advice from a Jewish mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, yes, this is exactly the advice I would give my daughters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RELATED ON &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/women/" target="_hplink"&gt;HUFFPOST WOMEN&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nina-bahadur/susan-patton-daily-princetonian-find-a-husband-princeton_b_2979789.html?utm_hp_ref=women&amp;ir=Women?utm_hp_ref=women&amp;ir=Women" target="_hplink"&gt;7 Questions For The Alumna Telling Princeton Women To 'Find A Husband'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063759/thumbs/s-PRINCETON-FIND-A-HUSBAND-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Our Caregiver Took Advantage Of My Father, But We Couldn't Let Her Go</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/31/elder-abuse-caregiver-problems_n_2979814.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2979814</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-31T12:42:53Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T12:42:58Z</updated>
    
    <summary>SPECIAL FROM Next Avenue By Jane Gottlieb In the end, our concern for Dad's care was a higher priority than our worries about his money...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Next Avenue</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rebecca-klein/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://big.assets.huffingtonpost.com/NextAveLogo2.jpg" align="left" style="margin: 0px 15px 10px 0px;" /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPECIAL FROM&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.nextavenue.org"&gt;Next Avenue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Jane Gottlieb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the end, our concern for Dad's care was a higher priority than our worries about his money&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two hours before my father died three years ago at age 85, my sister and I dismissed the home hospice aide and called for Hana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after 10 days of watching dad wither, we were wholly unprepared for the awful moment when he would leave us for good. Hana, as always, seemed to come out of nowhere and set things right.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(MORE:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.nextavenue.org/article/2011-09/talking-loved-one-near-end-life" target="_hplink"&gt;Talking to a Loved One Near the End of Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She lowered the shade, turned off some lights and adjusted the height of the bed. "Rub his feet," she urged, as she spread moisture cream on his yellowed face. "He can hear you. You can talk to him."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time Hana left, the three of us had shared thoughts about the difficult weeks leading up to that moment, read a prayer together and raised a glass of sherry. At her suggestion, we even allowed my father some. For months, we had suspected that her influence on our declining father, and especially on his finances, had become too strong. At this moment, though, we welcomed whatever powers she could muster. This was our family now: Elderly parent, paid caregiver and two daughters visiting from far away.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Hana (whose name has been changed here) had entered the household as a background player four years earlier, a helper-for-hire who prepared meals and left a pot of soup on the stove "for later." Thanks to her, Dad's refrigerator, once barren save for a few take-out containers, brimmed with food of all colors. She drove him to his ever-more-frequent doctor appointments and called me with the reports. When the newspaper's weekly TV schedule arrived, she promptly marked the football games and movies she had come to know Dad would want to watch.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Soon, Hana's husband began spending afternoons at the house and making basic home repairs. When Dad entertained, the couple came as invited guests. And as he advanced into his 80s and entered a new reality of falls and memory lapses, Hana began bunking on the couch to see that he made it peacefully to morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk of assisted living was quickly extinguished because, after all, didn't everyone have a right to remain in his own damn home? Dad certainly did. Our family model was altered for good.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(MORE: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nextavenue.org/blog/your-loved-ones-caregiver-qualified" target="_hplink"&gt;Is Your Loved One's Caregiver Qualified?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Hana remained a mainstay, other helpers would eventually be needed to fill what became three full daily shifts. Caribbean and West African accents filled the house, along with attitudes ranging from loving commitment to visible resentment toward the work of keeping someone else's family alive. Small colonies of aides' shopping bags, filled with folded clothes, cropped up behind the furniture, subtly changing the look of our family home.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Speaking for Dad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point, "Do you want to talk to Hana?" became Dad's usual, and unsettling, first question when we called. Our birthday gifts arrived in the mail from stores he never visited, with &lt;em&gt;Love, Dad&lt;/em&gt;, penned in an unfamiliar cursive. For him, my visits, though still appreciated, lacked their former urgency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our requests that he get out of the house for a walk, see his doctor or visit friends annoyed him, so we learned to channel those suggestions through Hana. She alone convinced him to start using his walker, months after we'd purchased it. It was Hana who found a doctor that made house calls. As Dad grew more brittle, she filled his hours and offered us solace.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
And she alone stayed the course as my father's invective-filled rants drove less hardy aides from the house, their only sin having been trying to help. When yet another one quit, Hana, speaking like a knowing older sister, would say, "You know how your father is."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closing Accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember the days before Hana arrived. I could spend an hour struggling to help Dad traverse a city block, because the cane he insisted on using supported his worn out-body about as well as a matchstick. I remember how he'd look at me with such defeat when I'd say, "I need to go home now," at the end of an afternoon or weekend visit. There were doctors who could no longer speak to me about my father's condition because he had withdrawn consent. The visiting nurse service we'd arranged stopped coming because he refused the physical therapy and grooming assistance they prescribed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there were the police officers who would call to tell me that Dad had dialed 911 after falling once again. One had come by so frequently that he was able to remark that Dad had rearranged some of the furniture.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Someone recommended that we get off-the-books help -- this tall woman, Hana -- and my father approved. Dressed in designer slacks and knit jackets, she had an ambiance more Lord &amp; Taylor than Meals on Wheels. As a caregiver, she stood among the best, but I think Hana succeeded so well in Dad's universe because she had a way of making it clear that he was the head of the household.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No doubt, his giving her extra cash reinforced that impression.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(MORE:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.nextavenue.org/article/2012-04/how-protect-your-parents-financial-fraud" target="_hplink"&gt;How to Protect Your Parents From Financial Fraud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dad lived with a level of cognitive impairment that had not been fully diagnosed, in part because of his persistent resistance to having it formally checked. But legally, he was not mentally unsound. We did not have power of attorney and could not manage his finances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a surprise, then, when his bank called us to say Hana had attempted to cash a six-figure "gift" from my father. Earlier, Hana had told us she'd declined his offer to pay for her cancer-related surgery. In reality, she'd accepted the money. He'd wanted her to have it, she told me. Caring for him had been hard. She needed the operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bank froze Dad's account and alerted the police, but no criminal charges could be filed since there was no actual victim – my father was a willing participant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not long after this episode, his health rapidly declined. Finally, a hospice team arrived, taking the place of the regular caregivers. And yet even though we'd begun to sense the scope of our father's payouts to Hana and realized that her role in our lives had metastasized, we called her that last night to relieve the hospice aide so she could help us see him to the end. We needed her.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
After Dad's death, though, we changed the locks and hired a lawyer. Our accountant uncovered check after check, written by Hana, signed by my father and marked "Household." A few such checks one month eventually grew to dozens, representing tens of thousands of dollars as Dad's health failed. His willingness to sign his name, it seemed to me, coincided with an overwhelming need to be close to at least one human being who understood him.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;(MORE:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.nextavenue.org/blog/professional-caregivers-need-mourn-your-loved-one-too" target="_hplink"&gt;Professional Caregivers Need to Mourn Your Loved One, Too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memory of that hour Hana spent helping to ease us toward my father's death was still vivid as my sister and I sat in court a year later watching her testify in our civil suit that this check was a "bonus," that one "vacation pay," and so on. Here we were again: Dad's two adult daughters and the person who probably knew him best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, Hana paid us a small settlement to put the matter to rest. But before that, as our lawyers politely duked it out, the thought occurred to me that my father must have been laughing at his warring, sparring family for thinking we could actually outsource our love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more on Next Avenue&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nextavenue.org/article/2012-03/how-family-caregivers-can-find-and-hire-home-help" target="_hplink"&gt;How Family Caregivers Can Find and Hire at-Home Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nextavenue.org/article/2013-02/when-loved-one-you-cared-dies-what-comes-next" target="_hplink"&gt;When the Loved One You Cared For Dies, What Comes Next?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nextavenue.org/article/2012-06/building-network-look-out-your-parents" target="_hplink"&gt;Building a Network to Look Out for Your Parents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062467/thumbs/s-ELDER-ABUSE-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>PHOTOS: 17 Frighteningly Awkward Easter Photos</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/30/awkward-family-photos-easte_n_2985791.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2985791</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T23:54:32Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T15:01:56Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Christmas photos get a bad rap for being awkward, but families in pastel outfits at Easter brunch give those wearing ugly holiday sweaters a run...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Farah L. Miller</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/farah-l-miller/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/13/awkward-family-photos-holidays-christmas_n_2293623.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Christmas photos&lt;/a&gt; get a bad rap for being awkward, but families in pastel outfits at Easter brunch give those wearing &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/12/14/ugly-christmas-sweaters/" target="_hplink"&gt;ugly holiday sweaters&lt;/a&gt; a run for their money. Plus, as we already know, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/babies-not-impressed-easter-bunny_n_2979970.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents" target="_hplink"&gt;setting children on a giant bunny's lap&lt;/a&gt; is a recipe for picture disaster (or gold, depending on how you look at it). With that in mind, we bring back the annual Easter roundup from the guys at &lt;a href="http://www.AwkwardFamilyPhotos.com" target="_hplink"&gt;Awkward Family Photos&lt;/a&gt;. Enjoy the vintage fun, and have a happy holiday! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more awkwardness, visit &lt;a href="http://www.AwkwardFamilyPhotos.com" target="_hplink"&gt;AwkwardFamilyPhotos.com&lt;/a&gt; and get the new &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00BCMDWXM?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creativeASIN=B00BCMDWXM&amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;tag=awkwfamiphot-20" target="_hplink"&gt;Awkward Family Photos Frame Kit&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063599/thumbs/s-AWKWARD-EASTER-PHOTOS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: A Letter From The Easter Bunny's Biggest Supporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/30/cute-kid-note-of-the-day-dear-easter-bunny_n_2985863.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2985863</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T22:07:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T22:09:06Z</updated>
    
    <summary>We can only hope that today's cute kid note reaches its intended recipient, especially after the public shaming of E.B. that took place in 2012....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Farah L. Miller</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/farah-l-miller/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;We can only hope that today's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/kid-note-of-the-day" target="_hplink"&gt;cute kid note&lt;/a&gt; reaches its intended recipient, especially after &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/04/09/funny-dear-easter-bunny-letter-photo_n_1412199.html" target="_hplink"&gt;the public shaming of E.B.&lt;/a&gt; that took place in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; Dear Easter Bunny&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; Linus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Age:&lt;/strong&gt; 8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future occupation:&lt;/strong&gt; Motivational speaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subliminal message for the bunny:&lt;/strong&gt; "I want candy."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Child who could help Linus come up with a few more asks: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/06/cute-kid-note-of-the-day-dear-santa_n_2237847.html" target="_hplink"&gt;7-year-old Ella&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="katemckinneynote" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063601/thumbs/o-KATEMCKINNEYNOTE-570.jpg?15" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Has your child drawn or written something adorable? Send a photo, along with your child's name and age, to &lt;a href="mailto:kidnotes@huffingtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;kidnotes@huffingtonpost.com&lt;/a&gt; or via &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/huffpostparents" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/huffpostparents" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; -- and it may be featured as our &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/kid-note-of-the-day/" target="_hplink"&gt;Cute Kid Note of the Day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next Cute Kid Note of the Day: &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/cute-kid-note-of-the-day-joshuas-timeline_n_2958603.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Joshua's Amazing Timeline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063601/thumbs/s-KATEMCKINNEYNOTE-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>12 Sweet Names For Spring Babies</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/30/easter-baby-names-_n_2973029.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2973029</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T20:00:05Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T20:00:08Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Written by Linda Rosenkrantz for Nameberry Easter-themed baby names can spring from all sorts of sources. These range from those that are related to the...</summary>
    <author>
        <name/>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nina-zipkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Linda Rosenkrantz for &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Nameberry &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easter-themed baby names can spring from all sorts of sources. These range from those that are related to the name and time of the holiday itself in English and in other languages, to relevant Biblical characters, to symbolic animals and trees and flowers -- and even to a classic movie musical celebrating the holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Nameberry&lt;/a&gt; picks of the names leading the &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Easter" target="_hplink"&gt;Easter&lt;/a&gt; parade, some as obvious as &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Lily " target="_hplink"&gt;Lily&lt;/a&gt;, others as oblique as a Hollywood hoofer.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061265/thumbs/s-EASTER-BABY-NAMES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Parenting Bubbles That Unite And Divide Us</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/30/parenting-memories-parent-bubbles_n_2985051.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2985051</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T18:34:25Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T12:55:22Z</updated>
    
    <summary>“It has been a long week,” my friend said, her tone full of a meaning I couldn’t put my finger on at first. She was...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Lisa Belkin</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-belkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;“It has been a long week,” my friend said, her tone full of a meaning I couldn’t put my finger on at first. She was waiting for me to ask ... something? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh yes, college acceptances. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year at this time I could have told you the exact dates that every top tier school sent out their admissions decisions. I knew which used actual thin and thick envelopes and which sent their news online. I had a pretty good handle on the predicted acceptance rates of a dozen or more college, along with who in my extended circle were waiting to hear from each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, I forgot about admissions entirely. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much of parenting is like that -- you are immersed, defined, all-encompassed ... and then ... you’re not. Every stage (every &lt;em&gt;day&lt;/em&gt;) of raising children is its own isolated bubble. You can see others, but you are on your own. Sleep training. Potty training. Toddler tantrums. Homework. Teen angst. Everything feels like no one has ever really done this before. And once one stage ends, you can’t reinhabit the obsessions that came with it. You can remember and share tales. And smile knowingly, even empathetically. But you can’t go back to the place when a parenting challenge was new, and insistent and yours. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had an inkling of this before my children were born. I would drive past the school parking lot, filled to overflowing, and realize that, for some of my neighbors, it was parent-teacher night, or the science fair or graduation, while for me it was just Tuesday. We lived in the same town, but in parallel villages -- side-by-side yet invisible to each other. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s why bridal magazines run the same features month after month, and why parenting blogs revisit the same themes in essays that have a hungry new audience every time. When you are primed to notice, then everything is a revelation, a personal message. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in that moment, you burrow in completely. It changes you, yes, and leaves traces and footprints. But it does not become the whole of you. You think it will -- you can’t imagine that there is anything beyond this point in time, this all encompassing feeling, or juggle, or uncertainty or joy, just as you don’t clearly remember what came before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know there was a time when you were not yet the parent-of-a-child-at-this-crystallized-instant-of-life. You can  &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; that past, through the incandescent walls of your bubble and the haze of time and memory, but you can no longer &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This conundrum both enhances and diminishes the advice mothers and fathers give each other. I worry, when I write about parenting and when I lend an ear to friends, that I sound distant. I am speaking of "then" when they are standing in "now." But then I remember the advice I got when I was on the other side, and think that maybe that’s what made it most valuable -- the unspoken message that “this too shall pass, this will become a chapter, a memory, a data point a tale ….” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what happens when our bubbles are like armor? Are the thin walls between us what all the so-called Mommy Wars are about? We see each other and we think we understand each other, but we are in spheres that do not touch. Are the bubbles also why parents never rise up as a movement and demand what they need -- better childcare, more generous parental leave, more flexible work environments -- because when we are in the moment we are too busy and exhausted, and when we are past it, the urgency is gone? It is definitely why so much remarkable change comes from parents who become advocates -- for gun control, for research into diseases that steal childhoods -- because theirs are bubbles that never set them free.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us, though, move from one unforgettable beat to the next, remembering, but not fully, as we go. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I forgot how to do my Mommy Bounce,” our HuffPost Parents editor, Farah Miller, told me the other day, after holding a colleague’s 7-week-old. Time was when that was instinct, seemingly indelible, but now her own baby is 3-years-old and what she’ll never forget is potty training and last night’s bedtime tantrum. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until she does. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063515/thumbs/s-LISAGELBNOTFORREUSE-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Marie Osmond Backs Gay Marriage: 'I Don't Think God Made One Color Flower, I Think He Made Many'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/30/marie-osmond-gay-marriage_n_2985060.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2985060</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T17:37:28Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T14:58:54Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Marie Osmond subtly re-affirmed her support of marriage equality in a poignant new interview. The singer-actress, who is currently promoting her new memoir The Key...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Curtis M. Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/curtis-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Marie Osmond subtly re-affirmed her support of marriage equality in a poignant new interview. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The singer-actress, who is currently promoting &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Key-Love-Daughters-Gratitude/dp/0451240316/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1364664832&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=Marie+Osmond" target="_hplink"&gt;her new memoir&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Key Is Love: My Mother's Wisdom, A Daughter's Gratitude&lt;/em&gt;, spoke frankly about her daughter Jessica, who is openly gay. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The God that I believe in is a god of love, not fear," Osmond, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2010/03/10/marie-osmond-my-mormon-fa_n_492950.html" target="_hplink"&gt;who is a practicing Mormon&lt;/a&gt;, told Diane Sawyer.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for same-sex marriage, Osmond noted, "I believe in [my daughter's] civil rights, as a mother. I think that my daughter deserves everything that she desires in life. She's a good girl. She's a wonderful child." She then added, "I don't think God made one color flower. I think He made many." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Osmond, 53, &lt;a href="http://www.towleroad.com/2009/05/marie-osmond-on-gay-rights-and-her-lesbian-daughter.html" target="_hplink"&gt;has spoken out in support&lt;/a&gt; of lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender rights in previous years, usually citing Jessica's role in that mindset. "I think everybody should have the right to share homes and finances with somebody that they care about," she told &lt;a href="http://www.kost1035.com/main.html" target="_hplink"&gt;KOST 103.5 Los Angeles&lt;/a&gt; in 2009. "You know on those types of things I'm very supportive. When it comes to marriage...I think that civil rights need to be for all." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Osmond's brother Alan reportedly hosted a "pro-family" rally at the Utah State Capitol earlier this week, aimed at "benefitting the protection of marriage" from gay and lesbian Americans, &lt;a href="http://www.towleroad.com/2013/03/osmond-family-hosting-hate-rally-at-utah-capitol.html" target="_hplink"&gt;according to Towleroad&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063463/thumbs/s-MARIE-OSMOND-GAY-MARRIAGE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Our Favorite Tweets From Parents This Week</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/30/best-parenting-tweets_n_2981277.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2981277</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T17:23:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T17:25:45Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It's always fun -- and a little bit scary -- to show off your former life as a non-parent to your children. Whether you're sharing...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Samakow</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-samakow/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;It's always fun -- and a little bit scary -- to show off your former life as a non-parent to your children. Whether you're sharing school pictures or the wedding album, it's amazing to see what kids think of Mommy and Daddy before they &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; Mommy and Daddy. So what if one of piece of your history was appearing as the ultimate teen heroine in possibly the most classic 80s movie ever? &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MollyRingwald/status/317136255781568512" target="_hplink"&gt;Molly Ringwald answered that question for us&lt;/a&gt; this week when she tweeted, "Showing 'Pretty in Pink' to my nine year old for the first time. She's 'Team Duckie.'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, we could stop right there and call our beloved brat-packer's statement &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; parenting tweet of the week, but many moms and dads were in top form on Twitter, thanks in part to Easter planning. Click through the gallery below to see our favorite quips and make sure to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostParents" target="_hplink"&gt;follow @HuffPostParents&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063259/thumbs/s-BEST-PARENTING-TWEETS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
