<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jemma Wayne: Mother Judgement: How Women Are Undermining Modern Feminism</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/jemma-wayne/women-undermining-modern-feminism_b_3006752.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3006752</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T23:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T17:08:46Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There is a quieter, yet just as dangerous trend undermining feminist values, and this trend is being perpetrated most, by women. The arena: online forums, Facebook groups, press articles, NCT circles, even groups of friends. The reason: Mother Judgement - the war between those who do and those who don't.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jemma Wayne</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jemma-wayne/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;The National Union of Teachers is this week warning that sexism is being rebranded and young people damaged by an over-sexualised culture. This is far from news. Highly sexualised images blast every day out of shop windows, from billboards, on buses. You can be the most diligent censor of your child's media, but unless you never leave your home, it's impossible to shelter them from such objectification. These are insidious attacks on a child's developing identity, and a very public failure of modern feminism. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is however a quieter, yet just as dangerous trend undermining other feminist values, and this trend is being perpetrated most, by women. The arena: online forums, Facebook groups, press articles, NCT circles, even groups of friends. The reason: Mother Judgement - the war between those who do and those who don't. Those who do breastfeed. Those who do go out to work. Those who do co-sleep. Those who do controlled crying. Those who do buy food in a jar. The arguments are both large and small, but equally volatile and the result: the continued branding of women. At a time in life when women are often most looking for community, reassurance and support, many are instead resorting to judgement and labelling. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contradictory media 'advice' never helps. But mothering forums in particular reveal how quick we can be to condemn another woman's choices, 'choice' being the foundation of feminism. This is not to negate the sage advice and absolute lifeline that some sites offer. But an innocently posted question can quickly spiral into all-out combat: "How long should I leave my 6month-old to Cry It Out?" - the response, a dozen or so CIO cheerleaders before a tentative suggestion to er, not let the baby CIO, followed by unmitigated fury. "Has anyone split the MMR?" - a near violent crusade against those irresponsible enough not to do exactly what the NHS says exactly when and how they say it. And even, believe it or not, "Does anyone want a nearly-new Disney Princess colouring book?" - an assault on parents who project dangerous gender stereotypes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within what is intended to be a supportive environment, at the speed of a click we berate and criticise and condemn. Why? Do we really care that passionately how another mother chooses to parent her child? Are we so insecure that we have to - vocally and publicly - justify are own choices? Or perhaps it's a rudimentary allegiance to the 'team' we've picked, like boys and football.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the reason, the great tragedy is that with every wagging finger we are unravelling the victories of feminism in the most intimate arena of womanhood. We are denying choice. And whether the idealised images we are each trying to fulfil are stay-at-home Earth Mama, or do-it-all Super Mum, we are once again projecting onto each other unrealistic and unhelpful ideas about what constitutes a 'good mother', a 'good woman', a woman. Rather than accepting differing choices as merely that, it is as though by validating another woman's decisions, we are branding our own as failures. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is telling is that while the individual issues are infinite, increasingly they seem to divide two distinct camps: Attachment Parents versus Babywise Parents. For those unfamiliar, in (very simplistic) terms, Attachment parents value emotional responsiveness and are led by the child, while Babywise parents value routine and direct the child. It is admittedly too crude an analysis, but many of the hot issues (breastfeeding, controlled crying, co-sleeping) favour either a decision to be led by the child's needs, or by the woman's own, and often what this boils down to (or is prompted by) is the choice either to stay at home or return to work. Thus, the content of condemnation may have moved on - the judgement today most certainly flows both ways - but we have nevertheless returned to a climate in which a woman's 'place' is too often viewed as right or wrong, good or bad. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet one of the biggest challenges for every mother is exactly this balance. A delicate juggling act between one's role as a mother, and one's identity as an individual entity. Different women weight the scales in very different proportions. But this balance, and the right to create it, is fundamental to modern feminism. How to achieve it, perhaps the biggest issue today's women face. The question is no longer whether we can excel in the workplace - we have long ago proven we can and we do. Now the question is how we choose to balance this against the other fundamental aspects of womanhood. Aspects that have been negated for too long. Because there is no getting away from the fact that for most women, the private and public spheres are not distinct, and will at some point collide. &lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
Today, being able to choose whether or not to work is not enough of a choice. Real choice would be being able to work and mother without having to make unacceptable compromises in either sphere. Compromises that lead to guilt and anger - and judgement. But for this to ever be realised, there must be a revolution in the workplace: greater childcare provided affordably and onsite (enabling women, if they choose, to breastfeed and work); more flexibility with part-time employment; hours that reflect children's needs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women are no longer a disenfranchised gender. We are politicians, editors, designers, educators. We have the power to affect change, be it by adding clothes to a billboard or pushing for childcare reform. These are the battles that are the next stage in the evolution of feminism. To win them, this is where we must focus our fury; resisting distracting disputes amongst ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/707434/thumbs/s-FEMINISME-mini.jpg?9" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How FLOTUS Is Getting Ready For Spring</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/04/michelle-obama-white-house-garden_n_3016764.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3016764</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T19:55:42Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T20:33:26Z</updated>
    
    <summary>WASHINGTON &amp;mdash; Salad using lettuce from Michelle Obama's garden could be served up in just a few weeks. The first lady on Thursday planted lettuce...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/michelle-manetti/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON &amp;mdash; Salad using lettuce from Michelle Obama's garden could be served up in just a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first lady on Thursday planted lettuce and other crops in her garden on the South Lawn of the White House, with an assist from schoolchildren from Washington, D.C., and several school districts around the country.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Two varieties of wheat were planted for the first time: club wheat and bread wheat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lettuce should be ready in a couple of weeks. The wheat will need until at least July to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other crops now growing in the garden are spinach, kale, Swiss chard, endive, potatoes, radishes, garlic, fennel, broccoli, cauliflower, collard greens and herbs, along with raspberries, blueberries, strawberries and an apple tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Are you ready to go?" the first lady asked the kids after she met them at the garden on a crisp, sunny afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students who attend school in Bradenton, Fla., Somerville, Mass., Knox County, Tenn., and Milton, Vt., were invited, she said, because their districts are doing "such wonderful things" to put in place new federal nutrition standards for school lunches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first lady personally planted rows of wheat, spinach and kale, with help from a few students. Other students planted the remaining crops, with an assist from White House staff members. Also helping were military veterans in training for careers in sustainable agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mrs. Obama planted the garden in 2009 to help launch her campaign against childhood obesity and encourage healthier eating. She says involving children in the growing of fruits and vegetables makes it more likely that they will eat them, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The garden so far has produced more than 3,000 pounds of food. The White House gives some to a local soup kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;___&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow Darlene Superville on Twitter: &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/dsupervilleap"&gt;http://www.twitter.com/dsupervilleap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1071299/thumbs/s-MICHELLE-OBAMA-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Anti-Bullying Plea Packs Viral Wallop</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/04/dad-bullying-facebook-wisconsin_n_3012613.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3012613</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T19:37:59Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T19:52:45Z</updated>
    
    <summary>His son said he was being bullied at middle school, so Matthew Bent fought back on Facebook. Now, the Kaukauna, Wisc., dad's post to end...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ron-dicker/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;His son said he was being bullied at middle school, so Matthew Bent fought back on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the Kaukauna, Wisc., dad's &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=4714199776188&amp;set=a.1374294600646.2044380.1330251396&amp;type=1" target="_hplink"&gt;post to end school bullying&lt;/a&gt; everywhere has attracted hundreds of thousands of readers. Some had their own stories to tell; others applauded Bent's peaceful approach to a national problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bent told The Huffington Post on Thursday that the response has been "a complete surprise." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said his son had endured a year of torment that recently came to a head when a bully took the boy's shoes during gym class. Then, one of the bully's friends threw a shoe at Bent's son, hitting him in the groin and forcing him to the ground. According to Bent, his son's main antagonizer came over and pretended to offer a hand, but instead body-slammed the child several times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A school police officer interviewed Bent's son and the other three students supposedly involved, but the incident was dismissed as horseplay, Bent said. The officer told the father the case was closed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last straw came when the principal didn't return Bent's call to protest. On March 26, Bent went ahead and posted a photo of himself and his son with a sign accusing the school district of ignoring the problem. He urged others to pass along the photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Story continues below.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="dad bullying facebook" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1070681/original.jpg" /&gt; &lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Credit: Matthew Bent, Facebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Facebook, he added the following text: &lt;blockquote&gt;Please share and send a message to every school district that protecting bullies and doing nothing about their actions is wrong!! My son has been bullied all school year by this group of thugs, and not 1 teacher, administrator, councillor or officer will do anything to make it stop, they only offer excuses and blame the victims!!! Please help me in the effort to stop bullying!!!&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superintendent Mark Duerwaechter told Green Bay-based news outlet WFRV that the district &lt;a href="http://wearegreenbay.com/fulltext?nxd_id=187142" target="_hplink"&gt;"does not protect bullies"&lt;/a&gt; and is committed to handling unresolved cases. Bent told HuffPost that officials appear to be following through on his son's  case. "We're making progress," he said. "Time will tell. The school is stepping up and doing a good job so far."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the local police, Bent is still fuming at what he perceives to be an inadequate response. But in a recent press conference, posted by Green Bay's Fox 11, Kaukauna Police Chief John Manion &lt;a href="http://www.fox11online.com/dpp/news/local/fox_cities/kaukauna-police-dept-news-conference-on-bullying" target="_hplink"&gt;chided the Facebook community for jumping to conclusions&lt;/a&gt;. The chief acknowledged that Bent's son had the breath knocked out of him but said the boy had voluntarily engaged in wrestling. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson for the police department was not immediately available for comment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bent said his son was not seriously hurt in the incident and pointed out that many victims are not so fortunate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href="http://www.dailydot.com/society/dad-song-bully-facebook-message-bent/" target="_hplink"&gt;Hat tip, Daily Dot&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1070681/thumbs/s-DAD-BULLYING-FACEBOOK-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Cooper Smith Koch: HelpUsAdopt.org Seeks LGBT Applicants For Adoption-Assistance Grants</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/cooper-smith-koch/helpusadoptorg-seeks-lgbt-applicants-for-adoption-assistance-grants_b_3001591.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3001591</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T19:32:50Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T19:32:54Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Through HelpUsAdopt.org Becky Fawcett gives out grants up to $15,000 to help families with the expenses associated with adopting children, and she wants more gays and lesbians to apply. "It drives me crazy that we don't get more LGBT grant applications," Becky wrote to me.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Cooper Smith Koch</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/cooper-smith-koch/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Recently my friend Johnnie introduced me to a woman whom I think every family considering adoption should know, especially gays and lesbians who want to be parents. I certainly wish Todd and I had known her four years ago when we adopted our two kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Yorker Becky Fawcett is on a mission to help as many people as possible afford to adopt, and her vision of family is all-inclusive. Through &lt;a href="http://HelpUsAdopt.org" target="_hplink"&gt;HelpUsAdopt.org&lt;/a&gt;, the nonprofit organization she started five years ago, she helps give out individual grants up to $15,000 to help families with the expenses associated with adopting children. They've helped 73 families so far, to the tune of about $570,000, with the goal of increasing their gifts to $200,000 each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becky wants more gays and lesbians to apply. Currently, of the approximately 400 applications her organization receives each semiannual cycle, only about 10 to 12 are from gays and lesbians. She wants that number to hit 50 this year, and even more in future years. The deadline to apply for the next cycle of grants is Friday, April 12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It drives me crazy that we don't get more LGBT grant applications," Becky wrote to me a few weeks ago in an email. "WHY??? WHY???" This prompted me to jump on the phone with her to learn more about HelpUsAdopt.org and its work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becky told me about her many costly attempts to get pregnant through various fertility treatments, all of which ended in miscarriages -- and $85,000 in expenses. Down to their last bit of savings, she and her husband Kipp decided that they needed to consider adoption. Nearly four years after they started trying to have a child, they brought home a baby boy, followed four years later by a newborn girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After her own ordeal, Becky looked for a way to help other families pay for adoption, but she found that all the organizations had criteria that restricted their grants to straight, married couples, specifically excluding gays and lesbians, as well as single straight people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I don't believe in defining family, so I told my husband, 'I can't give a nickel or the time of day to these groups,'" she told me. "That's not how my brain works. I couldn't give any money or support to any of those organizations."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to not limiting its grants to certain types of relationships, HelpUsAdopt.org also supports all types of adoptions. According to Becky, there are no other adoption grants that fulfill such an inclusive list of criteria. Also, their grants don't require application fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We strive to give larger, life-changing, problem-solving grants that put children in homes. We are pure help, with no fees or strings attached, for families of all kinds," Becky told me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know firsthand how expensive it can be to adopt. If you ask around, you'll hear that average domestic adoption in America is estimated to cost about $35,000 to $40,000, give or take some change. And that doesn't include travel expenses, meals while away from home and the like. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"A lot of people live a very nice life but don't have a $40,000 to $50,000 lump sum at their disposal," Becky said. "I didn't plan on being infertile! We save up for homes and weddings, but for most people, you don't think to save up for adoption."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Full details and online application can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.helpusadopt.org" target="_hplink"&gt;HelpUsAdopt.org&lt;/a&gt;. The deadline for applying for the organization's June grants is Friday, April 12, 2013.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1071224/thumbs/s-GAY-ADOPTION-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Win Bassett: Millennials Shift Seder Focus From Freedom to Family</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/win-bassett/millennials-shift-seder-focus-from-freedom-to-family_b_3015138.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3015138</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T18:47:26Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T19:50:43Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Like its counterparts of the synagogue and the halakha, the Passover meal observed today may not be so traditional. It is now steeped in a different tradition -- doctrine is out, and family is in.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Win Bassett</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/win-bassett/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;It's no secret that religious affiliation within the United States has been &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2013/01/14/169164840/losing-our-religion-the-growth-of-the-nones"&gt;declining&lt;/a&gt;, especially in the last two decades. Between the rise of the "&lt;a href="http://www.pewforum.org/Unaffiliated/nones-on-the-rise.aspx"&gt;nones&lt;/a&gt;" and the "spiritual but not religious" crowd, one-fifth of American adults now claim no affiliation with a particular religion, &lt;a href="http://www.pewforum.org/Unaffiliated/nones-on-the-rise.aspx"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href="http://www.pewforum.org"&gt;Pew Research Center&lt;/a&gt;. The numbers for those under the age of thirty are even more remarkable-one in three don't identify with a religion. In fact, "[y]oung people today are not only more religiously unaffiliated than their elders; they are also more religiously unaffiliated than previous generations of young people ever have been as far back as we can tell," Greg Smith, a senior research at Pew, &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2013/01/14/169164840/losing-our-religion-the-growth-of-the-nones"&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org"&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-04-04-family_haggadah.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-04-04-family_haggadah.jpg" width="350" height="350" style="float: right; margin:10px" /&gt;And the practices of those that still happen to claim one of the religions polled also reflect the waning of membership. Of the estimated &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2013/01/14/169164840/losing-our-religion-the-growth-of-the-nones"&gt;6 million Jews&lt;/a&gt; in the United States, "nearly 70% ... attend a Seder, compared to the 25% who pray regularly at a synagogue or observe dietary laws in their homes," according to the &lt;a href="http://www.jewishfederations.org/"&gt;Jewish Federations of North America&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887324373204578374391890158564.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Traditional observations and exercises, notably participating in activities at an official place of worship or in a congregational setting, are out, and holidays are in. "The Seder is among the few religious rituals most American Jews still embrace,"	the &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887324373204578374391890158564.html"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; reports. Nonetheless, like its counterparts of the synagogue and the &lt;a href="http://www.jewfaq.org/halakhah.htm"&gt;halakha&lt;/a&gt;, even the Seder observed today may not be so traditional. Or rather, the freedom feast during Passover is now steeped in a different tradition -- doctrine is out, and family is in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Our practice is more reformed and more family-oriented than synagogue-oriented," says Matt Steinberg, a 35-year-old systems engineer and brewery founder from Pompton Lakes, N.J. But it hasn't always been this way. His father came from a kosher, Orthodox home in Brooklyn, and his mother, formerly Protestant, converted to Judaism when she married his father. As a child, Steinberg had Seder each year at his parents' house or his uncle's house, and his grandfather typically led the celebration. "We would go to synagogue as a family as well," he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after his grandfather passed away, however, his family stopped going to synagogue. Today, "we still do more or less the same family Seder," Steinberg says, with one change. "It's usually held on whatever weekend falls during Passover as it's much easier on the working and traveling family members." But he doesn't mind this break from the conventional date. "I think each Seder and each tradition is unique to the family and should be as such. I believe in maintaining family tradition even if it's something non-traditional," Steinberg says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah Annese, a 26-year-old freelance writer in Brooklyn, knows all about the non-traditional family Seder. "My great-uncle&amp;#8230;would look at his watch at the beginning of the Seder and keep the time so it would be as short and efficient as possible," she explains. "We've gotten the Seder time down to around 18 minutes, 15 if we're extremely efficient and no one stops to crack jokes." This rarely happens, however. "After we're finished with all the plagues, my dad and great uncle will always add a few more modern struggles," says Annese. " 'Negative cash flow,' 'Pain-in-the-ass clients,' 'George Bush.' "&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And like Steinberg, she celebrates the non-traditional nature of her Seder practice because it brings her family together. "Traditions are traditions, and if something 'non-traditional' is important to the way people come together and celebrate a holiday, then great," Annese says. "Jewish holidays are important to me not for the religious significance so much as for coming together, laughing, and eating as a family."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Modell, a 32-year-old attorney from Arlington, Va., stopped celebrating Seder during his years as an undergraduate because he attended an out-of-state college, and he didn't have any Jewish friends in his new city. He found himself in a similar situation in law school but celebrated Seder again this year. Modell's family served as the catalyst for the event. "There have been a few years where the whole family happens to be together, and in those years, we will have Seder," he says. This year was one of those years. "I was on vacation in Ft. Lauderdale during Passover, and I have family in Boca Raton. What Jew doesn't?" he adds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modell says his uncle, a rabbi, led them this year in a "surprisingly less formal and shorter" Seder to which he was accustomed. And in 2010, he celebrated Seder "on small TV trays in my apartment" when his family happened to be in Elizabeth City, N.C., during Modell's stint as a judicial clerk. He describes himself as "a traditionalist when it comes to these things," but he has begun to embrace the shorter Seder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trent Gillis, Senior Editor of &lt;a href="http://americanpublicmedia.publicradio.org/"&gt;American Public Media&lt;/a&gt;'s	&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.onbeing.org/"&gt;On Being&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, describes a similar acceptance of changing traditions. In discussing the overlap of Passover and Holy Week this year, he &lt;a href="http://www.onbeing.org/blog/sacred-seasons-overlap-and-create-space-for-renewing-our-narratives/5191"&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt; "that history isn't something merely to be memorized, but that these cargo of hidden stories come alive when they are made anew and transcend time." And in the case of those born in the early 1980s to the early 2000s, family appears to make this transcendence possible. Jess Rainer, co-author of "&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Millennials-Connecting-Americas-Largest-Generation/dp/1433670038"&gt;The Millennials: Connecting to America's Largest Generation&lt;/a&gt;," feels similarly. "Unlike earlier generations, Millennials prioritize relationships, especially family, over religion," she &lt;a href="http://www.religionnews.com/2013/03/29/for-many-holy-days-have-become-family-holidays/"&gt;says&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Pot Legalization Wins Majority Support Nationwide</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/04/marijuana-legalization-poll-2013_n_3015813.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3015813</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T18:15:52Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T19:05:37Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A national Pew Research Center poll released Thursday shows the majority of Americans support pot legalization 52 percent to 45 percent, with 72 percent who...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Lucia Graves</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lucia-graves/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;A national &lt;a href="http://www.people-press.org/2013/04/04/majority-now-supports-legalizing-marijuana/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pew Research Center poll released Thursday&lt;/a&gt; shows the majority of Americans support pot legalization 52 percent to 45 percent, with 72 percent who say that the cost of federal law enforcement efforts are not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results mark the first time in more than four decades of Pew's polling that a majority has taken that position. As recently as a decade ago, only about one-third of American adults backed making marijuana legal. Support for legalizing pot is up 11 points since 2010, the most dramatic change since the late 1960s, according to pollsters. A Gallup survey conducted in 1969 found only 12 percent favored legalizing marijuana use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest poll also found the percentage of people who say they have used marijuana in the past year (roughly 1 in 10) or at any point in their lives (roughly half) is virtually identical in states that have legalized some marijuana use and those that have not, suggesting that more liberal laws have simply made usage more visible, not increased it, as some have feared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The numbers are driven in part by an apparent shift in how baby boomers feel about the drug of their youth. The poll found most Americans don't see marijuana as a "gateway" to more dangerous drugs anymore, and the majority no longer see use as immoral. Half of Americans said use was immoral as recently as 2006 -- now that number has dropped to a third, while half say that marijuana usage is "not a moral issue."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's time for politicians to catch up to the voters on this issue," said &lt;a href="http://MarijuanaMajority.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Marijuana Majority&lt;/a&gt; spokesman Tom Angell. "Not too long ago, it was widely accepted in political circles that elected officials who wanted to get reelected needed to act 'tough' on drugs and go out of their way to support the continued criminalization of marijuana. The opposite is quickly becoming true. A majority of Americans support legalizing marijuana, and you're going to start seeing more politicians running toward our movement instead of away from it, just as we've seen happen with marriage equality recently."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poll's most marked divisions are by age, with younger Americans being significantly more likely to support legalization than older Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parenthood also appears to be a significant indicator. Among respondents between the ages of 30 and 49, parents are much less likely to support legalization than non-parents. Parents with school-aged children at home were closely divided on the issue, while those without children at home support pot legalization by 62 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pew poll was conducted March 13 to March 17 by telephone among 1,501 American adults. The margin of error is 2.9 percentage points.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1070938/thumbs/s-MARIJUANA-LEGALIZATION-POLL-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>INFOGRAPHIC: 1 In 5 Teen Moms Give Birth Again By 20</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/04/repeat-teen-pregnancies_n_3014685.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3014685</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T18:00:31Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T18:07:13Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Of the four mothers on MTV's reality show "Teen Mom 2," three have gotten pregnant for a second time since the show first aired. Though...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Samakow</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-samakow/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Of the four mothers on MTV's reality show "Teen Mom 2," three have &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/16/jenelle-evans-pregnant-teen-mom-2_n_2487987.html" target="_hplink"&gt;gotten pregnant for a second time&lt;/a&gt; since the show first aired. Though their repeat pregnancies &lt;a href="http://jezebel.com/5992476/why-do-teen-mom-stars-keep-having-more-babies" target="_hplink"&gt;might seem unusual&lt;/a&gt;, a new report from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shows that &lt;a href="http://www.cdc.gov/vitalsigns/TeenPregnancy/index.html" target="_hplink"&gt;teen mothers with multiple children are not that uncommon&lt;/a&gt;. Nearly one-fifth of teen moms gives birth to a second child by the time they turn 20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the 365,000 girls, ages 15â€“19, who gave birth in 2010, almost 20 percent already had at least one child. Of that 20 percent, most girls (86 percent) were delivering their second child while 13 percent welcomed their third.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data shows that young women are using birth control -- 91 percent of sexually active teen mothers used it.  However, only 22 percent used the most effective types including hormonal implants and IUDs. Methods like the pill and condoms are considered less effective (the chart below indicates which birth control methods were more likely to reduce the risk of pregnancy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"What that's telling us is nearly all teen moms want to avoid pregnancy and are taking steps to avoid a repeat pregnancy. But the challenge is only one in five are using the most effective means of doing that," &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2013/04/02/teen-births-repeat/2047519/" target="_hplink"&gt;CDC Director Tom Frieden told USA Today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CDC recommends ways the government, parents, health care professionals and teens &lt;a href="http://www.cdc.gov/vitalsigns/TeenPregnancy/index.html" target="_hplink"&gt;can prevent unwanted repeat pregnancies&lt;/a&gt;. Their report states that &lt;a href="http://www.cdc.gov/teenpregnancy/parents.htm" target="_hplink"&gt;parents should talk to teens&lt;/a&gt; about avoiding pregnancy, check with insurers about birth control coverage and and discuss effective programs with community leaders. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="graphic1" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1070697/original.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="graphic2_980px" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1070701/original.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="graphic3_980px" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1070704/original.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1070839/thumbs/s-REPEAT-TEEN-PREGNANCIES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Earl Martin Phalen: The Importance of Parental Involvement in Schools</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/earl-martin-phalen/the-importance-of-parenta_b_3010545.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3010545</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T17:44:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T17:44:44Z</updated>
    
    <summary>According to a PBS report, close to one million American children drop out of school every year. In light of the staggering rate and our current crisis, it is important parents are involved in their children's education early.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Earl Martin Phalen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/earl-martin-phalen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;According to a PBS report, close to &lt;a href="http://http://www.pbs.org/newshour/bb/education/july-dec12/dropouts_09-24.html" target="_hplink"&gt;one million &lt;/a&gt;American children drop out of school every year. In light of the staggering rate and our current crisis, it is important parents are involved in their children's education early. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat down with Principal Jeremy Baugh to discuss the impact of parental involvement. Baugh has a Master of Science in School Administration from Butler University and was the Principal of Mill Creek West Elementary School in Amo, Indiana for seven years. In his role as principal, Mr. Baugh implemented building-level change that led to major school improvement.  He specifically developed a school-wide focus on data analysis and usage, including a tiered intervention model for math and reading.  High parental involvement was also a key factor in his school's success. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-04-04-JeremyBaugh22613.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-04-04-JeremyBaugh22613.jpg" width="308" height="208" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Principal Jeremy Baugh  (Courtesy of Phalen Leadership Academies)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the fall of 2013, Principal Baugh will lead the inaugural year of the George and Veronica Phalen Leadership Academies, which will provide a high quality academic blended learning curriculum to children in Indianapolis. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earl&lt;/strong&gt;: In light of the current drop out crisis, why do you think it's important for parents to get involved in the elementary education of their children? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principal Baugh:&lt;/strong&gt; A child's elementary education is the foundation of a solid, life-long education. Since parents are the first educators in a child's life, it is essential for parents and school staff to ensure a high quality, rigorous education so that opportunities abound in the future without hurdles of difficulty and struggles in school. Without a partnership between families and the school, parents miss out on vital sharing of information about a child's academic strengths and challenges.  Parents are the number one advocate for their child.  A parent is the key for information sharing between grade-levels, various schools, and from teacher to teacher.  When a parent takes an active role in their child's education the child understands that education is important to their family.  &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earl&lt;/strong&gt;: What steps can parents take to be more involved in their child's school?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principal Baugh&lt;/strong&gt;:  Simple steps include attending parent meetings, open houses, parent/teacher conferences, Parent Teacher Organization meetings (PTO).  I would also recommend that parents sign up to volunteer in their child's classroom at least once per week.  Volunteering could include: working as a facilitator of small group instruction, tutoring a student, or reading with an individual or small group.  For parents who are not able to volunteer during the school day, I would recommend some of the following opportunities: make copies for your child's teacher, cut out and prepare lesson material from home, make flash cards, ensure that your child has a consistent study routine at home.  Additionally parents should email or call their child's teacher frequently, weekly is best, in order to stay on top their child's progress in class.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-04-04-PLAMathandSciencePic.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-04-04-PLAMathandSciencePic.jpg" width="460" height="170" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Courtesy of Phalen Leadership Academies)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earl: In terms of the parent-school relationship, how might a charter school be a better fit for some parents? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Principal Baugh:  Charter schools cater to the needs of scholars and families.  Families choose to attend charter schools, and therefore it is essential that schools constantly monitor the effectiveness of instruction, and parent/family satisfaction.  Charter schools also cater to working families by offering extended school days (8 a.m. - 4:00 p.m. at PLA), an extended school year (200 days vs. 180 days at PLA), and summer enrichment (25 days of Summer Advantage USA at PLA).  For these reasons, I believe that parents might find charter schools to be a better fit for their families.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earl&lt;/strong&gt;: Do you have any advice for parents of children who may be struggling in school? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principal Baugh&lt;/strong&gt;:  Parents need to find out what the critical issues are with their child.  Parents should request a meeting with their child's teacher as soon as possible.  They should also be specific in their request.  Ask for two or three skills that they can work on at home to improve.  Working on more than two to three goals is often not effective in meeting the needs of scholars.  Request a meeting with the school's Response to Intervention (RTI) Team in order to develop a plan for placing their child back on track.  Parents should expect additional support from staff at school as well as additional work and practice for their child at home.  Finally, parents should establish a regular study routine at home.  This routine should include math fact and sight word practice, as well as fifteen minutes of reading per night on text that is at or above grade level.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information and resources: &lt;a href="http://www.pbs.org/parents/education/" target="_hplink"&gt;PBS Parents&lt;/a&gt;, Phalen Leadership Academies, and &lt;a href="http://kids.usa.gov/grown-ups/for-parents/get-involved/index.shtml" target="_hplink"&gt;Parents Get Involved&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1032330/thumbs/s-SEQUESTER-SPECIAL-EDUCATION-CUTS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Brad Garrett &amp; Elizabeth Perkins: Those 'Parents' You've Always Wanted</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/2013/04/04/how-to-live-with-parents-brad-garrett-elizabeth-perkins-interview_n_3015139.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3015139</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T17:44:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T17:44:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Dysfunctional families and embarrassing parents have always made for prime sitcom fodder, but for "How to Live with Your Parents (For the Rest of Your...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>HuffPost Canada TV</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/chris-jancelewicz/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Dysfunctional families and embarrassing parents have always made for prime sitcom fodder, but for "&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/04/how-to-live-with-your-parents-premiere-video_n_3011918.html" target="_hplink"&gt;How to Live with Your Parents (For the Rest of Your Life)&lt;/a&gt;"creator &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/claudia-lonow/how-to-live-with-your-parents-for-the-rest-of-your-life_b_2993150.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Claudia Lonlow&lt;/a&gt;, the inspiration for her new show hit a little closer to home. That's because almost 16 years ago, Lonlow and her young daughter moved back in with her parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that's precisely what happens to &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/03/how-to-live-with-your-parents-tv-show-sarah-chalke_n_3010241.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Sarah Chalke&lt;/a&gt;'s Polly, who, along with her daughter, moves in with her mom Elaine (&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/elizabeth-perkins" target="_hplink"&gt;Elizabeth Perkins&lt;/a&gt;) and stepfather Max (&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/brad-garrett" target="_hplink"&gt;Brad Garrett&lt;/a&gt;) for the foreseeable future, thanks to a divorce and the pressures of a lackluster economy. But it's a decision Polly immediately regrets thanks to her parents, who have a much more laissez-faire approach to child-rearing than she does. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, while much is made of &lt;a href="http://www.aoltv.com/show/how-to-live-with-your-parents-for-the-rest-of-your-life/9259543" target="_hplink"&gt;Polly's frustrating parents&lt;/a&gt;, Garrett and Perkins see things a little differently -- it's Polly who's imposing on them. HuffPost TV recently spoke to the comedic duo about their no-longer empty nest, their instant chemistry, and their advice to parents in similar situations. The show premiered on April 3, yet Garrett and Perkins are already finishing each other's sentences like the old married couple they portray.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HuffPost TV: So what was it that appealed to you about the show? Had you always been interested in doing something with a twelve-word title?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Elizabeth Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; [Laughs] I was looking more for eleven or ten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brad Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, it was longer. They trimmed it. Seriously, that's not a bit. But well, I wanted to work with two beautiful women who wouldn't call the authorities on me, and that was Sarah [Chalke] and Ms. Perkins. The pilot script really resonated with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Thank you. It's a very interesting premise that I think is very relatable right now in today's economy. There are a lot of people getting out of college who can't afford to live on their own. In our case, our daughter Polly, who's played by Sarah Chalke, goes through a divorce and can't afford to live on her own. So she and her young six-year-old daughter move in with us, and we've been kind of loving our empty nest. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, we love our empty nest. It's like, "What's going on?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Suddenly, there she is for the rest of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; With a needy kid. She's wonderful, but we have a life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; We were enjoying the peace and quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since the show is based off creator Claudia Lonlow's real-life, did you two ever meet her parents?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Oh yeah. [Laughs]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Ironically, her dad is one of the co-owners of the &lt;a href="http://hollywood.improv.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Improv Comedy Club&lt;/a&gt; in Los Angeles, so I've known him for literally going on 30 years. And yeah, he doesn't like me, I don't think. But that's OK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; [Laughs] And Claudia's mother, who was a former actress and a stand-up comedian, I got to spend a lot of time with her and base a lot of Elaine on her energy and her spirit. It was great to have them around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, it was a lot of fun. They're very eccentric...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Very.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; And you know, they do a lot of things in the buff. Which has to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, they've got to stop that. And Claudia still lives at home, so...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, and her daughter's off to college. She's been there this whole time, and still isn't leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; She's got her own little wing over there in the house. The parents are going to leave before she does. [Laughs]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you know that your character's inspired by a real person, how do you make them your own? Is that a difficult process at all, especially after you've met them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; No, you just gotta take poetic license. You just gotta let 'er rip, because you know, you're never gonna be exactly who that person is. And luckily, with Claudia's parents, they're very giving and very cool, and love what we're doing. And have nothing but positive things to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; And my guy in real-life is very boring. So I had to bring my B-game, for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, you definitely are more interesting. [Laughs]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you guys enjoy getting to play characters with seemingly no filter?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, because we have such big filters in real life. [Laughs]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Especially in real life. I'm kind of known for not having a filter, I'm doing pretty good now though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; And I'm learning to be filter-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, it's fun to play people that really have no boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Right, because you can just sort of have a good time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, and what's fun on the set is comedically we all try things and swing for the fences. And Sarah Chalke is so wonderful to work with, comedically fearless, so I think that helps. Especially when you're discovering your character early on in the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obviously the chemistry between you two is a big key to the show. Was it easy for you to develop that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; You know, it was interesting. When I came along, I really wanted the role, and Ms. Perkins and obviously Sarah were already on board. And I did a chemistry read with Ms. Perkins to see if, you know, and it was just immediate that there was just something there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, we just clicked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; She's a very generous, talented actor...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Aw, so's he! We get along like a house on fire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; But you have to be very transparent comedically as an actor, especially for a good ensemble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Especially when you're playing people who've been married as long as our characters have been married, there just has to be a shorthand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; And I love how we're not picking on each other. We accept each other. We like each other. Sure, we have our little things, but...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; We're not this bickering old couple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, you know, there are people that are married a long time that dig it. I don't know of any, but they're there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did the idea that you'd be playing grandparents take some getting used to at first?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Well, they're grandparents, yes, but in a lot of ways they're almost younger-acting than Polly, Sarah Chalke's character. They're almost more free-spirited, they like to have more fun, they like to go out and do more things. They're more adventurous, more outspoken. So they don't really feel like "grandparents" to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, nor do we like the term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; No, I'm not a granny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, which is kind of fun, because as Polly moves home, she's the one who's more parental and all uptight. And that's kind of the twist on everything that we're trying to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you're playing over-the-top characters like Max and Elaine, is it important to still find ways to identify with your characters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Well, you know, I just like to get high ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; No, he doesn't mean in real life. He means in the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins: &lt;/strong&gt;[Laughs] There's a lot I can identify with in Elaine and a lot that I can't. I mean, I'm definitely not as outrageous as she is. But maybe I am a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett: &lt;/strong&gt;Well, I think we have to. You know, comedy, if I can for a moment...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Please do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Is almost like a small flame. A small flame. And how much are we going to ignite it, and what are we going to add to it? Still, we are eccentric people, but we need to be grounded and believable so we can go that way, so we don't end up sketch-y or worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, I can't really show up high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, she can't. I can, she can't.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any advice for parents if their kid wants to move back in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; "No."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, say "No." [Laughs] No, of course not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garrett:&lt;/strong&gt; Listen, we're kind of helicopter parents in real-life. So, who could say no? I mean, how can you not be there for a kid?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perkins:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, I couldn't say no. I don't know of any parent who could, but that doesn't mean that it isn't a difficult situation. And you get through it the best you can. And sometimes there's a lot of humor involved, which I think is what our show's about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Catch "How To Live With Your Parents (For The Rest Of Your Life)" on Wednesdays at 9:30 p.m. ET on ABC in the U.S. and City in Canada.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--226524--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1070761/thumbs/s-BRAD-GARRETT-ELIZABETH-PERKINS-PARENTS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Hollee Actman Becker: How A Little Posse Of Tween Girls Made A Huge Change</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/hollee-becker/beauty-is-only-skin-deep-instagram-is-to-the-bone_b_2994360.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2994360</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T17:31:03Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T17:36:14Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It's time for us to take our collective blinders off and really pay attention. Because the minute we give our kids an iPhone or iPod or any other gadget that puts technology quite literally in the palms of their hands, we become responsible for whatever happens next.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Hollee Actman Becker</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/hollee-becker/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;If you are a parent of a tween, stop right now and take this pop quiz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's only one question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you ready for it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here goes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is your kid on Instagram?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) No freaking way #inserteyeroll&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b) Totes! #likeduh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you answered (a), um... you're wrong. And I'm sorry to hear about that rock you just crawled out from under.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you answered (b), congrats! You just earned 10 Insta points! And I so just made that up! Go ahead and pat yourself on the back, but your job is far from over. Because letting your child have an Insta (you knew they called it that, right?) without teaching them how to use it properly is like buying your kid a car without teaching them how to drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or some other metaphor that's a little less lame. Still. The point I'm trying to make here is an important one so just bear with me, k?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So... Are you on Instagram? Do you follow your child to see what he or she is doing? Is their account set to "private" with geotagging turned off? Have you instructed your children not to accept follower invites from anyone they don't know? And to never, ever, ever give out any personal information like address, location or phone number? Like, ever?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well done. You just earned three more Insta points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But those were only the starter questions. Now take this next set out for a spin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you pissed because I said at the beginning that there would only be one question?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, guess what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have a tween now. Get used to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, have you told them yet how they should never post a picture that will hurt, embarrass or make someone feel left out? Explained to them -- really sat down and explained -- that any picture they post on Instagram is out there forever? And how that cute bikini pic they posted on vacay is just one screenshot away from landing in front of the wrong, creepy set of eyes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sad and hard to talk about, but true nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, did you tell them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're anything like me, your answer falls somewhere between um, I think I did and well... kind of, sort of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that's not enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that there are beauty pageants on Instagram?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well then you may want to sit down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because you know who the participants in these pageants are?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait. What?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, right now, as I sit here typing this, there is a tween girl with an iPhone somewhere making a grid out of four pictures of her besties using Instacollage or Mixel or whatever cool new app is making the rounds this week (omg Juxtaposer is sooooo amaze!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she's finished, she will post that grid on Instagram, and then write something along the lines of: BEAUTY CONTEST! VOTE SOMEONE OUT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you just throw up in your mouth a little? I know I did when this whole thing blew up here on the Main Line over the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I'll get to that in a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait. That's not even the worst part. Because what happens next is this: People will actually vote for who they think is the least attractive in the comments, and whichever girl's name is written the most will be awarded a big fat X drawn across her face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want me to repeat that last part?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you don't, but I'm going to anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whichever girl's name is written the most will be awarded with a big fat X drawn across her face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the question will be repeated two more times, until there is only one gorgeous X-free girl left standing, the fairest of them all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you thought you had it tough in middle school because no one had invented Japanese hair straightening yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don't hate the players. They're just kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don't hate the game. Instagram was designed to be an online photo-sharing app that let users pimp-out their pics with cool filters and then share them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, who do we hate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hate the coaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because we are the coaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we are failing our children by not giving them the tools they need to properly navigate this scary new world, and by not monitoring their interactions in this world closely enough once we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had heard about the beauty pageants from a friend in New York a few months ago. But I didn't realize it was going on in my own town until late Saturday night, when, after five days of being on vacay in Mexico, I finally got in bed with my iPhone and signed onto my daughter's account to see what was going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because part of the deal I have with my daughter is that until she turns 13, I can access her account any time. And if there are any followers, posts, comments or people she is following that I think are inappropriate, she will delete them, no questions asked. True story, except for the "no questions asked" part. Because she usually does have questions and/or arguments, but I am her mom and I said so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started scrolling down her news feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that's when I saw them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty contest grids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a half dozen of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there, smiling out from one of the squares, was my kid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holy freaking shit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I asked her about it the next day, she said she knew someone had put her picture in a contest, but that she didn't really care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Impressive, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then again, she hadn't been voted out yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were other girls who weren't so lucky. And they were devastated, which is a ridiculous understatement, to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first instinct was to block all the girls who had posted the grids from my daughter's account. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here's the thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These girls were friends of my daughter's who had been in my car, at my parties, in my house. They liked to dance, and sing camp songs and bake brownies. They weren't Heathers. Or Reginas. Or even Monas. And if you don't know who Mona is, you need to go watch an ep of PLL like, now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These were good, sweet, funny girls who I knew and who I liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, what they were doing was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how could I blame them when they were playing a game they had never been given the rules to? My own daughter waved the grids off as all in good fun until I actually explained to her what made them so offensive and vile. In the wake of events like what took place in Steubenville, it's becoming more important than ever for us to empower our kids with the tools they need to decipher right from wrong -- both online and IRL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so instead of banishing the girls, I did this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-04-02-SkinDeep.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-04-02-SkinDeep.jpeg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-04-02-SkinDeep-thumb.jpeg" width="450" height="514" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
At first, nothing much happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I noticed that the beauty grids were slowly starting to disappear from my daughter's news feed. And in their place were things like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-04-04-Love" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-04-04-Love" width="450" height="518" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-04-04-You" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-04-04-You" width="450" height="525" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-04-04-Peace" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-04-04-Peace" width="450" height="516" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Slowly but surely, this little posse of fourth and fifth grade girls -- who had just spent hours feeling bad about themselves -- picked themselves up and took to Instagram to post inspirational messages of their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you just get chills?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I did. Because if this is not just the most amazing show of tween girl power, then I don't know what is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, when it comes to social media, a little guidance goes a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is why it's time for us to take our collective blinders off and really pay attention. Because the minute we give our kids an iPhone or iPod or any other gadget that puts technology quite literally in the palms of their hands, we become responsible for whatever happens next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when my kids get home tonight -- they are 7 and 10 and yes, they are both on Instagram -- I'm going to take a few moments before all the after-school craziness begins to really sit down and talk to them about what it means to use social media correctly and responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something we should ALL be doing. We potty train our kids, teach them good table manners and spend 10 minutes deciphering the food label on a candy bar. And yet, we set our kids up on social media, and then for all intents and purposes, we hang them out to dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checking our kids' news feeds to see what they are viewing, scrolling through their profiles to see what they're posting, investigating the people who want to follow them, finding out who they've given their password to and monitoring all of their accounts (because most kids have more than one Instagram account, in case you didn't know) doesn't make us helicopter parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes us smart parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there is nothing more beautiful than being smart.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1066601/thumbs/s-HOLLEE-ACTMAN-BECKER-mini.jpg?9" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: Louis C.K. Explains How To Not Be An A**hole</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/04/louis-ck-tells-letterman-why-he-doesnt-take-photos-with-fans_n_3016231.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3016231</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T17:18:06Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T18:14:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Louis C.K. stopped by "Late Show with David Letterman" on Wednesday to promote his new HBO special "Oh My God," and explained to Dave why...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Ross Luippold</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ross-luippold/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Louis C.K. stopped by "Late Show with David Letterman" on Wednesday to promote his new HBO special "Oh My God," and explained to Dave why he doesn't take photos with fans -- and how his policy can backfire on him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He told an anecdote where some women asked him for a picture, and he declined, but wanted to be polite and asked for their names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Then I see the two women give their camera to some guy to take their picture with &lt;em&gt;each other,&lt;/em&gt;" he said. "So then I look at the story from their point of view. They want a picture of themselves, then I said, 'I just don't like doing that. I'm so sorry. But what's your name?' What a creep!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also described his conflicting feelings about raising his daughters to be good people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, how to tell them not to lie: "Honey, your word is the most important thing. Don't lie, because lying only fixes everything. The truth is, lying fixes everything. Forever. It's like magic," he said. Letterman disagreed with Louie, perhaps exhibiting his own history of having a &lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/tv-movies/letterman-sex-scandal-blame-article-1.1233145" target="_hplink"&gt;tricky relationship&lt;/a&gt; with the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the clip above, where Letterman makes Louie answer why he screamed "f*ck you, Letterman!" at the Ed Sullivan Theater in an episode of "Louie" last season.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1071035/thumbs/s-LOUIS2-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: Are These Two Women Long-Lost Twins?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/04/samantha-futerman-anais-bordier-_n_3015471.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3015471</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T17:14:47Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T17:14:52Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When Los Angeles actress Samantha Futerman logged on to Facebook on Feb. 21, she got a message that would change her life forever. "So...I don't...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Anna Almendrala</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/anna-almendrala/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;When Los Angeles actress Samantha Futerman logged on to Facebook on Feb. 21, she got a message that would change her life forever. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"So...I don't want to be too Lindsay Lohan, well...but...how to put it... I was wondering where you were born?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writer was Anais Bordier, a French woman studying in London. And that "Lindsay Lohan" mention? A reference to the remake of the classic film "Parent Trap," in which twins separated at birth discover each other for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The women, both 25 years old, confirmed that they were born on the same date in the same town in South Korea. Both had been adopted -- Futerman by a family in Verona, N.J., and Bordier by parents in Paris, France. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We both share a twisted sense of humor, a love of cheese despite any &amp; all lactose intolerance, flatulence as a result of said lactose intolerance, &amp; an apparent napoleon complex to name a few," writes Futerman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both women also tend to "artistically sleep 10h a day &amp; eat the rest of it," adds Bordier. But it was their differences that helped Bordier discover Futerman in the first place. While Bordier was vigilant about keeping her social network information private, Futerman was an outgoing actress with her own YouTube channel and a big social media footprint. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last December, Bordier and her friends stumbled across Futerman acting in &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/T2U233WF7A4" target="_hplink"&gt;this raunchy YouTube clip&lt;/a&gt; and marveled at the facial similarities between the two. A couple of months later, Bordier saw her again -- this time in a &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/AHVS5sHCRB4" target="_hplink"&gt;trailer&lt;/a&gt; for the film "21 &amp; Over." The credits listed Futerman's name, which helped Bordier discover &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/OFJrKSetVI8" target="_hplink"&gt;Futerman's video diary&lt;/a&gt; about how it felt to be adopted. That's when Bordier decided to reach out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maybe-twins decided to create a documentary about their newfound relationship and plan to film their first meeting and DNA test confirmation. To raise money, they turned to Kickstarter for support. With two weeks left to go on their fundraising campaign, the "Twinsters" project has already reached $35,450 -- well above their initial $30,000 goal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get to know more about their journey by watching the video below, and check out their &lt;a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1746892989/twinsters?ref=live" target="_hplink"&gt;Kickstarter page&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="571" height="428" src="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1746892989/twinsters/widget/video.html" frameborder="0"&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1070755/thumbs/s-SAMANTHA-FUTERMAN-ANAIS-BORDIER-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Mike Julianelle: 10 Reasons Why I 'Hate' My Son</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mike-julianelle/10-reasons-why-i-hate-my-son_b_2832011.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2832011</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T16:55:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T16:55:20Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Having kids is not all it's cracked up to be. For one thing, you have a tiny human being in your house. This is almost as bizarre as having an animal in your house, but at least animals have fur. All my son has is tons and tons of drool.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Mike Julianelle</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mike-julianelle/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Having kids is not all it's cracked up to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one thing, you have a tiny human being in your house. This is almost as bizarre as having an animal in your house, but at least animals have fur. All my son has is tons and tons of drool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part it's fun to have him around, except of course for the drain on my finances, the stress on my marriage, the elimination of my social life, the inability to sleep, the constant threat of fecal explosion, etc. It's actually very much like running a farm; at the beginning there was even milking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this is old news; everyone already knows that kids are a drag. But not all kids are a drag in the same ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here then, is a list of things I hate about my son, and my son only.*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. He makes everything more important.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work, money, food, health, free time. Everything means more now. I need to work harder to make more money to buy more food. More expensive, healthy food that won't make him get fat and get diabetes. I have to eat healthier too, and I have to exercise so I don't get fat and have a heart attack. Free time is no longer free, it's time to spend with him, and I need more of it because he needs more of me, and I can't go to the movies or to the bar because he can't come and I can't watch the stuff I want to watch when he's around because it might make him kill people so I have to make sure he watches the proper stuff which just gives me a headache and I can't let him watch too much because he has to go outside and oh my god there's just so much to think about, get out of my HEAD SCHWARTZ!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.  He's better looking than me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is funny, because everyone tells me how much we look alike. But it's clear he blows me away, just by virtue of being younger and not having bags under his eyes or a scowl on his face. I've never in my life gotten as many compliments as this kid. I mean, the dude's a chick magnet, and it's a lot of fun to get all this attention from the ladies, but not that fun since I'm married and he's a long way from puberty. It's like having a superpower you can't use. I feel like Mr. Incredible, except when he's fat and hates his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. My wife likes him more than me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every husband knows this is true. Ask Oedipus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong &gt;4. He reminds me of my mortality.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone tells you that having a kid around teaches you to see old things as new again; reinvigorates your perspective on life; let's you experience things through a child's eyes. All it has taught me is that I've wasted my life and I'm 35 going on 60 and apparently that's gonna happen in the blink of an eye since &lt;a href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/02/10/the-fast-and-the-furious/" title="The Fast and the Furious" &gt;having kids somehow accelerates time&lt;/a&gt;, according to every single parent I've ever met. Great. So I'm old, and I'm getting older, and he's in my face with his wasted, idiotic youth all the time, AND soon he'll be 25 and I'll be dead. Parenting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. My parents like him more than me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He's their only grandson and they don't remember what he was like as a teenager because he's only two. I, on the other hand, revert to being a teenager with every visit home. Advantage: grandson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. He gets terrible music stuck in my head.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I defy you to not be humming this song all day long:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src="http://network.coull.com/activatevideo?video_provider_id=2&amp;pid=8165&amp;website_id=12191&amp;width=490&amp;height=306&amp;video_provider_url=http%3A//www.youtube.com/embed/Py2f38iPBeI%3Fversion%3D3%26rel%3D1%26fs%3D1%26showsearch%3D0%26showinfo%3D1%26iv_load_policy%3D1%26wmode%3Dtransparent" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" width="490px" height="306px" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And then there's &lt;em&gt;Yo Gabba Gabba! &lt;/em&gt;At first you're like, oh, a hipster show for kids, maybe the music will be tolerable! And then you can't stop singing "Try it! You'll like it! TRY IT AND YOU'LL LIKE IT!" to yourself over and over and over and over. I don't blame the shows themselves -- they are what they are. I blame my son. He did this to me. Thankfully I got a little payback -- he's been humming "Call Me Maybe" for weeks. REVENGE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Everyone likes him more than me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, this kid is a charmer. It's gross. He has more social skills than I've ever had. I can barely go two minutes without insulting someone, this kid has gang members blowing kisses on the F train. The last time I blew a kiss at a gang member, well... let's just say I'm lucky I was still able to have a kid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong &gt;8. He makes &lt;strike &gt;drinking/being hungover/going to the movies/going to dinner/sleeping&lt;/strike&gt; everything harder.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He makes every adult-based and/or private and/or quiet activity harder. I can't get drunk when he's around, and even when he's not around, he will be the next morning, when the cure for a hangover is NOT his Elmo guitar in my face. I can't sleep late when he's &lt;strike &gt;around&lt;/strike&gt; alive. I can't go to the movies or dinner with him, which means I need a babysitter, and last week we scared off our best one when we came home drunk. He just makes life harder. More rewarding? More meaningful? Sure, whatever. I just want to get drunk in peace. Is that a crime?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. I like him more than me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He's a better person. It's just a fact. Even though he's still stained with Original Sin! BETTER PERSON THAN ME.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. He makes everything less important.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who gives a shit about going to the movies or watching &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;? I could sit and stare at my son all night long and that would be entertainment enough. I mean, ALL HE DOES is fall on his face. It's hilarious. He has 100 percent ruined my life, yes, but that was my old life and this is my new one (a fact that is both pathetic and, frankly, kind of necessary). He is my new one. I honestly couldn't care less about myself anymore. Like I said above, he's Me 2.0 and he's better in every. single. way. Which makes me have to try and be better too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which, in all honesty, is a major pain in the ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* Fine. Maybe it should be "10 reasons why I 'hate' my son..."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="mikejulianelle not for reuse" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1070736/thumbs/m-MIKEJULIANELLE-NOT-FOR-REUSE-460x307.jpg?8" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/07/27/top-10-reasons-i-hate-my-son/" target="_hplink"&gt;This post originally appeared on Dad and Buried. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1070736/thumbs/s-MIKEJULIANELLE-NOT-FOR-REUSE-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>BabyPost: When it Comes to Car Seats, Almost Isn't Good Enough</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/babypost/baby-car-seat-safety_b_3009383.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3009383</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T16:42:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T16:43:23Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I am not paranoid. I am not hyper vigilant. I am not the safety police. And my suggestion that people make sure their car seats are installed and used properly isn't something that should be met with annoyance or an eye roll. Car seats save lives.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>BabyPost</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/babypost/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;It is not very often that I stand on my soap box, but every now and again I see a real-life illustration of why I care about some things so deeply that it reinforces that I'm not crazy and I'm not "hyper vigilant," as I've been called. I just believe in taking easy and necessary precautions to keep my children safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot count the number of times I have had people, some close to me, dismiss my feelings on car seat safety. I have often heard the ol' "I didn't have X and I survived" line. I have also heard "I'm a safe driver. I can prevent accidents."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are called accidents for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could happen to anyone. And after &lt;a href="http://www.jphotographerblog.com/?p=1352" target="_hplink"&gt;reading this blog post&lt;/a&gt; of how a family narrowly escaped injury, it hit it close to home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I was doing just under the speed limit (yeah, I'm that kind of driver -- sorry!) and going through an empty intersection, we were smashed into by another driver doing almost double the speed limit."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you prevent that? How can you avoid that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"There are no skid marks, no signs he saw us, tried to stop... or even looked up from his phone."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can't avoid that. The best you can do is protect yourself as best you can to survive it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am often told by family members that I make the car seat straps too tight and the children are uncomfortable. I will let the other blogger, the one who survived a serious crash, explain why I don't care if my kids whine that the straps are tight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;"As always, my daughter hollered that the straps of her car seat were too tight, asked to have her arms to have 'more space'. My alter ego, Mean Mom -- she is immune to tears/crying/whining and can just do what has to be done, takes over here and squashes that small voice in my head that says I'm being to rough, that having the straps a bit looser might be more comfortable -- don't worry, that voice will never be heard again! If your child can talk, you know this feeling -- stick with your guns!!! Do.not.loosen the straps!!! Car seats are designed to be tight."&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as their chests can rise and fall to breathe with ease, the straps are not too tight. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Car seats save lives. This not my opinion. This is something countless crash tests, both controlled and in every day life, have proven over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related: &lt;a href="http://babypost.com/products/10-strangest-parenting-products-market" target="_hplink"&gt;10 of the Strangest Parenting Products on the Market&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not paranoid. I am not hyper vigilant. I am not the safety police. And my suggestion that people make sure their car seats are installed and used properly isn't something that should be met with annoyance or an eye roll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm the kind of parent who let my 22-month-old master the steep stair case in my new house by letting him climb them on his own (with me right behind him, but I didn't touch him unless he asked for help or seemed to need it). I am not petrified my child is going to hurt himself every minute of every day. I take (calculated) risks so that my kids learn how to do things safely for themselves. But car seat safety is on a whole other level. There are no calculated risks when it comes to car seats and there is no "almost" when it comes to it being done successfully. Almost, when it comes to car seats, is not good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seat being 'almost' secure enough, 'almost' upright or reclined enough, the chest clip 'almost' at arm pit level, is not good enough. And it's better to find that out from a manual or a website or a car seat clinic than on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blogger's children survived, in part due to their mother being vigilant about car safety. They story would have ended quite different and much more tragically, had she not been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celia, who posted the photographer's blog, put this forward on it. She said it better than I ever could. Using a car seat safely is not that hard. And it is more than worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;"Tether your forward-facing seats (even if they're in tight without being). Keep your child rear-facing as long as your car seat allows. Make sure the straps are tight enough (even if your child complains, like mine). Position the chest clip at armpit level. Make sure your car seats are installed correctly (read the manual again if you're unsure, and find a car seat tech to help you if you're still unsure after!). Adjust the straps as they grow (when RF the straps should come from under the shoulders, for FF, from above). I'm as free range a parent as any, but car seat safety is not something to be taken lightly. It's fine if your child is not secured properly if you never get in an accident. But you just never know. This could be you tomorrow. Take your time and make sure your children are safe."&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's true that many children back when cars and car seats were less safe than they are now lived to tell the tale. And I'm sure I'm not the only one who has heard that as a reason for not taking the importance of their proper installation and use more seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you may have been lucky enough to survive. The many kids who didn't can't raise their hand and say "but I didn't."&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Written by Leslie Kennedy for &lt;a href="http://BabyPost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;BabyPost.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More from BabyPost&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://babypost.com/blogs/rebecca-eckler/rebecca-eckler-im-dating" target="_hplink"&gt;Rebecca Eckler: I'm Dating&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://babypost.com/pregnancy/baby-names/cool-old-fashioned-baby-names-3" target="_hplink"&gt;Cool Old-Fashioned Baby Names&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://babypost.com/babies/infant-development/can-you-spoil-baby" target="_hplink"&gt;Can You Spoil a Baby?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEPOLLAJAX--222885--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1070737/thumbs/s-CAR-SEAT-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Our Tax System Hurts Mothers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/04/how-the-irs-hurts-mothers_n_3015439.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3015439</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-04T16:32:33Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T18:04:02Z</updated>
    
    <summary>LOST in the debate between Anne-Marie Slaughterâ€™s chronicle of the obstacles confronting career-oriented mothers and Sheryl Sandbergâ€™s call to â€œlean inâ€ is a crucial reality:...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The New York Times</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/teri-dangelo/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;LOST in the debate between Anne-Marie Slaughterâ€™s chronicle of the obstacles confronting career-oriented mothers and Sheryl Sandbergâ€™s call to â€œlean inâ€ is a crucial reality: taxes. Women -- no less than other humans, it turns out-- can be rational economic actors.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1071032/thumbs/s-MOMS-AND-TAXES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
