<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>We're Getting Unhealthier</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/adults-metabolically-healthy-past-generations_n_3071549.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3071549</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-19T03:27:08Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-19T03:27:10Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Adults today are less "metabolically healthy" -- meaning health with regard to cholesterol, body weight and blood pressure -- than adults from past generations, according...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Amanda L. Chan</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/amanda-l-chan/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Adults today are less "metabolically healthy" -- meaning health with regard to cholesterol, body weight and blood pressure -- than adults from past generations, according to a new study in &lt;a href="http://cpr.sagepub.com/content/early/2013/04/08/2047487313485512.abstract" target="_hplink"&gt;the European Journal of Preventive Cardiology&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The &lt;a href="http://www.escardio.org/about/press/press-releases/pr-13/Pages/today-adult-generations-less-healthy.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;prevalence of obesity&lt;/a&gt; in our youngest generation of men and women at the mean age of 40 is similar to that of our oldest generation at the mean age of 55," study researcher Gerben Hulsegge, of the the Dutch National Institute for Public Health and the Environment, said in a statement. "This means that this younger generation is '15 years ahead' of the older generation and will be exposed to their obesity for a longer time."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study included data from 6,377 people who were part of the Doetinchem Cohort Study in the Netherlands. People in the study were examined for their cholesterol, body weight and blood pressure starting in 1987, and were followed up again six, 11 and 16 years later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers found that for all the study participants, being overweight, obesity and high blood pressure all got more common through time. &lt;em&gt;But&lt;/em&gt;, they did find that more of those who were born later experienced these conditions, compared with people born 10 years before. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, 40 percent of men who were in their 30s in the first analysis of metabolic risk factors were considered overweight. But when researchers looked at the data for 11 years after that analysis, 52 percent of the next generation of men in their 30s were considered overweight. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers surmised in the study that "the &lt;a href="http://cpr.sagepub.com/content/early/2013/04/08/2047487313485512.abstract" target="_hplink"&gt;lifelong exposure to especially obesity&lt;/a&gt; will increase. As a consequence, more elderly of the future will develop overweight-related diseases such as diabetes and cardiovascular disease." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing younger adults are experiencing more than older generations? &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/08/millennials-stress_n_2646947.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Stress&lt;/a&gt;, according to a survey from the American Psychological Association. The "Stress in America" survey showed that people between ages 18 and 33 report higher stress levels than the national average.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084583/thumbs/s-ADULTS-METABOLICALLY-HEALTHY-mini.jpg?9" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jessica Zaleski: Everyone Gets What They Want</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-zaleski/glee-recap-sweet-dreams_b_3113904.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3113904</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-19T02:59:34Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-19T07:25:11Z</updated>
    
    <summary>After a very dramatic school shooting last week, "Glee" gave us a fluff episode this week. Everyone gets what they want, because that's entertaining!</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Zaleski</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-zaleski/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: Do not read on if you have not yet seen Season 4, Episode 19 of Fox's "Glee," titled "Sweet Dreams."&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a very dramatic school shooting last week, "Glee" gave us a fluff episode this week. It starts with a Finn voiceover where the former football star is talking about how he enrolled in Lima University to become a teacher because that's his dream (get ready, this episode is all about dreams. Yawn). He's absolutely loving college so far because, as he says, "College is like this perfect little bubble between being a kid and being an adult." He has the rest of his life to grow up and deal with adult problems like rehab. But right now, he has to start piling on that substance abuse at frat party after frat party with Puck (who is his roommate despite not being enrolled in the school). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn't get to see Rachel and Kurt in the last episode, but their unrealistic New York lives are back for our viewing pleasure. Rachel's biggest dream is to play Fanny Brice in "Funny Girl" on Broadway. And what do you know? "Funny Girl" has never done a Broadway revival before and NOW they are! Oh! And they're holding open auditions for the role of Fanny! How convenient that Rachel has been preparing for this since she was 5!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we pause here for a second and talk about how Rachel's biggest problem in New York so far has been having a hot boyfriend who's a prostitute on the side for extra cash? Most people have a tough time adjusting to New York. There are so many people here, you aren't just going to be the best at everything and get whatever you want ... unless your name is Rachel Berry, apparently. She has no problem buying the latest fashions despite being a college student in the most expensive city in the world, she rents a trendy Brooklyn apartment DECKED OUT in the Anthropologie collection, and she gets to audition for her dream role! Meanwhile, when I first moved to New York, I lived with a hoarder in a disgusting house on Staten Island and made like $200 dollars a month freelancing. But I guess that's what happens when your dad isn't Ryan Murphy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the actual glee club, we learn that Marley's big dream is to be a singer/songwriter like Norah Jones and she &lt;em&gt;really &lt;/em&gt; wants the club to sing one of her original songs at regionals. When Mr. Schue tells the club the theme of regionals, which is "Dreams" (surprise!), Marley thinks one of her songs will be perfect. But mean Mr. Schue has already picked what they're singing. He's chosen literal interpretations of the theme, like "Dream Weaver." The club then has a secret meeting to talk about how they hate those songs and they want to pick new ones. Marley suggests one of hers, but Kitty shoots it down saying "No one wants to hear a song about a fat mom." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at Party University, Finn and Puck have set up a Slip 'N Slide in the hallway and Finn charges girls their bikini tops to get into the sudsy rager. Right when the girls rip their clothes off, Mr. Schue shows up, apologizing to Finn and asking him to come back to the glee club. But, sorry old man, Finn has better stuff to do, like sing Beastie Boys at a frat party. (Sidenote: I went to a state school, which was also one of the top party schools in the country, and none of this happened. If someone would have tried to start a singalong at a party, people would have been like, 'Bye, weirdo!")&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schue returns to the glee club and takes out his anger toward Finn on the club. Blaine mentions the club wanted to different songs, and the Chancellor bellows, "WHY WOULD YOU DO THAT? HOW DARE YOU OPENLY DEFY ME?" Watch out kids, this guy used to be a Spanish teacher once. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rachel wants to sing a Streisand song for her audition, but Idina Menzel returns as her mom and tells her that's a bad idea. They sing a boring tune, and it makes me want to go listen to my "Wicked" soundtrack instead. Since Rachel still doesn't know what song to pick after her duet with mommy, she calls Finn. She tells him how sweet it was that he beat up her gigolo boyfriend and that she really needs help picking her audition song. Her ex tells her to "do something that takes you back to the roots of your passion." At her actual audition we see that she decided to go with "Don't Stop Believin'" and sees mirages of Mercedes, Finn, Kurt, Tina, and Artie from the very first episode. Oh Rachel, how far you've come. You're so close to achieving your biggest dream at just 19 years old. Hope you're okay with your life being all downhill from here! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting yelled at by Puck for not focusing on school and teaching, Finn returns to McKinley to tell Mr. Schue that he will come back and help with glee club under the condition that he isn't treated like Schue's assistant. Will says that he has a condition too and it's that the guys have to move past this falling out. You would think his condition would be "Don't kiss my wife anymore," but whatever. The two guys both go to the choir room and break the news that they aren't doing Mr. Schue's awful songs for regionals. In fact, they want Marley to teach the club one of her songs. How adorable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the episode Rachel is staring at her phone waiting for a call from "Funny Girl," and when it finally rings, she freaks. It's the producers on the phone, and she's extremely nervous. But when she hangs up, she screams that she got a callback. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, isn't that just a happy ending for everyone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"Glee" airs Thursdays at 9 p.m. ET on Fox.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--219644--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094708/thumbs/s-GLEE-SWEET-DREAMS-RECAP-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: Sharks Patch Things Up With Young, Tearful YouTube Sensation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/ryane-clowe-trade-boy_n_3111681.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>newscred-488e148b16555bff5766f6358a39e2d8</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T23:37:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T21:55:07Z</updated>
    
    <summary>SAN JOSE -- A 7-year-old Sharks fan whose tear-filled reaction to the trading of Ryane Clowe became a YouTube favorite got a chance to meet...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>San Jose Mercury News</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/robin-wilkey/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;SAN JOSE -- A 7-year-old Sharks fan whose tear-filled reaction to the trading of Ryane Clowe became a YouTube favorite got a chance to meet with players and coaches Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vincent Savage of San Ramon was captured on video crying over the April 2 trade of Clowe to the New York Rangers as his mother, Lauren, tried to console him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I'm sad about everything the Sharks have done," Vincent says on the video that was picked up by a variety of web sites. "I'm so mad at them."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team invited Vincent and his mother to the Sharks pre-game skate and they were ushered into the locker room afterward, where he got to talk with his players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vincent turned out to be a critic when he met Dan Boyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I can't believe you haven't won any Stanley Cups," the boy told Boyle, who politely corrected him. Boyle did win the Stanley Cup with the Tampa Bay Lightning in 2004.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"But you haven't won one with the Sharks," Vincent responded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the invitation from the Sharks, Vincent got a phone call and a signed jersey from Clowe. ___&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="nc_footer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;(c)2013 the San Jose Mercury News (San Jose, Calif.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit the San Jose Mercury News (San Jose, Calif.) at &lt;a href="http://www.mercurynews.com"&gt;www.mercurynews.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributed by MCT Information Services&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src="http://pixel.newscred.com/px.gif?key=YXJ0aWNsZT00ODhlMTQ4YjE2NTU1YmZmNTc2NmY2MzU4YTM5ZTJkOCZvd25lcj0zNDQ5NjhiY2NjN2VmZjJhNDYzYTk2ZjA3YzVmYTQ2NSZub25jZT01MjkzM2VjYy0xYzYwLTQ4ZDYtOTg2ZS1lMWQxNzFlMWZlNzImcHVibGlzaGVyPTA4YzIwOWI5YTg3MzA2ZjRiZjkyNjAwYTQ0ZDIxMTlm" alt="" height="1" width="1" class="nc_pixel"/&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094357/thumbs/s-RYANE-CLOWE-TRADE-BOY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: Dad's Hilarious Photobomb Goes Viral</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/dad-photobomb_n_3109587.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3109587</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T22:24:09Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T22:24:14Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Awwww, baby. Aw, beer? Photographer Ashley Hempel posted this photo on Facebook of dad-to-be Aaron photobombing his pregnant wife Laura on Saturday and it has...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Samakow</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-samakow/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Awwww, baby.  &lt;em&gt;Aw, beer?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photographer &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=626219394059204&amp;set=a.194548433892971.57252.192116600802821&amp;type=1&amp;theater" target="_hplink"&gt;Ashley Hempel posted this photo on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; of dad-to-be Aaron photobombing his pregnant wife Laura on Saturday and it has since &lt;a href="http://fox4kc.com/2013/04/16/picture-of-kansas-city-couple-becomes-talk-of-the-internet/" target="_hplink"&gt;gone viral&lt;/a&gt;. Can't say we're surprised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="aaron morgan photobomb" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1093440/original.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
“Well I do have a slight beer belly, so I was showing it off because, well, she got to show off her belly, so I figured I’d get to show mine off too,” &lt;a href="http://fox4kc.com/2013/04/16/picture-of-kansas-city-couple-becomes-talk-of-the-internet/" target="_hplink"&gt;Aaron told WDAF-TV&lt;/a&gt;. Laura is eight months pregnant with the couple's second daughter and plans to name her Molly Grace, the news outlet reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mommyish.com/2013/04/17/husband-photobombs-pregnant-wife/" target="_hplink"&gt;(hat tip Mommyish)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And now, from the hilarious pregnancy shot, to the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/09/22/awkward-family-photos-pregnancy_n_1904528.html" target="_hplink"&gt;painfully awkward&lt;/a&gt;. We give you...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1093440/thumbs/s-AARON-MORGAN-PHOTOBOMB-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How To Co-Parent When You Can't Stand Your Ex</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/five-tips-for-coparenting_0_n_3112613.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3112613</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T22:08:50Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T22:07:37Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The process of divorce is hard enough, but when you have to co-parent with an ex who has become the bane of your existence, things...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>www.goodtherapy.org</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;The process of divorce is hard enough, but when you have to co-parent with an ex who has become the bane of your existence, things can get worse. Some parents become better at being caregivers after divorce because they find their own voice and style outside the relationship. Others transform into an unrecognizable version of themselves, making parenting a horribly intolerable experience. Either way, when you can’t stand the person you are parenting with, life can become a drag, and the battle becomes exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094413/thumbs/s-FIGHTING-FAMILY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Truth About Being A Single Mom</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/the-truth-about-being-a-s_n_3112633.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3112633</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T22:08:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T22:07:24Z</updated>
    
    <summary>AS a five-year veteran of the single mom gig, I’ve been on a constant emotional rollercoaster—feeling like queen of the universe for potty-training my son...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>www.businessmirror.com.ph</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;AS a five-year veteran of the single mom gig, I’ve been on a constant emotional rollercoaster—feeling like queen of the universe for potty-training my son in a month, panicking at 3 am as I nurse his 104-degree fever, and even doing a happy dance after dropping him off at day care. I’m free, I think...even though I’m headed straight to work. Then there’s the sinking guilt of raising my son without his father and the exhaustion of having to do it all. Being a single mom is pretty much as tough as it’s cracked up to be, but that doesn’t mean I don’t love it.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094428/thumbs/s-SINGLE-MOM-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Giovanni Ribisi Is Heading Back To TV</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/giovanni-ribisi-dads-fox-pilot_n_3112614.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3112614</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T21:46:33Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T22:26:58Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Giovanni Ribisi has replaced Tommy Dewey in Fox's multicamera comedy "Dads," Deadline reports. The six-episode series was created by Seth MacFarlane, Alec Sulkin and Wellesley...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Laura Prudom</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/laura-prudom/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.deadline.com/2013/04/giovanni-ribisi-to-star-in-fox-comedy-series-dads/" target="_hplink"&gt;Giovanni Ribisi has replaced Tommy Dewey in Fox's multicamera comedy "Dads,"&lt;/a&gt; Deadline reports. The six-episode series was created by Seth MacFarlane, Alec Sulkin and Wellesley Wild, the team behind "Ted" (in which Ribisi also starred). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comedy is centered around Warner (Ribisi) and Eli (Seth Green), two successful men whose lives are thrown into disarray when their high maintenance fathers (played by Martin Mull and Peter Riegert) move in with them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to The Hollywood Reporter, &lt;a href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/giovanni-ribisi-star-seth-macfarlanes-442195" target="_hplink"&gt;the role was reimagined after the pilot taping last week&lt;/a&gt;, and Ribisi was apparently a better fit than Dewey. The character is described as "co-owner of a successful video game company and a family man with a wife and two young children." &lt;a href="http://www.deadline.com/2013/03/vanessa-lachey-to-co-star-in-foxs-seth-macfarlane-produced-comedy-series-dads/" target="_hplink"&gt;The role of Warner's wife was also recast&lt;/a&gt;, with Vanessa Lachey taking over from Erin Pineda following the table read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ribisi's best known TV roles include his stint on "Friends" as Phoebe's kooky brother Frank Jr., and Ralph Mariano on "My Name is Earl," but the actor has generally stuck to film since 2008. &lt;a href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/fox-orders-seth-macfarlane-live-414648" target="_hplink"&gt;"Dads" was ordered straight to series for a six-episode run in January&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you looking forward to "Dads"?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--292399--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094477/thumbs/s-GIOVANNI-RIBISI-DADS-FOX-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'Kris' Is Coming</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/kris-talk-show-kris-jenner_n_3112383.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3112383</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T21:30:01Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T21:52:42Z</updated>
    
    <summary>LOS ANGELES &amp;mdash; The studio behind Kris Jenner's new daytime talk show says it will launch the program in July. Twentieth Television said Thursday that...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/chris-harnick/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;LOS ANGELES &amp;mdash; The studio behind Kris Jenner's new daytime talk show says it will launch the program in July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twentieth Television said Thursday that the show, titled "Kris," will air for six weeks starting July 15 on selected Fox-owned stations. Those will include stations in New York and Los Angeles, with more to be announced later.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The studio says Robert Lifton has been picked as the executive producer of Jenner's show. His credits include "Access Hollywood" and "ESPN Sportscenter."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The limited run for "Kris" is aimed at proving itself for a national niche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kris Jenner is the matriarch of the media clan that includes daughters Kourtney, Kim and Khloe Kardashian.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094346/thumbs/s-KRIS-TALK-SHOW-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Irish Nanny Pleads Not Guilty To Killing Baby</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/aisling-brady-mccarthy-ir_0_n_3112401.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3112401</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T21:17:50Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T22:17:24Z</updated>
    
    <summary>WOBURN, Mass. &amp;mdash; An Irish nanny accused of killing a baby who died of what prosecutors say was "abusive head trauma" while in her care...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/david-moye/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;WOBURN, Mass. &amp;mdash; An Irish nanny accused of killing a baby who died of what prosecutors say was "abusive head trauma" while in her care pleaded not guilty on Thursday to a murder charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aisling Brady McCarthy, 34, was ordered held without bail at her arraignment on charges of murder and assault and battery on a child.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;McCarthy was caring for Rehma Sabir at the baby's family's apartment on her first birthday, Jan. 14, while her parents were at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That afternoon, an ambulance was summoned to the apartment in Cambridge, just outside Boston, after Rehma was found to be unresponsive. Rehma died two days later at Boston Children's Hospital of what an autopsy found were blunt-force head injuries, prosecutors said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State police said in court documents that a pillow, a blanket and baby wipes that were stained with blood were found in the baby's bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authorities have accused McCarthy of "violently injuring" the baby, causing her death. They said a neighbor reported hearing the baby crying for nearly an hour on her birthday, followed by more intense crying, but knocks on the family's door went unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McCarthy, of nearby Quincy, had pleaded not guilty earlier to assault and battery of a child, and she had been held on $500,000 bail. She was indicted on the murder charge last week after the medical examiner found the baby's death was a homicide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defense attorney Melinda Thompson said McCarthy maintains her innocence and has cooperated with investigators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prosecutor Patrick Fitzgerald argued Thursday that McCarthy should be held without bail because she is in the United States illegally and if released could seek deportation to Ireland, which does not extradite defendants who could face life sentences without the possibility of parole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thompson has called McCarthy "an innocent person sitting in jail" and said she wouldn't seek deportation if she were released on bail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"She wants to answer these charges and clear her name," Thompson said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immigration officials have said McCarthy entered the United States in 2002 from Ireland under a tourist program that allowed a 90-day stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baby's parents, Nada Siddiqui and Sameer Sabir, told police McCarthy had been a nanny for their family for about six months.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094349/thumbs/s-AISLING-BRADY-MCCARTHY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jordan Cieciwa: The 4 Biggest Excersie Obstacles for New Moms and How to Overcome Them</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/jordan-cieciwa/new-moms-obstacles-fitness_b_3110776.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3110776</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T21:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T21:47:28Z</updated>
    
    <summary>As a personal trainer, I get a lot of emails from new moms asking me how to lose the weight, how to exercise from home, how to stay motivated and how to maximize their time. I've finally devised a plan for these moms that will solve the four biggest fitness obstacles that new moms face.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jordan Cieciwa</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jordan-cieciwa/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Who's more important on this planet than a mom? I have one of the best. Just recently having beat breast cancer, she spends all her free time with my dad in Costa Rica finding clothes for less fortunate, feeding those in need, and teaching English to the youth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she reads this, she's going to be mad. She hates when I brag about her. But who would I be without her to look up to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings me to the point of this blog: Letting kids see their parents exercising, and moms specifically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get a lot of emails from new moms at &lt;a href="http://onefitcity.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;One Fit City&lt;/a&gt; asking me how to lose the weight, how to exercise from home, how to stay motivated and how to maximize their time. After years of working as a personal trainer, I've finally devised a plan for these women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've solved four common problems:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Child Care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation from a group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making personal training affordable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting in more time with friends&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's tackle the biggest issue new moms seem to have: child care. Cost and trust are the two concerns that are brought up most often. With money being tight, the cost of taking care of a little one is always a concern. Then next issue is finding a quality person to watch your child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my solution: Grab a group of friends -- at least four -- and bring all of your children to the same house for a workout. While two moms work out for a solid 45 minutes, the other two can watch the kids. At 45 minutes, the switch is made and everyone gets a workout. The cost is zero, and who better to watch your kids than a good friend?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this method of training also gets you into a group -- a group that expects you to be there and will encourage you to get results. The support is built into the project; what you and your friends do from there is completely up to you. The best feedback that I get is that with this program, moms don't need to wait around or plan their days around a class time. Your local gym may not have Zumba when you want it, but your DVD player is ready to go anytime you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's why I got involved with &lt;a href="http://www.nexersys.ca/" target="_hplink"&gt;Nexersys&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to find a way for people to bring cardio kickboxing home. Having a machine there that you can start up when you want means no wasted time waiting for a class. If you want to kickbox at 11:12 a.m. or 5:43 p.m. because that's when you find the time, you'll need to have the home equipment to do it. Your schedule should in no way deter you from success. Having your home set up and bringing friends over gives you no room for excuses. Plus, you can stay cutting edge with the hot trends by buying DVDs and splitting the cost of equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/iGA1t1n0LRo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Since I started personal training, I have suggested to groups to clients to split their visits between two or three friends, if you follow the group idea for new moms that I've suggested. Bringing in a trainer for an hour-and-a-half and splitting it four ways will save lots of money in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a personal training growth consultant, I started working with Snap Fitness River Heights in Winnipeg. We are launching a brand new small group program in which gym members tell us the time that works for them, and we start matching members to groups and trainers. The groups are four to six people in size. Everyone wins. Members can afford more sessions, trainers can motivate and use partner drills to keep things interesting, and the results begin to speak for themselves fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason small groups have become one of the top fitness trends is because of the low cost and extra motivation. You still get very focused time with a qualified trainer, but you don't have to pay for all the down time -- when you are resting, your trainer is with another member of the group. Doing something easy like bike sprints? Your trainer can be correcting form on another group member who is doing a kettle bell swing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask your gym if they offer small group sessions. It's money well spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last benefit to the small group is time with friends. New moms especially rave to me about getting to spend an hour-and-half with an adult. Men and women without children don't understand how much a good conversation means to a new mom. It's the best thing they can get, and as far as weight loss goes, that time with friends and the ability to unwind allows can lessen stress -- and less stress means having an easier time losing weight and a more restful sleep at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would love to see people take this to heart. Start a small group, get your friends together or join something going at your local gym. You'll meet new, fitness-oriented people and who knows how far it can go. With all my new members and new groups I do a 90-day challenge. It's a goal-setting time, with an end period to reach the goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the group works towards their individual goals, everyone wins. For trainers, it's a way to extend their reach and make more money. For business owners it's the best way to service their clients. For those looking for results, there is nothing like making new friends focused on health, or taking old ones and committing to being fit for your children to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of social media and the Internet is meeting people online who can support you. That's my hope for my &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/fitcityjordan" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/pefitness/feed" target="_hplink"&gt;Youtube page&lt;/a&gt;. I want to support as many people as possible start down the journey of wellness and healthy weight loss. Questions are always welcome, and I am here to help you goal set if you want to take the next 90 days and make the biggest changes of your life. The beach is just around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094075/thumbs/s-NEW-MOMS-FITNESS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Mom Makes Superhero Capes For Sick Kids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/tinysuperheroes_n_3111167.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3111167</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T20:23:10Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T22:59:03Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Brenna’s parents knew from the moment their little girl smiled through her grim diagnosis that she was a superhero. But it was a mom in...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/eleanor-goldberg/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tinysuperheroes.blogspot.com/2013/01/super-brenna.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Brenna’s parents&lt;/a&gt; knew from the moment their little girl smiled through her grim diagnosis that she was a superhero. But it was a mom in Seattle who let the world in on their secret. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mom is &lt;a href="http://tinysuperheroes.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Robyn Rosenberger&lt;/a&gt;who sews superhero capes for children living with disabilities or serious illnesses. She then posts their stories to her website, TinySuperheroes, to empower the kids and highlight just how strong they are. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="brenna_jpeg" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094218/thumbs/o-BRENNA_JPEG-570.jpg?8" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was first inspired to make capes when she read a blog post about Brenna, a 1-year-old with a rare skin disorder that makes her susceptible to infection and leads to the build up of thick plaques of white scaly skin all over her body, &lt;a href="http://todayhealth.today.com/_news/2013/04/17/17780774-tiny-superheroes-fight-big-illnesses-in-little-capes?lite" target="_hplink"&gt;TODAY reports. &lt;/a&gt;Inspired by the baby’s tenacity, Rosenberger reached out to Brenna’s mom to see if she could send her a cape. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[Brenna’s mom] was ecstatic and told me that they have been calling Brenna their superhero since she was born,” &lt;a href="http://todayhealth.today.com/_news/2013/04/17/17780774-tiny-superheroes-fight-big-illnesses-in-little-capes?lite" target="_hplink"&gt;Rosenberger told TODAY. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the fierce advocate posted Brenna’s story on her website, her mission took off. Since then, &lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/life-style/health/tinysuperhero-capes-empower-sick-kids-article-1.1319437" target="_hplink"&gt;she’s sent out 300 capes to kids across the country &lt;/a&gt;that generous donors have sponsored for $33 a pop, according to the New York Daily News. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cute superhero" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094227/thumbs/o-CUTE-SUPERHERO-570.jpg?6" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People can nominate superheroes on Rosenberger’s website and she then takes to Facebook to find donors to buy their capes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognizing just how much of an impact turning struggling kids into caped crusaders can have, Zaarly, the San Francisco-based company that processes Rosenberger’s orders, committed to donating capes to every child hospitalized in &lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/life-style/health/tinysuperhero-capes-empower-sick-kids-article-1.1319437#ixzz2QqTiVc5t" target="_hplink"&gt;Boston after Monday’s explosions&lt;/a&gt;, according to the New York Daily News&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the colorful capes give struggling kids a reason to smile, they also raise awareness about rare diseases and disabilities and let the world learn about a whole army of resilient and inspiring fighters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angel, for example, is one determined kid who embodies the essence of the “TinySuperhero mantra." &lt;a href="http://tinysuperheroes.com/?page=1" target="_hplink"&gt;He was diagnosed with Neuroblastoma cancer in 2008&lt;/a&gt; when he was 5 years old. He has undergone three surgeries, 28 radiations, one stem cell transplant antibody treatment, and two chemotherapy medical trials, according to Rosenberger's blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="tinysuperheroes" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1093921/thumbs/r-TINYSUPERHEROES-large570.jpg?15" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s currently facing his fifth relapse, but he and his family will do whatever it takes to beat the disease. His mom recently even shaved her head to support her son. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Rosenberger hopes her contribution can give Angel, and other kids just like him, a boost of power to keep going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[TinySuperheroes] exemplify strength and determination as they overcome great adversity,” Rosenberger wrote on her blog. “We feature them...in hopes of giving them a voice, their illness or disability a face, and the world the opportunity to stretch.”&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094251/thumbs/s-CUTE-SUPERHERO-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Linda K. Wertheimer: Marathon Bombings Show Randomness of Life, Death</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/linda-k-wertheimer/marathon-bombings-show-randomness-of-life-death_b_3110420.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3110420</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T20:22:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T20:22:45Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I heard the news about the bombings as I drove home from Crane's beach with my son asleep in his booster seat behind me.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Linda K. Wertheimer</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/linda-k-wertheimer/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Randomness. That word sticks in my mind in the aftermath of the bombings near the Boston Marathon finish line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The randomness of it all when it came to who was injured and who was not, who died and who survived. The randomness of who decided to watch the marathon that day and who chose instead to spend a day at a beach, a zoo, or Revolutionary War reenactments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the attacks were intentional. But what strikes me as random is who happened to be where and when. Any of us, especially those of us who live in the Boston area, could have chosen to head toward the marathon and jostle our way as close as we could to watch runners at the finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought fleetingly of taking my 5-year-old son to downtown Boston that day, but instead opted for a day at Crane's Beach. At home, unless my son is not around, my husband and I do not talk about the bombings. We do not want to shatter our little one's innocence, though the innocence of so many young people was shattered on Monday. Already, the 9/11 attacks are not as fresh in our memories. Today's fifth- and sixth-graders are not old enough to remember them. They are old enough to remember Monday. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why write of randomness? Because as intentional as this act of terror seems to have been, the attackers did not aim their bombs at particular people. The three dead victims are an 8-year-old boy, a 23-year-old graduate student at Boston University and a 29-year-old woman originally from Medford. I didn't know any of them, but two have connections to my community. I teach part-time at BU, where everyone is mourning killed student Lingzi Lu and monitoring the progress of her friend, who was injured. The mother of 29-year-old Krystle Campbell worked at Harvard Business School and is close friends with members of my temple in Lexington. I have no connection to 8-year-old Martin Richard, but it does not matter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard the news about the bombings as I drove home from the beach with my son asleep in his booster seat behind me. Like so many others, I scrambled to find out if people I knew that might be near the marathon site were OK. One was a college friend I just saw again for the first time in 25 years. She came to Boston to watch a runner friend. She had said she was going to the finish line. The other person was the daughter of another college friend. I thought, too, of my former &lt;em&gt;Boston Globe&lt;/em&gt; colleagues who would be covering the marathon. All were fine. But what if? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem self-serving to connect this terroristic attack to tragedies of my past. I do that just to make the point about the randomness of tragedy. One day, your family is whole; the next day, it is changed forever. My 23-year-old brother, Kevin decided to drive all the way through from California to Colorado after a week's vacation in 1986. At some point, he fell asleep at the wheel, and his jeep rolled over a cliff. He died of massive head injuries. If he had stopped for coffee somewhere, maybe the accident would never have happened. If he had been driving on a less curvy road, maybe his jeep would have just rolled into a ditch. When he was 16, he fell asleep at the wheel and woke up when his lime green Barracuda hit a fence post. He was unharmed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years before, a driver blacked out and hit another car, instantly killing my Great-Aunt Bessie and severely injuring my Grandma Pearl. Grandma survived. What if Bessie, who was driving, had chosen another road that day? What if that driver, who had a history of blackouts, had chosen to stay home? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday near the finish line, the deaths and injuries happened at random. People standing near the victims survived. Runners finished at various times based on their particular performance that day. Some people who were there may have come on the spur of the moment. Others might have made a last-minute decision. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of casualties on Monday is lighter than other attacks in our country and elsewhere in recent years. I don't call that lucky. I call it another example of randomness. There is nothing lucky about what happened in Boston this week. Maybe people who stood near the victims feel a sense of luck that they survived. But I wonder how many more feel guilty that the bombs took the person next to them while they were spared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn't sure whether to write at all, but when something like this happens, I must write. It is my way, I guess, of catharsis. This isn't my personal tragedy, but it is, in a sense, everyone's heartache this week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to work full-time as a journalist. If I were still working in a newsroom, I would have been helping in some way with the coverage. Instead, Monday was a day off from preschool for my son Simon and one of our Mommy and Me days. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband posted some of his thoughts on Facebook that night. It is his last few lines that I loved. "Simon and I planted carrots that evening. I hope that is what he remembers."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of us old enough to remember, it will be hard to shake away the images. We will remember the photos and video of people running away from the scene in terror and of medical responders running toward the victims. We will remember the pictures of severely injured people. We will remember, too, the photos of the victims when they were alive. The one that sticks with me the most is a photo of Martin Richard holding a poster he made in school with the words: "No more hurting people" and "peace." Was he writing about Newtown? Was he writing about 9/11? Was he just writing his wish for the universe? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why write about this and throw in the word randomness? Because it is random who was killed and who was spared. It is random who is now a mourner, and who is not. It is this randomness that haunts me. What if, what if, what if? Who cannot help but ask that question this week? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt uneasy driving into Boston on Tuesday to teach. It was a much different feeling than I had on Sept. 11, 2001, when I drove into downtown Dallas to my job as a reporter as most of the city evacuated to get away from the skyscrapers. The 9/11 attacks happened in another state. This one happened in my state and in the city where I work and often play. I was on Boylston Street right near the finish line over the weekend. I walked by hundreds of people laughing, talking. A street musician played Irish jigs on his fife. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents are writing on my hometown's listserv that they will not take their children into Boston as planned this week. They do not want their young children to see the police presence and ask questions. I understand that worry. I don't want my young child to think he should be afraid of just walking down a street. I don't want him to know that this week, I had that feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>NYC Parents Ditching Diapers For Au Naturel Toileting Trend</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/parents-ditch-diapers-for_n_3111922.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3111922</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T20:15:32Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T20:24:55Z</updated>
    
    <summary>GREENPOINT — Pardis Partow decided to give her year-old son, Parker, some diaper-free time at home — much to the consternation of her Yorkshire terrier....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>DNAinfo</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/christopher-mathias/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;GREENPOINT — Pardis Partow decided to give her year-old son, Parker, some diaper-free time at home — much to the consternation of her Yorkshire terrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of Parker’s terrible diaper rash, the Bedford-Stuyvesant lawyer-turned-Reiki healer became interested in “elimination communication” — or EC, as it’s called— responding to her son’s cues for when to go to the bathroom instead of having to rely on a diaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094239/thumbs/s-AMYZIMMER-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Social Media May Skew Kids' Values: Survey</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/social-media-kids_n_3111259.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3111259</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T20:09:31Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T20:13:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Almost a quarter of preteens are using social media and it is having a profound impact on their values, a new national survey released Thursday...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Catherine Pearson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/catherine-pearson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Almost a quarter of preteens are using social media and it is having a profound impact on their values, a new national survey released Thursday has found. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Children who went online to post and tag photos, meet people, follow celebrities and "like" brands were more likely to value fame, as were those who regularly watched TV and movies and used a cell phone, according to researchers with the Children's Digital Media Center in Los Angeles, which conducted the survey. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"There was a really strong relationship between kids using more media -- and more social media -- and valuing fame," researcher Yalda T. Uhls, a researcher with the Children's Digital Media Center, told The Huffington Post. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"These tools invite children to seek likes, comments, audience and friends and they pick up on that," she added. "As a culture, we need to really think about, 'Is this what we want?' Do we want our children to focus so much on getting an audience and becoming famous?'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uhls and her co-researchers got parental permission to ask more than 330 9- to 15-year-olds from across the country about how much they use different types of technology, as well as how important certain values like fame, community feeling and kindness were to them. The findings from the online survey will be presented at a &lt;a href="http://www.srcd.org/meetings" target="_hplink"&gt;Society for Research in Child Development&lt;/a&gt; meeting in Seattle on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than half of the children in the survey were under 13, and 23 percent of those preteens said they had a social networking profile -- even though Facebook requires that users be at least 13 years of age before they can sign up for an account. And 26 percent of the kids under 13 indicated they had YouTube account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's not like, 'Oh my God! Every single kid under 13 is doing this,'" Uhls said. "At the same time, these kids are not supposed to have social media accounts. So the number that do &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; surprising." (The &lt;a href="http://business.ftc.gov/content/coppa-rulemaking-and-rule-reviews" target="_hplink"&gt;Children's Online Privacy Protection Act&lt;/a&gt; limits the information that websites can collect from children under 13 without parental notice and consent.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kids who watched more TV and movies or used a cell phone also valued fame more, but there was no link between watching TV or movies and valuing community and community involvement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same pattern held true for social media use: Activities like tagging and posting photos and videos were linked to valuing fame, both in the present and as a long-term goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We can't determine a clear cause and effect, but kids become the messages they get the most," said Jim Taylor, author of &lt;em&gt;Raising Generation Tech: Prepare Your Children for a Media-fueled World&lt;/em&gt; (and a frequent HuffPost blogger). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I think it's pretty safe to say that the shift toward values most of us would consider not healthy are coming from technology, from social media, and basically the [constant] presence of popular culture," he continued. Taylor did not work on the new survey, but he had reviewed it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey is the third study conducted by Uhls and her colleagues on the intersection between values and media. In an earlier study, they looked at the &lt;a href="http://newsroom.ucla.edu/portal/ucla/popular-tv-shows-teach-children-210119.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;values emphasized in TV shows&lt;/a&gt; that are popular with 9- to 12-year-olds over a 50-year period. Fame went from being below average in terms of importance to the most important value emphasized by popular TV shows. The most dramatic change occurred between 1997 and 2007, coinciding with the explosion of the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which means, Uhls said, that children not only watch TV shows that value fame, they also engage in fame-seeking behaviors online on a regular basis, looking for friends and likes and shares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They know how to use these tools to get an audience at a very young age," she said. "And they are using these tools to seek an audience at a very young age." Part of the way children learn that behavior is by watching their parents' habits, so moms and dads should think carefully about what kind of message it sends to their children when they post photos and videos of them online, she said, while cautioning that the results are still preliminary and she is only just beginning to analyze them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now the key is for parents to be thoughtful and deliberate about how and when they let their children use social media, and to limit their own use in front of their children, Taylor said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I think parents need to sit down and say, 'What do we value? What kind of kids do we want our kids to be? And to help create those kids, what do we need to do? What are the obstacles?'" he said.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094085/thumbs/s-SOCIAL-MEDIA-KIDS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>George Lopez Is Back</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/george-lopez-show-fx-saint-george_n_3111722.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3111722</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T19:56:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T20:16:04Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There's a new George Lopez show on the way! FX has picked up Lopez's half-hour sitcom "Saint George," which he co-created and will star in....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jaimie Etkin</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jaimie-etkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;There's a new &lt;a href="http://www.nickatnite.com/shows/george-lopez/" target="_hplink"&gt;George Lopez show&lt;/a&gt; on the way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FX has picked up Lopez's half-hour sitcom "Saint George," which he co-created and will star in. The new &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Lopez_(TV_series)" target="_hplink"&gt;Lopez show&lt;/a&gt; marks the comedian's first starring TV role since "George Lopez" ended its six-season run on ABC in May 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Saint George" will be a multi-camera ensemble comedy that centers on the chaotic life of a recently divorced working class Mexican-American turned successful entrepreneur (Lopez). He struggles to balance his demanding ex-wife, his 11-year-old son, his overbearing mother who just moved in, and his uncle, as well as his new role as a philanthropist “giving back” by teaching history once a  week at a night school.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'm excited about my new show, couldn't think a better group of people or better place to create than FX," Lopez said in a statement. "Now to get ready ... Back to Pilates!" &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FX ordered "Saint George" under the 10/90 model: Ten episodes will be made and if the series earns a certain level of ratings succes over it first 10-episode run, FX will order an additional 90 episodes. The model has been successful in recent history with another FX series "Anger Management" and Tyler Perry’s "House of Payne" and "Meet The Browns" on TBS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“George Lopez is an incredibly gifted actor-producer and one of the most talented comedians in the business,” Chuck Saftler, FX's executive vice president, said in a statement. "The 10/90 model requires a unique individual who has the ability to pull off this kind of daunting schedule. George is that guy and we couldn’t be happier that he chose FX as the home for his new project.”&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Matt Williams and his Wind Dancer Films partner David McFadzean co-created "Saint George" with Lopez. The trio will serve as executive producers and will also co-write the first episode of the series. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Production on &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0310460/" target="_hplink"&gt;Lopez's new show&lt;/a&gt; is set to begin in August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/02/28/george-lopez-new-sitcom_n_1307519.html&lt;br /&gt;
" target="_hplink"&gt;News of Lopez's new series first broke in February 2012&lt;/a&gt; and though "Saint George" marks Lopez's return to sitcoms, it's not his first time back on TV. The comedian had a late-night run on TBS with "Lopez Tonight," which ran from 2009 to 2011, and &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/06/08/take-me-out-george-lopez-flirty-thirty-dating-show-video_n_1579830.html" target="_hplink"&gt;hosted Fox's dating game show "Take Me Out"&lt;/a&gt; in the summer of 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think about &lt;a href="http://www.deadline.com/2013/04/fx-picks-up-new-george-lopez-sitcom-in-1090-deal-with-lionsgatedebmar-mercury/" target="_hplink"&gt;Lopez's upcoming show&lt;/a&gt;? Will you watch? Sound off in the comments!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094159/thumbs/s-GEORGE-LOPEZ-SHOW-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
