<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Schoolgirl Dating Website Advert Banned For 'Grooming'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2013/04/16/schoolgirl-dating-website-advert-banned-grooming_n_3097100.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3097100</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-17T03:23:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-17T04:04:14Z</updated>
    
    <summary>An ad for a dating website that appeared on Facebook with a picture of a woman in a school uniform has been banned for potentially...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>PA/The Huffington Post UK</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/sarah-o-meara/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;An ad for a dating website that appeared on Facebook with a picture of a woman in a school uniform has been banned for potentially encouraging grooming of young children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ad - headed "Older Men Wanted" - read: "Browse local singles who are looking to date older men only at Date Matures!", while an accompanying picture showed a young woman wearing what appeared to be a school uniform with the visible part of her shirt unbuttoned and her tie hanging loosely around her neck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Advertising Standards Authority (ASA) received a complaint that the ad was offensive, harmful and irresponsible for portraying the model as a school-aged child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advertiser, Mate1.com, did not respond to the complaint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook said the ad was in violation of its guidelines and had been disabled, as had any other ads using the same image. They had also issued a warning to the advertiser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ASA said the model would be understood by readers as being of school age due to her youthful appearance and the impression that she was wearing a school uniform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It said: "In the context of the other claims in the ad - 'Older Men Wanted', 'datemature.com' and 'Browse local singles who are looking to date older men Only at Date Matures!', and the fact that the ad appeared on a social networking site - we considered that the image was irresponsible because it could be understood as an allusion to, and encouragement of, the so-called 'grooming' of young children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"For these same reasons we considered that the ad was likely to cause serious and widespread offence."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It added: "Although the ad appeared to be targeting 'older men', we considered the implication that young children could also join the dating service, in order to meet older men, was a breach of the code rules."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It ruled that the ad must not appear again in its current form.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090584/thumbs/s-ADULT-SCHOOL-GIRL-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Natalie Thomas: What I Will Tell My Unborn Child About the Boston Bombings</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/natalie-thomas/what-i-will-tell-my-child_b_3094422.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3094422</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-17T01:36:04Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-17T01:32:56Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Eventually, when she's old enough, I'll tell her about that dreaded day in Boston. But my focus will be on the citizens, runners, emergency workers and bystanders -- all everyday heroes, who made (and make) Boston an amazing place to call home.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Natalie Thomas</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/natalie-thomas/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;My firstborn is due any day now. A daughter. The biggest and best dream I've had my whole life is finally coming true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've spent the majority of the last few months making sure everything is ready and perfect for her. Her nursery just so, her clothing and blankets washed in the most delicate and eco-friendly way, her products and toys top of the line, free from chemicals and completely wiped down, her gear of the safest possible standards and codes, her medicine cabinet stocked. I've logged dozens of hours at parenting and CPR classes. Everything she'll ever need to be comfortable, safe, protected and loved has been thought of, handled and is here waiting for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what about the world around her?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happened in Boston yesterday is devastating and a further reminder that no matter how protective we are in our homes, no matter how much love we give, the same cannot be said for once we step foot outside our doors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My family and I just relocated back to NYC, arguably making us even more of a target now than we were in our previous home of LA. But we know from the Aurora's, Newtown's and Tucson's that no one is truly safe, that it can happen anywhere. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first reaction in these situations is to cry. Cry for the lives taken, those irreparably injured, their families, our people. Cry for our children and their uncertain, potentially volatile future. Since I'm 9 and ½ months pregnant, this time, there were more tears than usual. But it wasn't just the hormones. It was the thought of bringing my little girl into this, often times, scary, scary world. When we can't do simple, every day, otherwise joyous acts like watch a marathon, go to school, the supermarket or the movies, what is sacred?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost instantly, however, my thoughts changed from ones of fear to those of pride. I'm always amazed that immediately following the worst of humanity, we witness the best. Within the same breath, without skipping a beat, ordinary people become superhuman. There is something within us that, when disaster happens, when it really matters, when our neighbor is in trouble, our city in peril, we run towards the flame. We drop our airs, affiliations, priorities, to-do lists, forgo our own fears and put ourselves in the line of fire for others, complete strangers, someone else's daughter, brother, wife, mother. Unaware of what lies ahead, that another bomb or shot may lie in wait, defiant to the uncertainty, concern for others overpowers any other sense or inkling. It's a beautiful thing. I witnessed it firsthand on 9/11 and I saw it again yesterday in Boston. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That selflessness, bravery and overwhelming compassion makes me proud to call myself an American, even prouder to raise my daughter as one. We will always prevail over the evil, vengeful, hateful and cowardly when we band together. As long as we're thinking of others before ourselves, as long as our impulse is to double back instead of lurch forward, terrorists will never win. In their attempts to take us down, harm, hurt and break us, they only make us stronger, wiser, more unified. While it might be a senseless world at times, it's an overall resilient, hopeful, positive place and our people are what make it so. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can't wait to teach her about the beauty of humanity, instill in her a fearlessness that is inherent in all of us and get her involved at a very early age with helping others. I look forward to telling her about all the people who willingly choose a profession in which every day they put their lives in danger for the benefit, peace of mind and safety of others. And those that don't but for one day, one moment follow suit and, in the heart of tragedy, sacrifice their lives for the sake of strangers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, eventually, when she's old enough, I'll tell her about that dreaded day in Boston. But my focus won't be on the terrorists -- it'll be on the citizens, runners, emergency workers, and bystanders -- all everyday heroes, who made (and make) Boston an amazing place to call home.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Malin Akerman Announces Baby News</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/sebastian-zincone-malin-akerman-baby-boy_n_3096511.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3096511</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-17T01:25:26Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-17T01:24:00Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Congrats go out to Malin Akerman and her husband Roberto Zincone! The couple welcomed their first child, a son named Sebastian, on Tuesday morning, the...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Leigh Blickley</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/leigh-blickley/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Congrats go out to Malin Akerman and her husband Roberto Zincone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://celebritybabies.people.com/2013/04/16/malin-akerman-welcomes-son-sebastian/" target="_hplink"&gt;The couple welcomed their first child&lt;/a&gt;, a son named Sebastian, on Tuesday morning, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MalinAkerman" target="_hplink"&gt;the "Rock of Ages" star tweeted&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;My husband and I welcomed our beautiful, healthy baby boy to this world this morning! Biggest joy of my life!!! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search/%23lovemykid"&gt;#lovemykid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Malin Akerman (@MalinAkerman) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MalinAkerman/status/324324144869163008"&gt;April 17, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;PS and his name is...Sebastian Zincone :))) Love him more than life itself!! &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search/%23whatafeeling"&gt;#whatafeeling&lt;/a&gt; !!!&lt;/p&gt;— Malin Akerman (@MalinAkerman) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MalinAkerman/status/324325719742242816"&gt;April 17, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Akerman, 34, and Italian musician Zincone &lt;a href="http://www.instyle.com/instyle/package/general/photos/0,,20352342_20355381_20761755,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;tied the knot in June 2007&lt;/a&gt; after meeting in 2003. The actress admits that she and Zincone have wanted to add to their brood for a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My husband and I have been talking about it for the past 10 years that we’ve been together," &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/349979/malin-akerman-talks-up-going-green-at-emas-jokes-that-being-pregnant-feels-like-being-hungover" target="_hplink"&gt;she told E! News about the pregnancy&lt;/a&gt;, "so it’s about time."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090549/thumbs/s-SEBASTIAN-ZINCONE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'They Don't Need To See Any More Dead Kids After Newtown'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/how-parents-explain-boston-tragedy_n_3095526.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3095526</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T23:07:25Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T23:21:28Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Carole Tedesco, an attorney from Winchester, Mass., was sitting in the Prudential Skywalk watching the Boston Marathon with her children when she heard the blasts,...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Joy Resmovits</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/joy-resmovits/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Carole Tedesco, an attorney from Winchester, Mass., was sitting in the Prudential Skywalk watching the Boston Marathon with her children when she heard the blasts, just seconds apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her kids, Luca, 9, and Isabella, 8, thought it was thunder. Carole knew it wasn't. She thought the building might have been hit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The building's loudspeaker announced that there would be a "shelter in place" due to "criminal activity in the neighborhood." The term "shelter in place," a common school drill refrain, triggered Luca's fear. "What's going on?" Luca asked, frantically. He started crying. An off-duty cop speculated that they were going to be stuck in the building all day, which only elevated Luca's worries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'm afraid they're going to come in with guns and shoot us," Luca said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carole reassured him that it wasn't that type of attack. But as she recalled the next day, Luca's mind kept returning to Newtown. When the family finally left the building, Luca kept thinking he was walking into an unsafe situation. Carole promised him that he was going be home that night to sleep in his bed with Flora, his favorite stuffed animal -- but in the back of her mind, as she heard the sirens blaring, she wasn't sure if she could deliver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time they finally got home, Carole and her husband had instituted a media ban. "They don't need to see any more dead kids after Newtown," she said. "When we talked to them, we tried to put it in the context of bad things happen but not that often. But it's very hard to sell that. It seems like we were just telling them that in December."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of the Boston Marathon bombings, parents in Boston and across the country are struggling to explain the senselessness of the attack to their children. Around Boston in particular, parents are put in a unique situation, since there is a school break this week. During school-day crises, teachers can be &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/09/09/teachers-dealt-with-september-11_n_950916.html" target="_hplink"&gt;first responders,&lt;/a&gt; and they are often taught how to break potentially traumatizing news to children. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to parents outside Boston, while the pain might not feel as close to home, determining age-appropriate vocabulary for tragedy less than six months after the Newtown massacre is particularly troubling. This time, parents themselves know even less about what caused the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though schools are not in session, Carol Johnson, the superintendent of Boston Public Schools, sent a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/carol-johnson-boston-explosion_n_3092434.html?1366126541&amp;utm_hp_ref=fb&amp;src=sp&amp;comm_ref=false#sb=1565852,b=facebook" target="_hplink"&gt;memo to parents advising them&lt;/a&gt; to limit their children's news consumption, to let children ask questions and express their feelings, and to answer their questions with facts in "age-appropriate" language. "Our city is full of heroes and we are thankful for every one -- and we are thankful for you, too," she wrote. "We look forward to seeing you back at school next week."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letting children verbalize their concerns can help blunt the impact of their feelings, said Anthony Mancini, a Pace University psychology professor who focuses on grief and trauma. "Children do have the capacity to bounce back, and experiencing something horrific like the Boston Marathon … is not a sentence of trauma by any stretch at all," he said. "Most children will do fine in the way that most adults would do fine." While children who witnessed the explosion first-hand could face some degree of post-traumatic stress disorder, Mancini said, children are often resilient and bounce back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joy Budewig Harms, a Boston speech pathologist, hopes that's the case. Though some &lt;a href="http://api.viglink.com/api/click?format=go&amp;key=32baf9faf91103bc2a7aa19ce37d8c0d&amp;loc=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.huffingtonpost.com%2F2013%2F04%2F16%2Fcarol-johnson-boston-explosion_n_3092434.html&amp;v=1&amp;libid=1366154468143&amp;out=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.nasponline.org%2Fresources%2Fcrisis_safety%2Fhelpingchildrencope.aspx&amp;ref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com%2F&amp;title=Carol%20Johnson%2C%20Boston%20Public%20School%20Superintendent%2C%20Advises%20Parents%20On%20How%20To%20Talk%20About%20The%20Explosions&amp;txt=Click%20here%20to%20visit%20it.&amp;jsonp=vglnk_jsonp_13661544781173" target="_hplink"&gt;psychologists&lt;/a&gt; recommend sheltering kids from media exposure during tragic events, Harms had no choice. Her four-year-old daughter, Clara, kept asking questions, eventually getting her hands on a copy of the Wall Street Journal, Harms said. While Harms had explained to Clara that something bad happened at the marathon, people were hurt, and the good guys were trying to make sure it never happened again, Clara focused in on the WSJ photo she saw. "Are those people hurt? What happened?" she asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's hard keeping it from her. I wish her view were true -- that it's good guys versus bad guys -- but it's not that simple," Harms said. "This week, violence is in Boston, but it's always happening in Pakistan, Syria, all over the world. We would like to keep our children from that experience, but we have to start shepherding them through this concept early in their lives," she said, as she started to cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That simplistic children's view also affected Cheryl Stober, an investment firm product analyst in Newton, Mass. "If I told my son there were bad guys in the city, he's going to want to run out the door and karate-chop them," she said. "It's easier for him not to hear." Stober's 9-year-old daughter, though, was aware of the event: She was with her father in his office when Stober called. Stober's husband shared with their daughter that there was a bomb at the marathon, but that mom was safe. The family learned soon afterwards that the 9-year-old's teacher, who was running the marathon, was safe as well. Stober's daughter will spend time later this week at a local daycare center, Bright Horizons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ilene Serpa, vice president of communications at Bright Horizons, said her employees were careful to not expose kids to the news of the day. "We want to make sure we're providing supports for our employees, letting them take time off if they need," she said. Bright Horizons has 12 centers in Boston, and many of them were open late on Monday since parents weren't able to get to their kids. "Teachers are doing what's best for kids at a young age: protecting them from the news," Serpa said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann Zeiser, a media professional in Enfield, Mass., a Boston suburb, tried to do the same. "I turned off the television," she said. "Watching tragic events can have a cumulative effect." After she explained to her 8-year-old what had happened, she took him out for a bike ride, she said. On Tuesday, she sent him to her town's recreational program. "I want to help him process it over the week. I want to tell him there are heroes, and we love each other."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090409/thumbs/s-HOW-PARENTS-EXPLAIN-BOSTON-TRAGEDY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Parents Are Talking About The Boston Marathon Explosions With Kids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/talking-about-boston-marathon-explosions-with-kids_n_3095447.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3095447</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T22:57:02Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T22:57:04Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Parents in Boston and across the globe are struggling to talk to their children about the bombs that exploded on Monday. What is safe to...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Farah L. Miller</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/farah-l-miller/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Parents in Boston and across the globe are &lt;a href="http://boston.cbslocal.com/2013/04/15/boston-marathon-explosions-talking-to-your-children/" target="_hplink"&gt;struggling to talk to their children about the bombs&lt;/a&gt; that exploded on Monday. What is safe to tell them? What &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to say? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experts have some answers, but the discussions each parent chooses to have is a personal decision. We asked our readers what they and their families chose to talk about. Here are some of their answers, in their own words. Use the comments or email us at &lt;a href="mailto:parents@huffingtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;parents@huffingtonpost.com&lt;/a&gt; to tell us about the conversations at your house. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tracey Wynne, Arlington, VA &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I am a mother of a 6-year-old and 8-year-old. They were off from school yesterday, so I expect that they will come home today with questions. My goal is to give them very basic information about what happened and to assure them that they are safe. I will also take a cue from Mister Rogers and let them know how many people rushed to the aid of those who were hurt. (Thank God for the helpers!)

&lt;p&gt;The toughest part for me is managing my own insecurities about tragedies such as this. I am not a great actress -- it's difficult for me to hide my feelings and anxieties during times such as these. With that in mind, I will certainly be keeping the television off -- for their sake as well as mine.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michele Brown, San Antonio, TX &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Last week, my 6th grader’s school went into lockdown after a man with a toy gun came on campus. My son’s friends saw the man and notified their teacher. The drills they had previously only practiced became something truly unnerving. 

&lt;p&gt;The man was subsequently arrested by police. My son later told me he was hiding behind a trash can holding the biggest thing he could find --  his Spanish book -- to “defend himself.”  Every little noise was terrifying for him. Thirty minutes later, it was over.  Thirty… long… minutes.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
When the Newtown shootings took place, I made the mistake of NOT telling my children (I have a 12 year-old and an right year-old).  I figured if they did not watch it at home, they were safe. Bad call on my part. They later asked all kinds of questions based on information -- much of it incorrect -- heard from their peers. I kicked myself for not knowing better. But as parents, how in the world do you prepare for THIS?&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
My son is on edge with the news yesterday. I have worked to make sure he knows enough to be aware but not to terrify him.  We did lean into the famous Mr. Rogers comment -- focusing on the helpers. Scholastic.com also provided insight yesterday that helped.  We told my son, “If you see something, say something” and explained why that is important for MANY circumstances he might come across in life.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do think my 8-year-old daughter is too young to understand a true impact.  As for my son? He seemed okay this morning, but time will tell.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amy Oztan, Brooklyn, NY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;When the bombs went off at the Boston Marathon I knew I had to tell my 8-year-old daughter what happened. I hadn’t told her about Newtown. She heard about it at school, and I found out that what she hears first makes a big impression. This time, I kept it simple: there was a big race being run today in Boston, and some very bad people set off some explosions that hurt a lot of people. I assured her that there were lots of people in Boston helping, and other people in New York City (where we live) making sure that we’re safe.

&lt;p&gt;Fiona and I are running a 5K together in June -- her first race. I told her that nothing like that would happen at our race. It doesn’t matter that I can’t possibly know that, I told her anyway. One of her questions surprised me: “Are there any pictures?” I told her that there were, and also videos, because so many people were there waiting for their friends and family members to cross the finish line. She wanted to see them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got home I sat behind Fiona, my hand on the remote, ready to turn the TV off if it looked like anything graphic was coming. She watched the explosions wide-eyed. They interviewed runners in Boston, and (this being local news), they interviewed some people in Brooklyn. By that point Fiona had lost interest and wandered away, to feed her doll and get a snack and be an 8-year-old. I’m watching closely for signs that she’s scared or wants to talk about it more, but so far -- nothing.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donna Gorman, Amman, Jordan &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Because we work at the Embassy here, and because their dad is in charge of security, my kids (ages 4-13) have some experience dealing with this topic. Every time there is an attack on an Embassy somewhere in the world, they know about it, because all of the adults talk about it. And of course they hear their dad on the phone, and they see the protestors, and the tanks in front of the Embassy during particularly trying times. They even know that they, as Americans, are targets.

&lt;p&gt;It saddens me that they have this knowledge in their heads, but what to do? We've had several problems since we've been here, and when they were at the Embassy for a real duck-and-cover, I was relieved to know that they understood the seriousness of the situation and followed the directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, it was hard to hear my 6-year-old this morning. She misunderstood the conversation and thought our Embassy had been blown up. She wasn't even upset, so much as curious.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cecelia Wu Tanaka, Chapel Hill, NC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I have a just-turned 9 year old and I told him what I knew. I grew up in the area (now out of state) and his grandparents live 15 minutes away.  Boston means so much to me -- my parents immigrated there from China by way of Peru, and Boston made everything possible for us. I couldn't hide my tears and my mood yesterday. If anything, he is the one who consoled me. 

&lt;p&gt;Just yesterday morning I was teaching him to use a scale of 1 to 10 to describe his feelings, anything from a cut on his knee to hurt feelings to the temperature of his food. Then when he saw me upset at the news he asked me how I was feeling on a scale of 1 to 10. I said, after some thought, "8…9 and 10 are for those who were there and lived through it, or who got hurt, or who had a family member or friend who got hurt or killed." My son replied, "You said 8 because you grew up there? You can take a 9." He gave me permission to feel a 9.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michele Chabin, Jerusalem, Israel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;When our children were 6 years old we actually got rid of the TV largely to shield them from the nightly news. Then, a little over a year ago, when the kids were 9, the uncle, aunt and three little cousins of one of our twins' classmates were murdered in their home by two Palestinian terrorists. 

&lt;p&gt;Their teachers informed the parents the tragedy would be discussed in school the next day. We woke up the kids a bit earlier the next morning and told them the news before school. They wanted to know "How did it happen?" "Could it happen to us?" As parents we tried to reassure them by saying the incident took place far away (actually only a few miles) and that we always take precautions (never touch suspicious objects, for example), and that we believe we are as safe as any human being can be. One of my twins became clingy and insisted, every night, that we lock the front door. He knows the danger is there but he seems to have made peace with it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mary Caffrey, Robbinsville, NJ &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;My eighth-grade son, Bobby, was very upset by yesterday’s bombing. It’s not just the violence, but it’s the marathon too. Bobby is a very talented distance runner, and it’s not a stretch to think that he might run the race someday. We talked about the bombing when I picked him up from track practice, and he asked to watch the coverage with me before he went to his AAU basketball practice. Afterward, he had to get started on an essay about, of all things, the 1963 Birmingham church bombings. I thought about suggesting he connect the two, but he was so upset I kept quiet.

&lt;p&gt;Bobby was tired after basketball and got up early this morning to finish his essay. He asked me to look at it, and I was proud that he talked about the Boston Marathon attack and wrote that when bombers act they do so not just to do damage,  but also to create fear. We talked about whether the Ku Klux Klan were “terrorists,” and he had never thought about applying that term to them. As he considered it, he agreed that the Klan were terrorists just like the modern-day kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 50 years, I pray my great-grandchildren will write an essay about what the Boston Marathon bombing meant, and the idea that it could happen again will be just as unthinkable.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More From Parents About The Tragedy&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/claire-mccarthy-md/how-the-explosions-at-the_b_3093130.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents" target="_hplink"&gt;How The Explosions Changed Parenthood Forever For Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/liz-gumbinner/a-mothers-mind-after-the-boston-marathon-bombing_b_3091900.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents" target="_hplink"&gt;Inside A Mother's Mind After Tragic News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/mr-rogers-look-for-the-helpers_n_3088716.html" target="_hplink"&gt;The Advice From Mr. Rogers We Really Need To Hear Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090437/thumbs/s-PARENTS-TALKING-ABOUT-BOSTON-MARATHON-EXPLOSIONS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Terry Gaspard, MSW, LICSW: The Forever Dad: Shattering the Myth of the Self-Centered Dad</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/terry-gaspard-msw-licsw/the-forever-dad-shatterin_b_3084692.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3084692</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T22:40:16Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T22:40:23Z</updated>
    
    <summary>What kids need is a loving, predictable father figure -- whether married to their mother or divorced. I don't think anyone can argue that point. However, I believe that divorced dads are often portrayed in the media in a negative light.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Terry Gaspard, MSW, LICSW</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/terry-gaspard-msw-licsw/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;What kids need is a loving, predictable father figure -- whether married to their mother or divorced. I don't think anyone can argue that point. However, I believe that divorced dads are often portrayed in the media in a negative light. For instance, Alison Patten's article The &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/alison-patton/uncle-dad-syndrome_b_2986705.html" target="_hplink"&gt;'Uncle Dad Syndrome' &lt;/a&gt;posted on HuffPost Divorce recently depicts divorced dads as irresponsible blockheads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The media often portrays a demoralized and demeaning image of divorced fathers. The typical divorced dad comes across as immature, self-centered, and irresponsible. When was the last time you read a story or saw a television show about a caring divorced father who was in touch with the needs of his children? Fathers and their kids suffer from assuming the worst about dads after a family dissolves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, it's important to counteract the negative press given to fathers post-divorce and to mention all of the "Forever Dads" who aren't immature, irresponsible or self-centered. What exactly is a "Forever Dad?" They are the ones who don't disappear. The dads you see at dance recitals and soccer games. They try hard to maintain a regular visitation schedule and call when they are running late. They thrive on watching their kids grow and support their healthy development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to better understand the obstacles faced by fathers after divorce, I interviewed several young adult women and their fathers who participated in &lt;a href="www.movingpastdivorce.com" target="_hplink"&gt;my research study&lt;/a&gt;. The following is a summary of the characteristics that the father-daughter pairs mentioned during our interviews. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A competent dad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Considers fatherhood an honor, a privilege, and a lifetime commitment.&lt;br /&gt;
•	Believes he plays an important role in the life of his kids.&lt;br /&gt;
•	Values input from his children's mother and speaks well of her.&lt;br /&gt;
•	Puts his kid's needs first and practices positive parenting.&lt;br /&gt;
•	Enjoys spending time with his kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most outspoken dads I met with, Brian, in his late forties, was eager to tell me about his close bond with his daughter Amanda. Brian personifies a father who is devoted to his daughter and wants the best for her. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian never remarried after his four year marriage to Felicia dissolved -- making regular contacts with his daughter Amanda a priority. He describes his split from his ex-wife as contentious, saying "I made a point of recognizing that I'm going to do whatever is in Amanda's best interest. So even if I'm getting a line of baloney from my ex that she doesn't want to come (for a visit), I'm going to respect that. I'm not going to be a disruptive element in Amanda's life." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda, age 19, was an infant at the time of her parents' breakup and the custody arrangement was fairly traditional -- with her spending every other weekend and one weeknight with her dad. Brian has worked hard to reduce conflict with his ex-wife and reports swallowing many words and biting his tongue in an effort to keep the peace. With intensity in his voice, he says, "I always say to Amanda, you do what works for you. I'm not going to feel slighted or upset -- do whatever works for you." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenges Brian and other dads face is the stereotypes that exist about divorced fathers. It's crucial to examine our beliefs and attitudes about the role of dads after divorce if we are going to break down barriers that create distance between fathers and their children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, fostering alienation between a child and his or her dad is one of the cruelest and most selfish acts a parent can do to their own child. Society perpetuates a negative view of dads post-divorce. The exception is the movie &lt;em&gt;Spanglish&lt;/em&gt;, director James Brooks' poignant portrayal of a father who is a far better parent to his daughter than her mother.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are some of the barriers that prevent dads and kids from maintaining a close bond after parental divorce? Many experts cite the importance of a divorced mom promoting her child's relationship with her father. Whenever possible, mothers need to encourage their children to sustain regular contact with their dads -- such as phone calls, holiday time, and special occasions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's also important for moms to eliminate negative comments about their ex-husband so her kids don't feel caught in the middle. Lastly, fathers who remain an integral part of their child's life after divorce can promote a loving relationship that endures through rough patches. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When parents divorce, children are forced to give up their sense of control. Let's face it, divorce is a decision made by parents -- not children. Divorce is a painful experience for everyone, but children raised in disrupted homes often feel the sting of divided loyalties. Loyalty conflicts are frequently at the root of a father/child wound because kids feel they have to choose between their parents.  Since children of divorce are particularly vulnerable to conflict between their parents, it's important for parents to be cordial and to avoid arguments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-custodial fathers, I believe, get a bad rap because divorce really disempowers them from being "half-time" parents. Instead, the emphasis is often placed on financial support. I would like to suggest that the emphasis should be equally placed on dads balancing time with their children and meeting their economic needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his landmark book, &lt;em&gt;Always Dad&lt;/em&gt;, Paul Mendelstein advises divorced fathers to find ways to play a crucial role in their children's lives. He suggests that they call a truce with their ex-spouse -- to put an end to active fighting and to collaborate. While this is may be a challenge at times, collaboration with an ex paves the way for greater cooperation in the future. Children flourish best when raised by both a father and a mother -- whether in a divorced or intact family. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow Terry Gaspard MSW, LICSW on &lt;a href="www.twitter.com/movepastdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/MovingPastDivorcecom/199571693452926?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://movingpastdivorce.com" target="_hplink"&gt;movingpastdivorce.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090440/thumbs/s-DIVORCE-DADS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Things Get Even More 'Awkward' This Season</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/awkward-season-3-premiere-cast-preview_n_3095750.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3095750</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T22:35:20Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T23:58:14Z</updated>
    
    <summary>"Awkward" Season 3 premieres April 16 at 10 p.m. ET on MTV, and in preparation for more shenanigans at Palos Hills High, The Huffington Post...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Laura Prudom</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/laura-prudom/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/18/awkward-season-3-premiere-date_n_2898312.html" target="_hplink"&gt;"Awkward" Season 3 premieres&lt;/a&gt; April 16 at 10 p.m. ET on MTV, and in preparation for more shenanigans at Palos Hills High, The Huffington Post visited the Los Angeles-based set to catch up with the cast. We talked to Brett Davern (Jake), Beau Mirchoff (Matty), Jillian Rose Reed (Tamara), Molly Tarlov (Sadie), Greer Grammer (Lissa), Desi Lydic (Val) and Nikki DeLoach (Lacey) about what junior year has in store, including more romantic entanglements and a potential pregnancy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/awkward-season-3-ashley-rickards_n_3082452.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Ashley Rickards told us that Jenna and Matty are "very in love"&lt;/a&gt; after summer vacation, that doesn't mean their lives are free of drama -- it's high school, after all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jake and Tamara had an unexpected hook-up in the Season 2 finale, and Reed acknowledged that although Jenna gave BFF Tamara her blessing to date Jenna's ex, "It doesn't matter if you say 'go for it,' it's still gonna be strange. Tamara and Jenna weren't together over the summer, so Jenna doesn't really know anything that's progressed. When we come back in the first episode, there's definitely that feeling of separation and having to get back into the swing of things and have that conversation about what's happened."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davern said that although Jake might never have looked at Tamara in a romantic light before, things have definitely evolved since we last saw them. "They had this impulsive moment in the car [in the finale] and he has that hero complex so he saw a damsel in distress and had this moment with her, and I don't know if he thought anything would happen with her going forward. You go to Europe, you have that summer camp syndrome, maybe the chaperones weren't around that much ... I think they had a really fun time and found things in each other that they really liked."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this side of the pond, Mirchoff promised that Matty and Jenna's time together at camp has helped them "grow this budding relationship and learn about each other and deepen the relationship -- it's hit a new level."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, this being "Awkward," the foursome will have their share of obstacles. "Matty and Jenna were extremely comfortable with each other," Mirchoff observed. "Jake and Tamara come back and things have gotten different again, school's started so how are they gonna act in front of people? Matty was insecure about his relationships [before] -- is he gonna be the same? There's some insecurities with Jake, Matty's best friend -- are there any residual feelings left there? How are they all going to hang out together without any tension or awkwardness?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Davern, "As far as Jenna and Jake are concerned, they had that great friendship to begin with. Even after she broke his heart, he was able to forgive and move on, so he and Jenna are great friends, and I think the writers do a really great job of tackling that kind of situation with Matty and Tamara maybe sometimes feeling like a third wheel because Jake and Jenna have this great past. It's gonna get awkward, there's gonna be some weird moments, but that makes for fun TV."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of the quadrangle, resident school bully Sadie Saxton will have her share of trouble this year, according to Tarlov: "Sadie has a lot of things happen to her in the beginning of the season. We'll see a lot of it in the first episode ... We do see Sadie dressing a little bit differently, there will be a distinct difference. It'll be talked about at school; rumors are flying. There's some pretty life-changing stuff that happens to Sadie and we'll get that all at the top."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately (or perhaps unfortunately, from Sadie's perspective), Sadie will have clueless best friend Lissa to lend a supportive ear. "There's some interesting stuff between Sadie and Lissa, you get to see them both go through a pretty big change this year, separately," Grammer previewed. "It's interesting to see how they react to the other's situation. You definitely see how they're there for each other and how their friendship really works."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On "Awkward," the adults are sometimes as hilariously immature as the teenagers, but both DeLoach and Lydic promise that Lacey and Val will be a strong presence for Jenna this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Jenna thought that her mom was this one person and then last season revealed that her mom was always standing by her and always there for her. I think that reveal really shifted their relationship, so now it's in a place that it's never been," DeLoach admitted. "Jenna's trusting her mom and Lacey's really trying to step up and be the mother that she personally never had and the mother that Jenna has always needed."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having been through her own share of relationship drama last year with Jenna's father, Kevin (Mike Faiola), Lacey is well-positioned to offer her daughter advice, for once. "[Jenna and Matty] are going to struggle in their relationship, the same way that Lacey and Kevin did, because Kevin wasn't always there for her. He left a lot and he wasn't always dependable, so that means that her daughter's probably going to have to struggle with that. Kevin's a great guy with a good heart and he's a great dad ... [and] Lacey sees that Matty's a really good kid, and that's the most important thing: do you have a good heart, do you make my daughter happy? Matty has done that." &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
At school, Jenna will have kooky Vice Principal Val on her side, and according to Lydic, the duo is "as strong as ever. The fun part about their relationship is it started with Val forcing herself on her and Jenna reluctantly having to walk into her office, and there's a nice shift that's happened where Jenna has seen the good in Val like Val has seen the good in Jenna."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, Lydic did preview that this season will see "the power shifting" for Val and that she'll be "going back to her roots." She'll also have some "fun stuff with Ming [Jessica Lu]" and Matty, and will team up with Jake for an installment of &lt;a href="http://www.mtv.com/shows/awkward/video.jhtml" target="_hplink"&gt;"Awkward's" tie-in webseries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"There is a thread within the show [that ties into] the webisodes," Lydic revealed. "It's a bit different, tonally -- it's a little more experimental. We're playing with different genres from webisode to webisode, and there's a little bit of a mystery I'm following." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out more about the mystery Val will be trying to solve, as well as Sadie's big change and the evolving love square, tune in for Season 3 of "Awkward," Tuesdays at 10 p.m. ET on MTV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--280226--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1042265/thumbs/s-AWKWARD-SEASON-3-PREMIERE-DATE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'THIS DOESN'T MAKE SENSE': Victim's Mother Delivers Heartbreaking Statement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/patty-campbell-krystle-campbell-dead-boston-marathon_n_3095294.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3095294</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T22:04:41Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T22:04:38Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Patty Campbell, the mother of Krystle Campbell, a 29-year-old woman who was killed in Monday's Boston Marathon explosions, gave an emotional statement to the press...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Alana Horowitz</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/alana-horowitz/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Patty Campbell, the mother of &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/krystle-campbell-boston-marathon-bombing-victim_n_3093884.html?" target="_hplink"&gt;Krystle Campbell,&lt;/a&gt; a 29-year-old woman who was killed in Monday's Boston Marathon explosions, gave an emotional statement to the press outside her home in Medford, Massachusetts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We are heartbroken at the death of our daughter, Krystle Marie," she said on Tuesday. "She was a wonderful person, and everybody that knew her loved her... she had a heart of gold. She was always smiling, friendly. You couldn't ask for a better daughter. I can't believe this is happening. She was such a hard worker in everything she did. This doesn't make any sense."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campbell continued through tears, her voice breaking: "She was the best."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krystle Campbell's father, William Campbell, had confirmed her death earlier Tuesday. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"My daughter was the most lovable girl, &lt;a href="http://news.yahoo.com/blogs/lookout/second-boston-marathon-victim-identified-krystle-campbell-174401374.html" target="_hplink"&gt;he told Yahoo News.&lt;/a&gt; "She helped everybody and I'm just so shocked right now. We're just devastated."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 29-year-old restaurant manager had been apparently been waiting by the finish line to see her friend's boyfriend finish the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 170 people were &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/boston-explosion-news_n_3088615.html" target="_hplink"&gt;injured in Monday's attacks,&lt;/a&gt; which killed Campbell and at least two others. &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/martin-richard-dead-boston-marathon-explosions_n_3090386.html" target="_hplink"&gt;An 8-year-old boy,&lt;/a&gt; Martin Richard, was also killed in the blasts. Multiple people also lost limbs. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090382/thumbs/s-PATTY-CAMPBELL-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kim Garst: Cyberbullying: Your Kids Need You on Their Side</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kim-garst/cyberbullying-your-kids-n_b_3093412.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3093412</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T21:54:03Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T21:54:42Z</updated>
    
    <summary>While these are great strides taken in attempt to stop cyberbullying, parents themselves need to learn to spot the signs of a child that is being harassed.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kim Garst</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kim-garst/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Whichever angle you look at it, bullying of any type is bad. Before social media existed, however, kids only had to be worried about being harassed while the bully was physically present. For kids in the digital age, though, bullies can pester them 24 hours a day through cell phone calls, text messages, and now Facebook, Twitter, Google+, and other social networking sites. To add to their torment, not only can the bullied child see this harassment, but all of their friends can as well. At such an impressionable age, the stress created by knowing that everybody is watching you be bullied can often make the problem worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media does many great, positive things, whether it's raising awareness about important issues like cyberbullying, helping small business owners reach customers, or helping people make connections they never thought they would. While these are huge benefits, there is clearly a dark side to social media as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple of sad facts: about &lt;a href="http://www.isafe.org/outreach/media/media_cyber_bullying" target="_hplink"&gt;half&lt;/a&gt; of adolescents and teens have been bullied online and about the same number have engaged in cyberbullying themselves. Over half also report that they have not told their parents or an adult about something mean or hurtful that happened to them online.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of these frightening statistics, courts have started taking cyberbullying seriously. On April 4th, the Maryland Senate voted unanimously to pass a bill that would make it a crime to harass a minor online. Appropriately titled "&lt;a href="http://www.chesapeakefamily.com/index.php/blog/new-a-notable/4298-grace-s-law-cyber-bullying-bill-passes-in-the-maryland-house" target="_hplink"&gt;Grace's Law&lt;/a&gt;," this bill is named after 15-year-old Grace McComas. McComas committed suicide on Easter Sunday of last year after being relentlessly bullied online by a neighbor. Because of Grace's Law, someone who harasses a minor based on sex, race, or sexual orientation could face up to a year in jail and a $500 fine. Minnesota, Florida, and Iowa have proposed similar bills as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baltimore Ravens running back Ray Rice has shown an immense amount of support for Grace's Law. In March, Rice&lt;a href="http://d1dkhwu97wvoh4.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/HB-testimony.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt; wrote a letter&lt;/a&gt; to the Maryland Judiciary Committee, saying, "Cyberbullying has gotten out of hand. We need to act... NOW!" He goes on to say how he receives hundreds of messages each week from kids and teen that are bullied to the point of contemplating suicide because of the things said about them on social media. He believes that youth culture needs to be changed so that children understand that their words have consequences. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these are great strides taken in attempt to stop cyberbullying, parents themselves need to learn to spot the signs of a child that is being harassed. Sadly, parents aren't as aware of this threat as they should be. &lt;a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/~/media/Files/Reports/2011/PIP_teens_Kindness_Cruelty_SNS_Report_Nov_2011_FINAL_110711.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;Studies&lt;/a&gt; estimate that only 7 percent of parents are worried about cyberbullying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If at all possible, parents should try to prevent cyberbullying before it happens. The best way for parents to do this by communicating with their child. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication is the Key:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may sound simple, but it's not necessarily easy.  Every strategy to prevent and respond to cyberbullying is rooted in communicating with our kids, not talking at them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preventing Cyberbullying Takes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Staying aware of threats to your kids even as those threats continue to change  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Talking to your kids about your family's rules about security and privacy online&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Communicating with your kids so that you are a trusted adult they can talk to at once if they become the victim of cyberbullying&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Keeping that relationship with your kids strong so they know that you are on their side, will help protect them, and will respond appropriately to anyone who bullies them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's important for your kids to know that if you're providing the resources for them to be online, whether via smart phone or computer at home, you reserve the right to monitor their online activity -- for their own safety. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think this is too much of a breach of privacy, realize that you're also teaching them to think about their online posting -- before it affects their ability to get a job or get into college. When they enter the work world, I guarantee their employer will reserve that very same right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do monitor your kids' online activity, it's important to know what to confront them about and what to let go.  If you start to use it as a way to nitpick every single behavior you find bothersome, you'll risk them creating alternate accounts you know nothing about. It's important you realize that this is a tool for you to help protect your children -- use it while keeping that at the front of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyber Bullying Response:  What to Do If Your Child is a Victim&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, communication is the key.  First, believe your child and the seriousness of the threat. Keep a record of the incidents and pursue appropriate responses from the school (if applicable), the parents, and local law enforcement if need be.  It's critical that your children know that &lt;strong&gt;you are on their side &lt;/strong&gt;and that this won't be tolerated.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/838622/thumbs/s-CYBERBULLYING-mini.jpg?8" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Dem Rep Mourns Loss Of 8-Year-Old Boston Bombings Victim</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/stephen-lynch-martin-richard_n_3094437.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3094437</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T21:35:31Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T21:49:54Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Rep. Stephen Lynch (D-Mass.) appeared on MSNBC Tuesday, mourning the loss of 8-year-old Boston bombing victim Martin Richard. Lynch said he has known the Richard...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nicholas-abrams/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Rep. Stephen Lynch (D-Mass.) appeared on MSNBC Tuesday, mourning the loss of 8-year-old Boston bombing victim Martin Richard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynch said he has known the Richard family for 25 years, describing them as "wonderful, wonderful" people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They are carrying a heavy burden," Lynch said. "They lost their son." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Associated Press reported earlier Tuesday on &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/martin-richards-boston-marathon-remembering_n_3092890.html" target="_hplink"&gt; the Richard family's horrific experience&lt;/a&gt; at Monday's Boston Marathon. Bill, the father, and his oldest son, Henry, were separated from mother Denise, daughter Jane, and Martin, cheering on friends as they crossed the finish line. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Lynch said the family was attempting to get over the race barriers and into the street when the second blast occurred, killing Martin. Bill Richard and the older brother, Henry, were not seriously injured, but doctors did remove ball bearings from Bill Richard's leg, Lynch said.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CBS News reported earlier Tuesday that Jane had suffered a &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-201_162-57579819/eight-year-old-martin-richard-killed-in-boston-bombings/" target="_hplink"&gt;severe leg injury&lt;/a&gt; due to the blast. "Their daughter Jane is still not out of the woods," said Lynch in his Tuesday MSNBC appearance, regarding the condition of Martin's 6-year-old sister. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They are so thankful for the emergency responders," Lynch added, "The family is also very thankful for the Dorchester community, the city of Boston, the state and the country for their show of support."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090018/thumbs/s-MARTIN-RICHARD-DEAD-STEPHEN-LYNCH-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Colic In Babies Linked With Later Migraines</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/colic-in-babies_n_3095198.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3095198</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T21:23:01Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T21:23:05Z</updated>
    
    <summary>By: Rachael Rettner, MyHealthNewsDaily Senior Writer Published: 04/16/2013 04:36 PM EDT on MyHealthNewsDaily Some babies who cry incessantly may be experiencing an early form of...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Samakow</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-samakow/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;By: Rachael Rettner, MyHealthNewsDaily Senior Writer &lt;br /&gt;
Published: 04/16/2013 04:36 PM EDT on MyHealthNewsDaily&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Some babies who cry incessantly may be experiencing an early form of a migraine headache, a new study from France suggests.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; In the study, children ages 6 to 18 who visited an emergency room for migraine headaches were about six times more likely to have experienced colic — or frequent, unexplained crying — as an infant compared with children who visited the emergency room for other reasons.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The association was specific for migraines — there was no link between typical, less severe tension headaches and the likelihood of experiencing colic as an infant.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The study adds to a growing body of research linking &lt;a href="http://www.myhealthnewsdaily.com/2513-infant-colic-migraine-headache.html"&gt;infant colic with migraines&lt;/a&gt;. For instance, a study presented last year at American Academy of Neurology meeting found that women who had migraines were about twice as likely as those without migraines to have babies with colic. (Migraines can run in families.) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The new findings suggest infant colic and migraines may be symptoms of the same underlying condition, said study researcher Dr. Luigi Titomanlio, of the pediatric emergency department at Robert Debré Hospital in Paris.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; However, the study found only an association, and cannot prove that infant colic is an early sign of &lt;a href="http://www.myhealthnewsdaily.com/2267-migraines-linked-depression-women.html"&gt;migraine headaches&lt;/a&gt;. And even if this were true, researchers don't know if colicky babies are experiencing head pain or some other type of discomfort.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Studies that follow children forward in time are needed to confirm the link, the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Colic and migraines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; A baby is considered colicky if it cries at least three hours a day, three days a week for three weeks, and the crying is not due to a medical problem.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The cause of colic is not known, although some have suggested colicky babies are experiencing abdominal pain caused by gas. A study published earlier this year found that some &lt;a href="http://www.myhealthnewsdaily.com/3433-gut-bacteria-infant-colic.html"&gt;colicky babies have abnormal gut bacteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; In the new study, Titomanlio and colleagues analyzed information from 208 children who were diagnosed with migraines after visiting emergency rooms between April and June 2012, and 471 children who visited the ER for other reasons during the same period. Researchers interviewed parents about symptoms of colic their child experienced as a baby, and also looked at notes taken by the child's doctor when the child was an infant.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; About 73 percent of kids with migraines experienced colic as an infant, while only 26 percent of kids without migraines were colicky.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Because the study asked parents to think back to when their children were babies, it's possible they did not accurately remember how much their children cried, the researchers noted.  However, the parents' reports usually matched information in the doctor's notes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Better treatments?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Knowing the cause of colic may lead to improved treatments for the condition, said Dr. Jefry Biehler, a pediatrician at Miami Children's Hospital, who was not involved in the study.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;Colic has been elusive as far as the true cause, and pediatricians are always looking to try and find new, safe therapies that are effective and, of course, cause no harm,&amp;quot; Biehler said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Biehler stressed that at this time, it's too soon to test &lt;a href="http://www.myhealthnewsdaily.com/686-chronic-daily-headache-oxytocin-hormones-101216.html"&gt;migraine treatments&lt;/a&gt; on infants. Even if migraines turn out to be related to colic, the crying could have other causes as well, Biehler said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Another condition, called cyclic vomiting syndrome, in which children experience frequent and serious episodes of nausea and vomiting, often occurs in kids who later go on to develop migraines.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;If colic is an early form of migraine, this suggests that migraine disorders may represent a continuum, from colic in infancy to cyclic vomiting syndrome in young children to childhood and adult migraine,&amp;quot; Drs. Leon Epstein and Phyllis Zee, of the Feinberg School of Medicine at Northwestern University in Chicago, wrote in an editorial accompanying the study.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Further research is needed to examine why colic might be connected to migraines. Titomanlio speculates that inflammation around nerve fibers in the gut and the brain could cause both conditions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The study and editorial are published in today's (April 16) issue of the Journal of the American Medical Association.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Pass in on: In some cases, infant colic and migraines may be symptoms of the same underlying condition, a new study suggests.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;Follow Rachael Rettner &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/RachaelRettner"&gt;&lt;em&gt;@RachaelRettner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Follow MyHealthNewsDaily &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/MyHealth_MHND"&gt;&lt;em&gt;@MyHealth_MHND&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/MyHealthNewsDaily"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&amp; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/103155634052611125253/posts"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google+&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.myhealthnewsdaily.com/2131-10-medical-myths.html'&gt;10 Medical Myths that Just Won't Go Away&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.myhealthnewsdaily.com/3369-baby-myths-debunked.html'&gt;7 Baby Myths Debunked&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.myhealthnewsdaily.com/667-common-pregnancy-myths.html'&gt;11 Big Fat Pregnancy Myths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; Copyright 2013 MyHealthNewsDaily, a TechMediaNetwork company. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. ]]&gt; &lt;/content&gt; &lt;/article&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090267/thumbs/s-COLIC-IN-BABIES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Carbon Monoxide Kills Family Of 4</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/carbon-monoxide-kills-4-i_0_n_3095189.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3095189</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T21:17:53Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T21:47:46Z</updated>
    
    <summary>QUAKERTOWN, Pa. -- Carbon monoxide apparently killed a married couple and their two children in an eastern Pennsylvania home where police found a car running...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/david-moye/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;QUAKERTOWN, Pa. -- Carbon monoxide apparently killed a married couple and their two children in an eastern Pennsylvania home where police found a car running in the garage, stunning friends and neighbors who recalled the family Tuesday as happy and outgoing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn't clear whether the car was left running accidentally, or whether it was an intentional act. State police declined to comment on the investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Police were called to the home in Milford Township, Bucks County, at 11:20 p.m. Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"When troopers arrived at the residence, they found the house was clearly filled with high levels of carbon monoxide from a running vehicle in a garage below (inside) the residence," state police Lt. Vincent D'Angelo said in a news release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fire department also responded and discovered the victims. Efforts to revive them were unsuccessful. All four "appeared to have died from carbon monoxide poisoning," D'Angelo said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Police identified the victims as Gary and Michele Reitnauer and their children, Kimberly, 16, and Jamie, 10. Property records show the couple bought their ranch-style home, at the end of a long driveway in rural Bucks County, in 1996.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Good man," a nephew, Rob Zern, told reporters as he left the home. "The family was trying to save each other and it didn't work out ... don't know what all went wrong, but it's a tragedy all around."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Quakertown Community School District announced the deaths on its website and said counselors would be made available to help grieving students and teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six high school classmates of Kimberly Reitnauer placed flowers on the family's mailbox Tuesday afternoon, then formed a circle, clasped hands and prayed. Afterward, they remembered their friend as a highly intelligent student near the top of her class, and as a talented musician who played piano and trumpet. She was happy, kind and humble, they said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Everyone here loved her. She always had a smile on her face. Her whole family did. They were just the happiest people, and they made everyone else feel the same way," said Aislinn Strohecker, 17, a close friend and neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neighbors said there was no inkling of trouble in the Reitnauer home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michele Reitnauer, 58, gave Christmas cookies every year to a well-drilling company down the gravel road, and would fetch the company's mail when she got her own, according to Gloria Mayberry, a secretary at the firm. Gary Reitnauer, 59, known as "Ozzy," would use the bucket on his John Deere tractor to take his trash can to the end of the drive, a cigar usually hanging from his mouth, she recalled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The children were adopted from China, according to Maggie Chambers, a neighbor and Strohecker's mother. She said they were "just the sweetest family."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's not that kind of family. For me to even think for a minute that this was a deliberate thing, it's just not them," Chambers said. "It's not."&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090315/thumbs/s-CARBON-MONOXIDE-FAMILY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Dads Understand Baby Cries As Well As Moms</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/recognizing-babies-cries_n_3094961.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3094961</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T21:06:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T21:07:01Z</updated>
    
    <summary>By: Tia Ghose, LiveScience Staff Writer Published: 04/16/2013 11:50 AM EDT on LiveScience Dads are just as good as Moms at identifying their babies' unique...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Samakow</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-samakow/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;By: Tia Ghose, LiveScience Staff Writer &lt;br /&gt;
Published: 04/16/2013 11:50 AM EDT on LiveScience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Dads are just as good as Moms at identifying their babies' unique cries, new research suggests.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The findings, published today (April 16) in the journal Nature Communications, suggest experience, not maternal instinct, leads to the better recognition.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;Before this study it was thought that mothers were more able to recognize their child from their cries than the fathers,&amp;quot; said study co-author Nicolas Mathevon, a bioacoustician at Jean Monnet University in France. &amp;quot;Fathers are as good as mothers at this task and it's just a matter of learning.&amp;quot; [&lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/15950-countdown-history-12-good-dads.html"&gt;Father Tales: History's 12 Most Doting Dads&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Animal cries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; It's not clear that being able to distinguish one baby's cry from another is important for humans.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;We are not like penguins with children lost among hundreds of others that we have to recognize,&amp;quot; Mathevon told LiveScience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Still, being able to pick their baby's cries from others could mean a parent is better able to identify other needs, such as hunger or pain, from the teary wails, Mathevon said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Past studies suggested that women were in general better than men at this task, and some researchers still hold the view that a &amp;quot;&lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/19108-baby-love-human-brain.html"&gt;maternal instinct&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; rooted at least partly in genetics could explain this difference. Still other research suggested &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/17461-baby-cries-increase-testosterone.html"&gt;baby cries boost the macho hormone&lt;/a&gt; testosterone in men, something that may trigger &amp;quot;I will protect you&amp;quot; behaviors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;That's my baby&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; To see how men and women differed on the task, the group &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/28721-dads-can-recognize-their-baby-s-cry-too-new-research-suggests-video.html"&gt;recorded baby cries&lt;/a&gt; in two locations — France and the Democratic Republic of Congo. They then asked 27 fathers and 29 mothers to pick their babies cries out from four other babies.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; On average, parents were able to pick out their babies' cries about 90 percent of the time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Men could pick out their little ones' cries just as well as women — provided they spent at least four hours a day with the babies. Men who spent less time with their babies performed significantly worse at the task. The ability to pick out their babies didn't differ cross-culturally or with the baby's sex.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; In follow-up work, Mathevon's team also showed that women who spent less than four hours per day with their tots also performed worse at the cry-recognition task, suggesting that experience, not instinct, honed this ability.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Cooperative breeders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The findings buttress the notion that humans evolved to be cooperative breeders, with not just mothers, but fathers, siblings, aunts and uncles all lending a hand to raise children, Mathevon said. As a result, everyone — not just women — would need the ability to care for a child.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;There's an African saying that you need a village to raise a child, and I think it's well in line with that,&amp;quot; Mathevon said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; As follow-up work, Mathevon wants to see if men and women differ in their ability to pick out specific needs, such as hunger or discomfort, in their babies' cries.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;Follow Tia Ghose on Twitter &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/tiaghose"&gt;&lt;em&gt;@tiaghose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Follow&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;LiveScience &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter/livescience" title="http://twitter.com/#!/livescience"&gt;&lt;em&gt;@livescience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/#!/livescience" title="http://www.facebook.com/#!/livescience"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&amp; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/101164570444913213957/posts"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google+&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Original article on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/28753-dads-identify-babies-cries.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;LiveScience.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/17894-10-scientific-parenting-tips.html'&gt;10 Scientific Tips For Raising Happy Kids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/12932-11-facts-parent-baby-brain.html'&gt;11 Facts Every Parent Should Know About Their Baby's Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/14343-amazing-brainy-baby-abilities.html'&gt;That's Incredible! 9 Brainy Baby Abilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; Copyright 2013 LiveScience, a TechMediaNetwork company. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. ]]&gt; &lt;/content&gt; &lt;/article&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090178/thumbs/s-RECOGNIZING-BABIES-CRIES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>What Nobody Remembers About New Motherhood</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/before-i-forget-what-nobo_n_3095133.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3095133</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T21:06:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T21:12:29Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Early one morning when my daughter Rosie was a few weeks old, I packed her up in a baby carrier and took her to the...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Atlantic</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/teri-dangelo/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Early one morning when my daughter Rosie was a few weeks old, I packed her up in a baby carrier and took her to the drugstore, which felt at the time like an ambitious outing. It had been a rough night, and she was now happily sleeping off her bender. I got into line with my stain stick and baby wipes and let my eyes go out of focus.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090228/thumbs/s-NEW-MOTHERHOOD-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Ann Brenoff: Bomb Shelters Won't Keep Us Safe, And Neither Will Worrying</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ann-brenoff/talking-to-kids-about-tragedy-what-to-tell-the-kids-boston-marathon_b_3092962.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3092962</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T20:56:43Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T20:56:46Z</updated>
    
    <summary>During the 1950s, we regularly practiced air raid drills in elementary school. We were taught to get on all fours in the hallway with our hands locked behind our necks and our chins tucked down. These preparations brought the adults in my life a sense of control over the world's dangers.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Ann Brenoff</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ann-brenoff/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;During the 1950s, we regularly practiced air raid drills in elementary school. We were taught to get on all fours in the hallway with our hands locked behind our necks and our chins tucked down. This was in case the Communists bombed us. The teacher's whistle would be the signal when it was safe to look up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were told there were bad guys in the world, but that the adults in our life could keep us safe, as long as we kept our chins tucked down and didn't look up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also during the 1950s, many families in my neighborhood constructed bomb shelters. In fact, the &lt;a href="http://www.nebraskastudies.org/0900/frameset_reset.html?http://www.nebraskastudies.org/0900/stories/0901_0132.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Civil Defense recommended we all do it&lt;/a&gt;.  If you couldn't dig a bomb shelter in your backyard, you were suppose to construct one in the corner of your basement. We watched our fathers stock our basements with canned food, jugs of water and medical kits, and compare opinions on the wisdom of buying a radiation detector. My Dad was of the opinion that it was a waste of money because the government would just test everybody anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The doors of any bomb shelter worth its name had to be sealed with duct tape -- a double layer. This was to keep out the radiation. And just like the teacher's whistle at school, the air raid blast would be the signal when it was OK to come out again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, we were told there were bad guys in the world, but the adults in our life could keep us safe, as long as we didn't mess with the duct tape seal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These preparations seemed to bring the adults in my life a sense of control over the world's dangers. I remember Dad standing back proudly, admiring his handiwork on the bomb shelter he built over one weekend. He had darkened the basement window so that flying glass wouldn't cut us and lined all the walls with sandbags. He built plywood shelves that contained the provisions the Civil Defense said we would need. When my mother pointed out that Dad had made no preparations for our sleeping, he told her that we'd have plenty of time "on the day" to fetch our pillows and bedding and that he had made the plywood shelves "plenty wide" so we could sleep on them if we moved away all the canned goods. Mom returned to folding laundry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this was the stuff of nightmares that literally followed me into adulthood. I wanted to know what would happen to our dog if we had to go into the bomb shelter. She would come with us, right? Where would she go pee? What if she had to be there with the neighbor's dog who was mean? What if I had to be there for a long time and miss school? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was equally dissatisfied with what they told me at school. I questioned my teachers about the logic of hugging a cement wall because wouldn't chunks of it fall on us when the bombs dropped?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents, my teachers, my government -- they all meant well. They understood that taking action helps people feel in control of the uncontrollable. That, or maybe they really thought duct tape would keep out radiation and tucked chins would spare you injuries from falling cement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I find myself explaining terrorism to children with access to online news 24/7. I tell them how their chances of being a terrorism victim are considerably smaller than getting into a car accident on the busy and dangerous roads we travel on. I tell them that the world has always had crazy people in it and that isn't likely to change. I tell them that worry is nothing more than an attempt to control tomorrow -- and we can't. And I tell them that the pain and empathy they feel for the people of Boston is a healthy thing. But mostly what I tell them is we all do the best we can with the knowledge we have and one thing I know is that duct tape is principally good on the arms of my husband's Laz-E-Boy.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090131/thumbs/s-TALKING-TO-KIDS-ABOUT-TRAGEDY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
