<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/parents/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Parents on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Maureen Sullivan: Sad State Of America's School Libraries</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/maureen-sullivan/state-of-americas-school-_b_3063055.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3063055</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T11:39:36Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T11:39:54Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Providing our children with the best educational resources and empowering all our children to access, evaluate, and use information for academic and personal learning - this is the critical mission of school libraries and librarians.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Maureen Sullivan</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/maureen-sullivan/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Providing our children with the best educational resources and empowering all our children to access, evaluate, and use information for academic and personal learning - this is the critical mission of school libraries and librarians. As an educator and president of the American Library Association (ALA), I am concerned that school administrators may not fully understand the critical role school libraries and their librarians play in fostering and academic achievement and student success in a technology-driven world.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
As school libraries celebrate National Library Week (April 14 - 20) and School Library Month during April, the American Library Association's State of America's Libraries Report, an analysis of data from 2011 to 2012, projects a stormy horizon for our nation's school libraries.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
The report shows that funding for school libraries in 2013 is more uncertain since sequestration began on March 1, 2013. The full effect of sequestration on school libraries and student education will become more apparent as time passes, but some effects are already clear. Under sequestration funding to the Department of Education was cut more than 5.2 percent. This is likely to have a direct impact on grant programs that provide school library funding. One example is the Innovative Approaches to Literacy program. The Library Services and Technology Act (LSTA) also has been cut by more than 5.2 percent. This is the only federal funding that is exclusively set aside for libraries. This reduced funding comes at a time when school libraries are already dealing with budget reductions at the state and local level.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Recently the ALA has tracked multiple news reports regarding school districts that have placed school librarian positions on the chopping block in response to budget deficits. Do school officials who are making these decisions understand the valuable resource that they are casting aside? Do they know that that the ability to find accurate and reliable information to solve problems and make decisions has been identified as an essential 21st century skill by business leaders? Do these school districts consider the effects of eliminating librarians on student learning and student success?&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
For example, Pasco County (Fla.) School Superintendent Kurt Browning proposed a plan to eliminate 28 school media specialist positions in the next school year because of a budget shortfall. Such a reduction will have a strong negative impact on students' academic learning, their opportunity to pursue personal interests, and even their motivation to read.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
In Sarasota, Florida, more than 18,000 middle and high school students may be without a school librarian. Local school board officials there are considering a proposal to eliminate all school media specialists. If this action is taken, there will be no school librarian to support classroom learning and the students' self-directed education outside of the classroom.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
School Districts in Louisiana, Maryland, Washington State and New York State also are considering proposals or reorganization plans that would eliminate school librarians. Tough choices must be made in this economic climate, but eliminating school librarians and slashing funding for school library resources is not the answer. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
School librarians offer students much more than access to books. They serve as a vital component of the education teams found in today's schools. Librarians teach essential skills of inquiry, critical thinking, digital citizenship and technology. They foster a love of reading. Their efforts to educate our children are recognized by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards. They are understood to be educators whose instruction can be measured to meet standards for professional teaching excellence.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
How will students meet the new Common Core Standards without the guidance of school librarians? Schools are adopting more technologies to meet the Common Core guidelines. Yet it seems that many school administrators hold a false assumption that search engines, Wikipedia, and social media are adequate substitutions for the research expertise - and the guidance of - school librarians.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
This assumption could not be further away from the truth. School librarians help more than 30 million students each week navigate a vast landscape of digital content, because the majority of students still lack the ability to analyze information found online.   &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Pew Research Center's Internet &amp; American Life Project Online Survey of Teachers&lt;/em&gt; found that although the Internet has opened up a vast world of information for today's students, their digital literacy skills have yet to catch up. Twenty-four percent of those surveyed stated that students lack the ability to assess the quality and accuracy of information they find online. Another 33 percent reported that students lack the ability to recognize bias in online content.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
It has been proven time and again that school librarians are essential to effective learning throughout K-12 education.  More than 60 education and library studies have produced clear evidence that school library media programs staffed by a qualified school librarian have a strong and positive impact on student academic achievement.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
As budgets continue to tighten and tough choices need to be made, I urge local and national leaders to recognize the value of our school libraries and librarians. School librarians make a significant difference in student achievement and their work is a critical component of the success of all of our children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maureen Sullivan is the president of the American Library Association (ALA).  The ALA is the oldest and largest library association in the world, with 58,000 members. Its mission is to promote the highest quality library and information services and public access to information.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1082412/thumbs/s-SCHOOL-LIBRARIES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Claudia Cevenini and Sue Wildish: The Rudest Question You Can Ask A Post 50 Woman</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/claudia-cevenini-and-sue-wildish/without-children-childless-and-middle-aged_b_3042829.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3042829</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T10:25:29Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T11:13:48Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There are two questions I get asked with an annoying regularity. They come as a pair.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Claudia Cevenini and Sue Wildish</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/claudia-cevenini-and-sue-wildish/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;There are two questions I get asked with an annoying regularity. They come as a pair.&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
The first is: "Why aren't you married?" This one I dispatch easily: I either go for the laugh, "I'm still waiting for that billionaire." Or -- if the questioner is an ass I will say: "No one ever wanted me. I guess I am just not worth being loved." My voice will catch and I will avert my eyes sadly (a la Princess Di).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The follow up: "Got any kids?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not being married and in your 50s is like having a weird stain on your clothing or food in your teeth. People want to help you -- but they don't know how. So they look away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not having any kids implies a problem. The subtext is: single women, married or divorced women, straight or gay women, women over 40 can have kids. So why didn't you? &lt;em&gt;What's wrong with you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We Western chicks in our 40s and 50s were given carte blanche for life. We're the first generation of women after feminism -- we got to make our own choices: work, travel, contraception, abortion, partners. We could choose not to procreate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But did we pay a price for all that freedom?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claudia always knew she didn't want children: "My clock never ticked. And now (at 50) when reproduction is not completely impossible but highly unlikely: I have no regrets." But she is a step mom -- so she is kind of off the hook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did flirt with the idea for a couple of months in the mid-1990s -- but I didn't want to give up my job. There was no way I could have lived on the road with kids along. And leaving them at home for weeks at a time just wouldn't have been fair. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-04-10-Scan4.jpeg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-04-10-Scan4.jpeg" width="212" height="320" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;The author (right) and Carla in the mid-90s&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As Claudia and I explored the issue -- we realized how many of our close girlfriends are childless (urgh -- even that word implies a lacking). And decided to discover why that was. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The replies surpassed our expectations. Who knew our friends had been sitting with all this pain and wisdom? Or, that they would be so willing to tell us about it. Not everyone was thrilled. As Simonetta (an ex-music business guru -- just turned 60) pointed out succinctly: "Asking a woman why she is childless is even ruder than asking how much money she makes." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"For me it wasn't much of a choice", said Annamaria, (52, who writes for TV and radio): "My maternal instinct never kicked in. I remember, even as a child playing with my dolls: I would pretend they were my students, not my children."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kimberly, a writer/professor in her mid-40s, seconded that emotion: "Friends and even strangers would tell me that having children is the best thing this world has to offer, and if I didn't, I would regret it. They told me that I would never know the beauty of 'true, unconditional love'."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I would say in all honesty I had no maternal instincts until I hit 40," admitted Carla (49/ex rock-chick and now property flipper). "Which didn't give me much time. But I look back now and see my life was pretty selfish, and in some ways, I was very immature, certainly about relationships." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"(For me) it boils down to one thing: I don't have the energy..." wrote Kimberly. "I would rather focus on my career and my husband. I feel my choices may be considered selfish, but they are also selfless. I know I will never hold my own sweet child, but I just don't think I could 'do it all'."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mercia (a marketing exec, just turned 41) felt the same: "I understood very early on that my personality would not have allowed me to be a working mother. The guilt and pressures of doing both (jobs) well would've driven me crazy. I made the conscious decision to be financially independent and have a career."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relationships, failed and otherwise, also played their part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carla: "I met someone six months after my 40th birthday and spent a year in Australia with him. My relationships have never segued into one another. I spent many years as a single woman and I remember, vividly, sitting on the plane home -- coming to terms with the fact that I probably faced spending years on my own again. And along with the loss of the relationship -- went my last chance to have a child." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mercia's marriage "was not in a good place from the start. I was determined to not have children until we could sort out our problems. We never did. We got divorced. And I am very grateful that I did not have children."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also an element of bad timing, which Carla laid out candidly. "It came down to: wrong man/right time, right man/wrong time," she wrote. "I have just married for the first time at the age of 49. My husband is 47 and has one daughter. There is no doubt for either of us that, had we been younger, we would have tried to have a child together."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We read sadder notes too. For some friends -- their choice was informed by loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Spanish friend told of a miscarriage late in her second trimester. It was an event so devastating she never tried for a baby again. "The blood and the pain and that little body that I saw were too much for me," she said. "After that, for me, it just wasn't possible anymore". &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Fabienne had terminated a pregnancy when an amniocentesis revealed her baby had Down syndrome. "I know what people say -- that Down babies are loving and non-judgemental and sweet, but what if I hadn't been able to love him? What if I couldn't bear to be with him -- how would that have turned out?" She never took that chance again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for others -- being childless wasn't a choice; it was the end of a dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"If you don't mind -- I don't want to be part in this" wrote one friend. I heard the echo of sadness and understood. For her something she had hoped and wished for had never come to pass.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
L was more direct: "You know the answer to that Sue -- I couldn't find anyone who wanted to marry me let alone have kids with me. And I didn't want to do it on my own."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won't be quite so flip next time someone asks me "Why not married, why no kids?" These questions go to the heart of femininity, to the core of being a woman. The answers define us -- both in other people's eyes and our own. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps we owe it to all the women before and after us to look the questioner in the eye and say instead: "you know, that's a complicated one, and I would like to do your question justice. How long have you got?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="border-bottom:solid 1px;text-transform:uppercase;font-size:10px;font-weight:bold;font-family:sans-serif;"&gt;Earlier on Huff/Post50:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--250597--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084272/thumbs/s-WITHOUT-CHILDREN-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'The Show With Vinny': Kesha Gives Uncle Vino A Glitter Bath</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/the-show-with-vinny-kesha-glitter-video_n_3082851.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3082851</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T07:45:02Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T08:38:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Fans of "Jersey Shore" got a special sneak preview of Vinny Guadagnino's new series after the "MTV Movie Awards." The interview project is called "The...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Hughes</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jason-hughes/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Fans of "&lt;a href="http://remotecontrol.mtv.com/2013/04/14/jersey-shore-cast-mtv-movie-awards-photos/" target="_hplink"&gt;Jersey Shore&lt;/a&gt;" got a special sneak preview of &lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/tv-movies/guadagnino-mom-takes-lead-show-vinny-article-1.1315356" target="_hplink"&gt;Vinny Guadagnino's&lt;/a&gt; new series after the "&lt;a href="http://www.mtv.com/news/articles/1705670/rebel-wilson-les-miserables-movie-awards.jhtml" target="_hplink"&gt;MTV Movie Awards&lt;/a&gt;." The interview project is called "&lt;a href="http://www.mtv.com/news/articles/1705634/show-with-vinny-mtv.jhtml" target="_hplink"&gt;The Show With Vinny&lt;/a&gt;," and features Vinny interviewing various celebrities in his home ... with his family. It's certainly a unique take on the interview show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure things kicked off with an outrageous bang, the preview episode saw Vinny and his family welcoming &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2309187/MTV-Music-Awards-2013-Kesha-Snoop-Lion-smoke-suspicious-spliff-onstage.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Kesha&lt;/a&gt; into their home. While she was there, she treated Vinny's Uncle Nino to a glitter treatment. By the end of it, he was absolutely covered in glitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"“It’s really impressive," Kesha said. "This is like the beginning of the weirdest porno."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/tv-movies/guadagnino-mom-takes-lead-show-vinny-article-1.1315356#ixzz2QVm5f3o5" target="_hplink"&gt;Vinny explained what makes his show special&lt;/a&gt; to the New York Daily News. "These huge superstars are coming into the house as regular people ... They leave the Hollywood life behind for a couple of hours," he said. "My mother and uncle don’t know who any of these celebrities are, so they treat them like regular people and they like that."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kesha is actually spinning off into her own show, a docuseries premiering ten days before Vinny's show. Catch Kesha's "&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6cH4NsS4cRg" target="_hplink"&gt;My Crazy Beautiful Life&lt;/a&gt;" when it debuts on April 23, and then come back for Vinny Guadagnino and "The Show With Vinny" when it premieres May 2.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TV Replay scours the vast television landscape to find the most interesting, amusing, and, on a good day, amazing moments, and delivers them right to your browser.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1086440/thumbs/s-THE-SHOW-VINNY-KESHA-130414-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Hell Of American Day Care</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/hell-of-american-day-care_n_3082757.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3082757</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T06:56:22Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T07:02:55Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Excellent day cares are available, of course, if you have the money to pay for them and the luck to secure a spot. But the...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>New Republic</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jade-walker/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Excellent day cares are available, of course, if you have the money to pay for them and the luck to secure a spot. But the overall quality is wildly uneven and barely monitored, and at the lower end, it’s Dickensian.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1086423/thumbs/s-HELL-OF-AMERICAN-DAY-CARE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Biggest Factor In Whether Parents Vaccinate Is ... ?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/vaccination-choices-_n_3070086.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3070086</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T04:04:56Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T04:04:58Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When she was pregnant, Ashley Grover Desmarais did not give much thought to vaccinating her child. It hadn't occurred to her that she could do...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Catherine Pearson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/catherine-pearson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;When she was pregnant, Ashley Grover Desmarais did not give much thought to vaccinating her child. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It hadn't occurred to her that she could do anything "out of the norm" until late in her pregnancy, when a friend posted on Facebook the reasons why her daughter was unvaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The post prompted her to do some research. Grover Desmarais, 30, discussed vaccination with her pediatrician, other friends and family, and read various books and articles on the subject. Ultimately, she settled on an augmented schedule: Her daughter, who will be 3 in June, and her son, almost 1, will be fully vaccinated by the time they're school age, but they are following a delayed timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Many of my other friends have also done augmented schedules for their children's vaccinations," said Grover Desmarais. "I think it's because there's more awareness, more research available, and we're all able to post our findings and experiences on social media."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite clear support from major medical groups in the United States, some parents grapple with whether to vaccinate their children according to the &lt;a href="http://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/schedules/easy-to-read/child.html" target="_hplink"&gt;immunization schedule&lt;/a&gt; recommended by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. A new study, among the first to probe the social factors that affect parents' decisions, found that friends, family and health care providers play a huge role in what parents choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers surveyed 196 first-time parents about who they discussed vaccination with, as well as the types of sources they consulted, including books, media outlets or research articles. One hundred twenty-six followed the nationally recommended vaccination schedule, and 70 did not. (The study, published in the journal &lt;a href="http://pediatrics.aappublications.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pediatrics&lt;/a&gt; on Monday, was based in Washington, a state that has one of &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/09/20/health/washington-state-makes-it-harder-to-forgo-immunizations.html" target="_hplink"&gt;lowest vaccination rates&lt;/a&gt; in the U.S.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly all the parents indicated they had what the researchers called "people networks" -- groups of individuals whom they consulted about vaccination. Parents who decided to delay vaccinations, who opted for only some vaccinations, or who decided against vaccination -- dubbed "non-conformers" -- tended to have slightly larger networks. They also tended to have significantly more non-conformers in their social circles. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average, 72 percent of non-conformers' networks recommended against following the recommended vaccination schedule, versus only 13 percent of those in "conformers'" social networks. Overall, parents said that their partners were the most influential people in their networks, followed by doctors, family members and friends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents who did not stick to the recommended vaccination schedule were also more likely to seek information from books, research articles and mainstream media outlets. But the variable that best predicted parents' choices was the number of people in their networks who advocated for something other than government recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"For the majority of the parents in this study, the decision came down to the percent of people in their networks saying, 'don't do this' in one form or another," study author Emily Brunson, a medical anthropologist with Texas State University-San Marcos, told The Huffington Post. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brunson said it is unclear if the parents in the study knew whether they were going to vaccinate before having their babies, then constructed networks that reflected the decisions they made, or if the social networks influenced parents' choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Are the networks driving the decisions, or are the decisions driving the networks?" she asked, adding that she hopes to tackle the question next in her research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, she said the study has a clear message for parents: Who they surround themselves with can have a significant impact on the decisions they make, as can what they say to family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It, frankly, really does matter when you're having conversations with other people about vaccination," Brunson said. "It actually has a big effect."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's something mom Ella Rucker, 40, takes very seriously. She chatted with friends and family about vaccination, and read stories about parents who were staunchly opposed to it, but Rucker ultimately decided it was important to follow the government guidelines. Though Rucker is certain it was the right decision for her 3-year-old daughter, she is careful about what she says to friends when they come to her for advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I tell them what I did, and why it was right for [my daughter]," she said. "But I don't want to be responsible for what anyone else decides."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084230/thumbs/s-VACCINATION-CHOICE-mini.jpg?13" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Daniel R. Porterfield, Ph.D.: The Pre-Commencement Speech Seniors Need Now</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/daniel-r-porterfield-phd/college-graduation_b_3068375.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3068375</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T03:46:10Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T03:46:18Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I find that the most engaged students may suffer these pre-commencement blues most acutely. It's precisely because they've cared so much that they may grieve so deeply -- during what they think should be a joyous period.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Daniel R. Porterfield, Ph.D.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/daniel-r-porterfield-phd/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Commencement season will soon be upon us, which means that more than two million black-robed graduates will conclude their college years hearing the sage advice of all manner of speakers, from peers to politicians to celebrities. However, my 16 years of college teaching tell me that seniors need to hear more personal words of wisdom &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt; from friends, mentors and loved ones as they deal with the strong emotions attendant on closing this distinct chapter in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seniors often feel a heightened appreciation for their college experience -- the insights of a seminar, the community of a team, the thrill of performance and artistic creation or the self-driven discoveries of a thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, they also experience tremendous stress. Of course, many worry about finding the right job or taking out loans for graduate school. And this transition provokes deep questions. What do I want to do and become? Where should I be? How can I use my education? Am I ready to be out on my own?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's also the anxiety provoked by the upcoming shift in identity and community. Some graduates can feel regret over unresolved relationships with friends, professors, coaches and mentors. Some feel remorse for not having achieved more in college, particularly in comparison with others. And some feel intense pressure to finish ambitious academic projects. All of this can be overwhelming, and we should be empathetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that the most engaged students may suffer these pre-commencement blues most acutely -- the meaning-makers who have studied seriously, led clubs, played sports, counseled peers, edited newspapers, tutored children and performed on stage. It's precisely because they've cared so much that they may grieve so deeply -- during what they think should be a joyous period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such highs and lows have been part of the academic year's annual rhythm for as long as we've had colleges, but the feelings are experienced anew by each class of seniors. Rather than waiting for commencement speakers to provide wisdom, there's a lot that families, faculty and friends can say right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we can encourage seniors to make these final days and weeks count. They can share memories with their friends. They can reconnect with people who helped define their early college years. They can seek out professors and advisors, who are used to the rituals of ending. They can say thank you, again and again, to everyone who helped them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, we can help seniors to think of achievement in broad terms. As a reflective exercise, I like to ask my students to imagine writing alternative "resumes" that convey life lessons rather than jobs held and GPAs. From your college years, what learning will truly last? When did you experience joy? When did you cope well with adversity? When did you help someone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to these questions may matter most in the long term, because adulthood isn't simply about honors and titles. It's about developing our capacities for learning, for service, for happiness, for resilience, for giving freely and for lifelong growth. Most of our seniors know deep down that these "achievements" have enduring value and also should be celebrated, but they need to be reminded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And third, for all those young women and men who lament leaving communities they've created and come to love, we can offer a simple truth: You may be graduating, but you don't have to leave. Your college experience will always be a part of you and will grow in significance as your adult identity continues to emerge. For searchers, learners, creators and givers, commencement is not goodbye, but an invitation to a life of meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1086366/thumbs/s-GRADUATION-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Court To Hear Emotional Challenge On Adoption Law</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/14/supreme-court-indian-child-welfare-act_n_3081842.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3081842</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-14T23:38:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-14T23:38:23Z</updated>
    
    <summary>COLUMBIA, S.C. -- The U.S. Supreme Court this week will hear an emotional family challenge to longstanding federal law on the adoption of Native American...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mollie-reilly/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;COLUMBIA, S.C. -- The U.S. Supreme Court this week will hear an emotional family challenge to longstanding federal law on the adoption of Native American children, with several states, tribes and children's welfare groups lining up to support the current rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case involves a South Carolina couple fighting for custody of their adopted daughter who, after a court battle, was returned to her biological father in Oklahoma.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;At issue is the Indian Child Welfare Act, a federal law that gives tribes and relatives a say in decisions affecting children with Native American heritage. Passed in 1978 because of the high number of Indian children being removed from their homes by public and private agencies, the act gives the tribe and relatives a say in decisions affecting the child. In the current case, to be heard Tuesday, more than a dozen states and 23 current and former members of Congress have filed briefs supporting the law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt and Melanie Capobianco adopted a baby several years ago, but the girl's father &amp;ndash;  a member of the Cherokee Nation whom she had never met &amp;ndash; argued that the child's mother gave her up without his consent. The state's highest court sided with him, and she was returned to Oklahoma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Dusten Brown challenged the Capobiancos' adoption, he said federal law favored the girl living with him and growing up learning tribal traditions. A South Carolina court agreed with Brown, who took the girl &amp;ndash; named Veronica, and now age 3 &amp;ndash; back to Oklahoma in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appealing to the state Supreme Court, the Capobiancos said they had bonded with Veronica and argued that removing her was detrimental to her development. But justices sided with Brown last summer, saying in an emotional opinion that, while the Capobiancos were "ideal parents," federal law requires that custodial preference be given to the child's Native American parent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court has considered Native American adoption before. In 1989, the court ruled that it was up to tribal courts to make decisions about Indian adoptions. In that case, a tribal court ultimately ruled that a set of toddler twins could stay with their adoptive parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 18 states that have signed onto a brief supporting the federal law are Alaska, Arizona, California, Colorado, Connecticut, Georgia, Idaho, Illinois, Maine, Michigan, Mississippi, Montana, New Mexico, New York, North Dakota, Oregon, Washington and Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the federal government has filed an amicus brief backing the law, as have more than a dozen child welfare organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State courts have been at odds on the law's application. The American Association of Adoption Attorneys hopes the matter will be clarified by the high court. The group has filed a brief supporting the Capobiancos' case. It says the court previously has ruled on the rights of mothers and unwed fathers &amp;ndash; rights that, a past president of the group said, federal law hasn't defined, at least for Native American children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Those cases clearly state that unwed fathers do not have an automatic fully protected right to participate in decisions about the child," Seattle adoption attorney Mark Demaray said last week during a conference call with reporters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Case law aside, Demaray said, the emotional aspects of the case are hard to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We often refer to cases like this one before the Supreme Court as a tragic situation we all want to avoid," Demaray said. "There's no question this case is tragic for all the families and parties involved in it, particularly for this child, no matter what the outcome."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday's case is Adoptive Couple v. Baby Girl, 12-399.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;___&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruce Smith contributed to this report from Charleston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;___&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kinnard can be reached at &lt;a href='http://www.twitter.com/MegKinnardAP'&gt;http://www.twitter.com/MegKinnardAP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1086246/thumbs/s-SUPREME-COURT-INDIAN-CHILD-WELFARE-ACT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>George W. Bush Welcomes First Grandchild</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/14/margaret-laura-mila-hager-born_n_3081400.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3081400</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-14T20:45:07Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T05:03:57Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Jenna Bush Hager gave birth to a baby girl, Margaret Laura 'Mila' Hager, on Saturday, the Bush family announced in a Sunday statement. The Dallas...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Mollie Reilly</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mollie-reilly/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Jenna Bush Hager gave birth to a baby girl, Margaret Laura 'Mila' Hager, on Saturday, the Bush family &lt;a href="http://trailblazersblog.dallasnews.com/2013/04/george-w-bush-and-his-wife-laura-are-now-grandparents-daughter-jenna-gives-birth-to-margaret-laura-mila-hager.html/" target="_hplink"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; in a Sunday statement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://trailblazersblog.dallasnews.com/2013/04/george-w-bush-and-his-wife-laura-are-now-grandparents-daughter-jenna-gives-birth-to-margaret-laura-mila-hager.html/" target="_hplink"&gt;Dallas Morning News&lt;/a&gt; reports that the former first daughter, who is married to Henry Hager, gave birth to Mila Saturday evening in New York City. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Former President George W. Bush and his wife, Laura, said the baby was named after her grandmothers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Laura and I are thrilled to announce the birth of our grandchild,” read the Bush family's &lt;a href="http://politicalticker.blogs.cnn.com/2013/04/14/jenna-bush-hager-gives-birth-to-baby-girl//" target="_hplink"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;. “We met our beautiful granddaughter today. Jenna and Mila are healthy. And our family is elated.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The couple's first grandchild arrives just in time for the opening of the &lt;a href="http://www.georgewbushlibrary.smu.edu/en/News-and-Events/News/Bush%20Center%20Dedication%20Plans.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;George W. Bush Presidential Center&lt;/a&gt;, which will be dedicated on April 25 and open to the public on May 1. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hager, who has been a correspondent for the "Today Show" since 2009, &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/reliable-source/post/jenna-bush-hager-is-pregnant-she-announces-on-today/2012/12/12/61358e7c-445e-11e2-9648-a2c323a991d6_blog.html" target="_hplink"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; her pregnancy on the NBC program in December.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1086162/thumbs/s-MARGARET-LAURA-MILA-HAGER-BORN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Paris Jackson Opens Up About Her Father</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/14/michael-jacksons-daughter-paris-jackson_n_3081292.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3081292</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-14T20:08:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-14T20:06:50Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Paris Jackson opens up about her late father Michael Jackson in the Mail on Sunday's Event magazine. According to the Daily Mail, the 15-year-old admits...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Leigh Blickley</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/leigh-blickley/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Paris Jackson opens up about her late father Michael Jackson in the Mail on Sunday's Event magazine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Daily Mail, &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/home/event/article-2308275/Paris-Jackson-He-incredible-father--He-wanted-didnt-normal-childhood.html" target="_hplink"&gt;the 15-year-old admits in the mag that Michael was a wonderful father&lt;/a&gt; and that all he wanted was to give her and her brothers Prince, now 16, and Blanket, now 11, a normal childhood. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I have lots of memories of my father. He was an incredible father. We all loved him to death," Paris says, continuing, "He’d try to educate us as much as he could and was always looking out for us. He was very protective." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paris goes on to explain that &lt;a href="http://globalgrind.com/entertainment/paris-jackson-normal-childhood-michael-event-magazine-photos" target="_hplink"&gt;he wanted to give his children the childhood he never had&lt;/a&gt;, which explains why Michael always had them wear face masks while out in public. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"He didn’t want anyone to see what we looked like. That way we could have what he didn’t, which was a normal childhood," she shares. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paris, Prince and Blanket &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/01/paris-jackson-new-look-short-hair_n_2790796.html" target="_hplink"&gt;have been living a life in the spotlight&lt;/a&gt; since Michael's death in July 2009, but Paris insists they are still a lot like any other kids, revealing she attends a public school so she can "have a normal high-school experience."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next on Paris' list? Restoring the Neverland ranch, which &lt;a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/04/paris-jackson-wants-to-restore-neverland/" target="_hplink"&gt;she wants to bring back so that sick children can enjoy it&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I cried and cried," Paris explains of the moment she saw the estate's Ferris Wheel was gone. "It’s beautiful there," she adds, "It still has good energy." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And her positive attitude and devotion to her father might explain why Paris aspires to be a heart surgeon. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I want to help people," Paris simply states. "That's it."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1086141/thumbs/s-MICHAEL-JACKSON-DAUGHTER-PARIS-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: Disney Princesses Get A MAJOR Makeover</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/14/disney-princesses-as-the-avengers_n_3071115.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3071115</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-14T18:44:35Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-14T18:44:51Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Just a few years after Disney bought Marvel, the merger is having a distinct effect on some of each company's most beloved characters... In one...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Emma Mustich</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-mustich/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Just a few years after &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2009/08/31/disney-acquires-marvel-fo_n_272608.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Disney bought Marvel&lt;/a&gt;, the merger is having a distinct effect on some of each company's most beloved characters... In one artist's imagination, at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In work posted on deviantART, Christopher Stoll has &lt;a href="http://christopherstoll.deviantart.com/gallery/37232032?rnrd=38610" target="_hplink"&gt;reimagined Disney princesses (and the Sultan from "Aladdin") as characters from "The Avengers"&lt;/a&gt; -- for instance, transforming Pocahontas into an &lt;a href="http://christopherstoll.deviantart.com/art/Princess-Avengers-CAPTAIN-AMERICA-336921248?q=gallery%3Achristopherstoll%2F37232032&amp;qo=2" target="_hplink"&gt;"empowered"&lt;/a&gt; Captain America and Snow White into an intimidating Hulk-hybrid heroine whose bad side we most definitely wouldn't want to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a time when it's still depressingly normal for franchises like "The Avengers" to be &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/11/sexist-avengers-t-shirts-_n_3063942.html" target="_hplink"&gt;marketed with sexist slogans&lt;/a&gt;, Stoll's art is a powerful way to flip princess culture inside out. And if he's ever moved to put his own images on T-shirts, we already know &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/girl-power-photo-baby_n_3068742.html" target="_hplink"&gt;the perfect model&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/ellievhall/disney-princesses-as-avengers-are-appropriately-badass" target="_hplink"&gt;(h/t Buzzfeed)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1086049/thumbs/s-DISNEY-PRINCESSES-AVENGERS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>14 Fiery Baby Names</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/14/redhead-baby-names_n_3063441.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3063441</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-14T14:57:08Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-14T14:57:09Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Written by Linda Rosenkrantz for Nameberry If red hair runs in your family, you may be looking for a redhead name. The most common way...</summary>
    <author>
        <name/>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nina-zipkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Linda Rosenkrantz for &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Nameberry&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If red hair runs in your family, you may be looking for a redhead name. The most common way to go about finding one is to sort through the long list of names that &lt;em&gt;mean&lt;/em&gt; red-haired, from &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Rory" target="_hplink"&gt;Rory&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Rufus" target="_hplink"&gt;Rufus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Flynn" target="_hplink"&gt;Flynn&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Flanagan" target="_hplink"&gt;Flanagan&lt;/a&gt;. An alternative is to find yourself a worthy ginger namesake, either from the pages of history or a current celeb. So, at the risk of offending by omission such ordinary-named notables as &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Helen" target="_hplink"&gt;Helen&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Troy" target="_hplink"&gt;Troy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Emily " target="_hplink"&gt;Emily&lt;/a&gt; Dickinson, &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Mark" target="_hplink"&gt;Mark&lt;/a&gt; Twain, &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/James" target="_hplink"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Joyce " target="_hplink"&gt;Joyce&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Margaret " target="_hplink"&gt;Margaret&lt;/a&gt; Sanger -- here are our nominations for best-named redheads of all time. Oh -- and where is the most famous redhead of all? Turns out &lt;a href="http://nameberry.com/babyname/Lucille " target="_hplink"&gt;Lucille&lt;/a&gt; Ball’s natural hair color was mousey brown.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1085932/thumbs/s-REDHEAD-BABY-NAMES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Babble.com: Why My Grief Therapist's Baby News Hit So Close To Home</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/babblecom/my-miscarriage-grief_b_3064263.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3064263</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-14T14:22:28Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-14T14:22:32Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I started seeing my therapist, who specializes in loss and grief, a few months after losing my twins at 20 weeks in May. She is an amazing woman who has been through a lot of the same experiences as me, and who deeply understands my loss.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Babble.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/babblecom/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Diana Stone for &lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/pregnancy/my-grief-therapist-told-me-shes-pregnant-with-twins/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||041113||MyGriefTherapistToldMeShesPregnantWithTwins|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;Babble.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started seeing my therapist, who specializes in loss and grief, a few months after losing my twins at 20 weeks in May. She is an amazing woman who has been through a lot of the same experiences as me, and who deeply understands my loss. It's been such an incredibly healing experience to begin working on myself with her help and guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday I went to my first session in nearly three weeks (she'd been sick, I'd been away), and when I sat down, I heard her say, "I have some news..."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked up, and she sure did! She was pretty obviously pregnant, and I squealed. "I'm just a few weeks behind you," she said, and I noticed she seemed really nervous but happy. I was astounded how fast she was showing, and it never even crossed my mind it could be two, even though I knew she had gone through IVF before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea why this hadn't occurred to me, but for some reason it didn't, and I kept chatting away about how excited I was for her, asking how far along, etc. She hesitated during a break and said, "So we may have to work on transference in here now -- for my pregnancy."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at her completely confused. She was having a baby, so was I, this was such a blessing -- did she really think I would lose it over her telling me that? Or? ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's twins."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; wish I could say I hugged her or threw confetti, but instead I burst into tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hated that that was my reaction. I still do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/being-pregnant/2012/02/24/10-things-you-should-never-say-to-a-miscarriage-survivor/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||041113||MyGriefTherapistToldMeShesPregnantWithTwins|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;Related: 10 things you should NEVER say to someone who has had a miscarriage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She waited and I could see her tear up. I was &lt;em&gt;so shocked&lt;/em&gt; that for a few minutes I couldn't find any words at all. I don't know why it hit me so hard; obviously she didn't say, "I'm pregnant with your twins." Knowing how much she'd been through to get to this point, and what a wonderful woman she is, I felt awful that I couldn't muster anything more than an, "I'm so sorry, it was just a bit of a surprise."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a good portion of that session talking about that, and in a way it was almost a relief to deal with her pregnancy, right there, in my face. I want so badly to not have this reaction forever, and this was probably a great place to start. A safe place with someone who completely understands, from a non-emotional view, why I would cry. No offense taken, no hurt feelings, no angry words. She got it, and I was able to start to work on issues that are still there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She has said that if I need to transfer to another therapist at any point she'll understand completely, but I've shared so much of my life and feelings with her I really can't fathom starting over. Especially with us moving in a few months. It's been 11 months since I lost my sons. This is a point where I think it's good for me to begin to work through this. Maybe I'll never be "happy" immediately, there will always be a sharp pang there, but I'd love to not burst into tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realized I feel incredibly protective of her and those babies already. I wouldn't wish what I went through on anyone, and I know how hard twin pregnancies can be. Hers has been rough. I pray each night she's able to make it to viability and beyond. It's an odd mix of feelings to sort out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm working on it. It might get harder in the months to come, but I'm hoping that from this experience I'm able to grow as a person, as a mom who grieves and rejoices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/pregnancy/5-things-you-may-not-expect-after-a-miscarriage-that-could-happen/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||041113||MyGriefTherapistToldMeShesPregnantWithTwins|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;For 5 things you might not expect after a miscarriage, visit Babble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE ON BABBLE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/being-pregnant/2011/10/19/the-many-faces-of-labor-25-powerful-photos-of-women-giving-birth/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||041113||MyGriefTherapistToldMeShesPregnantWithTwins|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;25 powerful photos of women giving birth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/pregnancy/my-pregnancy/etiquette-rules-pregnancy-jokes-humor-rude-comments/etiquette-rules-pregnancy-jokes-humor-rude-comments-1/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||041113||MyGriefTherapistToldMeShesPregnantWithTwins|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;29 things you should NEVER say to a pregnant woman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/pregnancy/conception/prenatal-bucket-list-before-pregnancy/prenatal-bucket-list-before-pregnancy-1/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||041113||MyGriefTherapistToldMeShesPregnantWithTwins|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;10 things you must do before you get pregnant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.babble.com/pregnancy/from-bored-to-overwhelmed-13-ways-to-cope-with-a-high-risk-pregnancy/?cmp=ELP|bbl|lp|HuffingtonPost|Main||041113||MyGriefTherapistToldMeShesPregnantWithTwins|famE|||" target="_hplink"&gt;13 ways to cope with a high-risk pregnancy &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084552/thumbs/s-GRIEF-COUNSELOR-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Monica Bielanko: What I Finally Gave Up To Become A Better Mom</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/monica-bielanko/surrender-dorothy_b_2695715.html?utm_hp_ref=parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2695715</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-14T13:48:14Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-14T13:48:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I find myself really sinking into motherhood in a way I've never experienced before. Up until recently, I engaged myself in battles I should've known I couldn't win.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Monica Bielanko</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/monica-bielanko/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;We've had a kind of rolling sickness affecting our household for the past two months, and while I thoroughly enjoy motherhood, my enjoyment most definitely does not stretch into the perverse realms of tending to sick kids. Sick kids who have suddenly reached that horrific phase of childhood that involves pinching and whacking each other over and over and over and over again and after each transgression, shouting, "&lt;em&gt;Mom, he hit me! Mom, she pinched me! Mom, Sister hurt me! Mom, Henry's stanking me!" &lt;/em&gt;Yes, Henry's innocent and necessary habit of bowel elimination is perceived by Violet as an attack. Come to think of it, I'm starting to perceive that shit as an attack as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, it's 5 a.m. and everyone is sleeping, although the occasional phlegm-rattling cough echoes through the hall and strikes fear in my heart. Not because of the sickness itself -- that's old news -- but because I will go batshit if a cough attack wakes up one of them. This 5 a.m. business is the only time I can get to myself! A 25-year-old me just gave herself a hysterectomy when she realized the kind of early bird-ness inherent in motherhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I find myself really sinking into motherhood in a way I've never experienced before. I kinda sort of feel like I've been fighting motherhood until now. It's hard to describe what I mean, but up until recently, I engaged myself in battles I should've known I couldn't win. Trying to get them to eat certain foods, to wear certain things, to brush their teeth, even. I found myself uttering trite parenting phrases like BECAUSE I SAID SO or YOU HAVE UNTIL THE COUNT OF THREE and oh my God I totally said YOU ARE CRUISIN' FOR A BRUISIN' a couple weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But lately, I find that a lot of the battles I pick with my kids aren't that big of a deal and won't affect whether or not I ultimately raise serial killers. For instance, if they don't want to eat, I don't force the issue. "Fine. You're done," I say without emotion. I tell them to take their plate to the sink. Most of the time they continue eating. Funny, isn't it? It's like they want the fight. As if they take pleasure in my begging. Without the fight there is no enjoyment in refusing to eat. Little sadists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just letting it all go is a kind of reverse psychology (that often works!) and also a new-found freedom. But you can't view it as reverse psychology strategy or else you're still angling to win. You have to truly let go. Don't want to brush your teeth? Fine. Go to bed with dirty teeth, I don't care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before, I would've struggled with a screaming Henry in a desperate effort to brush his teeth, sometimes losing myself in the struggle in the same way I would in an argument with Serge. I wanted to win, but for the wrong reasons. Wanted him to brush his teeth because I'M THE MOM AND I'M TELLING YOU TO BRUSH YOUR TEETH AND YOU ARE DEFYING ME and not so much because I wanted him to have clean teeth. The clean teeth were important, yes, and the impetus for the battle, but somewhere after minute ten of a logic-defying argument with a 2-year-old, I was just trying to prove my authority, my mom-ness, and make him brush. Now I let it go. Not all the time, mind you. But when I see the struggle will be epic and pointless I just shrug and tell them to have dirty teeth for all I care. More often than not, they end up doing what I want when they see it isn't that important to me. Oh, they're evil, to be sure. Mind games like no other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this sinking into motherhood I refer to isn't just because I'm learning to pick my battles better; it's a general state of mind. The best way to describe it is that I'm enjoying the chores of motherhood now as opposed to rushing through them to get to the other side. Instead of rushing through bathtime so the kids are clean already and I can attempt to read another chapter of &lt;em&gt;Les Miserables&lt;/em&gt; (very slow-going), I park myself on the bathroom floor and enjoy bathtime. Instead of being annoyed by traffic on the way to pre-school to the point of distraction, I engage the kids in conversation and am usually dazzled by the craziness that comes out of their mouths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shift comes from an acceptance of kids &lt;em&gt;as they are&lt;/em&gt;. Toddlers are insane, kids are nuts and you can fight it until you're as cuckoo as they are or just relax and roll with it. And not just roll with it, but &lt;em&gt;enjoy&lt;/em&gt; it, because that's why you became a parent, for godsakes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, that's it! &lt;em&gt;That's&lt;/em&gt; what I'm trying to say. I finally got to it there after a couple rambling paragraphs: Enjoy the children in all their children-ness and be mindful of not losing your mind over the little things. Their children-ness is why you became a parent, is it not? And before you know it, the whole gig will be over and you'll be sitting in your La-Z-Boy looking for an episode of "CSI" you haven't seen 454 times and complaining that you're out of pickled onions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sink into it. Revel in it. Even the arguments that make your brain leak out of your ears. Pretty soon, your only arguments will be with "The Bachelor" from season 745 when he gives the wrong girl the rose and you give him The Business from your recliner in between sips of your nightly warm milk before bedtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oop. Here's Henry now. Creeping through the secret passage that connects our closets. Time to revel in it. The early morning cartoons, silly arguments, demands for milk, dirty diapers and runny noses. I can sink into it all... Except maybe the Dora theme song.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/997877/thumbs/s-MONICA-BIELANKO-mini.jpg?17" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Can Maryland Ban Cyberbullying?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/14/maryland-cyberbullying_n_3070765.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>newscred-5d5820e4e706d30c5bad65a2e25afd7e</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-14T13:32:54Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-14T13:33:55Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A 2013 Maryland General Assembly bill bearing the name of a Howard County teenager who killed herself last year is expected to be signed into...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Baltimore Sun</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/arin-greenwood/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;A 2013 Maryland General Assembly bill bearing the name of a Howard County teenager who killed herself last year is expected to be signed into law, but it stands on shaky constitutional ground, an official of the Maryland ACLU said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The "Misuse of Interactive Computer Service" bill is also known simply as Grace's Law, named for Grace McComas, the 15-year-old Glenelg High School student who committed suicide on Easter Sunday last year after months of being harassed on social media sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her parents, David and Chris McComas, said they tried to stop the malicious messages, but police and courts told them nothing could be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate version of the statewide bill making it a misdemeanor to harass youngsters online was sponsored by Howard County Sen. Allan H. Kittleman, a Republican who lives in Glenelg and whose children went to school with McComas and one of her sisters. He called the bill "one of the most important pieces of legislation that got through the Assembly this year."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is whether the bill, sponsored on the House side by Del. Jon S. Cardin of Baltimore County and which went through several revisions, will survive potential challenges on grounds that it violates the right to free speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sara Love, the policy director for the American Civil Liberties Union of Maryland, thinks not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"My heart went out to the McComas family," Love said. "The ACLU understands completely the problem of cyberbullying. Unfortunately a portion of this bill is still unconstitutional."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love said the portion of the bill that prohibits making threats online is in keeping with existing law, but not a part that refers to using a computer in "a course of conduct that inflicts serious emotional distress."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That line, she said, could potentially restrain a wide range of language, making the law "too broad to pass constitutional muster."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love said "society needs to address the issue of cyberbullying" but that this law is not the way to do it. She did not say the ACLU is planning legal action at the moment, but said the law is vulnerable to challenge, either on the basis of its application in a specific case or for the constitutional issues it raises on its face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Courts have established that except for threats and obscenity, "you cannot criminalize speech," Love said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kittleman said the measure went through several versions as lawmakers tried to draft a law that would protect youngsters and also pass a constitutional test. He said he felt the final version struck that balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You had to narrowly tailor it so it wouldn't violate someone's right to go out and Tweet something," Kittleman said. He said that's why the "course of conduct" language was added, to make clear that this was not meant to punish someone who just sent a message or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said the bill -- which sets penalties of up to a year in jail or a $500 fine -- "gives a tool to the state's attorney. This is something we could prosecute. ... If we'd had that a year and a half ago, maybe the person who was doing this to Grace would have stopped."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;arthur.hirsch@baltsun.com ___&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="nc_footer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;(c)2013 The Baltimore Sun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit The Baltimore Sun at &lt;a href="http://www.baltimoresun.com"&gt;www.baltimoresun.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributed by MCT Information Services&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src="http://pixel.newscred.com/px.gif?key=YXJ0aWNsZT01ZDU4MjBlNGU3MDZkMzBjNWJhZDY1YTJlMjVhZmQ3ZSZvd25lcj0zNDQ5NjhiY2NjN2VmZjJhNDYzYTk2ZjA3YzVmYTQ2NSZub25jZT00YzkzMDMzZi1iOGQzLTRkY2QtOTA5ZS1kNDU3OTkyYWNiM2QmcHVibGlzaGVyPTA4YzIwOWI5YTg3MzA2ZjRiZjkyNjAwYTQ0ZDIxMTlm" alt="" height="1" width="1" class="nc_pixel"/&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1085883/thumbs/s-MARYLAND-CYBERBULLYING-BAN-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>U.S. Faces New Education Challenges</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/14/us-bilingual-education-_n_3079950.html?utm_hp_ref=parents&amp;ir=Parents"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3079950</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-14T13:28:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T11:58:08Z</updated>
    
    <summary>MIAMI &amp;mdash; Duna Lopez started school in Miami last fall not knowing a single word of English. The 8-year-old girl from Barcelona, Spain, with dark...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/zuania-capo/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;MIAMI &amp;mdash; Duna Lopez started school in Miami last fall not knowing a single word of English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 8-year-old girl from Barcelona, Spain, with dark blond hair was placed in the Coral Way Bilingual K-8 Center, the nation's oldest bilingual school. For half the day, she receives classes in Spanish; it's English for the rest. During language arts, she gets pulled out with three other new arrivals for extra help on grammar and phonics.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;After seven months, she's one of the most active participants in class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"In five months, like that, I learned it," she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duna's success is exceptional, but the language challenge she faced is increasingly common across the U.S. educational map. Nationwide, nonwhites are expected to become a majority of the population within a generation, and schools are at the cutting edge of that historic shift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School-age children who speak a language other than English at home are one of the fastest-growing populations. Their numbers doubled between 1980 and 2009, and they now make up 21 percent of school-age kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were 4.7 million students classified as "English language learners" &amp;ndash; those who have not yet achieved proficiency in English &amp;ndash; in the 2009-10 school year, or about 10 percent of children enrolled, according to the most recent figures available from the U.S. Department of Education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"This is part of a new reality that our public schools are facing," said Robert Linquanti, an expert in English learner students for WestEd, an education research agency based in San Francisco. "It's been coming for a long time but now it's hitting a tipping point."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the challenges facing minority students and their schools, English learners are arguably the most disadvantaged. It's hard to find enough teachers who are qualified to instruct them, and there's little consistency in the programs used to educate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The country is divided over the best way to educate them, with bilingual programs gathering steam but also provoking a sometimes heated debate with those who favor an English-only approach. English learner students are more likely to be in poor, overcrowded schools and in many places represent an added cost to already cash-strapped school districts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The longer these students stay in special language programs, the further they fall behind in other subjects. In several states, their graduation rates are at less than 60 percent, and as low as 29 percent in Nevada, according to federal data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just 7 percent of fourth-grade and 3 percent of eighth-grade English learners scored "proficient" or above in a nationwide reading exam, and thousands languish for years in ineffective English-as-a-second-language programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a scale of one to 10, the education of the nation's English learners is "below five," said Gary Cook, a specialist with the Wisconsin Center for Education Research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Their success is our success," Cook said. "If they really can't meet the educational expectations of what's coming &amp;ndash; that is, the need to be knowledge workers, not necessarily physical workers &amp;ndash; then we're in a world of hurt."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of English learners, more than two-thirds at the elementary school level, were born in the United States. They represent many different languages and ethnicities, but the majority is Hispanic. Overall, 38 percent of Hispanic fourth-grade students were identified as English learners, as well as 20 percent of Hispanic eighth-grade students, according to the 2011 National Assessment of Education Progress math test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latino students overall have some of the highest dropout rates and the lowest share of the population with a bachelor's degree. The language barrier does not affect the majority, but for those who enter school as English learners the challenges are even greater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asian students represent the second largest group of English learners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;States such as California, Texas, New Mexico and Nevada have some of the largest proportions of English learners in their school-age populations. They also are widely concentrated in low-income, urban schools. A study by the Urban Institute found that 70 percent are educated in 5,000 elementary schools, just 10 percent of the nation's schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The segregation of these students is reflective of both neighborhood segregation and a decision on the part of some districts to group these students together in order to provide them with qualified teachers and bilingual programs that are scarce, said Richard Fry, a senior research associate for the Pew Hispanic Center. But the schools they attend also tend to have the highest rates of poverty, larger pupil-teacher ratios and bigger schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They are clearly at risk," said Fry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An English learner's entrance into the public school system usually starts with a home language survey, which asks whether another language is used at home and which language the child speaks most frequently. The questions can vary significantly from state to state, and in some places there's been criticism for including questions that identify children as being in need of language services when they are not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Miami, for example, one of the questions is what's the student's first language. But as Coral Way's principal, Josephine Otero, pointed out, that doesn't necessarily mean a child isn't fluent in his or her second language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How best to teach English learners is under debate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research is inconclusive, though there has been recent momentum for bilingual education programs such as the one at Coral Way, which has been at it longer than most schools. The school adopted a bilingual program for all students, regardless of language proficiency, in the 1960s after receiving a wave of Cuban immigrants fleeing the 1959 communist revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believing they'd eventually return to Cuba, many families wanted to make sure their children didn't lose their Spanish. Most never returned to the island, but the dual-language program remained and the school has consistently been given an "A" by the state&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virginia Collier and Wayne Thomas from George Mason University in Virginia studied more than 6 million student records and found that full-immersion bilingual programs in which native and nonnative students are given instruction in both languages are the most effective. They studied bilingual programs in the Houston Independent School District and found that native-Spanish speakers were at or above grade level in English and Spanish in first grade through fifth grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"This is a program that is spreading all throughout the United States very, very fast," Collier said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some of the programs, students are taught half their subjects in English and the other half in Spanish, or they start with more time in the dominant language until becoming equally fluent in both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One problem is that it's not always easy to find teachers who not only speak Spanish but also can teach and explain it academically as well. It's a challenge even in Miami, where speaking Spanish is practically a requirement for everyday life. A 1997 study found that only 2.5 percent of English-as-a-second-language teachers had a degree in bilingual or English language education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's not in all cases bilingual education works better," Linquanti said. "It depends on quality of instruction, material and support for the community."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bilingual programs also face a political hurdle. In California, Massachusetts and Arizona, bilingual education has been banned by proponents of an English-only approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Bilingual education connects to a lot of lightning rod issues in the national discourse," Linquanti said. "Immigration. Multiculturalism. People will see bilingual education through those issues. That's why the controversy continues."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many districts continue to separate English learners for special instruction, teaching them primarily in English. There are examples around the country that show that approach can be successful, though critics say it isolates students from their peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 19-month U.S. Department of Education investigation of the Los Angeles Unified School District found the district failed to provide equal education to English learners and black students, resulting in wide academic disparities. Only 5 percent of high school English language learners were rated proficient in English or math; for black students, 32 percent were proficient in English and 9 percent in math, according to the district's 2009-10 report card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The district, the nation's second largest, agreed to a complete overhaul of its English-learning program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes students with the lowest skill levels five years to seven years to become proficient in English, research by Cook and Linquanti has shown. But in some places, students are getting stuck in English-as-a-second-language programs all the way until graduation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In California, 59 percent of secondary school English learners were found to have been in U.S. schools for more than six years without reaching English proficiency, according to a study by Californians Together, a statewide coalition of parents, teachers and education advocates. The group found that many students received minimal or no help in developing their second language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Many are stuck at an intermediate level of development," said Shelly Spiegel-Coleman, the group's executive director.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the report came out, districts around the state began devising new language courses. Academics also are hopeful that there soon will be greater national consistency in how English learners are identified and how proficiency is defined through the Common Core standards and assessments, a set of uniform benchmarks adopted by 45 states and the District of Columbia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the approach, resources remain limited. Schools with few English learners may get no money at all, and federal help is heavily tied to census figures, which are believed to significantly underrepresent the number of students in need of services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One study by a Miami-Dade School Board member and Republican political consultant found it takes about $1,500 to provide English language instruction for each student. A 2008 study by the New York Immigration Coalition found quality English-learner education costs about twice as much as for students not in those programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a recent day in Lopez's third-grade English class in Miami, the students learned the four points of the compass by reading and acting out a poem. The students are from Egypt, Puerto Rico, Cuba and Spain and eagerly put up their hands when teacher Julia Puentes asks them a question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puentes said with her school's approach, most start getting a firmer grasp of the language within three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's just amazing," she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is how well the rest of the nation can replicate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;___&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow Christine Armario on Twitter: &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/cearmario"&gt;http://www.twitter.com/cearmario&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1085881/thumbs/s-US-BILINGUAL-EDUCATION-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
