<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Fair Languages</title>
	<atom:link href="http://fairlanguages.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://fairlanguages.com</link>
	<description>Celebrating Multilingualism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 15:25:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Europeans should Learn two Foreign Languages says Commissioner Vassiliou</title>
		<link>http://fairlanguages.com/europeans-should-learn-two-foreign-languages-says-commissioner-vassiliou/</link>
		<comments>http://fairlanguages.com/europeans-should-learn-two-foreign-languages-says-commissioner-vassiliou/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 15:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kirsten Winkler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multilingualism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fairlanguages.com/?p=1906</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The European Union committed to promote multilingualism with the goal of every citizen of the EU learning two foreign languages.</p><p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/europeans-should-learn-two-foreign-languages-says-commissioner-vassiliou/">Europeans should Learn two Foreign Languages says Commissioner Vassiliou</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1909" alt="European Union learn two foreign languages" src="http://fairlanguages.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/European-Commission.jpg" width="600" height="234" /></p>
<p>According to Europe’s Language and Culture Commissioner Androulla Vassiliou learning foreign languages can be a way out of the economic crisis for many Europeans. We already wrote about examples in other countries like Canada which show that <a title="Big Bucks for Language Learners – Bilinguals Earn More Money" href="http://fairlanguages.com/big-bucks-for-language-learners-bilinguals-earn-more-money/">being bilingual pays off</a>.</p>
<p>The European Union committed to promote multilingualism with the goal of every citizen of the EU speaking at least two foreign languages. This way people would become more mobile and language savvy and enable them to find work across borders.</p>
<p>At the European Economic and Social Committee that took place early March Vassiliou stated that institutions and businesses in the EU must also learn to better cope with a multilingual society.</p>
<p>The latest figures of the European Commission show that only 42% of 15 year olds in the EU are competent in their first foreign language which they usually learned for seven years in school. But this figure varies heavily across the EU with for example 82% of 15 year olds being competent in Sweden compared to only 9% in the UK.</p>
<p>Vassiliou also thinks that language skills should not only be a field for experts like linguists, translators or interpreters.</p>
<blockquote><p>“Languages, like politics, are too important to our lives to be left to specialists only.”</p></blockquote>
<p>She also addressed the notion that English is now the de facto lingua franca in Brussels and therefore gaining influence as the main language of the workplace in the European Union. Though speaking English is probably a basic skill today, it should not come at the expense of the other European languages.</p>
<blockquote><p>“I am still absolutely convinced that it is more and more the knowledge of other languages that can make the difference in getting a job and progressing in one’s career.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Due to the current economic crisis the multilingualism strategy of the European Commission, also called “mother tongue plus two”, policy makers are now more open to once again revisit the strategy and work on a new European benchmark for language acquisition. Vassiliou hopes that the new proposal which is going to measure how many students are learning two foreign languages will be adopted in 2014.</p>
<p>Via <a title="Learning languages a way out of crisis, says Vassiliou" href="http://www.euractiv.com/culture/learning-languages-way-crisis-va-news-518306" target="_blank">EurActiv</a> | <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Banderas_europeas_en_la_Comisi%C3%B3n_Europea.jpg" target="_blank">Image</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/europeans-should-learn-two-foreign-languages-says-commissioner-vassiliou/">Europeans should Learn two Foreign Languages says Commissioner Vassiliou</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fairlanguages.com/europeans-should-learn-two-foreign-languages-says-commissioner-vassiliou/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Misconceptions about Language Learning #6: They definitely got it right in school</title>
		<link>http://fairlanguages.com/misconceptions-about-language-learning-6-they-definitely-got-it-right-in-school/</link>
		<comments>http://fairlanguages.com/misconceptions-about-language-learning-6-they-definitely-got-it-right-in-school/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 21:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kerstin Hammes</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Learning Tips & Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adult learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language learning methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misconceptions about language learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myths]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schools]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fairlanguages.com/?p=1896</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Hassled teachers, giggling back rows, noisy common rooms... many would-be learners will have memories of school that are not encouraging future learning.</p><p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/misconceptions-about-language-learning-6-they-definitely-got-it-right-in-school/">Misconceptions about Language Learning #6: They definitely got it right in school</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1902" alt="misconceptions about language learning" src="http://fairlanguages.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/opendoor.jpg" width="600" height="234" /></p>
<p>Hassled teachers, giggling back rows, noisy common rooms&#8230; many would-be learners will have memories of school that are not encouraging future learning. If you are above the age of 13 and you attended school, you are very likely to have come into contact with language learning. The common scenario is that your tuition was in a larger group of your peers, involved homework and regular tests, and was structured around a curriculum set by people who don&#8217;t know you. And for some learners, it wasn&#8217;t right. The amount of people who mention this scenario to me when they talk about language learning is staggering!</p>
<p>But let&#8217;s get real: You&#8217;re not a teenager anymore. You are not herded into a classroom anymore. You can learn like an adult, go at your own pace and feel free from constraint. Ask yourself the following questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Have you ever learnt with a goal in mind?</li>
</ul>
<p>A goal is not something imposed on you that you don&#8217;t believe in. Some find themselves motivated by the desire to score an A on the next exam, but others do not. So if you have never had a goal that was relevant for you, it might be time to put a value on why you want to learn.</p>
<ul>
<li>In past learning environments, did you feel proud of your successes?</li>
</ul>
<p>You should be able to look at your achievements with a good, satisfied glow. I&#8217;m new to indoor climbing and I cannot tell you how pleased I was with myself last week when I put a new move into practice for the first time. The same goes for language learning. Be pleased with yourself when you achieve something, otherwise you won&#8217;t be going for long.</p>
<ul>
<li>Was the pace right for you?</li>
</ul>
<p>Pace is usually an issue with group learning in a set curriculum environment. The goalposts are set by people who don&#8217;t know you as an individual. They may be making assumptions about your general age group, or even worse, they might just have counted backwards from the exam content and guessed at how to squeeze that content into an academic year. Just consider <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/teacher-network/teacher-blog/2013/mar/21/overhaul-modern-foreign-languages-teaching-british-schools">this teacher&#8217;s view</a> of how far the reality in UK schools is from the ideal language school.</p>
<p><strong>Don&#8217;t let others tell you how fast or slow you are supposed to be.</strong> If you want to understand an issue in depth before moving on to the next, do it. If you want to skim many lessons and get a big picture view, do it. It&#8217;s important to be consistent. Pace is secondary.</p>
<ul>
<li>Did you get answers to all your questions?</li>
</ul>
<p>Some learning systems make assumptions about what learners want to know and what they don&#8217;t want to know. If you felt that learning a tense stoked your curiosity, just to be left clueless about where to find out more, you may have taken away the belief that your way of learning wasn&#8217;t right. The way to address this is to investigate who will give you that information and how you want it to be delivered to you.</p>
<h2>Draw Conclusions</h2>
<p>If the answer to any of these questions is no, your misconception shaped by past experience may be holding you back. Think about what you like and didn&#8217;t like in past experiences, what worked for you and what made you feel like you&#8217;re achieving and progressing well. Consider different methods: group tuition, e-learning, individual lessons or language exchanges. It might be time rearrange your learning landscape for productivity and motivation. Take a break from what others say (yes, even we on Fairlanguages) and have a good old session with yourself, your questions and a piece of paper.</p>
<p>Good luck shaking it up!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sxc.hu/photo/1410757" target="_blank">Image by bschwehn via sxc.hu</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/misconceptions-about-language-learning-6-they-definitely-got-it-right-in-school/">Misconceptions about Language Learning #6: They definitely got it right in school</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fairlanguages.com/misconceptions-about-language-learning-6-they-definitely-got-it-right-in-school/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Romanagiri is the new Youth Language in India</title>
		<link>http://fairlanguages.com/romanagiri-is-the-new-youth-language-in-india/</link>
		<comments>http://fairlanguages.com/romanagiri-is-the-new-youth-language-in-india/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Anne Hwang</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science & Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romanagiri]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fairlanguages.com/?p=1887</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Romanagri, have you heard of this language? It is a new language used by young people across India and its evolution is different from other languages.</p><p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/romanagiri-is-the-new-youth-language-in-india/">Romanagiri is the new Youth Language in India</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1888" alt="romanagiri" src="http://fairlanguages.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/indian-youth.jpg" width="600" height="234" /></p>
<p>Romanagri, have you heard of this language? It is a new language used by young people across India. The interesting thing is the evolution of this language is different from the other languages.</p>
<p>Languages traditionally developed through gradual accumulation of words and syntax and spread through the brain and the tongue. Romanagri, a protmanteau of English and Hindi, changes and proliferates via cell phones rather than speech. Romanagri is a natural language among young Indians, but confusing to English language purist.</p>
<p>This is <a title="Does Texting equal Bad Grammar?" href="http://fairlanguages.com/does-texting-equal-bad-grammar/">the language of BlackBerry messengers</a>, Tweets, Facebook posts and SMS. The language could simply be a regional language written in English as a phone message or Tweet such as “Mera naam Jacob hain” (my name is Jacob) to very complex combinations like “Picture main feel nahin thee” (The film lacked pizzazz).</p>
<p>Though the use of transliterated script like Romanagri isn’t something new in India, but it does pose a complex problem in India for the reasons that majority are more fluent in their native language than English and are taught to read English before they speak it, yet <a title="Survey finds: Indians only have Moderate English Proficiency" href="http://fairlanguages.com/survey-finds-indians-only-have-moderate-english-proficiency/">disadvantaged economically and professionally</a> because English is preeminent language for a white-collar.</p>
<p>Disconnection has remained a barrier for people who have been unable to tap into India’s consumer market despite the widespread use of cellphones. To break the barrier, clever inventors have tried to invent technologies such as language keyboards, voice-to-text conversion etc to overcome the constraints of English.</p>
<p>There’s doubt that Romanized language will have much potential say for news website or anything that involves more than a couple of sentences, but will continue to be the language for getting film music or movies.</p>
<p>To show the complexity of Romanagri, a study was done to test participants who had studied both Hindi and English and routinely conversed in text messages that interspersed both languages. The participants had to read sets of words that were interlingual homophones, or words that sound the same but have different meanings in both Hindi or English. Based on what they read, participants had to search concrete nouns from the words that were written in Hindi, English and Romanagri. Indeed, Romanagri took more time and was prone to more errors, even if the words involved were comparably familiar.</p>
<p>Researches found that Romanagri evoked responses from several regions of the brain for the “attention network” of the brain which is what helps people to <a title="How Speaking Foreign Languages Helps to Make Better Decisions" href="http://fairlanguages.com/how-speaking-foreign-languages-helps-to-make-better-decisions/">multi task and prioritize</a> between tasks that are competing for our attention. This additionally proves the complexity of the language and led researchers to ask questions of whether bilinguals extract information from language differently from mono-linguals and whether there are costs associated with having to juggle multiple languages.</p>
<p>Perhaps with the complexity of a language <a title="Research shows that Bilingual Immigrants are Healthier" href="http://fairlanguages.com/research-shows-that-bilingual-immigrants-are-healthier/">come benefits</a>. We have seen <a title="Does Multilingualism prevent Dementia? Indian Researchers plan to find out" href="http://fairlanguages.com/does-multilingualism-prevent-dementia-indian-researchers-plan-to-find-out/">several researches</a> in the past indicating that individuals with a higher degree of bilingualism showed a <a title="Prevent Mental Aging and even Alzheimer’s through Language Learning" href="http://fairlanguages.com/prevent-mental-aging-and-even-alzheimers-through-language-learning/">slower progress into early symptoms of Alzheimer’s</a> than monolinguals.</p>
<p>A professor at the Centre for Behavioral and Cognitive Sciences in Allahabad, argues that the natural condition of most Indians of knowing two or three languages and having varying degrees of proficiency in communicating them is in general beneficial. Also, studies have indicated <a title="Bilingual Brains are better at Attention, Memory and Multitasking" href="http://fairlanguages.com/bilingual-brains-are-better-at-attention-memory-and-multitasking/">bilinguals have better skills at multi-tasking</a>.</p>
<p>Apart from multi-tasking, study point to possible lines of investigation in understanding dyslexia among children not trained in English and reworking the pedagogy of English learning in India.</p>
<p>Via <a title="Romanagiri: India’s new Lingua Franca?" href="http://www.livemint.com/Consumer/fi4tgewOi5rn4PmCjmgBSJ/Using-cellphone-lingo-to-understand-link-between-brain-and-l.html" target="_blank">live mint</a> | <a title="Morguefile" href="http://mrg.bz/Gwkly7" target="_blank">Image</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/romanagiri-is-the-new-youth-language-in-india/">Romanagiri is the new Youth Language in India</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fairlanguages.com/romanagiri-is-the-new-youth-language-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Using a Language is Simpler than People Think</title>
		<link>http://fairlanguages.com/using-a-language-is-simpler-than-people-think/</link>
		<comments>http://fairlanguages.com/using-a-language-is-simpler-than-people-think/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 14:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Anne Hwang</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science & Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cognitive science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fairlanguages.com/?p=1881</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Maybe it’s human nature, but people often tend to make things more complex than it actually is. Using a language for example is simpler than people think.</p><p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/using-a-language-is-simpler-than-people-think/">Using a Language is Simpler than People Think</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1882" alt="using a language" src="http://fairlanguages.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/nestingdolls.jpg" width="600" height="234" /></p>
<p>Maybe it’s human nature, but people often tend to make things more complex than it actually is. For many years, language scientists have assumed that language is like a Russian nesting dolls, made up of small parts in turn made of smaller parts. A new study done in Cornell suggests language is simpler than they had thought.</p>
<p>Language system deals with words by grouping them into little clumps that are associated with meaning. When these word clumps are arranged in a particular order, it’s simply understood. For example “bread and butter” might be represented as a construction. On the other hand, if we reverse the sequence, it would likely not make any sense.</p>
<p>This sequential simplicity demonstrates that language is naturally sequential, given the temporal cues that help us understand and be understood as people use language. Also, the hierarchy concept of small parts in turn made of smaller parts doesn’t take into consideration the many other cues that help convey meaning such as the speaker’s intention and the setting.</p>
<p>The researchers in the study drew on evidence in language related fields such as psycholinguistics and cognitive neuroscience. Research in evolutionary biology indicates that human acquired language because we have evolved the abilities in an array of areas such as the ability to correctly guess other’s intentions and learn different sounds that we then relate to meaning to create words. While this is the indication from evolutionary biology, hierarchy concept suggests that humans have language due to the highly specialized “hardware” in the brain, but neuroscientists have yet to find it.</p>
<p>Research in cognitive neuroscience suggested that language is processed sequentially. Recent studies have shown that how well adults and children perform on a sequence learning task predicts how well they can process the inundation of words that come at us when we’re listening to someone. The better one is at handling sequences, the easier it is to comprehend language.</p>
<p>This research brings some insight into language learning for language learners and teachers. From a language teaching perspective, I believe teaching collocations may be one good way to help English learners. If humans have the ability to correctly guess other’s intentions, then helping students build background information prior to reading and listening empowers a learner to guess and ­­increase comprehension.</p>
<p>Via <a title="Language use is simpler than previously thought" href="http://phys.org/news/2012-09-language-simpler-previously-thought.html" target="_blank">PHYS.ORG</a> | <a title="MorgueFile" href="http://mrg.bz/Y7UMa7" target="_blank">Image</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/using-a-language-is-simpler-than-people-think/">Using a Language is Simpler than People Think</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fairlanguages.com/using-a-language-is-simpler-than-people-think/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Burnistoun &#8211; Scots in an Elevator with Voice Recognition</title>
		<link>http://fairlanguages.com/burnistoun-scots-in-an-elevator-with-voice-recognition/</link>
		<comments>http://fairlanguages.com/burnistoun-scots-in-an-elevator-with-voice-recognition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 19:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kirsten Winkler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Language Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scottish]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fairlanguages.com/?p=1876</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This sketch is about two Scots in an elevator with voice recognition and probably a take on Siri that apparently has trouble with the Scottish accent.</p><p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/burnistoun-scots-in-an-elevator-with-voice-recognition/">Burnistoun &#8211; Scots in an Elevator with Voice Recognition</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/5FFRoYhTJQQ?rel=0" height="338" width="600" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Another Friday, another funny language related video. Today&#8217;s clip comes from a Scottish comedy show called <a title="Burnistoun" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burnistoun" target="_blank">Burnistoun</a> which I recently came across in a short documentary about Scottish television.</p>
<p>This sketch is about two Scots in an elevator with voice recognition and probably a take on Siri, the voice recognition app from Apple that apparently has <a title="Lost in translation: Siri cannot understand the Scottish accent" href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/london/lost-in-translation-siri-cannot-understand-the-scottish-accent/261" target="_blank">trouble with the Scottish accent</a>. Enjoy!</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/burnistoun-scots-in-an-elevator-with-voice-recognition/">Burnistoun &#8211; Scots in an Elevator with Voice Recognition</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fairlanguages.com/burnistoun-scots-in-an-elevator-with-voice-recognition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Italian Dialects: Why Italians speak Thousands of Languages</title>
		<link>http://fairlanguages.com/italian-dialects-why-italians-speak-thousands-of-languages/</link>
		<comments>http://fairlanguages.com/italian-dialects-why-italians-speak-thousands-of-languages/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 18:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Serena Pasqualetto</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Italian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dialects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[italian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[languages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fairlanguages.com/?p=1855</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Italians speak one language. No, actually, they speak thousands of them. Italian is a newborncompared to the thousands of Italian dialects spoken in Italy.</p><p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/italian-dialects-why-italians-speak-thousands-of-languages/">Italian Dialects: Why Italians speak Thousands of Languages</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1871" alt="Italian Dialects" src="http://fairlanguages.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/italian_dialects.png" width="567" height="383" /></p>
<p>Italians speak one language. No, actually, they speak thousands of them. I will tell you more: Italian is a newborn baby compared to the thousands of languages spoken in this country.</p>
<p>Let’s start from the beginning: let’s go back to <strong>1861</strong>, when <strong>Italy</strong> was finally born, later than other European countries. The Regno d’Italia (Italian Kingdom) had just been formed, but what about the language?</p>
<p><em>“Fatta l&#8217;Italia</em>, <em>facciamo gli Italiani”</em><em> (“We’ve made Italy. </em><em>Let’s make the Italian people!”) </em>This is what Italian writer and politician Massimo d’Azeglio rightly said<em>. </em>A unified country needed a unique language.</p>
<p>Which was not easy at all, since Italian people had been speaking their <strong>local dialects</strong> for centuries. This is why it took a lot of time for Italians to “learn” a unique language, and in this process television played a great role in that it helped spreading the language across the peninsula, alongside school education and newspapers.</p>
<p>But what is the status of our dialects and how did they develop throughout time? Despite they are (wrongly) classified as bad versions of the Italian language, <strong>dialects in Italy</strong> are real languages, that originated from Latin long before Italian was born – we are talking of a period of latinization that took place prior to the Roman empire times. Some of them, which are spoken in  the northern part of the country, derive from German; some are Slovenia dialects, and there are also dialects deriving from Greek and Croatian.</p>
<p>We have an extremely precious wealth of languages that is Italy’s past and present – yes, because Italians still speak (and most of them think in) dialects. I myself grew up in a family where Venetian was the first language, so I can consider myself bilingual. Speaking of my city, Venice, a curious phenomenon is worth mentioning, namely what sociolinguistics would call “<strong>diglossia</strong>”: a situation in which two languages or dialects coexist in the same area, but are used in different spheres of social interaction. In Venice, the Venetian dialect is used in informal situations, and has a lower prestige, whereas Italian is spoken in formal contexts and has a higher prestige.</p>
<p>Our <strong>dialects</strong> are therefore the “grandparents” of <strong>modern Italian</strong>: more specifically, only one Italian dialect, the <strong>Florentine</strong> one, gave birth to the “lingua italiana”, and this is due to a purely random reason. In fact, Florence happened to be the cradle of the Italian literature, home to big names such as Dante, Petrarca and Boccaccio. But if things had gone differently, another dialect could have stood out, and now we would be speaking a language very similar to it.</p>
<p>Although speaking only the national language is becoming increasingly popular among Italian families, we should not be ashamed of speaking to our children using dialects: they are our heritage, just as the Colosseum and the many art treasures we cherish.</p>
<p>What’s your opinion about it? Have you ever heard anyone speaking dialect in Italy?</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/italian-dialects-why-italians-speak-thousands-of-languages/">Italian Dialects: Why Italians speak Thousands of Languages</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fairlanguages.com/italian-dialects-why-italians-speak-thousands-of-languages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monty Python: Italian Lesson</title>
		<link>http://fairlanguages.com/monty-python-italian-lesson/</link>
		<comments>http://fairlanguages.com/monty-python-italian-lesson/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 15:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kirsten Winkler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Language Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[english]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[italian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fairlanguages.com/?p=1864</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Italian lesson is a classic sketch from Monty Python in which an English speaking teacher teaches Italian to Italians.</p><p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/monty-python-italian-lesson/">Monty Python: Italian Lesson</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/k9TVYCffHEE?rel=0" height="450" width="600" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/monty-python-italian-lesson/">Monty Python: Italian Lesson</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fairlanguages.com/monty-python-italian-lesson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Be Yourself On Teaching Tube TV.</title>
		<link>http://fairlanguages.com/how-to-be-yourself-on-teaching-tube-tv/</link>
		<comments>http://fairlanguages.com/how-to-be-yourself-on-teaching-tube-tv/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 13:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sylvia Guinan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Brain-friendly Insights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EFL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[english]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ESL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fairlanguages.com/?p=1801</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In this post Sylvia shares her observations on what makes a great teacher on YouTube. She interviewed fellow online teachers and adds her analysis.</p><p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/how-to-be-yourself-on-teaching-tube-tv/">How to Be Yourself On Teaching Tube TV.</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1841" alt="original" src="http://fairlanguages.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/original.jpg" width="600" height="234" /></p>
<p><em>Another chapter in my creative Edupreneur series</em></p>
<p>Every once in a while, I emerge from my nerding cave to get a whiff of what my colleagues are up to online. There is never a dull moment. These days it’s particularly exciting. I say ‘nerding cave’, because I am at heart, a reader, writer and researcher, as well as teacher. I write content, blog, plan. I am also writing ebooks and making my way into publishing.</p>
<p>All of this is great, but what about the showmanship, sharing, and great social clout of teaching on YouTube? Perhaps in future I will follow the footsteps of some of my amazing colleagues who embraced YouTube from the start – right now, I’m happy to observe and describe their YouTube exploits.</p>
<h2>Who are ESLebrities when they’re at home?</h2>
<p>They are teachers just like you and I who have embraced the web to share their passions. I have come to associate with many passionate teachers in my personal learning network, and the most inspiring thing I can tell you about them is that they are modest, yet enamoured with the power of sharing and learning. I have observed that the most successful people in my network are just &#8216;normal people&#8217; but they have integrity, a natural charm and a great work ethic. Of course there is talent and intelligence too. – but, as we know, talent can be nurtured. That’s what this article is about.</p>
<h2>The X-factor.</h2>
<p>From my observations, experiments and associations, all I can say is that the X-factor seems to lie in a mixture of dedication, authenticity and passion for the cause. I’m going to feature some YouTube teachers today, and explore what kind of universal appeal leads to their success. I’m doing this for one reason. If you are over-awed by statistics, viewing, exposure, publicity and the popularity of major you tube personalities in teaching, you may feel that it’s an exclusive club.</p>
<p>I’m here to tell you that it’s not. YouTube is available to all of us. If you want to teach online or make a name, YouTube is a powerful avenue to take. But the most important thing you need is the right attitude. After that comes commitment and staying power. I’ll let my featured YouTube stars tell you more.</p>
<p>I’ll start by briefly mentioning two amazing showmen, Fluency MC and Mau Buchler. They are two professionals I like to follow and I have interviewed and featured both of them on more than one occasion. You can find some coverage of <a title="Why We need Strategies for Creativity Part 2 – The Outliers" href="http://fairlanguages.com/why-we-need-strategies-for-creativity-part-2-the-outliers/">Mau and Jason here</a>, and another recent interview with Jason R. Levine here on <a title="OpenLanguage Learner Series: Interview with Jason Levine, the Fluency MC - See more at: http://openlanguage.com/blog/521/openlanguage-learner-series-interview-jason-levine-fluency-mc#sthash.aums7hYw.dpuf" href="http://openlanguage.com/blog/521/openlanguage-learner-series-interview-jason-levine-fluency-mc">OpenLanguage</a>, a major e-learning platform. I also have an exclusive scoop on Mau to be published on Fair languages within the next month.</p>
<h2>Kirsten Winkler</h2>
<p>As a pioneering Edupreneur, Kirsten has a huge following on YouTube. For those of us who know Kirsten Winkler online, it’s obvious how much of her vision and passion she puts into video-making. DeutschHappen is Kirsten&#8217;s channel for teaching German. Her short video lessons work in tandem with lesson plans on<a href="http://deutschhappen.com/"> her website </a>of the same name. Kirsten has a very professional voice on YouTube, matching the quality of those we see on TV.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t speak German at all, so I found it wonderful that I could follow her video lessons despite that. I watched some of her basic level videos, and a more advanced one about the rain. Being Irish I couldn&#8217;t resist a lesson about the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EK-gZprz-SI&amp;list=UUH_QC9OhujDHxaGSvc9ILyg&amp;index=9">many words for rain</a> and muddy boot or wellies. I loved listening to her voice and following the subtitles for key words. The lessons are perfectly pitched for a YouTube audience. Complex language chunks are presented simply and clearly. Her outdoor lessons give a sense of fun spontaneity without impinging on the quality of the lesson. It’s hardly surprising that her following is so great, as the videos are ultra-professional, personable and information-rich.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/EK-gZprz-SI?rel=0" height="450" width="600" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<h3>Here is Kirsten’s heavy-weight tip.</h3>
<blockquote><p>“Already today the quality of video content on YouTube is light-years ahead compared to the days when I started uploading videos. People expect content that looks great, just like what they are used to from TV. This is important because with Internet connected TVs coming to your living room, people will consume more and more Internet based video content on the big screen.</p>
<p>This means that you need to get practice in creating and editing good looking content early on. No one will watch a crappy looking video, even if the content it features is great. You need to offer both.” <a href="http://www.kirstenwinkler.com/more-signs-for-paid-youtube-channel-subscriptions-appear/">Follow the full article here</a>.</p></blockquote>
<p>As I said before, YouTube is there for all of us to use in our businesses, but success comes as much from practice and determination as it does from vision and enthusiasm. Nobody featured in this article has taken any short-cuts with regard to You Tube success.</p>
<p>If you are an Edupreneur, hard work comes with the territory. The difference is that those of us who persist just love the business.</p>
<h2>Drew Badger</h2>
<p>The first time I remember seeing Drew on video was with a class of tiny Chinese children having an outdoor lesson. This was no special effect movie clip. It was a natural, vibrant clip of little kids caught up in Drew&#8217;s intuitive, rapport- building teaching style. What struck me was his ease with children &#8211; a magic touch indeed. I&#8217;ve also been impressed by the breadth of his work, especially the creative ideas and drama involved. The video clip I&#8217;m about to show here gives a taste of his dramatics, fun, and natural style. If I were to classify his style I&#8217;d start with &#8216;story-telling&#8217;, because that&#8217;s what he does with his body language, drama and field-trip style videoing.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='620' height='379' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/Fs66s0QY8-0?version=3&#038;rel=0&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>Drew is, of course, very expressive in his teaching and thinking style, so I was delighted to get this teaching on tip in the form of a quote:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Great teaching should mirror great design. Make your lessons as intuitive as possible, and people will feel themselves learning immediately.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>&#8220;Make your lessons as intuitive as possible&#8221; &#8211; it&#8217;s true that we FEEL Drew&#8217;s videos, and it&#8217;s also true that social/emotional learning is just now being explicitly discussed in educational circles. This is the real X-factor in teaching. So, I believe, that to be natural on You Yube, you&#8217;ve got to feel it&#8230;. get into the groove, as they say.</p>
<h2>Nina EnglishBrno</h2>
<p>Nina has a special glow on video, and a large part of this is her interpersonal communication style, which is evident in her broacasting tip below. The camera loves her and she loves her work &#8211; a deadly combination indeed. For those of you out there who want to feel comfortable on camera, I believe that it&#8217;s an inside job. The glow is a special kind of confidence, and I think that it was very generous of Nina to give away, what I think is probably her top tip, or even &#8216;secret&#8217; to presence on camera.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='620' height='379' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/_qVd5Fps0lE?version=3&#038;rel=0&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>What stands out for me in this clip is clarity, focus and brevity. Great teaching is about clarifying the absurdly complex. Note also that Nina didn&#8217;t need any special effects for this video &#8211; all she had was a piece of paper. I know that Nina values simplicity. By watching these video clips, I hope that you, aspiring You Tubers, will also notice subtle qualities like these, and will glean your own personalised insights.</p>
<p>And&#8230;.here&#8217;s our tip from the Video Queen..</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;My number one tip: Be short, authentic and energetic. No one likes to watch long, boring videos.</p>
<p>Speak to the camera as if you´re speaking to a friend or your favourite student.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Dave skype lessons</h2>
<p>I really enjoyed watching Dave&#8217;s grammar presentation, as it&#8217;s something I&#8217;ve been teaching for years with intermediate and proficiency students. He seamlessly demonstrates the big picture of tenses with his visualisation of time frames and examples. In my opinion, this kind of big picture summary is necessary for exam revision and fluency for upper intermediate and advanced/proficency classes.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='620' height='379' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/vwM56VUYvLA?version=3&#038;rel=0&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>Also, many students only EVER get bits and pieces of time-frame rules in English &#8211; disjointed detail that can NEVER become fluent &#8216;ownership&#8217; without seeing the &#8216;whole&#8217;, which is greater than the parts. It is also an example of simplicity, though it may not seem so at first. The simplicity of this is like Nina&#8217;s because he&#8217;s talking about the whole, complex tense system in the English language, yet breaking it down into bite-sized chunks of clear description.</p>
<p>Dave&#8217;s You Tube tip is a practical one for expanding your online presence and following:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;My top tip is add subscribe buttons on every video, and make sure you promote your videos in facebook groups and other social networks.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>It was a pleasure to take time out and watch these YouTube videos presented by my colleagues. Quite often in the rush of business and social media, we can&#8217;t fully appreciate the extent and value of what&#8217;s being shared around us. As an Edupreneur, I highly recommend these &#8216;time-outs&#8217; to keep tabs on what&#8217;s going on &amp; to keep inspiration alive &amp; kicking.</p>
<p>Special thanks to my guest stars from YouTube.</p>
<p>And now my thoughts wander back to blogging &#8230;and all the great bloggers out there&#8230;</p>
<p>Next time it may have to be a blogging special:)</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/how-to-be-yourself-on-teaching-tube-tv/">How to Be Yourself On Teaching Tube TV.</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fairlanguages.com/how-to-be-yourself-on-teaching-tube-tv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fair Languages is Finalist at THE 2013 BLOGGIES</title>
		<link>http://fairlanguages.com/fair-languages-is-finalist-at-the-2013-bloggies/</link>
		<comments>http://fairlanguages.com/fair-languages-is-finalist-at-the-2013-bloggies/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 17:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kirsten Winkler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2013 BLOGGIES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finalist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weblog awards 2013]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fairlanguages.com/?p=1784</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I am very excited to announce that Fair Languages is among the five finalists as Best Education Weblog at the 2013 BLOGGIES. Please vote until March 17th!</p><p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/fair-languages-is-finalist-at-the-2013-bloggies/">Fair Languages is Finalist at THE 2013 BLOGGIES</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1792" alt="2013 Bloggies" src="http://fairlanguages.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013bloggies.jpg" width="600" height="209" /></p>
<p>I am very excited to announce that Fair Languages is among the five finalists as Best Education Weblog at the 2013 BLOGGIES.</p>
<p>The BLOGGIES or Weblog Awards are already in their thirteenth year which makes them one of the longest running awards for blogs. Therefore, I am especially thrilled that we have made it on the list of finalists which was voted by 200 randomly selected people. It&#8217;s a huge honor to have made it in such a short time.</p>
<p>I want to specially thank all of our language guides and contributors who of course play an important role in the success of Fair Languages. This award nomination is truly a shared effort.</p>
<p>You have time to cast your vote for Fair Languages until Sunday, March 17th 10:00pm EDT. In order to cast your vote for Fair Languages as Best Education Weblog follow the steps below.</p>
<h3>1. Go to <strong><a title="The 2013 BLOGGIES" href="http://2013.bloggi.es" target="_blank">http://2013.bloggi.es</a></strong></h3>
<h3>2. Scroll down to the category <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Best Education Weblog</strong></span> and <strong>select <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Fair Languages</span></strong>.</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1787" alt="2013 BLOGGIES" src="http://fairlanguages.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013bloggies01.jpg" width="600" height="167" /></p>
<h3>3. Scroll down to the bottom of the page, enter the captcha text, your email address and click Submit your Nominations.</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1788" alt="2013 BLOGGIES" src="http://fairlanguages.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013bloggies02.jpg" width="600" height="165" /></p>
<h3>4. Important: Check your email inbox and <strong>click on the confirmation link</strong>. If you don&#8217;t confirm your vote by clicking on the link, it won&#8217;t count.</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1791" alt="2013 BLOGGIES" src="http://fairlanguages.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/2013bloggies03.jpg" width="600" height="131" /></p>
<p>Other than with our nomination at the Edublog Awards last year you only have one ballot per email address. If you have multiple email addresses you can of course vote for us multiple times <img src='http://fairlanguages.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';)' class='wp-smiley' /> . Thank you all for reading and supporting Fair Languages!</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/fair-languages-is-finalist-at-the-2013-bloggies/">Fair Languages is Finalist at THE 2013 BLOGGIES</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fairlanguages.com/fair-languages-is-finalist-at-the-2013-bloggies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why do we get stuck learning languages?</title>
		<link>http://fairlanguages.com/why-do-we-get-stuck-learning-languages/</link>
		<comments>http://fairlanguages.com/why-do-we-get-stuck-learning-languages/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 15:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Andrew Weiler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Language Learning Methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strategies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fairlanguages.com/?p=1772</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Many language learners do put enough effort in the initial stages to get to a certain level of proficiency but eventually get stuck learning languages.</p><p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/why-do-we-get-stuck-learning-languages/">Why do we get stuck learning languages?</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1780" alt="stuck learning languages" src="http://fairlanguages.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/dead-end.jpg" width="600" height="234" /></p>
<p>Many language learners do put enough effort in the initial stages to get to a certain level of proficiency but can&#8217;t seem to get above that level, try as they might. There can be any number of reasons for this. I will go through a number of them here. Have a read through them and see which may apply to you. Maybe, more than one. The important thing to realise is that two of the key reasons that stop people moving forwards is that they do not know what is holding them back and they do not know which way to move forward. Once you know, you can take steps to remedy the situation.</p>
<p><strong>No pressing need</strong></p>
<p>We have so many factors calling for our attention in our busy lives &#8211; family, job, hobbies, friends, etc so to make time to work at improving your language requires that you place it into a higher priority than where it is now. This is because the lower priority activities only get attended to when the higher ones have been dealt with. Without improving the lower priority that language learning might have in your life, you won&#8217;t be able to make the time it needs. It&#8217;s not enough to think &#8220;it is important&#8221;, you actually need to recalibrate what you &#8220;really believe&#8221; unconsciously or at the very first time you are &#8220;invited out for lunch with your friends&#8221; for e.g., you will defer your language learning time.</p>
<p><strong>Haven&#8217;t worked out strategies to integrate language use into your life</strong></p>
<p>This is related to the time issue we just talked about. Some people believe there is lack of time to do the &#8220;practice&#8221;, whereas the real problem may be that they have not integrated their language use into their life as well as they could. I will pose some questions below (for all kinds of settings) so you can be prompted to do some reflecting on what it is that you could better in this region:</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Do you go into shops where the language you are learning is spoken?</span></li>
<li>Do you use the language you are learning whilst you are driving ( listening to it &#8211; talks, music, books; speaking it to yourself&#8230;a running commentary on what you are doing&#8230;what you are seeing etc )?</li>
<li>Do you watch TV (without subtitles &#8211; for listening; with subtitles &#8211; for reading)?</li>
<li>Do you have the radio on ( with internet radio on, it&#8217;s so easy) whilst you are cooking, walking, cleaning, washing?</li>
<li>Whilst you are watching a DVD, have you tried listening for the language structure &#8211; not the content.  So for e.g., have you focussed on a grammar problem, pronunciation difficulty, etc  and listened to a part of it ( maybe all of it) just for that problem.</li>
<li>Ditto for reading.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Consider looking for new ways of learning</strong></p>
<p>One of the typical ways that language learners add to their vocabulary is through translated word lists. This method can work for the few but for most people it is most ineffective as it is not strengthening the language they are learning, instead it is working on translating skills. We do not translate when we speak or listen, so to access words learned in that way is difficult. And then of course how to put that new word to use is another issue! That is why so many people say, &#8220;My memory is so poor&#8221;. The odds are that there is nothing wrong with their memory. The problem is how they are going about trying to remember new vocabulary.</p>
<p>Instead, have a go at putting a new word in a sentence in the target language. A sentence that is personal AND meaning packed about that word. For example. <em>My sister gave me that beautiful blue <strong>fountain pen</strong>  as a birthday present. </em>One sentence may not be enough, but by the time you worked out the second, I can all but guarantee you that you will never forget that word or how to use it. Sometimes it might take you a little time to work out a sentence but <em>all that time is useful</em> as you are working on thinking and working on the structures in the target language. So you are getting triple benefit. Each one supporting the other!</p>
<p><strong>Growing cycles of power or diminishing cycles of energy</strong></p>
<p>Many language learners believe that they have little language ability. Why? Because that was their experience in learning languages at school. Never mind that the methods used were so boring or ineffective for the most part. So we start with such a belief, then go to a language school where not much has changed. All that does is confirm that first belief. The homework is boring, the classes difficult and the results meagre. There is no impetus to work, because underneath we believe that we never really will learn. Guess what the result is&#8230;.we don&#8217;t want to go on with it, just too disheartening an experience.</p>
<p>Consider an alternative, even if we start from the same premise, a depressing experience at school. Find a way of learning that you enjoy AND you get results in. Then all of a sudden there is a change and you see hope.  The trick here is to be very clear that you will not put up with ways of learning that are boring, repetitive (boring) and that do not produce tangible results. You keep looking until you find ways that are interesting, challenge you at the level you are at, provide results and you walk away form thinking, &#8220;How good was that!&#8221;  And that way you will want to do more of it!</p>
<p>So do an inventory of the practices you employ now. How do they measure up? If they don&#8217;t, start looking around. I can assure you that there are practices and classes out there that measure up in terms of the criteria mentioned. That is why so many people say, find a girlfriend/boyfriend in the language you are learning. You can&#8217;t get enough of the experience <img src='http://fairlanguages.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':-)' class='wp-smiley' />  &#8230;.a key to learning anything! Of course that will not work for all of us. What I am suggesting will.</p>
<p>Language learners who are stuck may have other reasons for their predicament, such as a reluctance to talk to people maybe brought on by shyness or an attitude that does not embrace a willingness to make mistakes ( an inevitable result in the process of learning anything). So there can be many reasons why language learners can experience feeling stuck in their learning. Whatever the case, it is just a feeling that one can pass through once one understands the reasons that gave that experience. If one is willing to take some steps, that feeling can be replaced once again by seeing improvements happening every day.</p>
<p><a href="http://mrg.bz/KaHuMG" target="_blank">Image</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="http://fairlanguages.com/why-do-we-get-stuck-learning-languages/">Why do we get stuck learning languages?</a> appeared first on <a href="http://fairlanguages.com">Fair Languages</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fairlanguages.com/why-do-we-get-stuck-learning-languages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
