<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</title>
	
	<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com</link>
	<description />
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 22:38:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.1</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/FlashpackerFamily" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="flashpackerfamily" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">FlashpackerFamily</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>Changing Gears, Conquering Your Fears and Taking on the Impossible</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/changing-gears-conquering-your-fears-and-taking-on-the-impossible/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/changing-gears-conquering-your-fears-and-taking-on-the-impossible/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 22:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3337</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Nancy Sathre-Vogel is an inspiration. She&#8217;s one of the few people in this world who knows what conquering your fears and living your dreams is all about. Nancy is one of the first women I encountered in the blogosphere and has been a continual source of motivation and a shoulder to cry on when things [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/changing-gears-conquering-your-fears-and-taking-on-the-impossible/">Changing Gears, Conquering Your Fears and Taking on the Impossible</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://familyonbikes.org/blog/about-2/author-profile/" target="_blank">Nancy Sathre-Vogel is an inspiration</a>. She&#8217;s one of the few people in this world who knows what conquering your fears and living your dreams is all about. Nancy is one of the first women I encountered in the blogosphere and has been a continual source of motivation and a shoulder to cry on when things go wrong. She&#8217;s powerful, strong and a brilliant writer. Last year while backpacking around Asia I read a copy of her book &#8220;Twenty Miles Per Cookie: 9000 Miles of Kid-Powered Adventures&#8221; &#8211; an entertaining tale of the family&#8217;s bike tour around North America. But&#8230; this is not what Nancy is known for.</p>
<p>Nancy has just published a new book on their three year journey from the top of Alaska to the tip of Argentina. <em><strong>Changing Gears: A Family Odyssey to the End of the World</strong> </em>chronicles the Vogel family&#8217;s incredible 17,000 mile voyage overland through no less than 15 countries. Sounds like an impossible feat, no? Consider that the Vogels undertook this with their twin boys, 10 years old at the start of the journey. Sounds even more impossible? Get this &#8211; the Vogel family undertook this mean feat not by plane, car or public transport but&#8230; <strong>by bicycle.</strong> Yes really. Eight legs, four people, three bikes and 17,000 miles of open road. You get now why I consider Nancy a great inspiration.</p>
<p><em><strong>Changing Gears</strong></em> is the story of their journey but it&#8217;s also a glimpse into the mind of a Mom who wants to instill a sense of adventure, self confidence and gratitude into her children. Nancy&#8217;s family stripped back their lives to the bare minimum &#8211; literally what they could carry on their bikes. Enough food for the moment, a roof over their heads (albeit temporary), a world to travel in. Nancy&#8217;s story is one of an epic odysessy sure but it&#8217;s deeper than that. Read the book, visit her site, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=mMasmrJOmEo" target="_blank">watch her TedX talk</a> and you will find out what I mean.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re an armchair traveler who enjoys unbelievable tales from the road &#8211; this is the book for you. If you&#8217;re looking for a little encouragement to move beyond your comfort zone &#8211; this is the book for you. If your family is stuck in a rut, looking for a change and wanting to break out of the ordinary &#8211; this is the book for you, your husband and your kids. </p>
<p><a href="http://familyonbikes.org/blog/2013/03/changing-gears-is-finally-released-order-your-copy-today/" target="_blank">Order the book</a>. Get inspired. Conquer your fears. Take on the impossible.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="text-align: justify;">In celebration of the release of <strong><em>Changing Gears</em></strong>, Nancy, with the help of a few of her favorite sponsors, is holding a giveaway of the following prizes:</div>
<div>
<ul>
<li>North St bags – <a href="http://northstbags.com/collections/convertibles/products/route-seven-pannier" target="_blank">Grocery Pannier</a></li>
<li>Subscription to <a href="http://www.womensadventuremagazine.com/" target="_blank">Women’s Adventure</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Man-Cycled-Americas-ebook/dp/B0052Z3HKI/ref=tmm_kin_title_0" target="_blank">The Man Who Cycled the Americas</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bekindtocyclists.org/store.html" target="_blank">Be Kind to Cyclists</a>- T-Shirts</li>
<li><a href="http://www.kryptonitelock.com" target="_blank">Kryptonite lock</a></li>
<li><a href="http://sihpromatum.com/savannah_bookorders.html" target="_blank">Sihpromatum</a></li>
<li><a href="http://shop.ibex.com/Apparel/Womens-Long-Sleeve" target="_blank">ibex</a> – 2 wool jerseys</li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Bottles-Backpacks-Gypsy-Travel-ebook/dp/B0071CGOO6" target="_blank">Bottles to Backpacks: The Gypsy Mama’s Guide to REAL Travel With Kids</a> – ebook</li>
<li><a href="http://www.lightandmotion.com/bike/" target="_blank">Light &amp; Motion </a>- bike light</li>
<li><a href="http://www.novica.com/" target="_blank">Novica</a> $100 Gift Certificate</li>
<li><a href="http://www.carrentals.co.uk/" target="_blank">Car Rental </a></li>
</ul>
<h6><em><a href="http://drivemecrazyfamilyadventure.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/CarHire.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-939 aligncenter" src="http://drivemecrazyfamilyadventure.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/CarHire.png" alt="CarHire" width="550" height="80" /></a></em><em><br />
</em></h6>
</div>
<div><em style="text-align: justify; font-size: 13px;">Disclosure: Flashpacker Family is not responsible for sponsor prize shipment. This event was organized by Victoria at <a title="Drive Me Crazy Family Adventure" href="http://drivemecrazyfamilyadventure.com" target="_blank">Drive Me Crazy Family Adventure</a> on behalf of the author, Nancy Vogel, <a title="Changing Gears" href="http://familyonbikes.org" target="_blank">Family on Bikes</a>. This giveaway is open to U.S. Residents and will end at 11:59 pm on March 27th. Three winners will be chosen. Each winner will receive a subscription to <em>Women&#8217;s Adventure Magazine</em> and their own copy of <em>Changing Gears</em>.  Remaining prizes will be divided among the finalists.</em></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;"></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;"></div>
<p><a id="rc-f4d37249" class="rafl" href="http://www.rafflecopter.com/rafl/display/f4d37249/" rel="nofollow">a Rafflecopter giveaway</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Featured image used with permission by FamilyonBikes.org.</em><script type="text/javascript" src="//d12vno17mo87cx.cloudfront.net/embed/rafl/cptr.js"></script></p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/changing-gears-conquering-your-fears-and-taking-on-the-impossible/">Changing Gears, Conquering Your Fears and Taking on the Impossible</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/changing-gears-conquering-your-fears-and-taking-on-the-impossible/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Best Places to Ski in New Zealand</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-places-to-ski-in-new-zealand/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-places-to-ski-in-new-zealand/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 01:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3171</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m no expert when it comes to skiing or snowboarding &#8211; in fact I&#8217;ve only been on the slopes twice in my life. There are plenty of great places to ski in New Zealand so I asked Mike from Nomads on the Road to share them with me. He&#8217;s the go-to guy when it comes [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-places-to-ski-in-new-zealand/">The Best Places to Ski in New Zealand</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m no expert when it comes to skiing or snowboarding &#8211; in fact I&#8217;ve only been on the slopes twice in my life. There are plenty of great places to ski in New Zealand so I asked <strong>Mike from Nomads on the Road</strong> to share them with me. He&#8217;s the go-to guy when it comes to anything snow related so listen up and learn!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Finding great places to ski in New Zealand is not as daunting as you may think. You just need to be realistic about the terrain and quality of snow. As someone who has lived, worked and skied in the French Alps, Colorado, Canada as well as New Zealand, I can tell you New Zealand is right up there for fun on the slopes. New Zealand’s ski scene is predominately based in the South Island; there are a splattering of ski hills and club fields in the North Island which is where we will start our round-up of places to ski in New Zealand.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>The North Island</h2>
<div id="attachment_3195" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Mount-Ruapehu-Photo-Credit-Cusegoyle-e1362975364961.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3195" title="Mount Ruapehu - Photo Credit - Cusegoyle" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Mount-Ruapehu-Photo-Credit-Cusegoyle-e1362975364961.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mount Ruapehu<br />Source: Cusegoyle on Flickr</p></div>
<p>Starting in the North Island and the obvious and logical mountain to focus on is the volcanic Mount Ruapehu. <strong>Mount Ruapehu</strong> is not only a very active volcano, but it also holds the distinction of being the largest ski area in New Zealand. Home to two commercial ski fields, <strong>Whakapapa</strong> (the largest ski area in New Zealand) to the north and <strong>Turoa</strong> on the southern slope, Mount Ruapehu is also home to a little club field to the east, <strong>Tukino</strong>.</p>
<p>Home to New Zealand’s largest beginners’ area, known as Happy Valley, <strong>Whakapapa</strong> is proud of the fact they set it away from the rest of the ski hill. Equipped with its own café, rental shop and ski school meeting area, Happy Valley has a long gentile slope accessed by a slow moving chairlift, perfect for learning. With more than 30 groomed intermediate trails, skiers and boarders are offered a nice variety of trails, bumps, chutes, bowls and wide groomers. For those more advanced skiers and boarders Whakapapa offers 24 black and black diamond runs, as well as lift-accessed back country. The back country area is known as Black Magic and each September plays host to the popular ‘Extreme Competition’.</p>
<p>The beginners’ area at Turoa is known as Alpine Meadow, a superb little learner’s hill. With a huge 120m long carpet, Alpine Meadow offers a mellow introduction to skiing and snowboarding. With the Alpine Chalet right next to the beginners’ area, guests will be able to recoup with coffee, meals, snacks or even a moral boosting beer after a day on the slopes. The intermediate area at Turoa mainly consists of wide and smooth runs; though for the more adventurous there are a few chutes and bowls. With 12 intermediate groomers linking to one another, skiers and boarders can enjoy long and challenging riding all the way from the top of Australasia’s highest lift to the base. Turoa’s advanced area consists of 25 black and black diamond runs and two lift-accessed backcountry areas where riders will find a huge variety of terrain. Natural half-pipes and chutes through the Organ Pipes and Solitude backcountry area along with the sweeping terrain of the Triangle and Glacier backcountry area makes skiing and boarding at Turoa very special in New Zealand.</p>
<div id="attachment_3199" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Tukino-photo-credit-elbroka-e1362975844138.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3199" title="Tukino - photo credit - elbroka" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Tukino-photo-credit-elbroka-e1362975844138.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Tukino<br />Source: elbroka on Flickr</p></div>
<p>Located on the eastern slopes of Mount Ruapehu, Tukinooffers that rare combination on a ski hill, lack of crowds, friendly faces and superb terrain. The slopes at Tukino are sheltered from the westerly winds and the club often operates with clear skies while the rest of the mountain could be covered in cloud. Snow conditions vary but for those who make it up the hill early will rewarded with fine conditions in the mornings with the sun softening up the snow.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>The South Island</h2>
<p>Reeling off the list of resorts on New Zealand’s South Island is an article in its own right. Treble Cone, Cardrona, Snow Park, The Remarkables, Coronet Peak, Oahu, Roundhill, Mount Hutt, and Porters are all top ski hills. That is before we even mention the excellent club fields of Fox Peak, Mount Dobson, Hanmer Springs Ski Area and the four clubs which make their home on the Craigieburn Range – Broken River, Craigeburn Valley, Mount Cheeseman and Mount Olympus.</p>
<p>Starting with the impressive Treble Cone located in Wanaka, the ski hill overlooks the pristine waters of Lake Wanaka, yet there is more to Treble Cone than just great views. Treble Cone offers the largest ski area and the longest vertical in the South Island, long uncrowded groomed slopes and some of the best off-piste terrain in New Zealand. Heading away from Wanaka and into the Crown Range, skiers and boarders will have two options on opposite sides of the valley.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3198" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cardrona.-Photo-Credit-Ca.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3198" title="Cardrona.-Photo-Credit---Ca" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cardrona.-Photo-Credit-Ca.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Cardrona<br />Source: Ca on Flickr</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>On the right heading out from Wanaka is <strong>Cardrona</strong>. With a peak elevation of 1860m, vertical rise of 600m and 345 hectares to play in, Cardrona is a great all-round ski hill. On the opposite side the valley is New Zealand’s only dedicated terrain park. <strong>Snow Park</strong> offers freestyle skiers and snowboarders’ world-class park riding. It’s not often people call skiing and snowboarding in the Southern Hemisphere world-class but in Snow Park they have a world-class terrain park, presenting a range jibs, jumps, rails, boxes and half pipes for shredders.</p>
<p>Moving on to the <strong>Queenstown</strong> ski hills, there are two to choose from, <strong>The Remarkables</strong> and <strong>Coronet Peak</strong>. The Remarkables certainly live up to their name, maybe not quite for the quality and quantity of snow but for the views. One of the most famous and photographed mountain ranges in the world, thanks to the combination of jagged shapes which rises steeply above the shores of Lake Wakatipu. Coronet Peak is the most popular ski hill in South Island, entirely due to its proximity to Queenstown. This ski hill is perfect for beginners and intermediate skiers and snowboarders. So much so that Powderhound magazine has given Coronet Peak a ‘best skiing in New Zealand’ award for their intermediate terrain. With only 280 hectares and 481 metres of vertical, the simple fact is Coronet Peak is small. However 30 per cent of its terrain is classed as black, and with various off-piste runs around the edges of the resort and a few chutes, advanced skiers and riders can have some fun too.</p>
<p><strong>Oahu</strong> is one of New Zealand’s hidden gems, as much we don’t like to refer to places in those terms; it’s true in this case. This little South Island ski hill has the vibe of a local club field yet is a fully commercial enterprise. No crowds mean fresh lines can be found, when the snow is willing to oblige. Located in the Mackenzie District, 3.5 hours from Christchurch, Oahu overlooks the lake of the same name.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3196" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Roundhill-Photo-Credit-olso-council-e1362975547972.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3196" title="Roundhill - Photo Credit olso council" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Roundhill-Photo-Credit-olso-council-e1362975547972.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="399" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Roundhill<br />Source: Olso Council on Flickr</p></div>
<p>Moving north towards Lake Tekapo and you will find the charming small resort<strong> Roundhill</strong>. While it retains the vibe of a chill club field, in 2010 the introduction of a ropetow has opened up an incredible adjoining face, which was once hike-only. The lift now gives Roundhill 780 metres of vertical, the longest of any New Zealand ski hill as well as increasing the skiable terrain from 60 hectares to 500 hectares.</p>
<p><strong>Mount Hutt</strong> is a ski hill which receives an impressive (by New Zealand standards) four metres of snow on average each year. However the 365 hectares is often closed due to Mount Hutt sitting on the edge a mountain range and therefore exposed to cold and strong winds. The ski area and the steep windy access road are at Mother Nature’s mercy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3197" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Porters-Photo-Credit-elrentplats-e1362975629974.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3197" title="Porters - Photo Credit - elrentplats" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Porters-Photo-Credit-elrentplats-e1362975629974.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Porters<br />Source: elrenplats on Flickr</p></div>
<p>The closest ski area to Christchurch is <strong>Porters</strong> and while it is no Vail or Whistler it is a pretty damn fine resort by New Zealand standards. The resort offers a new day lodge, café, shop and ski rental area. But more importantly it offers great views of Lake Coleridge. With plenty of skiable terrain at Porters to appeal to beginners and intermediates, advanced riders may feel left out. Yet the vertical drop is impressive and there is a lot for these riders to enjoy. Easily accessed backcountry bowls means Porters is much bigger than the in-bounds 230 hectares suggests.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>South Island Club Fields</h2>
<p>With a range of commercial ski hills to choose from, many skiers and boarders like to get away from the crowds – not easy on an island where it seems half the southern hemisphere loved to shred. Yet the abundance of well-run club fields in the South Island means for those wishing to escape the crowds and enjoy some great lines, the option is there.</p>
<p><strong>Fox Peak</strong> and <strong>Mount Dobson</strong> are two club fields in the Lake Tekapo area. Dobson has that unique Kiwi relaxed attitude. The 400 hectares of Mount Dobson terrain is contained within a treeless bowl. No crowds mean powder days at Mount Dobson can be epic.</p>
<p><strong>Fox Peak</strong> is a classic club field, run by an old ski club which was established in 1929, and with non-members welcome to visit the hill it still retains that ski bum vibe. With 850 vertical metres and 500 hectares of lift accessed terrain, Fox Peak is a large ski hill by New Zealand standards.</p>
<p>Getting to <strong>Hanmer Springs Ski Area</strong> is half the fun. But those who succeed will be rewarded with thin or non-existent crowds, cheap accommodation, lifts that spin from sun up to sundown, views to cry over and friendly staff. The ski field, formerly known as Amuri, is basically one wide open bowl with no trees – alpine style.</p>
<p>Four clubs which make their home on the Craigieburn Range – <strong>Broken River, Craigeburn Valley, Mount Cheeseman</strong> and <strong>Mount Olympus.</strong> <strong>Broken River </strong>is a no-frills club field which caters to skiers and snowboarders with an adventurous side. <strong>Craigeburn Valley</strong> offers some of New Zealand’s most challenging terrain, offering steep, narrow chutes to wide-open bowls &#8211; no groomers to be found here. <strong>Mount Cheeseman</strong> is a club field which offers only two T-bar lifts, a learners’ tow and 320 metres of vertical. Sitting within an alpine basin the terrain varies from mellow to steep. <strong>Mount Olympus</strong> sounds like something from ancient Greece and the motto of the Mt Olympus ski area is ‘Playground of the Gods’. This club field offers big mountain skiing, slopes which capture powder and of course no crowds. Hike to the best spots and enjoy fresh lines all day.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Profile-pic.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3305 alignleft" style="border: 2px solid black; margin: 5px;" title="Profile-pic" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Profile-pic.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a></em></p>
<p><em style="font-size: 13px;">Mike is a writer and wannabe mountain man, if he could grow a big bushy beard he would, but he will settle for writing about all things adventure. Currently living in <strong><a href="http://www.nomadsontheroad.com/" target="_blank">Fernie</a></strong>, BC. You can also follow Mike on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/nomadsontheroad">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.twitter.com/MikeCjourno">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://plus.google.com/117190067562005577854">Google Plus</a> and <a href="http://pinterest.com/mikecjourno">Pintrest</a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>What’s your favourite place to ski or snowboard in NZ? Let us know in the comments below…</em></strong></p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-places-to-ski-in-new-zealand/">The Best Places to Ski in New Zealand</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-places-to-ski-in-new-zealand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dohop vs Skyscanner</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/dohop-vs-skyscanner/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/dohop-vs-skyscanner/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 03:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3304</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m always looking for new ways to search for cheap flights. Kate from RTW Travel Guide just posted this great post comparing flight booking sites. She compared Momondo with a newer flight search engine called Dohop and found them to be great at identifying cheap flights. I&#8217;d never heard of Dohop before so I did [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/dohop-vs-skyscanner/">Dohop vs Skyscanner</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m always looking for new ways to search for cheap flights. Kate from RTW Travel Guide just posted this great post <a href="http://rtw-travel-guide.com/momondo-versus-dohop/" target="_blank">comparing flight booking sites</a>. She compared Momondo with a newer flight search engine called <a href="http://www.dohop.com/" target="_blank">Dohop</a> and found them to be great at identifying cheap flights. I&#8217;d never heard of Dohop before so I did a little research for myself and experimented by comparing them to my go-to flight search engine <a href="http://www.skyscanner.co.nz" target="_blank">Skyscanner</a>.</p>
<p>Like Skyscanner, Dohop searches include some budget airlines which I find super helpful. In addition to flights, Dohop also searches hotels and rental cars. Their site is responsive which means you can comfortable view in on different sized laptops, tablets and smart phones. All very big pluses.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m pricing up a few ideas for a European trip at the moment. Specifically, a trip to Ireland for a conference in October followed by a stay in the Emilia Romanga region of Italy. I used the research for this trip as an excuse to experiment with Dohop.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Six days Car Hire around Ireland</h2>
<p>We want to spend a week exploring Ireland before the conference. The best way to get around Ireland is to hire a car so I searched a six day &#8220;Economy&#8221; car hire across the same dates (picking up and dropping off in Dublin) on both search engines.</p>
<p>The results?</p>
<p>Skyscanner and Dohop both returned similar results. The same companies, the same cars but Dohops prices were a couple of Euros less per week in each car class. For a Toyota Yaris rented through Sixt Skyscanner quoted €125.18 and Dohop quoted €122.73. The cost of renting a toddler seat and a GPS were the same with both booking engines. <strong>Even if it&#8217;s only a saving of €2.50, Dohop wins! </strong>Europe is expensive so I&#8217;ll take any small win I can get.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Flights from Dublin to Bologna</h2>
<p>There are no direct flights between Dublin and Bologna and we would need to arrive in Bologna at a reasonable time of day which complicates this leg of the journey somewhat.</p>
<p>The results?</p>
<p>Both Dohop and Skyscanner are again evenly matched on this account. Unless we fancied a 17 hour stopover in Copenhagen, the only reasonbley priced option would be to piece together a connection flight on budget airline RyanAir. Both booking engines presented me this option but Skyscanner hides it initially as it&#8217;a multi part booking. You can&#8217;t book connecting flights straight through on RyanAir, you have to clear customs and collect bags before checking into the next flight. I can understand why Skyscanner would try to deter people from doing this as it is rather messy but for those of us who like to save money on flights it is nice to be presented ALL the options clearly.</p>
<p>Dohop suggested a flight from Dublin to Chaleroi and then onto Bologna for a total price of <strong>€89 and a total journey time of 5 hrs 30. </strong>Skyscanner suggested a route through London Stansted Airport which cost <strong>€91 with a total journey time of 11 hrs 10. </strong><strong>Because of the journey time alone, Dohop wins on this occasion.</strong> I would NOT recommend playing around with DIY connections on RyanAir as they are notorious at providing bad service, late flights or <a href="http://walkingontravels.com/2013/02/05/travel-disaster-ryanair-dumped-my-family-at-the-wrong-airport/" target="_blank">landing the plane at a different airport and not telling you</a> as my friend Keryn from Walking On Travels found out the hard way in Sicily recently.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Flights from Dublin to Milan</h2>
<p>While our ultimate destination is Bologna, Milan is only 200kms away. As it&#8217;s a major hub I also investigated flying into Milan and catching the train to Bologna. There&#8217;s no direct flight between Dublin and Bologna so whether we travel via two planes or a plane then a train makes no difference to me. Lee and Reuben haven&#8217;t been to Milan so it could be a good opportunity to visit.</p>
<p>The results?</p>
<p>Both Dohop and Skyscanner found me the same Aer Lingus flights direct from Dublin to Milan &#8211; one to Malpensa and one to Linante. <strong>Skyscanner quoted €68 and Dohop quoted <strong>€67. </strong></strong>Train tickets from Milan to Bologna go for as little as €10 so the price is definitely right on this option.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>One Night in a Hotel in Milan</h2>
<p>While <a title="Toddler Travel Tips: Vacation Apartment Rentals" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/toddler-travel-tips-vacation-apartment-rentals/" target="_blank">we prefer vacation rentals</a> overall, if we&#8217;re only in town for a few nights a hotel suits us better. There&#8217;s no cleaning fee or faffing about making arrangements with owners. Sure you lose the benefits of a kitchen and seperate sleeping space for Reuben but you also gain a location advantage and access to hotel amenities and services. I visited Milan back in 2008 and stayed in a great hotel that I&#8217;d like to visit again so I used both search engines to find a price for <a href="www.hotelcristoforocolombo.com" target="_blank">Hotel Cristoforo Colombo</a>.</p>
<p>The results?</p>
<div>Both Dohop and Skyscanner returned identical search results - <strong>€93 a night down from <strong>€143 </strong></strong>which seems like a pretty good rate to me. I&#8217;m surprised at how similar the hotel booking section of both sites are.</div>
<div></div>
<h2>Summary</h2>
<p>While Skyscanner has long been my favourite way to search flights online, Dohop might become a fast favourite. Even thought the savings made in this booking were minor, when you&#8217;re a travelling family purchasing multiple tickets, these little wins all add up. (Unlike Kate at RTW Travel Guide who managed to <a href="http://rtw-travel-guide.com/momondo-versus-dohop/" target="_blank">find a saving of AU$400 using Dohop</a>!)</p>
<p>The design of Dohop&#8217;s homepage is simple, clean and easy to use. I love that on each of the search results you can map the flight out &#8211; super handy if you don&#8217;t know where every single airport in the world is. (I didn&#8217;t know that Charleroi was in Belgium until I looked at Dohop&#8217;s map.) You can also share each flight you find by email right from the booking page which makes coordinating travel with others simple.</p>
<div><strong>In short, I&#8217;m loving Dohop! Give it a go next time you&#8217;re searching for flights, cars or hotels.</strong></div>
<div></div>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/dohop-vs-skyscanner/">Dohop vs Skyscanner</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/dohop-vs-skyscanner/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How a Rainy Day in Yangon Turned Into My Best Ever Travel Moment</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-a-rainy-day-in-yangon-turned-into-my-best-ever-travel-moment/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-a-rainy-day-in-yangon-turned-into-my-best-ever-travel-moment/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 01:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Burma]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3098</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that March is National Umbrella Month? Funny that. How does this relate to a travel tale, you ask? I&#8217;m about to tell you how a rainy day in Yangon turned into my best ever travel moment. And, yes, there is an umbrella in this story. It&#8217;s 2009. May. The middle of the [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-a-rainy-day-in-yangon-turned-into-my-best-ever-travel-moment/">How a Rainy Day in Yangon Turned Into My Best Ever Travel Moment</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that March is <strong>National Umbrella Month</strong>? Funny that. How does this relate to a travel tale, you ask? I&#8217;m about to tell you how a rainy day in Yangon turned into my best ever travel moment. And, yes, there is an umbrella in this story.</p>
<div id="attachment_3225" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/P1060615.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3225" title="Storm Clouds Brewing Over Shwedagon Pagoda, Yangon, Burma" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/P1060615-e1363050741896.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Storm Clouds Brewing Over Shwedagon Pagoda</p></div>
<p>It&#8217;s 2009. May. The middle of the stinking hot season in South East Asia and I decide, on impulse, to spend a week in Burma. I&#8217;m walking the streets of Yangon one sunny afternoon. Temperatures have been hovering around 40 degrees all week and it is HOT. I&#8217;m pawing of street market stalls buying dodgy bootleg DVDs and even dodgier jewellery made of bullets when suddenly the heavens open. Bucketloads of rain are literally spilling down on top of me and I&#8217;m quickly getting soaked through. The vendors all quickly pack up their things and I stand there like a dummy not knowing what to do. Anywhere else in Asia I&#8217;d simply hop in a taxi or on the back of a bike and zoom back to my hotel. But this is Yangon. Taxi&#8217;s are few and fair between and the ones I do find don&#8217;t know where my guesthouse is or can&#8217;t speak English. The only thing to do is to keep on walking. Not that I know where I&#8217;m going&#8230;.</p>
<p>Out of nowhere a kind voice asks me, in English because obviously I don&#8217;t speak Burmese, if I need an <em><strong>umbrella</strong></em>. I turn around and see an even kinder face repeating the offer. A young monk introduces himself to me and suggests I step under his umbrella. I gladly accept and he proceeds to chat away at me in pretty good English. He offers to take me to a tea shop to wait out the storm and, again, I gladly accept. We retreat to a little shop and sit on plastic children&#8217;s chairs and sip a strange blend. I am a stranger in this environment and receive a lot of strange stares. We pass the time by discussing the usual topics &#8211; where are you from, where are you going, what do you think of Burma? An hour passes and the rain ceases. My new friend escorts me to a taxi. Giving me his phone number he insists we meet again when I pass back through Yangon at the end of the week.</p>
<p>If he hadn&#8217;t been a monk, the whole thing would have been terribly romantic.</p>
<p>The week passes. I travel to Bagan and once back in Yangon, the receptionist at my guesthouse helps me call the monastery. After a few failed attempts, we finally make contact with my monk who has been out at English lessons all day. We make plans for me to arrive the next morning and visit the monastery in which he lives.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m greeted by a friendly wave from the gate of the monastery. My monk shuffles me around the grounds showing me the different areas &#8211; the monks quarters, the mess hall and the incredibly simple orphanage where 40-odd boys from around the country have come to live having lost their parents to violence or to Cyclone Nargis the year before. The boys are much more interested in their television than they are in meeting a foreigner. We proceed to the mess hall where I&#8217;m left alone with the Abbott to discuss Buddhism while my friend collects our lunch. The Abbott speaks a little English and with the help of a phrasebook we converse. My monk returns with a home cooked meal for the two of us to share. As monk&#8217;s rise early and don&#8217;t eat after 12pm, lunch is served at 10.30am. Each day a different woman from the community prepares a lunch for my monk. I&#8217;m sure on this day she&#8217;s been instructed to prepare a feast fit for a fat foreigner.</p>
<div id="attachment_3227" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/P1060908.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3227" title="Lunchtime at the Orphanage, Yangon, Burma" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/P1060908-e1363050812545.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="800" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Lunchtime at the Orphanage</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3228" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/P1060902.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3228" title="Orphanage Yangon Burma" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/P1060902-e1363050917631.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Residents Crowded Around the Television</p></div>
<p>After a large meal of vegetarian delights, I have to make a speedy exit to catch my flight back to Bangkok. Not wanting to waste a moment of time together, my monk accompanies me by taxi back to my guesthouse to collect my bags and then on to the airport. He tells me I&#8217;m the first foreigner he&#8217;s ever had the courage to speak to despite taking English lessons for a year. He tells me of his plans to move to Sri Lanka to study for a Masters&#8217; degree at a Buddhist University. I feel compelled to give him my remaining cash to pay for more English lessons and contribute to his flight &#8211; about US$200 and a few handfuls of Kyat. Our extraordinary meeting comes to an end as I slip past the security gate and onto my flight but our friendship continues to this day through the modern marvel of Facebook.</p>
<div id="attachment_1441" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/P1060906.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1441" title="Buddhist Monk, Yangon, Burma" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/P1060906-e1363050974783.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">With Ashin Panyin at the Monestary in Yangon</p></div>
<p>If I&#8217;d had my own <em><strong>umbrella</strong> </em>the best moment I&#8217;ve ever had on the road would never have happened.</p>
<p><strong>The moral of the story? Never be prepared and always talk to strangers.</strong></p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-a-rainy-day-in-yangon-turned-into-my-best-ever-travel-moment/">How a Rainy Day in Yangon Turned Into My Best Ever Travel Moment</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-a-rainy-day-in-yangon-turned-into-my-best-ever-travel-moment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Zealand Travel Tips from the Experts</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/new-zealand-travel-tips-from-the-experts/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/new-zealand-travel-tips-from-the-experts/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 01:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3082</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve enlisted the help of an army of bloggers to create an expert list of New Zealand travel tips. They&#8217;ve been there, done that and bought the t-shirt. If anyone knows how to travel around New Zealand, it&#8217;s these guys. They&#8217;ve also weighed in on the best places in New Zealand to visit. Behold! The [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/new-zealand-travel-tips-from-the-experts/">New Zealand Travel Tips from the Experts</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve enlisted the help of an army of bloggers to create an expert list of New Zealand travel tips. They&#8217;ve been there, done that and bought the t-shirt. If anyone knows how to travel around New Zealand, it&#8217;s these guys. They&#8217;ve also weighed in on the <a title="The Best Place in New Zealand" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-place-in-new-zealand/">best places in New Zealand to visit</a>.</p>
<p>Behold! The ultimate list of New Zealand travel tips, written by the experts!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3088" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 609px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Camping-Chris-Cristensen.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3088" title="Coromandel Peninsula" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Camping-Chris-Cristensen-e1362556489643.jpg" alt="" width="599" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A shot in Coromandel Peninsula.<br />Source: Chris of AmateurTraveler</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;New Zealand is well set up for people who want to camp. You can either tent camp or rent an RV but camp sites for both are easy to find. You will need to plan ahead more in the New Zealand Summer when the kiwis (the people) are also out camping.&#8221; &#8211; Cris at <a href="http://amateurtraveler.com/tag/new-zealand/">Amateur Traveler</a></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Everyone has to hitchhike. Put aside any and all fears you have about it. The hitchhiking culture is prevalent in New Zealand (it was the locals who talked me into doing it). You will meet some great Kiwis and come back with the best stories of your entire visit. I wrote about one of my experiences hitchhiking <a href="http://www.goseewrite.com/2010/02/hitchhiking-and-general-niceness-in-new-zealand/">here</a>&#8220;</em>. &#8211; Michael at <a href="http://www.goseewrite.com/2011/03/best-of-new-zealand/">GoSeeWrite</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Country motels are very good accommodation deals. If you buy or hire a car (and you should) &#8211; you can often stay in motel complete with your own kitchen for the same price as a dorm in a hostel if there are 2 or 3 of you travelling together. The AA puts out good guides to all the regions &#8211; obviously mainly advertising but good maps and good overviews of the region. Too many overseas visitors skip Taranaki, and New Plymouth &#8211; far more interesting than Matamata IMHO.The transport system isn&#8217;t great, we don&#8217;t have the population to support decent public transport like say the UK. Cars, are cheap to buy, if you are staying for month or more, you&#8217;ll find it straightforward to buy a car, and even if you have to abandon it at the end of the trip, it will be cheaper than renting.</em><span style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">- Elisabeth at </span><a style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;" href="http://listraveltips.com/new-zealand-travel/">LisTravelTips</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3090" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 609px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Rafting.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3090" title="Rafting" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Rafting-e1362556813542.jpg" alt="" width="599" height="399" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">White Water Rafting in NZ.<br />Source: Simon of LADventurers.</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;NZ can be very expensive. It&#8217;s so easy to spend all of your money due to the vast amount of activities you can do. I spent all of mine doing skydiving, bungee jumps, white water rafting, biking, kayaking etc etc. You need to look ahead and choose one thing perhaps per week for a big budget splurge. It&#8217;s really not sustainable doing everything in each place like I did. By the time you get to the big stuff, you&#8217;ve spent all your money. Having said that, I don&#8217;t regret doing any or all of it, even if it might have meant I was in the red for a while. </em><em style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">Another tip is to research the activity you want before booking it. Sky diving in Queenstown for example might be hundreds of dollars cheaper than sky diving in Auckland. I think over Lake Taupo is the cheapest.</em><span style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">&#8221; &#8211; Simon at </span><a style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;" href="http://www.ladventurers.com/">LADventurers</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;If you visit both islands (and I highly recommend you do), try to give it at least 3 weeks &#8211; 2 on the South Island, 1 week on the North Island. It&#8217;s tempting to whizz from A to B as there are so many stunning things to see and exciting things to do, but it&#8217;s better to concentrate on a few and really enjoy them. Driving is the best option to get from A to B, but don&#8217;t underestimate the distances; it will take you longer as there are no motorways, and you&#8217;ll want to stop and take pictures all the time.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Christina at <a href="http://sandalroad.com">SandalRoad</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Don&#8217;t miss out Northland just because it&#8217;s far away, if possible! Chat to the locals, and explore! It might be a bit trickier to get around if you haven&#8217;t hired a car, but aren&#8217;t those places often most worth it? You&#8217;ll be rewarded with plenty of remote beautiful beaches and real friendly kiwis.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Kate at <a href="http://canuckiwikate.com">Canuckiwikate</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3091" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Carole-Terwilliger-Meyers-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3091" title="Cape Kidnappers" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Carole-Terwilliger-Meyers-2-e1362557158267.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="800" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Birds in Cape Kidnappers, North Islands<br />Source: Carole of TravelsWithCarole</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Don&#8217;t miss the massive gannet colony at Cape Kidnappers on the North Island, where you can get very close to the birds. The birds arrive here in late July; the chicks hatch in late November and December; and igration begins again in March.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Carole at <a href="http://www.travelswithcarole.blogspot.com">TravelsWithCarole</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3092" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8106649626_a065d1a129_c.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3092" title="FamilyAdverntureProject" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8106649626_a065d1a129_c-e1362557335336.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: Stuart of FamilyAdventureProject</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;Take some sleeping bags and a tent. Camp where you can; most campsites are excellent and well equipped with playgrounds and facilities. And if or when you&#8217;re fed up with camping, stay in the wonderful cabins that you&#8217;ll find at most campsites, with their bunk beds, TV and kitchens. You&#8217;ll save a fortune in accommodation costs and have a lot more family fun.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Stuart at <a href="http://familyadventureproject.org/category/destinations/australasia/new-zealand/">FamilyAdvertureProject</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;I&#8217;d recommend people get off the beaten track. A campervan is the best way to see New Zealand because you can go anywhere, sleep anywhere and stay as long as you like. I know on a two week trip that people stick to the main tourist attractions but you can find amazing places all over New Zealand which only Kiwis visit if you have more time. Some little known places I&#8217;d recommend that most tourists don&#8217;t get to are the Hokianga Harbour, the Coromandel Penninsular and Great Barrier Island which are on or near the North Island. They all have rugged, unspoilt scenery and capture the spirit of pioneering New Zealanders.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Annabel at <a href="http://www.getinthehotspot.com/destinations/oceania/new-zealand/">GetInTheHotSpot</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Roadtrip around NZ, sure you can always catch the Kiwi Experience or the Magic Bus but there are some ‘off-the-beaten-track’ places which can only be reached by car or even better by foot.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Michael at <a href="http://www.nomadsontheroad.com/2011/11/12-reasons-to-visit-new-zealand/">NomadsOnTheRoad</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Kiwi travel tip: Dress in layers! Hot one moment, cold and rainy the next. If you don&#8217;t like the weather don&#8217;t worry, it will change in 15 minutes.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Larissa at <a href="http://www.changesinlongitude.com/category/destinations/oceania-posts/new-zealand-travel/">ChangesInLongtitude</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Make sure you think well about what kind of experience you would like to get in New Zealand. Are you a starting backpacker just looking to make friends and see the highlights in a short time? A bus tour might be for you. Are you visiting because of the nature and would you like to take it more slowly? You probably would like to have your own car, a tent and a pair of hiking boots. Make the right choice of how to get around to avoid disappointment and you&#8217;ll have the NZ experience that suits you best.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Nienke at <a href="http://www.thetraveltester.com/">TheTravelTester</a></p>
<p><div id="attachment_3093" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/LaurenceonthesummitofTaranaki1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3093" title="LaurenceonthesummitofTaranaki[1]" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/LaurenceonthesummitofTaranaki1-e1362557509709.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">On The Summit of Mount Taranaki<br />Source: Laurence of FindingTheUniverse</p></div><em>&#8220;If you&#8217;re on the North island, you should make the time to either tour the east cape, or head out to Mount Taranaki on the west coast (or both!). Both are spectacular for their own reasons, but far less visited than some of the other sights.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Laurence at <a href="http://www.findingtheuniverse.com/search/label/New%20Zealand%20Guides ">FindingTheUniverse</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;On arriving into Auckland I went out on a weekend liveaboard to The Poor Knights Islands where divers are treated to one of the most pristine underwater environments anywhere on the planet. The wealth of life is spectacular and because the area is a managed Marine Park it&#8217;s inhabitants are unfamiliar with human destruction meaning they are much more docile with divers. Once an active volcano the islands provide a retrospect of the past submerged in the ocean. Steeped in Maori history they are strictly off limits and no one may set foot on their soil.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Charli at <a href="http://wanderlusters.co.uk/">Wanderlusters</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Be sure to check out my guides to travel hacking in New Zealand:</p>
<ul>
<li><a title="Travel Hacking New Zealand: Finding Cheap Accommodation &amp; Activities" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/travel-hacking-new-zealand-finding-cheap-accommodation-activities/">Finding Cheap Accommodation and Activities in New Zealand</a></li>
<li><a title="Travel Hacking New Zealand: Finding Cheap Flights in New Zealand" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/travel-hacking-new-zealand-finding-cheap-flights-in-new-zealand/">Finding Cheap Flights in New Zealand</a></li>
<li><a title="Travel Hacking New Zealand: Transportation on the Cheap" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/travel-hacking-new-zealand-transportation-on-the-cheap/">Transportation on the Cheap in New Zealand</a></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Got any New Zealand travel tips to add? Let me know with a comment below.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/new-zealand-travel-tips-from-the-experts/">New Zealand Travel Tips from the Experts</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/new-zealand-travel-tips-from-the-experts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Do People Love New Zealand?</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/why-do-people-love-new-zealand/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/why-do-people-love-new-zealand/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3016</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m always surprised when other travellers tell me they&#8217;ve always wanted to visit New Zealand. For many, it&#8217;s their dream destination. Because I grew up here, I sometimes forget what an amazingly beautiful country New Zealand is. When you&#8217;re surrounded by towering mountains, lush rainforests and crystal clear lakes your whole life you can end [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/why-do-people-love-new-zealand/">Why Do People Love New Zealand?</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m always surprised when other travellers tell me they&#8217;ve always wanted to visit New Zealand. For many, it&#8217;s their dream destination. Because I grew up here, I sometimes forget what an amazingly beautiful country New Zealand is. When you&#8217;re surrounded by towering mountains, lush rainforests and crystal clear lakes your whole life you can end up taking it for granted. So, what is it that people love about New Zealand? For me, it&#8217;s got to be the relaxed nature of the people, the uncrowded cities and the great cafes and restaurants. It&#8217;s always refreshing to come home to what I consider &#8220;normal&#8221;. New Zealand is just home to me so to gain a little perspective I asked my travel blogging tribe to enlighten me on what it is they love about New Zealand.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Why do people love New Zealand?</strong></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3027" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Maori.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3027" title="Maori Meeting House" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Maori.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Bay of Islands<br />Source: Chris of Amateur Traveler</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;I enjoyed the beauty of the islands and also the exposure to the Maori culture.&#8221;</em> -Chris Christensen at <a href="http://amateurtraveler.com/tag/new-zealand/" target="_blank">AmateurTraveler</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Simply put, New Zealand has the friendliest people in the world. I love the scenery, the things to do, the outdoor culture, and more, but in the end it comes back to the people.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Michael Hodson at <a href="http://www.goseewrite.com/2011/03/best-of-new-zealand/" target="_blank">Go See Write</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;It&#8217;s an easy country to live in and run a business, we are usually ranked #1 in the world for ease of setting up a business, and the tax system is very straightforward too. The coffee is good, better than most places in the western world &#8211; this is amazing because until I left for the first time in the early 1980&#8242;s I&#8217;d never even seen a cappuccino! It&#8217;s small and compact, it&#8217;s easy to get around, and has huge variety of scenery within a day&#8217;s drive.&#8221; </em>- Elisabeth Sowerbutts at <a href="http://listraveltips.com/new-zealand-travel/" target="_blank">Lis&#8217;s Travel Tips</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3113" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 614px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/189_21354905577_6711_n1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3113" title="Kayaking in the South Island, New Zealand" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/189_21354905577_6711_n1.jpg" alt="" width="604" height="453" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kayaking in the South Island<br />Source: Simon Flood at LADventurers</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;New Zealand was a place, prior to travelling, I knew very little about. I thought Australia would be the highlight for me on my first ever RTW trip. It turned out it wasn&#8217;t. New Zealand upstaged Australia in every way possible. It had everything. Every single town/stop off has something for you and every single thing is different. There honestly isn&#8217;t a thing I can think of that New Zealand doesn&#8217;t have.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Simon Flood at <a href="http://www.ladventurers.com/" target="_blank">LADventurers</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;New Zealand is exactly on the other side of the world from where I grew up, and since I was a child I really wanted to visit just for that reason. Nowadays it is not only the remoteness but the many varied and simply stunning landscapes that attract me. I&#8217;m a very outdoorsy and adventurous kind of person, so I love all that New Zealand has to offer to the active traveller. On top of that, in the years that I have lived in London I have made quite a few kiwi friends , and their laid-back no-nonsense culture suits me really well. When I&#8217;m in NZ, I just love being in the mountains, cycling around the lakes, or being active outdoors in general. It&#8217;s got a very creative and quirky vibe, friendly, down-to-earth people, and great coffee. What more could you ask for?&#8221;</em> &#8211; Christina Hegele at <a href="http://sandalroad.com" target="_blank">Sandalroad</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3034" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Kate-Clarke.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3034" title="Kate Clarke" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Kate-Clarke-e1362471041915.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="449" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: Kate of CanuckiwiKate</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;Tough question after 4 years of living here! I think my list of what I DON&#8217;T love would be much shorter. I love the diversity of scenery compacted into one little far away package &#8211; you&#8217;ve got beaches for days in the winterless north, a multitude of volcanoes and unique geothermal activity, remarkable mountains strengthening &#8216;the backbone&#8217; of the south island, rugged coastlines, mighty fiords that soar into the sky and plunge hundreds of metres below the sea &#8211; it baffles my little mind! But I think the thing that has kept me here, has been the kiwi way of life. It&#8217;s a bit slower, relaxed, and often led by the &#8220;she&#8217;ll be riight&#8221; kind of mantra, and New Zealand has just got this unified pride that links the whole country. Air New Zealand has Grab a Seat, which makes it easy to jet set away each beautiful little corner for something different.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Kate Clarke at <a href="http://canuckiwikate.com/" target="_blank">CanucKiwiKate</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;It seems behind the times in a good way. I ran into few crowds, and prices are great.&#8221;</em> -Carole Meyers at <a href="http://www.travelswithcarole.blogspot.com" target="_blank">TravelsWithCarole</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;For families, especially those with younger children, it&#8217;s an easy, safe, friendly yet adventurous destination. There are no nasty insects, diseases or vaccinations needed. It has diverse attractions and a great outdoor lifestyle in a fairly small and compact area. And with two such different islands, it&#8217;s like two destinations in one.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Stuart at <a href="http://familyadventureproject.org" target="_blank">FamilyAdventureProject</a></p>
<div id="attachment_3036" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Annabel-Candy.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3036" title="Tairua" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Annabel-Candy-e1362472031969.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Beautiful Place of Tairua<br />Source: Annabel of GetInTheHotSpot</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;The laid back people, quirky charm and wild scenery. New Zealand is so varied you can see beaches, volcanoes, rainforest and even desert in one day. It&#8217;s a safe, easy place to travel with friendly, creative people and endless walks for nature lovers like me.&#8221;</em> -Annabel at <a href="http://www.getinthehotspot.com/destinations/oceania/new-zealand/ " target="_blank">GetInTheHotSpot</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;I love the landscape, around every corner is a different view designed to blow your mind.&#8221;</em> -Michael at <a href="http://www.nomadsontheroad.com/2011/11/12-reasons-to-visit-new-zealand/ " target="_blank">NomadsOnTheRoad</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3038" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Larissa-Milne.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3038" title="In front of a biplane" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Larissa-Milne-e1362472433279.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="481" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">In front of a biplane.<br />Source: Larissa of Changes In Longtitude</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;What we love about New Zealand: It&#8217;s not Australia. But seriously, the incredibly clean air, the unspoiled nature, the sweeping views when driving along the Southern Scenic Route, the relaxed carefree attitude of the people.&#8221;</em> -Larissa at <a href="http://www.changesinlongitude.com/category/destinations/oceania-posts/new-zealand-travel/" target="_blank">ChangesInLongtitude</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;New Zealand has great opportunities for making long hikes and going camping. It&#8217;s one of the reasons I&#8217;d love to go back one day as I didn&#8217;t do nearly enough of this during my first visit!&#8221;</em> -Nienke at <a href="http://www.thetraveltester.com/bucket-list-ideas-active/" target="_blank">TheTravelTester</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;I love that the country has such incredible variety in a relatively small amount of space. You can see fantastic mountains (and ski on them), then hit up the surf or go explore some jungles. From hikers to city lovers &#8211; New Zealand really has got something to offer everyone.&#8221;</em> -Laurence at <a href="http://www.findingtheuniverse.com/search/label/New%20Zealand%20Guides" target="_blank">FindingTheUniverse</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Having only been in the country a little over six weeks&#8230; I can tell you why I have already fallen in love with this wonderful country. Growing up New Zealand was just a shape on the map. Along with Australia, China and Japan they were exotic faraway lands that we learnt about in our Geography lessons along with tectonic plates and weather systems. The idea that I would ever visit such a magical place never crossed my mind.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Charli at <a href="http://wanderlusters.co.uk/">Wanderlusters</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>If you&#8217;ve been to New Zealand, tell me what it is you loved about it.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/why-do-people-love-new-zealand/">Why Do People Love New Zealand?</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/why-do-people-love-new-zealand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Best Place in New Zealand</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-place-in-new-zealand/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-place-in-new-zealand/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3054</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>What&#8217;s the best place in New Zealand? As New Zealand is my home country, this is a question I often get asked by other travellers when I&#8217;m out on the road myself. So many people want to visit New Zealand &#8211; seeing it as a magical, untouched paradise down in the corner of the world. [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-place-in-new-zealand/">The Best Place in New Zealand</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What&#8217;s the best place in New Zealand? As New Zealand is my home country, this is a question I often get asked by other travellers when I&#8217;m out on the road myself. So many people want to visit New Zealand &#8211; seeing it as a magical, untouched paradise down in the corner of the world. If you asked me I&#8217;d say that the <a title="Photo Essay: The Drive from Christchurch to Greymouth" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/drive-from-christchurch-to-greymouth/" target="_blank">West Coast of the South Island</a> was the most scenic and interesting part of the country but I may be biased as that&#8217;s where I grew up. <span style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">I haven&#8217;t travelled the length and breadth of New Zealand so I can&#8217;t definitively say&#8230; so I polled a great group of travel bloggers  and asked them;</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">What&#8217;s the best place in New Zealand?</h2>
<p>And these were their answers&#8230;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3066" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Michael-Hodson.jpeg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3066 " title="Michael Hodson" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Michael-Hodson-e1362552747968.jpeg" alt="" width="600" height="401" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A view in the Northlands.<br />Source: Michael at GoSeeWrite</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;I really enjoyed <strong>Northland</strong>, which is the area just north of Auckland. Auckland is such a typical huge, boring city (in my opinion) and it’s a relief that there is such a small-town oasis only an hour or so north of there. Plus, the scuba diving up there is great also.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Michael at <a href="http://www.goseewrite.com/2011/03/best-of-new-zealand/">GoSeeWrite</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;I really adore all of New Zealand, but I have to say I&#8217;m an Otago girl at heart. <strong>Otago</strong> is in a region in the south of the South Island, and home to some excellent Pinot Noir, as well as the Remarkables, which are great for hiking or skiing, and towns like <strong>Queenstown, Wanaka and Arrowtown</strong>, which I love. Queenstown is the adventure capital of New Zealand, where you can do anything from rafting to bungy jumping. Wanaka is slightly smaller but equally located beside a beautiful lake, and has some great skydiving and hiking, while Arrowtown is perhaps a little more laid back with its gold mining history and quaint setting.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Christina at <a href="http://sandalroad.com">SandalRoad</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3068" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Michael-Cotton.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3068" title="Michael Cotton" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Michael-Cotton.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: Michael of NomadsOnTheRoad</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;<strong>Wanaka</strong> – the laid back vibe that comes from knowing you live in a cool mountain town. The lake is epic in the summer, the mountains epic in the winter and superb hikes in every direction.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Michael at <a href="http://www.nomadsontheroad.com/2011/11/12-reasons-to-visit-new-zealand/">NomadsOnTheRoad</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3064" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Chris-Cristensen-The-Best-Place-in-New-Zealand.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3064" title="Chris Cristensen  The Best Place in New Zealand" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Chris-Cristensen-The-Best-Place-in-New-Zealand.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Blackwater Rafting &#8211; Waitomo<br />Source: Chris of Amateur Traveler</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;The best experience was Blackwater Rafting in the <strong>Waitomo Caves</strong>. Getting in a wetsuit and tubing down an underground river is not a common experience.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Chris at <a href="http://amateurtraveler.com/tag/new-zealand/">Amatuer Traveler</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3070" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/189_21354905577_6711_n.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-3070 " src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/189_21354905577_6711_n.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="453" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Breathtaking view in Southlands.<br />Source: Simon of LADventurers</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;I love <strong>Nelson</strong>&#8216;s point and <strong>Golden Bay</strong>. It&#8217;s at the very top of the South Island. You can kayak around and in between islands. The area is not accessible by any other mode of transport and it&#8217;s just amazing. You kayak between islands, stopping off where you like and meet other travellers doing the same. Engage in a game of beach cricket, eat lunch and have some beers (which you&#8217;ve of course brought yourself) before heading off to another place. The sunsets were amazing and it&#8217;s the one place in NZ that I really remember very well.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Simon at <a href="http://www.ladventurers.com/">LADventurers</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Best? Oh dear, this is going to be a tough one. I really enjoyed the south island immensely &#8211; the glaciers on the <strong>West Coast</strong> &amp; the boat trip out into <strong>Milford Sound</strong> being particular highlights. I guess <strong>Fiordland</strong> and <strong>Westland</strong> rate pretty highly from my year out there, but really, the whole country is just one long pile of awesome <img src='http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';)' class='wp-smiley' /> &#8221;</em> &#8211; Laurence at <a href="http://www.findingtheuniverse.com/search/label/New%20Zealand%20Guides ">FindingTheUniverse</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3072" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Nienke-Krook.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3072" title="Nienke Krook" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Nienke-Krook-e1362553670969.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="399" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Behind me is Lake Tekapo<br />Source: Nienke of TravelTester</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;The one place that I loved about New Zealand was <strong>Lake Tekapo</strong> on the South Island. It simply took my breath away, never seen anything like it. Unfortunately I booked myself a bus tour (big mistake) and had the driver honking at me for being late after only 5 minutes! I could&#8217;ve easily spend my whole stay staring at the beauty of this lake.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Nienke at <a href="http://www.thetraveltester.com/">TheTravelTester</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Best place we visited: <strong>Christchurch</strong>. We were there 9 months after the devastating earthquake. Downtown was still fenced off and being demolished. Yet the resiliency and optimism of the people who lost everything were like no other place on our around-the-world journey. It made us reflect on the meaninglessness of possessions and look at our own life in a whole new way.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Larissa at <a href="http://www.changesinlongitude.com/category/destinations/oceania-posts/new-zealand-travel/">ChangesInLongtitude</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3074" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Annabel-Candy1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3074" title="OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Annabel-Candy1-e1362553987118.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: Annabel of GetInTheHotSpot</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;If I had to pick one place I&#8217;d choose <strong>Waiheke Island</strong> where I lived for eight years. It has stunning beaches, some lovely little bush walks and the island is stuffed with award-winning wineries and vineyard restaurants. Sitting at the Mud Brick Restaurant with a wine in hand watching the sunset over the Hauraki Gulf with Auckland just across the water you feel like you&#8217;ve won the lotto.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Annabel at <a href="http://www.getinthehotspot.com/destinations/oceania/new-zealand/">GetInTheHotSpot</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;My top picks are <strong>Queenstown</strong>/<strong>Central</strong> <strong>Otago</strong> region: good in every season, and with some of the most reliable weather in the country. Huge range of things to do from scaring yourself to death doing adrenalin sports, to just chilling in some of the most accessible and beautiful scenery <strong>Wellington</strong> on a good day is spectacularly lovely, and on a bad day (of which there are plenty) Te Papa (the National museum), and the coffee shops will keep you entertained.&#8221;</em> -Elisabeth at <a href="http://listraveltips.com/new-zealand-travel/">LisTravelTips</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;It&#8217;s a tough choice, because I&#8217;ve found one of NZ&#8217;s best kept secrets, the <strong>Far North</strong>, and it has completely stolen my heart. It&#8217;s not for everyone, being quite a distance away from everything else on less than fabulous quality roads. But it&#8217;s quite and quaint, simple and ruggedly beautiful. </em><em style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">I also really love <strong>Milford Sound</strong></em><em>, because it is completely beautiful and unique rain or shine. I&#8217;ve been 3 times now, and it certainly has a magic about it. The anticipation of reaching such a remote destination gets me. The drive out is absolutely stunning, and there&#8217;s lots to see along the way. I&#8217;ve driven myself in, as well as flown over the Remarkables and have just been floored in awe of nature every time. I&#8217;ve done the standard cruise, as well as kayaked to Sterling Falls and back. I still need to get out to Doubtful Sound though</em><em style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">.&#8221;</em><span style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">- Kate at </span><a style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;" href="http://canuckiwikate.com">Canuckiwikate</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3075" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8106654714_eb6ec2e63c_z.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3075" title="Stuart Wickes" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8106654714_eb6ec2e63c_z-e1362554336293.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: Stuart of FamilyAdventureProject</p></div>
<p><em>&#8220;We cycled from the southernmost tip to the northern most tip with two toddlers and saw so much it&#8217;s hard to pick a place. Between us we loved the two extremes. I loved the wilderness of South Island and riding the backroads into the madness of adventure capital <strong>Queenstown</strong>. Kirstie loved the solitude and spiritual vibe of <strong>90 mile Beach</strong> and <strong>Cape Reinga</strong>, where the oceans meet and Maori spirits are said to depart for the afterlife. And the kids loved the sand duning on the Cape too.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Stuart at <a href="http://familyadventureproject.org/category/destinations/australasia/new-zealand/">FamilyAdvertureProject</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;I especially loved <strong>Christchurch</strong>. It is of course damaged now after the big earthquake, but it has an ancient English-style feel to it, and I enjoyed one of the best Indian meals ever (extraordinary, very hot Southern Indian murgee madras chicken curry) at Little India.</em> &#8211; Carole at <a href="http://www.travelswithcarole.blogspot.com">TravelsWithCarole</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Having just spent eleven months travelling around Australia I thought perhaps I&#8217;d be road tripped out by the time I arrived here in <strong>Auckalnd</strong>. However my thirst for exploration grows with every page I read of my New Zealand travel guide. This country does scenic views like nowhere else on the planet and having seen a large proportion of them recently on the cinema screen I can confidently say I am bursting with excitement. I had thought that the canvas on which the popular movies were filmed may have been jazzed up for the viewing public however I am starting to realise that was not the case.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Charli at <a href="http://wanderlusters.co.uk/">Wanderlusters</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So&#8230; there you have it. Basically, the best place in New Zealand lies anywhere from the very tip of the country to the tail!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Have you been to New Zealand? What do you consider the best place to visit?</strong></p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-place-in-new-zealand/">The Best Place in New Zealand</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-place-in-new-zealand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Things to Do in Port Douglas with Kids</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/things-to-do-in-port-douglas-with-kids/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/things-to-do-in-port-douglas-with-kids/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 23:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=2721</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Port Douglas, Luxury Resort Town or Family Destination? Since the 1970s Port Douglas in Far North Queensland has been known as an upmarket playground for the rich and famous. Celebrity sightings aren&#8217;t uncommon, the marina is full of beautiful charter boats and there is plenty of top end accommodation and dining. But times are changing, [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/things-to-do-in-port-douglas-with-kids/">Things to Do in Port Douglas with Kids</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><strong>Port Douglas, Luxury Resort Town or Family Destination?</strong></h2>
<p>Since the 1970s Port Douglas in Far North Queensland has been known as an upmarket playground for the rich and famous. Celebrity sightings aren&#8217;t uncommon, the marina is full of beautiful charter boats and there is plenty of top end accommodation and dining. But times are changing, money is tighter and Port Douglas is becoming more of a family destination. We still see the celebrities, George Michael, Pink and Kylie have been through here in the last few years, but looking around town we see more and more families visiting along with the crowds of backpackers. So&#8230;</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">&#8230;what is there to do in Port Douglas with kids?</h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3469" src="http://worldtravelfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Four-Mile-Beach-600x450.jpg" alt="OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<h2>Four Mile Beach</h2>
<p>Isn&#8217;t it beautiful? Port Douglas has a long expanse of smooth sand lapped by a tropical sea, the perfect beach for small children to play on, no rocks, no big waves or rips to worry about. Perfect for making sand castles. If you fancy an old-school seaside holiday, Port Douglas is for you. Remember that Port Douglas has a stinger season, the beach is netted in summer, life guards will give you advice on the current stinger risk. If you are feeling energetic you can hire bikes and pedal the entire length of Four Mile Beach at low tide.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3471" src="http://worldtravelfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Mossman-Gorge-600x450.jpg" alt="Mossman Gorge" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<h2>Mossman Gorge</h2>
<p>For a fresh water, stinger free, swimming experience take a 10 minute drive up to the Mossman Gorge. Visitors park at the information centre and catch the shuttle bus up through the Kuku Yalangi settlement and into the rain forest itself. It costs a few dollars but the service is great and the new visitor&#8217;s centre is worth a look. The gorge has beautiful new boardwalks, making stroller or wheelchair access fairly easy, there are still steps down to the main swimming area. The water is icy cold, crystal clear and full of friendly fish.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3534" src="http://worldtravelfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/011-2-600x450.jpg" alt="011 (2) (600x450)" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<h2>The Sunday Market</h2>
<p>Sunday is THE day in Port. Market day. You will find loads of great jewellery, locally produced crafts, toys, soaps, tropical fruit, chocolate, snacks, face painters and sometimes, buskers. The size of the market reflects the time of year, it shrinks in the wet season and is at its biggest in the winter. Go early, before it gets too hot. You can easily spend half a day hanging out at the market grounds.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3474" src="http://worldtravelfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Wildlife-Habitat-600x450.jpg" alt="Wildlife Habitat Port Douglas" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<h2>The Wildlife Habitat</h2>
<p>You always get a great wildlife fix just wandering around Port. You can&#8217;t miss the rainbow lorikeets and fruit bats, you may get lucky and see a python or a green tree frog, you can even see crocodiles if you know where to look. If you want all of this in one spot, <a href="http://www.wildlifehabitat.com.au/" target="_blank">visit The Wildlife Habitat</a>. You can hand feed wallabies and kangaroos, get as close as you like to an emu and have your photo taken holding a koala or python for a small extra charge. They have a café on site, their daily Breakfast With The Birds is pretty special, the children will love eating their bacon with a lorikeet perched on their heads.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3546" src="http://worldtravelfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Lady-Douglas-600x449.jpg" alt=" lady douglas" width="526" height="394" /></p>
<h2>Crocodile Spotting on the Lady Douglas</h2>
<p>This is one of my favourite ways to spend a few hours in Port Douglas. A lazy cruise up Dickson&#8217;s inlet taking in the view, the mangrove forests and yet more wildlife. I&#8217;ve taken this cruise many times and we&#8217;ve always seen salt water crocodiles, the family that owns the <a href="http://www.ladydouglas.com.au/" target="_blank">Lady Douglas</a> really love crocs and give a brilliant commentary on wildlife and local history as you sit sipping a chilled glass of something or munching on chocolate cake. I took my boys yesterday. &#8221; Did you enjoy that?&#8221; I asked. &#8221; No&#8221; D replied. &#8220;I LOVED it!&#8221; Children get to drive the boat!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3532" src="http://worldtravelfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/036-600x450.jpg" alt="OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<h2>Plenty of Playgrounds</h2>
<p>I&#8217;ve been there, travelled with toddlers and preschoolers &#8211; a playground can be a lifesaver. We have plenty, at the Market Ground, at Stinger Park ( Rex Smeal Park ) and a gorgeous one on Solander Boulevard, right behind the beach. They all have free gas barbecues, make a picnic of it and enjoy a glass of bubbly at sunset while the kids do their thing.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3530" src="http://worldtravelfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/great-barrier-reef-600-600x428.jpg" alt="things to do port douglas snorkel reef" width="600" height="428" /></h3>
<h2>Snorkelling on the Reef</h2>
<p>I&#8217;ve saved the best &#8217;till last. A day on the reef is jawdroppingly fabulous, it comes at a price but it&#8217;s worth every cent. Yes, you can take the kids, this is my 6 year old having an amazing day, he&#8217;s not a strong swimmer, but he was plenty good enough to thoroughly enjoy <a title="snorkelling on The Great Barrier Reef with kids" href=" http://worldtravelfamily.com/snorkeling-on-the-great-barrier-reef/" target="_blank">snorkelling The Great Barrier Reef</a>. There are quite a few boats to choose from, they depart Port Douglas Marina daily.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are plenty of other things to do in Port Douglas with kids, this is just the tip of a tropical iceberg! Hire a car and explore the Atherton Tablelands, swim in the Lagoon in Cairns or explore further into the Daintree Rainforest. I haven&#8217;t even told you about the most exciting thing that happens in Port Douglas, <a title="Feeding George the Groper. Port Douglas." href=" http://worldtravelfamily.com/george-the-groper/" target="_blank"> feeding George the Groper</a> is pretty cool, don&#8217;t miss it!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/144-150x150.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2741 alignleft" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="Alyson from World Travel Family" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/144-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a>Alyson is a British expat living in Port Douglas with her young family. She writes a family travel blog at <a href="http://worldtravelfamily.com" target="_blank"><strong>World Travel Family</strong></a>. She is about to take off round the world, to travel indefinitely, for fun, for family time and to give the children an amazing education. You can follow their adventure via the blog or via the <a title="World travel family on Facebook" href=" https://www.facebook.com/worldtravelfamily" target="_blank">World Travel Family Facebook page</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/things-to-do-in-port-douglas-with-kids/">Things to Do in Port Douglas with Kids</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/things-to-do-in-port-douglas-with-kids/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>House Sitting in New Zealand: Borrowing a Kiwi Burrow</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/house-sitting-in-new-zealand-borrowing-a-kiwi-burrow/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/house-sitting-in-new-zealand-borrowing-a-kiwi-burrow/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 03:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=2943</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>A humorous take on house sitting in New Zealand by the wonderful Wanderlusters&#8230;. &#160; &#160; The geographic isolation of New Zealand means that a large proportion of the native flora and fauna can not be found anywhere else in the world. The most iconic on this list of unique species is the curious little kiwi bird. Unlike [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/house-sitting-in-new-zealand-borrowing-a-kiwi-burrow/">House Sitting in New Zealand: Borrowing a Kiwi Burrow</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A humorous take on house sitting in New Zealand by the wonderful <a title="Wanderlusters" href="http://wanderlusters.co.uk" target="_blank">Wanderlusters</a>&#8230;.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The geographic isolation of New Zealand means that a large proportion of the native flora and fauna can not be found anywhere else in the world. The most iconic on this list of unique species is the curious little kiwi bird. Unlike many of his feathered friends he spends his nights alone, foraging for worms, spiders, bugs, grubs and fruit. Unable to fly he makes his home in a cosy little burrow in the ground. To the distress of all Kiwis their origin has been traced back to the Australian mainland. Long before the separation of the two land masses they were part of a larger super continent Gondwana. As the landscape evolved the kiwi bird made his home on the islands of New Zealand and here he has happily remained for the last seventy million years.</p>
<p>For British badgers such as ourselves the burrow of a curious kiwi bird has an exotic allure. Having spent much of our lives in the damp and overcrowded warrens of the UK we often dreamt of experiencing life in a Kiwi nest. The warm climate, relaxed lifestyle and striking landscape all aid in enticing foreigners half way across the globe, however we were unsure if a British badger would be welcomed into the kiwi bird’s burrow.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Lesson One: Kiwi Behaviour</strong></h2>
<p>Prior to our arrival in New Zealand we spent eleven months touring Australia in a motorhome and during our trip had taken the opportunity to gather as much information as we could regarding the curious Kiwi. His friendly neighbour the Wallaby had informed us that we were likely to succeed in our search for an empty burrow as the Kiwi regularly made the trip across the water in search of new opportunities. This was our first insight into the migratory behaviours of the adventurous kiwi bird.</p>
<p>The second came when we spoke to a born and bred Kiwi. During our conversation he divulged that not only did his kind leave their burrow for exploratory trips overseas, they also utilised public holidays to frequent an alternate burrow known as a ‘Bach’ thus escaping from the grind of daily life.</p>
<p>This was most interesting to hear.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Lesson Two: Recognising the Curious Kiwi</strong></h2>
<p>The easiest way to discover if there are Kiwis in the area is to listen for them. They are known to talk enthusiastically about outdoor pursuits, extreme adrenaline inducing sports and zorbing. When walking through one of the countries many natural reserves you can spot them running, cycling and generally being far too active for the warm temperature and time of day.</p>
<p>If none of the above character traits are clearly visible you can always spot a Kiwi by initiating conversation and listening intently to the grammatical structure of their reply. If they finish their sentence with an interrogative ‘eh’ you have found yourself a purebred Kiwi.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Lesson Three: Locating a Burrow to Borrow</strong></h2>
<p>So now that you understand the Kiwis a little better we can tell you how you can experience life in a Kiwi community.</p>
<p>We are fortunate enough to have been welcomed into communities all over the world but nowhere have we felt quite as at home as here in New Zealand. Despite our jovial portrayal of New Zealanders we have quickly learnt that they are a people proud of their heritage and the rich land they inhabit. The most forgiving of souls they smile as we butcher the Maori names given to many of the towns and cities across the country with our terribly British pronunciation. For this we are most grateful.</p>
<p>If you’ve the urge to leave your own nest and try out another for size, house sitting could provide the opportunity to do just that. Having looked after eleven homes since leaving the UK a little under two years ago house sitting has provided us with the chance to submerse ourselves in a wealth of different cultures during our travels.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" title="Diving in the Poor Knights' " src="http://wanderlusters.co.uk/wp-content/gallery/poor-knights-islands/nudibranch-poor-knights.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<p>Arriving in New Zealand at the beginning of December 2012 we hop footed it up to Tutakaka in Northland for a weekend of scuba diving at the <a title="Diving The Poor Knights Islands Marine Reserve" href="http://wanderlusters.co.uk/poor-knights-islands-marine-reserve/" target="_blank">Poor Knights Islands</a>. Just before we left Australia we’d successfully arranged to borrow our first Kiwi burrow and were keen to explore a little before caring for the home over Christmas and New Year.</p>
<p>We’ve both been overwhelmed by the generosity of the Kiwi families we have house sat for. Familiar only with the sound of our voice and the images we’ve attached to our house sitting profile they have all greeted us as they would close family and we were immediately made to feel at home.</p>
<p>Caring for a house in an unfamiliar area gives us the opportunity to explore new environments, cultures and communities. Each assignment is unique however they have all benefited our experience of travel in much the same way.</p>
<p>Living as a local enables you to join in with community life and meet the neighbours and friends of the home owners. You will often find yourself with invites to Thanksgiving, birthdays and festive celebrations, experiencing local life as a resident not a hotel hopping tourist.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Lesson Four: Becoming a House Sitter</strong></h2>
<p>Before leaving the UK we signed up with a house sitting service that unites home owners in need of property and pet care with those interested in temporarily living in a new environment.</p>
<p>Signing up online is very simple. Register, create a comprehensive profile and apply for the assignments that appeal to you. We use a brilliant website called <a title="TrustedHousesitters.com" href="http://www.trustedhousesitters.com" target="_blank">TrustedHousesitters.com</a> with whom we’ve secured assignments in <a title="Volunteering in Costa Rica – Why I CARE" href="http://wanderlusters.co.uk/volunteering-in-costa-rica/" target="_blank">Costa Rica</a>, Canada, USA, <a title="House Sitting in Valla Beach Australia" href="http://wanderlusters.co.uk/house-sitting-australia/" target="_blank">Australia</a> and here in New Zealand.</p>
<p>House sitting provides us with the opportunity for respite from our nomadic existence, it enables us to keep within our monthly budget and gives us chance to catch up on our freelance projects. However it can be utilised for finding holiday accommodation, hotel alternatives and inspiration for travel to locations off the beaten track.</p>
<p>Our Kiwi adventure has so far taken us to two house sitting assignments and we have just committed to another. Although we’ve only been in the country for a few months we already feel as though we’ve acquired an extended Kiwi family. This just about sums up the nature of the curious little Kiwi bird. He may not be able to fly but he’ll spread his wings and welcome you into his burrow.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="alignleft" style="margin-left: 3px; margin-right: 3px;" title="Northern Arch" src="http://wanderlusters.co.uk/wp-content/gallery/poor-knights-islands/northern-arch-poor-knights.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="166" />In 2010 Charli &amp; Ben made the decision to live a life less ordinary and six months later embarked on an undefined period of travel. Enforcing no restrictions on their itinerary they have chosen to travel at a slow pace and incorporate house sitting assignments in each country they visit. With no time limit on their adventure they are content to continue exploring the world as digital nomads. From backpacking through Central America to road tripping around Australia they embrace each and every opportunity for adventure. They run their own travel website <a title="Wanderlusters" href="http://wanderlusters.co.uk" target="_blank">Wanderlusters</a> and you can also find them on <a title="Facebook" href="http://www.facebook.com/Wanderlusters" target="_blank">Facebook</a> and <a title="@wanderlustersuk" href="https://twitter.com/wanderlustersuk" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.</p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/house-sitting-in-new-zealand-borrowing-a-kiwi-burrow/">House Sitting in New Zealand: Borrowing a Kiwi Burrow</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/house-sitting-in-new-zealand-borrowing-a-kiwi-burrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Travel Hacking New Zealand: Transportation on the Cheap</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/travel-hacking-new-zealand-transportation-on-the-cheap/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/travel-hacking-new-zealand-transportation-on-the-cheap/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 08:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=2888</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Transport will take a big chunk of your New Zealand budget. For such a small country, the distances between main centres are reasonably large. Diversifying your travel options will most likely be your best option. I&#8217;ve already covered how to get cheap flights in New Zealand so now let&#8217;s cover travel hacking New Zealand via [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/travel-hacking-new-zealand-transportation-on-the-cheap/">Travel Hacking New Zealand: Transportation on the Cheap</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Transport will take a big chunk of your New Zealand budget. For such a small country, the distances between main centres are reasonably large. Diversifying your travel options will most likely be your best option. I&#8217;ve already covered <a title="Travel Hacking New Zealand: Finding Cheap Flights in New Zealand" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/travel-hacking-new-zealand-finding-cheap-flights-in-new-zealand/" target="_blank">how to get cheap flights in New Zealand</a> so now let&#8217;s cover travel hacking New Zealand via ground transportation.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Trains</h2>
<p>New Zealand has some wonderfully scenic train rides. Travel by train often offers a slightly different perspective to travel by road. Just sit back and enjoy the scenery without having to worry about speed limits, toilet breaks and how much gas is left in the tank. The only downside? Rail travel in New Zealand ain&#8217;t cheap. You can, however, cut the costs with these simple tips:</p>
<ul>
<li>Book online using the <a href="kiwirailscenic.co.nz" target="_blank">Kiwi Rail website</a>. There are three regular fare options available &#8211; Super Saver, Smart Saver, Fully Flexi and occasionally seasonal specials.</li>
<li>Book in advance. Rail tickets get more expensive closer to the date of travel. If you book less than a week out, there won&#8217;t be any Super Saver tickets.</li>
<li>Book from within New Zealand. I have it on good authority from the <a href="http://www.seat61.com/NewZealand.htm" target="_blank">Man in Seat 61</a> that outside of New Zealand, if you search fares online, the Fully Flexi fare will be the only one displayed. If you want to book in advance outside of New Zealand use the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/download/download-easy.html.en" target="_blank">Tor Browser</a> to mask your IP address and give you access to the Super Saver and Smart Saver fares.</li>
<li>Children get a slight discount but family passes are available for two adults and two kids or one adult and three kids.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Ferries</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;re travelling the whole of New Zealand by car or camper, you will need to use the Interislander ferry to hop between the North and South Islands. If you&#8217;re using public transport it less than half the price to fly between Wellington and Christchurch than it is to use the train &amp; ferry combo. In fact, the ferry can be so costly that it might be cheaper overall if you hire a car an do a loop of the South Island and then fly to the North Island and hire a car there. For example, a one way ferry ride between Picton and Wellington with a car plus two adults and two children will cost over $250.</p>
<ul>
<li>Book online through the <a href="http://www.interislander.co.nz" target="_blank">Interislander</a> website. There are three fare options &#8211; Web Saver, Saver Change and Easy Change. Booking in advance doesn&#8217;t seem to alter the price. Web Saver fares always seem to be available, even when booking for same day travel.</li>
<li>Once again, booking online within New Zealand (or Australia) displays the Web Saver fares while booking from overseas does not. Either book within New Zealand or mask your IP address as above.</li>
<li>Sign up to the Interislander newsletter as they often email out promo codes.</li>
<li>Children get a slight discount but family passes are available for two adults and two kids.</li>
<li>See if your car hire company offers discounted ferry tickets. Occasionally deals will come up for car hire which includes a ferry ticket.</li>
</ul>
<div></div>
<h2>Buses</h2>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">There are plenty of bus (coach) companies that will get you from A to B in Aotearoa either independently or as part of a tour. There are no glaring easy ways to save money on bus travel in New Zealand but if you&#8217;re travelling solo or are under 21 it might be worth adding a few bus routes instead of hiring a car.</span></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://nakedbus.co.nz" target="_blank">Naked Bus</a> is the best option for intercity bus travel in New Zealand. You can get a seat for $1 if you book well in advance (like 3 to 6 months in advance) but typically booking a week or more in advance will save you $10 to $15 on each fare. There&#8217;s free wifi on board too.</li>
<li><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.intercity.co.nz/" target="_blank">Intercity</a> have point to point fares throughout New Zealand with some sale fares costing only $1 though these are tricky to find. There&#8217;s a night bus between Auckland and Wellington that can save you a night&#8217;s accommodation. There are travel passes available but at over $1000 a pop there are better ways to get around the country.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.kiwiexperience.com/passes/NZ/start-auckland/Pages/Buzzy-Bee.aspx" target="_blank">Kiwi Experience</a> buses are a hop on, hop off tour company that run set routes around the country. If you&#8217;re a young&#8217;un who likes being surrounded by other backpackers then give it a go. You can get from Auckland to Queenstown with at least a dozen stops for only $399 if you get it on sale through their website.</li>
<li><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.straytravel.com/" target="_blank">Stray Travel</a> is another hop on, hop off service that runs along a fixed route. Prices are around the $1000 for most routes but cover dozens of stops. Unless you got a great sale and were travelling alone, there are better options for getting around the country.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Car and Camper Hire</h2>
<p>Getting around New Zealand by car or camper is a good option. All the value in coming to New Zealand lies outside the cities in the stunning scenery. You&#8217;ll find many little spots to pull off, take in a glorious vista, eat a picnic lunch and enjoy the journey. The downside? Petrol is expensive &#8211; currently $2.20 a litre and car hire isn&#8217;t nearly as cheap as the US. Pick and choose the times you&#8217;ll really need a car or camper.</p>
<ul>
<li>If you&#8217;re going to be in New Zealand for a long period, consider buying a car or camper. The market for backpacker vehicles is good and if you buy a camper you&#8217;ll get all the kit along with it. Here are some sites to get you started:
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.trademe.co.nz/" target="_blank">Trade Me</a> is the number one site in New Zealand for buying and selling online. It&#8217;s the Kiwi equivalent of Ebay. It can&#8217;t be used outside New Zealand &#8211; you can browse but you can&#8217;t register in order to contact sellers.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.backpackerscars.com/" target="_blank">Backpacker Cars</a> in Christchurch</li>
<li><a href="http://www.backpackercarschristchurch.co.nz/" target="_blank">Backpackers Car Market</a> in Christchurch</li>
<li><a href="http://www.backpackerboard.co.nz/articles/buying-car-new-zealand.php" target="_blank">Backpacker Board</a> has a great notice board for buying and selling cars and campers.</li>
<li>For information on getting car insurance, registration and warrants check out this post on <a title="Life as an Expat in New Zealand" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/life-as-an-expat-in-new-zealand/" target="_blank">expat life in New Zealand</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>For short term travel, look for a relocation hire. If you&#8217;re flexible you can get relocations between main centres. Sometimes they&#8217;re free and include insurance, fuel and ferry tickets, sometimes there&#8217;s a small charge. Either way a relocation rental is by far the cheapest way to travel by car or camper. Here&#8217;s a list to the relocation pages of all the companies offering relocation cars and campers.
<ul>
<li><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="https://www.transfercar.co.nz/" target="_blank">Transfer Cars</a><span style="font-size: 13px;"> - relocation specialists</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 13px;"><a href="http://www.spaceshipsrentals.co.nz/deals/campervan-relocation-nz/" target="_blank">Spaceship Campers relocations</a></span></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thrifty.co.nz/index.cfm/1,119,299,0,html/FREE-Relocation-Deals-" target="_blank">Thrifty relocations</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.rentalcar.co.nz/new-zealand-car-hire-relocation-deals.aspx" target="_blank">About Rentals relocations</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.jucy.co.nz/special-offers/car-campervan-relocations.aspx" target="_blank">Jucy relocations</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.acerentalcars.co.nz/relocation/" target="_blank">Ace Rental Cars relocations</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.omegarentalcars.com/hot-deals/relocations/" target="_blank">Omega Rentals relocations</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.apexrentals.co.nz/RentalCarHotDeals/new-zealand-car-hire-relocation-deals.aspx" target="_blank">Apex Rentals relocations</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.britz.co.nz/cheap-new-zealand-motorhome-rental" target="_blank">Britz relocations</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 13px;">Look on group booking sites for vouchers for car or camper hire companies. Jucy Rentals have had deals on <a href="http://www.grabone.co.nz/auckland/jucy-rentals" target="_blank">Grabone</a> for specific deals (like Queenstown to Auckland for $25 including ferry tickets) or vouchers for $100 worth of rental for only $50 with the ability to buy and combine up to 10 vouchers!</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 13px;"><a href="http://grabaseat.co.nz/cars" target="_blank">Grabaseat have car rental</a> deals as well. They&#8217;re not quite as cheap as a relocation but you don&#8217;t have to be as specific.</span></li>
</ul>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Let me know how these tips for travel hacking New Zealand work out for you!</strong></div>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/travel-hacking-new-zealand-transportation-on-the-cheap/">Travel Hacking New Zealand: Transportation on the Cheap</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Flashpacker Family - Family Travel Blog, Travel with Kids, Toddler Travel Tips</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/travel-hacking-new-zealand-transportation-on-the-cheap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced

Served from: flashpackerfamily.com @ 2013-03-22 12:42:40 -->
