<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</title>
	
	<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com</link>
	<description>Flashpacker Family is a family travel blog sharing adventures and tips on travel with kids.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 07:11:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.1</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/FlashpackerFamily" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="flashpackerfamily" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">FlashpackerFamily</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>Keeping Kids Connected While Travelling</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/keeping-kids-connected-while-travelling/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/keeping-kids-connected-while-travelling/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 07:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family Travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3476</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>As our family is moving towards full-time nomadic travel, we&#8217;re thinking about ways we can keep Reuben connected to his extended family back home. He has a great relationship with his grandparents and aunties that we need to keep up even though we won&#8217;t be seeing them every weekend. Luckily, as one set of his grandparents already [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/keeping-kids-connected-while-travelling/">Keeping Kids Connected While Travelling</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As our family is moving towards full-time nomadic travel, we&#8217;re thinking about ways we can keep Reuben connected to his extended family back home. He has a great relationship with his grandparents and aunties that we need to keep up even though we won&#8217;t be seeing them every weekend. Luckily, as one set of his grandparents already lives overseas, he&#8217;s grown up having Skype dates and making phone calls with them so we&#8217;re already part way there.</p>
<p>Here are five ways you can encourage keeping kids connected while travelling:</p>
<h2>Phone Calls</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.rebtel.com/en/Services/international-phone-calls/" target="_blank">Making international phone calls</a> can be expensive. Services, like Rebtel, that can make it cheap to phone family and friends even if you don&#8217;t have a smartphone or internet access by using virtual <a href="http://www.rebtel.com/en/Services/phone-cards-rebtel/" target="_blank">calling cards</a>. Time differences can make things tricky. You may not be able to phone Grandma at home in New Zealand in the evening when you&#8217;re in New York and it&#8217;s 3am! Set up a call schedule and plan to grab Gran in the morning before she heads to work or over her lunch break. Get a Skype Number. Relatives and friends can phone a local number which will forward to Skype on your iPhone, iPad or laptop.</p>
<h2>Video Calls</h2>
<p>Use Skype or Facetime for face to face calls when you can. If you need to, coach the grandparents up on the ins and outs of Skype <em>before</em> you leave. Technosavvy relatives with iPhones can keep intouch with you via Facetime. Don&#8217;t just limit video calls to chatting about your day &#8211; use that time to read stories, sing songs or say prayers together.</p>
<h2>Photos</h2>
<p>If your children are really little and you don&#8217;t want them to forget their extended family, put together a small photo album or book with pictures and names of their relatives. Babies love flicking through pictures of faces.</p>
<h2>Write</h2>
<p>Don&#8217;t forget about traditional correspondence! If you want your kids to practice their handwriting, have them send snail mail home. If they&#8217;re older, set up a group email address so they can send friends updates from the road or even create a blog for them. Write or draw postcards as a way of <a title="Toddler Travel Tips – Entertaining Kids On The Road" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/toddler-travel-tips-entertaining-kids-on-the-road/">keeping your kids entertained while travelling.</a> You could even have Grandma scrapbook them as a memento from your child&#8217;s travels.</p>
<h2>Visits</h2>
<p>Convince your parents, brothers or sisters to meet up with you somewhere on the road. Not only will it give them time to bond with your children but it will allow you a little parental reprieve. Just think, you might be able to have a date night! My Mum came to <a href="http://www.goingtovegas.com" target="_blank">Las Vegas</a> with us for ten days on one of our extended trips and it worked brilliantly.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>What methods do you use for keeping kids connected while travelling?</strong></p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/keeping-kids-connected-while-travelling/">Keeping Kids Connected While Travelling</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/keeping-kids-connected-while-travelling/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ten Tips to Avoid Drugging Your Child on a Flight</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/ten-tips-to-avoid-drugging-your-child-on-a-flight/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/ten-tips-to-avoid-drugging-your-child-on-a-flight/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 22:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Toddler Travel Tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3456</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s an article on the Daily Mail website which is making waves across the internet. In it the author, a mother, advocates using anti-histamines like Phengran &#38; Benadryl to drug kids for flights for their own benefit and for the benefit of the passengers around them. I wholeheartedly disagree that the only way for a [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/ten-tips-to-avoid-drugging-your-child-on-a-flight/">Ten Tips to Avoid Drugging Your Child on a Flight</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s an article on the Daily Mail website which is making waves across the internet. In it the author, a mother, advocates using anti-histamines like Phengran &amp; Benadryl to drug kids for flights for their own benefit and for the benefit of the passengers around them.</p>
<p>I wholeheartedly disagree that the only way for a small child to fly quietly and comfortably is to drug them. Our son Reuben had been on over twenty flights before he was two. I&#8217;ve never felt that drugging him was the only method for him and passengers around him to fly happily. I know flying with young children isn&#8217;t easy (three hours sleep on an overnight to Singapore, anyone?) but drugging little children isn&#8217;t the answer.</p>
<h2>Here are ten tips you can use to avoid drugging your child on a flight</h2>
<p><strong>1. Get your child&#8217;s ears checked by a doctor before you fly.</strong> Ear pain, due to cabin pressure change, is the biggest cause for distress amongst children when flying as they are unable to pop their own ears. Any sign of ear infection can heighten the pain. If your child does show signs of an ear infection, don&#8217;t fly. Your travel insurance will cover you to make flight changes due to illness.</p>
<p><strong>2. Talk to children,even if they&#8217;re little. </strong>Mentally prepare them for a flight. Let them know how long it&#8217;s going to be, what&#8217;s expected of them, how much fun they&#8217;ll have and why they&#8217;re flying. Children cope much better when they know what to expect.</p>
<p><strong>3. Physically prepare your children.</strong> Let them burn off as much energy as possible preflight. The best way to do this is to move through the airport as quickly as possible and settle at your departure gate. Let them run and play as much as possible at the departure gate, right up until getting on the flight.</p>
<p><strong>4. Choose your flights carefully.</strong> Time short haul flights to coincide with nap times if your kids still have them. If they&#8217;re no longer napping pick a flight at meal time so there&#8217;s a focus to the flight. Pick long haul flights that fly overnight. Break up long flights. If you have the choice, don&#8217;t do extreme long haul flights all in one go. Auckland to London is an extremely hard flight even for an adult. It must seem like an eternity to a toddler. Build in a stop over that allows your family to sleep in a real bed, eat decent meals, get fresh air and burn off some energy.</p>
<p><strong>5. Keep up your normal routines as best you can.</strong> When you&#8217;re taking a night flight, follow your usual bedtime routine. Put on their pajamas, brush their teeth and read them their bedtime stories.</p>
<p><strong>6. Ask check in staff and cabin staff to give you a few extra seats if the plane isn&#8217;t full.</strong> It&#8217;s better for you and better for other passengers. It&#8217;s a lot easier to entertain a small child with a bit of extra space. Other passengers don&#8217;t want to sit next to excited or upset children.</p>
<p><strong>7. Bring comfort items and activities. </strong>Your child&#8217;s blanky, binky or cuddly toy is the best antidote to distress from flying. Lavender oil is relaxing. Put a few spots on their blanket or clothes (but don&#8217;t go overboard as the flowery smell could irritate other passengers). Pack whatever games and toys you&#8217;ll need to entertain them on board. Small cars, dolls, colouring books, stories. You don&#8217;t need a massive amount of gear as the flight itself is pretty entertaining and exciting.</p>
<p><strong>8. Avoid sugary foods like the plague.</strong> The excitement factor in kids is way up and sugary foods &amp; drinks will only heighten your child&#8217;s energy levels. Keep meals as healthy as you can. Don&#8217;t rely on airplane meals &#8211; bring your own snacks.</p>
<p><strong>9. Mentally prepare yourself.</strong> Flying with children isn&#8217;t the same as flying alone. Consider it your job to keep your child happy, quiet and comfortable. Expect to bend to your child&#8217;s every will on a flight. If you have to take 20 trips up and down the aisles on a four hour flight, just do it. Don&#8217;t drink any alcohol.</p>
<p><strong>10. Try your best and don&#8217;t despair.</strong> Sure, you&#8217;ll get judgey looks from grumpy child-free passengers if your kids are screaming but as long as you&#8217;re doing your best to soothe, control and entertain them other passengers <em>will</em> understand.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not the only one who disagrees with drugging children on flights. Keryn from Walking On Travels wrote this post last year on the issue of <a href="http://walkingontravels.com/2012/03/13/who-are-you-really-drugging-on-a-plane/" target="_blank">drugging kids on flights.</a></p>
<p><strong>Do you have any tips of your own to avoid drugging your child on a flight? Leave me a comment below and let me know.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For more information about <a title="Toddler Travel Tips – Flying with Toddlers" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/toddler-travel-tips-flying-with-toddlers/">flying with toddlers</a> check out my posts in the <a href="http://www.flashpackerfamily.com/category/toddler-travel-tips" target="_blank">Toddler Travel Tips</a> section.</p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/ten-tips-to-avoid-drugging-your-child-on-a-flight/">Ten Tips to Avoid Drugging Your Child on a Flight</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/ten-tips-to-avoid-drugging-your-child-on-a-flight/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Build Your Own Cheap RTW Ticket from the US</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-to-build-your-own-cheap-rtw-ticket-from-the-us/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-to-build-your-own-cheap-rtw-ticket-from-the-us/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 12:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3451</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I discovered how easy it is to build a cheap RTW ticket using Skyscanner&#8217;s Everywhere search function. I quickly and easily planned out my own 16 country, five continent RTW adventure for under $3000. Naturally, as I was thinking of myself, I started and finished in New Zealand. Because it was so much fun [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-to-build-your-own-cheap-rtw-ticket-from-the-us/">How to Build Your Own Cheap RTW Ticket from the US</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I discovered how easy it is to build a <a title="How to Build Your Own Cheap RTW Ticket" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-to-build-your-own-cheap-rtw-ticket/">cheap RTW ticket</a> using Skyscanner&#8217;s Everywhere search function. I quickly and easily planned out my own 16 country, five continent RTW adventure for under $3000. Naturally, as I was thinking of myself, I started and finished in New Zealand.</p>
<p>Because it was so much fun (yes, I am that much of a travel nerd!) I thought I&#8217;d plan one out for my North America friends to show just how simple and effective the Skyscanner tool is to use. Getting to and from New Zealand is a costly exercise so I predict that a independently built RTW ticket from North America will be even cheaper.</p>
<p>Here are the rules in case you missed them yesterday:</p>
<p>I’ll travel around the world by picking the cheapest destination that the “Everywhere” option provides as my next stop provided I’m:</p>
<ul>
<li>Not backtracking to any previous country, region or continent except on connecting flights</li>
<li>Always moving East</li>
<li>Stopping no more than three times on one region or continent</li>
</ul>
<p>As it&#8217;s a central point and major hub I&#8217;m going to start the route in Chicago.</p>
<p><strong>Beginning in North America</strong></p>
<p>Chicago to Toronto, Canada on Porter Airlines $136</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $136</p>
<p><strong>Hop Across to Europe</strong></p>
<p>Toronto to Reykjavik, Iceland on Iceland Air $445</p>
<p>Reykjavik to Cologne, Germany on German Wings $92</p>
<p>Cologne to Katowice, Poland on Wizz Air $32</p>
<p>It was hard to find flights from Katowice outside of Europe so I searched from all of Poland instead.</p>
<p>Warsaw to St Petersburg, Russia via Riga Latvia on Air Baltic $152</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $721</p>
<p><strong>Exploring the Middle East</strong></p>
<p>St Petersburg to Yerevan, Armenia on Aeroflot $199</p>
<p>Yerevan to Riyadh, Saudi Arabia (via Dubai) on Fly Dubai $295</p>
<p>Riyadh to Karachi, Pakistan (via Doha) on Qatar Airways $150</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $644</p>
<p><strong>Into Asia</strong></p>
<p>Karachi to Bangkok, Thailand on Thai Airways $285</p>
<p><em>Incidentally, if you wanted to fly from St Petersburg to Bangkok you could do so for under $600 saving $300 but skipping over the Middle East. </em></p>
<p>Bangkok to Phnom Penh, Cambodia on Air Asia $47</p>
<p>Phonm Penh to Guangzhou, China (via Singapore) on Tiger Aiways $140</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $472</p>
<p><strong>Homeward Bound</strong></p>
<p>Guangzhou to Chicago on Hainan Airlines (via Beijing &amp; Seattle) $694</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $694</p>
<p><strong>That&#8217;s 3 continents, 12 countries and only $2667. Not too shabby. What do you think?</strong></p>
<p>On a traditional RTW ticket you wouldn&#8217;t visit countries such as Iceland, Armenia, Pakistan and Saudi Arabia. Personally I think this is more interesting than a standard RTW ticket because I&#8217;ve been to many of the typical destinations. But for a first time traveller, Riyadh and Yerevan aren&#8217;t exactly high on the list.</p>
<p>A typical RTW ticket would go something like this Los Angeles &#8211; New York &#8211; London &#8211; Paris &#8211; Rome &#8211; Bangkok &#8211; Singapore &#8211; Sydney &#8211; Auckland &#8211; Los Angeles. Let&#8217;s see how this stacks up to my more creative method of RTW planning.</p>
<p><strong>Starting in North America</strong></p>
<p>Los Angeles to New York on United for $141</p>
<p>New York to London on Iceland Air (via Reykjavik) for $530</p>
<p><strong>Taking in the Best of Europe</strong></p>
<p>London to Paris on Easy Jet for $43</p>
<p>Paris to Rome on Ryan Air for $33</p>
<p><strong>Getting a Taste of Asia</strong></p>
<p>Rome to Bangkok on Sri Lankan Airlines for $444</p>
<p>Bangkok to Singapore on Air Asia for $66</p>
<p><strong>Going Down Under</strong></p>
<p>Singapore to Sydney on Air Asia (via Kuala Lumpur) for $247</p>
<p>Sydney to Auckland on Jet Star for $123</p>
<p><strong>And Heading Home</strong></p>
<p>Auckland to Los Angeles on Air Pacific (via Nadi, Fiji) for $804</p>
<p><strong>That&#8217;s 4 continents and 8 countries. The grand total for this bog standard cheap RTW ticket is $2431. </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Which of my cheap RTW tickets would you prefer?</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Cover image used with permission © Friendlydragon | <a href="http://www.dreamstime.com/">Dreamstime Stock Photos</a>&amp; <a href="http://www.stockfreeimages.com/">Stock Free Images</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-to-build-your-own-cheap-rtw-ticket-from-the-us/">How to Build Your Own Cheap RTW Ticket from the US</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-to-build-your-own-cheap-rtw-ticket-from-the-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Build Your Own Cheap RTW Ticket</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-to-build-your-own-cheap-rtw-ticket/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-to-build-your-own-cheap-rtw-ticket/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 10:19:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel Planning]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3425</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been professing my love for Skyscanner all over my Facebook page these week. Skyscanner conveniently allows you to select &#8220;Everywhere&#8221; as an option when searching for flights. This makes it super easy to select the cheapest destination from your point of origin or the cheapest origin to your desired destination. This makes it really [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-to-build-your-own-cheap-rtw-ticket/">How to Build Your Own Cheap RTW Ticket</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been professing my love for <a href="http://www.skyscanner.com" target="_blank">Skyscanner</a> all over <a href="http://www.facebook.com/flashpackerfamily" target="_blank">my Facebook page</a> these week. Skyscanner conveniently allows you to select &#8220;Everywhere&#8221; as an option when searching for flights. This makes it super easy to select the cheapest destination from your point of origin or the cheapest origin to your desired destination. This makes it really easy to pick somewhere to travel when budget is your biggest constraint.</p>
<p>I thought I&#8217;d put Skyscanner&#8217;s &#8220;Everywhere&#8221; function to the test to create my own, cheap RTW ticket.</p>
<p>Starting in New Zealand, I&#8217;ll travel around the world by picking the cheapest destination that the &#8220;Everywhere&#8221; option provides as my next stop provided I&#8217;m:</p>
<ul>
<li>Not backtracking to any previous country, region or continent except on connecting flights</li>
<li>Always moving West</li>
<li>Stopping no more than three times on one region or continent</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Starting in the South Pacific</strong></p>
<p>Auckland &#8211; Sydney, Australia on Air New Zealand $106</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $106</p>
<p><strong>Next Up, Asia</strong></p>
<p>Sydney &#8211; Jakarta, Indonesia via Kuala Lumpur on Air Asia $290</p>
<p>Jakarta &#8211; Singapore on Air Asia $35</p>
<p>Singapore &#8211; Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia $36 on Tiger Airways</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $361</p>
<p><strong>Moving On to the Indian Sub-Continent</strong></p>
<p>Kuala Lumpur &#8211; Kolkata, India $55 on Air Asia</p>
<p>International flights out of Kolkata were very pricey so I switched and searched India to Everywhere assuming that you&#8217;d want to spend a little time exploring India overland.</p>
<p>Delhi to Kathmandu, Nepal on IndiGo $92</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $147</p>
<p><strong>Hitting the Middle East</strong></p>
<p>Kathmandu to Dubai, United Arab Emirates via Delhi on Air India $208</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $208</p>
<p><strong>Dipping into Africa</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong><span style="font-size: 13px;">Now how&#8217;s this for something a little unexpected</span><span style="font-size: 13px;">! Not your usual RTW routing but interesting nonetheless. </span></p>
<p>Dubai to Khartoum, Sudan on FlyDubai $126</p>
<p>Khartoum to Alexandria on Samara Airlines $169</p>
<p>International flights going West out of Alexandria where few and far between so I switched to Cairo assuming that I&#8217;d want to poke around Egypt for a bit.</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $295</p>
<p><strong>Off To Europe</strong></p>
<p>Cairo to Istanbul on Turkish Airlines for $218</p>
<p>Istanbul to Ercan, Cyprus on Onur Air for $69</p>
<p>Flights of Ercan where expensive so I went for flights from Paphos only two hours drive across the island nation.</p>
<p>Paphos to Thessaloniki, Greece on Ryan Air for $54</p>
<p>Thessaloniki to Rome, Italy on Ryan Air for $33</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $374</p>
<p><strong>Beeline for North America</strong></p>
<p>Rome to Las Vegas on Condor $631</p>
<p>Las Vegas to Vancouver on Air Canada $152</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $783</p>
<p><strong>Back Home</strong></p>
<p>Vancouver to Auckland on Air New Zealand $713</p>
<p>Leg total &#8211; $713</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>That&#8217;s five continents, 16 countries and a g<span style="font-size: 13px;">rand total of only $2989 &#8211; less than a package RTW ticket from one of the major airline alliance and with great flexibility.</span></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>What do you think of my cheap RTW ticket?</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Cover image used with permission © Bobby.mn | <a href="http://www.dreamstime.com/">Dreamstime Stock Photos</a> &amp; <a href="http://www.stockfreeimages.com/">Stock Free Images</a></p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-to-build-your-own-cheap-rtw-ticket/">How to Build Your Own Cheap RTW Ticket</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/how-to-build-your-own-cheap-rtw-ticket/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Does Paris Smell Like Pee?</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/why-does-paris-smell-like-pee/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/why-does-paris-smell-like-pee/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 09:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3380</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m constantly intrigued at the random things people Google and subsequently reach my site. Seriously, there are some weird people out there and some even weirder questions. I&#8217;m not entirely sure the average internet user knows that Google passes on the information on what you have searched to the website owner (via Google Analytics). The [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/why-does-paris-smell-like-pee/">Why Does Paris Smell Like Pee?</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m constantly intrigued at the random things people Google and subsequently reach my site. Seriously, there are some weird people out there and some even weirder questions. I&#8217;m not entirely sure the average internet user knows that Google passes on the information on what you have searched to the website owner (via Google Analytics). The internet is essentially a pretty anonymous place and Google appears as a safe place to ask all sorts of wacky questions you can&#8217;t ask your friends.</p>
<p>Sometimes I wish I could talk to these strangers stumbling around the internet who somehow, through a random search term, arrive at this site. So, I&#8217;ve decided the best way to communicate with the random readers who arrive here via Google is simply to answer their questions directly.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">The burning question on everyone&#8217;s mind seems to be&#8230; </span></p>
<h2>Why does Paris smell like pee?</h2>
<p>Really? Apparently this is <em>the</em> question my dear readers would like to know the answer to.</p>
<p><strong>Paris does, in fact, smell like pee. Every alleyway. Every Metro station walkway.</strong> You&#8217;re about to sneak a kiss in a quiet corner of a Parisian street but, uh oh, there&#8217;s that smell. Again and again. Wherever you go on Paris&#8217;s streets the smell of pee will follow you.</p>
<p>The origins of pee&#8230; animal, human? I&#8217;m not sure. Human&#8230; I think. The poo all over the sidewalk is definitely of animal origin. The French are fond of their little dogs, non? I guess if they&#8217;re pooping all over the show they&#8217;re probably peeing just as much (if not more) on lampposts and pretty Parisian trees.</p>
<p>Is there a lack of public toilets in Paris? Well, actually yes. You&#8217;ve probably heard the advice dished out to many a tourist&#8230; if you the urge to purge your bladder strikes while taking in the sights in Europe, find a McDonalds and use their facilities. Public toilets aren&#8217;t as ubiquitous on the streets of Europe as they are in the US, Australia, New Zealand or Great Britain. Does that mean local (men) just go whenever, wherever they need to?</p>
<p>Many Metro stations are open all hours so it&#8217;s a favourite spot for homeless people to spend cold nights. They&#8217;re not going to go outside and seek out a public toilet in the middle of the night now, are they?</p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 13px;">Little dogs + lack of public toilets +homeless folk sleeping in the Metro station = aroma d&#8217;urine</span></strong></p>
<p>Just deal with it. Pull your scarf over your nose and power through any particularly pongy Metro stations or alleys. Paris is a city to be enjoyed whatever the cost.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/why-does-paris-smell-like-pee/">Why Does Paris Smell Like Pee?</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/why-does-paris-smell-like-pee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unique New Zealand: Aoraki Mount Cook by Helicopter</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/unique-new-zealand-aoraki-mount-cook-by-helicopter/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/unique-new-zealand-aoraki-mount-cook-by-helicopter/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 21:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3368</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I love hearing personal stories from travellers who have enjoyed New Zealand. As a local, sometimes I just can&#8217;t appreciate the natural beauty of New Zealand until I see it from an outsider&#8217;s perspective. In this guest post, Linda from Eco Traveller Guide shares a little slice of unique New Zealand. &#160; &#160; It wasn’t [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/unique-new-zealand-aoraki-mount-cook-by-helicopter/">Unique New Zealand: Aoraki Mount Cook by Helicopter</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love hearing personal stories from travellers who have enjoyed New Zealand. As a local, sometimes I just can&#8217;t appreciate the natural beauty of New Zealand until I see it from an outsider&#8217;s perspective. In this guest post, Linda from Eco Traveller Guide shares a little slice of unique New Zealand.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">It wasn’t the way I’d imagined seeing a glacier for the first time, but flying side-on, zig-zagging down its path meant the moment was sure to be etched on my memory forever more.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_6376" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://www.ecotravellerguide.com/?attachment_id=6376" rel="attachment wp-att-6376"><img class="size-full wp-image-6376" src="http://www.ecotravellerguide.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/2.-View-of-the-summit-of-Mount-Cook-from-the-helicopter.jpg" alt="The magnificent cloud-covered summit of Mt Cook, New Zealand." width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The magnificent cloud-covered summit of Mt Cook, New Zealand.</p></div>
<p>I was on the return flight from a trip to the summit of Mount Cook – the highest peak in New Zealand – and was wearing a cheek-aching grin from sheer exhilaration. This is one experience you do not want to miss when you visit the country’s South Island.<br />
Known also by its Maori name of Aoraki, Mt Cook is 3,750 metres high and was established as a national park in 1953. It is also now a UNESCO World Heritage Site. There are three summits in all, imaginatively named Low Peak, Middle Peak and High Peak, with the Tasman Glacier and Hooker Glacier running off from the main peak.</p>
<p>We had waited three days to get a good weather report before the helicopter could visit the summit safely. On the evening before, we had already decided to head on to our next destination if the bad weather didn’t lift, so when we peeked out the curtains that morning to see blue skies… and a cloud-covered summit poking its head up over the mountains for the first time, we knew it was going to happen.</p>
<div id="attachment_6375" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://www.ecotravellerguide.com/?attachment_id=6375" rel="attachment wp-att-6375"><img class="size-full wp-image-6375" src="http://www.ecotravellerguide.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/1.-Pointing-towards-Mt-Cook.jpg" alt="Finally seeing the summit of Mt Cook after a three day wait." width="600" height="453" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Finally seeing the summit of Mt Cook after a three day wait.</p></div>
<p>Today was the day!</p>
<p>Once we boarded the helicopter and donned the headphones, flashbacks of early Saturday morning shows of Airwolf filled my head… as did the theme tune. Another little pang of excitement helped spread a smile across my face as the blades started to rotate, quickly gaining momentum until they emitted the familiar ‘wucca wucca’ sound. And we were off.<br />
The deep blue of the sky belied the miserable grey that had hung around for days previously. It was perfect picture taking light, so I pulled out the camera and started clicking away. It was the first digital camera I ever owned; a little black box that threw out the odd crazy, LSD inspired wavy images all on its own, but mostly produced some pretty spectacular shots, I think, considering it had all of 16 MB capacity.</p>
<div id="attachment_6379" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://www.ecotravellerguide.com/?attachment_id=6379" rel="attachment wp-att-6379"><img class="size-full wp-image-6379" src="http://www.ecotravellerguide.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/5.-Descending-over-the-glacier.jpg" alt="Descending over the glacier, with the view across the surrounding South Island." width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Views view across the surrounding South Island.</p></div>
<p>Flying towards Mount Cook, the mountains shrunk back, the clouds became thinner and the most wonderful panoramic scenes of a rugged, jagged landscape of the South Island extended to the horizon all around. I realised after not too long that I was having the usual struggle of wanting to take photographs and being in the moment. I forced myself to put down the camera and, quite literally, enjoy the ride.</p>
<p>Once I’d stopped snapping and dragged my eyes to the front, the vast snowscape of the mountain unfolded before us. Clouds formed and dissipated above the top of the summit, constantly changing, evolving.</p>
<p>Across the white, marshmallow-like landscape, a black speck hovered.</p>
<p>Wondering what it could be up here, I kept an eye on it. Slowly, the speck grew and came into focus. It took me a while to realise it was another helicopter heading our way. It wasn’t until now that I appreciated just how big this area just below the summit was, and that we were not ‘just below the summit’ at all. The snow skewed distance. We were still hundreds of kilometres from the grand peak.</p>
<div id="attachment_6378" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://www.ecotravellerguide.com/?attachment_id=6378" rel="attachment wp-att-6378"><img class="size-full wp-image-6378" src="http://www.ecotravellerguide.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/4.-Our-ride-for-the-helicopter-trip-over-the-glacier-and-Mt-Cook.jpg" alt="Our ride for the trip, with High Peak in the background to the left." width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Our ride for the trip, with High Peak in the background to the left.</p></div>
<p>Here, the helicopter landed, and when we stepped out onto the snow, ours were the only footsteps. No one had been here before us; well, not since the last snowfall, anyway. Like skittish kids, my boyfriend and I made fresh marks, looking back to see our tracks after each step. It was impossible to not lie down and make snow angels. He was itching to have a good ski around; I was just completely in awe of my surroundings.</p>
<p>It would have been wonderful to hang around for longer, immerse myself in the natural beauty of this amazing place, but alas we had to leave.</p>
<div id="attachment_6377" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://www.ecotravellerguide.com/?attachment_id=6377" rel="attachment wp-att-6377"><img class="size-full wp-image-6377" src="http://www.ecotravellerguide.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/3.-Standing-at-the-near-the-sumit-of-Mt-Cook.jpg" alt="Standing near the summit of Mount Cook. The area is so much bigger than it looks. " width="600" height="393" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Standing near the summit of Mount Cook. The area is so much bigger than it looks.</p></div>
<p>Then, as if he knew we’d be suffering from immediate withdrawals, the helicopter pilot flew twice around Aoraki summit before flying low over the glacier, and back to Mount Cook Village below.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Linda-McCormick-ITWA.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-3373" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="Linda McCormick ITWA" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Linda-McCormick-ITWA.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a>Linda McCormick is the founder and editor of <a href="http://www.ecotravellerguide.com">Eco Traveller Guide</a>. Since her first backpacking trip at the age of 13, she’s been devising ways of dodging a regular 9 to 5 job to be able to spend more time travelling. Eco Traveller is part of the ‘big plan’, and is where she shares her passion for ecotourism and responsible travel. She also has a secret life as personal finance writer from time-to-time, but don’t hold it against her! You can connect with Linda on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/EcoTraveller">@EcoTraveller</a> or via <a href="https://www.facebook.com/EcoTravellerGuide">Eco Traveller’s Facebook page</a>.</p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/unique-new-zealand-aoraki-mount-cook-by-helicopter/">Unique New Zealand: Aoraki Mount Cook by Helicopter</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/unique-new-zealand-aoraki-mount-cook-by-helicopter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ten Tips for Tackling Jet Lag in Children</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/ten-tips-for-tackling-jet-lag-in-children/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/ten-tips-for-tackling-jet-lag-in-children/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Toddler Travel Tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3347</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;ve all felt it after a long flight across time zones, jet lag hurts and can take days to shake. Jet lag is more than just being tired after a flight. It affects your whole body. Aside from sleepiness, some of the symptoms of jet lag can be include an upset tummy, fuzzy-headedness, inability to [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/ten-tips-for-tackling-jet-lag-in-children/">Ten Tips for Tackling Jet Lag in Children</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;ve all felt it after a long flight across time zones, jet lag hurts and can take days to shake. Jet lag is more than just being tired after a flight. It affects your whole body. Aside from sleepiness, some of the symptoms of jet lag can be include an upset tummy, fuzzy-headedness, inability to concentration, weakness and changes to urination and bowel movements. Jet lag definitely effects children and can be difficult to manage, especially in young children who can&#8217;t tell you precisely what&#8217;s wrong.</p>
<h2>Here are ten tips for tackling jet lag in children:</h2>
<p>1. Find flights that travel overnight for minimal sleep disruption. It makes the concept of a time change easier to manage if you&#8217;re getting on a plane, going to sleep and then waking up somewhere different at a different time. The physical act of being on a plane can be exhausting, not just the jet lag so a night flight is your best bet on waking up refreshed when you reach your destination.</p>
<p>2. Set your watch to local time as soon as your arrive&#8230; or even better, while you&#8217;re on board the plane.</p>
<p>3. Set your daily routine to local time. Try and eat meals at set times each days in congruence with when locals eat meals. If your eating schedule is off it can be difficult to find restaurants or cafes that are open.</p>
<p>4. Fresh air and sunshine are the best combatants to jet lag&#8230; not sleep! The sun helps regulate the body clock so when you reach your destination, spend some time outdoors in a garden or park.</p>
<p>5. Allow a nap but keep it short. Don&#8217;t let your little ones oversleep during the day. It&#8217;ll only take them longer to adjust especially if they&#8217;re sleeping late in the afternoon or into the evening.</p>
<p>6.Try not to go to bed too early when you arrive at your destination. If you&#8217;re travelling East to West, the temptation could be to hit the sack at 5pm but this will only throw you off for the next day.</p>
<p>7. Trying to keep sleepy, grumpy children awake a few extra hours until bedtime can be difficult. This can make dinner time a nightmare. Pick a hotel with a pool and restaurant so you don&#8217;t have to do anything for the first few days other than focus on getting over the jet lag.</p>
<p>8. If you do find yourself awake in the middle of the night, don&#8217;t fight it too hard. Get up for an hour or so. Watch a DVD, read some stories and then explain that you need to get back to bed and try and sleep until morning.</p>
<p>9. Be prepared for late nights and/or early starts. Have some games or DVDs and snacks available. There&#8217;s nothing worse than being stuck in a hotel room from 4am with no breakfast and nothing to do!</p>
<p>10. Don&#8217;t confuse jet lag with <a title="Toddler Travel Tips: Dealing with Culture Shock in Toddlers" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/toddler-travel-tips-dealing-with-culture-shock-in-toddlers/">culture shock</a>. The symptoms can be similar but if your child still hasn&#8217;t settled after a week, culture shock could be affecting them not jet lag.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>How do you cope with jet lag? What strategies do you have to help your little ones get over jet lag?</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/ten-tips-for-tackling-jet-lag-in-children/">Ten Tips for Tackling Jet Lag in Children</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/ten-tips-for-tackling-jet-lag-in-children/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Changing Gears, Conquering Your Fears and Taking on the Impossible</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/changing-gears-conquering-your-fears-and-taking-on-the-impossible/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/changing-gears-conquering-your-fears-and-taking-on-the-impossible/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 22:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3337</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Nancy Sathre-Vogel is an inspiration. She&#8217;s one of the few people in this world who knows what conquering your fears and living your dreams is all about. Nancy is one of the first women I encountered in the blogosphere and has been a continual source of motivation and a shoulder to cry on when things [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/changing-gears-conquering-your-fears-and-taking-on-the-impossible/">Changing Gears, Conquering Your Fears and Taking on the Impossible</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://familyonbikes.org/blog/about-2/author-profile/" target="_blank">Nancy Sathre-Vogel is an inspiration</a>. She&#8217;s one of the few people in this world who knows what conquering your fears and living your dreams is all about. Nancy is one of the first women I encountered in the blogosphere and has been a continual source of motivation and a shoulder to cry on when things go wrong. She&#8217;s powerful, strong and a brilliant writer. Last year while backpacking around Asia I read a copy of her book &#8220;Twenty Miles Per Cookie: 9000 Miles of Kid-Powered Adventures&#8221; &#8211; an entertaining tale of the family&#8217;s bike tour around North America. But&#8230; this is not what Nancy is known for.</p>
<p>Nancy has just published a new book on their three year journey from the top of Alaska to the tip of Argentina. <em><strong>Changing Gears: A Family Odyssey to the End of the World</strong> </em>chronicles the Vogel family&#8217;s incredible 17,000 mile voyage overland through no less than 15 countries. Sounds like an impossible feat, no? Consider that the Vogels undertook this with their twin boys, 10 years old at the start of the journey. Sounds even more impossible? Get this &#8211; the Vogel family undertook this mean feat not by plane, car or public transport but&#8230; <strong>by bicycle.</strong> Yes really. Eight legs, four people, three bikes and 17,000 miles of open road. You get now why I consider Nancy a great inspiration.</p>
<p><em><strong>Changing Gears</strong></em> is the story of their journey but it&#8217;s also a glimpse into the mind of a Mom who wants to instill a sense of adventure, self confidence and gratitude into her children. Nancy&#8217;s family stripped back their lives to the bare minimum &#8211; literally what they could carry on their bikes. Enough food for the moment, a roof over their heads (albeit temporary), a world to travel in. Nancy&#8217;s story is one of an epic odysessy sure but it&#8217;s deeper than that. Read the book, visit her site, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=mMasmrJOmEo" target="_blank">watch her TedX talk</a> and you will find out what I mean.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re an armchair traveler who enjoys unbelievable tales from the road &#8211; this is the book for you. If you&#8217;re looking for a little encouragement to move beyond your comfort zone &#8211; this is the book for you. If your family is stuck in a rut, looking for a change and wanting to break out of the ordinary &#8211; this is the book for you, your husband and your kids. </p>
<p><a href="http://familyonbikes.org/blog/2013/03/changing-gears-is-finally-released-order-your-copy-today/" target="_blank">Order the book</a>. Get inspired. Conquer your fears. Take on the impossible.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="text-align: justify;">In celebration of the release of <strong><em>Changing Gears</em></strong>, Nancy, with the help of a few of her favorite sponsors, is holding a giveaway of the following prizes:</div>
<div>
<ul>
<li>North St bags – <a href="http://northstbags.com/collections/convertibles/products/route-seven-pannier" target="_blank">Grocery Pannier</a></li>
<li>Subscription to <a href="http://www.womensadventuremagazine.com/" target="_blank">Women’s Adventure</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Man-Cycled-Americas-ebook/dp/B0052Z3HKI/ref=tmm_kin_title_0" target="_blank">The Man Who Cycled the Americas</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bekindtocyclists.org/store.html" target="_blank">Be Kind to Cyclists</a>- T-Shirts</li>
<li><a href="http://www.kryptonitelock.com" target="_blank">Kryptonite lock</a></li>
<li><a href="http://sihpromatum.com/savannah_bookorders.html" target="_blank">Sihpromatum</a></li>
<li><a href="http://shop.ibex.com/Apparel/Womens-Long-Sleeve" target="_blank">ibex</a> – 2 wool jerseys</li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Bottles-Backpacks-Gypsy-Travel-ebook/dp/B0071CGOO6" target="_blank">Bottles to Backpacks: The Gypsy Mama’s Guide to REAL Travel With Kids</a> – ebook</li>
<li><a href="http://www.lightandmotion.com/bike/" target="_blank">Light &amp; Motion </a>- bike light</li>
<li><a href="http://www.novica.com/" target="_blank">Novica</a> $100 Gift Certificate</li>
<li><a href="http://www.carrentals.co.uk/" target="_blank">Car Rental </a></li>
</ul>
<h6><em><a href="http://drivemecrazyfamilyadventure.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/CarHire.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-939 aligncenter" src="http://drivemecrazyfamilyadventure.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/CarHire.png" alt="CarHire" width="550" height="80" /></a></em><em><br />
</em></h6>
</div>
<div><em style="text-align: justify; font-size: 13px;">Disclosure: Flashpacker Family is not responsible for sponsor prize shipment. This event was organized by Victoria at <a title="Drive Me Crazy Family Adventure" href="http://drivemecrazyfamilyadventure.com" target="_blank">Drive Me Crazy Family Adventure</a> on behalf of the author, Nancy Vogel, <a title="Changing Gears" href="http://familyonbikes.org" target="_blank">Family on Bikes</a>. This giveaway is open to U.S. Residents and will end at 11:59 pm on March 27th. Three winners will be chosen. Each winner will receive a subscription to <em>Women&#8217;s Adventure Magazine</em> and their own copy of <em>Changing Gears</em>.  Remaining prizes will be divided among the finalists.</em></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;"></div>
<div style="text-align: justify;"></div>
<p><a id="rc-f4d37249" class="rafl" href="http://www.rafflecopter.com/rafl/display/f4d37249/" rel="nofollow">a Rafflecopter giveaway</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Featured image used with permission by FamilyonBikes.org.</em><script type="text/javascript" src="//d12vno17mo87cx.cloudfront.net/embed/rafl/cptr.js"></script></p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/changing-gears-conquering-your-fears-and-taking-on-the-impossible/">Changing Gears, Conquering Your Fears and Taking on the Impossible</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/changing-gears-conquering-your-fears-and-taking-on-the-impossible/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Best Places to Ski in New Zealand</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-places-to-ski-in-new-zealand/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-places-to-ski-in-new-zealand/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 01:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3171</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m no expert when it comes to skiing or snowboarding &#8211; in fact I&#8217;ve only been on the slopes twice in my life. There are plenty of great places to ski in New Zealand so I asked Mike from Nomads on the Road to share them with me. He&#8217;s the go-to guy when it comes [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-places-to-ski-in-new-zealand/">The Best Places to Ski in New Zealand</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m no expert when it comes to skiing or snowboarding &#8211; in fact I&#8217;ve only been on the slopes twice in my life. There are plenty of great places to ski in New Zealand so I asked <strong>Mike from Nomads on the Road</strong> to share them with me. He&#8217;s the go-to guy when it comes to anything snow related so listen up and learn!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Finding great places to ski in New Zealand is not as daunting as you may think. You just need to be realistic about the terrain and quality of snow. As someone who has lived, worked and skied in the French Alps, Colorado, Canada as well as New Zealand, I can tell you New Zealand is right up there for fun on the slopes. New Zealand’s ski scene is predominately based in the South Island; there are a splattering of ski hills and club fields in the North Island which is where we will start our round-up of places to ski in New Zealand.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>The North Island</h2>
<div id="attachment_3195" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Mount-Ruapehu-Photo-Credit-Cusegoyle-e1362975364961.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3195" title="Mount Ruapehu - Photo Credit - Cusegoyle" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Mount-Ruapehu-Photo-Credit-Cusegoyle-e1362975364961.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mount Ruapehu<br />Source: Cusegoyle on Flickr</p></div>
<p>Starting in the North Island and the obvious and logical mountain to focus on is the volcanic Mount Ruapehu. <strong>Mount Ruapehu</strong> is not only a very active volcano, but it also holds the distinction of being the largest ski area in New Zealand. Home to two commercial ski fields, <strong>Whakapapa</strong> (the largest ski area in New Zealand) to the north and <strong>Turoa</strong> on the southern slope, Mount Ruapehu is also home to a little club field to the east, <strong>Tukino</strong>.</p>
<p>Home to New Zealand’s largest beginners’ area, known as Happy Valley, <strong>Whakapapa</strong> is proud of the fact they set it away from the rest of the ski hill. Equipped with its own café, rental shop and ski school meeting area, Happy Valley has a long gentile slope accessed by a slow moving chairlift, perfect for learning. With more than 30 groomed intermediate trails, skiers and boarders are offered a nice variety of trails, bumps, chutes, bowls and wide groomers. For those more advanced skiers and boarders Whakapapa offers 24 black and black diamond runs, as well as lift-accessed back country. The back country area is known as Black Magic and each September plays host to the popular ‘Extreme Competition’.</p>
<p>The beginners’ area at Turoa is known as Alpine Meadow, a superb little learner’s hill. With a huge 120m long carpet, Alpine Meadow offers a mellow introduction to skiing and snowboarding. With the Alpine Chalet right next to the beginners’ area, guests will be able to recoup with coffee, meals, snacks or even a moral boosting beer after a day on the slopes. The intermediate area at Turoa mainly consists of wide and smooth runs; though for the more adventurous there are a few chutes and bowls. With 12 intermediate groomers linking to one another, skiers and boarders can enjoy long and challenging riding all the way from the top of Australasia’s highest lift to the base. Turoa’s advanced area consists of 25 black and black diamond runs and two lift-accessed backcountry areas where riders will find a huge variety of terrain. Natural half-pipes and chutes through the Organ Pipes and Solitude backcountry area along with the sweeping terrain of the Triangle and Glacier backcountry area makes skiing and boarding at Turoa very special in New Zealand.</p>
<div id="attachment_3199" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Tukino-photo-credit-elbroka-e1362975844138.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3199" title="Tukino - photo credit - elbroka" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Tukino-photo-credit-elbroka-e1362975844138.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Tukino<br />Source: elbroka on Flickr</p></div>
<p>Located on the eastern slopes of Mount Ruapehu, Tukinooffers that rare combination on a ski hill, lack of crowds, friendly faces and superb terrain. The slopes at Tukino are sheltered from the westerly winds and the club often operates with clear skies while the rest of the mountain could be covered in cloud. Snow conditions vary but for those who make it up the hill early will rewarded with fine conditions in the mornings with the sun softening up the snow.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>The South Island</h2>
<p>Reeling off the list of resorts on New Zealand’s South Island is an article in its own right. Treble Cone, Cardrona, Snow Park, The Remarkables, Coronet Peak, Oahu, Roundhill, Mount Hutt, and Porters are all top ski hills. That is before we even mention the excellent club fields of Fox Peak, Mount Dobson, Hanmer Springs Ski Area and the four clubs which make their home on the Craigieburn Range – Broken River, Craigeburn Valley, Mount Cheeseman and Mount Olympus.</p>
<p>Starting with the impressive Treble Cone located in Wanaka, the ski hill overlooks the pristine waters of Lake Wanaka, yet there is more to Treble Cone than just great views. Treble Cone offers the largest ski area and the longest vertical in the South Island, long uncrowded groomed slopes and some of the best off-piste terrain in New Zealand. Heading away from Wanaka and into the Crown Range, skiers and boarders will have two options on opposite sides of the valley.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3198" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cardrona.-Photo-Credit-Ca.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3198" title="Cardrona.-Photo-Credit---Ca" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cardrona.-Photo-Credit-Ca.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Cardrona<br />Source: Ca on Flickr</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>On the right heading out from Wanaka is <strong>Cardrona</strong>. With a peak elevation of 1860m, vertical rise of 600m and 345 hectares to play in, Cardrona is a great all-round ski hill. On the opposite side the valley is New Zealand’s only dedicated terrain park. <strong>Snow Park</strong> offers freestyle skiers and snowboarders’ world-class park riding. It’s not often people call skiing and snowboarding in the Southern Hemisphere world-class but in Snow Park they have a world-class terrain park, presenting a range jibs, jumps, rails, boxes and half pipes for shredders.</p>
<p>Moving on to the <strong>Queenstown</strong> ski hills, there are two to choose from, <strong>The Remarkables</strong> and <strong>Coronet Peak</strong>. The Remarkables certainly live up to their name, maybe not quite for the quality and quantity of snow but for the views. One of the most famous and photographed mountain ranges in the world, thanks to the combination of jagged shapes which rises steeply above the shores of Lake Wakatipu. Coronet Peak is the most popular ski hill in South Island, entirely due to its proximity to Queenstown. This ski hill is perfect for beginners and intermediate skiers and snowboarders. So much so that Powderhound magazine has given Coronet Peak a ‘best skiing in New Zealand’ award for their intermediate terrain. With only 280 hectares and 481 metres of vertical, the simple fact is Coronet Peak is small. However 30 per cent of its terrain is classed as black, and with various off-piste runs around the edges of the resort and a few chutes, advanced skiers and riders can have some fun too.</p>
<p><strong>Oahu</strong> is one of New Zealand’s hidden gems, as much we don’t like to refer to places in those terms; it’s true in this case. This little South Island ski hill has the vibe of a local club field yet is a fully commercial enterprise. No crowds mean fresh lines can be found, when the snow is willing to oblige. Located in the Mackenzie District, 3.5 hours from Christchurch, Oahu overlooks the lake of the same name.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3196" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Roundhill-Photo-Credit-olso-council-e1362975547972.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3196" title="Roundhill - Photo Credit olso council" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Roundhill-Photo-Credit-olso-council-e1362975547972.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="399" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Roundhill<br />Source: Olso Council on Flickr</p></div>
<p>Moving north towards Lake Tekapo and you will find the charming small resort<strong> Roundhill</strong>. While it retains the vibe of a chill club field, in 2010 the introduction of a ropetow has opened up an incredible adjoining face, which was once hike-only. The lift now gives Roundhill 780 metres of vertical, the longest of any New Zealand ski hill as well as increasing the skiable terrain from 60 hectares to 500 hectares.</p>
<p><strong>Mount Hutt</strong> is a ski hill which receives an impressive (by New Zealand standards) four metres of snow on average each year. However the 365 hectares is often closed due to Mount Hutt sitting on the edge a mountain range and therefore exposed to cold and strong winds. The ski area and the steep windy access road are at Mother Nature’s mercy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3197" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Porters-Photo-Credit-elrentplats-e1362975629974.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3197" title="Porters - Photo Credit - elrentplats" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Porters-Photo-Credit-elrentplats-e1362975629974.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Porters<br />Source: elrenplats on Flickr</p></div>
<p>The closest ski area to Christchurch is <strong>Porters</strong> and while it is no Vail or Whistler it is a pretty damn fine resort by New Zealand standards. The resort offers a new day lodge, café, shop and ski rental area. But more importantly it offers great views of Lake Coleridge. With plenty of skiable terrain at Porters to appeal to beginners and intermediates, advanced riders may feel left out. Yet the vertical drop is impressive and there is a lot for these riders to enjoy. Easily accessed backcountry bowls means Porters is much bigger than the in-bounds 230 hectares suggests.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>South Island Club Fields</h2>
<p>With a range of commercial ski hills to choose from, many skiers and boarders like to get away from the crowds – not easy on an island where it seems half the southern hemisphere loved to shred. Yet the abundance of well-run club fields in the South Island means for those wishing to escape the crowds and enjoy some great lines, the option is there.</p>
<p><strong>Fox Peak</strong> and <strong>Mount Dobson</strong> are two club fields in the Lake Tekapo area. Dobson has that unique Kiwi relaxed attitude. The 400 hectares of Mount Dobson terrain is contained within a treeless bowl. No crowds mean powder days at Mount Dobson can be epic.</p>
<p><strong>Fox Peak</strong> is a classic club field, run by an old ski club which was established in 1929, and with non-members welcome to visit the hill it still retains that ski bum vibe. With 850 vertical metres and 500 hectares of lift accessed terrain, Fox Peak is a large ski hill by New Zealand standards.</p>
<p>Getting to <strong>Hanmer Springs Ski Area</strong> is half the fun. But those who succeed will be rewarded with thin or non-existent crowds, cheap accommodation, lifts that spin from sun up to sundown, views to cry over and friendly staff. The ski field, formerly known as Amuri, is basically one wide open bowl with no trees – alpine style.</p>
<p>Four clubs which make their home on the Craigieburn Range – <strong>Broken River, Craigeburn Valley, Mount Cheeseman</strong> and <strong>Mount Olympus.</strong> <strong>Broken River </strong>is a no-frills club field which caters to skiers and snowboarders with an adventurous side. <strong>Craigeburn Valley</strong> offers some of New Zealand’s most challenging terrain, offering steep, narrow chutes to wide-open bowls &#8211; no groomers to be found here. <strong>Mount Cheeseman</strong> is a club field which offers only two T-bar lifts, a learners’ tow and 320 metres of vertical. Sitting within an alpine basin the terrain varies from mellow to steep. <strong>Mount Olympus</strong> sounds like something from ancient Greece and the motto of the Mt Olympus ski area is ‘Playground of the Gods’. This club field offers big mountain skiing, slopes which capture powder and of course no crowds. Hike to the best spots and enjoy fresh lines all day.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em><a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Profile-pic.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3305 alignleft" style="border: 2px solid black; margin: 5px;" title="Profile-pic" src="http://flashpackerfamily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Profile-pic.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a></em></p>
<p><em style="font-size: 13px;">Mike is a writer and wannabe mountain man, if he could grow a big bushy beard he would, but he will settle for writing about all things adventure. Currently living in <strong><a href="http://www.nomadsontheroad.com/" target="_blank">Fernie</a></strong>, BC. You can also follow Mike on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/nomadsontheroad">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://www.twitter.com/MikeCjourno">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://plus.google.com/117190067562005577854">Google Plus</a> and <a href="http://pinterest.com/mikecjourno">Pintrest</a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>What’s your favourite place to ski or snowboard in NZ? Let us know in the comments below…</em></strong></p>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-places-to-ski-in-new-zealand/">The Best Places to Ski in New Zealand</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/the-best-places-to-ski-in-new-zealand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dohop vs Skyscanner</title>
		<link>http://flashpackerfamily.com/dohop-vs-skyscanner/</link>
		<comments>http://flashpackerfamily.com/dohop-vs-skyscanner/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 03:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethaney Davies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flashpackerfamily.com/?p=3304</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m always looking for new ways to search for cheap flights. Kate from RTW Travel Guide just posted this great post comparing flight booking sites. She compared Momondo with a newer flight search engine called Dohop and found them to be great at identifying cheap flights. I&#8217;d never heard of Dohop before so I did [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/dohop-vs-skyscanner/">Dohop vs Skyscanner</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m always looking for new ways to search for cheap flights. Kate from RTW Travel Guide just posted this great post <a href="http://rtw-travel-guide.com/momondo-versus-dohop/" target="_blank">comparing flight booking sites</a>. She compared Momondo with a newer flight search engine called <a href="http://www.dohop.com/" target="_blank">Dohop</a> and found them to be great at identifying cheap flights. I&#8217;d never heard of Dohop before so I did a little research for myself and experimented by comparing them to my go-to flight search engine <a href="http://www.skyscanner.co.nz" target="_blank">Skyscanner</a>.</p>
<p>Like Skyscanner, Dohop searches include some budget airlines which I find super helpful. In addition to flights, Dohop also searches hotels and rental cars. Their site is responsive which means you can comfortable view in on different sized laptops, tablets and smart phones. All very big pluses.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m pricing up a few ideas for a European trip at the moment. Specifically, a trip to Ireland for a conference in October followed by a stay in the Emilia Romanga region of Italy. I used the research for this trip as an excuse to experiment with Dohop.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Six days Car Hire around Ireland</h2>
<p>We want to spend a week exploring Ireland before the conference. The best way to get around Ireland is to hire a car so I searched a six day &#8220;Economy&#8221; car hire across the same dates (picking up and dropping off in Dublin) on both search engines.</p>
<p>The results?</p>
<p>Skyscanner and Dohop both returned similar results. The same companies, the same cars but Dohops prices were a couple of Euros less per week in each car class. For a Toyota Yaris rented through Sixt Skyscanner quoted €125.18 and Dohop quoted €122.73. The cost of renting a toddler seat and a GPS were the same with both booking engines. <strong>Even if it&#8217;s only a saving of €2.50, Dohop wins! </strong>Europe is expensive so I&#8217;ll take any small win I can get.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Flights from Dublin to Bologna</h2>
<p>There are no direct flights between Dublin and Bologna and we would need to arrive in Bologna at a reasonable time of day which complicates this leg of the journey somewhat.</p>
<p>The results?</p>
<p>Both Dohop and Skyscanner are again evenly matched on this account. Unless we fancied a 17 hour stopover in Copenhagen, the only reasonbley priced option would be to piece together a connection flight on budget airline RyanAir. Both booking engines presented me this option but Skyscanner hides it initially as it&#8217;a multi part booking. You can&#8217;t book connecting flights straight through on RyanAir, you have to clear customs and collect bags before checking into the next flight. I can understand why Skyscanner would try to deter people from doing this as it is rather messy but for those of us who like to save money on flights it is nice to be presented ALL the options clearly.</p>
<p>Dohop suggested a flight from Dublin to Chaleroi and then onto Bologna for a total price of <strong>€89 and a total journey time of 5 hrs 30. </strong>Skyscanner suggested a route through London Stansted Airport which cost <strong>€91 with a total journey time of 11 hrs 10. </strong><strong>Because of the journey time alone, Dohop wins on this occasion.</strong> I would NOT recommend playing around with DIY connections on RyanAir as they are notorious at providing bad service, late flights or <a href="http://walkingontravels.com/2013/02/05/travel-disaster-ryanair-dumped-my-family-at-the-wrong-airport/" target="_blank">landing the plane at a different airport and not telling you</a> as my friend Keryn from Walking On Travels found out the hard way in Sicily recently.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Flights from Dublin to Milan</h2>
<p>While our ultimate destination is Bologna, Milan is only 200kms away. As it&#8217;s a major hub I also investigated flying into Milan and catching the train to Bologna. There&#8217;s no direct flight between Dublin and Bologna so whether we travel via two planes or a plane then a train makes no difference to me. Lee and Reuben haven&#8217;t been to Milan so it could be a good opportunity to visit.</p>
<p>The results?</p>
<p>Both Dohop and Skyscanner found me the same Aer Lingus flights direct from Dublin to Milan &#8211; one to Malpensa and one to Linante. <strong>Skyscanner quoted €68 and Dohop quoted <strong>€67. </strong></strong>Train tickets from Milan to Bologna go for as little as €10 so the price is definitely right on this option.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>One Night in a Hotel in Milan</h2>
<p>While <a title="Toddler Travel Tips: Vacation Apartment Rentals" href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/toddler-travel-tips-vacation-apartment-rentals/" target="_blank">we prefer vacation rentals</a> overall, if we&#8217;re only in town for a few nights a hotel suits us better. There&#8217;s no cleaning fee or faffing about making arrangements with owners. Sure you lose the benefits of a kitchen and seperate sleeping space for Reuben but you also gain a location advantage and access to hotel amenities and services. I visited Milan back in 2008 and stayed in a great hotel that I&#8217;d like to visit again so I used both search engines to find a price for <a href="www.hotelcristoforocolombo.com" target="_blank">Hotel Cristoforo Colombo</a>.</p>
<p>The results?</p>
<div>Both Dohop and Skyscanner returned identical search results - <strong>€93 a night down from <strong>€143 </strong></strong>which seems like a pretty good rate to me. I&#8217;m surprised at how similar the hotel booking section of both sites are.</div>
<div></div>
<h2>Summary</h2>
<p>While Skyscanner has long been my favourite way to search flights online, Dohop might become a fast favourite. Even thought the savings made in this booking were minor, when you&#8217;re a travelling family purchasing multiple tickets, these little wins all add up. (Unlike Kate at RTW Travel Guide who managed to <a href="http://rtw-travel-guide.com/momondo-versus-dohop/" target="_blank">find a saving of AU$400 using Dohop</a>!)</p>
<p>The design of Dohop&#8217;s homepage is simple, clean and easy to use. I love that on each of the search results you can map the flight out &#8211; super handy if you don&#8217;t know where every single airport in the world is. (I didn&#8217;t know that Charleroi was in Belgium until I looked at Dohop&#8217;s map.) You can also share each flight you find by email right from the booking page which makes coordinating travel with others simple.</p>
<div><strong>In short, I&#8217;m loving Dohop! Give it a go next time you&#8217;re searching for flights, cars or hotels.</strong></div>
<div></div>
<!-- Start Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><!-- End Shareaholic Recommendations Automatic --><p>The post <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com/dohop-vs-skyscanner/">Dohop vs Skyscanner</a> appeared first on <a href="http://flashpackerfamily.com">Family Travel Blog - Flashpacker Family Travel with Kids Around the World</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flashpackerfamily.com/dohop-vs-skyscanner/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced

Served from: flashpackerfamily.com @ 2013-04-17 00:57:11 -->
