<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xml:lang="en-US">
  <id>tag:svbtle.com,2012:/feed</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://svbtle.com" />
  
  <title>Svbtle Featured</title>
  <updated>2013-03-31T11:33:06-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Svbtle.com</name>
    <uri>http://svbtle.com</uri>
    <email>hello@svbtle.com</email>
  </author>
  <generator>Svbtle.com</generator>
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/svbtle" /><feedburner:info uri="svbtle" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>svbtle</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><entry>
    <id>tag:zackshapiro,2012:Post/want-to-learn-to-code-start-here</id>
    <published>2013-03-31T11:33:06-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T11:33:06-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/uLg93HD7WzI/want-to-learn-to-code-start-here" />
    <author>
      <name>Zack Shapiro</name>
      <uri>http://blog.zackshapiro.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Want to learn to code? Start here.</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last September, I wrote a post called &lt;a href="http://zackshapiro.com/post/31672964808/want-to-learn-rails-start-here"&gt;Want to learn Rails? Start here.&lt;/a&gt; which has been pretty successful. I&amp;#39;ve met and emailed a good amount of people who have follow up questions or are in the middle of learning how to build things with software. I&amp;#39;ve referred a bunch of people to the post as well. I&amp;#39;m proud that the post is actionable and helpful. Since I wrote that post a while ago and developed my engineering skills much, much further. I wanted to write a follow-up post, some revised thoughts on learning how to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is intended for working professionals who feels a strong desire to code to build things that they want to see exist in the world. This post is not intended for the person who &lt;em&gt;thinks they should code&lt;/em&gt; because they hear so much about it. I mean no offense but I&amp;#39;ve found those people to be lacking in the short and medium-term fire it takes to learn to actually build software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Nights, weekends are bad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given my personal experiences and a slew of conversations, I&amp;#39;ve found that learning how to code only on nights and weekends is a terrible way to go about it. When your brain is not trained to think the way coding forces you to think, it&amp;#39;s very easy to lose where you were or not remember a key concept you just picked up. Putting in as much time as possible is your friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This point of view is reinforced by programs like &lt;a href="http://devbootcamp.com/"&gt;Dev Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; which not only require a full nine weeks of your life but also make you pay tuition to attend (which is not a small sum). They make you buy in temporally and financially to ensure your success.  &lt;strong&gt;You have to throw yourself in or you will fail.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Forget Codecademy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;#39;m learning how to code! I&amp;#39;m doing Codecademy!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t know how many people tell me this. If I follow up with any of those people six-to-eight weeks later, they&amp;#39;ve fallen off the boat completely. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s why Codecademy doesn&amp;#39;t work in the long term: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;re coding in a browser which you literally never do outside of Codecademy. Learning the syntax of JavaScript, Python, or Ruby is good but that&amp;#39;s about all you get out of the program, in my opinion. You&amp;#39;ll learn these skills elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t know how to set up a development environment. Any time you have the slightest inkling to build something for yourself leveraging what you&amp;#39;ve learned in Codecademy, you can&amp;#39;t and probably don&amp;#39;t know where to start. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ll need to go through the process of setting up your dev environment which can be incredibly challenging for someone with very little coding experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Have a real project you want to build&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have something &lt;em&gt;tiny&lt;/em&gt; you want to build. One of my first projects was called Today I Learned. It&amp;#39;s a text box that you enter stuff into and it shows the date you entered it in descending order. That&amp;#39;s all it does. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your first project is going to be crappy. But it will be done. And it will be done by you. And that&amp;#39;s fucking awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Everything you build, builds on top of the stuff you&amp;#39;ve built before&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built Today I Learned and whatever I built next, was better because of one or two concepts I learned while building TIL. You&amp;#39;ll constantly be referencing your old code, code other places in the codebase or code from the Internet, once you understand what the pieces mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Don&amp;#39;t copy and paste others&amp;#39; code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tommy Nicholas wrote &lt;a href="http://www.shockoe.com/blog/typingcodeout/"&gt;a post&lt;/a&gt; in December which echoes the same point. You learn things when you write code out. You question what certain pieces mean. Hopefully you Google those questions to learn more and understand more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) Stop telling people you&amp;#39;re learning to code unless they&amp;#39;re technical and you want them to help you&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;#39;re starting out, your goal should be to find a technical mentor or two, not impress your other non-coding friends with the fact that you&amp;#39;ve taken the first step. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a firm believer that if you talk about what you want to do, you never actually do it. So unless you&amp;#39;re talking to someone you hope will be a mentor, close your mouth, put your head down, and keep building. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loose lips sink ships&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7) Coding is failing a ton and understanding why. It&amp;#39;s painful and frustrating&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way you learn how to build software is by making the same mistake a few times, learning why that doesn&amp;#39;t work, and doing it correctly. The next time you come across a similar problem (and trust me, you will), you&amp;#39;ll either remember the way you did it last time or at least the part of the codebase that you struggled in, which you will then reference and remember what you learned from all of that failing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rewards for building software are incredible. The feeling of &amp;ldquo;that came out of my brain&amp;rdquo; is what I live for. I love it. But the road to get to that point can be tough. &lt;a href="http://blog.zackshapiro.com/momentum-is-a-hell-of-a-drug"&gt;Build momentum. Keep going.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8) Stop trying to figure out what you should do and just start.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of a friend kept emailing me with a bunch of questions. He was trying to figure out all of the places he could fail before he even started. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s the absolute wrong way to go about this. Pick a language, (Ruby or Python) buy a really recent book that assumes you know nothing and just start. Do chapter one. Do it again maybe. The amount that you don&amp;#39;t know that you don&amp;#39;t know is bigger than you can imagine. Don&amp;#39;t worry about that. You&amp;#39;ll understand more pieces in time. We all will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you have tips for beginners learning how to code, please &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5469623"&gt;share them on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;. Your time and effort may really help someone out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/uLg93HD7WzI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.zackshapiro.com/want-to-learn-to-code-start-here</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ethankap,2012:Post/in-the-cold-light-of-day-our-tools-make-us-all-douchebags</id>
    <published>2013-03-31T09:08:10-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T09:08:10-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/IGIUqc7lb0I/in-the-cold-light-of-day-our-tools-make-us-all-douchebags" />
    <author>
      <name>Ethan Kaplan</name>
      <uri>http://ethankaplan.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>In the cold light of day, our mastery and use of tools make us all douchebags</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ethan Kaplan runs product at Live Nation Labs, including overseeing mobile, engineering, design and operations. He lives deep in the suburbs of Los Angeles with his wife Amy, almost four-year old Eli and two pugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phone&lt;/strong&gt;: Black iPhone 5, 64gb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ringtone&lt;/strong&gt;: None. I generally don&amp;#39;t answer my phone and instead text people back. I dislike synchronous communication for the most part that is voice based. If I turn on the ringer, the opening few bars of Harborcoat by R.E.M.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case&lt;/strong&gt;: None. I like the form of the device too much to put a case on it, and if I drop it, oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;: Lock screen: my son. Home screen: some grass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last Text&lt;/strong&gt;: From my wife, while she was in another part of our house asking me to bring her something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last App I Used&lt;/strong&gt;: Netflix, I AirPlay it to our living room TV so I can control what my son watches on a Saturday morning while I attempt to sleep in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currently Obsessed with&lt;/strong&gt;: AlienBlue. The social structures of Reddit fascinate me. I studied virtual communities a lot in college and seeing emergence of social foundations and norms in such a rapid fashion never ceases to be interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last Download&lt;/strong&gt;: Mailbox. Also my last deletion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Surprising App on Home Screen&lt;/strong&gt;: Indigo from Perceptive Automation with customized interfaces. It lets me control all the lights, the thermostat and our front-yard fountain from my bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text or Call&lt;/strong&gt;: Text. I hate talking to people on the phone and rarely answer calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remaining Battery&lt;/strong&gt;: 87%. I do most of my long-form reading on the iPad or  one of the Mac&amp;#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your move Gruber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/IGIUqc7lb0I" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ethankaplan.com/in-the-cold-light-of-day-our-tools-make-us-all-douchebags</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:youssef,2012:Post/an-observation-on-the-2nd-amendment-and-gun-ownership</id>
    <published>2013-03-30T14:12:07-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T14:12:07-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/B4an7wtRgeE/an-observation-on-the-2nd-amendment-and-gun-ownership" />
    <author>
      <name>Youssef Sarhan</name>
      <uri>http://sefsar.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>An observation on the 2nd Amendment and gun ownership</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There has been quite a lot of debate surrounding the notion of gun control, particularly as we move into an age of 3D printed guns. Some find the notion of strong gun control unruly, while others believe it is critical. The debate is engaging, with both sides presenting coercive arguments. Yet, I have to wonder if the issue is more seminal than that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sorts of weapons available at the time of the 2nd Amendment&amp;#39;s adaptation (1791) were modest in their capabilities. Like a pirate&amp;#39;s cannon, the 18th century handgun required the owner to push a bullet down a barrel before each shot was fired — even then it was rarely fatal, if it even hit it&amp;#39;s intended target at all. The first successful semiautomatic pistols didn&amp;#39;t exist until over one hundred years after the 2nd Amendment was instated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="500" height="281" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/4D3HfqrpVhk?rel=0" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas nowadays, weapons are so incomprehensibly powerful that we don&amp;#39;t grasp the damage they&amp;#39;re causing. 60 rounds, 2 magazines, less than 30 seconds, and this guy doesn&amp;#39;t seem to be in a rush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="500" height="281" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6ihR5JmUd1s?rel=0" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SCUD missiles were never &lt;em&gt;A Right&lt;/em&gt;, they were obviously too destructive for civilians to use. Perhaps the same should be applicable to modern guns? Could it be that the Bill of Rights is wrong and that we&amp;#39;ve never questioned it&amp;#39;s dogma? I&amp;#39;m not sure what the answer is, but I feel there needs to be a high level of discussion happening that has nothing to do with guns, but rather the fundamentals upon which society operates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/B4an7wtRgeE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sefsar.com/an-observation-on-the-2nd-amendment-and-gun-ownership</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:bb,2012:Post/saying-goodbye-to-a-sister</id>
    <published>2013-03-30T10:24:36-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T10:24:36-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/xieOFyqK7Rc/saying-goodbye-to-a-sister" />
    <author>
      <name>Brian Bailey</name>
      <uri>http://brianbailey.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Saying Goodbye to a Sister</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/bb_24563121681870_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_bb_24563121681870_raw.jpg" alt="photo.JPG"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My priority this weekend was putting together a site to raise money for my sister&amp;#39;s increasing medical bills. Then, I received a phone call that her condition was rapidly worsening. An hour later, my phone rang again from the same number. No part of me wanted to answer it. She was gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laura was the middle child in our family and I was the baby. I would often tell people that being three years apart, we were constantly mad at each other growing up, but as I looked through photos from those days, there we are, side by side in picture after picture, smiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We played innumerable board games together, wrestled over the remote control, fought until there was physical evidence. I kept score at her high school volleyball games and marveled as she went on multi-day bike trips with my dad. In the days before the Internet, DVRs or even VCRs, I would watch her favorite soap opera to let her know what happened when she got home late from school. I teased her about her first boyfriends and sat on the bed and listened to her when they broke her heart. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laura was so great about my first girlfriend, of course, that she was a bridesmaid when Lori and I got married. Laura knew food and cooking better than most anyone and she and Lori shared many irreplaceable hours in the kitchen together, most recently at Thanksgiving. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She lived with us for a few months while our son was a toddler. He used to push the door open and tiptoe into her room to get a peek at this exciting new presence. She would sneak up to meet him with a surprise, &amp;ldquo;Boo!&amp;rdquo; and he would squeal and laugh and run while she chased him. For years she was known in our house as Aunt Boo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a sweet woman she was.  Everyone who met her loved her, every man was mesmerized by her beauty. She agonized over the smallest decisions, but jumped at every sudden opportunity to get on a plane. She sought out beaches constantly and found peace at the ocean&amp;#39;s edge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were always interesting tales from her travels. For some reason, her story about getting pulled over for speeding while driving across New Mexico was one of my favorites. She started by expressing surprise, but the cop would have none of it. &amp;ldquo;We&amp;#39;ve been following you for 10 miles. The only time you slowed down was when someone didn&amp;#39;t get out of your way fast enough!&amp;rdquo; She told it with the biggest smile. I doubt she actually got a ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laura was so unique.  She helped endless new families and babies as a doula. She played guitar and had a wonderful voice, became fluent in sign language, was a vegetarian before most knew such a thing existed, and danced to reggae in Jamaica. She was the one who seemed unsure of her opinions, but left you wondering why you were so sure of yours.  Somehow she introduced &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; to Firefly, yet doubted my ability to pick out clothes for her, even from her beloved Sundance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever we watched movies and shows together, she would get frustrated and groan at unrealistic scenes. &amp;ldquo;That would never happen.&amp;rdquo; Each time, I&amp;#39;d chide her, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;#39;s a story! Who wants to watch real life?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not me, not today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, she and a girlfriend traveled the globe for six months, from Thailand to New Zealand to Malawi and more.  They brought with them nothing more than massive backpacks and a fierce belief that there is no time like the present. She knew better than anyone I know that all that matters in life is people and moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God, I miss her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;d like to contribute to Laura&amp;#39;s memorial fund, donations will help cover her medical and memorial expenses. &lt;a href="http://www.youcaring.com/medical-fundraiser/in-memory-of-laura-bailey/50339"&gt;Visit this site to give&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you for your kindness and generosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/xieOFyqK7Rc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://brianbailey.me/saying-goodbye-to-a-sister</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:cadelllast,2012:Post/beyond-pangaea</id>
    <published>2013-03-29T17:44:47-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T17:44:47-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/D86w7CyZCWw/beyond-pangaea" />
    <author>
      <name>Cadell Last</name>
      <uri>http://theratchet.ca</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Beyond Pangaea</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/WYSrzWi.png" alt="Pangaea"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning I came across a &lt;a href="http://deeptime.info/"&gt;remarkable website that attempts to illustrate the concept of deep time using a metaphorical 12 hour clock&lt;/a&gt;.  As I stated before in The Ratchet, &lt;a href="http://www.theadvancedapes.com/theratchet/2013/3/26/comprehending-deep-time"&gt;metaphors like this are necessary for the human mind to conceptualize millions and billions of years&lt;/a&gt;.  They are also necessary to conceptualize some biological events like speciation and most geophysical events like the formation and separation of continents.  This is because phenomena like speciation and the separation of continents occur on larger time scales than we are accustomed to experiencing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the process of plate tectonics (which causes the formation and separation of continents) occurs so slowly that our collective popular imagination has really only allowed for the incorporation of one supercontinent: Pangaea.  Most people have heard of Pangaea from high school geography class (or from the animated film &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1667889/"&gt;Ice Age: Continental Drift&lt;/a&gt;, which incorrectly includes the separation of the supercontinent within its narrative).  However, few people are aware that Pangaea is not the first supercontinent to have existed on Earth, nor will it be the last.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Earth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pangaea existed between 300-200 million years ago during the late Paleozoic and the early Mesozoic.  During this time the clade Dinosauria evolved and dominated the terrestrial landscape.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Earth is 4.5 billion years old and geologists have realized that our planet goes through supercontinent cycles that occur roughly every 600 million years.  This means that Pangaea was not the first supercontinent; it was just the most recent supercontinent, which makes it the easiest to conceptualize.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first billion years of Earth’s existence continents as we know them today probably did not exist.  Once the Earth cooled oceans dominated the surface.  However, proto-continents began to form driven by the slow movement of Earth’s super hot semi-solid mantle.  Geologists are still unsure if supercontinents existed during this period of our planet’s history.  Some suspect that parts of modern day Madagascar, India, and Australia were connected but this claim is still highly controversial and not known with a high degree of certainty.  But even if a connected landmass did exist at this time, it would have only been half the size of modern day Australia!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Three Known Giants&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/jaQlXBr.png" alt="Columbia"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Columbia - 1.8 billion years ago&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evidence of the Earth’s terrestrial composition is far more reliable as we approach what many geologists consider to be the “first true supercontinent”: &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Columbia_(supercontinent"&gt;Columbia&lt;/a&gt;.  Columbia existed 1.8 billion years ago in the Paleoproterozoic Era.  Although this landmass was 50 million square kilometers in size, that is quite small when compared to the 150 million square kilometers of land exposed on Earth today.  For some further context &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Afro-Eurasia"&gt;Afro-Eurasia&lt;/a&gt; alone is 84 million square kilometers, almost double Columbia’s size.  However, after approximately 200 million years Columbia split leading to a new era of continental drift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/sBZnXY7.png" alt="Rodinia"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Rodinia - 1.0 billion years ago&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rodinia"&gt;Rodinia&lt;/a&gt; was the next supercontinent to form approximately 1 billion years ago in the Neoproterozoic era.  Although it was larger than Columbia, Rodinia formed entirely south of the equator.  Like Columbia, Rodinia was completely devoid of life.  The supercontinent existed before the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cambrian_Explosion"&gt;Cambrian Explosion&lt;/a&gt; and all life (both single-celled and multi-celled) had yet to transition to a terrestrial niche.  When Rodinia began to separate (~750-650 mya) it may have initiated a transformative global environmental period: &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Snowball_earth"&gt;Snowball Earth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our beloved &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pangaea"&gt;Pangaea&lt;/a&gt; was the next in the succession of supercontinents.  It was the first supercontinent to possess life and was home to the first major proliferation of megafauna on our planet.  Pangaea may have allowed dinosaurs to become globally dominant quickly because there were no major oceans separating populations.  Many paleontologists believe that Pangaea also contributed to low genetic diversity within the Dinosauria clade and a homogenization of general dinosaur body plans.  The most obvious physical evidence of Pangaea’s existence can be noticed an any world map: the South American and African coasts (which appear to fit like two pieces of a jigsaw puzzle).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/AC1izAv.png" alt="threescenarios"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today many geologists believe we are in a half-way point between supercontinental cycles.  We know that a future supercontinent will exist, but we are unsure of what type of supercontinent it will be.  Currently there are three different models: Pangaea Ultima, Amasia, and Novopangaea.  These three forms are all based on calculations of contemporary incremental movement and fragmentary data of plate tectonic dynamics.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Pangaea Ultima scenario the Atlantic Ocean will start to close, opening up the Pacific once again.  North American and Africa would collide, South American and Antarctica would collide, and Australia and South-East Asia would collide.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Amasia and Novopangaea scenarios the Atlantic Ocean would become the “super ocean” and the Pacific would close.  In these scenarios the Americas would crash into Asia, but it is unknown whether Antarctica would join the other continents in the Northern Hemisphere.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, current calculations predict this future supercontinent will exist in 250 million years.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study of plate tectonics is remarkably young and geologists have just started to figure out our planet’s continental history (and potential future).  The effects that major continental collisions and separations have on ecosystems are profound.  Future research should reveal more about how they affect climate and biodiversity.  But in my opinion we already have enough data to reveal the astounding fact that if you were to go backwards or forwards in time 250 million years, our planet would look like an alien.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like life itself, our planet is undergoing constant change.  This means that the number of future supercontinents will only be limited by the life of our star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Below is a video illustrating the past 250 million years of continental drift and the next 250 million years of continental drift under the Pangaea Ultima scenario):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/NYbTNFN3NBo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/D86w7CyZCWw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://theratchet.ca/beyond-pangaea</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:hardaway,2012:Post/10-tips-for-small-business-marketing</id>
    <published>2013-03-29T14:39:13-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T14:39:13-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/XmMH-9g2jxQ/10-tips-for-small-business-marketing" />
    <author>
      <name>Francine Hardaway</name>
      <uri>http://francinesblog.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>10 Tips for Small Business Marketing</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When Goldman Sachs invested in Arizona-based Infusionsoft last year, they were actually investing in small business as the economic engine of the future. Infusionsoft, one of the largest of the many small business marketing companies, grows its own business by creating a community of its customers, and encouraging them to help each other grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small businesses often face a conundrum: they know they need to do more marketing to attract more customers, but since they don&amp;#39;t have much in the way of resources, they pretty much have to do it themselves. And they don&amp;#39;t have time, don&amp;#39;t know how, and can&amp;#39;t outsource it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Infusionsoft solves that problem with its slogan &amp;ldquo;Automation Means Domination&amp;rdquo; and an army of experts who help each other learn how to create marketing programs that work. At this year&amp;#39;s InfusionCon, I sat in on the Ultimate Marketer Contest finals and listened to the finalists talk about what worked for them. The three finalists in the contest had all tripled the size of their businesses in the past year. And believe me, they weren&amp;#39;t in typical gazelle businesses: they were a company that helps churches raise money, an orthodontics practice, and a team sports apparel company. They&amp;#39;re the kinds of companies that go from $200,000 in revenue to $2 million in a year using common marketing strategies, good software, and guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here were ten big takeaways from the Ultimate Marketer Finalists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.Don&amp;#39;t grow away from your customers. As you grow, you may find you are interacting with customers less. That&amp;#39;s bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automation trumps determination. You can&amp;#39;t stay in touch without help; marketing automation creates a foundation of stability as the business grows and allows you to keep close to customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a webinar that will help your target customers do something important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use broadcast email to invite them and others to the webinar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn what the perfect customer life cycle is for your business. Examine how long it takes to make a sale after you generate a lead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attract traffic to your web site using social media, but don&amp;#39;t try to do it all. Use one tool well&amp;ndash;either Facebook, or Twitter, or LinkedIn. Don&amp;#39;t try to maintain too many profiles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7.Build a list of email addresses. Test several different landing pages to see which attracts the most email addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build campaigns based around your email addresses, and offer free information. Convert this to sales by offering a free trial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Send handwritten thank you notes to new customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turn your customers into affiliate marketers and/or advocates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was amazed at how much these small businesses were able to do with a little guidance and a good software package. Those who are willing to invest some time in automating their marketing will undoubtedly see a return on their investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/XmMH-9g2jxQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://francinesblog.com/10-tips-for-small-business-marketing</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:kivestu,2012:Post/accuracy-vs-precision-what-it-means-for-your-product-decisions</id>
    <published>2013-03-29T12:58:05-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T12:58:05-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/56Pb4SSgDrU/accuracy-vs-precision-what-it-means-for-your-product-decisions" />
    <author>
      <name>Kenton Kivestu</name>
      <uri>http://blog.kentonkivestu.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Accuracy vs. precision: what it means for your product decisions</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#39;s the difference between accuracy and precision? My Dad asked me this at the age of 10. I told him it was a stupid question. However, it&amp;#39;s increasingly important as we become inundated with data. There is a risk of PMs / orgs / companies over-utilizing a &amp;ldquo;data-driven&amp;rdquo; approach to the point where decision makers neglect pursuing step-function changing ideas because the &amp;ldquo;data doesn&amp;#39;t support it.&amp;rdquo; A healthy use of this data requires a keen understanding of when to ignore it. This is where precision vs. accuracy enters the picture. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia nicely sums up the technical difference (I added some formatting for emphasis):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accuracy of a measurement system is the degree of closeness of measurements of a quantity to that quantity&amp;#39;s actual (true) value. The precision of a measurement system, also called reproducibility or repeatability, is the degree to which repeated measurements under unchanged conditions show the same results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a visual depiction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/38/Accuracy_and_precision.svg" alt="accuracy_vs_precision"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize, the more precise you are, the tighter the bell curve. The more accurate you are, the closer the center of your bell curve is to the actual true reference value. This is highly relevant for product stakeholders because we are confronted daily with making tradeoffs between:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) Building features we have strong conviction in based off of past success and internal data (eg, we can precisely estimate impact), and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b) Taking bigger risks on opportunities that are more difficult to quantify, but that we believe will drive step function changes in the business (eg, accurately nail big opportunities).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why does it matter?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Precision is seductive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the age of big data, it&amp;#39;s an increasingly effective tool of the Sirens. It&amp;#39;s easy to be seduced into building features whose impact you&amp;#39;ll be able to predict precisely. For example, in the gold rush days of FB platform apps, many developers spent significant resources optimizing FB request flows. Why? Because it was alluringly simple to precisely predict the impact tweaks would have, execute them and measure the results. No doubt, the human brain gets an inordinate satisfaction out of this - it&amp;#39;s like magic! You said X would happen, and you were right (X*.98 happened)! It might be fun to be a prognosticator, but &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Precision has an opportunity cost.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a significant opportunity cost in consistently prioritizing precision over accuracy. Accuracy is about launching what the market needs, precision is about optimizing and delivering relentlessly on it. Unless you&amp;#39;ve nailed the former, material effort on the latter is going to be wasted because you&amp;#39;re optimizing something too far from the true north (the accurate goal) you should be pursuing. As Andrew Chen pointed out, startups that don&amp;#39;t have product/market fit don&amp;#39;t need growth hackers - that&amp;#39;s akin to focusing on precision when you haven&amp;#39;t nailed accuracy yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum it up, when you&amp;#39;re building product, it&amp;#39;s important to be cognizant of whether you&amp;#39;re striving for accuracy or precision (and whether that is appropriate within the context of your product / org / company). If you find yourself carefully justifying feature decisions with overly tidy, buttoned-up, high confidence items, ask yourself whether you&amp;#39;re sacrificing accuracy for precision. &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#39;s better to be directionally accurate than precisely wrong.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/56Pb4SSgDrU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.kentonkivestu.com/accuracy-vs-precision-what-it-means-for-your-product-decisions</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/pitch-deck</id>
    <published>2013-03-29T07:33:25-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T07:33:25-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/xYXiMXqVLiI/pitch-deck" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The 7 Questions A Startup Should Answer in their Fund Raising Pitch</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24562216432584_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24562216432584_raw.jpg" alt="question.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of our companies started financing processes in earlier this quarter. At a strategy session with one of our companies, the team and I crafted the outline of the pitch deck. They asked me what questions a venture investor might ask in the initial meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distilling the investment analysis into a small number of general questions is challenging because of the diversity of businesses we see but, I gave it a try and came up with the following questions I might ask a startup to answer in an initial meeting.
&lt;ol style="line-height: 19px; padding-top: 25px;"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;[Value prop] What is the problem and is it worth solving? Why is now the right time to solve it?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;[Team] Does the team have the vision and the wherewithal to build this company?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;[Go to market] What is the competitive angle (competitive barrier to entry and/or go-to-market) that will enable this company to succeed where others have tried and failed?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;[Sales effectiveness &amp;amp; product validation] Who does the startup sell to? Which customers have used the product and how have they received it? How much is each customer worth?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;[Product distribution] How does the company acquire customers cost effectively?  What are the unit economics (customer acquisition cost, contribution revenue, and churn rates)?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;[Revenue model] Does the company have the revenue model to build a big (&amp;gt;$100M annual revenue) business with good margins (gross ~ 50 to 60% / net ~15 to 25%) under reasonable assumptions?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;[Market size] Can the market enable or bear a $100M revenue Alternatively, is this product in a quickly growing market or riding a disruptive wave?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tomtunguz.com/the-11-risks-vcs-evaluate"&gt;Other risks including legal risks, technology development risks, value chain implications and so on may also be important&lt;/a&gt;. But when building a generic fund-raising deck, answering these questions in your pitch deck will serve as a solid starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s important to unite these points with a single theme or story to sell the dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/xYXiMXqVLiI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/pitch-deck</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jbrandonbb,2012:Post/15-things-you-cannot-do-with-a-chromebook-pixel</id>
    <published>2013-03-28T19:23:52-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T19:23:52-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/SzOIyY91kgA/15-things-you-cannot-do-with-a-chromebook-pixel" />
    <author>
      <name>John Brandon</name>
      <uri>http://byjohnbrandon.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>15 Things You Cannot Do With a Chromebook Pixel</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I will do anything for love, but I won&amp;#39;t do that.&amp;rdquo; - Meatloaf &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I have resorted to leading off with a Meatloaf quote. This not only cheapens the quality of this fine blog but also makes me hungry. But, before you complain too much or mumble to yourself about how lame that is, please note: there is a method to this madness. Mostly, it is to keep me from getting bored. Also, I&amp;#39;m secretly hinting to my wife that meatloaf might make a good dinner entrée. (Home by 7 honey!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, instead of writing a review, I&amp;#39;ve decided to list just &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the things the new Chromebook Pixel won&amp;#39;t do. But first, a little backstory. The Chromebook Pixel ($1299) is a marvel of engineering. It has a responsive high-res touchscreen (check), an elegant machined-aluminum chassis (check), a speedy processor (check), and Google (check). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you&amp;#39;re a glutton for punishment (e.g., Windows 8), the Pixel is everything anyone would ever want in a touchscreen laptop and thensome. (It&amp;#39;s so awesome, I&amp;#39;ve invented the word thensome just for this post.) But it won&amp;#39;t do everything. And to prove it won&amp;#39;t do everything, I have decided to make up a few things it won&amp;#39;t do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Pretend to be a hot plate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;#39;ve tried this one, believe me. The steps are fairly straightforward. You login with your Google password, then set the laptop on a hot driveway for about seven hours. My test results: Initially, I was getting some bubbling with eggs and my toast felt warm, then &amp;ndash; nothing. I don&amp;#39;t mind some of the cracks, and I don&amp;#39;t think Google PR will either. (E-mail me if you can get yours to work like a hot plate, but I think the aluminum chassis might be designed only for warming up Pop Tarts and egg rolls.) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Run the original version of Doom&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I have also tried this. It&amp;#39;s the first thing I did after the hot plate test. Now, for the naysayers out there (comments are disabled just for you!): I realize there are gaming portals that let you run Doom illegally in a browser. That&amp;#39;s like reading the new Al Gore book as a stolen PDF: boring and wrong. I&amp;#39;m talking about installing Doom from my original floppy disks. I&amp;#39;m not sure when I felt the most remorse: when I realized there wasn&amp;#39;t a floppy disk drive or when I realized no one knows what that is. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Perform surgery on a human&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Chromebook Pixel cannot perform surgery. While this is probably a good thing, you should know some of the limitations before you purchase one. You might be thinking: I have decided to buy a laptop that performs surgery. The Chromebook is not for you, seek medial help. Or maybe it&amp;#39;s a relief knowing this limbless Linux derivative (you did know Chrome is a derivative of Linux, right? I mean, right?) is not perfect. That should not be a barrier to entry. Not having a functioning appendix, that definitely is. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Photoshop&lt;/strong&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Telling you jokes and puns in a quirky robotic voice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I used to think this is important, back when I had a closer relationship with Apple Siri. We&amp;#39;ve grown distant latley. I now have a new artificial friend named Google Now. But does Google Now work on the Chromebook Pixel? Not really. (Post in comments if it actually does let you use Google Now. Wait, I forgot &amp;ndash; comments are disabled!) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Stargazing on a clear night with someone you love&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
One of the delineating features of the original Android smartphones was that you could hold the little sucker up to the night sky and see star constellations. I mean, wonder of wonders! This feature alone made me question my iPhone purchasing habits. Unfortunately, there does not appear to be any way to do this with the Chromebook Pixel. You can use one to block the sun on your morning commute, though. I have already let Google know the whole Chromebook stargazing thing would be cool. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Solving world peace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Chromebook will not solve world peace. I feel that&amp;#39;s a little less critical than the Photoshop problem I mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Connecting pretty much anything by USB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Okay, harsh! But there&amp;#39;s this pesky problem that is worth mentioning to anyone who is confused: the Chromebook Pixel does not run Windows. I need to let that sink in a little. Wait for it. Okay &amp;ndash; also, since the Chromebook does not run Windows, it does not run Windows drivers. So let&amp;#39;s say you own some amazing USB recording equipment and want to make an album. Or let&amp;#39;s say you have a fancy USB telephone system for your office. Or, anything USB-related. Good news: you can warm up your toast! (Disclaimer: Many printers, webcams, and toasters do work.) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Performing data-intensive experiments related to nuclear fission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Actually, it can do that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Developing a complex Web site using Windows software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You remember that point I made about USB drivers? I know you&amp;#39;re still coming to grips with that. More bad news for you: a Chromebook Pixel cannot run complex Windows desktop programming software. Like, none. It does work perfectly fine for Joomla, WordPress development, most Java programming, some mild cooking, and recording cat videos. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. Doorstop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
That&amp;#39;s why God created Windows 8 laptops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. Chatting over Apple&amp;#39;s Facetime app&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I know! I was surprised by this one, too. No Apple Facetime app &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;. I repeat: Nada on Facetime. There&amp;#39;s a perfectly good webcam, too. If you try to do anything related to Facetime you just get a blank stare/screen. The webcam is only good for taking photos of kittens. Oh, and for stargazing in real-time once Google gets my message about that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13. Photoshop&lt;/strong&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14. Microsoft Office, Excel, PowerPoint, and OneNote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Okay, like anyone really takes OneNote seriously. And, technically speaking, there are Google equivalents. Also, if you really need to use Word, you can use the Chrome Remote Desktop app and tap into a Windows computer. Or move on in life. Or dictate documents using Google Keep in 20-second intervals. Or write them by hand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15. Time travel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I had high expectations for this one. I thought, hey &amp;ndash; maybe the Chromebook Pixel does time travel? Or maybe it can tap into the multiverse? That would make up for the whole USB driver problem or the Photoshop issues I mentioned (twice). But the Chromebook Pixel does not do time travel or the multiverse quite yet. You can do experiments in nuclear fission, program complex Web sites, chat over pretty much everything except Facetime, warm your toast, and record a document by voice in 20-second intervals. Oh, and type up sardonic blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/SzOIyY91kgA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://byjohnbrandon.com/15-things-you-cannot-do-with-a-chromebook-pixel</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:youssef,2012:Post/the-alarm-clock-as-an-mmo-game</id>
    <published>2013-03-28T19:16:50-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T19:16:50-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/hy7XDKgFWQc/the-alarm-clock-as-an-mmo-game" />
    <author>
      <name>Youssef Sarhan</name>
      <uri>http://sefsar.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The alarm clock as an MMO game?</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Most of us use alarm clocks, but something about them feels broken. Sure, the alarm will ring at exactly the right time, but after being disturbed from a long nights rest, we just want to go back to sleep, so we hit snooze – and we all know how that plays out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with the alarm clock is that there&amp;#39;s no obvious incentive to get up. At least no incentive that we can readily perceive in our morning mutant states. Breakfast in bed or the smell of freshly brewed coffee will usually do the trick. However, in the absence of such bounty, perhaps there are a few things we can try as a substitute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if we turned the alarm clock into a massive multiplayer online game? My reckoning is that at any given moment there are at least a few million people on this earth waking up to an alarm clock. The habit –usually the hardest part when building a product– is already there, it&amp;#39;s just waiting to be experimented with. Here&amp;#39;s how it might work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open the app. Set your alarm time. The app will now pair you with another player who wishes to wake at the same time – and that&amp;#39;s it, the game is set. To prevent people from cheating, you can&amp;#39;t exit the app. If you exit the app the game will end and you&amp;#39;ll be forced to forfeit the points of the round to your opponent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the alarm rolls around you&amp;#39;ll both be alerted with a task/game to complete. The games will vary every morning and will generally take about 30 – 60 seconds to complete. You gain points for every battle you win and bonus points if you achieve a streak of wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games could include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find an international city on a map. (Maps integration, with no search.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Answer a trivia question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spot the difference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move your phone as far from its current location as possible within the next 60 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most taps on the screen within a 30 second period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify a song. (iTunes integration)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whack-a-mole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solve a simple math equation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transcribe an audio sentence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper–Scissors–Rock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and so on..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game could be a lot more interesting with leader-boards, crazier game types, and various other social mechanisms. Perhaps you could play the same person everyday, if you both wished? This is just a silly idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;d use it, would you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/ys"&gt;Let&amp;#39;s make it happen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/hy7XDKgFWQc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sefsar.com/the-alarm-clock-as-an-mmo-game</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:justin,2012:Post/how-to-do-anything</id>
    <published>2013-03-28T14:38:38-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T14:38:38-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/3AbEbwjV_bI/how-to-do-anything" />
    <author>
      <name>Justin Kan</name>
      <uri>http://justinkan.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>How to do anything</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many people, when faced with doing something new that they know nothing about, won’t ever get started. The project seems too daunting and they don’t have any context for even where to begin. In fact, in the very beginning, Justin.tv was exactly this type of problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first conceived of Justin.tv, it was simple to explain: we’d have a live streaming video feed of our exploits in San Francisco broadcast from a camera in real time to many viewers simultaneously watching on the web. It wasn’t as simple to figure out how to make this a reality, in fact, Emmett and I (it was just us at first) didn’t know the first thing about online video protocols, servers or infrastructure, cameras, or mobile network connections. At that point, we were simply two web developers with a year of experience building an AJAX calendar app. To us, the whole project appeared to be one big black box:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build Justin.tv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we could break this down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figure out how to build a mobile camera that streamed video to one server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figure out how to ingest a video and stream to multiple viewers from our server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going further:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to an expert in hardware devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research available mobile data transmission technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to a startup we’d recently met who was doing live streaming (to figure out what tech they were using)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate using a Content Delivery Network for streaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve found that when faced with a set of seemingly insurmountable challenges, the first step towards making it easier is to break things down into as large a set of small individual tasks as possible. In this case, our list of to-dos was broken down further many times. #1 lead us to Kyle, who became a cofounder and built the first streaming device (a computer that encoded video data from an analog camera). We learned that EVDO Rev A was coming to San Francisco, enabling us to send data at reasonable speeds over the cell networks (#2). Following up with #3 lead us to learn about streaming server options, and eventually choose #4 (paying someone else to stream our video for us). Six months after we first began working on the Justin.tv project full time, starting from a place with zero knowledge, we had a mobile streaming hardware device that sent video to multiple viewers, and launched our show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process is simple to apply to any set of challenges, from the fantastic to the mundane. Make yourself a list of what must be done and go through that list. For example, if you need to graduate from university and get a job so you can take care of your family, that probably entails a large set of smaller, more manageable things: getting decent grades in each of a set of credits, creating a resume, applying to jobs, practicing interviewing, etc. In turn, each of these things can be reduced to a set of smaller tasks that will seem more accomplishable: getting a decent grade in a class turns into a set of tasks including studying, writing term papers, and preparing for an exam. Often times, the first step in accomplishing your goals might be as simple as buying the assigned books for a class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recall a disagreement I had with a friend many years ago. My claim was that anything I set my mind to was achievable; he thought this idea was ridiculous. The point came up because he thought the idea of private spaceflight orchestrated by individuals would never work. &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/2012/10/07/spacex-capsule/1618411/"&gt;Looks like I was right.&lt;/a&gt; You can achieve anything you set your mind to; doing so is just process of reduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are of a like-minded attitude, &lt;a href="http://iamexec.com/hiring"&gt;come build things at Exec&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/3AbEbwjV_bI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://justinkan.com/how-to-do-anything</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:EAKoester,2012:Post/forked-founder-vs-early-employee</id>
    <published>2013-03-28T11:00:30-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T11:00:30-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/-i3hRIinzLw/forked-founder-vs-early-employee" />
    <author>
      <name>Eric Koester</name>
      <uri>http://ekoester.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Forked: Founder vs. Early Employee</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s funny how much hero worship there is out there about being the &amp;ldquo;founder&amp;rdquo; of a startup company.  That&amp;#39;s not to say I don&amp;#39;t appreciate it &amp;ndash; to some degree.  But the reality is that how different is it to be the &amp;ldquo;founder&amp;rdquo; or the first group of folks to really put your shovel in the ground versus on of the early team to pour the cement, build the frame and get a roof on that building?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it better to take your shot as a founder or join up as an early employee?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I&amp;#39;ve wondered about that question after announcing I was leaving Zaarly.  Lots of great folks have asked if I&amp;#39;d join their company, go to the dark side (as an investor), cofound something with them or simply help lead something that was moving up the hockey stick. All of these were great opportunities and things that made me pause. In some ways its that proverbial &amp;ldquo;fork&amp;rdquo; in the road for me and my career.  And so I&amp;#39;ve been forced to ask, &amp;ldquo;What makes sense for me at this point in my life?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last part of this is where I found the most insight: &lt;em&gt;&amp;#39;at this point in my life.&amp;#39;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;#39;s what I&amp;#39;ve realized: founding something is a great learning experience.  It truly truly is.  BUT, I learned more about how to found something from my experience at Appature (learning from the founders Kabir aand Chris who&amp;#39;d closed their Series A a few months before I joined) and working with dozens of founders as a lawyer.  And now as I start the process of founding my next company, I realize how much collectively I learned going through the process at Zaarly and all those experiences before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it isn&amp;#39;t &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; you should found something, but more like &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip; and if you think about your journey as a founder in those terms, turns out its much easier (non) choice you&amp;#39;re making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, Which Fork?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I don&amp;#39;t pretend to sit here and give prescriptive advice to anyone&amp;hellip; turns out startups are a challenge whether you found it or you join it early on.  What I&amp;#39;ve learned about myself is that as a founder you must be able to be a teacher and inspire confidence.  From my first hacky side project startup to Zaarly to my new project, each time I&amp;#39;ve gotten more confident, more experienced and more knowledgable.  That isn&amp;#39;t to say I can control the outcomes any better, but perhaps I&amp;#39;ll just make fewer of the same mistakes&amp;hellip; again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I thought through my opportunities, I asked myself these questions:
- Are you able to teach others that work with you something?
- Can you lead people towards an ambiguous aim?
- Will you be better able to convince others to follow your lead in one to three years?
- Are you convinced you are ready to take &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; shot?
- Do you have the resources (time, money, support) to go for a while without a paycheck?
- Describe how this fails?  Does that scare you from doing it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these come down to the question of timing (and confidence in that timing answer), in some form of another.  Maybe it&amp;#39;s now or maybe it&amp;#39;s later, but most of these are experiences, skills or resources &amp;ndash; and all of which require you personally believing now is the right time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I decided to forgo other opportunities because it feels a little like I&amp;#39;ve been preparing for this for my whole life&amp;hellip; and that&amp;#39;s the answer I needed to know I was ready to go back out for another swing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turns out, it&amp;#39;s hard.  So don&amp;#39;t make it harder.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So do you found or not?  I think the answer is yes (if you are asking the question), of course you found&amp;hellip; but the question really is about &lt;strong&gt;when&lt;/strong&gt; do you found it.  That&amp;#39;s not easy to know, but it&amp;#39;s something that will become obvious as you begin your journey.  If you are confident you want to found something, make your journey about answering those questions &amp;ndash; with the right experience, knowledge, connections and resources.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, I love startup people and the guys and gals I meet who are taking the risk to do a startup.  But I often wonder why there is the infatuation with being &amp;ldquo;the&amp;rdquo; founder and not part of that early early team?  It&amp;#39;s lessons learned doing the startup grind that ready you to found &amp;ndash; but rather than &amp;ldquo;pay their dues&amp;rdquo;, people move forward with founding.  I wonder if you&amp;#39;d get more out of learning from a successfully founded company than struggling through your first one without any prior experience.  Not every situation is the same, but there are some very common lessons along any startup journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I&amp;#39;m totally enjoying the process of founding another startup.  I truly am. It&amp;#39;s way harder than I remembered, and takes extreme patience, but that&amp;#39;s okay. At the same time, each day I realize how MUCH I didn&amp;#39;t know just a few years ago before my first startup.  Little things like tricks, timelines, structures, hacks, shortcuts, mistakes to avoid, quirks, etc.  You can get some on the fly, but others are just so much easier learning from/with others.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life&amp;#39;s all about preparing you for that moment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s awesome to see all the enthusiasm for starting companies &amp;ndash; we probably have a few guys like Steve Jobs, Mark Zuckerberg and Bill Gates to thank for that.  But if you look at their journeys, they each had figured out the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; time for them to found something&amp;hellip; whether than meant putting in the time in school, in another company, via a hobby or just in life.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But founding a company isn&amp;#39;t about if, its about when.  And if you know you want to do it&amp;hellip; create that plan and that path to actually do it.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuz it&amp;#39;s terrifying and awesome on this journey.  Wouldn&amp;#39;t be anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/-i3hRIinzLw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ekoester.com/forked-founder-vs-early-employee</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:cap,2012:Post/formspring-a-postmortem</id>
    <published>2013-03-28T10:24:57-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T10:24:57-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/AnnN49xgCgY/formspring-a-postmortem" />
    <author>
      <name>Cap Watkins</name>
      <uri>http://blog.capwatkins.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Formspring - A Postmortem</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This Sunday, after nearly three and a half years, &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/15/formspring-the-pioneering-anonymous-qa-platform-is-shutting-down/"&gt;Formspring is shutting down&lt;/a&gt;. While it’s a sad moment for me to see a startup I worked on and loved close its doors, I can’t help but also look back and examine ways we could have steered the product toward a more successful outcome. What follows are a few points that I’ve been reflecting on ever since Ade announced Formspring’s closure that I hope will be helpful for current and future entrepreneurs. To be clear, my critique is of product decisions we all made together, as a company (while I was there). As we would have shared in its success, so too shall we share and learn from its end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We protected anonymous content to a fault&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formspring’s initial success was, in large part, due to giving our users the ability to ask each other questions anonymously (even without a Formspring account). In under a year, we skyrocketed to our first billion questions answered and showed few signs of slowing down. Yet even as we celebrated these milestones, we were all discussing how anonymity would or wouldn’t play a part in the future of our product. On the one hand, anonymity was a really popular feature (duh). On the other hand, we saw a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of bad and abusive content come through that channel (&lt;a href="http://www.penny-arcade.com/comic/2004/03/19"&gt;double duh&lt;/a&gt;). A fact that we wound up being &lt;a href="http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2010/12/29/formspring-the-site-for-prying-questions-gears-up-but-will-it-grow-up/"&gt;pretty infamous&lt;/a&gt; for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But man was it hard to let go of anonymity as a core feature. We tried workaround after workaround. We prompted for sign-up after asking an anonymous question. We started pushing privacy settings for users into our on-boarding (which they never changed, of course). We started setting up elaborate filters to catch bad or abusive questions and put them behind a “Flagged Questions” link in users’ inboxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a lot of time on anonymity. It was our sacred cow. Looking back, we should have spent that time finding ways to gracefully degrade that feature instead of finding ways to keep it alive. When you find yourself constantly giving a feature CPR, you should stop and consider whether or not it’s worth saving (or even possible to save).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our opaque follow-model shot us in the foot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, this lines up with our stance on anonymity. Following on Formspring was, for &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt; completely anonymous. You couldn’t see who followed you and others couldn’t see that you were following them. This meant that we gave people a microphone and they kind of had to &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; people heard what they were saying. And until we eventually launched our Smiles feature (akin to Facebook Likes), there was no way to know that your content was being consumed. We debated this a lot internally and came to the conclusion that the Twitter public-follow model was broken in that it put unnecessary social pressure on users to follow back. We felt we could build social features on top of the content (like Smiles) that let our users receive feedback and let their followers out themselves purposefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formspring eventually allowed public following (not as a default, and after I left), but it was too little too late. My takeaway from this has been to always double check to make sure you’re not designing toward your own biases instead of what’s best for your product and users. Formspring had clearly struck a chord with people aching to share more about themselves with their friends. And instead of making it apparent that they were achieving their goal, we put an artificial barrier in place and prevented them from knowing if Formspring was working for them or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We skated toward the hockeystick&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest sin of them all from a product perspective, but also the hardest to avoid (and one that I see companies make over and over again).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our initial graphs at Formspring, as you probably know, all hockeysticked up and to the right. Nearly straight up. That part was totally awesome! We were super popular! We could be the next [insert gigantic company name here]!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh wait, the graph has peaked and is starting to slowly (very slowly) trend downward. What do we do? Make big bets, right? Try to recapture that crazy growth!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so we tried. The first big project we worked on was a Formspring button that sites could embed at the end of blog posts or other content. We had millions of users, so we figured it wasn’t a stretch to imagine they browsed other web sites and would gladly click a Formspring button at the end of a post (which asked “What did you think?” and allowed them to post a response to their Formspring page). This was just as the Facebook Share and Twitter “Tweet This” buttons were appearing, so we figured it made perfect sense to follow who we viewed as our closest competitors at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We literally spent months on that system. We had to make sure our servers could handle a potentially huge influx of traffic (we based our estimations on our main site’s traffic, which was honestly insane), had to design and implement the feature, make sure the implementation was easy for publishers, make deals with publishers, etc. We bet huge. On someone else’s (Facebook and Twitter’s) plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about photos? Instagram had just come out and was killing it! Our users would surely be more engaged if they could represent their questions and answers visually, right? I worked on those designs for at least a month and a couple more were spent iterating on and actually implementing that work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually don’t know exactly how that launch went (because I had moved on to Amazon right before it went out the door), but now it seems obvious that photos weren’t the killer feature we’d all hoped they would be. Oof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurs: build &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; product, not someone else’s. The most successful products execute on a vision that aligns with their product’s and users’ goals. It’s hard to put blinders on when your stats are slowly coming down and you see other startups skyrocketing around you with various tactics and strategies. &lt;em&gt;For the love of god, put them on.&lt;/em&gt; It’s the only way to build what you should instead of chasing others’ ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, print out &lt;a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2012/03/the-startup-curve.html"&gt;Paul Graham’s Startup Curve&lt;/a&gt; and put it on every wall in your office. It will be you. Buckle up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in the face of Formspring’s shutdown, I’m grateful for having been a part of it. I learned so much from both the team we built and the product that I’ll carry with me the rest of my career. I learned that small changes can frequently (and surprisingly) have the biggest impacts. I learned that gigantic, sweeping changes make it hard to track what’s going right and what’s going wrong. I learned just how hard it is to keep a huge site up and operational (also what happens when all of EC2-East goes down). I learned that I love designing for people I can communicate with every day within the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most of all, I learned to focus. To put the product vision first. To not try keeping up with what’s trending. To build &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; product for &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Formspring. It was a wild ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/AnnN49xgCgY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.capwatkins.com/formspring-a-postmortem</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:daslee,2012:Post/listening</id>
    <published>2013-03-28T08:29:12-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T08:29:12-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/hEoNJq0nUzw/listening" />
    <author>
      <name>David Lee</name>
      <uri>http://daslee.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Listening</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You need to prepare, listen and engage.
-&lt;a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3004361/a-conversation-charlie-rose-biz-stone-ev-williams"&gt;Charlie Rose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve met a lot of incredibly successful, accomplished and well-known people. In some cases, I&amp;#39;ve even worked with them. This is one of the huge perks of working with Ron Conway, who I put in this bucket.  (Incidentally, this sounds like a nested &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23humblebrag&amp;amp;src=typd"&gt;humblebrag&lt;/a&gt; but just because I met these folks obviously doesn&amp;#39;t put me in that bucket.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, one skill that really stands out among some of these folks is their ability and willingness to listen. I&amp;#39;m not just talking about the level of listening where you remember what the other person said. And not the pollyannish notion of &amp;ldquo;I feel your pain.&amp;rdquo;  I&amp;#39;m talking about the deeper level of listening that requires a mastery of body language, a genuine level of empathy and most important, a genuine interest and curiousity in the speaker or subject matter, or both. They are curious in either the person or the material, regardless of the person or material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;#39;ve tried to become a better listener. About fifteen years ago, I bought &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Listening-Forgotten-Skill-Self-Teaching-Guides/dp/0471015873/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1364482828&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=listening"&gt;this book&lt;/a&gt; and even highlighted portions of it. I got through about a quarter of it and threw it into my &amp;ldquo;Books Aborted&amp;rdquo; pile, which is a very large pile by the way.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t want to sound too &lt;a href="http://www.decipheringthesimpsons.com/index.php?p1=vocab&amp;amp;p2=obsequious"&gt;obsequious&lt;/a&gt;, but Ron is one of the best listeners I have ever seen. People like him lock into the other person a la Bill Clinton, who is probably the Mozart when it comes to this. For every meeting that Ron does, he brings a huge pile of notes related to the other person (i.e., he prepares) and completely locks into that person. His signature move is to furiously jot notes to record and remember what the other person is saying. I&amp;#39;ve asked him why he does this and he said, &amp;ldquo;Because I forget shit.&amp;rdquo; But the signal it sends to the speaker is immeasurable. It&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Charisma-Myth-Personal-Magnetism/dp/1591844568"&gt;charisma&lt;/a&gt; in a nutshell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When I first met Ron in 2005, we would talk about online video, his then-current interest. He would scribble notes furiously, sometimes on cocktail napkins. I thought I was the  smartest person in the world on video. When I realized a few years later that he did that with virtually everyone on every topic, I was a bit crestfallen to say the least.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I were a better listener. I&amp;#39;m subpar. Ask my &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gracelee"&gt;wife&lt;/a&gt;. And to her chagrin, I want to improve not necessarily because I want to be a better and more empathic person. it&amp;#39;s because I think it&amp;#39;s an incredibly valuable skill to have as an investor, particularly in the startup world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of your approach or &lt;a href="http://daslee.me/your-investors-business-model"&gt;business model&lt;/a&gt;, a huge part of startup investing (and in some cases, the only part) is human talent evaluation. &amp;ldquo;We invest in people&amp;rdquo; is probably the most common refrain for startup investors. And if you&amp;#39;re investing in people, you need to understand not only their skill, aptitude and potential but also their insight, drive, motivation and toughness - the immeasurables. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;#39;s where listening comes in. One difference between a good investor and a great investor is that the great investor asks the right questions. And just as importantly, they&amp;#39;re able to process and synthesize the answers. They ask the incisive ones that cut through the noise. And identifying the right question is a function of great listening. Listening increases the throughput of data and also filters out the noise. If you watch Charlie Rose or watch great interviewers, they ask the great follow-up, unscripted questions that reveal the most important and telling details. This can unearth the people who have the missionary and authentic drive to do something great - and just as importantly, weed out the people who say the right things but don&amp;#39;t actually mean it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other person who comes to mind for me ont his topic is Michael Moritz, the legendary investor at Sequoia Capital. We&amp;#39;ve co-invested a lot with Sequoia, but I&amp;#39;ve never really worked with him personally. But his path to investing is not necessarilyt the conventional one. Before his investing career, he was a journalist and writer. And without speaking to him about this or knowing if this is bullshit, it kind of makes sense.  Without knowing anything about the profession, a great journalist has to ask the right questions and synthesize the answers (among other things). And that&amp;#39;s a dynamic exercise that&amp;#39;s a direct function of getting the right information and inputs - i.e., being a great listener. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clayton Christensen said that &lt;a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3225-what-are-questions"&gt;questions are places in your mind where answers fit.&lt;/a&gt; The relevant facts are there for &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; but you need to be able to ask the right questions to unearth them. The great investors can get to the most insightful answers and meaningful insights faster than the rest of us. In the startup world, where data is scarce but potential is abundant, that is an elite skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/hEoNJq0nUzw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://daslee.me/listening</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/the-11-risks-vcs-evaluate</id>
    <published>2013-03-28T07:40:54-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T07:40:54-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/zauGf1YfQ48/the-11-risks-vcs-evaluate" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The 11 Risks VCs Evaluate</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24560610974892_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24560610974892_raw.jpg" alt="risk.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the industry is called venture capital, the goal of a VC isn&amp;#39;t to maximize every risk. Instead, we try to understand all the risks a business might face and weigh those risks with the reward - the exit. Here are the major risks that I typically review when a startup pitches. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market timing risk&lt;/strong&gt; - Is now the right time for the business? It&amp;#39;s often hard to evaluate this risk, but nevertheless, it&amp;#39;s an important consideration. There are many stories of people saying I invented Facebook before Facebook, which may very well be true. But the market just wasn&amp;#39;t yet ready for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business model risk&lt;/strong&gt; - Is there a clear business model? Do the unit economics seem to work? If not, what are the assumptions required to achieve profitability?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market adoption risk&lt;/strong&gt; - Are there strong competitive players in the market? What are the major barriers to entry?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market size risk -&lt;/strong&gt; If the company is successful, is the exit scenario large enough to &lt;a href="http://tomtunguz.com/how-to-align-founder-and-vc-incentives-why-fund-size-matters"&gt;provide the types of returns our fund needs&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Execution risk&lt;/strong&gt; - Does the team have the right skills and passion to reach their goals? If not, are they amenable to finding others to complement their skills?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology risk&lt;/strong&gt; - Does the company have to develop a new technology that may not reach fruition, or may take much longer than expected? This is typically more prevalent in cleantech and hardware companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capitalization structure risk&lt;/strong&gt; - does the company have enough room in the cap table to take more investment necessary to grow while still ensuring employees and executives are well compensated?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platform risk&lt;/strong&gt; - Is the startup building atop YouTube, Twitter or Facebook? How strong is their relationship? Are their product plans in the direct path of the platform or complementary?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venture management risk&lt;/strong&gt; - Is the company receptive to feedback? Is the team candid about the state of the business?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial risk&lt;/strong&gt; - How much money does the company require to achieve its goals? Is the financing risk manageable given the current environment and company trajectory?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal risk&lt;/strong&gt; - Does the company have a high likelihood of lawsuit for patent or copyright infringement? Does the company have any outstanding complaints with early employees or founders? Are there regulatory challenges involved in this sector?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list of these risks applies differently to each startup, but it&amp;#39;s a good general outline for entrepreneurs to think through when they pitch their companies to VCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/zauGf1YfQ48" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/the-11-risks-vcs-evaluate</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jared,2012:Post/dont-mislead-your-users</id>
    <published>2013-03-27T12:30:01-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T12:30:01-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/eUzlH8kZiKQ/dont-mislead-your-users" />
    <author>
      <name>Jared Erondu</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jarederondu.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Don't Mislead Your Users</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever tapped an icon or used a gesture only to end up in the wrong place? You were mislead. It&amp;#39;s a sucky feeling. It&amp;#39;s also why we designers should be specific in our intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design is rapidly evolving and &lt;a href="http://theindustry.cc/2013/01/07/13-design-trends-for-2013/"&gt;trends are appearing&lt;/a&gt; all the time. Right now, our interfaces are leaning more towards iconography and &lt;a href="http://www.gesturemanifesto.com"&gt;gestures&lt;/a&gt; rather than text. Which is awesome, and more &lt;a href="http://blog.jarederondu.com/brevity-in-design"&gt;concise&lt;/a&gt;. But with them is a greater chance to mislead. You see, it&amp;#39;s hard to mislead your user with words because they&amp;#39;re words–the explicit and original way to communicate (unless, of course, you skipped English class). But there&amp;#39;s no popover hovering above our icons and gestures. We&amp;#39;re assuming that our users will deduce their meaning and in some cases, discover them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shape our products based on what we envision, but sometimes, those visions can be blurry in some areas. Then four hours after our product has gone into the wild, we begin receiving redundant messages exclaiming how this or that was misleading. We weren&amp;#39;t specific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/jared_24537915822366_raw.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_jared_24537915822366_raw.gif" alt="lied.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;So &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; specific.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specificity is clarity. I&amp;#39;m not saying you should write a paragraph beneath each trigger in your product, but pass it by a few people. Ask them what they think a particular icon or gesture does. If your accurate response rate is less than 90%, your intent is still blurry. In that case, reanalyze your intention and figure out a better and more &lt;a href="http://blog.jarederondu.com/brevity-in-design"&gt;concise way&lt;/a&gt; to convey it. Ask yourself if any other message could be inferred from that icon other than your intended one. Understand the placement, the context, and the message. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be specific. Be simple. Be direct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/erondu"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/eUzlH8kZiKQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jarederondu.com/dont-mislead-your-users</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:danielle,2012:Post/racehorses-gotta-run</id>
    <published>2013-03-27T11:48:26-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T11:48:26-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/RWFDAotsr58/racehorses-gotta-run" />
    <author>
      <name>Danielle Morrill</name>
      <uri>http://distributionhacks.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>YC Demo Day, the Morning After</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apparently, this year it’s particularly in vogue to express a certain ennui about the batch of Y Combinator startups that presented at Demo Day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I checked in with investors and friends who attended the event, the overwhelming response was that there were tons of solid companies but nothing “amazing” or “10x”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the tech press can’t seem to get behind one single company, instead making their obligatory &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/26/top-y-combinator-startups/"&gt;“top 7”&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/insider/2013/03/26/here-are-our-six-favorite-startups-from-the-first-batch-of-y-combinators-winter-2013-demo-day/?fromcat=all"&gt;“6 favorite”&lt;/a&gt; lists. This morning’s &lt;a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2013/03/26/at-smaller-y-combinator-social-is-out-revenue-is-in/"&gt;story in the Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; confirms the overall sentiment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;founders are tackling “boring” problems that generate cash &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founders risk everything, move across the country or further, endure endless stress, damage relationships, sacrifice their health and pour their every waking moment into creating something people want — and they’re rewarded with a yawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If companies are too serious they’re boring, and if they’re too social then they’re fluffy and we’re headed for the next bubble. Fuck that noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/FsqJFIJ5lLs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/RWFDAotsr58" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://distributionhacks.com/racehorses-gotta-run</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:nate,2012:Post/draft-everywhere</id>
    <published>2013-03-27T09:53:37-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T09:53:37-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/fCXtqXyrb5c/draft-everywhere" />
    <author>
      <name>Nathan Kontny</name>
      <uri>http://ninjasandrobots.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Draft Everywhere</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two big Draft announcements today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://draftin.com"&gt;Draft (http://draftin.com)&lt;/a&gt; documents can now easily be published to Wordpress and Tumblr from inside Draft. Go to Settings -&amp;gt; Places to Publish. You&amp;#39;ll then get a Publish button next to your documents. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I couldn&amp;#39;t stop there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bookmarklets and browser extensions like Instapaper, Evernote&amp;#39;s Clearly, and Readability make reading anything on the web simple, focused, and gorgeous. Why can&amp;#39;t writing be that way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/draft/amlbbbgcijmiooecobhkjblcdkjldmdk"&gt;here&amp;#39;s a Chrome extension that lets you&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any webpage that you can write on, you can now use Draft with. Your blog, Gmail, Twitter, Facebook, even comment boxes on websites like Reddit and Hacker News.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just place your cursor in the box you want to write in, click the Chrome Draft extension, and Draft will open up in a new Chrome Tab. Choose an already written document or something new to write in Draft (any text from the original text box will carry over). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/draftapp/images/Screen+Shot+2013-03-27+at+10.52.28+AM.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;#39;re done, there&amp;#39;s a menu button to paste your work back into the text box you came from. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/draftapp/images/Screen+Shot+2013-03-27+at+11.00.08+AM.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of a sudden, everything you write everywhere is focused, versioned, and able to be shared with friends for help before you publish. I hope you like it. This might be the handiest and neatest thing I&amp;#39;ve ever made. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/draft/amlbbbgcijmiooecobhkjblcdkjldmdk"&gt;Click here to access the Draft Chrome extension.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve also &lt;a href="https://github.com/n8/draft_extension"&gt;open sourced the Chrome extension&lt;/a&gt; in case anyone wants to make it better or start similar projects for Firefox and Safari. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the past couple weeks I&amp;#39;ve improved a lot of other things. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change your font style and size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Drive syncing is a lot better. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Draft is much more usable now on narrow devices like iPads in landscape mode. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a CTRL+r/CMD+r shortcut to switch between edit and view modes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been a really exciting couple weeks since I launched Draft. The feedback and support have been incredible. Thank you so much for the help, the criticism, and the motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned. &lt;a href="http://draftin.com"&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt; has so much more in store to help us become better writers. I&amp;#39;m just getting started. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/fCXtqXyrb5c" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ninjasandrobots.com/draft-everywhere</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/how-to-align-founder-and-vc-incentives-why-fund-size-matters</id>
    <published>2013-03-27T07:30:33-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T07:30:33-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/140xOjmlNoo/how-to-align-founder-and-vc-incentives-why-fund-size-matters" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>How to Align Founder and VC Incentives: Why Fund Size Matters</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24559109319240_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24559109319240_raw.jpg" alt="richard cook.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When deciding if to raise a venture round, it&amp;#39;s &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;critical&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to ensure your venture investor shares the vision for the company: both the product roadmap and the financial goals of the company. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most founders never consider the impact on fund size on VC motivations. As long as there are enough reserves to invest as the company grows, a founder might think, that&amp;#39;s fine with me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is naive. Fund sizes dictate a VC&amp;#39;s strategy. To achieve their target returns, a $50M fund and a $500M fund must pursue very different investment and management styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s take a look at the economics of two hypothetical funds, a $50M and a $500M fund. Assuming each fund seeks to return three times the capital invested in 10 years to provide a good return for investors, the total value of the portfolios must be $150M and $1,500M respectively. The funds have different target ownerships and therefore different average investment sizes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this boils down to a target value of a company at exit. The larger the fund, the larger the exits must be for the venture investors to be successful.
&lt;table width="100%"&gt;

&lt;tr style="border-bottom: 1px solid gray;"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$50M fund&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$500M fund&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Target return multiple&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Implied Portfolio Holding Value&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;$150M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;$1,500M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Average Ownership&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;10%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Total Market Cap of Portfolio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;$1,500M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;$6,000M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Avg Investment Size including reserves&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;2.5M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;$10M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Number of Investments per Fund&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Company Failure Rate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Successful Investments&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Avg Market Cap of Exit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;$150M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;$400M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smaller fund a $150M exit fits the model. It&amp;#39;s a great outcome. But the same can&amp;#39;t be said for the larger fund, which seeks exits three times larger. VCs understand this math - it&amp;#39;s the same calculations they use to pitch potential investors. But it&amp;#39;s equally important founders understand the motivations and the goals of their investors, to ensure both are aligned. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Larger funds will push companies to pursue larger exits. When raising capital, ensure that your investors share the same vision and commitment to the product, but also verify that your target outcomes for the business are in the same ballpark and that you both define success in the same terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/140xOjmlNoo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/how-to-align-founder-and-vc-incentives-why-fund-size-matters</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/strategy-for-releasing-music-online</id>
    <published>2013-03-27T07:30:21-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T07:30:21-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/aNdqUVTimC8/strategy-for-releasing-music-online" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Strategy For Releasing Music Online</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Releasing an album of music can be as simple as listing it on iTunes and calling it a day, but I think there&amp;#39;s a better way. A way to take advantage of different online stores and services to promote discovery while not losing out on any potential revenue from people willing to spend some money on melodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s what I would do if I was releasing a newly recorded album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an effort to deter piracy and please the biggest fans, as soon as the album was mixed, mastered, and finished, I would put it up on Bandcamp for sale for $10. People following a band closely enough to know when new music is coming out also probably already use Bandcamp (or can figure it out). I&amp;#39;m convinced that piracy of &amp;ldquo;leaked&amp;rdquo; music before it&amp;#39;s released happens by super fans too impatient for the chance to buy it. You can fix that by making it available to buy before people can get it for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I would plan an official release date shortly thereafter, ramp up a little marketing and getting the word out for the release on iTunes and Amazon. This mainstream release on the major music stores is to get the more casual music fans, people browsing around, and others that may somehow find the album. I would knock the price down to $7.99 at this point to further encourage the purchase of music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, after 30 days of the album being on iTunes I would put it on Spotify and Rdio. Not just from stuff I read, but when I hear personal stories from managers, bands, and those in the industry that say they still haven&amp;#39;t made more than $100 for the entire length of time they&amp;#39;ve been on Spotify, something&amp;#39;s wrong. Streaming services are important for discovery reasons, but they aren&amp;#39;t providing any (or much) revenue. Until they can bring &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; to the table &amp;ndash; even if it&amp;#39;s less &amp;ndash; there&amp;#39;s no reason for musicians not to think of them as second class services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on adoption of the album and how sales are going, after 6+ months I would look into sites and services like NoiseTrade.com that focus on promotional gain over financial gain. Capturing emails, growing the fan base, and getting the most people to hear the music would the goal for the remainder of the album&amp;#39;s life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most musicians aren&amp;#39;t creating music just for the chance to be broke and in debt and need to &amp;ndash; at minimum &amp;ndash; recoup the costs that went into making the album. By playing off the immediacy of digital distribution to please your biggest fans and people willing to pay a premium, you capitalize on sales. Using a trickle down approach to services that have less return, you don&amp;#39;t cannibalize potential sales in the name of discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/aNdqUVTimC8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/strategy-for-releasing-music-online</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:adii,2012:Post/coping-as-an-entrepreneur</id>
    <published>2013-03-27T04:06:27-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T04:06:27-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/uUfb5jTdo8Q/coping-as-an-entrepreneur" />
    <author>
      <name>Adii Pienaar</name>
      <uri>http://adii.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Coping as an Entrepreneur</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I wrote about &lt;a href="http://adii.me/youre-born-an-entrepreneur"&gt;being born an entrepreneur&lt;/a&gt;, I did so to communicate what I felt / thought in an effort to be validated. Because if I can be validated, if I can find others like me, then surely it means that &lt;em&gt;I&amp;#39;m not crazy&lt;/em&gt;. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The various tweets &amp;amp; affirmations that I got subsequently made me feel like I wasn&amp;#39;t alone. But then I read &lt;a href="http://pandodaily.com/2013/02/20/why-many-entrepreneurs-are-privately-suffering-and-what-to-do-about-it/"&gt;this article about entrepreneurs being &lt;em&gt;soft-bipolar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;In general, though, many believe that running startups can drive people to experience intense ups and downs. While this is true, it’s often the other way around: People in the bipolar spectrum are attracted to entrepreneurship. Building businesses can be a great way for hypomanic entrepreneurs to apply their energy and creativity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people are more vulnerable to mood fluctuations and can also experience episodes of dark depression that may include feelings of hopelessness, irritability, fatigue, concentration problems, and feelings of worthlessness.&amp;rdquo;*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fuck.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October last year, my wife &amp;amp; I had an argument (can&amp;#39;t even remember what it was about) and at one point she turned to me to say: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You need to spend time with your son, not because you need to manage him, but because you really want to spend time with him.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those very serious words hit me very hard and I left me speechless. What my wife had said was true; not because it was my intention, but it was the consequence of so many other decisions that I was making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left the room and upon reflection, I had to admit that deep-down I was incredibly unhappy. So I decided to see my therapist (who had I had been seeing on &amp;amp; off), who suggested that I definitely have a mild case of depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To hear those words from a therapist was tough. I had never considered myself depressed or an unhappy person; instead I&amp;#39;m an extrovert that always wants to be happy, optimistic &amp;amp; proactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearing these words from my wife (who is the one person in this world that &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; knows me) and my therapist though, pushed me to explore other aspects of my life &amp;amp; thoughts that might not have been as obvious. I found that I used the ups to disguise and forget about the downs. As such I was able to &lt;em&gt;cope&lt;/em&gt;, but every now &amp;amp; again that coping mechanism completely failed as the ups would just not come quickly enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to admit &amp;amp; accept that regardless of how successful or happy I was, part of me was imperfect &amp;amp; broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then I&amp;#39;ve done a couple of things to help me cope on what is a pretty rollercoaster ride when being an entrepreneur:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://adii.me/weve-broken-this-startup-thing"&gt;I tweaked a couple of small things&lt;/a&gt; in my daily routine: I work less, I exercise more, I take vitamins to sleep better &amp;amp; I generally attempt to shut down my mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I write about the things that are in my head. Instead of writing about &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;5 Steps to Grow Your Business&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; or commenting on what&amp;#39;s happening with other companies, I prefer to just share what is going on in my head &amp;amp; heart. This has helped me to cleanse my mind of some things that I grapple with daily and also helps me to distill those thoughts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I joined &lt;a href="http://www.eonetwork.org/"&gt;EO&lt;/a&gt;, where I meet with a group of like-minded entrepreneurs every month to get help. I see this as some kind of &lt;em&gt;Entrepreneurs Anonymous&lt;/em&gt;, where I can just be me, be vulnerable and ask fo help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m reminded of Dan Martell&amp;#39;s recent &lt;a href="http://blog.clarity.fm/living-life-in-permanent-beta/"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Living Life in Permanent Beta&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; blog post, where he speaks of building &lt;em&gt;soft assets&lt;/em&gt; as an entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the tweaks that I&amp;#39;ve made in my life in the last couple of months aren&amp;#39;t necessarily something that I need every, single day. But I&amp;#39;m putting money in the bank and when those downs hit, I have an asset-base on which I can rely to help me cope (as an entrepreneur).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/uUfb5jTdo8Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://adii.me/coping-as-an-entrepreneur</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:francis,2012:Post/your-business-is-your-thesis</id>
    <published>2013-03-26T19:05:53-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T19:05:53-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/91fvjYI6q7E/your-business-is-your-thesis" />
    <author>
      <name>Francis Pedraza</name>
      <uri>http://francispedraza.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Your business is your thesis</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I began my last post, “&lt;a href="http://francispedraza.com/to-think-like-midas"&gt;To think like Midas&lt;/a&gt;”, by saying that great entrepreneurs think like investors. I spent the rest of it explaining how a great investor might think. Using the past to see the future, we discussed trends and megatrends, and how the winners - the “Great Men” - see them coming, make them happen and shape them. Those are the people you want to bet on if you’re an investor, and if you’re an entrepreneur, those are the people you want to be. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, this way of thinking shouldn&amp;#39;t just apply to founders. Leadership should be fractal. If you work for a startup, this is how you want to think. &lt;em&gt;Everyone&lt;/em&gt; is an investor. &lt;em&gt;Everyone&lt;/em&gt; is an entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If great entrepreneurs think like investors, then what follows is the corollary: your business is your investment thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A business is an argument, of sorts. It’s a statement about value: about what you find valuable, what other people will find valuable, and how best to create that value in the world while making a profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every business asserts that it has found the best solution to a problem – and that the problem is not only worthy, but that it is the &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; worthy of all the problems it could possibly solve – given limited time and capital, risk, and the passions and talents of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Framing the decision&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting a business is an investment decision. Dating is an investment decision. Hiring someone is an investment decision. Paying for a service, using a product, working on a project – every application of time, money or energy – is an investment decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a framework for thinking about investment: cost plus opportunity cost must be less than expected value. Or, to put it the other way: expected value must be greater than cost plus opportunity cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expressed in symbols: &lt;strong&gt;V &amp;gt; C + O.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s run through one of those decisions…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: Should we hire someone?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Well, how much do they cost in dollars (salary + equity + incentives + overhead)? Okay, X dollars a year. How much do they cost in time (including recruiting, setup and ongoing communications)? Approximately how much does all of that time cost, if you put a dollar number, Y, to it? Okay, add X to Y get the cost, C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now comes the hard part: estimate the opportunity cost. Who else could we hire? What else could we buy? Or what else could we build? What else is competing for C dollars? Of those alternatives, estimate their expected values then subtract their costs to calculate their expected profits. Take the highest positive number and call that option B: the next best alternative.  Opportunity cost is the profit forgone from the next best alternative, or O = V(next best) – C(next best).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: Should we continue to employ someone? Should I use your product? Should I pay for your service? Should I spend time with you? Should I invest in your startup? Should I start this company? Should I keep working on this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: Repeat the thought process above. The same framework applies to many different contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why decisions are complicated&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it’s such a simple formula, then why are some decisions so complicated?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are at least three reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Liquidity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liquidity - the ability to trade something for cash - is an acute constraint on the cost variable in the formula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have capital?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it takes years before the expected value pays off. Can you shoulder the costs long enough to receive the benefits? Can you afford to pay them right now and keep paying them as long as it will take for them to pay for themselves?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what capital is for. To solve the company&amp;#39;s liquidity problem, you have to sell debt or equity. The amount and terms you’re able to raise depend on how capital markets, specifically the investors which make the market, perceive the risks associated with your company and ‘the deal’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can you back out?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many decisions can’t be reversed, or only with a penalty. That’s unfortunate, because when circumstances change, so do the variables. Costs, opportunity costs, and expected values go up or down. But you can’t always double down when times are good and pull out when times are bad, or when a more attractive opportunity shows up.  Cash investors in a startup cannot generally back out early or easily. And sweat equity investors - the startup&amp;#39;s team - can&amp;#39;t either.  The natural and inherent inability of all the investors to back out quickly and regain liquidity has critical consequences on the framework for decision making in startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have time?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The first rule in business is to never run out of money.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What’s the second rule?”&lt;/em&gt;, I asked.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Never run out of money!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone once told me that. I promptly forgot it, but it’s a lesson that life doesn’t let you forget for very long. For me, the day of reckoning has come and gone three times now, once per financing. When it’s over, and the money is in the bank, it’s such a relief. Running out of money is running out of time, which is a stressful experience. Ahead of you, there’s a looming ‘cliff’ - that date, that ‘dead’ line - after which you can’t make payroll. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process is not fun, but it&amp;#39;s inherent in the game. Until a startup has established its unit economics - its cost per user/customer acquisition and lifetime value per user/customer - and shown that it can continue to raise venture financing as a &amp;ldquo;scale-up&amp;rdquo;, it will always be racing towards a cliff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it’s not true that if things are going well, you can always raise more money. It &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; true that if things are going well and there’s plenty of money in the bank so that they will &lt;em&gt;keep&lt;/em&gt; going well, that you can always raise more money. Liquidity is no joke. When you run out of money, you run out of moves. The runway ends before you can take off. Game over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another wise piece of advice I once heard: “Create options, then make decisions.” To that, I would like to add: “Improve your options, then improve your decisions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taken together, this advice adds up. Let’s pull it together…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liquidity is about scarcity and runway.  The lack of liquidity for investments in a startup means cash from investors is justifiably scarce.  And it can only provide liquidity for a limited time, giving you a certain amount of runway. Without that liquidity, you can’t make decisions, even good ones. Liquidity buys you time. Without options, you can’t make decisions. So spend the time creating options. Then, improve your options and your decisions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; That’s a recipe for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Asymmetry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asymmetry is about expanding the opportunity cost variable in the formula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In economic literature, information asymmetry refers to principals and agents, but its a subset of a larger class of problems caused by imperfect information. In this essay, I&amp;#39;d like to explore the asymmetry between a decision maker and reality, which is immense and complex, such that the cost of acquiring more information is very high, upward curving, and ultimately infinite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s an infinite amount of information. You have access to a tiny fraction of it. When you make decisions, you’re dealing with imperfect knowledge. The decision you’re weighing is infinitely more complex than you will ever know, or need to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say, for example, your startup has just received enough funding to make some additional hires, and you set out to hire your first marketing person. Suppose you reach out to ten marketing people, three become serious discussions, and you hire one. By pulling the trigger, though, you were also, by definition, ruling out every other eligible marketing candidate on the planet for that role. You were comfortable doing that, because, of course, you were not willing to interview them all, and you judged that your sample size of ten was sufficient. You knew that you might be missing out on some incredibly superior candidate who’s out there – somewhere - but your sense for how hard it would be to find that candidate and how very few exist is such that you’re comfortable pulling the trigger on the candidate in front of you. But what if you’re wrong? What if you didn’t look far enough, or in the right places? What if an incremental increase in time invested upfront in looking beyond your immediate network would have uncovered a trove of talent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We acquire information in order to create and improve our options. Your sense for the opportunity cost of a decision is based on the very limited information you have about all the possible alternatives. Making decisions with limited information is an art. The mature response to “the information problem” is not to get squeamish when you don’t have enough information to make a perfectly informed decision. Rather, it’s probably to identify which data points, of those available, are most operative to making a decision, and then, if those are not sufficient, to identify which data points, of those necessary but not available, will be cheapest to acquire. Then, the game becomes getting the right information, and getting it rapidly and at lowest cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which begs the question - how? I use three processes to support my overall strategy: networking, canvassing and landscaping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Networking&lt;/em&gt; is an art. I don’t profess to be a master. However, I do dislike the stereotype of the charismatic-hustler-schmoozer-wheeler-dealer-connector-talker that some people associate with sales people. Many people who profess to be salespeople are decent at one or two aspects, but may not get the rest. They may be acting as pawns instead of queens. It’s not enough to make a move; one has to comprehend the entire board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By meeting lots of new people, you are acquiring information. Every individual is a data point on the grid. The more data points, the more complete your understanding of reality and the fewer your blind spots. You are also creating an option, because friendly relationships don’t have an expiration date. Once you’ve established rapport, respect and trust with someone, and you become their friend, you can lean on them, at any point in the future, for information, advice, perspectives, ideas, introductions, help, opportunities and even capital - as long as the relationship is maintained. Not every relationship is lucrative, but every relationship has potential upside. It’s an option. Preserving and expanding your optionality is wise. And it’s a two way street…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s suppose that you know 50 venture capitalists, but you don’t know any current high school students. Then, you happen to take a short plane flight with a venture capitalist and a high school student, but you can only sit with one. To maximize your benefit, which do you choose? Now, obviously, there are unknown variables here, so there’s no right answer, but I’d like to make a case for the high school student. There is marginal benefit in meeting an additional VC, but there’s a lot of valuable information built-in to the high school student that you don’t currently have access to. High school students are a blind spot for you. If, for whatever reason, you someday need to design a product for them, or recruit them as interns, or be aware of trends in popular culture or public education or any number of intersections that this individual represents, albeit, with a sample size of one, then you could get back in touch. Repeat this exercise with Norwegians, salsa dancers, gun control lobbyists, material scientists and Franciscan priests…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Canvassing&lt;/em&gt; is asking questions of others systematically to gain information, perspectives, advice and insights to achieve what I called &amp;ldquo;parallax&amp;rdquo; in a &lt;a href="http://francispedraza.com/create-parallax"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;. So while you network, you’re extracting information. Earlier this week I found myself standing next to a Franciscan priest from Italy while standing in line waiting for a bus at JFK. Through the conversation I learned a lot of interesting information about the Catholic Church. So, if networking is about going broad - knowing more people - canvassing is going deep - knowing people more. To be good at it, you have to be curious and fascinated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expand your network, ask them questions, gain more information - then what? Then, you put all of this information together into a coherent understanding of reality. I call that process &lt;em&gt;Landscaping&lt;/em&gt;. It’s like an exercise in cartography: this is my map and here are the mountains, here are the rivers, the Black Forest and beyond here, there be dragons… Or, it can be likened to finding new puzzle pieces, then fitting them together. Landscaping lends itself to spending lots of time alone to think, read and write. New information and perspectives can be gained from conversations with others, but ultimately landscaping is about putting it all together into a story that makes sense about the world and the way it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spending time on these three activities should expand your opportunity costs. You’ll increasingly realize that for every thing you do, you are choosing not to do many other worthy things. And the more options you create, the higher the likely value of the best option, and the greater the foregone profit of the next best option.  An ironic take away might be: “At all costs, expand opportunity costs!” Even though deliberately increasing the “cost” side of the equation by increasing opportunity costs seems counter-intuitive, it’s what great business leaders do. It forces the bar ever higher for the value side of the equation, so that when they do decide to invest time and resources, it’s very high leverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Subjectivity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subjectivity is inherent in calculating the expected value variable in the formula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sake of argument, so far we’ve assumed that human beings are rational actors, which isn’t exactly right. Are they irrational, then? No, they’re not. When economists talk about “rational” actors, they are referencing the classic textbook definition: calculated profit-seeking. But money is a store of value, so profit-seeking is only a subset of value-seeking, and value is fundamentally subjective. Let’s think about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is valuable to you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not value what you value. If we did, we would be the same. But we are not the same, we are different. We want and care about different things because we see the world in different ways. We may have some things in common, but not everything. And that’s why we trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figuring out what you truly value is a process of self-discovery. Why are you starting this business? If you succeed, what will it do for you? What do I want more of in my life? Given all that I could be doing, why is this the best use of my time? Given trade-offs between freedom and security, or work-life balance and financial success, what would I choose? Ask yourself enough questions like this and you’ll quickly uncover your own philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is valuable to others?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No two people value things precisely the same way, but there is usually a fair amount of overlap. Even if there weren’t, there would still be gains from trade. You want this? I want your money. I give you this, you give me your money. Prices coordinate supply and demand. Demand is subjective, so prices coordinate subjective inputs and make them visible, coordinating action across time for vast numbers of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figuring out what is valuable to large groups of other people is a lucrative skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are there social, cultural and emotional complications?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you give the job to your friend, or the more qualified outsider? Do you invest in the startup you love, or the startup that’s going to make your limited partners more money? Do you do what your told, or stand up for what you believe? Are you passionate about what you do every day, or do you just show up for the check?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subjectivity brings color to a colorless ledger of profit and loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Justifying your decision to yourself and others&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the formula? Expected value must be greater than cost plus opportunity cost: V &amp;gt; C + O. It is a framework as disarming in its simplicity as it is enchanting in its complexity.  The nuances, caveats, subjective inputs and infinite information that form the context for every investment decision must ultimately be weighed in the balance by you - the decision maker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I wrote this, the image that kept coming to mind was that of a pole vaulter. Sprinting down the track, every muscle pumping, then planting the pole, leaping off the ground and catapulting into mid-air. In that moment, there’s one question: will you get high enough to clear the hurdle? Get ready - you are that pole vaulter. That hurdle is your opportunity cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That formula is the test. Your business (and your life, for that matter) has to pass the test. Again and again and again. If you’re an entrepreneur, you know what it’s like. You pitch. Not just once, or dozens, or hundreds - but thousands upon thousands of times. Yesterday I had seven meetings and three phone calls. In every single one of those, I had to help other people see that the expected value of what I wanted them to do (invest, partner, etc.) was greater than their cost and opportunity cost. They’re not me, so they don’t necessarily value what I value. Every person asks different questions and has different reservations. Patterns emerge in these conversations – which you revisit, prompting you to reconsider your logic again and again. You have to justify your investment decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your business is your thesis. It is your ultimate answer to how you will create value, both for yourself and for others, both now and in the future. It is your grand statement, your philosophy in motion, your logic incarnate. Given all the costs. Given all the opportunity costs. Given all the context and considerations. Given the world in which you find yourself. Given you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answer the question: WHAT IS VALUABLE?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This. This is what is valuable. This, this, this!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you work on, speaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speak your passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/91fvjYI6q7E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://francispedraza.com/your-business-is-your-thesis</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:sash,2012:Post/having-two-mothers</id>
    <published>2013-03-26T12:20:57-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T12:20:57-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/suzH_TfemAE/having-two-mothers" />
    <author>
      <name>Sash MacKinnon</name>
      <uri>http://sashmackinnon.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>What it's like to have gay parents</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/13/pope-francis-gay-marriage-anti_n_2869221.html"&gt;&amp;ldquo;At stake is the identity and survival of the family: father, mother and children. At stake are the lives of many children who will be discriminated against in advance, and deprived of their human development given by a father and a mother and willed by God.” 
- Pope Francis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was born into a family with two mothers, Laurie and Kerrie. I wasn&amp;#39;t adopted; I was conceived through artificial insemination using donor sperm. My parents fell in love and went through the process in the late 80&amp;#39;s, which was pretty controversial at the time. I&amp;#39;ve met many other children who were conceived the same way, but they were always younger, conceived after it had become more socially acceptable. The only thing I was told about my father is the color of his hair. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mum and Kerrie are both female feminist family therapists so I have never exactly had a father figure in my life. Despite this, our family was incredibly close&amp;ndash;I grew up in an environment where I became used to telling my parents everything and receiving unconditional love in return. When I was young, I used to pretend to be sick during school so I could spend the day with Mum or Kerrie at work. I&amp;#39;ve never met another family as close as ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often asked me, &amp;quot;Do you think not having a father changed you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I had graduated from high school, my parents asked me to come into the kitchen to listen to a talk show on the radio with them. There was a South Australian politician who was avidly preaching that &amp;ldquo;Gay parents are discriminating against their children by taking away their right to a father&amp;rdquo;, which would &amp;ldquo;handicap them in later life&amp;rdquo;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The radio opened up to viewer discussion and I called in, furious. While I waited on hold, I began to shakily scribble what I would say on a discarded piece of paper. I&amp;#39;ve kept it to this day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;#39;ve heard you talk very passionately and at great length about discrimination against children, but you haven&amp;#39;t talked about how you&amp;#39;ve come to this conclusion. Are you close to families where you have experienced, first hand, the negative effects of gay parenting? Are you referencing research? And, what do you even mean by discrimination: mental wellbeing, family relationships, success in life? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From where I stand it seems as though you are simply stating an opinion, one which is not based in research or anecdote. And from that single, subjective, uninformed opinion, you are trying to enforce policy that will affect the entire country&amp;#39;s perspective on my family.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was never taken off hold. When the show ended, Laurie, Kerrie and I sat in silence. It was only then that I realized my voice would never be heard&amp;ndash;people were so busy listening to politicians and priests that they forgot to ask the children what having gay parents was actually like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no doubt society that will one day accept gay marriage, but before it does we have to collectively change how we think. Right now, opinions are used interchangeably with facts. We often fail to look at things holistically, to look at the evidence and reason, to differentiate between fact and opinion.  We lose sight of the fact that we are individuals and that other people with other experiences may feel differently. We get so caught up in our own rationalization that we forget to ask how others feel. Subjectivity is the root of all discrimination. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was four years old, I remember complaining to my Mum. I whined &amp;ldquo;Mum, I wish I had a Dad&amp;rdquo;. She was shocked, and in retrospect, I can understand why. She must have felt worried that despite all her love, there was some fundmental truth to the discrimination in society. Maybe she had made a mistake. Maybe children did need fathers. She looked down and cautiously asked me &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grinned at her &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;That way he could go to work and I could spend all day with you and Kerrie!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/suzH_TfemAE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sashmackinnon.com/having-two-mothers</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:sohail,2012:Post/fantasy-vc</id>
    <published>2013-03-26T10:07:48-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T10:07:48-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/V9-6sHuZQOw/fantasy-vc" />
    <author>
      <name>Sohail Prasad</name>
      <uri>http://sohailprasad.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Fantasy VC</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;People who can&amp;#39;t own their own sports teams play fantasy sports. People who can&amp;#39;t invest in the stock market do virtual trading. Why should I be left out? I decided that I&amp;#39;m going to publish my list of investing picks (that I&amp;#39;ve kept private up til now), so that in the future I can (and you can) look back and see how I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make it more realistic, I&amp;#39;m giving myself ~$3M/year to invest &amp;ndash; that&amp;#39;ll keep me honest and help make me decide &lt;em&gt;how much&lt;/em&gt; I like each company, not just that I like them (which is important from an investor&amp;#39;s perspective). I&amp;#39;m including the date picked as that&amp;#39;s relevant to finding startups &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goals are to identify both super successful and undervalued companies, before they becomes &amp;ldquo;obviously successful.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;#39;ll be attending YC Alumni Demo Day and meeting with a bunch of people in the tech community, because I do that anyway. Disclosures and notes at bottom. I can&amp;#39;t currently afford to act on these, but if you do &amp;amp; make any profit, feel free to share. Some day in the future, I hope to put my money where my mouth is &lt;em&gt;(want to make that happen? let&amp;#39;s talk)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;By Date:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width="340" height="500&amp;#39;" frameborder="0" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/pub?key=0AslSowLKvgNIdFlJbDg0eFRXZk1ramFWTHpxWXZkZlE&amp;amp;single=true&amp;amp;gid=0&amp;amp;output=html&amp;amp;widget=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Year Totals:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;: $1.25M YTD (Balanced, Scoot Networks, Thalmic Labs, WeFunder, StyleUp, FlightCar, BitNami, Teespring, Screenhero, Prizeo, Zenefits, Lawdingo, Goldbely, Medisas, Stealth YC W13 Startup, Stealth YC W13 Startup)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;: $3M (Dwolla, Exec, Postmates, Crowdtilt, Karma, FundersClub, Virool, Instacart, Sponsorfied, Tracks.by, SideCar, OrderAhead, Coinbase, Clever, GitHub, Filepicker.io, Eligible, Amicus, AdRoll, Digg, Pocket, Upstart, Svbtle, Duolingo, LendUp, PayTango)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;: $3.1M (Rapportive, Bump Technologies, BankSimple, SoundCloud, Greplin, Hipmunk, Getaround, Friend.ly, Flipboard, Pulse, Viralheat, Chartboost, Gumroad, Stripe, Betterment, FreedomPop, Wealthfront)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Undated&lt;/strong&gt;: (Square, Uber, Twilio)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;
Disclosure: I currently have no financial positions in any of these companies, though many of them are founded by people I&amp;#39;m lucky to call my friends. If I could invest, this is where I&amp;#39;d put my money.
&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/V9-6sHuZQOw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sohailprasad.com/fantasy-vc</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/your-startups-10-most-important-metrics</id>
    <published>2013-03-26T06:03:03-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T06:03:03-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/cND_dxLihJs/your-startups-10-most-important-metrics" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Your Startup's 10 Most Important Metrics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24557450864274_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24557450864274_raw.jpg" alt="ruler.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the analytics tools today, it&amp;#39;s easy to measure hundreds if not thousands of different metrics for your business. Cutting through all the chaff to determine the most important or insightful metrics can be quite a challenge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are the ten metrics I&amp;#39;ve found to be most useful in board meetings. They answer the questions of how should a startup founder might measuring the business at the highest level. You should have many more metrics than these, but I&amp;#39;ve highlighted the ones that I recommend presenting to your board and reviewing each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Metrics Format&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clear data leads to productive conversations.  To best understand a data point and its implications, we have to put it in context. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve found dividing top level data in three slides, one for company priority (Distribution, Engagement, Revenue) helps to set the right context. Within the slide, a table that shows the metric and compares it to last month, then explicitly calculates the monthly change, the trailing six month average and finally compares the metric to the goal best communicates the state of that metric. See below for an example. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table width="100%"&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Metric
&lt;td&gt;This month
&lt;td&gt;Last Month
&lt;td&gt;% change
&lt;td&gt;TSM Average
&lt;td&gt;Goal
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Active Users&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;125%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Total User Base&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TSM Average column is the Trailing Six Month Compound Growth Rate. It is calculated in this way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(ending_value/starting_value)^(1/num_periods-1)-1.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most businesses, a monthly growth percent is too volatile to be meaningful. However the TSM Average smooths out the monthly change. Comparing the monthly to the TSM, we can get a sense of whether the monthly growth is accelerating or decelerating and how it compares to the goal you set each quarter. In this example, the total user growth was slower this month than in the past six month, but activity is way up. The next question, the one board members and founders should ask, is why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Metrics/Question Pairs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the base format of the metrics, let&amp;#39;s talk about which metrics matter. Each metric is followed by the question it&amp;#39;s designed to answer. Pick the ones that are relevant to your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Distribution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New users added last month by channel/TSM growth rate:&lt;/strong&gt; How are well are we growing the user base? Which user sources are the best?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total user base/TSM growth rate: &lt;/strong&gt;How important is our monthly growth compared to our total user base?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost of customer acquisition, lifetime value, pay back period:&lt;/strong&gt; Can we grow faster through paid acquisition? Are we acquiring customers profitably? How much can we afford to spend on new customers? How is this changing over time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active users (can defined in several different ways depending on your product) by channel/TSM growth rate:&lt;/strong&gt; Are we getting better at giving our customers what they want/need? Which channels of users are most effective in finding us the right kind of user?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;% of users using top 3 key features in a given month: &lt;/strong&gt;Are our product initiatives the right ones?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Revenue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue / TSM Revenue growth: &lt;/strong&gt;Are we growing our revenue?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conversion to paid rate in that month/by cohort: &lt;/strong&gt;How many users converted to paid? Are we improving our ability to convert customers to paid?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avg spend per paying customer of a managed account vs solo account: &lt;/strong&gt;What is the impact of the account management team?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Churn rate/ TSM Churn rate:&lt;/strong&gt; How well do we retain our customers?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Burn rate: &lt;/strong&gt;When are we profitable? When do we run out of cash? When do we need to raise?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the metrics that have been most valuable/insightful for me working with our companies. &lt;a href="http://branch.com/b/your-startup-s-10-most-important-metrics"&gt;Let me know if there are other metrics you use to measure your business that might be useful to add to this list on this Branch&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/cND_dxLihJs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/your-startups-10-most-important-metrics</feedburner:origLink></entry>
</feed>
