<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xml:lang="en-US">
  <id>tag:svbtle.com,2012:/feed</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://svbtle.com" />
  
  <title>Svbtle Featured</title>
  <updated>2013-03-19T09:00:51-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Svbtle.com</name>
    <uri>http://svbtle.com</uri>
    <email>hello@svbtle.com</email>
  </author>
  <generator>Svbtle.com</generator>
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/svbtle" /><feedburner:info uri="svbtle" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><entry>
    <id>tag:jamietie,2012:Post/hypocrisy-cowardice-and-the-Cherokee-Scout</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T09:00:51-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T09:00:51-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/OyrD3tu4xjA/hypocrisy-cowardice-and-the-Cherokee-Scout" />
    <author>
      <name>Jamie Kelly</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jamietie.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Hypocrisy, cowardice and the Cherokee Scout</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;#39;t really surprise me when &lt;em&gt;Cherokee Scout&lt;/em&gt; editor Robert Horne &lt;a href="http://jimromenesko.typepad.com/my-blog/2013/03/north-carolina-editor-who-made-controversial-gun-request-resigns.html"&gt;resigned&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes you do something and it renders you ineffective. He did the right thing, and it cost him his job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least he can leave North Carolina with his head held high, and with some well-deserved kudos from his publisher:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We wish Robert well in all his future endeavors,&amp;rdquo; said David Brown, publisher of the Scout and Journal. &amp;ldquo;He&amp;#39;s a good man who has done a lot of positive things for the area that should be remembered.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brown on the other hand, gets to stay in North Carolina and hang his head in shame. That shame isn&amp;#39;t just because he &lt;a href="http://blog.jamietie.com/in-defense-of-publishing-data-on-gun-ownership"&gt;backed down and licked the sheriff&amp;#39;s boots when confronted with controversy&lt;/a&gt;. No, he gets even more shame because of the ad he posted today on &lt;a href="http://www.journalismjobs.com/Job_Listing.cfm?JobID=1477263"&gt;JournalismJobs.com&lt;/a&gt;. That ad begins:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you always wanted to be the editor so you can order the rest of the newsroom around while challenging the community with your extreme political views? Then this isn&amp;#39;t the job for you. Instead, we&amp;#39;re looking for an editor who knows how to tell good stories&amp;mdash;the kind people will always make time to read&amp;mdash;from breaking news to heartwarming features to in-depth reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High praise indeed for Horne, who&amp;#39;d been out the door for fewer than three weeks. It&amp;#39;s another sad but not surprising sign that community journalism&amp;mdash;the kind where so many reporters and editors learn their craft&amp;mdash;is often no longer concerned with standing up for the public&amp;#39;s right to know, no longer interested in holding elected officials to account, and no longer interested in the kind of journalism that can actually change a community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/jamietie_24545715367176_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_jamietie_24545715367176_raw.jpg" alt="cloud.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(The next front page story in the &lt;em&gt;Scout&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing for openness, access and accountability are not extreme political views. They are, or they should be, the very foundation of a local newspaper. Shame on Brown for betraying that, and shame on any other editor, publisher or owner who would do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And perhaps the saddest part is that the damage&amp;mdash;if, indeed, there was any&amp;mdash;is already done. Anything Brown does no won&amp;#39;t have any effect on the people who&amp;#39;d decided the paper wanted to come for their guns. All it does is tell the people who had supported the paper before and the rest of the journalism community, that there is no principle Brown will hold to, given the right amount of pressure. That&amp;#39;s a sad message to send and an even sadder one to receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/OyrD3tu4xjA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jamietie.com/hypocrisy-cowardice-and-the-Cherokee-Scout</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:adii,2012:Post/success-measured-in-relevance</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T04:53:53-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T04:53:53-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/Jfpai-j67-E/success-measured-in-relevance" />
    <author>
      <name>Adii Pienaar</name>
      <uri>http://adii.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Success Measured In Relevance</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The answer comes down to one simple question – relevance. Many entrepreneurs don’t want to just be successful. They want to be relevant. And they want to stay relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Being relevant means people pay attention to you, care about what you have to say and talk about you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Money alone can’t buy relevance.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/today/post/article/20130317133520-1714080-when-is-it-ok-to-bash-a-founder"&gt;This is from a recent Michael Lazerow post&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; it reminded me a little of one of my personal needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In broad terms, &lt;a href="http://adii.me/happiness-success"&gt;happiness means success to me&lt;/a&gt;. But I&amp;#39;m also happy when I feel relevant; not just in professional life, but also my personal life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to be heard, I want to be validated and &lt;a href="http://adii.me/youre-born-an-entrepreneur"&gt;I want the opportunity to just be me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#39;t some narcissistic thing that only a elite few people experience either; I bet if you ask yourself why you get up in the morning to work on whatever, somewhere within that reason there&amp;#39;s the need to be relevant. Everyone wants to be proud of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shit thing about relevance however is that it&amp;#39;s very difficult to measure without doing so by the feedback of peers, which means you can&amp;#39;t control that. You don&amp;#39;t just wake up in the morning and feel relevant without getting that external feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So how do you measure relevance (and indirectly, success) in a way that you can control yourself?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/Jfpai-j67-E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://adii.me/success-measured-in-relevance</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:youssef,2012:Post/what-were-they-thinking</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T21:22:51-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T21:22:51-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/SiH2vtr-uMA/what-were-they-thinking" />
    <author>
      <name>Youssef Sarhan</name>
      <uri>http://sefsar.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>You thought Samsung was misogynistic? Blu Products just set a new standard</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier today I read &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/18/4100006/why-blu-products-can-beat-samsung"&gt;a post on The Verge&lt;/a&gt; about a &amp;ldquo;tiny, Florida-based phone maker that thinks it can beat Samsung&amp;rdquo;. I was interested, so I did some research on the company, Blu Products. I wanted to see if they really have what it takes to beat Samsung. Fortunately for Samsung, it appears they do. Yes, fortunately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, Samsung got a &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/18/4119052/samsung-weird-behind-the-scenes-of-the-sexist-galaxy-s4-launch"&gt;little weird&lt;/a&gt; on us. Not quite &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/1/8/3850056/qualcomms-insane-ces-2013-keynote-pictures-tweets"&gt;Qualcomm weird&lt;/a&gt;, but certainly weird. However, tonight I came across something that makes everything before it seem so acceptable, some might say admirable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my pleasure(?) to introduce Blu Products&amp;#39; understanding of marketing. In the following video, you will witness what I can only describe as prostitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="550" height="309" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/0mVrCxNe7uc?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video speaks for itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between this, &lt;a href="http://sefsar.com/terrible-copywriting-on-applecom"&gt;Apple&amp;#39;s &amp;ldquo;Why iPhone&amp;rdquo; page&lt;/a&gt;, last weeks Samsung event, the &lt;a href="http://sefsar.com/nokia-faked-the-still-photos-too"&gt;fake Nokia Lumia 920 photos&lt;/a&gt;, the Qualcomm pageantry and &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/HO7aX7vt7Qs"&gt;this horrible music video featuring Blackberry executives&lt;/a&gt; there is strong empirical evidence to suggest that the classiness of a company&amp;#39;s marketing is an accurate barometer of fiscal success within the mobile handset industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t stop laughing, I don&amp;#39;t even know why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case it wasn&amp;#39;t obvious, Blu Products used an iPhone in that advert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24545982530322_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24545982530322_raw.png" alt="iphone.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/SiH2vtr-uMA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sefsar.com/what-were-they-thinking</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jamietie,2012:Post/media-rape-culture-victim-blaming-and-stuebenville</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T12:39:57-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T12:39:57-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/rWw8xtn1-5Q/media-rape-culture-victim-blaming-and-stuebenville" />
    <author>
      <name>Jamie Kelly</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jamietie.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Media, rape culture, victim blaming and Steubenville</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine asked an insightful question on &lt;a href="http://fancycwabs.com/post/45685158350/in-which-our-intrepid-adventurer-is-confused"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; about how we&amp;#39;ve gotten to the point where young men would feel that raping an unconscious woman is acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of rape is unfathomable to me: I can’t wrap my brain around what would drive a man to put his penis into something that wasn’t actively interested in having a penis put into it. What drives a person, seeing an unconscious person, to think “you know what sounds like a good idea? Putting my penis into that person.”&lt;br&gt;
Where did we fall apart as a society to a degree where shoving your dong into people became a thing? Where our sexual response is so screwed up that uninterested people give us raging boners? Have we gotten ourselves so twisted up with sexual taboos and edicts that we demonize consensual behavior and give genuinely fucked up actions a pass? Are dudes being somehow taught that the world somehow owes them orgasms? That they’re out there, waiting to be plucked from a tree like a piece of fruit?&lt;br&gt;
Am I missing some critical part of male upbringing that was supposed to condition me to get aroused in the presence of unwilling partners?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, it is not at all inconceivable to many people. More than &lt;a href="http://www.rainn.org/get-information/statistics/frequency-of-sexual-assault"&gt;200,000 people are raped each year&lt;/a&gt;, and that&amp;#39;s despite the fact rape has decreased by more than 60 percent since 1993. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about that for a second: Even with historic declines in rape, one person is sexually assaulted every two minutes in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So rape is certainly conceivable to so very many people. And the punishment they face is often non-existent. According to the Rape, Abuse &amp;amp; Incest National Network and U.S. Justice Department statistics, &lt;a href="http://www.rainn.org/get-information/statistics/reporting-rates"&gt;97 percent of rapists never spend a day in prison&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps that&amp;#39;s one of the reasons a CNN anchor felt such sympathy for the two Stuebenville boys sentenced for raping a 16-year-old: A trial, let alone a conviction and sentence, is vanishingly 
rare in cases of rape and sexual assault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/jamietie_24545420515980_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_jamietie_24545420515980_raw.jpg" alt="Jailedrapists.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(Source: &lt;a href="http://www.rainn.org/get-information/statistics/reporting-rates"&gt;RAINN.org&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And part of that is because of the attitudes we&amp;#39;ve seen around the Stuebenville case. The &lt;a href="http://publicshaming.tumblr.com/post/45635407944/the-victim-blaming-slut-shaming-reactions-to-the"&gt;Public Shaming tumblr&lt;/a&gt; pointed to a lot of reactions blaming the victim for drinking, dressing provocatively, and for simply being present. One even suggested that Mays and Richmond did what any man would do when presented with an unconscious woman: they assaulted her. Thankfully every man does not act that way, but too many do. And they&amp;#39;re defended for doing so. One blog post (which I&amp;#39;m refusing to link to&amp;mdash;trolls thrive on links) suggested that the fact the victim was drinking, dressed provocatively, and around young men meant that her consent was implied. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is the logical equivalent of suggesting that someone driving on New Year&amp;#39;s Eve who is killed by a drunk driver was asking to be killed because he or she should have known better than to be out when it was dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this falls under the idea of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rape_culture"&gt;Rape Culture&lt;/a&gt;, where sexual assault is common, rarely punished, and treated as a minor offense. And when news organizations lament sentences for rapists as life ruining&amp;mdash;even when they&amp;#39;re really no such thing, as the pair will spend one to two years in juvenile detention, and at most be held through their 21st birthdays (they are 16 and 17 now), and Ohio&amp;#39;s adult justice system prescribes a minimum sentence of five years for rape&amp;mdash;they are contributing to that culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A responsible media organization, and as much as this truly pains me to say, a good example of that in this case is &lt;a href="http://gawker.com/5991003/cnn-reports-on-the-promising-future-of-the-steubenville-rapists-who-are-very-good-students"&gt;Gawker&lt;/a&gt;, would point out that the true solution to rape isn&amp;#39;t for women to stay home, stay sober, and dress in whatever passes for conservatively, it&amp;#39;s for people &lt;strong&gt;not to rape other people.&lt;/strong&gt; And it would make clear that no matter how drunk, or how she was dressed, or what the situation is, a woman has the absolute and total right not to be raped. That should be the lesson the Stuebenville story is teaching the world. Instead, thanks to CNN and legions of Internet rape apologists, we&amp;#39;re left with the same backward, misogynistic ideas we&amp;#39;ve always had. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/rWw8xtn1-5Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jamietie.com/media-rape-culture-victim-blaming-and-stuebenville</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jonrussell,2012:Post/geeks-on-a-plane-is-coming-to-southeast-asia</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T12:05:12-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T12:05:12-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/jys4yK4dsj0/geeks-on-a-plane-is-coming-to-southeast-asia" />
    <author>
      <name>Jon Russell</name>
      <uri>http://insidethenoodlebowl.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>'Geeks On A Plane' is coming to Southeast Asia</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://500.co/2013/03/13/this-summers-biggest-blockbuster-geeks-on-a-plane-southeast-asia/"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is pretty exciting news for Southeast Asia:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mission at 500 is to find incredible entrepreneurs wherever they are –  whether they’re in Silicon Valley, New York, or Thailand. Big things are happening in Southeast Asia (SEA), and we’re proud to announce that Geeks on a Plane will make its very first trip to SEA this June!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geeks on a Plane SEA will take place June 1st – June 15th and will be making stops in Singapore, Kuala Lumpur, Bangkok, and Jakarta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The region has the potential to grow to number hundreds of millions of Internet-crazed, mobile-first consumers, and I definitely think it is one for &lt;a href="http://insidethenoodlebowl.com/us-investors-showing-greater-interest-in-southeast-asia"&gt;US investors to at least get to know more about&lt;/a&gt;, if not begin focusing on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m looking forward to seeing the GOAP tour come to my city, Bangkok, it&amp;#39;s really quite hard to believe how much more vibrant the tech scene here is today. Yet there&amp;#39;s still plenty more development to come, perhaps aided by 500 Startups and GOAP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/asia/2013/03/17/geeks-on-a-plane-southeast-asia/"&gt;For more info see the TNW write-up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/jys4yK4dsj0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://insidethenoodlebowl.com/geeks-on-a-plane-is-coming-to-southeast-asia</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:cap,2012:Post/switching-from-rss-to-twitter</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T11:19:53-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T11:19:53-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/4R8giFr_oG8/switching-from-rss-to-twitter" />
    <author>
      <name>Cap Watkins</name>
      <uri>http://blog.capwatkins.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Switching from RSS to Twitter</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the recent news that Google is shutting down Google Reader, I decided to give Twitter feeds a try as a replacement. It&amp;#39;s been a few days now and I wanted to outline a few of the pros and cons, just in case anyone is considering making the switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little about my setup first: I chose to start a new Twitter account vs. using Twitter lists. Maybe it&amp;#39;s unnecessary complexity, but it seems pretty obvious that, like DMs, Twitter wishes Lists didn&amp;#39;t exist and would kill them if it could (and may still). I have a feeling they&amp;#39;re not apt to kill the ability to follow people anytime soon, so I opted for a second account. Using Lists would certainly make sharing easier (and Tweetbot has amazing Lists support), but I&amp;#39;m comfortable with the trade-off. Do whichever you like best! Anyway, here we go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro: One less app&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh man, this was an unintended consequence, but feels really, really good. Reeder is an amazing application, but getting to remove it from my Mac dock and iPhone homescreen gave me that one-less-thing feeling. I&amp;#39;m a pretty habitual organizer and consolidator, and know some people couldn&amp;#39;t care any less about that sort of thing. So yeah, your mileage may vary. I loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro: Simplified and synced feed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, this is a usage-specific nicety. I tend to always just press the &amp;ldquo;Unread&amp;rdquo; tab in Reeder and just work my way through the full list chronologically. This means scrolling to the very bottom and working my way up (new stuff is at the top in Reeder). That way I get to see the news evolve over the day and not piece it together in reverse. The beautiful thing about using Twitter (and Tweetbot specifically) is that no matter where I open the feed (Mac, iPhone, iPad), I&amp;#39;m a) synced to the last place I was and b) everything new is upward. It&amp;#39;s been like magic and has made me mad at myself for resisting trying this in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro: Sharing and starring are back!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, it&amp;#39;s Twitter. So yeah. Sharing and favoriting are the name of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Con: Not all the sites I followed on Reader have Twitter accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are few, but they definitely existed. I decided to try life without them and haven&amp;#39;t missed them very much at all. Kind of a good forced pruning tool, but would have been nice to have it be 1-to-1. This also limits me in the future if a new web site or blog doesn&amp;#39;t have a Twitter feed that links to their articles. Which brings me to the other con:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Con: Not all blog Twitter feeds are actually article links&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The example right off the top of my head is &lt;a href="http://www.swiss-miss.com/"&gt;swissmiss&lt;/a&gt;. Her RSS feed is one-to-one with her blog content (of course), but &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/swissmiss"&gt;her Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;, as far as I can tell, &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; links to her blog. It totally makes sense for that to be the case, but it just means I&amp;#39;m not receiving any ingress point to her content except to visit the web site directly (which, honestly, I&amp;#39;m probably not going to remember to do with any regularity).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;#39;ve started using Twitter for feeds, I&amp;#39;m unlikely to ever go back. The ease of sharing, Favoriting, Retweeting, sending to Instapaper, etc. not only match, but at times surpass even Reeder in terms of ease and simplicity. One less app to deal with is a win, not to mention that the links are ordered exactly as I like them (and holy crap, Tweetbot iCloud sync. So good).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1, wish I would have done this before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/4R8giFr_oG8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.capwatkins.com/switching-from-rss-to-twitter</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:maccman,2012:Post/analyzing-my-dna</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T09:47:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T09:47:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/Iy0-kom198Q/analyzing-my-dna" />
    <author>
      <name>Alex MacCaw</name>
      <uri>http://blog.alexmaccaw.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Analyzing my DNA</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently bought &lt;a href="http://23andme.com"&gt;23andme&lt;/a&gt;, a service which requires you to send off a DNA sample, and in return performs a series of interesting tests concerning your health and ancestry. I bought the test as a birthday present to myself, somewhat because I was interested in the results, but also because I wanted to treat it as a catalyst for learning more about the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have heard that a human&amp;#39;s genome is 98.5% identical to a chimpanzee&amp;#39;s. While this is true, the human genome contains over 3 billion base pairs, so just a one percent difference means that over 30 million nucleotides have changed. A single change in a base pair can dramatically alter the protein created, and easily account for the differences between our two species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans usually have 46 paired chromosomes, representing 23 chromosomes from each parent (hence the name 23andme). What&amp;#39;s interesting is that the older the species, the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_organisms_by_chromosome_count"&gt;more the chromosomes&lt;/a&gt;, or at least this is the trend. Some ferns, such as the adders-tounge, have 1440 chromosomes, whilst a mango has 40. As DNA replicates and mutates through generations, so more genes can be added. Indeed, our genome contains traces of &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-17809503"&gt;ancient dead viruses&lt;/a&gt;, introduced in a common ancestor over 100 million years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in the process of getting your DNA analyzed by 23andme, is to put a substantial amount of saliva into to a specialized container they mail you. This saliva contains cheek cells, which is what 23andme use for genotyping. They don&amp;#39;t need many cells, but the reason why they ask for so much saliva is so that it&amp;#39;s harder to take someone else&amp;#39;s DNA without their permission!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the DNA sample is mailed off to 23andme&amp;#39;s laboratory where it&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polymerase_chain_reaction"&gt;amplified through PCR&lt;/a&gt;, a process where the DNA is separated from the nucleus and replicated. Lastly it&amp;#39;s put through a machine which, rather than sequence the whole genome, looking for specific &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single-nucleotide_polymorphism"&gt;SNPs&lt;/a&gt;. These SNPs are responsible for a lot of the biological differences between people, and variations influence a variety of traits such as height, eye color and disease susceptibility. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now 23andme have analyzed about a million of your SNPs, it&amp;#39;s time to draw some conclusions from the genotyping. Most of the health and trait reports are based on genetic association studies, taking a specific SNP and testing for associations with factors like eye color and diseases like Parkinson&amp;#39;s. Furthermore, 23andme can correlate diseases and symptoms from all their users to specific SNPs, furthering research and understanding of how they affect our bodies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genetic associations are not a certainty that a specific SNP will have a specific outcome, but rather a probability. Correlations doesn&amp;#39;t mean causation either, and while there may be an association, additional research is needed to show whether the factor has a causal effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a bunch of heritable genetic disorders that 23andme tests carrier status for, such as Cystic Fibrosis. While the gene for Cystic Fibrosis is recessive, if you mate with someone who also has the same recessive gene, then the likelihood is that your child will develop the disease is one quater. Other disorders like Huntington&amp;#39;s are dominant, and only requires one parent to be a carrier. 23andme doesn&amp;#39;t seem to do much testing of dominant genetic disorders, as it&amp;#39;s likely that the parents are already aware of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working out how SNP affects a phenotype trait is tricky. Most SNP changes have no effect, while other characteristics are due to environmental factors. One way of investigating this, is by studying identical twins. Since they have the exact same DNA, any differences between the two can be attributed to environmental factors. Some phenotypes like height are mostly influenced by your genetics (assuming you have a good nutrition), while others like freckles are more affected by the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This difference between environmental and heritable traits is often called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nature_versus_nurture"&gt;nature vs nuture&lt;/a&gt;, and can be fairly controversial at times. Take, for example, IQ. The effect that parents have upon their children&amp;#39;s intelligence is in serious dispute and, while a neglectful and abusive upbringing can have an adverse effect, given a base minimum supportive parenting doesn&amp;#39;t have have much of an influence on IQ. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nature_versus_nurture#IQ_debate"&gt;Studies have shown&lt;/a&gt; that identical twins who grow up in separate families have an IQ correlation of 0.74, while adoptive siblings have no more similar IQ than strangers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not going to talk about the more sensitive health information I gleaned from the report, as while President Bush signed the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act I&amp;#39;m still wary of how it could affect my insurance in the future. However, let&amp;#39;s talk about a non sensitive trait, &lt;em&gt;lactose intolerance&lt;/em&gt;. Lactose intolerance is fairly heritable and is influenced by an SNP near the LCT gene which encodes lactase, an enzyme required for digestion of milk. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, the lactase enzyme is only produced in the first few years of a mammals life. However, certain European populations have a mutation that causes lactase to be produced throughout their lives. Dairy farming, which is widespread primarily in Europe, provided additional sources of nutrition to early inhabitants of Europe. Thus, it is thought, being able to drink milk throughout adulthood would have provided them with an evolutionary advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My genotype for this SNP is AG, or adenine and guanine. This has been correlated with higher adult lactase levels. This allele is rarer in Africa and Asia, hence the high cases of lactose intolerance in those regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SNP: rs4988235 (A or G)&lt;br&gt;
Alex&amp;#39;s Genotype: AG&lt;br&gt;
Gene: MCM6&lt;br&gt;
Chromosome: 2   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I say, while this trait is heritable, it is also influenced by environmental characteristics such as the bacteria in your gut. In other words, having a AG genotype doesn&amp;#39;t always mean you&amp;#39;ll be lactose tolerant, and vice versa. It&amp;#39;s all about probability, and in this case 23andme were correct - I am lactose tolerant, which is useful as I enjoy milk! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calculating ancestry through DNA is an interesting process, because it turns out that the variations between you and your ancestor&amp;#39;s DNA make it impossible to detect relations after a few generations or so. However the Y chromosome is passed down from father to son without much alteration, which means it makes a perfect candidate for looking into your past. Maternal descent is calculated from DNA found in the mitochondria, as this too is passed down unaltered from mother to child. Using these two pieces of information we can look hundreds of thousands of years into our past, as well as at our more recent history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ancestors, on both my mother&amp;#39;s and father&amp;#39;s side, are from Europe - mostly from the UK, Ireland and Scotland, with a little Spanish and German mix. My DNA is 2.9% neanderthal, which puts me in the top 91% of 23andme&amp;#39;s members (not sure what conclusions to draw from that!). I&amp;#39;m also distantly related to Jesse James on my mother&amp;#39;s side, and have found a previously unknown second cousin in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genetic family trees can be identified by looking at haplogroups, a set of genetic mutations that are shared by everyone in the group. The likelihood is that if you share a lot of specific genetic mutations with someone, than you&amp;#39;re related. All haplogroups can be traced back to a mutation in a single individual. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, 8 percent of asian males are in the &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1180246/"&gt;same haplogroup as Genghis Khan&lt;/a&gt;,  and carry Y chromosomes that share many of the same SNPs. Y chromosomes aren&amp;#39;t recombined when they&amp;#39;re inherited, so genetic mutations in them act as markers, allowing geneticists to trace them back and predict in time the moment they occurred. Such a rapid spread of this particular mutation is unlikely to have happened by chance, and suggests that 0.5% of the world&amp;#39;s population are descendants of Genghis Khan and his male relatives - quite a staggering amount. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geneticists can trace back humans to a single male and female, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Y-chromosomal_Adam"&gt;a genetic &amp;ldquo;Adam and Eve&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. What&amp;#39;s fascinating is that while Adam lived about 142,000 years ago, Eve lived much earlier, about 200,000 years ago - they never met each other. Y-chromosomal Adam lived at a time close to the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recent_African_origin_of_modern_humans"&gt;migration from Africa&lt;/a&gt;, and this turmoil could suggest a reason why so few males lineages survived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analyzing my DNA has given me a fascinating insight into my health and ancestry, and something I&amp;#39;d recommend to everyone. However, personally the best part of the whole process was learning more about DNA and how it effects us. It&amp;#39;s a fascinating subject which is undergoing a lot of research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a separate note, 23andme&amp;#39;s service is really commendable. Businesses that combine commercial products with scientific research and advances are close to my heart. Other examples of this kind of approach are SpaceX and Tesla. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/Iy0-kom198Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.alexmaccaw.com/analyzing-my-dna</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:buster,2012:Post/how-to-change-yourself-v01</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T08:03:04-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T08:03:04-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/cqR7GfvjMPs/how-to-change-yourself-v01" />
    <author>
      <name>Buster Benson</name>
      <uri>http://wayoftheduck.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>How to change yourself (v 0.1)</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are many other ways to change, but this is the one which is my current best/favorite theory. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Complete the sentence: &amp;ldquo;I am an aspiring ______.&amp;rdquo; Try to find the most succinct identity that represents what you want to change and why. It doesn&amp;#39;t have to explain why, or how. Just what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; I realize that this first step is not very easy to do. That&amp;#39;s intentional. Step #1 will require some thinking to find the right fit for your &amp;ldquo;lose 5 pounds&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;eat better&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;quit smoking&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;get in shape&amp;rdquo; goals. Think about the &lt;em&gt;kind of person you want to become&lt;/em&gt; that &lt;em&gt;naturally&lt;/em&gt; weighs less, eats well, doesn&amp;#39;t smoke, is in shape, etc. Make sure that you really do want to be that person. Use this identity as the anchor to pull all of the entangled habits and behaviors into yourself (assume here that you&amp;#39;re the bottom of the ocean and it is difficult to pull things towards you).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Update your bios on Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, and other favorite social networks with the sentence from #1. You don&amp;#39;t have to announce anything about it, but it needs to be somewhere that random people can see it. (This makes it feel real.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Craft another sentence describing a 1-month resolution which strategically gets you closer to #1, and has the following constraints:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#39;s only ONE resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phrase it in such a way that it is either HIT or MISSED for a given month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that it&amp;#39;s calibrated in such a way that if it ends up being HIT, you will be happy with yourself, and if it turns out to be MISSED for the month you&amp;#39;ll be unhappy with yourself. Do not make it so easy or so difficult that it&amp;#39;s possible to fail at the resolution while still being happy that progress has been made, or succeed at the resolution and still being unhappy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include any footnotes you feel are necessary to say what you think &amp;ldquo;counts&amp;rdquo; and what you think &amp;ldquo;doesn&amp;#39;t count&amp;rdquo; for interpretations of the resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; Join the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups=#!forum/rabbit-rabbit"&gt;Rabbit Rabbit Resolution Accountability Squad&lt;/a&gt; mailing list and introduce yourself by stating the answers to #1 and #3. Feel free to ask for help clarifying or zeroing in on what you&amp;#39;re really interested in working on. Prepare for friendly feedback from the group, too. Comment on as many threads from other people working on resolutions as you feel comfortable. (This is your accountability.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; Set a reminder on your calendar which repeats on the 1st of every month. Everyone on the mailing list will be expected to report in with progress, revise their resolution if necessary, and recommit to the next month. The three outcomes are HIT, MISS, and (if you neglect to check in within 3 days of the beginning of the month) ABSENT. (This helps you remember to remember, which is often the main culprit for failed resolutions.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Extra credit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; Start a public countdown on Twitter, Facebook, or your public venue of choice that starts at 1,000. Any time you do something that gets you a small step towards #1, state what you did along with the current number. I&amp;#39;ve been doing this with my aspiration to be a marathon runner and it&amp;#39;s been quite useful as a tool. 1,000 things is a lot, so I allow myself to include things that have a somewhat loose connection to the identity, and at the same time I am okay with missing a day here and there since getting to 0 is going to take a long time anyway. Also, because of the numbers, there will be plenty of significant milestones to celebrate along the way. (This helps you ignore small setbacks and stay focused on the long-term goal.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related reading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wayoftheduck.com/rabbit-rabbit"&gt;Earlier post from when Rabbit Rabbit started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wayoftheduck.com/huge-habits"&gt;Are habits tiny or huge?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wayoftheduck.com/belief-change"&gt;Behavior change is belief change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wayoftheduck.com/habit-manifesto"&gt;Habit Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;To slog successfully toward goals, habits, or a better life: Go slow. Work hard. Avoid shortcuts. Remember to remember. Be kind to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Buster (@buster) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/buster/status/308442636996452352"&gt;March 4, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suggest edits:&lt;/strong&gt;
If you want to help me improve this, suggest edits &lt;a href="https://draftin.com/documents/26163?token=JQaDVUDkO4s3Fm4CnWwPPp9a_1HNUIENGo2ac0vea3g"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/cqR7GfvjMPs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://wayoftheduck.com/how-to-change-yourself-v01</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/dark-social-on-google-analytics</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T07:43:24-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T07:43:24-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/ewnWHFe1Evs/dark-social-on-google-analytics" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Measuring Dark Social Using Google Analytics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24543684999792_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24543684999792_raw.jpg" alt="Lucas-Higgs-CE0047H-nice2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In social media, like the real world, there&amp;#39;s quite a lot of gossip going on behind your back. At least on the Internet, you can measure it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dubbed dark social, this &amp;ldquo;invisible&amp;rdquo; sharing brings 40% of the visitors to my blog and similar amounts of traffic to other content sites. The Atlantic Monthly, which receives 5M monthly uniques, &lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2012/10/dark-social-we-have-the-whole-history-of-the-web-wrong/263523/"&gt;reports 60% of traffic from dark social&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like its distant cousin dark energy, dark social is a massive and to date little understood force despite its importance. Dark social clicks originate from instant messages, emails containing links and links embedded in tweets opened in TweetDeck among other sources. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Analytics buckets dark social as direct navigation, incorrectly assuming these users spontaneously typed a long url from some epiphany. But as marketer Cody Boyte from Axial showed me last week, It is possible to approximate dark social traffic with Google Analytics. No Large Hadron Collider needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a filter for dark social traffic, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log into Google Analytics and click on the Advanced Segment button. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new segment called Dark Social that excludes the landing page that exactly matches &amp;ldquo;/&amp;rdquo; and the Source contains (direct). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a screenshot of the filter. To view more help on &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=1033017"&gt;Advanced Segments click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24543701890596_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24543701890596_raw.png" alt="ScreenCapture at Sun Mar 17 09:49:27 PDT 2013.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Advanced Segment will track all the visitors who arrived at your site with click to deep link without ever visiting the home page: Dark Social traffic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How important is Dark Social traffic for your site? &lt;a href="http://branch.com/b/measuring-dark-social-using-google-analytics/invite_link/KIGsROa-SsT3XQ"&gt;Let me know on this Branch.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/ewnWHFe1Evs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/dark-social-on-google-analytics</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:adii,2012:Post/youre-born-an-entrepreneur</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T02:30:24-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T02:30:24-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/koAlbaZoD4E/youre-born-an-entrepreneur" />
    <author>
      <name>Adii Pienaar</name>
      <uri>http://adii.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>You're Born An Entrepreneur</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Saturday morning, I was attending (i.e. my 16-month old son can&amp;#39;t drive; so I was the chaperone) a first birthday party for friends&amp;#39; twins and I got speaking to someone that I met there. The conversation quickly turned to entrepreneurship and how it can&amp;#39;t be taught; instead you&amp;#39;re either born with critical characteristics that makes you an entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/16/bring-out-the-beast/"&gt;I then read this&lt;/a&gt;, this morning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Startups, like professional football, are best done by the most desperate people on the planet. Products don’t just walk out the door on their own. Sooner or later, to ship something amazing, you have to dig deep and bring out your beast. A horse running wild is a rare sight, but it takes your breath away every time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This struck a chord with me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last 11-odd years that I&amp;#39;ve been building businesses (the initial attempts - when I was still at school - can&amp;#39;t really be called businesses and should probably be labeled as &lt;em&gt;projects&lt;/em&gt;), I&amp;#39;ve often considered my drive to be a curse and &lt;a href="http://adii.me/passion-work"&gt;my passion to be a beast that needs to be fed&lt;/a&gt;. I regularly compromised on all the aspects of my life (going out for drinks for friends, working on weekends, spending time with my family etc.) in the short-term in the pursuit of something greater in the long-term. And for most of that pursuit, I didn&amp;#39;t even know what that &lt;em&gt;something greater&lt;/em&gt; even was. (I&amp;#39;ve only recently distilled this to my passion for &lt;a href="http://adii.me/2-things-i-love"&gt;helping other entrepreneurs&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the average person, this probably constitutes irrational and abnormal behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can also remember a conversation I had with a friend back in the day when we were at varsity. My friend kept talking about business and how he was gonna be this hot shot entrepreneur one day. At one stage, I asked him when he&amp;#39;ll work on his first business and he replied: &amp;ldquo;One day when I&amp;#39;m older.&amp;rdquo;. Today he is doing really well in a corporate job, where he is climbing the ladder with some great pace. To this day, he also hasn&amp;#39;t shown any inclination to be an entrepreneur. &lt;em&gt;This has never made sense to me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brain has been wired in such a way that I can easily compute the risk &amp;amp; reward of any decision. My personality is such that I chase after the impossible and (when it comes to business at least) I&amp;#39;m fearless in that pursuit. I live for the adrenaline of being challenged, being out-of-my-depth and not really knowing what tomorrow holds (and how I will overcome that). I&amp;#39;m fueled by my ambition to change the world and my drive to learn something new every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was born this way. This is who I am.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the only version of me that I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heck, don&amp;#39;t get me wrong. Some days I wish I can switch off all of this and I can just be &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; (whatever that means). But I can&amp;#39;t; I don&amp;#39;t know where that switch is and whether it even exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I wake up every morning and I get back onto the rollercoaster. This is just what I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/koAlbaZoD4E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://adii.me/youre-born-an-entrepreneur</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jamietie,2012:Post/media-mishandling-of-a-rape-verdict</id>
    <published>2013-03-17T18:26:14-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T18:26:14-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/IGVQrCmn78I/media-mishandling-of-a-rape-verdict" />
    <author>
      <name>Jamie Kelly</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jamietie.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Media mishandling of a rape verdict</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Steubenville, Ohio, rape case has been media catnip for months now&amp;mdash;it has so many elements that make it compelling: cover-ups, fallen teenagers, social media misbehavior, &amp;amp;c. It draws people in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s been less focus on the victim, which is unsurprising&amp;mdash;it seems that a lot of network and cable journalists and talking heads are more interested in the impact of the rape on the culture of the town (which is very interesting, but secondary), and on the effect on the football team, particularly the two players accused of rape. That is less interesting, unless we talk about how the team culture enabled and protected them&amp;mdash;made them feel that of course they could sexually assault a young woman. But that hasn&amp;#39;t been the narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rawstory.com/rs/2013/03/17/cnn-grieves-that-guilty-verdict-ruined-promising-lives-of-steubenville-rapists/"&gt;One CNN anchor&lt;/a&gt; today spoke about how the verdict possibly ruined the boys&amp;#39; lives, and how it was sad to see so much potential be waster. She didn&amp;#39;t mention what it must have been like for a 16-year-old girl to wake up with no recollection of the night before, and then realized that she&amp;#39;d been raped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the fact is, the verdict and the sentence didn&amp;#39;t ruin the boys&amp;#39; lives. First, they both had fairly lenient sentences, and are guaranteed to be out of custody before their 21st birthday. Second, if anything ruined their lives it was &lt;strong&gt;their own actions&lt;/strong&gt;. They made a choice to assault the victim. Their actions before and after the assault belong to them alone, and focusing on how the verdict ruined their promising lives subverts that fact. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea about the character of the boys in question, and neither do the anchors or journalists covering the trial. What we do know&amp;mdash;what has been proved in court beyond a reasonable doubt&amp;mdash;is that they raped a 16-year-old girl, and spread pictures of the assault. CNN and everyone else should be more concerned about the impact the assault, threats, and trial had on the victim than on the perpetrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/IGVQrCmn78I" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jamietie.com/media-mishandling-of-a-rape-verdict</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:EAKoester,2012:Post/stop-creepy-cofounder-dating-and-start-convincing-someone-you-are-awesome-enough-to-work-with</id>
    <published>2013-03-17T11:50:35-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T11:50:35-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/BprvwF0L40E/stop-creepy-cofounder-dating-and-start-convincing-someone-you-are-awesome-enough-to-work-with" />
    <author>
      <name>Eric Koester</name>
      <uri>http://ekoester.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Stop creepy cofounder 'dating' and start convincing someone you are awesome enough to work with</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a phone call a couple weeks back with someone who was looking for a cofounder (not an uncommon thing, right?)  I asked what he&amp;#39;s been doing to find a cofounder and his response nearly made me spit out my coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I posted a few ads on job sites,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; he said.  &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Then I&amp;#39;m interviewing the people who reply to see if they&amp;#39;d be a good cofounder.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What?  Are you serious?  Like seriously serious? WTF?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please Stop Being Creepy&lt;/strong&gt;
Listen, let me explain this to you quite simply:  you don&amp;#39;t hire a cofounder.  You convince someone awesome that you are worth working on something together.  Key word &amp;ldquo;convince.&amp;rdquo;  Not key words like &amp;ldquo;connive&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;surprise&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;manipulate&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;hire&amp;rdquo;.  None of those words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t go to the &amp;ldquo;cofounder store&amp;rdquo; and pick up a lovely Rubyist, with a side of adaptive design.  You don&amp;#39;t stand on the street corner on Wall Street and yell, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Anyone good with metrics, data and financial instruments?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s start here:  Don&amp;#39;t be creepy.  You know what creepy is&amp;hellip; it&amp;#39;s doing things like posting ads on job sites, then sneakily hope you can convince someone to be a cofounder when they apply for a non-existent job in your non-existent startup.  Turns out a relationship built on lies&amp;hellip; yeah, those usually don&amp;#39;t turn out well.  Rule #1: Stop being the skeezy, creepy dude at the bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that&amp;#39;s out of the way (which should be a basic test, but obviously it wasn&amp;#39;t), I want you to reimagine how you find a cofounder:  Pretend you are single and are hoping to find the love of your life.  Remember how that goes?  You meet lots of frogs to find a prince or princess charming.  You talk to friends, you may go on Match.com, you go out to bars or church.  You are looking for things in common.  You want to have great conversation, enjoy the same things, be on the same page with stuff, and generally dig each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t walk into a bar and yell, &amp;ldquo;Hey, who wants to get married.&amp;rdquo;  Well, unless you are super f-ing creepy, then maybe you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Convince Someone You Are Awesome&lt;/strong&gt;
Here&amp;#39;s three things to try to show someone you are worth working on something with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Work on a short-term, test project together.  Go to a Startup Weekend with someone, attend a Hackathon, or just work on something simple for a week (hell, try to build a desk together&amp;hellip; I don&amp;#39;t really care.)  Just actually try out working together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Attend a bunch of meetings together.  A good working dynamic is crucial &amp;ndash; and there is no better way to test that than to attend a meeting together with someone outside the &amp;ldquo;team.&amp;rdquo;  If you guys &amp;#39;crush it&amp;#39;, then that&amp;#39;s a good first step&amp;hellip; then do 10 more.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Collaborate on something for several weeks.  Co-write a series of blog posts, work on some code together, build a simple website or co-consult with a prospect.  You&amp;#39;ll learn a ton about how you communicate &amp;ndash; and treat both sides with the respect that you&amp;#39;d want to receive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, each of these activities above is a &amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo; with the goal of finding someone worth getting hitched to&amp;hellip; and it may take a lot of dates or maybe a few.  But remember how hard you worked to impress a gal or a guy when you were interested in them &amp;ndash; do the same with cofounder candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every meeting, every lunch, every conference is a place you might meet someone worth spending more time with&amp;hellip; and that time may eventually lead to a cofounder.  Remember, each meeting is a potential cofounder interview: they are interviewing you for your awesomeness quotient and you are doing the same.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, please please please stop asking me if you know of a cofounder you should meet.  A cofounder is NOT a mail order bride.  It&amp;#39;s work and you should plan to spend some time finding someone amazing.  If you rush it and try and force the issue, something will break&amp;hellip; probably one of you and ultimately the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this doesn&amp;#39;t seem to make sense, do me a favor and watch 40 Year Old Virgin.  Don&amp;#39;t be the guy in the first half of the movie please&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post script (from a Twitter discussion with my good friend Tony Wright):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1 in the &amp;ldquo;How to Convince Someone You are Awesome&amp;rdquo; is to actually BE demonstrably awesome&amp;hellip; that means you don&amp;#39;t just show off, talk a big game, highlight what was done in the past or point people to your amazing LinkedIn profile.  Like actually be awesome in context&amp;hellip; and show while working on something together to a potential cofounder.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/BprvwF0L40E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ekoester.com/stop-creepy-cofounder-dating-and-start-convincing-someone-you-are-awesome-enough-to-work-with</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/exclusive-soundsupply-receives-funding-from-lightbank</id>
    <published>2013-03-17T07:47:14-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T07:47:14-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/5Q_JWaWDFOE/exclusive-soundsupply-receives-funding-from-lightbank" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Exclusive: Soundsupp.ly Receives Funding From Lightbank</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://soundsupp.ly"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soundsupply&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a new company, formed in early 2012, that takes the &amp;#39;deal site&amp;#39; approach to selling music. Called &amp;ldquo;Drops,&amp;rdquo; Soundsupply creates bundles of 10 digital albums, charges $15 for them, and gives people a 10 day window to purchase the deal. The company has just taken on seed funding from Lightbank, the same people responsible for Groupon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The currently undisclosed amount of funding received will give Tim and Eric Mortensen, the two founding brothers, the opportunity to make Soundsupply their full time responsibility, trying to grow the originally bootstrapped company into an influential music destination. Though the retail experience may be the obvious angle for Soundsupply, music discovery is also at the forefront of focus and one the founders are passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company has already created 6 Drops, with the 7th being released March 18th. No bands have been announced for Drop 7 yet, but I&amp;#39;ve heard it is set to include Cursive&amp;#39;s newest album, &amp;#39;I Am Gemini&amp;#39;. One of the highlights that makes the service attractive to bands is the ability to actually make some money and gain exposure, all within a 10 day window. Past Drops have proven finically rewarding to the point of at least a few artists receiving a 90x return over their Spotify royalties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of bundling digital music is a simple and brilliant one that begs other bigger players in music retail to clone the experience. As a first mover, Soundsupply really needs to capitalize on mind and market share, giving users little doubt they are the pioneers and can grab the big names and best music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new influx of cash, you&amp;#39;ll begin to see things like an improved site design, making navigation easier, along with improvements to the download service and other small refinements. Long term, the guys behind Soundsupply are still open to exploring different aspects of the changing music industry. While bundling music may be the start, they aren&amp;#39;t opposed to tweaking the formula and thinking big picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hypebot.com/hypebot/2012/06/sound-supply-co-founder-talks-sound-drop-3-and-more.html"&gt;Here&amp;#39;s my June 2012 Hypebot interview with Co-Founder Tim Mortensen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/5Q_JWaWDFOE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/exclusive-soundsupply-receives-funding-from-lightbank</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tedgonder,2012:Post/books-that-have-changed-my-life</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T23:59:46-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T23:59:46-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/FOEwyBaMXEA/books-that-have-changed-my-life" />
    <author>
      <name>Ted Gonder</name>
      <uri>http://blog.tedgonder.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Books that Have Changed My Life</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Charlie Jones said &amp;ldquo;The only difference between where you are today, and where you&amp;#39;ll be a year from today, are the books you read and the people you meet.&amp;rdquo; Since I started reading voluntarily at the age of 14, books have had a huge influence on my life. Most of the books below are ones I&amp;#39;ve read multiple times, dog-eared dozens of pages in, and given as gifts. They and their authors have shaped who I&amp;#39;ve become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time Management, Career, Behavior, and Health&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mastery-Robert-Greene/dp/0670024961"&gt;Mastery&lt;/a&gt;, by Robert Greene&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Start-up-You-Yourself-Transform/dp/0307888908/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363502986&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=startup+of+you"&gt;The Startup of You&lt;/a&gt;, by Reid Hoffman and Ben Casnocha&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/4-Hour-Workweek-Anywhere-Expanded-Updated/dp/0307465357/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503001&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=4+hour+workweek"&gt;The 4-Hour Workweek&lt;/a&gt;, by Tim Ferriss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss?url=search-alias%3Dstripbooks&amp;amp;field-keywords=4+hour+body"&gt;The 4-Hour Body&lt;/a&gt;, by Tim Ferriss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Power-Full-Engagement-Managing-Performance/dp/0743226755/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503023&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=power+of+full+engagement"&gt;The Power of Full Engagement&lt;/a&gt;, by Tony Schwartz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philosophy, Pyschology, and Worldview&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Meditations-Marcus-Aurelius/dp/1613823037/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503058&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=meditations+marcus+aurelius"&gt;Meditations&lt;/a&gt;, by Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Letters-Penguin-Classics-Lucius-Annaeus/dp/0140442103"&gt;Letters from a Stoic&lt;/a&gt;, by Seneca&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Tao-Te-Ching-Lao-Tzu/dp/1613822421/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503081&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=tao+te+ching"&gt;Tao te Ching&lt;/a&gt;, by Lao Tzu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/As-Man-Thinketh-James-Allen/dp/1482325632/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503096&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=as+a+man+thinketh"&gt;As a Man Thinketh&lt;/a&gt;, by James Allen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mans-Search-Meaning-Viktor-Frankl/dp/0807014273/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503114&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=man%27s+search+for+meaning"&gt;Man’s Search for Meaning&lt;/a&gt;, by Viktor Frankl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Secret-Psychology-How-Fall-Love/dp/0452288185/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503129&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=how+we+fall+in+love"&gt;How We Fall in Love&lt;/a&gt;, by Paul Dobransky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/50th-Law-Robert-Greene-Cent/dp/B0072B5MJE/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503147&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=the+50th+law"&gt;The 50th Law&lt;/a&gt;, by Robert Greene and 50 Cent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Books that Have Inspired Me to Lead and Serve&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Rules-Radicals-Saul-Alinsky/dp/0679721134/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503217&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=rules+for+radicals"&gt;Rules for Radicals&lt;/a&gt;, by Saul Alinsky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mountains-Beyond-Farmer-Random-Readers/dp/0812980557/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503229&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=mountains+beyond+mountains"&gt;Mountains Beyond Mountains&lt;/a&gt;, by Tracy Kidder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Acts-Faith-American-Struggle-Generation/dp/080700622X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503240&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=acts+of+faith"&gt;Acts of Faith&lt;/a&gt;, by Eboo Patel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Fountainhead-Ayn-Rand/dp/0452273331/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503257&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=the+fountainhead"&gt;The Fountainhead&lt;/a&gt;, by Ayn Rand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/One-Day-All-Children-Unlikely/dp/1586481797/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503273&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=one+day+all+children"&gt;One Day All Children&lt;/a&gt;, by Wendy Kopp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Our-America-Death-South-Chicago/dp/0684870444/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503289&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=our+american+life+and+death+on+the+southside+of+chicago"&gt;Our America: Life &amp;amp; Death on the South Side of Chicago&lt;/a&gt;, by LeAlan Jones &amp;amp; Lloyd Newman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Gang-Leader-Day-Sociologist-Streets/dp/014311493X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503312&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=gang+leader+for+a+day"&gt;Gang Leader for a Day: A Rogue Sociologist Takes to the Streets&lt;/a&gt;, by Sudhir Venkatesh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Monster-Autobiography-L-Member/dp/0802141447/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503328&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=monster+gang+l.a."&gt;Monster: The Autobiography of an L.A. Gang Member&lt;/a&gt;, by Sanyika Shakur&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Autobiography-Malcolm-X/dp/0345902335/ref=sr_1_2?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503350&amp;amp;sr=1-2&amp;amp;keywords=autobiography+of+malcolm+x"&gt;The Autobiography of Malcolm X&lt;/a&gt;, by Malcolm X&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Leadership-Dojo-Foundation-Exemplary-Leader/dp/1583942017/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503372&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=leadership+dojo"&gt;The Leadership Dojo: Build Your Foundation as an Exemplary Leader&lt;/a&gt;, by Richard Strozzi-Heckler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Search-Warrior-Spirit-Fourth-Disciplines/dp/1583942025/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503389&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=in+search+of+the+warrior+spirit"&gt;In Search of the Warrior Spirit: Teaching Awareness Disciplines to the Green Berets&lt;/a&gt;, by Richard Strozzi-Heckler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Warriors-Path-Second-Philosophy-Mythology/dp/158394219X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503401&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=on+the+warriors+path"&gt;On the Warrior’s Path&lt;/a&gt;, by Daniele Bolelli&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Heart-Fist-Education-Humanitarian-Making/dp/B0098RLDT8/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503415&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=heart+and+the+fist"&gt;The Heart and the Fist: the Education of a Humanitarian, the Making of a Navy SEAL&lt;/a&gt;, by Eric Grietens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Power-Love-Theory-Practice-Social/dp/1605093041/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503429&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=power+and+love"&gt;Power and Love&lt;/a&gt;, by Adam Kahane&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Books that Just Plain Spoke to Me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Fight-Club-Novel-Chuck-Palahniuk/dp/0393327345/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503515&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=fight+club"&gt;Fight Club&lt;/a&gt;, by Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Lullaby-Chuck-Palahniuk/dp/0385722192/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503527&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=lullaby"&gt;Lullaby&lt;/a&gt;, by Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Million-Little-Pieces-James-Frey/dp/0307276902"&gt;A Million Little Pieces&lt;/a&gt;, by James Frey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Million-Miles-Thousand-Years-Learned/dp/1400202981/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363501407&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=a+million+miles+in+a+thousand+years"&gt;A Million Miles in a Thousand Years&lt;/a&gt;, by Donald Miller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/White-Fang-Dover-Thrift-Editions/dp/048626968X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503564&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=white+fang"&gt;White Fang&lt;/a&gt;, by Jack London&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Call-Wild-Jack-London/dp/1613823495/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503580&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=call+of+the+wild"&gt;The Call of the Wild&lt;/a&gt;, by Jack London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/FOEwyBaMXEA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.tedgonder.com/books-that-have-changed-my-life</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tedgonder,2012:Post/quotes-that-have-changed-my-life</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T23:34:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T23:34:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/fXW3U2V4-ZM/quotes-that-have-changed-my-life" />
    <author>
      <name>Ted Gonder</name>
      <uri>http://blog.tedgonder.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Quotes that Have Changed My Life</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you follow me on Facebook, Twitter, or Linkedin, you know I&amp;#39;m always posting quotes. I&amp;#39;m a total quote junkie. It&amp;#39;s how I get through the day. Here are the ones I&amp;#39;ve printed out and taped to mirrors, written on my hands for inspiration on sad days, crammed into the front covers of Moleskines, and have memorized for opportune recitation. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you’re going through hell, keep going.” 
- Winston Churchill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It takes conviction and vulnerability to believe in something, and absolutely no balls to tear it down.&amp;rdquo; 
- Eileen Guo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is not the critic who counts: not the man who points out how the strong man stumbles or where the doer of deeds could have done better. The credit belongs to the man who is actually in the arena, whose face is marred by dust and sweat and blood, who strives valiantly, who errs and comes up short again and again, because there is no effort without error or shortcoming, but who knows the great enthusiasms, the great devotions, who spends himself for a worthy cause; who, at the best, knows, in the end, the triumph of high achievement, and who, at the worst, if he fails, at least he fails while daring greatly, so that his place shall never be with those cold and timid souls who knew neither victory nor defeat.&amp;rdquo;
- Theodore Roosevelt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The individual has always had to struggle to keep from being overwhelmed by the tribe. If you try it, you will be lonely often, and sometimes frightened. But no price is too high to pay for the privilege of owning yourself.” 
- Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All courses of action are risky, so prudence is not in avoiding danger (it&amp;#39;s possible), but calculating risk and acting decisively. Make mistakes of ambition and not mistakes of sloth. Develop the strength to do bold things, not the strength to suffer.&amp;rdquo; 
- Niccolo Machiavelli&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Commitment is what transforms a promise into reality. It is the words that speak boldly of your intentions. And the actions which speak louder than the words. It is making the time when there is none. Coming through time after time after time, year after year after year. Commitment is the stuff character is made of; the power to change the face of things. It is the daily triumph of integrity over skepticism.&amp;rdquo; 
- Abraham Lincoln&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My belief is in the blood and flesh as being wiser than the intellect. The body-unconscious is where life bubbles up in us. It is how we know that we are alive, alive to the depths of our soul and in touch somewhere with the vivid reaches of the cosmos.&amp;rdquo; 
- D. H. Lawrence”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To study the Way is to study the Self
To study the Self is to forget the Self
To Forget the Self is to be Awakened with All Things”
-Dogan, sixteenth-century Zen monk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Few are willing to brave the disapproval of their peers, the censure of their colleagues, the wrath of their society. Moral courage is a rarer commodity than bravery in battle or great intelligence. Yet it is the one essential, vital quality for those who seek to change a world that yields most painfully to change.” 
- Robert F. Kennedy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When you wake up in the morning, tell yourself: the people I deal with today will be meddling, ungrateful, arrogant, dishonest, jealous and surly. They are like this because they can&amp;#39;t tell good from evil. But I have seen the beauty of good, and the ugliness of evil, and have recognized that the wrongdoer has a nature related to my own - not of the same blood and birth, but the same mind, and possessing a share of the divine. And so none of them can hurt me. No one can implicate me in ugliness. Nor can I feel angry at my relative, or hate him. We were born to work together like feet, hands and eyes, like the two rows of teeth, upper and lower. To obstruct each other is unnatural. To feel anger at someone, to turn your back on him: these are unnatural.” 
- Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/fXW3U2V4-ZM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.tedgonder.com/quotes-that-have-changed-my-life</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:youssef,2012:Post/terrible-copywriting-on-applecom</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T21:49:53-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T21:49:53-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/PxHWHx-oiAQ/terrible-copywriting-on-applecom" />
    <author>
      <name>Youssef Sarhan</name>
      <uri>http://sefsar.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Terrible copywriting on Apple.com</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542929772910_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542929772910_raw.png" alt="Screen shot 2013-03-17 at 03.20.26.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple just updated their iPhone page with a &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/why-iphone/"&gt;Why iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; tab. Undoubtedly created to swoon any potential customers that may be debating between the recently announced Samsung Galaxy S4 and not-so-new iPhone 5. With examples, I plan to demonstrate where Apple could have improved their copywriting. Copywriting is an important but often neglected discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542931503052_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542931503052_raw.png" alt="opening_lead.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, beginning a sentence with &amp;ldquo;and&amp;rdquo; (a conjunction) is not recommended. This is because &amp;ldquo;and&amp;rdquo; is used to link or compare two points. Separating them with a period can create an awkward cadence. However, perhaps in this case the line-break forgives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue here is about sentiment, &amp;ldquo;and&amp;rdquo; coming after &amp;ldquo;There&amp;#39;s iPhone&amp;rdquo; is like some sort of vague comparison with their competitors. The next five sentences confirm this, first by opening with a question, then an uncertain answer, then another sentence beginning with a conjunction, then two more awkward redundant sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple should have stopped at the headline, because the rest is junk. There is no need for the extra sentences. The phones and apps are enough at this point. In fact, had they left out the extra sentences it would have taken on an entirely new and better meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have run with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s iPhone.&lt;br&gt;
Then there&amp;#39;s everything you can do with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if to suggest that just owning an iPhone is something special, this would have appropriately set the tone, and nicely segued the reader into more detailed information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542932091526_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542932091526_raw.png" alt="award.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up is some award that looks like a Jukebox that no one outside of the U.S. has ever heard of before. It&amp;#39;s great that people think Apple has a nice product, but I really don&amp;#39;t care what these guys think of it. J.D. Power and Associates means nothing to me. It occupies no point of reference in my mind, and thus means nothing to me. Apple should know their audience. If anything, this brings in to question what Apple values, or more importantly, what Apple thinks I value. So far, I&amp;#39;ve no inclination to buy an iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542932709430_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542932709430_raw.png" alt="battery.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is simple. Apple use the same word –Great– to describe a good thing and a bad thing. &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/9fgowvzfQ9U?t=3m18s"&gt;Great&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s not smart, it&amp;#39;s not witty, it&amp;#39;s bad, it&amp;#39;s muddled. It doesn&amp;#39;t leave the right impression. Be clear. That&amp;#39;s all you have to do, ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542933544828_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542933544828_raw.png" alt="power.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, using the same word to describe a good thing and a bad thing. There&amp;#39;s no need for it. Just be clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a bunch of other things, but it&amp;#39;s late and I&amp;#39;m tired. Whoever wrote this copy probably shouldn&amp;#39;t write copy for Apple anymore. Finally, notice how there are no black iPhones featured on the entire page, they are all White. I wonder if there&amp;#39;s a strategic reason for that, probably not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/PxHWHx-oiAQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sefsar.com/terrible-copywriting-on-applecom</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:dalton,2012:Post/sine-waves</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T15:25:52-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T15:25:52-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/u5VGLEJhUoM/sine-waves" />
    <author>
      <name>Dalton Caldwell</name>
      <uri>http://daltoncaldwell.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Sine waves</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One thing I have noticed studying web traffic logs is that daily human behavior at scale resembles a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sine_wave"&gt;sine wave&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/dalton_24542448166944_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_dalton_24542448166944_raw.png" alt="Wave.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, my mind&amp;#39;s eye has constructed an image of the daily ebb and flow of web traffic resembling the ebb and flow of ocean tides. I&amp;#39;ve learned that code tends to break at the &amp;ldquo;high tide&amp;rdquo;, and the best time to do site maintenance is at &amp;ldquo;low tide&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why does human behavior at scale look like a sine wave? It&amp;#39;s because of our daily cycles of waking and sleeping. In other words, we have a 24 hour cycle because of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Circadian_rhythm"&gt;circadian rhythms&lt;/a&gt;, which occur because of the cycles of darkness and light caused by planetary movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And why do we have a tidal system? It&amp;#39;s largely caused by the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tide"&gt;gravitational pull of the moon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It only recently occurred to me that the unconscious link I felt between tides and web traffic wasn&amp;#39;t a lazy &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Folk_science"&gt;cognitive crutch&lt;/a&gt;, rather, they are both causally related to planetary movement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, this minor insight was a helpful reminder: everything is connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/u5VGLEJhUoM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://daltoncaldwell.com/sine-waves</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:lautenbach,2012:Post/the-second-screen-obsession</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T08:30:22-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T08:30:22-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/mIfCDEzBoA0/the-second-screen-obsession" />
    <author>
      <name>Bradley Lautenbach</name>
      <uri>http://blog.bradleylautenbach.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The second screen obsession</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hollywood has grown fixated on the second screen. The &amp;ldquo;second screen&amp;rdquo; refers to the other thing we&amp;#39;re paying attention to while watching television or movies &amp;ndash; this could be a phone, tablet, or computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The industry fixates on the second screen because it feels threatened, and rightly so. In an era of alt-tab attention spans, fewer people are coming to long-form content by traditional means if they are coming at all. Between the actual dollars, and the perceived mental commitment, the cost of consuming content that is longer than your regular cat video on YouTube is not negligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, over the last 30+ years, as distribution channels have expanded (the movie multiplex, the 500+ cable television channels), quantity of content has increased while quality of content has decreased. Fortunately for Hollywood, this bad content didn&amp;#39;t have much to compete with in order to capture an audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the late 1990s, we saw wide-spread consumer adoption of the Internet. And the rise of file sharing. And the slow-and-then-fast disruption of the recorded music industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hollywood watched this happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came broadband. And suddenly it was easy to share and stream the larger video files that dialup couldn&amp;#39;t support. And Hollywood started to worry, mostly, and incorrectly, about piracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came Facebook. And suddenly there was a whole new type of content that was, in many cases, far more compelling than Hollywood&amp;#39;s. This content is always fresh, and, most importantly, it is free. This is social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the iPhone. And suddenly consumers could take this new stream of social content with them wherever they went - including the couch and the movie theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now we have arrived at the present model of consumer behavior where viewers are watching Hulu in one tab while they&amp;#39;re Facebooking in another, they&amp;#39;re playing Angry Birds on the couch while they&amp;#39;ve got ESPN on on the television, and they&amp;#39;re texting each other while they&amp;#39;re in the movie theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, bizarrely, Hollywood&amp;#39;s reaction to this is: LET US OWN THIS NEW SCREEN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus is born the &amp;ldquo;innovation group&amp;rdquo; at BigMediaCo. Thus do ex-producers decide to launch startups to &amp;ldquo;capture the second screen experience.&amp;rdquo; Thus does an entire industry begin to wonder if this Silicon Valley place might become &amp;ldquo;a thing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every few weeks, I get pitched a second screen opportunity, mostly by people who are content creators in Hollywood. Most of these businesses provide access to bonus content related to the first-screen experience, allow viewers to socialize with other people who are also consuming the first-screen experience, or, most commonly, create new revenue streams related to the first-screen experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;#39;s started to make me wonder&amp;hellip; are we stupid?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job of Hollywood is to create content (read: tell a story) that so delights an audience that the audience is willing to pay to consume this content. Why is Hollywood spending any time creating experiences to further distract the audience? Rather than fixate on the shiny new thing, shouldn&amp;#39;t Hollywood be doubling down on finding and telling incredible stories? Wouldn&amp;#39;t we put our second screens down in a heartbeat if we were actually being delighted by the content on the first screen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media has made it nearly impossible to recoup the investment in bad content. Mediocre opening weekends of a bad movie thanks to a big marketing spend are no longer possible. Twitter kills a bad movie after the first few screenings on Friday. But content is still king. And good content spreads itself. Social media has also spawned a whole new consumer behavior: Incredible television can now be discovered and binge-viewed season-by-season online. (see: Downton Abbey).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s pause. Let&amp;#39;s not take our eye off the ball. Let&amp;#39;s not pretend that the second screen is going to solve some underlying structural problems in the entertainment industry. Let&amp;#39;s instead be confident that we can tell wonderful stories, delight our audiences, and that in return our audiences will reward us with dollars and, more importantly, their undivided attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. .. .. ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are rare cases where the &amp;ldquo;second screen&amp;rdquo; becomes an innvoative part of telling the story, for one example, check out the movie, &lt;a href="http://www.fastcocreate.com/1682579/the-second-screen-comes-to-the-movies-with-app-enhanced-film-app"&gt;&amp;ldquo;App.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/mIfCDEzBoA0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.bradleylautenbach.com/the-second-screen-obsession</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/the-wrong-time-and-place-why-wii-was-nintendos-biggest-failure</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T08:22:08-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T08:22:08-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/yguc_smXiIA/the-wrong-time-and-place-why-wii-was-nintendos-biggest-failure" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The Wrong Time And Place: Why Wii Was Nintendo's Biggest Failure</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s curious the products that swing between highs and lows. Some have so much initial success that competitors race to rip it off. While other products are so disregarded at first, only to come back big later. It&amp;#39;s funny how timing can lead to disingenuous results, catapulting a company off course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Nintendo reporting such terrible sales of the Wii U in January and February, you can&amp;#39;t help but wonder if the Wii really scratched the average person&amp;#39;s itch for gaming or if it hit the market at just the right time. Nintendo stated early on that the Wii was a blue ocean move, meaning, with this product they were hanging a hard left and sailing to a place where motion control was king and there weren&amp;#39;t any sharks for miles. Everything about the Wii &amp;ndash; including its name &amp;ndash; was a bold move when the company first announced the console, and it paid off. You could barely get your hands on one for months and months after it was released, by all accounts the Wii was a blockbuster hit. At the time you&amp;#39;d be hard pressed to find someone calling it a failure, even looking back, few would use that word to describe the iconic white box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To continue the movie metaphors, of course Nintendo was going to follow up with a sequel rather than a completely new franchise, but they shouldn&amp;#39;t have. The company let past success dictate future moves rather than fully assessing the market they would be releasing a new product into. Obviously Nintendo saw tablets and similar devices coming or they would&amp;#39;t have put a massive one at the center of their gaming experience. The fault was that they desperately wanted to recreate the Wii&amp;#39;s success, rather than pull another blue ocean move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bolder move than the Wii U would have been to completely flip the tables and infiltrate the cellphone gaming market. Partnering with Apple or Samsung, or both, they could have had the upper hand to dictate lucrative terms and potentially get their franchise games onto every handset being sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who says that once you&amp;#39;re a hardware company you have to always stay a hardware company? Who says that you can&amp;#39;t switch back and forth over time as the circumstances arise. It&amp;#39;s still early for Mircosoft as a computer manufacture, but they needed to &amp;ldquo;grease&amp;rdquo; the windows tablet market and so they&amp;#39;re building the Surface. Barnes and Noble needed a compelling way to transition into the digital age and the Nook was born. Microsoft won&amp;#39;t necessarily always be a computer hardware company from here on out. If OEMs can build compelling devices and push the sales of Microsoft&amp;#39;s software, I have no doubt they&amp;#39;ll exit that hardware business. The better follow up to the Wii would have been if Nintendo transitioned itself into more of a software company willing to become ubiquitous on different platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;#39;s the desire for official Nintendo games to come to iOS and Android that&amp;#39;s coloring my opinions, but it seems like the writing is on the wall for some form of mobile gaming to eventually and completely push consoles to the side. At that time, software will be all Nintendo has left to cling to and they&amp;#39;ll be forced to make choices that aren&amp;#39;t their own, on terms that aren&amp;#39;t as favorable as once could have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake, the Wii was a big deal, so big in fact that it likely clouded Nintendo&amp;#39;s judgement on their future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/yguc_smXiIA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/the-wrong-time-and-place-why-wii-was-nintendos-biggest-failure</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:sash,2012:Post/what-its-like-to-die</id>
    <published>2013-03-15T10:27:54-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T10:27:54-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/KYMxPDgEGiM/what-its-like-to-die" />
    <author>
      <name>Sash MacKinnon</name>
      <uri>http://sashmackinnon.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>What it's like to die</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Six months ago, I died. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no recollection of the event, but I&amp;#39;ve heard the story retold so many times that I may as well have seen it all. I was at the gym in my apartment complex with my roommate, Sam. I was running on the treadmill when I turned and told him I was going to faint. I collapsed and fell onto the still-moving belt, which tore the skin off my knee and pushed me onto the floor. Sam was shocked. He called for help. A personal trainer and her client ran over, called an ambulance, and assisted Sam in giving me CPR while my body slowly drained of color. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My heart had gone into ventricular fibrillation. &amp;ldquo;Vfib&amp;rdquo;, as I heard numerous doctors call it, is an type of arrhythmia&amp;ndash;a series of irregular electrical signals in the ventricle chamber of the heart. Instead of beating normally, the walls quiver erratically, like they&amp;#39;re having a seizure . The heart quickly becomes unable to pump blood to other organs. I had suffered from what is officially, and somewhat morbidly, termed &amp;ldquo;Sudden Cardiac Death&amp;rdquo;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paramedics arrived and walked slowly down the length of the pool to the gym. This was procedure, they later told me; they didn&amp;#39;t want to run and cause alarm. When they reached me, they defibrillated my heart  by strapping patches to my abdomen and running a strong electrical current through my body. I was told that after the first administration my heart had remained in arrhythmia. After the second, it started beating regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those 4 minutes and 30 seconds, I was clinically dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next two days in a coma while the doctors cooled by body to 32 degrees in order to avoid brain damage. During this time I developed a pulmonary embolism and pneumonia. Whenever I visit a doctor now they are always surprised&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;each of those alone could have killed you, it&amp;#39;s a miracle you survived all three!&amp;rdquo; I survived by sitting through hours of MRIs with oxygen in my nose, three IV&amp;#39;s in my arm and ten pills a day for weeks. Sam and my two mothers, Laurie and Kerrie, rarely left my side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stories you hear about people dying usually end with tunnels, lights, flashbacks, God, and big epiphanies. That isn&amp;#39;t what happened to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finally regaining enough consciousness to understand my situation, I sat for hours staring at the hospital walls. I didn&amp;#39;t have any life changing realizations. I wasn&amp;#39;t regretful. In fact, I couldn&amp;#39;t think of anything in my life I wanted to change at all. Being trapped alone in that sterile room with wires hanging off my chest only made me think about everything in my life I wanted back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people I tell this story to think I&amp;#39;m unlucky because I had a cardiac arrest at 21 years old. But I don&amp;#39;t think so. Only five percent of people who suffer ventricular fibrillation out of the hospital survive. Of those that do survive, more than half of them have brain damage. That means only two and a half percent fully recover. Not only did I fully recover, but I did so in the company of the people closest to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is one lesson I took away from the experience, it is not to &amp;ldquo;live life to the fullest&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;have no regrets&amp;rdquo;. It is to feel lucky. Feeling lucky means you are appreciating the things in your life that sometimes go unnoticed. It means you are achieving more than think you deserve. Feeling lucky requires a certain humility we often lose sight of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it took losing everything to remember how lucky I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/KYMxPDgEGiM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sashmackinnon.com/what-its-like-to-die</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/outsourcing</id>
    <published>2013-03-15T08:19:47-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T08:19:47-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/f_m-LPNaVbA/outsourcing" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>A Startup's Guide to Outsourcing</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24540499571202_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24540499571202_raw.jpg" alt="barn raising.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the life of a startup, the question of outsourcing can arise frequently whether for PR, marketing, product design, sales or engineering. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outsourcing can be very attractive: consultants bring new points of view, relevant experience and (potentially) immediate results. Of course, consultants charge high fees and after their contract expires they leave with their knowledge and insights in tow. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founders may be challenged when deciding when and what to outsource. To simplify the decision, reflect on your startup&amp;#39;s key competencies needed to win your market. Like people, startups must focus on a few key skills to be successful. &lt;a href="http://tomtunguz.com/exploiting-your-startups-strength"&gt;Typically, startups win share by focusing on their strength: product design, sales effectiveness, marketing deft or technology advantages.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startups never should outsource their main advantage or the skill required to win in the market. If a team of founders believes product design will revolutionize mobile social networking, the team would blunder to outsource that design. Instead, the startup must cultivate a team to master that discipline. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other terrible candidates for outsourcing include long term projects without clear success metrics. The high churn rates of the PR industry reflect this reality. Most PR firms strive to win business, work diligently for a few quarters and then wane as ideas for stories become exhausted and new clients arrive. In my experience, hiring PR firms for particular launches and events works well. Otherwise, anointing an internal storyteller and empowering that person to achieve long term goals achieves success more reliably and at less cost. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startups should leverage consultants for narrowly defined, non-core initiatives when developing an expertise isn&amp;#39;t valuable to the business. For example, AirBnB didn&amp;#39;t need to build an internal team of cameramen to photograph the insides of homes all over the world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consultants offer tremendous leverage to a business and work best when tasked with ancillary, commodity services not required by a startup to win their market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your lessons from outsourcing? &lt;a href="http://branch.com/b/what-are-your-lessons-from-outsourcing-at-a-startup/invite_link/ThU0gpEEdAb53g"&gt;Join the conversation on Branch.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/f_m-LPNaVbA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/outsourcing</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:adii,2012:Post/dont-compete-on-features</id>
    <published>2013-03-15T02:09:07-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T02:09:07-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/qgnlxr9fJwU/dont-compete-on-features" />
    <author>
      <name>Adii Pienaar</name>
      <uri>http://adii.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Don't Compete On Features</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had quite a few &lt;a href="https://clarity.fm/#/adii"&gt;Clarity calls&lt;/a&gt; this past week with entrepreneurs asking for advice on how they should go about building &amp;amp; branding their new startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My best advice at the moment: &lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;#39;t try compete on features.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most markets that you can enter right now, are already quite saturated and you&amp;#39;re likely to face existing competition. Due to the very low barrier to entry to build a new SaaS / web / mobile app, you&amp;#39;ll also find that the competition&amp;#39;s offering is mostly the same as your solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that there&amp;#39;s simply no competitive advantage in trying to &lt;em&gt;out-feature&lt;/em&gt; your competitors and such a strategy is very unlikely to get you the traction you need to build a sustainable business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead here&amp;#39;s two alternatives to build a competitive advantage for your startup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Branding.&lt;/strong&gt; Tom Tunguz rightly says that &lt;a href="http://tomtunguz.com/branding"&gt;branding is the next essential startup competency&lt;/a&gt;. In a crowded space, it&amp;#39;s important to stand out and doing so why your branding is the lowest hanging fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Customer Service / Experience.&lt;/strong&gt; Delivering the most awesome experience imaginable to your customers will a) make them loyal to you; and b) make them tell their friends. This is a competitive advantage that you can leverage to grab market share away from your competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve applied both of these strategies at WooThemes to great success; especially considering that all of our code is open source and freely available elsewhere. Our 400 000+ customers however keeps coming back to us, because they know (due to our branding / reputation) that we&amp;#39;re awesome at supporting our products (delivering an awesome experience).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/qgnlxr9fJwU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://adii.me/dont-compete-on-features</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:francis,2012:Post/to-think-like-midas</id>
    <published>2013-03-15T02:00:32-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T02:00:32-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/xqvCM5fT6xQ/to-think-like-midas" />
    <author>
      <name>Francis Pedraza</name>
      <uri>http://francispedraza.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>To think like Midas</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to Greek myth, the god Dionysus gave Midas, a king of ancient Phrygia in the 8th century, the power of turning everything he touched into gold. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year, Forbes publishes a list of top technology investors called the &lt;a href="http://www.forbes.com/lists/midas/2012/midas-list-top-tech-investors.html"&gt;Midas list&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also would like to borrow the metaphor by calling the superhuman we imagined in the last post, “&lt;a href="http://francispedraza.com/who-then-can-see-the-future"&gt;Who, then, can see the future?&lt;/a&gt;”, Midas. If an investor had the ability to see the future, he would indeed be like Midas, every bet he would make would turn into gold. Within just the first year of business, he would have established a reputation so formidable that if he opened a fund, almost regardless of the terms, he would have a line of LPs wrapped around the building with checks in hand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where am I going with this? Why do I entertain these fantasies?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fiction’s not for babies, y’all. There’s just something in a myth&amp;hellip; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To return to the thread of my argument, I’m interested in learning how to think intelligently about the future. In other words, I would like to think like Midas. Great entrepreneurs think like investors, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who, then, can glimpse the future, if not Midas? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mind trained to study the past. The past is full of clues. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For it was once the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Of Great Men &amp;amp; Marxists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The disciplines of philosophy and history have an intimate relationship. If, in the &lt;a href="http://francispedraza.com/the-smallest-market-is-about-to-become-the-largest-market"&gt;market to come&lt;/a&gt;, philosophers are to be kings, then historians are to be queens. When it comes to the philosophy of history, there are two schools of thought: the “marxist” school and the “Great Man” school. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Marxist” historians, it’s worth noting, aren’t necessarily marxists, but they share with them a historical point of view: the vast majority of things that happen in society (and indeed, in the universe) are beyond the control of any one individual. Individuals are rounding errors in the grand scheme of things. What truly matters are large impersonal forces like capital structures, class movements, information flows, technological progress and the cultural evolution of ideas (Hegel’s &lt;em&gt;zeitgeists&lt;/em&gt;). As a result, they tend to think of long-run outcomes as fairly determinist. There is a certain inevitability to the waves that crash with the tides of time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the “Great Man” school fills its pages with the stories of the likes of Julius Caesar, Napoleon Bonaparte, George Washington or Steve Jobs. Remarkable individuals do not resign to fate, they hammer their destiny into stone through brute force of will. Like Achilles, they seek immortality through their deeds, or like Martin Luther King, they rally their fellow men behind a beatific vision. To understand history, you must understand the characters in the story, and these are heroes and villains of ambition, cunning and genius. History does not happen to them, they happen to history. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s imagine these two schools of thought expressed as investment strategies. The marxists, with a little irony, would invest in trends. The “great man” historians, would invest, (wait for it), in great men - in promising individuals. They would pride themselves as great judges of character and talent.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which strategy would perform better against the Midas index? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Trends and Megatrends&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are trends, and then there are megatrends. At any given point in time, there are many, many trends in the world. Usually, though, there are just a few megatrends. The difference is temporal and structural. What I mean by that is: a trend may come and go, and if it has a lasting effect, it is residual or gradual or incremental to what was already there before, but a megatrend, on the other hand, comes and completely alters the landscape, things change and don’t go back to normal, and the new normal is structurally different. Think of them like waves and tsunamis. Waves can crash on a beach for millennia. While the coastline will change, it will change slowly. If a tsunami comes, it alters all in its path. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, there are megatrends reshaping our world. The problem is we don’t have the historical perspective to see them. To use another metaphor: we can’t see the forest through the trees. Take, for example, the last ten years. There has been revolution after revolution in hardware and software, yet, “what’s next?” is the ever elusive question. That’s what Midas could see, but we can’t. Midas only bets on megatrends, while we run around chasing trends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Resolving the Paradox&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s truth in the paradox, as Kierkegaard might say, between the Marxists and the Great Men. The Marxists have a point. There are trends and megatrends shaping our world, and compared to them, individuals have very little agency. We are just a part of these broader movements, which loom powerful, impersonal, and beyond our control. Yet, despite that, time and again, it seems that certain individuals have a disproportionate impact on events. How do they do it? To resolve the paradox, let’s study the interplay between some great men and the trends of their day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would the Republic have fallen without Caesar? There’s reasons suggesting that it would. Through the class struggles between patricians and plebeians, so many checks and balances had emerged that the political system had become dysfunctional, and nobody could get anything done except in a crisis. Already the thread of culture had began, in the amphitheaters that were the precursors to the Colosseum, that taught Rome to celebrate the values of the victor in war. If might makes right, then the successful generals, who had in so short a time had amassed an empire sprawling in every direction, had a sympathetic audience in the capitol - and none had been more successful than the champion of the Gallic campaigns, Julius Caesar. If to the victor go the spoils, then Caesar had spoils in plenty: autonomy and sovereignty as the governor of the newly conquered Gallic provinces, he was entitled to a large income. Finding himself with legions, wealth and popularity, he looked to Rome. Perhaps before he looked to Rome, Pompey and the Senate looked to him, and trembled. His power had made him a threat to their power, and they ordered him to lay down his military command. Which he disobeyed by crossing the Rubicon and taking control of the city and its politics, becoming de-facto dictator, and ending, except in name, the Republic. While his remaining days were short, they were long enough to sketch the blueprint for a new order, which would survive even his assassination. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this story you have all the elements of a classic Marxist explanation: class struggles, cultural evolution, a structural imbalance of power. It’s not hard to weave a narrative that explains the fall of the Republic in such a way that Caesar is just an incidental detail, and that a similar figure would have emerged sooner or later, precipitating a similar chain of events. Perhaps that’s right. But, what was not inevitable, what was unexpected, if you will, is not that the Republic fell, but that the Empire emerged, and emerged the way it did, bearing Caesar’s image, with his idiosyncratic respect for the formalities of the Republic, with his populist flair. His way of doing business set broad parameters for the emperors to come. When they strayed too far from it, when they asserted their power too nakedly or circumvented process too blatantly, they upset a delicate precedent set by their namesake and found themselves tripping over the lingering remnants of old checks and balances. Here, the legacy of the Great Man. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Republic was going to fall. That was the megatrend. But the way it fell, and the nature of what emerged - that was the great man. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how the paradox is resolved: &lt;em&gt;there are megatrends and there are great men who see them coming, make them happen and shape them in the process.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Stamp on Events&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s briefly run through a few more examples. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would the 13 American colonies have split from Great Britain without one or more of the Founding Fathers? Perhaps - it was a megatrend. There were lots of deep structural reasons why that geopolitical relationship was strained, and so maybe it was inevitable that something would have happened, but what was not inevitable was the unique nature of the Revolution and the character and Constitution of the nation that it birthed. These the Great Men shaped. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would we still have laptops and tablets and smartphones today without Steve Jobs? Almost certainly. But in the late 70s, when the megatrend was little more than the rickety Homebrew Computer Club, he saw that these devices called computers, which filled huge rooms and could barely do basic math operations, would soon become very powerful and very small and take on a variety of form factors and would gobble up a myriad of functions currently occupied by analog devices, from clocks to scales to calendars to notepads and more, and that this would change everything. In his mind, it was inevitable - far before most people, even most people in the technology industry, caught on. Three, nearly four, decades later he was still riding the megatrend. Would we have had these devices? Yes. But we wouldn’t have had Apple, with its humanist values and care for design and craft and user experience. Steve was one of the Great Men of his generation who made the megatrend happen, and the unique expressions Apple gave to it were, and are, beautiful - and clearly, they have put their stamp on the future of technology, and shown us what is possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we have agency in a world where the vast majority of things are beyond our control? It’s an art, and it’s a little bit like surfing. The wave comes, the surfer sees it coming, paddles in its direction, and catches it in time for the energy of the wave to carry him along with it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s different about this, though, is that the great man can, at least to some extent, shape the megatrend, whereas the surfer cannot shape the wave. By making it happen, being its agent, if you will, he also gives it its unique expression - its name, it’s flavor, its voice. He fills in the details, and the details are important. They are the difference between the shape of a body and the statue of David. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wave, like the megatrend, is just a form of energy. Energy can be redirected: targeted, channeled, focused. There’s a physics to it. A wave is not a very malleable form of energy, and if you try moving it, it will probably move you. But there are ways of capturing tidal energy to create electricity, and with electricity, you can do lots of interesting things. It’s like Tai Chi, a form of martial arts which doesn’t focus on strikes, but on redirecting the energy of your opponent. Don’t resist, give away - like water. Very taoist. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Events may come and go, but individuals put their stamp on them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Touch to Gold&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the myth, to turn things into gold, Midas had to touch them; seeing them wasn’t enough. There’s a lesson there. Even an investor who can see the megatrend coming - who can, in a sense, glimpse the future - does not know exactly how it will manifest, and who will emerge to shape it, and what legacy it will leave in its wake. This is not the role of the investor, this is the role of the entrepreneur - the Great Man (or Woman) in the story - who not only sees the megatrend, but will actually touch it, every day, by building a company that will be its final expression. Yes, and thereafter, the company becomes the megatrend incarnate. It’s birth foretold, it’s destiny still unfolding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Predicting the future is as hard as it is valuable: extremely. In Greek mythology, even the Fates could only glimpse the future as through a fog. Sometimes, a few of the other gods, chiefly Apollo - or even, on rare occasion, a mortal - would receive a vision or a prophecy, which only the very gifted could interpret. Maybe even our imaginary “Midas” investor was a contradiction in terms - as the future cannot always be seen, even by the gods. And when it can, it is only the megatrends which rise above the fog. Only the outline and not the story. Only the block of stone and not the statue. Only the industry and not the company. The future cannot be seen, only glimpsed. Such that, even in the land of myth, if an investor could glimpse the future, he could not make money so easily, for glimpsing megatrends is not enough. You have to touch things to turn them into gold. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be continued&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.s. Apologies in advance to women. You can be Great too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/xqvCM5fT6xQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://francispedraza.com/to-think-like-midas</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:cadelllast,2012:Post/another-earth</id>
    <published>2013-03-14T20:19:15-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T20:19:15-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/O8-F_VgMdQU/another-earth" />
    <author>
      <name>Cadell Last</name>
      <uri>http://theratchet.ca</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Another Earth</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/a3jV3nJ.png" alt="Another Earth"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Astronomy is often referred to as the most intellectually humbling academic subject.  When you study astronomy you are confronted with scale, size, and time that is completely alien to the human mind.  We evolved to understand spatial scales of kilometers, not light-years, and to understand temporal scales of decades, not billions of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite this, it is always important to contextualize the human experience with astronomical knowledge.  And &lt;a href="http://www.theadvancedapes.com/theratchet/2012/12/22/top-science-discoveries-2012#"&gt;last year was a year of particularly insightful discoveries relevant to understanding our species place within the universe&lt;/a&gt;.  In 2012, astronomers discovered: a) the &lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/kepler/news/smallest-exoplanets.html"&gt;first earth-sized planets&lt;/a&gt;, b) an &lt;a href="http://www.theadvancedapes.com/theratchet/2012/10/19/discovery-of-first-earth-sized-exoplanet-in-context"&gt;earth-sized planet in the nearest star system to earth&lt;/a&gt;, and c) the &lt;a href="http://news.sciencemag.org/sciencenow/2012/12/another-earth-just-12-light-year.html"&gt;first earth-sized planet within the habitable zone of its parents star&lt;/a&gt;.  These discoveries represent major milestones in the development of human knowledge.  They allow us to better-contextualize our planets relationship to the rest of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, these discoveries provide the first empirical evidence that earth-like planets are likely very common in the Milky Way galaxy (and probably in most other galaxies as well).  As soon as astronomers had the technology and methods developed to detect planets as small as earth, they started detecting them.  In the coming years I expect that we will become overwhelmed with headlines similar to: “another earth-like planet detected.”  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, a &lt;a href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2013/03/130312152047.htm"&gt;paper accepted yesterday&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Astrophysical Journal Letters&lt;/em&gt; provided a statistical analysis indicating that we should find some of those earth-like planets in our cosmic neighbourhood.  Ravi Kopparapu, lead author of the study claims: “we now estimate that if we were to look at 10 of the nearest small stars we would find about four potentially habitable planets, give or take.  That is a conservation estimate.”  Since there are eight M-stars (small stars) within 10 light-years of Earth, we should conservatively expect to find three Earth-sized planets in the habitable zones of their parent star.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, these estimates are very surprising.  Last decade we had no data on likely frequency of earth-like planets and relatively little data on frequency of exoplanets.  I was someone who thought exoplanets would be very common (which they are), but I thought earth-like planets would be relatively rare.  But it looks like that guess was off.  And if current estimates are accurate, and there are three Earth-like planets within 10 light-years of Earth, we should expect some BIG discoveries in the next two decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?  Because of the launch of the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Webb_Space_Telescope"&gt;James Webb Space Telescope&lt;/a&gt; (JWST).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/CANiQ6U.png" alt="JWST"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember a few years ago I went to a special presentation at McMaster University with my granddad and a friend about the first image ever recorded of an exoplanet.  I was excited, but I knew before the presentation started that what we were going to be observing would be a grainy pixel on a dark black screen.  Even our best telescopes are very poor at directly detecting exoplanets (which is why all exoplanet discoveries are made indirectly by either a) detecting the light they bend when they cross their parent star(s) or b) their gravitation effects on their parent star(s)).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when the JWST (successor to the Hubble Space Telescope) is launched in 2018, we will be able to directly detect exoplanets within 25 light-years of our star system.  This means that if Kopparapu and others are correct we are going to be able to see images of other earth-like planets in the 2020s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll let that thought sink in a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait!  It gets better.  The JWST can also determine the chemical composition of planets.  This means that not only will we get detailed images of other Earth-like planets soon but also we will likely be able to tell if those planets are home to life.  This is because life creates, transforms, and regulates the biosphere, radically altering a planets chemical composition.  Obviously we will not be able to identify species and get specific biological information, but we would likely be able to tell if they were carbon-based life forms that depended on oxygen and hydrogen for survival (for example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this doesn’t get you interested in scientific discovery and the future of human understanding, I don’t know what will.  The discoveries of the past two years in astronomy definitely help us conceptualize our place within the Milky Way.  However, these discoveries make me even more excited for what is just around the corner.  We are on the technological edge of making the most profound discoveries in the history of science: finding another earth.  And if you think about how much &lt;a href="http://theratchet.ca/technology-for-the-world"&gt;seeing a picture of our planet from space did to our understanding of life and our place within the universe&lt;/a&gt;, just wait until you see &lt;strong&gt;another Earth&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/O8-F_VgMdQU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://theratchet.ca/another-earth</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:francis,2012:Post/who-then-can-see-the-future</id>
    <published>2013-03-14T18:17:42-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T18:17:42-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/txg3owcCpeI/who-then-can-see-the-future" />
    <author>
      <name>Francis Pedraza</name>
      <uri>http://francispedraza.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Who, then, can see the future?</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s put a twist on a favorite childhood question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you were an investor (so financial profit was your primary motive)&lt;/em&gt;, and you could choose a superpower, which would you take? Would you scale walls, or fly, or see faraway objects? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the choice, I think you would be wise to answer: &lt;em&gt;D) None of the above.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my last post, “&lt;a href="http://francispedraza.com/the-philosopher-kings"&gt;The Philosopher Kings&lt;/a&gt;”, I argued that the single skill that would come to differentiate successful captains of industry - the superheroes, if you will - from their otherwise talented and competent peers - us mere mortals - would be their &lt;em&gt;ability to think intelligently about the future&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;D) None of the above&lt;/em&gt; then &lt;em&gt;E) Other. Fill in the _____.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s fill in the blank with &lt;em&gt;the ability to see the future&lt;/em&gt; and imagine, for a moment, what we could do. Even if you could only gaze ten seconds ahead, or, for that matter, even one second ahead, you could make an endless amount of money. That is, of course, until the SEC finds out and bans you from trading with such an unfair advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends who work at banks on Wall Street tell me that the most expensive real estate in the world is the server room next to the New York Stock Exchange’s routing system, because if you can transact orders even a fraction of a second faster than the rest of the market, you can provide liquidity with high frequency trading and make a spread by buying from the sellers and selling to the buyers. Even if the spread is tiny, if you can do it enough times and with enough volume, over time you can make a fortune. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you could gaze even farther ahead, say a week, or a month, you would have an even larger and more unfair advantage. You would choose the security - a stock, for example - which you knew was going to make the most dramatic move, and invest in it heavily, and with as much leverage the market would lend you, and then you’d make a fortune. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the days tell you their secrets, you become a trader on Wall Street. If the years tell you their secrets, you become a venture capitalist on Sand Hill Road. You provide every round of financing to the next Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an interesting thought experiment, because the more you think about it, the more you realize how little hard information about the future you need to possess to become rich, and that the more information you have, the fewer and more targeted and more leveraged your investments would become. You wouldn’t need to have a portfolio. Portfolios are for investment managers who know they’ll have some winners and some losers, so they spread the risk around. Instead, as a rational profit-seeking actor, you would put everything you’ve got (or as much as they’ll let you) into the biggest winners in a descending order until you have no capital left to invest. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder how long it would take someone with this superpower to amass the first trillion dollar fortune. Less than ten years, certainly. Perhaps less than five. Or maybe, even then, I underestimate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why entertain this fiction? Because it is a practical fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes my point for me. Information about the future is valuable. Infinitely more so than gold. The prophet is the goose that lays the golden eggs. Only a fool would butcher that goose for dinner. Only a fool would trade that information for bullion. Yet it’s so easy to be a fool, and fools there are in legion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if there were a way for us, mere mortals, to drink a drop of some magical elixir that gave us that superpower for just a moment? What if it were possible for you and I to glimpse the future, if only through the fog? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a way. It’s there for the taking. And are we fools not to seize at the opportunity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, by proxy: the ability to think intelligently about the future is as close as we can come to actually seeing the future, and that is certainly close enough to reap the benefits, although not close enough to be error-proof. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who, then, can glimpse the future? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Midas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be continued&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/txg3owcCpeI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://francispedraza.com/who-then-can-see-the-future</feedburner:origLink></entry>
</feed>
