<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xml:lang="en-US">
  <id>tag:svbtle.com,2012:/feed</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://svbtle.com" />
  
  <title>Svbtle Featured</title>
  <updated>2013-04-04T11:19:41-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Svbtle.com</name>
    <uri>http://svbtle.com</uri>
    <email>hello@svbtle.com</email>
  </author>
  <generator>Svbtle.com</generator>
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/svbtle" /><feedburner:info uri="svbtle" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>svbtle</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><entry>
    <id>tag:bradmccarty,2012:Post/facebook-home-and-first-my-personal-hell</id>
    <published>2013-04-04T11:19:41-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T11:19:41-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/jVhmBY-pQP4/facebook-home-and-first-my-personal-hell" />
    <author>
      <name>Brad McCarty</name>
      <uri>http://uptake.co</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Facebook Home (and First) -- My Personal Hell</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If I had to consider what my personal version of hell would be like, it would be senseless arguments, baseless debates and uneducated ranting, shoved into my face at all hours of the day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be updates from &amp;ldquo;friends&amp;rdquo;, concerning things that nobody cares about such as little Billy&amp;#39;s first poo poo of the day (there will be 4 more such updates from this person in the next 24 hours.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yes, and between the times when I&amp;#39;m trying not to wretch from the vile filth that these so-called friends are spewing forth, I&amp;#39;ll be shown ads. Ads for things about which I couldn&amp;#39;t possibly care less. Because targeting only works if your audience is being truthful about themselves and allowing you to see it, targeted ads largely fail on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s exactly what Facebook has decided to provide, with &lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/facebook/2013/04/04/the-facebook-phone-is-here-htc-and-att-reveal-the-htc-first/?fromcat=all"&gt;the release of Home&lt;/a&gt; and its companion phone, First. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we marinate, for just a moment, on the stupidity of having to tell your friends &amp;ldquo;Yeah, it&amp;#39;s an HTC First&amp;rdquo;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, but what is it after it&amp;#39;s an HTC? You see where I&amp;#39;m going with this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal version of hell. And Facebook wants me to pay $99 for it. Or I can get it from the Android Market in a few days. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I should give my executioner a hand with that noose. It seems like a much better option than having Facebook any further involved with my life. There are, after all, many reasons that &lt;a href="http://uptake.co/something-ive-noticed-since-leaving-facebook"&gt;I left&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/jVhmBY-pQP4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://uptake.co/facebook-home-and-first-my-personal-hell</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:EAKoester,2012:Post/the-valley-attitude-and-why-you-need-to-get-some-of-it</id>
    <published>2013-04-04T09:52:55-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T09:52:55-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/KEn3PyN9vyU/the-valley-attitude-and-why-you-need-to-get-some-of-it" />
    <author>
      <name>Eric Koester</name>
      <uri>http://ekoester.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The 'Valley' Attitude and Why You Need to Get Some of It</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Valley is not just a place anymore, it&amp;#39;s a mind set, it&amp;#39;s a way of looking to things.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; - Shervin Pishevar (@Shervin)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who has &amp;#39;lived&amp;#39; in three different startup scenes in the past five years (Seattle, San Francisco Bay Area and now DC), I get asked a lot about what separates them all and whether people should just up and move to the Bay Area if they really want to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Startups-a-roni, the San Francisco Treat&lt;/strong&gt;
There is something incredibly unique in the Bay Area, but it&amp;#39;s not the weather, the tax rates or the smart phone penetration.  Turns out, the Bay Area (or the Valley as I sorta hate to call it) has something damn important: attitude.  It&amp;#39;s that attitude that pushes people to think longer term, dream a little bigger and team up a little more.  It&amp;#39;s a bit of a &amp;ldquo;we don&amp;#39;t really care what you think unless you are here&amp;rdquo; vibe.  And frankly, it works.  I didn&amp;#39;t understand that attitude while I was living in Seattle (I frankly thought it was a bit overrated), but once we plunked Zaarly down in Mint Plaza in SoMa, it became completely clear: the attitude to win is why more Bay Area startups with and is frankly contagious for the entrepreneurs that are living and working in the Bay Area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not to say that places like Seattle or DC aren&amp;#39;t great ecosystems in their own right.  They are both creating companies and will foster startups, and I&amp;#39;m more impressed every day by the startups I&amp;#39;m seeing.  BUT, you won&amp;#39;t get the attitude I see in &amp;#39;Valley&amp;#39; entrepreneurs without spending some quality time with the people that make up the SF scene.  I&amp;#39;d even go so far as to say that NYC has a touch of that attitude, but it&amp;#39;s not quite pervasive like I&amp;#39;ve experienced in San Francisco.  You get the sense that it&amp;#39;s okay to dream big, talk a little crazy, and maybe screw up royally&amp;hellip; but everyone else is doing it so it&amp;#39;s cool.  That&amp;#39;s the attitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So You&amp;#39;re Saying I Should Just Up and Move to SF?&lt;/strong&gt;
Okay, so just what am I saying here?  Am I playing the violin and saying &amp;#39;so sad for you&amp;#39; if you live in Peoria or Dallas or LA?  No, far from it.  In fact, I think today more than ever it is okay to live wherever you are and start a company there (as Steve Case says, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;#39;s the rise of the rest.&amp;rdquo;)  Instead, I&amp;#39;m saying any entrepreneur or startup person should be spending time in the Bay Area or with people who are from or have that Bay Area attitude.  It&amp;#39;s a bit hard to describe, but you want to develop that same attitude that says, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;#39;s a bit crazy, but let&amp;#39;s give it a shot.&amp;rdquo;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting and living that &amp;#39;Valley&amp;#39; attitude requires a bit of a different thought process.  That may mean you forgo the safe lead gen revenue model for a shot at building a transactional marketplace.  Or that may mean you decide to join four other talented people to cofound something rather founding five smaller companies.  Or that may mean you move to SF for a month and just meet, learn and experience before you really start your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rise of the Rest; Learn from the Best&lt;/strong&gt;
Okay, that was super cheezy and I apologize.  But it sorta works.  While I&amp;#39;ve met and hung out with great entrepreneurs in Seattle and new friends and entrepreneurs in DC, the ones that I&amp;#39;d invest in are those that embrace the uniqueness of the &amp;#39;Valley&amp;#39; attitude.  And I don&amp;#39;t think that&amp;#39;s to say they need to up and move their companies to San Francisco &amp;ndash; it&amp;#39;s just that they are attending conferences, drinking with SF-based entrepreneurs, talking to investors on Sand Hill Road, and embracing what is going on there.  And I don&amp;#39;t mean like doing an investor pitch session, but actually going to Sightglass or Blue Bottle or Coupa Cafe or Rosewood to talk with people and feel/experience their enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m bullish on the fact that entrepreneurship is being democratized in places like Des Moines or Tucson or Boulder or Detroit.  But I believe that startup companies that move the needle, need to experience and &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; why the Valley attitude has been going strong for the past couple decades.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So get out there.  Setup some coffees, some lunches, some meetups and some tours.  There are plenty of great entrepreneurs, investors and community members who would love to show you around.  It&amp;#39;s an investment in attitude worth making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/KEn3PyN9vyU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ekoester.com/the-valley-attitude-and-why-you-need-to-get-some-of-it</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:nate,2012:Post/how-to-innovate-focus-on-jobs-to-be-done</id>
    <published>2013-04-04T09:31:28-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T09:31:28-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/ve12SHz9E8Y/how-to-innovate-focus-on-jobs-to-be-done" />
    <author>
      <name>Nathan Kontny</name>
      <uri>http://ninjasandrobots.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>How to innovate. Focus on jobs to be done.</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a struggle for me to make something innovative. Often it seems like everything good has already been done. There&amp;#39;s already at least 20 competitors doing what I want to do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://draftin.com"&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt; is a software project I&amp;#39;ve been working on to help people &lt;a href="http://draftin.com"&gt;write better&lt;/a&gt;. So far I&amp;#39;ve been incredibly blessed to receive more positive feedback on this creation than anything else I&amp;#39;ve ever personally produced. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before this I was getting stuck on some project management software I was making. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clayton Christensen is the famous author of business books like Innovators Solution. Clayton advises wannabe innovators to focus on the jobs people are trying to hire products for. He describes a fast food company that figured out how to finally improve their product development when they stopped worrying about &amp;ldquo;market research&amp;rdquo; and instead spent time figuring out what jobs people were hiring their milkshakes for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to Clayton&amp;#39;s &amp;ldquo;jobs to be done&amp;rdquo; thinking, I&amp;#39;ve enjoyed Denis J. Hauptly&amp;#39;s writing on the subject: &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Something-Really-New-Creating-Innovative/dp/0814400329/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1365058293&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=something+really+new"&gt;Something Really New: Three Simple Steps to Creating Truly Innovative Products&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denis like Clayton, focuses on tasks people are trying to accomplish. Once you figure out the tasks, break them down into their individual steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innovation is simply removing or combining steps. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I make coffee with a set of steps. One interesting bit is that we&amp;#39;ll take the coffee pot and gently jam the pot into the area of the refridgerator that dispenses water. We jam it in such a way that the dispenser keeps dispensing water as we walk away. We do that because we multitask the coffee preparation, and we&amp;#39;re using the sink to wash the rest of the coffee maker&amp;#39;s parts while the refridgerator fills the pot with water. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve timed everything pretty well that we know when to go grab the pot. Usually. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last weekend, my in-laws were in town for Easter and my wife&amp;#39;s birthday. Now I&amp;#39;m making coffee for more people than I&amp;#39;m used to. I&amp;#39;m in the middle of the process, and my wife&amp;#39;s father is buzzing at the door to come inside from his walk with his cigar. The dog is going crazy barking. And I&amp;#39;m trying to quiet her down. A couple minutes go by and I notice&amp;hellip; Oh crap! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s water pouring out of the refridgerator dispenser all over the floor. I forgot about the pot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denis leads his book with an interesting example of innovating a commodity like water faucets. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He provides some typical market research: customers really like the style of their water faucets. With that information he encourages you to start brainstorming new faucet ideas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His next few pages completely predicted my &amp;ldquo;innovations&amp;rdquo;. I had some ideas on customizing the style of the faucet. As does everyone else it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what he explores next is thinking I&amp;#39;ve been working very hard to incorporate into how I build products. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He breaks down the tasks people have when using faucets. If you&amp;#39;re in a kitchen, one task might be to bake. If you list out all the steps to that process, you might notice that getting a measuring cup and measuring so many cups of water might be steps an innovative faucet could eliminate, if you had the ability to ask the faucet for measured quantities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know a faucet like that in my refrigerator would save me time when making coffee and avoid the mess I created when my in-laws were here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Draft I was creating a really simple project management tool for personal projects, but it didn&amp;#39;t seem like it was getting anyone to really notice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I forced myself to dig into the tasks I was using my project management software for. I found I was using it a lot for writing. I noticed I would store drafts of blog posts in the notes section of my tool. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Committing even more of my thinking to the jobs to be done approach, I focused entirely on tasks I have as a writer and a blogger, and retooling my software to eliminate steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I kept finding myself writing comments in blogs, Hacker News, or Reddit. But as I wrote them something would come up, and I&amp;#39;d save an unfinished copy of that comment in my tool. I&amp;#39;d eventually return to it later, finish it and then go through the process of copying and pasting it back into the comment box. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The steps roughly look like this: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+a in the original comment box to select all text. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+c to copy text. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+t to open a new tab to my project management app. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigate to a new note. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+v to paste the text. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save the text. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come back to navigate to the saved comment. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish writing the comment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+a to select all the text. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+c to copy the text. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open a new tab to find the comment box where I had stopped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl+v&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagined what it would be like to remove and combine some of these steps, and then &lt;a href="http://ninjasandrobots.com/draft-everywhere"&gt;created a Chrome extension for Draft&lt;/a&gt; that automates a lot of this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aren&amp;#39;t talking about curing cancer here or eliminating fossil fuels. I know that. I wish I could. This is just removing a few simple steps I do over and over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the response has been awesome. Someone said: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Chromium app is a little miracle!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe the most telling of all is someone who wasn&amp;#39;t even going to use Draft, until the Chrome extension:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I tried Draft (&lt;a href="https://t.co/9NCnyxuuyR" title="https://draftin.com/"&gt;draftin.com&lt;/a&gt;) for the first time I wasn&amp;rsquo;t impressed. Now, after just few weeks I am. It&amp;rsquo;s really nice editor.&lt;/p&gt;— Marcin Bujacz (@Sainti) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sainti/status/318033594574585856"&gt;March 30, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; 

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;@&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/natekontny"&gt;natekontny&lt;/a&gt; Chrome extension with syncing between Draft and other editors is really great.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Marcin Bujacz (@Sainti) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sainti/status/318043188009000960"&gt;March 30, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you&amp;#39;re struggling to figure out how to create a product amongst all the competition doing all the same things, I strongly encourage you to spend a lot more time exploring tasks people are trying to use a product for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are all the steps people take to do those tasks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might find you don&amp;#39;t have to do anything crazy to eliminate or combine just a few of them to create something people finally start noticing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/natekontny"&gt;It would be awesome to meet you on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want more about this topic, I highly recommend this 4 minute video of Clayton on milkshakes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/VmbSpTJXozk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s also folks like Bob Moesta from The Rewired Group and Jason Fried from 37signals who spend time exploring jobs to be done thinking in their writing, &lt;a href="http://www.therewiredgroup.com/category/jobs-to-be-done-radio/"&gt;podcasts&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://37signals.com/theswitchworkshop"&gt;workshops&lt;/a&gt;. Great stuff to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/ve12SHz9E8Y" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ninjasandrobots.com/how-to-innovate-focus-on-jobs-to-be-done</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/communication-and-the-artist</id>
    <published>2013-04-04T08:52:58-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T08:52:58-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/MuqyOCKial8/communication-and-the-artist" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Communication And The Artist</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From time to time I get discouraged that I&amp;#39;m not a painter or film maker or singer or songwriter. I get discouraged that I can&amp;#39;t communicate in drawings or melodies or capture video that&amp;#39;s perfectly framed. Words are the one communication method I cling to, though those aren&amp;#39;t always on my side either. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hypothesis is that any idea, thought, or story can be equally shared through any form of art, if the artist is skilled enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a writer penned a novel about a life cut short with the effects felt by the family long after, a painter would be able to convey the same emotion and feeling into a painting. A film maker would be able to create a movie one in the same, and even a video game programer would be able to tell the story with the same power through game play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve always measured myself against this untested, comforting and horrifying, hypothesis. Even though I may at times long for a different way to express thoughts, I&amp;#39;ve found comfort that with enough time and effort, words will accomplish what a song, painting, film, or other piece of art could. The horrifying aspect that comes along is that if writing hasn&amp;#39;t accomplished the power and emotion a different kind of art could, then my work wasn&amp;#39;t good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be intimidating to hear a spine tingling music album, only to have to write about it with flimsy words that are left pale in the sight of rock &amp;#39;n roll. After finishing a emotional page-turning journey, living in the author&amp;#39;s world for so long, only to then see your silly toy guitar not as an instrument, but as strings hanging off some wood. A movie with both visual and audio connections to the audience can easily make a few colored paints seem childish and inferior. Great art with great conviction often inspires, but for those with similar creative goals, powerful art, in any form, can occasionally be a fierce blow. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thought, &amp;ldquo;I could never do something that great,&amp;rdquo; has struck us all at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately though, the world spins on inspiration, not art forms competing against each other. The olympic athlete about to compete in front every nation dons a pair of headphones and sinks into a world of sound. The musician sits at home and watches the spectacle of the best of the best running the race and is inspired. The event, captured in photographs, later seen by elementary kids too young to remember at the time. Years later, remembering the glory captured in those photographs, one of those kids decides they want to run the race too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/MuqyOCKial8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/communication-and-the-artist</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/anatomy-of-a-reference-check</id>
    <published>2013-04-04T07:44:13-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T07:44:13-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/ltGRvO1DarI/anatomy-of-a-reference-check" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Anatomy of a Reference Check</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24571557261162_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24571557261162_raw.jpg" alt="reference.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tomtunguz.com/breaking-down-a-typical-vcstartup-diligence-process"&gt;Reference checks are part and parcel of the VC diligence process&lt;/a&gt; and most hiring processes. They are also one of the two most important analyses in hiring, next to the interview. Below, I&amp;#39;ve outlined my standard question set. I&amp;#39;m curious to hear feedback on what other questions or techniques might work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Types of References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it&amp;#39;s valuable to speak to references who have worked with the candidate in different roles. Below is a list of typical roles in rank order.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peers&lt;/strong&gt; provide fair feedback. They often competed or worked closely together and are often the most impartial checks.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managers&lt;/strong&gt; offer the best insight on day-to-day interactions and work quality.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direct reports&lt;/strong&gt; tend to be a bit more positive than others. But they provide insight about culture, team building and mentoring.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close colleagues&lt;/strong&gt; are the least valuable checks. Friends at work don&amp;#39;t have much direct experience to share save for personality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reference Check Outline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a list of questions prefaced by the rationale for the question. I&amp;#39;ll describe the &lt;strong&gt;referencer&lt;/strong&gt; as the person I&amp;#39;m chatting with and the &lt;strong&gt;referenced&lt;/strong&gt; as the person who I&amp;#39;m considering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background questions &lt;/strong&gt;provide context for the referencer. My goal is to understand the referencer&amp;#39;s background (technical/manager/etc) which informs the types of questions I can ask. I&amp;#39;m also looking to understand the referencer&amp;#39;s perspective on an organization. A sales manager will observe different characteristics than an engineer.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Questions Where do you work? How long have you been there? What kinds of teams do you manage?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relationship questions &lt;/strong&gt;establish the biases of the referencer toward the referenced. At this point, I&amp;#39;m also looking to establish whether referencer will provide a balanced reference. A skewed reference either entirely positive or exclusively negative is basically worthless and should serve only as a directional data point. Also, I look to establish the recency of the relationship.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Questions: How do you know the person being referenced? How long did you work with them? How did you work together? How long ago?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work questions&lt;/strong&gt; elucidate the type of work the referenced performed. I&amp;#39;m typically matching up the actual work to what the referenced has represented and also making sure it&amp;#39;s a fit for the role in case of a hire, or the sector, in case of an investment. Management experience is best examined here.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Questions: What was the referenced&amp;#39;s role in the company? Could you share some examples of the kinds of work the referenced performed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strengths&lt;/strong&gt; should be matched to the demands of the role or company. These are self-evident. A PM should have good communication and management skills. Engineers should have relevant technical skills. Examples are critical here.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Questions: Where does the referenced person shine? What kinds of work the referenced prefer to do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complementary skills. &lt;/strong&gt;Asking for weaknesses tends to put the referencer on the defensive, as if he or she is sharing something illicit. Instead, I ask the referencer the question below. Everyone has strengths and weaknesses. And most jobs require teamwork. The best team members complement each other&amp;#39;s weaknesses. This is an indirect path at reaching the same answer. It doesn&amp;#39;t always work, but it&amp;#39;s my preferred route. I spend the most time of the interview on this question.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Questions: What kinds of people does the referenced need around him/her to be successful?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Influence. &lt;/strong&gt;Understanding how a person is influenced is important. Everyone responds to a different approach. Some are very rational and respond to data. Others react to vision and passion. Still others might be consensus driven.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Questions: How is the referenced persuaded or convinced? What kinds of motivation does he/she respond best to?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day-to-day personality. &lt;/strong&gt;This line of questions aims at understanding the person&amp;#39;s culture in a work environment: serious, funny, team-oriented or individual contributor, darker or sunnier outlook. My purpose is to match working styles.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Questions: What is it like to work with the referenced day-to-day? How would you characterize your typical interactions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Ethics&lt;/strong&gt; is a checkbox question. It&amp;#39;s uncomfortable to ask but important to rule out any bad actors.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Questions: Any questions of ethics?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social proof. &lt;/strong&gt;Ask the referencer about their willingness to work with the referenced again.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Questions: Would you hire or work with this person again? How highly do you regard this person? Top 25%, 10%, 5%, 1%?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Suggestions?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have any suggestions or ideas for how to improve this outline? Or other tips on reference checks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/ltGRvO1DarI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/anatomy-of-a-reference-check</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ryancash,2012:Post/passcode-lock-for-apps</id>
    <published>2013-04-03T19:28:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-03T19:28:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/44TZlcR7V5A/passcode-lock-for-apps" />
    <author>
      <name>Ryan Cash</name>
      <uri>http://indygrab.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Passcode lock for apps</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It would be nice to have an advanced option in iOS to set a passcode for individual apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Passcode Lock screen, there could be a list of all apps installed on the device. A user could then choose to require the passcode for specific apps – for example Messages, Facebook, Email, and Photos. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would probably require a quick option to turn on &amp;ldquo;Lock Apps&amp;rdquo; (perhaps in the Multitasking Tray), to prevent people from having to enter the passcode every time they use the device themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people pass their iOS devices to friends and family – to show them something, to let them play a game, or simply because they&amp;#39;ve asked to see the new iPhone, etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we don&amp;#39;t want people looking around at personal stuff, and other times there&amp;#39;s sensitive business information we can&amp;#39;t have people seeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option would be a &amp;ldquo;Guest&amp;rdquo; mode of sorts, which would also lock out certain things you&amp;#39;ve preselected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither of these options are very Apple-like, I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps there&amp;#39;s a much better way to solve this problem – I haven&amp;#39;t spent too much time thinking about it. I don&amp;#39;t really expect anything like this to ever be implemented, but it would be nice to have as an option (off by default).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would definitely be even more handy on iPad – a device that&amp;#39;s often a shared computer in a household.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/44TZlcR7V5A" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://indygrab.me/passcode-lock-for-apps</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:daslee,2012:Post/welcome-back-coach</id>
    <published>2013-04-03T15:39:41-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-03T15:39:41-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/GhQWarZvEBk/welcome-back-coach" />
    <author>
      <name>David Lee</name>
      <uri>http://daslee.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Welcome Back, Coach</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am thrilled to welcome (back) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/brianp"&gt;Brian Pokorny&lt;/a&gt; to SV Angel! He will join as a General Partner starting  today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people in the tech community already know Brian, a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;Coach&amp;rdquo;. He was most recently the CEO of DailyBooth/Batch, a startup that was acquired by AirBnB. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to DailyBooth, Brian and I worked with Ron as partners for SV Angel on investment decisions and adding value to portfolio companies. Thus he is stepping back into a familiar role. However, he returns with a wealth of operational and startup knowledge from his 3 years at a startup. This experience will be invaluable insight for our portfolio founders. Many of the best young founders will already attest that he&amp;#39;s become a true &amp;ldquo;Coach&amp;rdquo; and trusted advisor to many entrepreneurs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian has been angel investing since 2006 and reviewing investment opportunities since 2004. Having seen so many opportunities, he has unique insight into the trends and cycles related to the Internet. Some of his personal angel investments include Twitter, Square, OMGPOP, Milo, Chomp, Tweetdeck, Circle, Bump, Posterous, Milk, Couple, Elepath, and MessageMe. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a personal note, I&amp;#39;ve known Brian since 2005 and we became friends through working together at Google. And so it is great for me to do business with a friend. Welcome back, &amp;ldquo;Coach&amp;rdquo;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/GhQWarZvEBk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://daslee.me/welcome-back-coach</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:dkr,2012:Post/being-introverted</id>
    <published>2013-04-03T10:23:37-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-03T10:23:37-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/_Wi6Z9ak08E/being-introverted" />
    <author>
      <name>D. Keith Robinson</name>
      <uri>http://howtomakelightning.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Being Introverted</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Introversion is something I&amp;#39;ve wanted to write about publicly for a few years now. Essentially ever since I began to understand it a bit&amp;ndash;and understand that I&amp;#39;m pretty damn introverted.  It&amp;#39;s a complex subject, something hard to understand, even for those people who consider themselves introverts. It&amp;#39;s also hard to explain. It&amp;#39;s also not a black and white thing. Some people are more introverted than others, some times interactions with others come easy, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I&amp;#39;ve sat down to write something, I can&amp;#39;t seem to find the words to describe what I want to say about it. That&amp;#39;s why I was so excited when I saw &lt;a href="http://the-pastry-box-project.net/chris-coyier/2013-april-3/"&gt;this piece from Chris Coyier today&lt;/a&gt;. He&amp;#39;s put to words something I&amp;#39;ve not been able to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://the-pastry-box-project.net/chris-coyier/2013-april-3/"&gt;Give it a read.&lt;/a&gt;  Then, if you want, come back for my story, culled from a draft post that&amp;#39;s been sitting here for well over a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Introversion: My Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years I would have considered myself sort of shy, but never introverted. I mean, I like people. I like being around people. If you were to meet me with my batteries all charged up, you&amp;#39;d probably never consider me to be introverted. But I am.  I really enjoy, and require, alone time.  I&amp;#39;m classically introverted: interaction with people drains me. Even talking intently to one person drains me. I need to prepare for being social; even the comfortable social time I enjoy with good friends and co-workers.  I actually enjoy big parties with lots of people, because it&amp;#39;s easier to limit my social interactions. I can kind of blend in and it&amp;#39;s easier to duck out. Irish goodbye FTW!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introversion is very often associated with laziness. Which just goes to show how little people understand about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, I had a friend of mine call me lazy quite often, referring to my desire to stay home, in my room and hang out with myself. In his mind I was probably sleeping. Far, far from the truth. I was reading, drawing, learning to DJ, playing with computers, writing, etc. I just preferred to do this on my own, and I still do. That&amp;#39;s not to say I don&amp;#39;t enjoy collaboration or social time, I just get recharged and powered up for that by my time to myself. It is true, when I was younger I preferred to be truly alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I get older I find that I&amp;#39;m much more comfortable being alone with others. I can co-work to great productivity and enjoy the presence of others (as long as there&amp;#39;s no talking.) I really enjoy going to shows, having a drink and a good read in a bar, or walking around town taking photos by myself.  It&amp;#39;s really the &lt;em&gt;interaction&lt;/em&gt; that drains me, not the presence of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alone time means a lot to me, and when I look back at it, it&amp;#39;s been instrumental in shaping me as an adult, both in my personal and professional lives.  I&amp;#39;ve always thought it was kind of strange, my desire to be alone, but as the years went by as I learned more and encountered people even more introverted than I am, I began to realize that it&amp;#39;s not all that strange, and that there is great benefit in this time.  I&amp;#39;m sure it&amp;#39;s hard for socially driven folks to understand, and it seems like our society is geared towards an extroverted life style, but that&amp;#39;s ok. I&amp;#39;ve found it&amp;#39;s not all that difficult to surround myself with people who understand and accept that I need time to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, I think, I&amp;#39;ve come to realize that it&amp;#39;s this desire to be alone, to get to know myself and to have time to tinker, read, learn, write and explore all on my own has been a big part of what makes me who I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good thing I like myself. Haha. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/_Wi6Z9ak08E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://howtomakelightning.com/being-introverted</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/lessons-learnt-on-blogging-3-years-in</id>
    <published>2013-04-03T07:11:12-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-03T07:11:12-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/KnrkHAF-UGg/lessons-learnt-on-blogging-3-years-in" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>What I've Learned about Blogging in 3 Years</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24564321885132_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24564321885132_raw.jpg" alt="typewriter.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been writing for three years now and it&amp;#39;s been a ton of fun. I hope to continue to write for many more. Along the way so far, I&amp;#39;ve learned a few lessons on frequency, content type, idea generation, voice, titles and distribution. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Frequency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two schools of thought on blogging frequency: high frequency vs high quality. At this point, it&amp;#39;s unclear to me which is better for building an audience because both work. Each camp has its exemplars of success. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the frequency camp, Fred Wilson posts every day and I suspect this is because when he started seven years ago it was essential to write daily to train an audience to visit avc.com. Today social media (twitter, hacker news) generates most of the traffic for a blog by bubbling up the best content. Building a core audience that visits tomtunguz.com every day is important to me, but I post every day because each writing book I&amp;#39;ve read recommends it. And I figure if I&amp;#39;m writing a blog post, I may as well publish it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write sometime between 5 and 7am each morning when it&amp;#39;s quiet and I can focus. Flights are also good times for blogging. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Representing the other point of view, Chris Dixon and Paul Graham pen monthly essays and posts which are better revised and often succinct, witty and always very well written. This technique concentrates engagement, maximizes social media reach and ensures great content. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Content Type&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never can predict with much accuracy which content will resonate with readers who tend to be startup founders and employees. But the most successful posts tend either to create an emotional connection through a personal story or share some detailed tactical advice.  The best posts enable readers to see a reflection of themselves in the story because they have or are living through something similar. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading and dissecting classic novels and well written magazine articles helped me begin to understand how other authors do this well. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BurtHelm"&gt;Burt Helm&lt;/a&gt; from Inc magazine shared &lt;a href="http://www.gq.com/news-politics/big-issues/201005/suicide-catchers-nanjing-bridge-yangtze-river-mr-chen"&gt;this GQ article about Suicide Catchers in China as a great example of storytelling.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One example of a successful emotional/storytelling post is &lt;a href="http://tomtunguz.com/the-biggest-professional-challenge-of-my-career-communication"&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Biggest Challenge of My Professional Career: Communication&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href="http://tomtunguz.com/your-startups-10-most-important-metrics"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your Startup&amp;#39;s 10 Most Important Metrics&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is example of a very tactical post that readers enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing every day demands lots of ideas. I jot down notes during conversations, sift through my calendar, read the news, and examine what&amp;#39;s trending on social media. Sometimes, I don&amp;#39;t have any ideas and to jog a stream I search for a strong opinion or reaction I&amp;#39;ve had recently. That seems to help breaking my writer&amp;#39;s block. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep a list of these ideas in draft blog posts. Sometimes I just jot down a title and other times it&amp;#39;s a jumble of ideas. Then I&amp;#39;ll go back the next day or in a few days to complete the content and edit the post. At any given time, I&amp;#39;m working on 3 or 4 drafts. I might hold onto a draft/idea for a month or two to let it mature a bit so I can better express it or gather examples. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks of practicing, storing and retaining ideas becomes part of a daily routine. Nevertheless, some days, I feel like I&amp;#39;m wading through mud to write a few paragraphs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Voice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog readers respond to strong individual voices. A blog shouldn&amp;#39;t resemble the Economist or the New Yorker whose editorial teams use style guides to ensure a consistent tone which is larger than any individual writer. The whole point of a blog is to hear a real human voice. It&amp;#39;s something I forget sometimes so I try to write the first draft the way I might speak and edit that output. Hemingway is my inspiration for human tone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Titles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Titles matter. I spend lots of time on my titles but I didn&amp;#39;t always which was a big mistake. Looking back through the first year or so of my blog titles, I can see now they were awful. Here&amp;#39;s an early one: &amp;ldquo;Binary pointillism - the intersection of Seurat and Felton.&amp;rdquo; Barf. Who wants to read that? It sounds like a dissertation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/danshipper"&gt;Dan Shipper&lt;/a&gt; taught me the best titles read like tweets. My goal is to drive as many retweets as possible so I shouldn&amp;#39;t ask the user to construct an interesting tweet on my behalf. Instead, I should make it easy for the reader to just hit a button and share something interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often write the title as the last step. It&amp;#39;s easier after having written the conclusion to summarize the point in 140 characters or fewer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Distribution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I post, I tweet the post, submit the post to Quibb and Hacker News. Then I monitor the reactions. If after 45 minutes, I don&amp;#39;t see many retweets or much engagement, I&amp;#39;ll try another title or two. Sometimes the post is to blame, but more often, I haven&amp;#39;t allured the reader with the right title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One blogger recommended ignoring the Google Analytics and Feedburner stats to me. I find that it helps quite a bit not to be so metrics focused. Then I&amp;#39;m not so concerned about the daily fluctuations but more on monthly stats, which is a better indicator of success. Nevertheless, &lt;a href="http://tomtunguz.com/how-to-measure-the-success-of-a-blog"&gt;I still haven&amp;#39;t figured out how best way to measure the success of this blog&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Patience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, it takes forever to build a blog that people know or read about or care about. For some, the reader base grows much much quicker than it did for me. Nevertheless building any kind of brand on the web through content or otherwise is a slow, incremental process. Every once in a while, I&amp;#39;ll reach the front page of Hacker News or spike on LinkedIn and I get an increase in readership. But it takes patience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find the more content I have produced, the more the blog pays dividends. Most of my posts are evergreen, timeless, so they appear in Google searches or are randomly resurrected in social media from time to time, rediscovered through some stroke of luck. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, blogging helps me refine my thinking and share it with people who are interested or curious. I hope this post helps motivate you to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;h/t to Stefano Bernardi @stefanobernardi, who inspired this post. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/KnrkHAF-UGg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/lessons-learnt-on-blogging-3-years-in</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:youssef,2012:Post/xbox-1440</id>
    <published>2013-04-02T16:24:38-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-02T16:24:38-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/n1wFGWED-DQ/xbox-1440" />
    <author>
      <name>Youssef Sarhan</name>
      <uri>http://sefsar.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Xbox 1440</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Convergence is inevitable, and Microsoft would be wise to acknowledge this. Microsoft should combine the Xbox console and screen. Consoles are at the mercy of the screens we plug them into. Most screens destroy the grade, the textures look terrible. If you value your developers, customers and the experience you&amp;#39;re building, you should value all aspects of it. Without knowing exactly what device the user is using, you&amp;#39;re designing for the lowest common denominator. Anyway, that&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the real opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They should call it Xbox 1440, it should have a 2560-by-1440 resolution display (hat-tip to &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/sean_nicholls"&gt;Sean&lt;/a&gt; for that idea), it should be super simple to set up, and it should &lt;em&gt;just work&lt;/em&gt;. One plug for power, and the rest is wireless. Controllers, internet, all wireless. They should call Netflix and Spotify, get them in as launch partners. If they&amp;#39;re even smarter they&amp;#39;ll start building something similar to &lt;a href="http://www.onlive.com/"&gt;OnLive&lt;/a&gt;. If you can stream HD movies, you should be able to stream HD games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft should market it as an entertainment platform, so even if you&amp;#39;re only using one feature you&amp;#39;re still getting an incredible product. This way it will appeal to more than gamers. I know I&amp;#39;d buy it. There, product category created and owned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/n1wFGWED-DQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sefsar.com/xbox-1440</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:parislemon,2012:Post/30-minutes</id>
    <published>2013-04-02T15:43:41-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-02T15:43:41-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/H0qPw_q7l1A/30-minutes" />
    <author>
      <name>MG Siegler</name>
      <uri>http://massivegreatness.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>30 Minutes</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_parislemon_24568959260664_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find the key is to think of a day as units of time, each unit consisting of no more than thirty minutes. Full hours can be a little bit intimidating and most activities take about half an hour. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— Will Freeman, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0H7VtFG9F-c"&gt;&lt;em&gt;About a Boy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have very poor time-management skills. It&amp;#39;s not that I sit around and do nothing — quite the opposite: once I commit to doing something, I have a hard time stopping. This often makes me late for basically everything in life. And on the flip side, it makes starting larger activities, like writing, even more daunting. I basically have to block off hours at a time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a full-time writer, this was less of a problem because I basically had one job: to write. Sure, I had a meeting here or there, but rarely more than one in a day. And often none at all. I was just chained to my desk all day, doing one thing. My calendar was simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href="http://crunchfund.com"&gt;an investor&lt;/a&gt;, my calendar is the exact opposite. I&amp;#39;m in meeting after meeting after meeting after meeting. As you might imagine, such a schedule exposed my time management issue. At first, this was a cause of great stress. But now, 18 months in (I can&amp;#39;t believe it has been 18 months either), I think I finally have a solid system down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30-minute meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this system won&amp;#39;t work for everyone. And indeed, it will be far from ideal for many people. But I&amp;#39;ve been pretty amazed how much more I can get done in a day by sticking to my Will Freeman-esque units of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, I would put a meeting on my books and leave it set for the setting that is the default on most calendars: one hour. Not only is a full hour intimidating — you only have 24 of them in a day, and really only 16-18 waking ones, and that&amp;#39;s if you&amp;#39;re &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; working — but I have found it to be excessive in the case of most meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Just to be clear, I&amp;#39;m talking about initial meetings here. Obviously, there often are plenty of reasons why longer meetings will be necessary on the road to an investment.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you go into a meeting knowing it&amp;#39;s set to be an hour long, I&amp;#39;ve found that all parties (myself included) will go out of their way to make sure they take up that full hour. That often means padding at the beginning of the conversation (the weather, sports, etc). And fillers at the end (unnecessary questions, &amp;ldquo;what&amp;#39;s the rest of your day look like?&amp;rdquo;, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For whatever reason, it seems to be built into our psyche that it&amp;#39;s rude to end a meeting early. So an hour meeting &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be an hour&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;Or more! Often, I&amp;#39;d find my hour meetings spilling beyond the 90-minute mark as well. Again, once I start something, I have a hard time stopping. This was the destroyer of entire days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30-minute meetings are so much sweeter. As long as you make the length clear at the beginning of the meeting, I find that everyone (again, myself included) gets right to the point and cuts out a lot of the filler and padding that makes up a ridiculous amount of every conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that may sound a bit crass. But pay attention to the next conversation you have — how much of it is filled with things that really don&amp;#39;t need to be said? A lot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, that&amp;#39;s a part of human nature and society — maybe you will make a connection with someone by something said in the filler time. But again, as I&amp;#39;ve been sticking to these 30-minute meetings, I&amp;#39;ve found that all parties are much happier. Entrepreneurs can get back to work. I can take some time to process the meeting rather than rushing to the next one that I&amp;#39;m already late for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with these 30-minute &amp;ldquo;units&amp;rdquo;, as Will Freeman notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s amazing how the day fills up, and I often wonder, to be absolutely honest, if I&amp;#39;d ever have time for a job; how do people cram them in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/H0qPw_q7l1A" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://massivegreatness.com/30-minutes</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:cadelllast,2012:Post/robot-sex-revolution</id>
    <published>2013-04-02T14:37:53-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-02T14:37:53-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/Tob7tm1u5xQ/robot-sex-revolution" />
    <author>
      <name>Cadell Last</name>
      <uri>http://theratchet.ca</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Robot Sex Revolution</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/iLldMLv.png" alt="robot sex"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The robotics revolution is coming.  In the not-to-distant future robots will completely transform our world in more profound ways than the internet did in the 1990s and 2000s.  The evidence for this coming revolution have already started to develop.  For example: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are already people that have &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Al5RhaJgxxU&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded"&gt;advanced robotic limbs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctors are &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=ffk55Qh7hBo"&gt;collaborating with advanced A.I.&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robots have been built to &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=knRyDcnUc4U&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded"&gt;develop like human children&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans are &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=76lIQtE8oDY#!"&gt;using their brains to communicate with robots&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers have &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6JNq1COqB_s&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded"&gt;designed robots with human-like skeletal and muscle-architecture&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers have already designed the early stages of a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=P_WRCyNQ9KY#!"&gt;human-like brain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B4jhMGzml7I"&gt;Research into A.I. with human language capabilities is accelerating at a faster pace than previously expected&lt;/a&gt;.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these examples represent the tip-of-the-iceberg in terms of what is currently possible.  Furthermore, this does not even begin to scratch the surface of what will be possible in the 2020s and 2030s.  As a result, I believe that research into the future of A.I. may be the most important area of research at the moment.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, even if robotics technology continues to evolve at its current pace, will robots ever be conscious entities that we have real relationships with?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="http://www.aeonmagazine.com/being-human/george-zarkadakis-love-artificial-intelligence/"&gt;recent Aeon Magazine article&lt;/a&gt;, George Zarkadakis wonders whether the ultimate goal of A.I. is to create conscious machines that we can love.  I will leave it for philosophers to decide whether that is our &amp;ldquo;ultimate goal&amp;rdquo; with the development of A.I.  However, I do believe that we will create robotic beings that we will fall in love with.  &lt;a href="http://www.theadvancedapes.com/theratchet/2013/1/6/the-substrate-of-mind"&gt;Whether or not they will actually be conscious is irrelevant&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a recent book titled &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Love-Sex-Robots-Human-Robot-Relationships/dp/0061359807"&gt;Sex and Love With Robots&lt;/a&gt; by artificial intelligence expert David Levy, Levy posits that this will happen by around 2050.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love with robots will be as normal as love with other humans while the number of sexual acts and lovemaking positions commonly practiced between humans will be extended, as robots teach us more than is in all of the world’s published sex manuals combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levy realistically expected that many people would have an intense negative emotional reaction to these ideas, stating that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would not surprise me if a significant proportion of readers deride these ideas until my predictions have been proved correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part, I agree with Levy.  In fact, my views on this issue are likely considered more extreme (or taboo) than his.  In my own theory of technological evolution, I feel as though this decade will witness the complete blurring of the &lt;a href="http://video.pbs.org/video/2337357546/"&gt;online and offline worlds&lt;/a&gt;.  In the next decade (2020s), I feel as though the same will happen with the biological and technological worlds.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blurring will include intimate relationships with robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human-like robots will most likely be physically and intellectually indistinguishable from humans towards the end of the 2020s.  This will inevitably spark massive societal conversations about the rights and role of robots within our society.  But perhaps more interestingly, this will also inevitably lead to situations where humans will have deep personal relationships with all kinds of robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I suspect people will view sexual partnership with robots in the same way people initially judged online dating last decade.  Over a relatively short period of time, once more and more people become accustomed to the new normal, the stigma against intimate relationships with robots should disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is why my views are probably more extreme than Levy&amp;#39;s.  Whereas he believes these intimate relationships will develop by 2050, I think that is a ridiculously conservative estimate.  By the 2030s robot-human sexual relationships will likely be quite pervasive.  I suspect that these sexual relationships will range from casual sex or prostitution to long-term bonds and marriage.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Henrik Christensen, founder of the European Robotics Research Network, thinks that sex with robots is only five years away.  Since he is referring to a very primitive type of robot, I pretty much agree.  He stated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are companies that already sell realistic sex dolls, and its just a matter of adding some electronics to them to add some vibration, or endowing the robots with a few audio responses.  That’s fairly primitive in terms of robotics, but the technology is already there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we have &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Siri_(software"&gt;started to have conversations with robots&lt;/a&gt;.  What happens when the mind of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Watson_(computer"&gt;Watson&lt;/a&gt; (or more advanced) is uploaded as software inside a robotic brain similar to the one designed by the University of Waterloo?  What happens when that brain is in the body of a human-like robot not dissimilar to those that already exist today?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conclusion may seem extreme and controversial to many.  But that won&amp;#39;t stop it from happening.  The robotics revolution is coming.  And human-robot sex will be a part of that revolution.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://hubski.com/pub?id=77766"&gt;Discuss this article on Hubski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/Tob7tm1u5xQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://theratchet.ca/robot-sex-revolution</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/breaking-down-a-typical-vcstartup-diligence-process</id>
    <published>2013-04-02T07:00:24-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-02T07:00:24-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/3oHPNof7ySU/breaking-down-a-typical-vcstartup-diligence-process" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Breaking Down a Typical VC/Startup Diligence Process</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24568393115790_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24568393115790_raw.png" alt="glass.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is my general outline for a typical diligence process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;First meeting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#39;m meeting a startup for the first time, my goal is to understand as much about the business and team as I can.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Founders/Team:&lt;/strong&gt; How do the founders know each other? How do they interact with each other? Are they passionate? How qualified are they? What would it be like to work with them?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business&lt;/strong&gt;: In some form, I walk through the Business Model Generation framework: value proposition, key activities, key partners, major assets, channels of distribution, customer segments, cost structure and revenue streams. Is the problem worth solving and if the startup succeeds, how valuable would it be?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go to market&lt;/strong&gt;: Can the company articulate their value proposition simply? Can the team explain how they will go to market? Do they have a good understanding of the competition?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The angle&lt;/strong&gt;: What secret, what insight has the founding team made that the rest of the market hasn&amp;#39;t yet realized? What discontinuity in the market can they leverage to win large share?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;After the first meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
After a startup has left and I&amp;#39;m &amp;ldquo;doing diligence,&amp;rdquo; I want to test some of the assertions made by the company.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Size Validation&lt;/strong&gt;: The first thing is to verify market size and whether it foots with the data the company presented. Then, I try to dig deeper into the nuances of the market. How concentrated is the market? What kinds of moves are the incumbents making and how they change the market? How might a startup disrupt this market?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pitch-it-myself test&lt;/strong&gt;: I stop a few partners in the office and give them the pitch to test their reactions. I do the same with my wife. In a sense, I&amp;#39;m getting their cursory opinions and some skewed market feedback, but I&amp;#39;m also testing the pitch, the go-to-market and the top level attractiveness of the company. It helps me think through a lot of the business and test my assumptions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Six degrees of separation&lt;/strong&gt;. I look up the founders on LinkedIn, send a few emails for references and then wait to hear back on some initial reference calls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Second and third meetings&lt;/h2&gt;
Follow up meetings are dedicated to metrics and the future.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pipeline&lt;/strong&gt;: Let&amp;#39;s get to brass tacks and some numbers. How many customers/users? How often are they using it? What are CAQ, LTV and churn metrics? How do those compare with industry benchmarks?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product roadmap&lt;/strong&gt;: I know it&amp;#39;s early and hard to forecast, but I&amp;#39;m looking to be convinced the founder have a good sense of where the company is going and why.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financing plan&lt;/strong&gt;: What are the major buckets of expenditures? How do they change over time? Is the revenue plan reasonable? What are the key metrics for the business?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;#39;ll call a few friends in the industry who can help me better understand the dynamics in the sector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional meetings/Full partner meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
At this point, I&amp;#39;m really interested and I&amp;#39;m trying to understand the investment risks better.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key issues analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: After a founder has met several partners, I gather questions and dig deeper to answer them as best I can. If I don&amp;#39;t have the material to answer the questions, I diligence some more: data, reference calls, and more meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;After the term sheet:&lt;/h2&gt;
After the term sheet is signed, the lawyers step in.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal diligence&lt;/strong&gt;:  I&amp;#39;m interested in learning how well formed the company is, if there are skeletons in the closet like fired co-founders or large debts or consultants who are owed shares or pending lawsuits. I&amp;#39;m also curious to see how a founder negotiates (though this comes through after the term sheet has been issued).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each fund raising process is unique. Sometimes investors will have deep experience in a sector or know the team very well both of which can accelerate the process significantly. But I hope this general outline sheds light on the key steps and questions answered in the fund raising process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/3oHPNof7ySU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/breaking-down-a-typical-vcstartup-diligence-process</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:adii,2012:Post/right-place-right-time</id>
    <published>2013-04-01T23:58:11-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T23:58:11-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/nX2NFp8hw0U/right-place-right-time" />
    <author>
      <name>Adii Pienaar</name>
      <uri>http://adii.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Right Place, Right Time</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since Google announced that they&amp;#39;d be shutting down Google Reader, I&amp;#39;ve been observing what&amp;#39;s been happening in the space of RSS readers / tools. What&amp;#39;s been interesting is that some companies / tools have been able to leverage this situation to their advantage by being an alternative option (to which ex-Google Reader customers could migrate to).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the companies that seems to have gained a lot of traction as a result is &lt;a href="http://feedly.com/"&gt;feedly&lt;/a&gt; (according to their &lt;a href="http://www.alexa.com/siteinfo/feedly.com#"&gt;traffic stats&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing about feedly is that I&amp;#39;ve been seeing it mentioned quite a few times in the Twitterverse in the last couple of months. It&amp;#39;s been touted as a great app, with a superior UI, and many of the people I follow (and regard as influencers to some extent) have adopted feedly (in favour of whatever they were using before).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the work that they did until now, feedly was in the right place at the right time to take advantage of changes elsewhere in the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a similar vein, whilst &lt;a href="https://posthaven.com/"&gt;Posthaven&lt;/a&gt; seemed to pop up just at the right place and time &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/22/posthaven-launches-in-public-beta-has-saved-850k-posts-since-posterous-announced-its-shutdown-date-of-april-30th/"&gt;as an alternative to Posterous&lt;/a&gt;, who announced they&amp;#39;ll be shutting down at the end of April. On the surface that seems &lt;em&gt;lucky&lt;/em&gt; and coincidental (especially in terms of the timing), but Garry Tan&amp;#39;s involvement (former founder of Posterous and now founder of Posthaven) is anything but lucky &amp;amp; coincidental.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it seems as if an entrepreneur or company just got lucky, but that&amp;#39;s rarely the case. The golfing legend Gary Player used to say, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;the more I practice, the luckier I get&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, which is what I&amp;#39;m reminded of when I see &amp;ldquo;coincidences&amp;rdquo; like these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both feedly and Posthaven were in the right place at the right time to leverage an opportunity. Being there and being ready required a lot of hard work prior to that though, which meant they were afforded an exclusive opportunity that most of us won&amp;#39;t have been privy to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, I&amp;#39;m sure that many entrepreneurs thought of using the shutting down of Google Reader to create a new RSS reading app. But by the time you could&amp;#39;ve put a V1 together from scratch the likes of feedly would&amp;#39;ve already beaten you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if anyone else built &amp;ldquo;a new Posterous&amp;rdquo; after it was announced that Posterous would close down, I bet it would&amp;#39;ve failed. That anyone else obviously excludes the former founders of Posterous though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there&amp;#39;s a couple of things that every startup and company should be doing that would give them the ability to execute and exploit these &lt;em&gt;lucky&lt;/em&gt; opportunities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As an entrepreneur, build your &lt;a href="http://blog.clarity.fm/living-life-in-permanent-beta/"&gt;soft assets&lt;/a&gt; and continuously improve your skills;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a great team;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a great product; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;#39;t waste money and have reserve kitty in your bank account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being in the right place at the right time is anything but being lucky. You only earn that privilege by putting in the hard yards long before that opportunity presents itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/nX2NFp8hw0U" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://adii.me/right-place-right-time</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:lautenbach,2012:Post/validation</id>
    <published>2013-04-01T21:41:44-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T21:41:44-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/cfr_jXAUI-8/validation" />
    <author>
      <name>Bradley Lautenbach</name>
      <uri>http://blog.bradleylautenbach.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Validation</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My generation suffers from a path addiction. (No, not that &lt;a href="http://path.com"&gt;Path.&lt;/a&gt;) Thanks, in part, to over-parenting, we are placed on a path from the moment we can walk and we follow it. And it becomes delightfully comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get put in preschool, then grade school, then we are prescribed extra-curriculars. Then we go to junior high school. High school comes next and then after that college. Always working toward the next step on the path. In college we are coached to develop &amp;ldquo;10-year plans.&amp;rdquo; Super-paths! And then we graduate. Real world. Shock. Horror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, as I have counseled friends on career decisions, and as I&amp;#39;ve started offering advice to recent college grads, I&amp;#39;ve learned something: we spend way too much of our early years knowing (and being prepared for) what&amp;#39;s coming next. When we finally get to the part where we have to fend for ourselves, develop a course of action and then execute, we fall down. Hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When offering guidance, I&amp;#39;ve too often been met with &amp;ldquo;but I&amp;#39;m not qualified for that&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;nobody would believe I&amp;#39;m capable of that.&amp;rdquo; We believe that, because someone else is doing something, they must have been anointed to do so. We think, &amp;ldquo;someone, somewhere validated that role.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;#39;d offer that the opposite is more likely true: most people aren&amp;#39;t qualified to be doing what they&amp;#39;re doing. Instead they were presented with an opportunity, and rather than waiting to be told they were ready, they simply jumped at the chance and figured it out as they went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a favorite passage from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_West_Wing"&gt;The West Wing:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leo McGarry:&lt;/strong&gt; Because I&amp;#39;m tired of it: year after year after year after year having to choose between the lesser of who cares. Of trying to get myself excited about a candidate who can speak in complete sentences. Of setting the bar so low, I can hardly bear to look at it. They say a good man can&amp;#39;t get elected President. I don&amp;#39;t believe that. Do you?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Jed Bartlet:&lt;/strong&gt; And you think I&amp;#39;m that man?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Leo:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Bartlet:&lt;/strong&gt; Doesn&amp;#39;t it matter that I&amp;#39;m not as sure?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Leo McGarry:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Nah. &amp;ldquo;Act as if ye have faith and faith shall be given to you.&amp;rdquo; Put another way: Fake it &amp;#39;til you make it!&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fake it &amp;#39;til you make it. Or: put down the path. Step away from the plan. Blaze your own trail. You are what you say you are - and nobody else needs to validate that. In fact, nobody else can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/cfr_jXAUI-8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.bradleylautenbach.com/validation</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jared,2012:Post/we-are-the-blank-for-blank</id>
    <published>2013-04-01T12:39:07-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T12:39:07-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/rHWwuZOdSIQ/we-are-the-blank-for-blank" />
    <author>
      <name>Jared Erondu</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jarederondu.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>We're the [blank] for [blank]</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;#39;re the Twitter for this and the Facebook for that.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/jared_24447436190640_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_jared_24447436190640_raw.png" alt="we-are-blank.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I read something like this, here is how I break it down. The first blank is the company you feel you relate to &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt;, and the second is the niche you wish to understand. But the overall sentence? Just a vague description. Open to multiple interpretations&amp;hellip; which is bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;When time is short&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t get me wrong. When you&amp;#39;re trying to pitch something or help someone quickly understand your product, yes it&amp;#39;s nice to give some context. Something people can quickly connect with and understand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;#39;s great for when you only have a brief moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;When you own the clock&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when communicating via text (your product website, email, etc.), using an existing product or company isn&amp;#39;t always the best route. After all, if you latch on to someone else&amp;#39;s product and reputation, you&amp;#39;re automatically limiting yourself to what &lt;em&gt;they&amp;#39;ve&lt;/em&gt; done–successes and failures. In the end, you still have to explain what makes &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; different. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So avoid taking the short route of describing your product with another. As one &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/xmcgraw"&gt;friend&lt;/a&gt; of mine said, &amp;ldquo;let the journalists form that mental picture.&amp;rdquo; And &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jbrewer"&gt;another&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;get to your own unique description sooner than later.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identify what it is that you do/solve and explain it in your own words. Build your own brand, your own identity. Make it that products after you will do with your name what you intended to do with others. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ve spent so much time working on your killer product. Don&amp;#39;t half-ass its description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be short, yet specific. What is it that you do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;#39;t figured that out yet, then you have bigger things to worry about than comparison points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/erondu"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twitter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/rHWwuZOdSIQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jarederondu.com/we-are-the-blank-for-blank</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:daslee,2012:Post/top-ten-things-i-think-i-think</id>
    <published>2013-04-01T11:42:41-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T11:42:41-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/O1nfMkt2Zpg/top-ten-things-i-think-i-think" />
    <author>
      <name>David Lee</name>
      <uri>http://daslee.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Ten Things I Think I Think</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If I could do it all over again, I&amp;#39;d be a sportswriter. Growing up in the mid-80&amp;#39;s, my favorite thing was to wake up and get the paper-delivered &lt;a href="http://www.grantland.com/story/_/id/7152773/the-best-sports-section-history"&gt;Boston Globe&lt;/a&gt; and open the sports pages (an anachronism for anyone born after 1975, probably). I wrote for the town newspaper and it&amp;#39;s the one thing (other than playing sports) that I truly enjoyed as a kid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still read some columns today. One column in particular is &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SI_PeterKing"&gt;Peter King&lt;/a&gt; of Sports Illustrated. He covers the NFL and mixes reporting, insight and locker-room gossip. He has the best access to teams, key personnel and leaders like an old school &lt;a href="http://www.grantland.com/story/_/id/7152773/the-best-sports-section-history"&gt;Peter Gammons, Will McDonough or Bob Ryan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of his features that I love is his weekly &lt;a href="http://sportsillustrated.cnn.com/nfl/news/20130331/carson-palmer-kevin-kolb-monday-morning-quarterback/?sct=hp_wr_a1&amp;amp;eref=sihp"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ten Things I Think I Think&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; which are quick hit snippets where he humbly pontificates about football and other stuff. With a hat tip to him, here goes my first installment on tech, startups and other stuff: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think if you wanted to read &lt;em&gt;one thing&lt;/em&gt; only to understand the history, philosophy and tactics related to startups, my vote is &lt;a href="http://blakemasters.com/peter-thiels-cs183-startup"&gt;Blake Master&amp;#39;s notes on Peter Thiel&amp;#39;s lectures for his CS183 class at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#39;d argue that that&amp;#39;s all you really need and will be as relevant in 20 years as it is today. (We are investors in &lt;a href="https://www.judicata.com/"&gt;Judicata&lt;/a&gt; where Blake is co-founder.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think &lt;a href="http://linkedin.com"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s product development in the past year is very impressive for a company of its size. Adding and accepting connections is very slick and easy, for example. It&amp;#39;s become my own little &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minesweeper_(video_game"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Minesweeper.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;   I&amp;#39;ve done it so much that people probably think I&amp;#39;m moving jobs (I&amp;#39;m not). Some of their &amp;ldquo;thought leader&amp;rdquo; pieces are must-reads as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think the most indispensable products for me are &lt;a href="http://swiftkey.net"&gt;swiftkey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://manytricks.com/moom/"&gt;moom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.boomeranggmail.com/"&gt;boomerang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.instapaper.com"&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://vemedio.com/products/instacast3"&gt;Instacast&lt;/a&gt;. None are SV Angel companies&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think sanebox was on that list but trying to figure out how to use it with &lt;a href="http://www.mailboxapp.com/"&gt;mailbox&lt;/a&gt;. (Mailbox and Dropbox were/are SV Angel portfolio companies.) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think Google is the &lt;a href="http://www.grantland.com/story/_/id/9109245/how-lebron-james-transformed-game-become-highly-efficient-scoring-machine"&gt;LeBron James&lt;/a&gt; of technology. Their greatness on so many dimensions is so consistent and persistent that we just take that for granted. They are not perfect but criticizing them for various tech shortcomings is like criticizing LeBron because he&amp;#39;s less effective driving left than right. ( used to work at Google so am a Google apologist.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it feels like startup ideas in the past 12 months or so are on average more diverse, bolder and harder. I don&amp;#39;t mean to diss the earlier startups because we also believe that many if not all of the biggest things look trivial at first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think I don&amp;#39;t know enough about 3D Printers to say with any data or conviction but &lt;a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/read/click-print-gun-the-inside-story-of-the-3d-printed-gun-movement-video"&gt;articles like this&lt;/a&gt; make me think that they may be overhyped in the short-term for many use cases but underhyped in the long-term in others. The 3D printed gun seems inevitable&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think we at SV Angel are seeing some of our &amp;ldquo;top&amp;rdquo; investment opportunities appear on &lt;a href="http://angel.co"&gt;AngelList&lt;/a&gt; and the like. So I think the &amp;ldquo;adverse selection&amp;rdquo; question is being answered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think the food at &lt;a href="http://www.bluebottlecoffee.com/"&gt;Blue Bottle Coffee&lt;/a&gt; is better than the coffee. And that&amp;#39;s not a back-handed slap because the coffee is very good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think that I am forcing this post so I will stop here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/O1nfMkt2Zpg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://daslee.me/top-ten-things-i-think-i-think</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:micah,2012:Post/curse-of-tomorrow</id>
    <published>2013-04-01T11:23:24-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T11:23:24-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/UY-mRHyFNps/curse-of-tomorrow" />
    <author>
      <name>Micah Baldwin</name>
      <uri>http://learntoduck.net</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The Curse of Tomorrow</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While April 1 is the day that the tech world fills the world with jokes, it was the day that I stopped being one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in 2006, on the March 31, I was sitting in my living room in Denver, Colorado. My living room didn&amp;#39;t have much life in it. The blinds were closed, the tv always on. The trash was rarely emptied, and I rarely showered. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was skinny (well as skinny as a fat man can be), and I had a pronounced limp. It was that limp that kept me on my couch for most of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, maybe not the limp. It was more likely the piles of drugs and alcohol that covered my glass top coffee table. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think about that day a lot because it was the day I decided to become normal. To be sober. It was the day that I broke the Curse that had chased me for most of my life. The Curse of Tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, on April 1, 2006, I chose life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a conscious decision and not a forgone conclusion. But, I woke up on April 1, 2006 and realized that I wasn&amp;#39;t ready to be finished. That today had become more important than tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an entrepreneur, I love being consumed by the vision of what the future holds. I thrive on my ability to see how things should work and my drive to make it reality. But, that constant belief that tomorrow will be better than today doesn&amp;#39;t create the appropriate balance between our mental selves and our emotional selves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have short memories &amp;ndash; the failures of yesterday fuel the successes of tomorrow. We have powerful drives &amp;ndash; tomorrow must be better than yesterday. We have incredible fortitude &amp;ndash; you may believe that what we are doing yesterday is adequate, but what you are doing tomorrow will amaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we fear today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For if today is ok, if today is full of magic, then there is no need for the dreamer. If today is fulfilling, there is no need for entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we fight against today. We look at it in disgust. We talk only about tomorrow. We dream only about tomorrow. We live in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by being under that curse, we break away from what is most important. Ourselves. We forget that we have the distinct need to just be; to just be in the world that surrounds us and helps us and supports us and lets us understand&amp;hellip;.us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand that believing in tomorrow is easy for entrepreneurs. It&amp;#39;s like our brains are set a day, a week, a year in advance and we struggle to engage with the world around us, with &amp;ldquo;normals,&amp;rdquo; with our friends and families that just don&amp;#39;t understand our ways of thought. We default every conversation to our vision of the technology future by reductive discussion of the pedantic efforts of today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is no surprise that startups are full of hipsters riding the cutting edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, in the midst of that mindset driven by the Curse of Tomorrow lives the beauty of today. Of the enormous force of taking a moment to look around and engage. To the simple pleasure of just sitting and absorbing the lights and sounds of today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April First is a special day for me. It was the day that I learned that wanting to live&amp;ndash;to live in the now&amp;ndash;was the secret to making tomorrow perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/UY-mRHyFNps" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://learntoduck.net/curse-of-tomorrow</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:bradmccarty,2012:Post/ease-your-eye-strain</id>
    <published>2013-04-01T09:06:29-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T09:06:29-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/8PlfrHtepzo/ease-your-eye-strain" />
    <author>
      <name>Brad McCarty</name>
      <uri>http://uptake.co</uri>
    </author>
    <title>14 Hours at the Computer and How I Fixed My Eye Strain</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On a typical day, I&amp;#39;m awake by 6:30 am and sitting at my computer. I spend around 14 hours looking at a screen and sometimes I move away from my computer to sit on the couch with my iPad. To say that I&amp;#39;ve experienced eye strain would be putting it very lightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a big fan of &lt;a href="http://signup.leagueoflegends.com/?ref=50784825c2e90653636648"&gt;League of Legends&lt;/a&gt; (psst, that&amp;#39;s a referral link), and I noticed &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LoLDyrus"&gt;Dyrus&lt;/a&gt; (one of my favorite top-lane players) wearing some funky yellow glasses about a year ago. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that these guys spend countless hours in front of a monitor, but I also know that they do a lot of sponsorship deals so I wasn&amp;#39;t fully convinced of the validity of what Gunnar was doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I met the people from the company. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#39;ve put tireless research into the design and fabrication of their lenses. There&amp;#39;s a lot of thought behind why they are the specific colors that they are, how they work and why they can benefit computer users. I was at least sold enough to try a pair for review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a couple of days to really notice the difference, but I think that&amp;#39;s because headaches and sore, dry eyes have become so normal to me that I don&amp;#39;t really recognize when they&amp;#39;re happening. At least I didn&amp;#39;t until they were gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, on day 3, I had that ah-hah moment where I looked away from the computer at 11pm and I didn&amp;#39;t feel exhausted. My eyes didn&amp;#39;t burn, my head didn&amp;#39;t hurt and I generally felt that I had more energy left at the end of the day. I hadn&amp;#39;t specifically changed anything else in my daily routine, so the Gunnars are the only thing to which I can really attribute the improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the weeks that have followed, I&amp;#39;ve made it a habit to wear my glasses when I&amp;#39;m at the computer. The one day that I forgot them? The headache reminded me to put them on. I noticed it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before this turns into an ad for Gunnar, let me say that there are likely other products on the market that work well too. My only experience is with this brand, so I can&amp;#39;t speak to any others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a lot of talk lately about standing desks, changing habits and other ways to help those of us who sit on our butts in front of computers live better and longer. But I think that while we&amp;#39;re paying attention to those things, we need to also focus on how easy it is to forget about our eyes. After all, without them the entire process of working on screens becomes considerably more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do some &lt;a href="http://www.mayoclinic.com/health/eyestrain/DS01084"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;. Find out for yourself if you&amp;#39;re experiencing direct or indirect effects of eye strain. Decide which course of action that you want to take, but please do something if you are. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclosure: Gunnar Optiks provided me, upon request for review, with a set of its &lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/gadgets/2013/01/10/gunnar-crystalline-review/"&gt;Crystalline&lt;/a&gt; glasses while I was at CES. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further Disclosure: I&amp;#39;m addicted to them and nobody at Gunnar is paying me to write this. I just feel that they&amp;#39;ve helped me, and I hope that they (or any other brand) can help others as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/8PlfrHtepzo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://uptake.co/ease-your-eye-strain</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/revisiting-the-house-of-cards-model</id>
    <published>2013-04-01T07:15:58-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T07:15:58-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/0E5Rk9gwtkY/revisiting-the-house-of-cards-model" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Revisiting The House Of Cards Model</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Was Netflix&amp;#39;s decision to release every episode of House of Cards at once the right one? I&amp;#39;m no expert, but I&amp;#39;d say so. After not having an active Netlifx account and re-signing up just to watch the [exclusive] show, I have now continued my subscription an extra two months and I doubt I&amp;#39;ll be canceling it again anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished the 13 episode &amp;ldquo;season&amp;rdquo; over the course of a week and thoroughly enjoyed the show. I binged on it because there was no reason not to. There aren&amp;#39;t water cooler moments about specific episodes any more, but rather about specific seasons lumped together as one big arc. Since the details of House of Cards release first came out, I maintained that there was no reason Netflix shouldn&amp;#39;t release all the episodes at once and &amp;ndash; if they were already filmed &amp;ndash; to artificially hold them back would be crazy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The argument for not releasing all the episodes at once was that people would just sign up for a single month [$7.99], finish the show and cancel. Meaning that Netflix would lose out on more money if they had opted to stretch 13 episodes over two or more months. I&amp;#39;ve already proved to myself &amp;ndash; that beyond laziness &amp;ndash; people will still continue to stay signed up. Even still, isn&amp;#39;t $8 for a single month from someone who wasn&amp;#39;t paying before still better than $0?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If House of Cards, or Netflix by association, has a problem, it&amp;#39;s the 1+ minute of opening credits starting each episode, it&amp;#39;s not the release schedule for their original content. There&amp;#39;s no reason others shouldn&amp;#39;t adopt the new release model, focusing their efforts on creating and maintaining quality content. Users will come and stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/0E5Rk9gwtkY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/revisiting-the-house-of-cards-model</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/your-startups-top-3-priorities</id>
    <published>2013-04-01T06:22:44-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T06:22:44-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/7NZsVCNfd44/your-startups-top-3-priorities" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Your Startup's Top 3 Priorities</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24566846487570_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24566846487570_raw.png" alt="ScreenCapture at Mon Apr 1 06:59:38 PDT 2013.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have built your product and it&amp;#39;s in the market, there are only three things that matter: &lt;strong&gt;distribution&lt;/strong&gt; (getting the product into users&amp;#39; hands), &lt;strong&gt;engagement&lt;/strong&gt; (validating that you&amp;#39;ve built the right product and that users are using it), and &lt;strong&gt;monetization&lt;/strong&gt; (making money from those engaged users). Some companies call this the 3 Rs: reach, retention and revenue. Whatever you call it, this is your strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At board meetings, I&amp;#39;ve started categorizing each portfolio company&amp;#39;s roadmap items into these three buckets. It&amp;#39;s a simplification that immediately reveals the priorities of the company at any stage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is most of the product development focused on growth or new product features that drive engagement? How have those priorities changed over time? Where are most of our people allocated? Are these priorities the right ones given the stage of the company?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking strategy into these three parts makes it easy - you now have a template, a stencil for describing your strategy. Make a table that looks like this:
&lt;table&gt;

&lt;tr style="background-color: #E0E0E0;"&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width="75px"&gt;Q1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width="75px"&gt;Q2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width="75px"&gt;Q3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width="75px"&gt;Q4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Distribution&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Engagement&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Monetization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fill it in with the top 2 to 3 initiatives per quarter. You have just built a board-level roadmap that describes your strategy. Explain it to your board, solicit feedback, then hold a town hall and describe it to your team. Then get back to building your company!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/7NZsVCNfd44" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/your-startups-top-3-priorities</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:zackshapiro,2012:Post/want-to-learn-to-code-start-here</id>
    <published>2013-03-31T11:33:06-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T11:33:06-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/uLg93HD7WzI/want-to-learn-to-code-start-here" />
    <author>
      <name>Zack Shapiro</name>
      <uri>http://blog.zackshapiro.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Want to learn to code? Start here.</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last September, I wrote a post called &lt;a href="http://zackshapiro.com/post/31672964808/want-to-learn-rails-start-here"&gt;Want to learn Rails? Start here.&lt;/a&gt; which has been pretty successful. I&amp;#39;ve met and emailed a good amount of people who have follow up questions or are in the middle of learning how to build things with software. I&amp;#39;ve referred a bunch of people to the post as well. I&amp;#39;m proud that the post is actionable and helpful. Since I wrote that post a while ago and developed my engineering skills much, much further. I wanted to write a follow-up post, some revised thoughts on learning how to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is intended for working professionals who feels a strong desire to code to build things that they want to see exist in the world. This post is not intended for the person who &lt;em&gt;thinks they should code&lt;/em&gt; because they hear so much about it. I mean no offense but I&amp;#39;ve found those people to be lacking in the short and medium-term fire it takes to learn to actually build software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Nights, weekends are bad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given my personal experiences and a slew of conversations, I&amp;#39;ve found that learning how to code only on nights and weekends is a terrible way to go about it. When your brain is not trained to think the way coding forces you to think, it&amp;#39;s very easy to lose where you were or not remember a key concept you just picked up. Putting in as much time as possible is your friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This point of view is reinforced by programs like &lt;a href="http://devbootcamp.com/"&gt;Dev Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; which not only require a full nine weeks of your life but also make you pay tuition to attend (which is not a small sum). They make you buy in temporally and financially to ensure your success.  &lt;strong&gt;You have to throw yourself in or you will fail.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Forget Codecademy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;#39;m learning how to code! I&amp;#39;m doing Codecademy!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t know how many people tell me this. If I follow up with any of those people six-to-eight weeks later, they&amp;#39;ve fallen off the boat completely. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s why Codecademy doesn&amp;#39;t work in the long term: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;re coding in a browser which you literally never do outside of Codecademy. Learning the syntax of JavaScript, Python, or Ruby is good but that&amp;#39;s about all you get out of the program, in my opinion. You&amp;#39;ll learn these skills elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t know how to set up a development environment. Any time you have the slightest inkling to build something for yourself leveraging what you&amp;#39;ve learned in Codecademy, you can&amp;#39;t and probably don&amp;#39;t know where to start. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ll need to go through the process of setting up your dev environment which can be incredibly challenging for someone with very little coding experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Have a real project you want to build&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have something &lt;em&gt;tiny&lt;/em&gt; you want to build. One of my first projects was called Today I Learned. It&amp;#39;s a text box that you enter stuff into and it shows the date you entered it in descending order. That&amp;#39;s all it does. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your first project is going to be crappy. But it will be done. And it will be done by you. And that&amp;#39;s fucking awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Everything you build, builds on top of the stuff you&amp;#39;ve built before&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built Today I Learned and whatever I built next, was better because of one or two concepts I learned while building TIL. You&amp;#39;ll constantly be referencing your old code, code other places in the codebase or code from the Internet, once you understand what the pieces mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Don&amp;#39;t copy and paste others&amp;#39; code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tommy Nicholas wrote &lt;a href="http://www.shockoe.com/blog/typingcodeout/"&gt;a post&lt;/a&gt; in December which echoes the same point. You learn things when you write code out. You question what certain pieces mean. Hopefully you Google those questions to learn more and understand more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) Stop telling people you&amp;#39;re learning to code unless they&amp;#39;re technical and you want them to help you&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;#39;re starting out, your goal should be to find a technical mentor or two, not impress your other non-coding friends with the fact that you&amp;#39;ve taken the first step. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a firm believer that if you talk about what you want to do, you never actually do it. So unless you&amp;#39;re talking to someone you hope will be a mentor, close your mouth, put your head down, and keep building. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loose lips sink ships&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7) Coding is failing a ton and understanding why. It&amp;#39;s painful and frustrating&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way you learn how to build software is by making the same mistake a few times, learning why that doesn&amp;#39;t work, and doing it correctly. The next time you come across a similar problem (and trust me, you will), you&amp;#39;ll either remember the way you did it last time or at least the part of the codebase that you struggled in, which you will then reference and remember what you learned from all of that failing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rewards for building software are incredible. The feeling of &amp;ldquo;that came out of my brain&amp;rdquo; is what I live for. I love it. But the road to get to that point can be tough. &lt;a href="http://blog.zackshapiro.com/momentum-is-a-hell-of-a-drug"&gt;Build momentum. Keep going.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8) Stop trying to figure out what you should do and just start.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of a friend kept emailing me with a bunch of questions. He was trying to figure out all of the places he could fail before he even started. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s the absolute wrong way to go about this. Pick a language, (Ruby or Python) buy a really recent book that assumes you know nothing and just start. Do chapter one. Do it again maybe. The amount that you don&amp;#39;t know that you don&amp;#39;t know is bigger than you can imagine. Don&amp;#39;t worry about that. You&amp;#39;ll understand more pieces in time. We all will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you have tips for beginners learning how to code, please &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5469623"&gt;share them on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;. Your time and effort may really help someone out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/uLg93HD7WzI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.zackshapiro.com/want-to-learn-to-code-start-here</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ethankap,2012:Post/in-the-cold-light-of-day-our-tools-make-us-all-douchebags</id>
    <published>2013-03-31T09:08:10-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T09:08:10-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/IGIUqc7lb0I/in-the-cold-light-of-day-our-tools-make-us-all-douchebags" />
    <author>
      <name>Ethan Kaplan</name>
      <uri>http://ethankaplan.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>In the cold light of day, our mastery and use of tools make us all douchebags</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ethan Kaplan runs product at Live Nation Labs, including overseeing mobile, engineering, design and operations. He lives deep in the suburbs of Los Angeles with his wife Amy, almost four-year old Eli and two pugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phone&lt;/strong&gt;: Black iPhone 5, 64gb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ringtone&lt;/strong&gt;: None. I generally don&amp;#39;t answer my phone and instead text people back. I dislike synchronous communication for the most part that is voice based. If I turn on the ringer, the opening few bars of Harborcoat by R.E.M.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case&lt;/strong&gt;: None. I like the form of the device too much to put a case on it, and if I drop it, oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;: Lock screen: my son. Home screen: some grass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last Text&lt;/strong&gt;: From my wife, while she was in another part of our house asking me to bring her something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last App I Used&lt;/strong&gt;: Netflix, I AirPlay it to our living room TV so I can control what my son watches on a Saturday morning while I attempt to sleep in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currently Obsessed with&lt;/strong&gt;: AlienBlue. The social structures of Reddit fascinate me. I studied virtual communities a lot in college and seeing emergence of social foundations and norms in such a rapid fashion never ceases to be interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last Download&lt;/strong&gt;: Mailbox. Also my last deletion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Surprising App on Home Screen&lt;/strong&gt;: Indigo from Perceptive Automation with customized interfaces. It lets me control all the lights, the thermostat and our front-yard fountain from my bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text or Call&lt;/strong&gt;: Text. I hate talking to people on the phone and rarely answer calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remaining Battery&lt;/strong&gt;: 87%. I do most of my long-form reading on the iPad or  one of the Mac&amp;#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your move Gruber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/IGIUqc7lb0I" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ethankaplan.com/in-the-cold-light-of-day-our-tools-make-us-all-douchebags</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:youssef,2012:Post/an-observation-on-the-2nd-amendment-and-gun-ownership</id>
    <published>2013-03-30T14:12:07-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T14:12:07-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/B4an7wtRgeE/an-observation-on-the-2nd-amendment-and-gun-ownership" />
    <author>
      <name>Youssef Sarhan</name>
      <uri>http://sefsar.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>An observation on the 2nd Amendment and gun ownership</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There has been quite a lot of debate surrounding the notion of gun control, particularly as we move into an age of 3D printed guns. Some find the notion of strong gun control unruly, while others believe it is critical. The debate is engaging, with both sides presenting coercive arguments. Yet, I have to wonder if the issue is more seminal than that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sorts of weapons available at the time of the 2nd Amendment&amp;#39;s adaptation (1791) were modest in their capabilities. Like a pirate&amp;#39;s cannon, the 18th century handgun required the owner to push a bullet down a barrel before each shot was fired — even then it was rarely fatal, if it even hit it&amp;#39;s intended target at all. The first successful semiautomatic pistols didn&amp;#39;t exist until over one hundred years after the 2nd Amendment was instated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="500" height="281" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/4D3HfqrpVhk?rel=0" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas nowadays, weapons are so incomprehensibly powerful that we don&amp;#39;t grasp the damage they&amp;#39;re causing. 60 rounds, 2 magazines, less than 30 seconds, and this guy doesn&amp;#39;t seem to be in a rush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="500" height="281" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6ihR5JmUd1s?rel=0" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SCUD missiles were never &lt;em&gt;A Right&lt;/em&gt;, they were obviously too destructive for civilians to use. Perhaps the same should be applicable to modern guns? Could it be that the Bill of Rights is wrong and that we&amp;#39;ve never questioned it&amp;#39;s dogma? I&amp;#39;m not sure what the answer is, but I feel there needs to be a high level of discussion happening that has nothing to do with guns, but rather the fundamentals upon which society operates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/B4an7wtRgeE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sefsar.com/an-observation-on-the-2nd-amendment-and-gun-ownership</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:bb,2012:Post/saying-goodbye-to-a-sister</id>
    <published>2013-03-30T10:24:36-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T10:24:36-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/xieOFyqK7Rc/saying-goodbye-to-a-sister" />
    <author>
      <name>Brian Bailey</name>
      <uri>http://brianbailey.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Saying Goodbye to a Sister</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/bb_24563121681870_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_bb_24563121681870_raw.jpg" alt="photo.JPG"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My priority this weekend was putting together a site to raise money for my sister&amp;#39;s increasing medical bills. Then, I received a phone call that her condition was rapidly worsening. An hour later, my phone rang again from the same number. No part of me wanted to answer it. She was gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laura was the middle child in our family and I was the baby. I would often tell people that being three years apart, we were constantly mad at each other growing up, but as I looked through photos from those days, there we are, side by side in picture after picture, smiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We played innumerable board games together, wrestled over the remote control, fought until there was physical evidence. I kept score at her high school volleyball games and marveled as she went on multi-day bike trips with my dad. In the days before the Internet, DVRs or even VCRs, I would watch her favorite soap opera to let her know what happened when she got home late from school. I teased her about her first boyfriends and sat on the bed and listened to her when they broke her heart. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laura was so great about my first girlfriend, of course, that she was a bridesmaid when Lori and I got married. Laura knew food and cooking better than most anyone and she and Lori shared many irreplaceable hours in the kitchen together, most recently at Thanksgiving. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She lived with us for a few months while our son was a toddler. He used to push the door open and tiptoe into her room to get a peek at this exciting new presence. She would sneak up to meet him with a surprise, &amp;ldquo;Boo!&amp;rdquo; and he would squeal and laugh and run while she chased him. For years she was known in our house as Aunt Boo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a sweet woman she was.  Everyone who met her loved her, every man was mesmerized by her beauty. She agonized over the smallest decisions, but jumped at every sudden opportunity to get on a plane. She sought out beaches constantly and found peace at the ocean&amp;#39;s edge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were always interesting tales from her travels. For some reason, her story about getting pulled over for speeding while driving across New Mexico was one of my favorites. She started by expressing surprise, but the cop would have none of it. &amp;ldquo;We&amp;#39;ve been following you for 10 miles. The only time you slowed down was when someone didn&amp;#39;t get out of your way fast enough!&amp;rdquo; She told it with the biggest smile. I doubt she actually got a ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laura was so unique.  She helped endless new families and babies as a doula. She played guitar and had a wonderful voice, became fluent in sign language, was a vegetarian before most knew such a thing existed, and danced to reggae in Jamaica. She was the one who seemed unsure of her opinions, but left you wondering why you were so sure of yours.  Somehow she introduced &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; to Firefly, yet doubted my ability to pick out clothes for her, even from her beloved Sundance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever we watched movies and shows together, she would get frustrated and groan at unrealistic scenes. &amp;ldquo;That would never happen.&amp;rdquo; Each time, I&amp;#39;d chide her, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;#39;s a story! Who wants to watch real life?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not me, not today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, she and a girlfriend traveled the globe for six months, from Thailand to New Zealand to Malawi and more.  They brought with them nothing more than massive backpacks and a fierce belief that there is no time like the present. She knew better than anyone I know that all that matters in life is people and moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God, I miss her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;d like to contribute to Laura&amp;#39;s memorial fund, donations will help cover her medical and memorial expenses. &lt;a href="http://www.youcaring.com/medical-fundraiser/in-memory-of-laura-bailey/50339"&gt;Visit this site to give&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you for your kindness and generosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/xieOFyqK7Rc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://brianbailey.me/saying-goodbye-to-a-sister</feedburner:origLink></entry>
</feed>
