<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xml:lang="en-US">
  <id>tag:svbtle.com,2012:/feed</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://svbtle.com" />
  
  <title>Svbtle Featured</title>
  <updated>2013-03-19T18:00:11-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Svbtle.com</name>
    <uri>http://svbtle.com</uri>
    <email>hello@svbtle.com</email>
  </author>
  <generator>Svbtle.com</generator>
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/svbtle" /><feedburner:info uri="svbtle" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><entry>
    <id>tag:micah,2012:Post/heart-startup</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T18:00:11-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T18:00:11-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/XkmWRM-dp_s/heart-startup" />
    <author>
      <name>Micah Baldwin</name>
      <uri>http://learntoduck.net</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Heart is Where The Startup Is</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The other day, I read Sarah Lacy&amp;#39;s post on &lt;a href="http://romotive.com"&gt;Romotive&lt;/a&gt; (a &lt;a href="http://techstars.com"&gt;Techstars&lt;/a&gt; Company!) moving to the bay area, &lt;a href="http://pandodaily.com/2013/03/15/more-bad-news-for-vegas-tech-fund-star-company-romotive-is-moving-to-the-bay-area/"&gt;More Bad News for Vegas Tech Fund&lt;/a&gt; and it stirred the same feelings I had when I moved &lt;a href="http://graphicly.com"&gt;Graphicly&lt;/a&gt; from Boulder to the Bay Area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the sentence that got me was in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KellerRinaudo"&gt;Keller&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s email to the Downtown Project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s my responsibility to make sure that Romotive is located where we are most likely to achieve this vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people who haven&amp;#39;t started a company think that there are simple decision points in deciding where that company should reside: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where do I want to live?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where the money at?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;#39;s not that simple. What Keller did was right, he listened to his business. His business told him where the best place was for them to achieve their goals, and unfortunately, it wasn&amp;#39;t Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dowsing"&gt;dowsers&lt;/a&gt;, great CEO&amp;#39;s have the ability to intrinsically listen to their companies, putting aside their egos and desires to do what is right for the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even as they bury themselves with metrics and analytics and report to boards and investors, they continue to listen to that ache in their stomachs that tells them what actions to follow through with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s like porn; you know it when you see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving a company is hard. There are people that can&amp;#39;t/won&amp;#39;t move. The community you are leaving looks at you askance and wonders why. your investors often came onboard because of where you were located.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not you; it&amp;#39;s me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I moved Graphicly to the Bay Area, I was pretty quiet about it. I didn&amp;#39;t think it was a big deal, and I still have people that ask me why I moved from Boulder, especially because Boulder is seen as such a startup mecca. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It honestly had nothing to do with Boulder, much like Romotive&amp;#39;s move has nothing to do with Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As founders, our only jobs are to put our companies in the best position to succeed. That means a focus on raising money, recruiting talent and articulating the vision of the business. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly, it means listening to the business and doing what is best for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kudos to Keller for listening, and more importantly, acting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/XkmWRM-dp_s" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://learntoduck.net/heart-startup</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:falon,2012:Post/early-stage-marketing</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T16:21:41-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T16:21:41-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/1D9aZkNbCI8/early-stage-marketing" />
    <author>
      <name>Falon Fatemi</name>
      <uri>http://falonfatemi.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Early Stage Marketing</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Depending on the nature of your product, you should not be investing in much marketing when you first launch. The main reason for this is to test out the performance of your product organically without any externalities affecting your data set. The only time you’ll have an opportunity to capture organic growth data is when you first launch and these metrics are critical in determining your next steps. The entire point of launching your product is to validate the core assumptions that your product is based on. It&amp;#39;s sometimes helpful to outline these assumptions and make sure you have the right tools implemented to track data against them post launch. That way you won&amp;#39;t let your emotions get in the way of data. I recommend writing out the company vision first, the problem you are solving, and they key value propositions that the product provides. These value propositions are essentially the assumptions that underly your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You shouldn’t have to invest in marketing &amp;ndash; if your product is good people will use it and will evangelize to their networks. Most of your marketing efforts should be spent focusing on tracking product/design metrics and user analytics such as engagement and traction.  Who is using your product? How are they using it? Are they telling their friends to sign up? What is the viral coefficient of the product? Is your design flow optimal for customer acquisition? You should be able to answer all of these questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once enough data has been gathered, generally over 2 - 3 months, you’ll be able to put together a robust marketing strategy that helps you drive towards growing the key metrics in your business. A brilliant marketing strategy will undoubtedly include a community development program that will transform your most active users into your biggest evangelists - your community will become your extended marketing team. More on that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools you can use:
- Mixpanel
- Flurry Analytics
- Localytics
- Kissmetrics
- UserVoice
- Olark
and many others ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/1D9aZkNbCI8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://falonfatemi.com/early-stage-marketing</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ben,2012:Post/that-time-i-climbed-kilimanjaro</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T15:59:11-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T15:59:11-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/NGXlAglOXxU/that-time-i-climbed-kilimanjaro" />
    <author>
      <name>Ben Yu</name>
      <uri>http://benyu.org</uri>
    </author>
    <title>That time I climbed Kilimanjaro (and got carried down in a stretcher)</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So this is just a short recounting of the time I decided to go to Africa and climb Kilimanjaro. I may decide to flesh it out once upon a future, and I may not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also not sure what the moral of the story really is. It’s either ‘don’t be an idiot’, or, ‘even if you’re an idiot all things usually turn out alright, so just go with the flow and wait for the stretcher’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How and why I went to Africa and what I did in the few weeks preceding my Kili climb is another story in itself. For now, suffice it to say that one day I suddenly found myself on a bus driving along the long road from Dar Es Salaam to Moshi. The story begins with my tragic choice of bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night before my hosts in Dar Es Salaam had thrown a huge party (aka Bingo at the Indian Restaurant Down The Street) celebrating their departure on the morrow for Sri Lanka. As a consequence, I stumbled to bed sometime around 2am. A traumatically short four hours later, I stumbled out of bed at 6am to catch my bus to Moshi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had heard horror stories about the abysmal state of bus driving in Tanzania before. The mortality rate seemed uncomfortably high on the lower tier buses, and so after much deliberation I decided to shell out the three or so extra dollars to upgrade to the very best luxury bus available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, this was a tragic mistake. Thoroughly deceived by the mildly warm ambient temperatures of about 200 Fahrenheit, I assumed a mere t-shirt and shorts would be sufficient climate protection on board the bus. Not so. Being a luxury bus, the contraption I entered had implemented a technological marvel that somehow managed to actively oppose the oppressive Tanzanian climate and maintain a steady temperature of about 50 degrees in the face of all odds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this probably seemed like paradise to every other passenger on board, to me it quickly became hell. With a solidly compromised immune system from last night’s sleep deprivation, the drastic shift in temperature proved too much for my fragile, delicate body to bear. Within a few hours I was freely shivering in the corner and feeling quickly nauseous. It was all I could do to concentrate on not throwing up, or crapping my pants, or fainting, or otherwise exemplifying poor Tanzanian luxury bus etiquette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six of the eight hours of the ride to Moshi were engaged in this way. By the time I arrived in Moshi, I had a healthy fever and a phlegmy cough. To date, this remains the fastest I have ever experienced a full transition from being healthy to thoroughly sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I had arranged accommodation before I made it to Moshi. After arriving sometime in the afternoon, I was picked up at the bus stop and spent the next few hours being driven up a mountain adjacent to Kilimanjaro before arriving at the aptly named Kilimanjaro View Lodge (it had a view of Kilimanjaro) where I was to stay the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happened next is a bit of a blur. After being warmly welcomed by Philip, the co-owner of the lodge, he brought up the guide who was to lead me up Kilimanjaro to advise me on my journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guide proceeded to thoroughly ascertain if I had everything I needed for the trip. I was exceedingly confident that I did. He was a little more skeptical. Glancing at the only bag I had brought on the trip, a meager 28L Deuter Futura backpack, he asked me if I had hiking boots. I replied that I had KSO Trek Vibrams, which would be more than adequate. He asked me if I had proper insulation. I had a two or three ounce down jacket and a similarly weighted windbreaker, which I again assured him would be fully sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trekking poles? No, but who needs those?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pants? Just the convertible pair I was wearing, though I did have a pair of waterproof pants I could throw over that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about a hat? A little wool beanie. It’ll be just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleeping bag? …of course not. But I have a cot, which is like, even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guide was really skeptical on this point. It took a lot of coaxing to convince him that my cot was Kili-worthy (spoiler: it was not).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I have to mention that I do feel guilty for all the trouble I put my guides through. And while I tipped them very generously, I feel bad about that too (more on that later). This is a cautionary tale. I was an idiot, and I did literally everything wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entirely unsatisfied, the guide eventually gave up and left me. Philip told me that he would return tomorrow morning to gather me before we went and got final supplies and began our hike. In the meantime, I could finally sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semi-delirious by now, I didn’t have to hear that twice, and immediately went to my cabin and fell asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True to Philip’s word, my guide arrived early the next morning with my porters and the cook in a janky little red car. I got in, we bumped down the mountain, stopped for some sunscreen, Diamox, and junk food, and made our way to the entrance gate for the route I was to climb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around noon when we finally arrived. The guide and I registered at the gate, paid our dues, and then, just as we were about to begin our climb, my guide seemed to deliberate with the porters and cook, and told me that we’d have to wait about thirty minutes before climbing. For some reason, this made perfect sense to my nonfunctional brain, and I didn’t ask any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should note here that no, my sickness did not, unfortunately, disappear overnight. In fact, I was much more sick than I had been the day before. I woke up with a fever literally coughing blood. But the excitement of climbing Kilimanjaro had gotten my adrenaline going, and against all odds I actually felt quite fine, save for the needing to keep fiercely bundled up in my down jacket despite it being about 90 degrees outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the story: after I busied myself for thirty minutes recording the endemic simian and giant scary ass crow population on my camera, the guide still hadn’t gotten back to me. Being juiced up on adrenaline and impatient to get started, I walked over and inquired what the holdup was. Reluctantly, the guide informed me that they had forgotten the cooking gear in the car…which was already well on its way back to Moshi. Hence, he’d have to go back and grab the gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not to worry – why don’t I just start climbing with the cook? He’d meet me at the first camp at night, and everything would be just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounded perfectly agreeable to me. My guide left, and the cook and I started to walk over to where they had left their packs. Leaving our packs unattended – bit of a mistake, that. Long before we got anywhere near them, we could see a horde of monkeys eagerly ripping through our possessions in search of precious nutrition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cook started shouting and ran at them to chase them away, and reluctantly they left. He inspected the packs, and there didn’t seem to be too much damage done yet. However, he informed me, it’d probably be best if he stayed with the packs until the porters came back so they could protect the packs. But not to worry again! – why don’t I just start climbing, and he’d be sure to catch up with me later?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, again, sounded like a wonderful idea to me. It was getting late, and I was already behind all the other climbers. I eagerly started up the mountain. “Pole pole!” the cook reminded me. He was reminding me to take it slow and keep a steady pace going up, lest altitude get the best of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuck that, I thought, as I nodded politely and smiled. I was late, and I felt great. The adrenaline had really gotten to me. I was going to book it up this mountain, and catch up with everyone else. The trail didn’t seem too steep at all, and despite not having exercised in ages, it seemed I could easily conquer it without strain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first few minutes, this proved true and I made it up the mountain at a remarkable pace. I even made it a personal goal to make sure that the cook wouldn’t catch up to me, and that I’d get to camp before he managed to overtake me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little while later, and I started passing my first hikers. I greeted them triumphantly in a self-satisfactory way, and kept pushing, priding myself increasingly on the number of hikers I managed to pass. Some guides eyed me suspiciously, and asked where my guides were. Back in town, I replied. They scoffed and told me I’d get lost. I just laughed inwardly and carried on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s when it hit me. Crap. I didn’t see this one coming, but bowel movements don’t lie. I really needed to take a shit. I looked around. There wasn’t much room off trail – it was pretty steep. I tried to push the crap back in and carry on. It wasn’t having any of it though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I couldn’t go any further and just had to step to the side of the trail and let it all out. Not very far, again. Essentially just a few feet off the trail next to a tree or two. I hoped I’d blend into the background and no one would really be able to see me. Porters passed by and waved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I dropped my pants and promptly discovered I had a pretty severe case of violent diarrhea. It was an immensely relieving sort of discovery though, so not all was bad. Finally I finished, as more porters walked by and pretended not to see me. I looked around for the toilet paper, and – ohh, that’s right. My guide had the toilet paper, and he’s in Moshi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bereft of a better option, I took some of the least questionable nearby jungle leaves and started wiping myself with them. They were wet, but it was better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got up, pretended once more to be dignified, and continued my trek up the mountain. I was feeling pretty good again, and so resumed passing as many people as I could at breakneck pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until the diarrhea struck again, of course. By now I knew the drill, so I went into the bushes and did my thing. This happened a couple more times as I moved up that day. Rinse and repeat, without the rinsing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last I passed what later turned out to be about half of all the trekkers that day, and met up with an Australian father-son duo. I would have passed them, but all of a sudden my borrowed adrenaline energy completely depleted and I hit a wall, barely able to move another inch, much less the final stretch to camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desperately I managed to keep pace with them and somehow made it to camp with even a little small talk sprinkled in, but as soon as I reached camp and signed in, I found the nearest log and sat down and didn’t move for about the next half hour until my cook arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He immediately spotted me, came over, and laughingly called me crazy for going so quickly. Then he gave me my lunch, which I had missed since I had kept ahead of the cook the entire hike, and I numbly attempted to make my way through it. My stomach was precariously on edge however, and it felt like any sudden or wrong move and I would be forced to eject all of my stomach’s contents, likely through my mouth, but also quite possibly through other orifices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow I managed to make my way through the entire little chicken drumstick and whatever else was in that little box (I think there was a biscuit, maybe? Something bready).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how my tent was setup and by whom, but at some point it was set up and I put up my cot and promptly attempted to sleep as darkness closed in. Still no sign of my guide. Oh well. I’d sleep and worry about it in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleep did not come as easily as I expected. In fact, it didn’t come at all. Why? My fucking vibrams. I had thought my clothing could keep me warm in the absence of a sleeping bag – how cold could it get in the middle Africa? – and for the most part I was right…save for my fucking feet. I had failed to take into account the fact that I had brought nothing but vibrams and a pair of overshoes, and neither of those things provided any warmth for my feet. I was certain my feet were actually going to freeze off that night. It was warm enough during the day, but at night, even at that first camp, it was frigidly code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow I managed to make it all the way through that first night – with no sleep, however – but when I woke up the next morning, I sheepishly informed my guide who had arrived sometime late last night that he was in fact right about the necessity of a sleeping bag, and that I might very well lose my feet without one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My guide was really the only reason I made it up that mountain. Incredibly resourceful. He somehow managed to procure a sleeping bag for me (something about one of the porters having one?), and we continued climbing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is to say, I went literally about eight meters up some large stone steps before practically collapsing and realizing I had failed to recuperate any energy at all and was in fact entirely exhausted and could go no further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I desperately asked my guide for a bit of rest, and everyone waited around as I sought to catch my breath. I looked pitiful. I was pitiful. And I felt pitiful. The thought of giving up and turning back flashed in my mind, and at first it seemed like the only real possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, I thought about how humiliatingly pathetic that would be. To have come all this way, to have flown to Africa, to have endured this crippling sickness, and to have made it all the way here to this mountain, only to turn back on the second day of a six day trek. It was beyond pathetic. It was beyond the scope of the definition of sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuck that. I resolved to myself that no matter what, I would somehow find a way up the mountain. And slowly but surely, I began to take start climbing once more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this day, I’m still not really sure how I made it through those next few days. I took some anti-diarrheal pills the first night, and by the second night my diarrhea was in control, so thankfully I never had to shit my pants in the presence of my guide and porters. Beyond that, it was just one step at a time, one night at a time, one meal I could barely stomach at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The food did not agree with me once on the entire trip. Every meal was a challenge in of itself. I just couldn’t stomach the food. It was some greasy bread with ketchup and some tea or something of the like. That’s mostly all I remember. But it was the antithesis of what pleased my stomach. I’m amazed I managed to stomach it all. The only thing that went down well was the fruit I believe, but there was a depressingly scarce amount of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, the next few days were a blur of exhaustion and precarious health. The trail was extremely demoralizing on certain days. We’d go up, and then we’d go all the way back down again. I couldn’t imagine ever getting to the top of this thing. When would it end?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But end it did, and at last we were at the final camp, the final reprieve before the push for the summit. There were no trees here, and it was quite chilly even during the day. My guide informed me we would be leaving just a bit past midnight in order to make it up in time for sunrise, so I’d best be going to sleep as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took his advice, but couldn’t sleep well. I tried listening to some Ellie Goulding on my Sansa Clip (I’d been carefully partitioning my mp3 player’s battery life throughout the climb and Ellie Goulding provided much needed inspiration to keep going). I put on all my winter gear – my gloves, my hat, my waterproof pants, my overshoes, my down jacket, my windbreaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True to my word, my guide woke me up at around 1am or so and handed me a pair of trekking poles he had managed to buy off another guide. Those trekking poles were the reason I made the final ascent. At some point my legs were no longer capable of stepping forward, and I would throw my trekking poles out in front of me with a strap around the handle looped around my wrists, and lean my weight on the poles and pull my feet up after the poles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lagged behind everyone else, and I desperately attempted to keep pace. I had a morbid fear of getting left behind. Only my guide and I were making this final ascent – the porters and the cook and stayed behind. He kept in front of me, as I lagged behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every part of me was freezing. My feet were numb and I couldn’t feel my toes at all. My hands were so cold I couldn’t hold the pole anymore – I had to keep my hands tightly balled up to keep the extremities from freezing off and hence could only rely on the poles being looped around my wrists. Eventually, I lost all feeling in my fingers as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow, miraculously, through sheer will and the good will of the mountain gods, I made it up the mountain. All the way. The sign said it all. Uhuru peak, 6900 meters above sea level (or something like that – check this later to make sure). My guide took some incredibly blurry pictures with his freezing hands (he didn’t seem to have brought gloves at all and had been just keeping his hands in his pockets), and we hastily made a retreat back to camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I remember is everyone passing me on the way back down the mountain. I distinctly remember the last person to pass me, a woman with trekking poles who was easily making it down the mountain as if it were her morning daily run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No such luck for me. I felt incredibly weak and tired, and every step took several seconds. I was lagging severely behind my guide, and at some point I was thoroughly worried I’d lose him and he’d leave me behind. I was by far the last one up the mountain, and I just couldn’t make it back down. My feet didn’t quite work anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later my guide would think that I had altitude sickness, but I’m not so sure. I think perhaps I just made had the wrong goal in mind: my goal had been to make it up the mountain, where it should have been to make it up the mountain and back down again. In any case, after what may have been anywhere from three to six hours but felt like an eternity, I told my guide that I really didn’t think I could make it down the mountain. I felt like I was out of options here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked around, and very fortunately there just happened to be another guide or scout or something skipping down the rocky slope. He conversed with him for a minute, and then the two of them grabbed me by each arm and helped me down the rest of the path to the camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At camp, he put me in a random cabin to rest and gave me some watermelon to eat. Delicious watermelon. I felt much better here, but still not well enough to physically exert myself. Eventually, my guide, my porters, my cook and I began the trek down the mountain and all I remember is that it seemed like the longest walk of my life. According to my guide, all we had to do was make it to the next camp where they had a stretcher, and they would be able to carry me down from there. It was only a little further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little further was forever. I was parched. My throat was felt incredibly dry. My feet were leaden. The path we came down was different from the path we went up, and so I had no idea where we were, and how much further we had to go. All I knew was that I wouldn’t be able to go much further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An excruciatingly long time later, and we finally made it to a grassy patch with a cabin where my guide managed to procure a stretcher, which literally consisted of a metal slab with some rope around it for securing me in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They put me on the stretcher and hoisted me up and began carrying me down the mountain. It was a tremendously bumpy ride, and I recall my head banging against the stretcher with every step. If I hadn’t been so shit-faced exhausted, it would likely have been the most uncomfortable stretcher ride of all time.  It also seemed remarkably dangerous to me – the path down was magnitudes steeper than the path up, and we were supposed to make it down the mountain in a single day, as opposed to the five days it took to make it up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, on some particularly steep steps it seemed as if they were essentially tossing me from the higher step to the lower step, and the people on the lower step were just hoping to catch me every time. In any case,  this did not concern me overly much at the time, though in retrospect it certainly should have, as a tumble down those steep rocky steps would have almost certainly meant my death, given how steep the off-trail slope was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I somehow managed to fall asleep somewhere along this stretcher ride, and when I awoke we were almost at the bottom of the mountain.  A short while later and we had made it to the exit. I remember blurrily something with a couple of white SUVs, having to pay someone to leave, and getting into an SUV and driving away, as well as some part where the car got stuck in some mud or something and for a solid twenty minutes or so of reversing and not reversing it seemed as if the car would never manage to get out. But somehow it did, and somehow we made it back. I also remember having to hike down the very end of the path, after we had to relinquish the stretcher. The cook, I believe, was listening to American music on his huge radio, and it was a foresty little trail we had to make it down. The guide, I believe, had gone ahead to fetch the car or something of that sort. We waited quite a good while after making it to the road for him to finally come back. It was a muddy road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, in more or less detail, is the full account of my travails on Kilimanjaro. For a month afterwards, I could not feel my fingers and toes. I saw a doctor about it, and he informed me that the quick changes in temperature often did this to people, and that it was nothing to worry about. While I was severely skeptical of his opinion at the time, I suppose he turned out to be right in the end, as my feeling slowly returned to me, though it was a month later and not the few days he had promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s much more to my travels in Tanzania to recount, but I’ll leave it at that for now. Not the best story I’ve told, but I’m riding on a plane back from Santiago right now and my thought has been constantly interrupted and bombarded by announcements and chatter, so I’m using that to excuse my less-than-stellar writing this time around. A story’s a story. Falser words have never been uttered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: Oh, and about this being short. Yeah, about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PSS: Ah right, and about me regretting even tipping my guides so much. So I tipped them enormously after the trip (withdrew 2x the amount to tip them too, the first time I withdrew my shillings I think I withdrew 400,000 shillings at the ATM and somehow the money disappeared. I still have no idea what happened to it. I probably just lost it&amp;hellip;d&amp;#39;oh. Anyway withdrew like over a million shillings or something to pay them or something like that), and then the day after that I saw my guide randomly crossing the street and he was bandaged up from head to toe and pretty much unrecognizable. According to Philip, that&amp;#39;s what happens when you tip too much. The guides celebrate, get wildly drunk, and then crash their motorcycles in the bushes. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/NGXlAglOXxU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://benyu.org/that-time-i-climbed-kilimanjaro</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:angus,2012:Post/how-to-read-a-book</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T10:31:34-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T10:31:34-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/w2RtmnBCevQ/how-to-read-a-book" />
    <author>
      <name>Angus Croll</name>
      <uri>http://blog.anguscroll.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>How to Read a Book</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although Ernest Hemingway&amp;#39;s brilliant 1927 story &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.asdk12.org/staff/grenier_tom/HOMEWORK/208194_Hills_Like_White_Elephants.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Hills like White Elephants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is only three pages long, there are tens of thousands of pages of academic analysis telling us how to read it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story itself is little more than tense, disjointed exchange between a man and a woman at a railway station somewhere between Barcelona and Madrid. Instinctive, melodic, enigmatic, irrefutable—the dialog is all we have, and it&amp;#39;s all we need. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried to eliminate everything unnecessary to conveying experience to the reader so that after he or she has read something it will become a part of his or her experience and seem actually to have happened. — Ernest Hemingway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hemingway gives us the bare minimum so that we might subconsciously fill the gaps with the logic and imagery of our own existence; he surely didn&amp;#39;t intend that blustering pedagogues and glorified cheat sheets should do it for us. And yet, at every turn there is a professor, a critic, or a study guide dishing up symbolism: the woman sees white elephants in the hills because the child she&amp;#39;s carrying is &amp;ldquo;the elephant in the room&amp;rdquo;; the train tracks are green on one side, barren on the other, evoking the differing attitudes of the main protagonists towards the woman&amp;#39;s pregnancy; the woman &amp;ldquo;recalls psalm 21 as she lifts up her eyes to the hills for help&amp;rdquo;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far from clarifying the original work, such absurdist pseudo-science only serves to obfuscate. A well written work of fiction speaks to something much deeper and more visceral than impersonal theorizing ever could. As the author&amp;#39;s work is coated by layer upon layer of scholarly inference, so the beauty, lucidity and intimacy of the original is smothered in the cold, hard varnish of academia. No wonder so many of us leave high school with no interest in literature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He knew everything about literature except how to enjoy it. — Joseph Heller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t know when the quest for the &lt;em&gt;message&lt;/em&gt; or the &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; of a work of fiction became a thing. It might have been around the time the definition of literature morphed from a canon of work into a discipline. The idea that you have to study for four years in order to appreciate Hemingway (or Woolf, or Tolstoy, or Wilde) is, to me, as bizarre as the (related) notion that the goal of reading a novel should be to dredge up some profound and indispensable truth which the author has cunningly hidden in the depths of the subtext. Our schools and colleges are awash with self-proclaimed arbiters of authorial intent who would have us approach fiction as though it were a science built on absolute truths. If you ever encounter a multiple choice literature test, burn it. Right or wrong is the product of an education system gone badly awry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not read, as children do, to amuse yourself, or like the ambitious, for the purpose of instruction. No, read in order to live. — Gustave Flaubert&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was an actual book called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Read_a_Book" target="_blank"&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/a&gt; published in the 1940s. It focused almost entirely on non-fiction and encouraged the reader to analyze everything ad nauseam. In case you hadn&amp;#39;t guessed, this essay is exclusively about fiction (never let mere accuracy get in the way of a good title) and advocates entirely the opposite approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t subject the text to moralizing, rationalization or allegory. Don&amp;#39;t seek knowledge or erudition from fiction; in fact don&amp;#39;t ask anything of it. Keep your left brain in check, immerse yourself in the author&amp;#39;s world and in doing so gain new perspective on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read for pleasure. Don&amp;#39;t approach a novel as a necessary evils to be digested like broccoli or fish oil; they won&amp;#39;t make you smarter, a better conversationalist, get you that dream job or impress your friends. The joy of fiction is much bigger than that: the intimacy of the bond between reader and author, the recognition of self and others by way of the universal traits of the human condition, an encounter with genius on our own terms. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skip the synopsis on the back cover, it&amp;#39;s just mediocre advertising copyright. Ignore the critics, the professors and the study guides. What a book means to them says nothing about your life, and what a book means to you is none of their business. Literary interpretation is phony; the only truth is the text, and your emotional reaction to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revel in it. Lose yourself in it. Live it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/w2RtmnBCevQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.anguscroll.com/how-to-read-a-book</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jamietie,2012:Post/hypocrisy-cowardice-and-the-Cherokee-Scout</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T09:00:51-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T09:00:51-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/OyrD3tu4xjA/hypocrisy-cowardice-and-the-Cherokee-Scout" />
    <author>
      <name>Jamie Kelly</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jamietie.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Hypocrisy, cowardice and the Cherokee Scout</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;#39;t really surprise me when &lt;em&gt;Cherokee Scout&lt;/em&gt; editor Robert Horne &lt;a href="http://jimromenesko.typepad.com/my-blog/2013/03/north-carolina-editor-who-made-controversial-gun-request-resigns.html"&gt;resigned&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes you do something and it renders you ineffective. He did the right thing, and it cost him his job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least he can leave North Carolina with his head held high, and with some well-deserved kudos from his publisher:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We wish Robert well in all his future endeavors,&amp;rdquo; said David Brown, publisher of the Scout and Journal. &amp;ldquo;He&amp;#39;s a good man who has done a lot of positive things for the area that should be remembered.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brown on the other hand, gets to stay in North Carolina and hang his head in shame. That shame isn&amp;#39;t just because he &lt;a href="http://blog.jamietie.com/in-defense-of-publishing-data-on-gun-ownership"&gt;backed down and licked the sheriff&amp;#39;s boots when confronted with controversy&lt;/a&gt;. No, he gets even more shame because of the ad he posted today on &lt;a href="http://www.journalismjobs.com/Job_Listing.cfm?JobID=1477263"&gt;JournalismJobs.com&lt;/a&gt;. That ad begins:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you always wanted to be the editor so you can order the rest of the newsroom around while challenging the community with your extreme political views? Then this isn&amp;#39;t the job for you. Instead, we&amp;#39;re looking for an editor who knows how to tell good stories&amp;mdash;the kind people will always make time to read&amp;mdash;from breaking news to heartwarming features to in-depth reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High praise indeed for Horne, who&amp;#39;d been out the door for fewer than three weeks. It&amp;#39;s another sad but not surprising sign that community journalism&amp;mdash;the kind where so many reporters and editors learn their craft&amp;mdash;is often no longer concerned with standing up for the public&amp;#39;s right to know, no longer interested in holding elected officials to account, and no longer interested in the kind of journalism that can actually change a community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/jamietie_24545715367176_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_jamietie_24545715367176_raw.jpg" alt="cloud.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(The next front page story in the &lt;em&gt;Scout&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing for openness, access and accountability are not extreme political views. They are, or they should be, the very foundation of a local newspaper. Shame on Brown for betraying that, and shame on any other editor, publisher or owner who would do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And perhaps the saddest part is that the damage&amp;mdash;if, indeed, there was any&amp;mdash;is already done. Anything Brown does now won&amp;#39;t have any effect on the people who&amp;#39;d decided the paper wanted to come for their guns. All it does is tell the people who had supported the paper before and the rest of the journalism community, that there is no principle Brown will hold to, given the right amount of pressure. That&amp;#39;s a sad message to send and an even sadder one to receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/OyrD3tu4xjA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jamietie.com/hypocrisy-cowardice-and-the-Cherokee-Scout</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/data-biases</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T07:45:22-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T07:45:22-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/bM5W3UAbLDY/data-biases" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Which Data Biases Challenge Your Startup?</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24546681820170_raw.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24546681820170_raw.gif" alt="lies3.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Sinofsky, executive at Microsoft for 24 years &lt;a href="http://blog.learningbyshipping.com/2013/03/16/using-data-to-inform-strategy/"&gt;penned an insightful post on the five data biases plaguing product decisions.&lt;/a&gt; It can be easy for any founder, product manager, marketer or engineer accept a data point at face value as the rationale behind a decision. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But understanding the nuances and biases of the data, questioning the data, is often just as important as the result. The corollary point argued in his post is data isn&amp;#39;t strategy - data can&amp;#39;t be blindly used to inform product design and decision making because the data might be &amp;ldquo;lies, damned lies and statistics&amp;rdquo;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve highlights five data biases seen often in his career:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representation.&lt;/strong&gt;  No data can represent all people using (or who will use) a product. So who was represented in the data?&lt;br&gt;
Forward or backward looking.  When looking at product usage, the data looks at how the product was used but not how it will be used down the road (assuming changes).  Is the data justifying the choice or informing the e
choice?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contextual.&lt;/strong&gt;  The data depends on context in which it is collected, so if the user interface is sub-optimal or drives a certain pattern the data does not necessarily represent a valid conclusion.  Did the data consider that the collection was itself flawed?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Counter-intuitive.&lt;/strong&gt; The data is viewed as counter-intuitive and does not follow the conventional wisdom, so something must be wrong.  How could the data overlook what is obvious?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Causation or correlation.&lt;/strong&gt; With data you can see an end state, but it is not always clear what caused the end-state.  If something is used a lot, crashes a lot, or is avoided there might be many reasons, most not readily apparent or at least open to debate, that cause that end-state.  Is the end-state coincident with the some variables or do those variables cause the end-state?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my day to day, the correlation or causation one is most common. When evaluating a businesse&amp;#39;s performance it&amp;#39;s easy to assume that one metric (new feature release) causes another to increase (engagement) but making that leap isn&amp;#39;t always correct.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which data biases do you encounter most often? &lt;a href="http://branch.com/b/which-data-biases-challenge-your-startup/invite_link/3qYqdlra6yEwnw"&gt;Tell me in this Branch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/bM5W3UAbLDY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/data-biases</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:adii,2012:Post/success-measured-in-relevance</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T04:53:53-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T04:53:53-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/Jfpai-j67-E/success-measured-in-relevance" />
    <author>
      <name>Adii Pienaar</name>
      <uri>http://adii.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Success Measured In Relevance</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The answer comes down to one simple question – relevance. Many entrepreneurs don’t want to just be successful. They want to be relevant. And they want to stay relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Being relevant means people pay attention to you, care about what you have to say and talk about you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Money alone can’t buy relevance.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/today/post/article/20130317133520-1714080-when-is-it-ok-to-bash-a-founder"&gt;This is from a recent Michael Lazerow post&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; it reminded me a little of one of my personal needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In broad terms, &lt;a href="http://adii.me/happiness-success"&gt;happiness means success to me&lt;/a&gt;. But I&amp;#39;m also happy when I feel relevant; not just in professional life, but also my personal life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to be heard, I want to be validated and &lt;a href="http://adii.me/youre-born-an-entrepreneur"&gt;I want the opportunity to just be me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#39;t some narcissistic thing that only a elite few people experience either; I bet if you ask yourself why you get up in the morning to work on whatever, somewhere within that reason there&amp;#39;s the need to be relevant. Everyone wants to be proud of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shit thing about relevance however is that it&amp;#39;s very difficult to measure without doing so by the feedback of peers, which means you can&amp;#39;t control that. You don&amp;#39;t just wake up in the morning and feel relevant without getting that external feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So how do you measure relevance (and indirectly, success) in a way that you can control yourself?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/Jfpai-j67-E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://adii.me/success-measured-in-relevance</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:youssef,2012:Post/what-were-they-thinking</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T21:22:51-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T21:22:51-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/SiH2vtr-uMA/what-were-they-thinking" />
    <author>
      <name>Youssef Sarhan</name>
      <uri>http://sefsar.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>You thought Samsung was misogynistic? Blu Products just set a new standard</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier today I read &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/18/4100006/why-blu-products-can-beat-samsung"&gt;a post on The Verge&lt;/a&gt; about a &amp;ldquo;tiny, Florida-based phone maker that thinks it can beat Samsung&amp;rdquo;. I was interested, so I did some research on the company, Blu Products. I wanted to see if they really have what it takes to beat Samsung. Fortunately for Samsung, it appears they do. Yes, fortunately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, Samsung got a &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/18/4119052/samsung-weird-behind-the-scenes-of-the-sexist-galaxy-s4-launch"&gt;little weird&lt;/a&gt; on us. Not quite &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/1/8/3850056/qualcomms-insane-ces-2013-keynote-pictures-tweets"&gt;Qualcomm weird&lt;/a&gt;, but certainly weird. However, tonight I came across something that makes everything before it seem so acceptable, some might say admirable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my pleasure(?) to introduce Blu Products&amp;#39; understanding of marketing. In the following video, you will witness what I can only describe as prostitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="550" height="309" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/0mVrCxNe7uc?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video speaks for itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between this, &lt;a href="http://sefsar.com/terrible-copywriting-on-applecom"&gt;Apple&amp;#39;s &amp;ldquo;Why iPhone&amp;rdquo; page&lt;/a&gt;, last weeks Samsung event, the &lt;a href="http://sefsar.com/nokia-faked-the-still-photos-too"&gt;fake Nokia Lumia 920 photos&lt;/a&gt;, the Qualcomm pageantry and &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/HO7aX7vt7Qs"&gt;this horrible music video featuring Blackberry executives&lt;/a&gt; there is strong empirical evidence to suggest that the classiness of a company&amp;#39;s marketing is an accurate barometer of fiscal success within the mobile handset industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t stop laughing, I don&amp;#39;t even know why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case it wasn&amp;#39;t obvious, Blu Products used an iPhone in that advert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24545982530322_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24545982530322_raw.png" alt="iphone.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/SiH2vtr-uMA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sefsar.com/what-were-they-thinking</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jamietie,2012:Post/media-rape-culture-victim-blaming-and-stuebenville</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T12:39:57-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T12:39:57-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/rWw8xtn1-5Q/media-rape-culture-victim-blaming-and-stuebenville" />
    <author>
      <name>Jamie Kelly</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jamietie.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Media, rape culture, victim blaming and Steubenville</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine asked an insightful question on &lt;a href="http://fancycwabs.com/post/45685158350/in-which-our-intrepid-adventurer-is-confused"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; about how we&amp;#39;ve gotten to the point where young men would feel that raping an unconscious woman is acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of rape is unfathomable to me: I can’t wrap my brain around what would drive a man to put his penis into something that wasn’t actively interested in having a penis put into it. What drives a person, seeing an unconscious person, to think “you know what sounds like a good idea? Putting my penis into that person.”&lt;br&gt;
Where did we fall apart as a society to a degree where shoving your dong into people became a thing? Where our sexual response is so screwed up that uninterested people give us raging boners? Have we gotten ourselves so twisted up with sexual taboos and edicts that we demonize consensual behavior and give genuinely fucked up actions a pass? Are dudes being somehow taught that the world somehow owes them orgasms? That they’re out there, waiting to be plucked from a tree like a piece of fruit?&lt;br&gt;
Am I missing some critical part of male upbringing that was supposed to condition me to get aroused in the presence of unwilling partners?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, it is not at all inconceivable to many people. More than &lt;a href="http://www.rainn.org/get-information/statistics/frequency-of-sexual-assault"&gt;200,000 people are raped each year&lt;/a&gt;, and that&amp;#39;s despite the fact rape has decreased by more than 60 percent since 1993. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about that for a second: Even with historic declines in rape, one person is sexually assaulted every two minutes in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So rape is certainly conceivable to so very many people. And the punishment they face is often non-existent. According to the Rape, Abuse &amp;amp; Incest National Network and U.S. Justice Department statistics, &lt;a href="http://www.rainn.org/get-information/statistics/reporting-rates"&gt;97 percent of rapists never spend a day in prison&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps that&amp;#39;s one of the reasons a CNN anchor felt such sympathy for the two Stuebenville boys sentenced for raping a 16-year-old: A trial, let alone a conviction and sentence, is vanishingly 
rare in cases of rape and sexual assault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/jamietie_24545420515980_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_jamietie_24545420515980_raw.jpg" alt="Jailedrapists.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(Source: &lt;a href="http://www.rainn.org/get-information/statistics/reporting-rates"&gt;RAINN.org&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And part of that is because of the attitudes we&amp;#39;ve seen around the Stuebenville case. The &lt;a href="http://publicshaming.tumblr.com/post/45635407944/the-victim-blaming-slut-shaming-reactions-to-the"&gt;Public Shaming tumblr&lt;/a&gt; pointed to a lot of reactions blaming the victim for drinking, dressing provocatively, and for simply being present. One even suggested that Mays and Richmond did what any man would do when presented with an unconscious woman: they assaulted her. Thankfully every man does not act that way, but too many do. And they&amp;#39;re defended for doing so. One blog post (which I&amp;#39;m refusing to link to&amp;mdash;trolls thrive on links) suggested that the fact the victim was drinking, dressed provocatively, and around young men meant that her consent was implied. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is the logical equivalent of suggesting that someone driving on New Year&amp;#39;s Eve who is killed by a drunk driver was asking to be killed because he or she should have known better than to be out when it was dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this falls under the idea of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rape_culture"&gt;Rape Culture&lt;/a&gt;, where sexual assault is common, rarely punished, and treated as a minor offense. And when news organizations lament sentences for rapists as life ruining&amp;mdash;even when they&amp;#39;re really no such thing, as the pair will spend one to two years in juvenile detention, and at most be held through their 21st birthdays (they are 16 and 17 now), and Ohio&amp;#39;s adult justice system prescribes a minimum sentence of five years for rape&amp;mdash;they are contributing to that culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A responsible media organization, and as much as this truly pains me to say, a good example of that in this case is &lt;a href="http://gawker.com/5991003/cnn-reports-on-the-promising-future-of-the-steubenville-rapists-who-are-very-good-students"&gt;Gawker&lt;/a&gt;, would point out that the true solution to rape isn&amp;#39;t for women to stay home, stay sober, and dress in whatever passes for conservatively, it&amp;#39;s for people &lt;strong&gt;not to rape other people.&lt;/strong&gt; And it would make clear that no matter how drunk, or how she was dressed, or what the situation is, a woman has the absolute and total right not to be raped. That should be the lesson the Stuebenville story is teaching the world. Instead, thanks to CNN and legions of Internet rape apologists, we&amp;#39;re left with the same backward, misogynistic ideas we&amp;#39;ve always had. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/rWw8xtn1-5Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jamietie.com/media-rape-culture-victim-blaming-and-stuebenville</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jonrussell,2012:Post/geeks-on-a-plane-is-coming-to-southeast-asia</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T12:05:12-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T12:05:12-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/jys4yK4dsj0/geeks-on-a-plane-is-coming-to-southeast-asia" />
    <author>
      <name>Jon Russell</name>
      <uri>http://insidethenoodlebowl.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>'Geeks On A Plane' is coming to Southeast Asia</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://500.co/2013/03/13/this-summers-biggest-blockbuster-geeks-on-a-plane-southeast-asia/"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is pretty exciting news for Southeast Asia:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mission at 500 is to find incredible entrepreneurs wherever they are –  whether they’re in Silicon Valley, New York, or Thailand. Big things are happening in Southeast Asia (SEA), and we’re proud to announce that Geeks on a Plane will make its very first trip to SEA this June!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geeks on a Plane SEA will take place June 1st – June 15th and will be making stops in Singapore, Kuala Lumpur, Bangkok, and Jakarta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The region has the potential to grow to number hundreds of millions of Internet-crazed, mobile-first consumers, and I definitely think it is one for &lt;a href="http://insidethenoodlebowl.com/us-investors-showing-greater-interest-in-southeast-asia"&gt;US investors to at least get to know more about&lt;/a&gt;, if not begin focusing on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m looking forward to seeing the GOAP tour come to my city, Bangkok, it&amp;#39;s really quite hard to believe how much more vibrant the tech scene here is today. Yet there&amp;#39;s still plenty more development to come, perhaps aided by 500 Startups and GOAP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/asia/2013/03/17/geeks-on-a-plane-southeast-asia/"&gt;For more info see the TNW write-up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/jys4yK4dsj0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://insidethenoodlebowl.com/geeks-on-a-plane-is-coming-to-southeast-asia</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:cap,2012:Post/switching-from-rss-to-twitter</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T11:19:53-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T11:19:53-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/4R8giFr_oG8/switching-from-rss-to-twitter" />
    <author>
      <name>Cap Watkins</name>
      <uri>http://blog.capwatkins.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Switching from RSS to Twitter</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the recent news that Google is shutting down Google Reader, I decided to give Twitter feeds a try as a replacement. It&amp;#39;s been a few days now and I wanted to outline a few of the pros and cons, just in case anyone is considering making the switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little about my setup first: I chose to start a new Twitter account vs. using Twitter lists. Maybe it&amp;#39;s unnecessary complexity, but it seems pretty obvious that, like DMs, Twitter wishes Lists didn&amp;#39;t exist and would kill them if it could (and may still). I have a feeling they&amp;#39;re not apt to kill the ability to follow people anytime soon, so I opted for a second account. Using Lists would certainly make sharing easier (and Tweetbot has amazing Lists support), but I&amp;#39;m comfortable with the trade-off. Do whichever you like best! Anyway, here we go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro: One less app&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh man, this was an unintended consequence, but feels really, really good. Reeder is an amazing application, but getting to remove it from my Mac dock and iPhone homescreen gave me that one-less-thing feeling. I&amp;#39;m a pretty habitual organizer and consolidator, and know some people couldn&amp;#39;t care any less about that sort of thing. So yeah, your mileage may vary. I loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro: Simplified and synced feed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, this is a usage-specific nicety. I tend to always just press the &amp;ldquo;Unread&amp;rdquo; tab in Reeder and just work my way through the full list chronologically. This means scrolling to the very bottom and working my way up (new stuff is at the top in Reeder). That way I get to see the news evolve over the day and not piece it together in reverse. The beautiful thing about using Twitter (and Tweetbot specifically) is that no matter where I open the feed (Mac, iPhone, iPad), I&amp;#39;m a) synced to the last place I was and b) everything new is upward. It&amp;#39;s been like magic and has made me mad at myself for resisting trying this in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro: Sharing and starring are back!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, it&amp;#39;s Twitter. So yeah. Sharing and favoriting are the name of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Con: Not all the sites I followed on Reader have Twitter accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are few, but they definitely existed. I decided to try life without them and haven&amp;#39;t missed them very much at all. Kind of a good forced pruning tool, but would have been nice to have it be 1-to-1. This also limits me in the future if a new web site or blog doesn&amp;#39;t have a Twitter feed that links to their articles. Which brings me to the other con:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Con: Not all blog Twitter feeds are actually article links&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The example right off the top of my head is &lt;a href="http://www.swiss-miss.com/"&gt;swissmiss&lt;/a&gt;. Her RSS feed is one-to-one with her blog content (of course), but &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/swissmiss"&gt;her Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;, as far as I can tell, &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; links to her blog. It totally makes sense for that to be the case, but it just means I&amp;#39;m not receiving any ingress point to her content except to visit the web site directly (which, honestly, I&amp;#39;m probably not going to remember to do with any regularity).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;#39;ve started using Twitter for feeds, I&amp;#39;m unlikely to ever go back. The ease of sharing, Favoriting, Retweeting, sending to Instapaper, etc. not only match, but at times surpass even Reeder in terms of ease and simplicity. One less app to deal with is a win, not to mention that the links are ordered exactly as I like them (and holy crap, Tweetbot iCloud sync. So good).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1, wish I would have done this before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/4R8giFr_oG8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.capwatkins.com/switching-from-rss-to-twitter</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:maccman,2012:Post/analyzing-my-dna</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T09:47:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T09:47:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/Iy0-kom198Q/analyzing-my-dna" />
    <author>
      <name>Alex MacCaw</name>
      <uri>http://blog.alexmaccaw.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Analyzing my DNA</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently bought &lt;a href="http://23andme.com"&gt;23andme&lt;/a&gt;, a service which requires you to send off a DNA sample, and in return performs a series of interesting tests concerning your health and ancestry. I bought the test as a birthday present to myself, somewhat because I was interested in the results, but also because I wanted to treat it as a catalyst for learning more about the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have heard that a human&amp;#39;s genome is 98.5% identical to a chimpanzee&amp;#39;s. While this is true, the human genome contains over 3 billion base pairs, so just a one percent difference means that over 30 million nucleotides have changed. A single change in a base pair can dramatically alter the protein created, and easily account for the differences between our two species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans usually have 46 paired chromosomes, representing 23 chromosomes from each parent (hence the name 23andme). What&amp;#39;s interesting is that the older the species, the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_organisms_by_chromosome_count"&gt;more the chromosomes&lt;/a&gt;, or at least this is the trend. Some ferns, such as the adders-tounge, have 1440 chromosomes, whilst a mango has 40. As DNA replicates and mutates through generations, so more genes can be added. Indeed, our genome contains traces of &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-17809503"&gt;ancient dead viruses&lt;/a&gt;, introduced in a common ancestor over 100 million years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in the process of getting your DNA analyzed by 23andme, is to put a substantial amount of saliva into to a specialized container they mail you. This saliva contains cheek cells, which is what 23andme use for genotyping. They don&amp;#39;t need many cells, but the reason why they ask for so much saliva is so that it&amp;#39;s harder to take someone else&amp;#39;s DNA without their permission!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the DNA sample is mailed off to 23andme&amp;#39;s laboratory where it&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polymerase_chain_reaction"&gt;amplified through PCR&lt;/a&gt;, a process where the DNA is separated from the nucleus and replicated. Lastly it&amp;#39;s put through a machine which, rather than sequence the whole genome, looking for specific &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single-nucleotide_polymorphism"&gt;SNPs&lt;/a&gt;. These SNPs are responsible for a lot of the biological differences between people, and variations influence a variety of traits such as height, eye color and disease susceptibility. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now 23andme have analyzed about a million of your SNPs, it&amp;#39;s time to draw some conclusions from the genotyping. Most of the health and trait reports are based on genetic association studies, taking a specific SNP and testing for associations with factors like eye color and diseases like Parkinson&amp;#39;s. Furthermore, 23andme can correlate diseases and symptoms from all their users to specific SNPs, furthering research and understanding of how they affect our bodies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genetic associations are not a certainty that a specific SNP will have a specific outcome, but rather a probability. Correlations doesn&amp;#39;t mean causation either, and while there may be an association, additional research is needed to show whether the factor has a causal effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a bunch of heritable genetic disorders that 23andme tests carrier status for, such as Cystic Fibrosis. While the gene for Cystic Fibrosis is recessive, if you mate with someone who also has the same recessive gene, then the likelihood is that your child will develop the disease is one quater. Other disorders like Huntington&amp;#39;s are dominant, and only requires one parent to be a carrier. 23andme doesn&amp;#39;t seem to do much testing of dominant genetic disorders, as it&amp;#39;s likely that the parents are already aware of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working out how SNP affects a phenotype trait is tricky. Most SNP changes have no effect, while other characteristics are due to environmental factors. One way of investigating this, is by studying identical twins. Since they have the exact same DNA, any differences between the two can be attributed to environmental factors. Some phenotypes like height are mostly influenced by your genetics (assuming you have a good nutrition), while others like freckles are more affected by the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This difference between environmental and heritable traits is often called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nature_versus_nurture"&gt;nature vs nuture&lt;/a&gt;, and can be fairly controversial at times. Take, for example, IQ. The effect that parents have upon their children&amp;#39;s intelligence is in serious dispute and, while a neglectful and abusive upbringing can have an adverse effect, given a base minimum supportive parenting doesn&amp;#39;t have have much of an influence on IQ. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nature_versus_nurture#IQ_debate"&gt;Studies have shown&lt;/a&gt; that identical twins who grow up in separate families have an IQ correlation of 0.74, while adoptive siblings have no more similar IQ than strangers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not going to talk about the more sensitive health information I gleaned from the report, as while President Bush signed the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act I&amp;#39;m still wary of how it could affect my insurance in the future. However, let&amp;#39;s talk about a non sensitive trait, &lt;em&gt;lactose intolerance&lt;/em&gt;. Lactose intolerance is fairly heritable and is influenced by an SNP near the LCT gene which encodes lactase, an enzyme required for digestion of milk. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, the lactase enzyme is only produced in the first few years of a mammals life. However, certain European populations have a mutation that causes lactase to be produced throughout their lives. Dairy farming, which is widespread primarily in Europe, provided additional sources of nutrition to early inhabitants of Europe. Thus, it is thought, being able to drink milk throughout adulthood would have provided them with an evolutionary advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My genotype for this SNP is AG, or adenine and guanine. This has been correlated with higher adult lactase levels. This allele is rarer in Africa and Asia, hence the high cases of lactose intolerance in those regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SNP: rs4988235 (A or G)&lt;br&gt;
Alex&amp;#39;s Genotype: AG&lt;br&gt;
Gene: MCM6&lt;br&gt;
Chromosome: 2   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I say, while this trait is heritable, it is also influenced by environmental characteristics such as the bacteria in your gut. In other words, having a AG genotype doesn&amp;#39;t always mean you&amp;#39;ll be lactose tolerant, and vice versa. It&amp;#39;s all about probability, and in this case 23andme were correct - I am lactose tolerant, which is useful as I enjoy milk! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calculating ancestry through DNA is an interesting process, because it turns out that the variations between you and your ancestor&amp;#39;s DNA make it impossible to detect relations after a few generations or so. However the Y chromosome is passed down from father to son without much alteration, which means it makes a perfect candidate for looking into your past. Maternal descent is calculated from DNA found in the mitochondria, as this too is passed down unaltered from mother to child. Using these two pieces of information we can look hundreds of thousands of years into our past, as well as at our more recent history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ancestors, on both my mother&amp;#39;s and father&amp;#39;s side, are from Europe - mostly from the UK, Ireland and Scotland, with a little Spanish and German mix. My DNA is 2.9% neanderthal, which puts me in the top 91% of 23andme&amp;#39;s members (not sure what conclusions to draw from that!). I&amp;#39;m also distantly related to Jesse James on my mother&amp;#39;s side, and have found a previously unknown second cousin in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genetic family trees can be identified by looking at haplogroups, a set of genetic mutations that are shared by everyone in the group. The likelihood is that if you share a lot of specific genetic mutations with someone, than you&amp;#39;re related. All haplogroups can be traced back to a mutation in a single individual. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, 8 percent of asian males are in the &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1180246/"&gt;same haplogroup as Genghis Khan&lt;/a&gt;,  and carry Y chromosomes that share many of the same SNPs. Y chromosomes aren&amp;#39;t recombined when they&amp;#39;re inherited, so genetic mutations in them act as markers, allowing geneticists to trace them back and predict in time the moment they occurred. Such a rapid spread of this particular mutation is unlikely to have happened by chance, and suggests that 0.5% of the world&amp;#39;s population are descendants of Genghis Khan and his male relatives - quite a staggering amount. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geneticists can trace back humans to a single male and female, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Y-chromosomal_Adam"&gt;a genetic &amp;ldquo;Adam and Eve&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. What&amp;#39;s fascinating is that while Adam lived about 142,000 years ago, Eve lived much earlier, about 200,000 years ago - they never met each other. Y-chromosomal Adam lived at a time close to the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recent_African_origin_of_modern_humans"&gt;migration from Africa&lt;/a&gt;, and this turmoil could suggest a reason why so few males lineages survived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analyzing my DNA has given me a fascinating insight into my health and ancestry, and something I&amp;#39;d recommend to everyone. However, personally the best part of the whole process was learning more about DNA and how it effects us. It&amp;#39;s a fascinating subject which is undergoing a lot of research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a separate note, 23andme&amp;#39;s service is really commendable. Businesses that combine commercial products with scientific research and advances are close to my heart. Other examples of this kind of approach are SpaceX and Tesla. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/Iy0-kom198Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.alexmaccaw.com/analyzing-my-dna</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:buster,2012:Post/how-to-change-yourself-v01</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T08:03:04-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T08:03:04-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/cqR7GfvjMPs/how-to-change-yourself-v01" />
    <author>
      <name>Buster Benson</name>
      <uri>http://wayoftheduck.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>How to change yourself (v 0.1)</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are many other ways to change, but this is the one that is my current best/favorite theory. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Complete the sentence: &amp;ldquo;I am an aspiring ______.&amp;rdquo; Try to find the most succinct identity that represents the difference between who you are now and who you want to be. It doesn&amp;#39;t have to explain why, or how, you will get there. Just put a flag down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; I realize that this first step is not very easy to do. That&amp;#39;s intentional. Step #1 will require some thinking to find the right fit for your &amp;ldquo;lose 5 pounds&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;eat better&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;quit smoking&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;get in shape&amp;rdquo; goals. Think about the &lt;em&gt;kind of person you want to become&lt;/em&gt; that &lt;em&gt;naturally&lt;/em&gt; weighs less, eats well, doesn&amp;#39;t smoke, is in shape, etc. Make sure that you really do want to be that person. Use this identity as the anchor to pull all of the entangled habits and behaviors into yourself (assume here that you&amp;#39;re at the bottom of the ocean and it is difficult to pull things towards you).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Update your bios on Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, and other favorite social networks with the sentence from #1. You don&amp;#39;t have to announce anything about it, but it needs to be somewhere that random people can see it. (This makes it feel real.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Craft another sentence describing a 1-month resolution which strategically gets you closer to #1, and has the following constraints:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#39;s only ONE resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phrase it in such a way that it is either HIT or MISSED for a given month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that it&amp;#39;s calibrated in such a way that if it ends up being HIT, you will be happy with yourself, and if it turns out to be MISSED for the month you&amp;#39;ll be unhappy with yourself. Do not make it so easy or so difficult that it&amp;#39;s possible to fail at the resolution while still being happy that progress has been made, or succeed at the resolution and still being unhappy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include any footnotes you feel are necessary to say what you think &amp;ldquo;counts&amp;rdquo; and what you think &amp;ldquo;doesn&amp;#39;t count&amp;rdquo; for interpretations of the resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; Join the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups=#!forum/rabbit-rabbit"&gt;Rabbit Rabbit Resolution Accountability Squad&lt;/a&gt; mailing list and introduce yourself by stating the answers to #1 and #3. Feel free to ask for help clarifying or zeroing in on what you&amp;#39;re really interested in working on. Prepare for friendly feedback from the group, too. Comment on as many threads from other people working on resolutions as you feel comfortable. (This is your accountability.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; Set a reminder on your calendar which repeats on the 1st of every month. Everyone on the mailing list will be expected to report in with progress, revise their resolution if necessary, and recommit to the next month. The three outcomes are HIT, MISS, and (if you neglect to check in within 3 days of the beginning of the month) ABSENT. (This helps you remember to remember, which is often the main culprit for failed resolutions.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Extra credit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; Start a public countdown on Twitter, Facebook, or your public venue of choice that starts at 1,000. Any time you do something that gets you a small step towards #1, state what you did along with the current number. I&amp;#39;ve been doing this with my aspiration to be a marathon runner and it&amp;#39;s been quite useful as a tool. 1,000 things is a lot, so I allow myself to include things that have a somewhat loose connection to the identity, and at the same time I am okay with missing a day here and there since getting to 0 is going to take a long time anyway. Also, because of the numbers, there will be plenty of significant milestones to celebrate along the way. (This helps you ignore small setbacks and stay focused on the long-term goal.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related reading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wayoftheduck.com/1000-small-things"&gt;1000 small things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wayoftheduck.com/rabbit-rabbit"&gt;Earlier post from when Rabbit Rabbit started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wayoftheduck.com/huge-habits"&gt;Are habits tiny or huge?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wayoftheduck.com/long-slog"&gt;The long slog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wayoftheduck.com/belief-change"&gt;Behavior change is belief change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wayoftheduck.com/habit-manifesto"&gt;Habit Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;To slog successfully toward goals, habits, or a better life: Go slow. Work hard. Avoid shortcuts. Remember to remember. Be kind to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Buster (@buster) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/buster/status/308442636996452352"&gt;March 4, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suggest edits:&lt;/strong&gt;
If you want to help me improve this, suggest edits &lt;a href="https://draftin.com/documents/26163?token=JQaDVUDkO4s3Fm4CnWwPPp9a_1HNUIENGo2ac0vea3g"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/cqR7GfvjMPs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://wayoftheduck.com/how-to-change-yourself-v01</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/dark-social-on-google-analytics</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T07:43:24-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T07:43:24-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/ewnWHFe1Evs/dark-social-on-google-analytics" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Measuring Dark Social Using Google Analytics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24543684999792_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24543684999792_raw.jpg" alt="Lucas-Higgs-CE0047H-nice2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In social media, like the real world, there&amp;#39;s quite a lot of gossip going on behind your back. At least on the Internet, you can measure it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dubbed dark social, this &amp;ldquo;invisible&amp;rdquo; sharing brings 40% of the visitors to my blog and similar amounts of traffic to other content sites. The Atlantic Monthly, which receives 5M monthly uniques, &lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2012/10/dark-social-we-have-the-whole-history-of-the-web-wrong/263523/"&gt;reports 60% of traffic from dark social&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like its distant cousin dark energy, dark social is a massive and to date little understood force despite its importance. Dark social clicks originate from instant messages, emails containing links and links embedded in tweets opened in TweetDeck among other sources. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Analytics buckets dark social as direct navigation, incorrectly assuming these users spontaneously typed a long url from some epiphany. But as marketer Cody Boyte from Axial showed me last week, It is possible to approximate dark social traffic with Google Analytics. No Large Hadron Collider needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a filter for dark social traffic, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log into Google Analytics and click on the Advanced Segment button. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new segment called Dark Social that excludes the landing page that exactly matches &amp;ldquo;/&amp;rdquo; and the Source contains (direct). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a screenshot of the filter. To view more help on &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=1033017"&gt;Advanced Segments click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24543701890596_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24543701890596_raw.png" alt="ScreenCapture at Sun Mar 17 09:49:27 PDT 2013.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Advanced Segment will track all the visitors who arrived at your site with click to deep link without ever visiting the home page: Dark Social traffic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How important is Dark Social traffic for your site? &lt;a href="http://branch.com/b/measuring-dark-social-using-google-analytics/invite_link/KIGsROa-SsT3XQ"&gt;Let me know on this Branch.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/ewnWHFe1Evs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/dark-social-on-google-analytics</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:adii,2012:Post/youre-born-an-entrepreneur</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T02:30:24-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T02:30:24-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/koAlbaZoD4E/youre-born-an-entrepreneur" />
    <author>
      <name>Adii Pienaar</name>
      <uri>http://adii.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>You're Born An Entrepreneur</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Saturday morning, I was attending (i.e. my 16-month old son can&amp;#39;t drive; so I was the chaperone) a first birthday party for friends&amp;#39; twins and I got speaking to someone that I met there. The conversation quickly turned to entrepreneurship and how it can&amp;#39;t be taught; instead you&amp;#39;re either born with critical characteristics that makes you an entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/16/bring-out-the-beast/"&gt;I then read this&lt;/a&gt;, this morning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Startups, like professional football, are best done by the most desperate people on the planet. Products don’t just walk out the door on their own. Sooner or later, to ship something amazing, you have to dig deep and bring out your beast. A horse running wild is a rare sight, but it takes your breath away every time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This struck a chord with me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last 11-odd years that I&amp;#39;ve been building businesses (the initial attempts - when I was still at school - can&amp;#39;t really be called businesses and should probably be labeled as &lt;em&gt;projects&lt;/em&gt;), I&amp;#39;ve often considered my drive to be a curse and &lt;a href="http://adii.me/passion-work"&gt;my passion to be a beast that needs to be fed&lt;/a&gt;. I regularly compromised on all the aspects of my life (going out for drinks for friends, working on weekends, spending time with my family etc.) in the short-term in the pursuit of something greater in the long-term. And for most of that pursuit, I didn&amp;#39;t even know what that &lt;em&gt;something greater&lt;/em&gt; even was. (I&amp;#39;ve only recently distilled this to my passion for &lt;a href="http://adii.me/2-things-i-love"&gt;helping other entrepreneurs&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the average person, this probably constitutes irrational and abnormal behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can also remember a conversation I had with a friend back in the day when we were at varsity. My friend kept talking about business and how he was gonna be this hot shot entrepreneur one day. At one stage, I asked him when he&amp;#39;ll work on his first business and he replied: &amp;ldquo;One day when I&amp;#39;m older.&amp;rdquo;. Today he is doing really well in a corporate job, where he is climbing the ladder with some great pace. To this day, he also hasn&amp;#39;t shown any inclination to be an entrepreneur. &lt;em&gt;This has never made sense to me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brain has been wired in such a way that I can easily compute the risk &amp;amp; reward of any decision. My personality is such that I chase after the impossible and (when it comes to business at least) I&amp;#39;m fearless in that pursuit. I live for the adrenaline of being challenged, being out-of-my-depth and not really knowing what tomorrow holds (and how I will overcome that). I&amp;#39;m fueled by my ambition to change the world and my drive to learn something new every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was born this way. This is who I am.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the only version of me that I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heck, don&amp;#39;t get me wrong. Some days I wish I can switch off all of this and I can just be &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; (whatever that means). But I can&amp;#39;t; I don&amp;#39;t know where that switch is and whether it even exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I wake up every morning and I get back onto the rollercoaster. This is just what I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/koAlbaZoD4E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://adii.me/youre-born-an-entrepreneur</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jamietie,2012:Post/media-mishandling-of-a-rape-verdict</id>
    <published>2013-03-17T18:26:14-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T18:26:14-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/IGVQrCmn78I/media-mishandling-of-a-rape-verdict" />
    <author>
      <name>Jamie Kelly</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jamietie.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Media mishandling of a rape verdict</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Steubenville, Ohio, rape case has been media catnip for months now&amp;mdash;it has so many elements that make it compelling: cover-ups, fallen teenagers, social media misbehavior, &amp;amp;c. It draws people in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s been less focus on the victim, which is unsurprising&amp;mdash;it seems that a lot of network and cable journalists and talking heads are more interested in the impact of the rape on the culture of the town (which is very interesting, but secondary), and on the effect on the football team, particularly the two players accused of rape. That is less interesting, unless we talk about how the team culture enabled and protected them&amp;mdash;made them feel that of course they could sexually assault a young woman. But that hasn&amp;#39;t been the narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rawstory.com/rs/2013/03/17/cnn-grieves-that-guilty-verdict-ruined-promising-lives-of-steubenville-rapists/"&gt;One CNN anchor&lt;/a&gt; today spoke about how the verdict possibly ruined the boys&amp;#39; lives, and how it was sad to see so much potential be waster. She didn&amp;#39;t mention what it must have been like for a 16-year-old girl to wake up with no recollection of the night before, and then realized that she&amp;#39;d been raped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the fact is, the verdict and the sentence didn&amp;#39;t ruin the boys&amp;#39; lives. First, they both had fairly lenient sentences, and are guaranteed to be out of custody before their 21st birthday. Second, if anything ruined their lives it was &lt;strong&gt;their own actions&lt;/strong&gt;. They made a choice to assault the victim. Their actions before and after the assault belong to them alone, and focusing on how the verdict ruined their promising lives subverts that fact. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea about the character of the boys in question, and neither do the anchors or journalists covering the trial. What we do know&amp;mdash;what has been proved in court beyond a reasonable doubt&amp;mdash;is that they raped a 16-year-old girl, and spread pictures of the assault. CNN and everyone else should be more concerned about the impact the assault, threats, and trial had on the victim than on the perpetrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/IGVQrCmn78I" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jamietie.com/media-mishandling-of-a-rape-verdict</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:EAKoester,2012:Post/stop-creepy-cofounder-dating-and-start-convincing-someone-you-are-awesome-enough-to-work-with</id>
    <published>2013-03-17T11:50:35-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T11:50:35-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/BprvwF0L40E/stop-creepy-cofounder-dating-and-start-convincing-someone-you-are-awesome-enough-to-work-with" />
    <author>
      <name>Eric Koester</name>
      <uri>http://ekoester.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Stop creepy cofounder 'dating' and start convincing someone you are awesome enough to work with</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a phone call a couple weeks back with someone who was looking for a cofounder (not an uncommon thing, right?)  I asked what he&amp;#39;s been doing to find a cofounder and his response nearly made me spit out my coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I posted a few ads on job sites,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; he said.  &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Then I&amp;#39;m interviewing the people who reply to see if they&amp;#39;d be a good cofounder.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What?  Are you serious?  Like seriously serious? WTF?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please Stop Being Creepy&lt;/strong&gt;
Listen, let me explain this to you quite simply:  you don&amp;#39;t hire a cofounder.  You convince someone awesome that you are worth working on something together.  Key word &amp;ldquo;convince.&amp;rdquo;  Not key words like &amp;ldquo;connive&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;surprise&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;manipulate&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;hire&amp;rdquo;.  None of those words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t go to the &amp;ldquo;cofounder store&amp;rdquo; and pick up a lovely Rubyist, with a side of adaptive design.  You don&amp;#39;t stand on the street corner on Wall Street and yell, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Anyone good with metrics, data and financial instruments?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s start here:  Don&amp;#39;t be creepy.  You know what creepy is&amp;hellip; it&amp;#39;s doing things like posting ads on job sites, then sneakily hope you can convince someone to be a cofounder when they apply for a non-existent job in your non-existent startup.  Turns out a relationship built on lies&amp;hellip; yeah, those usually don&amp;#39;t turn out well.  Rule #1: Stop being the skeezy, creepy dude at the bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that&amp;#39;s out of the way (which should be a basic test, but obviously it wasn&amp;#39;t), I want you to reimagine how you find a cofounder:  Pretend you are single and are hoping to find the love of your life.  Remember how that goes?  You meet lots of frogs to find a prince or princess charming.  You talk to friends, you may go on Match.com, you go out to bars or church.  You are looking for things in common.  You want to have great conversation, enjoy the same things, be on the same page with stuff, and generally dig each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t walk into a bar and yell, &amp;ldquo;Hey, who wants to get married.&amp;rdquo;  Well, unless you are super f-ing creepy, then maybe you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Convince Someone You Are Awesome&lt;/strong&gt;
Here&amp;#39;s three things to try to show someone you are worth working on something with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Work on a short-term, test project together.  Go to a Startup Weekend with someone, attend a Hackathon, or just work on something simple for a week (hell, try to build a desk together&amp;hellip; I don&amp;#39;t really care.)  Just actually try out working together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Attend a bunch of meetings together.  A good working dynamic is crucial &amp;ndash; and there is no better way to test that than to attend a meeting together with someone outside the &amp;ldquo;team.&amp;rdquo;  If you guys &amp;#39;crush it&amp;#39;, then that&amp;#39;s a good first step&amp;hellip; then do 10 more.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Collaborate on something for several weeks.  Co-write a series of blog posts, work on some code together, build a simple website or co-consult with a prospect.  You&amp;#39;ll learn a ton about how you communicate &amp;ndash; and treat both sides with the respect that you&amp;#39;d want to receive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, each of these activities above is a &amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo; with the goal of finding someone worth getting hitched to&amp;hellip; and it may take a lot of dates or maybe a few.  But remember how hard you worked to impress a gal or a guy when you were interested in them &amp;ndash; do the same with cofounder candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every meeting, every lunch, every conference is a place you might meet someone worth spending more time with&amp;hellip; and that time may eventually lead to a cofounder.  Remember, each meeting is a potential cofounder interview: they are interviewing you for your awesomeness quotient and you are doing the same.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, please please please stop asking me if you know of a cofounder you should meet.  A cofounder is NOT a mail order bride.  It&amp;#39;s work and you should plan to spend some time finding someone amazing.  If you rush it and try and force the issue, something will break&amp;hellip; probably one of you and ultimately the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this doesn&amp;#39;t seem to make sense, do me a favor and watch 40 Year Old Virgin.  Don&amp;#39;t be the guy in the first half of the movie please&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post script (from a Twitter discussion with my good friend Tony Wright):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1 in the &amp;ldquo;How to Convince Someone You are Awesome&amp;rdquo; is to actually BE demonstrably awesome&amp;hellip; that means you don&amp;#39;t just show off, talk a big game, highlight what was done in the past or point people to your amazing LinkedIn profile.  Like actually be awesome in context&amp;hellip; and show while working on something together to a potential cofounder.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/BprvwF0L40E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ekoester.com/stop-creepy-cofounder-dating-and-start-convincing-someone-you-are-awesome-enough-to-work-with</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/exclusive-soundsupply-receives-funding-from-lightbank</id>
    <published>2013-03-17T07:47:14-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T07:47:14-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/5Q_JWaWDFOE/exclusive-soundsupply-receives-funding-from-lightbank" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Exclusive: Soundsupp.ly Receives Funding From Lightbank</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://soundsupp.ly"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soundsupply&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a new company, formed in early 2012, that takes the &amp;#39;deal site&amp;#39; approach to selling music. Called &amp;ldquo;Drops,&amp;rdquo; Soundsupply creates bundles of 10 digital albums, charges $15 for them, and gives people a 10 day window to purchase the deal. The company has just taken on seed funding from Lightbank, the same people responsible for Groupon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The currently undisclosed amount of funding received will give Tim and Eric Mortensen, the two founding brothers, the opportunity to make Soundsupply their full time responsibility, trying to grow the originally bootstrapped company into an influential music destination. Though the retail experience may be the obvious angle for Soundsupply, music discovery is also at the forefront of focus and one the founders are passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company has already created 6 Drops, with the 7th being released March 18th. No bands have been announced for Drop 7 yet, but I&amp;#39;ve heard it is set to include Cursive&amp;#39;s newest album, &amp;#39;I Am Gemini&amp;#39;. One of the highlights that makes the service attractive to bands is the ability to actually make some money and gain exposure, all within a 10 day window. Past Drops have proven finically rewarding to the point of at least a few artists receiving a 90x return over their Spotify royalties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of bundling digital music is a simple and brilliant one that begs other bigger players in music retail to clone the experience. As a first mover, Soundsupply really needs to capitalize on mind and market share, giving users little doubt they are the pioneers and can grab the big names and best music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new influx of cash, you&amp;#39;ll begin to see things like an improved site design, making navigation easier, along with improvements to the download service and other small refinements. Long term, the guys behind Soundsupply are still open to exploring different aspects of the changing music industry. While bundling music may be the start, they aren&amp;#39;t opposed to tweaking the formula and thinking big picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hypebot.com/hypebot/2012/06/sound-supply-co-founder-talks-sound-drop-3-and-more.html"&gt;Here&amp;#39;s my June 2012 Hypebot interview with Co-Founder Tim Mortensen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/5Q_JWaWDFOE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/exclusive-soundsupply-receives-funding-from-lightbank</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tedgonder,2012:Post/books-that-have-changed-my-life</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T23:59:46-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T23:59:46-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/FOEwyBaMXEA/books-that-have-changed-my-life" />
    <author>
      <name>Ted Gonder</name>
      <uri>http://blog.tedgonder.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Books that Have Changed My Life</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Charlie Jones said &amp;ldquo;The only difference between where you are today, and where you&amp;#39;ll be a year from today, are the books you read and the people you meet.&amp;rdquo; Since I started reading voluntarily at the age of 14, books have had a huge influence on my life. Most of the books below are ones I&amp;#39;ve read multiple times, dog-eared dozens of pages in, and given as gifts. They and their authors have shaped who I&amp;#39;ve become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time Management, Career, Behavior, and Health&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mastery-Robert-Greene/dp/0670024961"&gt;Mastery&lt;/a&gt;, by Robert Greene&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Start-up-You-Yourself-Transform/dp/0307888908/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363502986&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=startup+of+you"&gt;The Startup of You&lt;/a&gt;, by Reid Hoffman and Ben Casnocha&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/4-Hour-Workweek-Anywhere-Expanded-Updated/dp/0307465357/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503001&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=4+hour+workweek"&gt;The 4-Hour Workweek&lt;/a&gt;, by Tim Ferriss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss?url=search-alias%3Dstripbooks&amp;amp;field-keywords=4+hour+body"&gt;The 4-Hour Body&lt;/a&gt;, by Tim Ferriss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Power-Full-Engagement-Managing-Performance/dp/0743226755/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503023&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=power+of+full+engagement"&gt;The Power of Full Engagement&lt;/a&gt;, by Tony Schwartz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philosophy, Pyschology, and Worldview&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Meditations-Marcus-Aurelius/dp/1613823037/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503058&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=meditations+marcus+aurelius"&gt;Meditations&lt;/a&gt;, by Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Letters-Penguin-Classics-Lucius-Annaeus/dp/0140442103"&gt;Letters from a Stoic&lt;/a&gt;, by Seneca&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Tao-Te-Ching-Lao-Tzu/dp/1613822421/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503081&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=tao+te+ching"&gt;Tao te Ching&lt;/a&gt;, by Lao Tzu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/As-Man-Thinketh-James-Allen/dp/1482325632/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503096&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=as+a+man+thinketh"&gt;As a Man Thinketh&lt;/a&gt;, by James Allen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mans-Search-Meaning-Viktor-Frankl/dp/0807014273/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503114&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=man%27s+search+for+meaning"&gt;Man’s Search for Meaning&lt;/a&gt;, by Viktor Frankl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Secret-Psychology-How-Fall-Love/dp/0452288185/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503129&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=how+we+fall+in+love"&gt;How We Fall in Love&lt;/a&gt;, by Paul Dobransky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/50th-Law-Robert-Greene-Cent/dp/B0072B5MJE/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503147&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=the+50th+law"&gt;The 50th Law&lt;/a&gt;, by Robert Greene and 50 Cent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Books that Have Inspired Me to Lead and Serve&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Rules-Radicals-Saul-Alinsky/dp/0679721134/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503217&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=rules+for+radicals"&gt;Rules for Radicals&lt;/a&gt;, by Saul Alinsky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mountains-Beyond-Farmer-Random-Readers/dp/0812980557/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503229&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=mountains+beyond+mountains"&gt;Mountains Beyond Mountains&lt;/a&gt;, by Tracy Kidder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Acts-Faith-American-Struggle-Generation/dp/080700622X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503240&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=acts+of+faith"&gt;Acts of Faith&lt;/a&gt;, by Eboo Patel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Fountainhead-Ayn-Rand/dp/0452273331/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503257&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=the+fountainhead"&gt;The Fountainhead&lt;/a&gt;, by Ayn Rand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/One-Day-All-Children-Unlikely/dp/1586481797/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503273&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=one+day+all+children"&gt;One Day All Children&lt;/a&gt;, by Wendy Kopp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Our-America-Death-South-Chicago/dp/0684870444/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503289&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=our+american+life+and+death+on+the+southside+of+chicago"&gt;Our America: Life &amp;amp; Death on the South Side of Chicago&lt;/a&gt;, by LeAlan Jones &amp;amp; Lloyd Newman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Gang-Leader-Day-Sociologist-Streets/dp/014311493X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503312&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=gang+leader+for+a+day"&gt;Gang Leader for a Day: A Rogue Sociologist Takes to the Streets&lt;/a&gt;, by Sudhir Venkatesh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Monster-Autobiography-L-Member/dp/0802141447/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503328&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=monster+gang+l.a."&gt;Monster: The Autobiography of an L.A. Gang Member&lt;/a&gt;, by Sanyika Shakur&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Autobiography-Malcolm-X/dp/0345902335/ref=sr_1_2?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503350&amp;amp;sr=1-2&amp;amp;keywords=autobiography+of+malcolm+x"&gt;The Autobiography of Malcolm X&lt;/a&gt;, by Malcolm X&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Leadership-Dojo-Foundation-Exemplary-Leader/dp/1583942017/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503372&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=leadership+dojo"&gt;The Leadership Dojo: Build Your Foundation as an Exemplary Leader&lt;/a&gt;, by Richard Strozzi-Heckler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Search-Warrior-Spirit-Fourth-Disciplines/dp/1583942025/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503389&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=in+search+of+the+warrior+spirit"&gt;In Search of the Warrior Spirit: Teaching Awareness Disciplines to the Green Berets&lt;/a&gt;, by Richard Strozzi-Heckler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Warriors-Path-Second-Philosophy-Mythology/dp/158394219X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503401&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=on+the+warriors+path"&gt;On the Warrior’s Path&lt;/a&gt;, by Daniele Bolelli&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Heart-Fist-Education-Humanitarian-Making/dp/B0098RLDT8/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503415&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=heart+and+the+fist"&gt;The Heart and the Fist: the Education of a Humanitarian, the Making of a Navy SEAL&lt;/a&gt;, by Eric Grietens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Power-Love-Theory-Practice-Social/dp/1605093041/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503429&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=power+and+love"&gt;Power and Love&lt;/a&gt;, by Adam Kahane&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Books that Just Plain Spoke to Me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Fight-Club-Novel-Chuck-Palahniuk/dp/0393327345/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503515&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=fight+club"&gt;Fight Club&lt;/a&gt;, by Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Lullaby-Chuck-Palahniuk/dp/0385722192/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503527&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=lullaby"&gt;Lullaby&lt;/a&gt;, by Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Million-Little-Pieces-James-Frey/dp/0307276902"&gt;A Million Little Pieces&lt;/a&gt;, by James Frey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Million-Miles-Thousand-Years-Learned/dp/1400202981/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363501407&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=a+million+miles+in+a+thousand+years"&gt;A Million Miles in a Thousand Years&lt;/a&gt;, by Donald Miller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/White-Fang-Dover-Thrift-Editions/dp/048626968X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503564&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=white+fang"&gt;White Fang&lt;/a&gt;, by Jack London&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Call-Wild-Jack-London/dp/1613823495/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503580&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=call+of+the+wild"&gt;The Call of the Wild&lt;/a&gt;, by Jack London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/FOEwyBaMXEA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.tedgonder.com/books-that-have-changed-my-life</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tedgonder,2012:Post/quotes-that-have-changed-my-life</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T23:34:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T23:34:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/fXW3U2V4-ZM/quotes-that-have-changed-my-life" />
    <author>
      <name>Ted Gonder</name>
      <uri>http://blog.tedgonder.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Quotes that Have Changed My Life</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you follow me on Facebook, Twitter, or Linkedin, you know I&amp;#39;m always posting quotes. I&amp;#39;m a total quote junkie. It&amp;#39;s how I get through the day. Here are the ones I&amp;#39;ve printed out and taped to mirrors, written on my hands for inspiration on sad days, crammed into the front covers of Moleskines, and have memorized for opportune recitation. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you’re going through hell, keep going.” 
- Winston Churchill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It takes conviction and vulnerability to believe in something, and absolutely no balls to tear it down.&amp;rdquo; 
- Eileen Guo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is not the critic who counts: not the man who points out how the strong man stumbles or where the doer of deeds could have done better. The credit belongs to the man who is actually in the arena, whose face is marred by dust and sweat and blood, who strives valiantly, who errs and comes up short again and again, because there is no effort without error or shortcoming, but who knows the great enthusiasms, the great devotions, who spends himself for a worthy cause; who, at the best, knows, in the end, the triumph of high achievement, and who, at the worst, if he fails, at least he fails while daring greatly, so that his place shall never be with those cold and timid souls who knew neither victory nor defeat.&amp;rdquo;
- Theodore Roosevelt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The individual has always had to struggle to keep from being overwhelmed by the tribe. If you try it, you will be lonely often, and sometimes frightened. But no price is too high to pay for the privilege of owning yourself.” 
- Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All courses of action are risky, so prudence is not in avoiding danger (it&amp;#39;s possible), but calculating risk and acting decisively. Make mistakes of ambition and not mistakes of sloth. Develop the strength to do bold things, not the strength to suffer.&amp;rdquo; 
- Niccolo Machiavelli&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Commitment is what transforms a promise into reality. It is the words that speak boldly of your intentions. And the actions which speak louder than the words. It is making the time when there is none. Coming through time after time after time, year after year after year. Commitment is the stuff character is made of; the power to change the face of things. It is the daily triumph of integrity over skepticism.&amp;rdquo; 
- Abraham Lincoln&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My belief is in the blood and flesh as being wiser than the intellect. The body-unconscious is where life bubbles up in us. It is how we know that we are alive, alive to the depths of our soul and in touch somewhere with the vivid reaches of the cosmos.&amp;rdquo; 
- D. H. Lawrence”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To study the Way is to study the Self
To study the Self is to forget the Self
To Forget the Self is to be Awakened with All Things”
-Dogan, sixteenth-century Zen monk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Few are willing to brave the disapproval of their peers, the censure of their colleagues, the wrath of their society. Moral courage is a rarer commodity than bravery in battle or great intelligence. Yet it is the one essential, vital quality for those who seek to change a world that yields most painfully to change.” 
- Robert F. Kennedy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When you wake up in the morning, tell yourself: the people I deal with today will be meddling, ungrateful, arrogant, dishonest, jealous and surly. They are like this because they can&amp;#39;t tell good from evil. But I have seen the beauty of good, and the ugliness of evil, and have recognized that the wrongdoer has a nature related to my own - not of the same blood and birth, but the same mind, and possessing a share of the divine. And so none of them can hurt me. No one can implicate me in ugliness. Nor can I feel angry at my relative, or hate him. We were born to work together like feet, hands and eyes, like the two rows of teeth, upper and lower. To obstruct each other is unnatural. To feel anger at someone, to turn your back on him: these are unnatural.” 
- Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/fXW3U2V4-ZM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.tedgonder.com/quotes-that-have-changed-my-life</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:youssef,2012:Post/terrible-copywriting-on-applecom</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T21:49:53-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T21:49:53-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/PxHWHx-oiAQ/terrible-copywriting-on-applecom" />
    <author>
      <name>Youssef Sarhan</name>
      <uri>http://sefsar.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Terrible copywriting on Apple.com</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542929772910_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542929772910_raw.png" alt="Screen shot 2013-03-17 at 03.20.26.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple just updated their iPhone page with a &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/why-iphone/"&gt;Why iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; tab. Undoubtedly created to swoon any potential customers that may be debating between the recently announced Samsung Galaxy S4 and not-so-new iPhone 5. With examples, I plan to demonstrate where Apple could have improved their copywriting. Copywriting is an important but often neglected discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542931503052_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542931503052_raw.png" alt="opening_lead.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, beginning a sentence with &amp;ldquo;and&amp;rdquo; (a conjunction) is not recommended. This is because &amp;ldquo;and&amp;rdquo; is used to link or compare two points. Separating them with a period can create an awkward cadence. However, perhaps in this case the line-break forgives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue here is about sentiment, &amp;ldquo;and&amp;rdquo; coming after &amp;ldquo;There&amp;#39;s iPhone&amp;rdquo; is like some sort of vague comparison with their competitors. The next five sentences confirm this, first by opening with a question, then an uncertain answer, then another sentence beginning with a conjunction, then two more awkward redundant sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple should have stopped at the headline, because the rest is junk. There is no need for the extra sentences. The phones and apps are enough at this point. In fact, had they left out the extra sentences it would have taken on an entirely new and better meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have run with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s iPhone.&lt;br&gt;
Then there&amp;#39;s everything you can do with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if to suggest that just owning an iPhone is something special, this would have appropriately set the tone, and nicely segued the reader into more detailed information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542932091526_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542932091526_raw.png" alt="award.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up is some award that looks like a Jukebox that no one outside of the U.S. has ever heard of before. It&amp;#39;s great that people think Apple has a nice product, but I really don&amp;#39;t care what these guys think of it. J.D. Power and Associates means nothing to me. It occupies no point of reference in my mind, and thus means nothing to me. Apple should know their audience. If anything, this brings in to question what Apple values, or more importantly, what Apple thinks I value. So far, I&amp;#39;ve no inclination to buy an iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542932709430_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542932709430_raw.png" alt="battery.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is simple. Apple use the same word –Great– to describe a good thing and a bad thing. &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/9fgowvzfQ9U?t=3m18s"&gt;Great&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s not smart, it&amp;#39;s not witty, it&amp;#39;s bad, it&amp;#39;s muddled. It doesn&amp;#39;t leave the right impression. Be clear. That&amp;#39;s all you have to do, ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542933544828_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542933544828_raw.png" alt="power.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, using the same word to describe a good thing and a bad thing. There&amp;#39;s no need for it. Just be clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a bunch of other things, but it&amp;#39;s late and I&amp;#39;m tired. Whoever wrote this copy probably shouldn&amp;#39;t write copy for Apple anymore. Finally, notice how there are no black iPhones featured on the entire page, they are all White. I wonder if there&amp;#39;s a strategic reason for that, probably not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/PxHWHx-oiAQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sefsar.com/terrible-copywriting-on-applecom</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:dalton,2012:Post/sine-waves</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T15:25:52-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T15:25:52-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/u5VGLEJhUoM/sine-waves" />
    <author>
      <name>Dalton Caldwell</name>
      <uri>http://daltoncaldwell.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Sine waves</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One thing I have noticed studying web traffic logs is that daily human behavior at scale resembles a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sine_wave"&gt;sine wave&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/dalton_24542448166944_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_dalton_24542448166944_raw.png" alt="Wave.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, my mind&amp;#39;s eye has constructed an image of the daily ebb and flow of web traffic resembling the ebb and flow of ocean tides. I&amp;#39;ve learned that code tends to break at the &amp;ldquo;high tide&amp;rdquo;, and the best time to do site maintenance is at &amp;ldquo;low tide&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why does human behavior at scale look like a sine wave? It&amp;#39;s because of our daily cycles of waking and sleeping. In other words, we have a 24 hour cycle because of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Circadian_rhythm"&gt;circadian rhythms&lt;/a&gt;, which occur because of the cycles of darkness and light caused by planetary movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And why do we have a tidal system? It&amp;#39;s largely caused by the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tide"&gt;gravitational pull of the moon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It only recently occurred to me that the unconscious link I felt between tides and web traffic wasn&amp;#39;t a lazy &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Folk_science"&gt;cognitive crutch&lt;/a&gt;, rather, they are both causally related to planetary movement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, this minor insight was a helpful reminder: everything is connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/u5VGLEJhUoM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://daltoncaldwell.com/sine-waves</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:lautenbach,2012:Post/the-second-screen-obsession</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T08:30:22-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T08:30:22-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/mIfCDEzBoA0/the-second-screen-obsession" />
    <author>
      <name>Bradley Lautenbach</name>
      <uri>http://blog.bradleylautenbach.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The second screen obsession</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hollywood has grown fixated on the second screen. The &amp;ldquo;second screen&amp;rdquo; refers to the other thing we&amp;#39;re paying attention to while watching television or movies &amp;ndash; this could be a phone, tablet, or computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The industry fixates on the second screen because it feels threatened, and rightly so. In an era of alt-tab attention spans, fewer people are coming to long-form content by traditional means if they are coming at all. Between the actual dollars, and the perceived mental commitment, the cost of consuming content that is longer than your regular cat video on YouTube is not negligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, over the last 30+ years, as distribution channels have expanded (the movie multiplex, the 500+ cable television channels), quantity of content has increased while quality of content has decreased. Fortunately for Hollywood, this bad content didn&amp;#39;t have much to compete with in order to capture an audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the late 1990s, we saw wide-spread consumer adoption of the Internet. And the rise of file sharing. And the slow-and-then-fast disruption of the recorded music industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hollywood watched this happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came broadband. And suddenly it was easy to share and stream the larger video files that dialup couldn&amp;#39;t support. And Hollywood started to worry, mostly, and incorrectly, about piracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came Facebook. And suddenly there was a whole new type of content that was, in many cases, far more compelling than Hollywood&amp;#39;s. This content is always fresh, and, most importantly, it is free. This is social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the iPhone. And suddenly consumers could take this new stream of social content with them wherever they went - including the couch and the movie theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now we have arrived at the present model of consumer behavior where viewers are watching Hulu in one tab while they&amp;#39;re Facebooking in another, they&amp;#39;re playing Angry Birds on the couch while they&amp;#39;ve got ESPN on on the television, and they&amp;#39;re texting each other while they&amp;#39;re in the movie theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, bizarrely, Hollywood&amp;#39;s reaction to this is: LET US OWN THIS NEW SCREEN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus is born the &amp;ldquo;innovation group&amp;rdquo; at BigMediaCo. Thus do ex-producers decide to launch startups to &amp;ldquo;capture the second screen experience.&amp;rdquo; Thus does an entire industry begin to wonder if this Silicon Valley place might become &amp;ldquo;a thing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every few weeks, I get pitched a second screen opportunity, mostly by people who are content creators in Hollywood. Most of these businesses provide access to bonus content related to the first-screen experience, allow viewers to socialize with other people who are also consuming the first-screen experience, or, most commonly, create new revenue streams related to the first-screen experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;#39;s started to make me wonder&amp;hellip; are we stupid?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job of Hollywood is to create content (read: tell a story) that so delights an audience that the audience is willing to pay to consume this content. Why is Hollywood spending any time creating experiences to further distract the audience? Rather than fixate on the shiny new thing, shouldn&amp;#39;t Hollywood be doubling down on finding and telling incredible stories? Wouldn&amp;#39;t we put our second screens down in a heartbeat if we were actually being delighted by the content on the first screen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media has made it nearly impossible to recoup the investment in bad content. Mediocre opening weekends of a bad movie thanks to a big marketing spend are no longer possible. Twitter kills a bad movie after the first few screenings on Friday. But content is still king. And good content spreads itself. Social media has also spawned a whole new consumer behavior: Incredible television can now be discovered and binge-viewed season-by-season online. (see: Downton Abbey).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s pause. Let&amp;#39;s not take our eye off the ball. Let&amp;#39;s not pretend that the second screen is going to solve some underlying structural problems in the entertainment industry. Let&amp;#39;s instead be confident that we can tell wonderful stories, delight our audiences, and that in return our audiences will reward us with dollars and, more importantly, their undivided attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. .. .. ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are rare cases where the &amp;ldquo;second screen&amp;rdquo; becomes an innvoative part of telling the story, for one example, check out the movie, &lt;a href="http://www.fastcocreate.com/1682579/the-second-screen-comes-to-the-movies-with-app-enhanced-film-app"&gt;&amp;ldquo;App.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/mIfCDEzBoA0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.bradleylautenbach.com/the-second-screen-obsession</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/the-wrong-time-and-place-why-wii-was-nintendos-biggest-failure</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T08:22:08-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T08:22:08-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/yguc_smXiIA/the-wrong-time-and-place-why-wii-was-nintendos-biggest-failure" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The Wrong Time And Place: Why Wii Was Nintendo's Biggest Failure</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s curious the products that swing between highs and lows. Some have so much initial success that competitors race to rip it off. While other products are so disregarded at first, only to come back big later. It&amp;#39;s funny how timing can lead to disingenuous results, catapulting a company off course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Nintendo reporting such terrible sales of the Wii U in January and February, you can&amp;#39;t help but wonder if the Wii really scratched the average person&amp;#39;s itch for gaming or if it hit the market at just the right time. Nintendo stated early on that the Wii was a blue ocean move, meaning, with this product they were hanging a hard left and sailing to a place where motion control was king and there weren&amp;#39;t any sharks for miles. Everything about the Wii &amp;ndash; including its name &amp;ndash; was a bold move when the company first announced the console, and it paid off. You could barely get your hands on one for months and months after it was released, by all accounts the Wii was a blockbuster hit. At the time you&amp;#39;d be hard pressed to find someone calling it a failure, even looking back, few would use that word to describe the iconic white box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To continue the movie metaphors, of course Nintendo was going to follow up with a sequel rather than a completely new franchise, but they shouldn&amp;#39;t have. The company let past success dictate future moves rather than fully assessing the market they would be releasing a new product into. Obviously Nintendo saw tablets and similar devices coming or they would&amp;#39;t have put a massive one at the center of their gaming experience. The fault was that they desperately wanted to recreate the Wii&amp;#39;s success, rather than pull another blue ocean move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bolder move than the Wii U would have been to completely flip the tables and infiltrate the cellphone gaming market. Partnering with Apple or Samsung, or both, they could have had the upper hand to dictate lucrative terms and potentially get their franchise games onto every handset being sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who says that once you&amp;#39;re a hardware company you have to always stay a hardware company? Who says that you can&amp;#39;t switch back and forth over time as the circumstances arise. It&amp;#39;s still early for Mircosoft as a computer manufacture, but they needed to &amp;ldquo;grease&amp;rdquo; the windows tablet market and so they&amp;#39;re building the Surface. Barnes and Noble needed a compelling way to transition into the digital age and the Nook was born. Microsoft won&amp;#39;t necessarily always be a computer hardware company from here on out. If OEMs can build compelling devices and push the sales of Microsoft&amp;#39;s software, I have no doubt they&amp;#39;ll exit that hardware business. The better follow up to the Wii would have been if Nintendo transitioned itself into more of a software company willing to become ubiquitous on different platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;#39;s the desire for official Nintendo games to come to iOS and Android that&amp;#39;s coloring my opinions, but it seems like the writing is on the wall for some form of mobile gaming to eventually and completely push consoles to the side. At that time, software will be all Nintendo has left to cling to and they&amp;#39;ll be forced to make choices that aren&amp;#39;t their own, on terms that aren&amp;#39;t as favorable as once could have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake, the Wii was a big deal, so big in fact that it likely clouded Nintendo&amp;#39;s judgement on their future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/yguc_smXiIA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/the-wrong-time-and-place-why-wii-was-nintendos-biggest-failure</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:sash,2012:Post/what-its-like-to-die</id>
    <published>2013-03-15T10:27:54-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T10:27:54-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/KYMxPDgEGiM/what-its-like-to-die" />
    <author>
      <name>Sash MacKinnon</name>
      <uri>http://sashmackinnon.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>What it's like to die</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Six months ago, I died. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no recollection of the event, but I&amp;#39;ve heard the story retold so many times that I may as well have seen it all. I was at the gym in my apartment complex with my roommate, Sam. I was running on the treadmill when I turned and told him I was going to faint. I collapsed and fell onto the still-moving belt, which tore the skin off my knee and pushed me onto the floor. Sam was shocked. He called for help. A personal trainer and her client ran over, called an ambulance, and assisted Sam in giving me CPR while my body slowly drained of color. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My heart had gone into ventricular fibrillation. &amp;ldquo;Vfib&amp;rdquo;, as I heard numerous doctors call it, is an type of arrhythmia&amp;ndash;a series of irregular electrical signals in the ventricle chamber of the heart. Instead of beating normally, the walls quiver erratically, like they&amp;#39;re having a seizure . The heart quickly becomes unable to pump blood to other organs. I had suffered from what is officially, and somewhat morbidly, termed &amp;ldquo;Sudden Cardiac Death&amp;rdquo;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paramedics arrived and walked slowly down the length of the pool to the gym. This was procedure, they later told me; they didn&amp;#39;t want to run and cause alarm. When they reached me, they defibrillated my heart  by strapping patches to my abdomen and running a strong electrical current through my body. I was told that after the first administration my heart had remained in arrhythmia. After the second, it started beating regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those 4 minutes and 30 seconds, I was clinically dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next two days in a coma while the doctors cooled by body to 32 degrees in order to avoid brain damage. During this time I developed a pulmonary embolism and pneumonia. Whenever I visit a doctor now they are always surprised&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;each of those alone could have killed you, it&amp;#39;s a miracle you survived all three!&amp;rdquo; I survived by sitting through hours of MRIs with oxygen in my nose, three IV&amp;#39;s in my arm and ten pills a day for weeks. Sam and my two mothers, Laurie and Kerrie, rarely left my side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stories you hear about people dying usually end with tunnels, lights, flashbacks, God, and big epiphanies. That isn&amp;#39;t what happened to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finally regaining enough consciousness to understand my situation, I sat for hours staring at the hospital walls. I didn&amp;#39;t have any life changing realizations. I wasn&amp;#39;t regretful. In fact, I couldn&amp;#39;t think of anything in my life I wanted to change at all. Being trapped alone in that sterile room with wires hanging off my chest only made me think about everything in my life I wanted back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people I tell this story to think I&amp;#39;m unlucky because I had a cardiac arrest at 21 years old. But I don&amp;#39;t think so. Only five percent of people who suffer ventricular fibrillation out of the hospital survive. Of those that do survive, more than half of them have brain damage. That means only two and a half percent fully recover. Not only did I fully recover, but I did so in the company of the people closest to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is one lesson I took away from the experience, it is not to &amp;ldquo;live life to the fullest&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;have no regrets&amp;rdquo;. It is to feel lucky. Feeling lucky means you are appreciating the things in your life that sometimes go unnoticed. It means you are achieving more than think you deserve. Feeling lucky requires a certain humility we often lose sight of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it took losing everything to remember how lucky I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/KYMxPDgEGiM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sashmackinnon.com/what-its-like-to-die</feedburner:origLink></entry>
</feed>
