<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xml:lang="en-US">
  <id>tag:svbtle.com,2012:/feed</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://svbtle.com" />
  
  <title>Svbtle Featured</title>
  <updated>2013-03-22T20:37:48-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Svbtle.com</name>
    <uri>http://svbtle.com</uri>
    <email>hello@svbtle.com</email>
  </author>
  <generator>Svbtle.com</generator>
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/svbtle" /><feedburner:info uri="svbtle" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>svbtle</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><entry>
    <id>tag:falon,2012:Post/its-a-power-struggle</id>
    <published>2013-03-22T20:37:48-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T20:37:48-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/zyeCXERDvfw/its-a-power-struggle" />
    <author>
      <name>Falon Fatemi</name>
      <uri>http://falonfatemi.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>It's a power struggle.</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m sure many of you have heard about the Python dev conference tweeting fiasco. In case you haven&amp;#39;t, what happened was that a few developers were inappropriately joking about dongles and made a woman sitting in the row in front of them uncomfortable. She decided to snap a photo of them and tweet about their indiscretion to her 10k+ followers on Twitter. This led to all parties being fired, including the female involved. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most women working in Silicon Valley, this is nothing new. Men can sometimes be inappropriate, and some may even call it a bit of a &amp;#39;nerd fraternity&amp;#39; or boys club. I&amp;#39;ll admit, it&amp;#39;s hard to get use to even if you&amp;#39;ve been working in the valley your whole life like me. But in order to be a successful woman in the tech community you have to learn how to handle these uncomfortable scenarios professionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hypothesis is that this woman felt powerless in the situation given that she was predominately surrounded by men (let&amp;#39;s face it, it&amp;#39;s a PYTHON conference). Overhearing a group of men behind her make inappropriate sexual jokes pushed her over the edge. There aren&amp;#39;t many women (myself included) that would feel comfortable in that situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for the woman in question,  she ended up going overboard by  ultimately robbing these men of their power. Instead of tweeting their photo to twitter,  it might have been better to be direct and tell them to shut up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The #1 lesson for women to take away from this unfortunate scenario is to be direct. When we feel uncomfortable because someone is saying something insulting, we simply say so in a polite, professional manner. By doing so, we create clear boundaries for what is appropriate and what isn&amp;#39;t. These situations are opportunities for educating others on becoming more self aware in social situations. It&amp;#39;s in the best interest of everyone involved and it&amp;#39;s our job as women to drive this change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The #1 outcome that I hope will come from this is an improvement in hiring strategy and employee training. Companies need to understand that their brand as a whole is defined by the reputation of their employees. There is a strong need to teach proper social skills and social awareness so we can create a more cohesive culture where men and women feel comfortable working together. While many men in Silicon Valley are extremely talented and have a high IQ, we&amp;#39;re seeing the increasing importance and value of a high emotional intelligence or EQ. If companies start to focus on EQ, I think we&amp;#39;ll see more inviting culture and ultimately be successful at building more successful products. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use to do a lot of social advising for YCombinator founders and other engineers and I&amp;#39;m more than happy to do my part and help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/zyeCXERDvfw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://falonfatemi.com/its-a-power-struggle</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jbrandonbb,2012:Post/the-world-of-handson-journalism-or-how-you-can-save-fido-from-a-certain-death</id>
    <published>2013-03-22T14:50:26-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T14:50:26-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/iABDAPvCKN0/the-world-of-handson-journalism-or-how-you-can-save-fido-from-a-certain-death" />
    <author>
      <name>John Brandon</name>
      <uri>http://byjohnbrandon.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The World of Hands-On Journalism, or How You Can Save Fido from Certain Death</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;#39;ve already been featured in top media outlets.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the famous last words I received in an e-mail today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some ways, it&amp;#39;s like telling a police officer you&amp;#39;ve already received enough speeding tickets. Or, explaining to your doctor you&amp;#39;ve already performed surgery on yourself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, it&amp;#39;s not the most effective way to deal with the media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a short phrase we like to use which is sort of a secret handshake in the field of journalism: the hands-on test. I might say hands-on when I need to see the thing in person. You make a widget, and I need to see if the widget does what it&amp;#39;s supposed to do. There&amp;#39;s a check and balance at play here. (Eventually, there&amp;#39;s also a check.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As journalists, we&amp;#39;re often paid to find out, on behalf of a customer, if something really works. We&amp;#39;re sort of a silent oracle, the space between two realities. (Some of us take up a bigger space than others.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you&amp;#39;ve invented a dog collar that connects to a transmitter in your kitchen. You say little Fido won&amp;#39;t run beyond a certain distance. I want to believe you, I really do. Something deep inside of me yearns to trust complete strangers by e-mail. And, I&amp;#39;m not so attached to my FedEx driver that I need to see her everyday, unless the delivery involves chocolate or coffee. In a few cases, a box cutter has turned on me, which is one of the few work injuries in my field that makes me nervous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, in almost every instance, we have to see the thing. We have to flip open the cover and look inside. We have to see the innards. Once we strap on the collar to little Fido and send him on his merry way and see that he will not be run over by a train or a food cart because of your app, we will be more than happy to write some glowing and solicitous prose about it. We&amp;#39;ll be earnest. But looking at a picture and some text on the Web does not help. Fido deserves a lot better than that, doesn&amp;#39;t he?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 12 years as a writer, I&amp;#39;ve seen quite a few interesting reactions to my product requests. Of course, it all starts with the Apple response: no. Then there&amp;#39;s the Microsoft response, which adds some flair: unfortunately, no. Or, there&amp;#39;s the response I half expect these days: the product is not available for testing yet. And, I get that. These things take time. Greatness is not easy. Still, I get a little confused (and constipated!) when I find out 400 other journalists have posted reviews about the product already. But maybe they are in a different epoch of time? Maybe there&amp;#39;s an alternate universe where the product is in wonderful abundance?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of these requests, we&amp;#39;re just doing our job. We&amp;#39;re being oracles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll tell you one of my favorite stories, which is almost completely true. There was a mystery tablet from a major tech company once. (I won&amp;#39;t give you any specifics about it other than to say the letters of this company start with H and P.) Things were pretty hush-hush, what with those folks at Gizmodo on the hunt for unreleased stuff. There were coded messages, whispers in dark alleys. Finally, someone admitted there was going to be a tablet, and it was going to be kind of similar to the Palm OS phone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used every tactic in the book: I will sign an NDA, I promise not to tell Gizmodo, I will sign in blood and offer my life in servitude if I break my silence. None of that worked, although I think the representative from this super-secret company was intrigued by the servitude bit. Eventually, the answer was no and it was always going to be no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then my editor got involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within a few minutes, another e-mail arrived. &amp;ldquo;Why, we found one right under the desk here!&amp;rdquo; Apparently, everyone in the office of this mysterious company (codenamed H and P, shhh) was pleasantly surprised when they found it hiding under that desk. They all smiled and laughed. &amp;ldquo;We will get this packaged up for ya right away and ship that off pronto!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all honesty, I felt a little conned, specifically by the &amp;ldquo;hey we found one right here under the desk&amp;rdquo; trick. Part of me knows they were probably in short supply. But, part of me also thinks there are those who work in shipping departments who are standing right in front of 14 product boxes typing a message on an iPad that says they don&amp;#39;t have any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this all leads me to the most flummoxing response of all: we already have enough coverage. Isn&amp;#39;t that like saying we already have enough money? Or we already have enough precious jewels? Or we already have enough gold bars? Or maybe &amp;ndash; we already have enough endorsements by famous supermodels? Oh, we would be interested in that coverage but we already have like a billion dollars because of the Gizmodo write-up. We can&amp;#39;t take any more money because our bank is not big enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m probably missing something here. I know that selling too many products can be a problem. Which, thankfully, is one of the few things that BlackBerry doesn&amp;#39;t have to worry about. But isn&amp;#39;t all press coverage good press coverage? Putting this stuff into the hands of a journalist is a good thing, depending on the cleanliness of the journalist? I&amp;#39;m not saying just mail stuff out willy-nilly to anyone who has a WordPress account. That would not be wise, and would also involve the phrase willy-nilly (lame!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is never really enough major media coverage. There&amp;#39;s Apple and there is everyone else. (Lately, even Apple has been happy for the coverage.) At the end of the day, this is just a happy exchange of goods and services. Some guy in Minnesota tests your stuff. It&amp;#39;s not that complicated. The customer is the ultimate winner. And, poor little Fido.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/iABDAPvCKN0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://byjohnbrandon.com/the-world-of-handson-journalism-or-how-you-can-save-fido-from-a-certain-death</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/productivity-for-normal-people</id>
    <published>2013-03-22T08:28:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T08:28:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/ehFaV81qKmM/productivity-for-normal-people" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Mobile Productivity for Normal People</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24551355774384_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24551355774384_raw.jpg" alt="google-now-landing_616.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few weeks, there has been a new refrain among consumer mobile startups that I&amp;#39;ve met with: we&amp;#39;re designing for normal people or &lt;a href="http://cdixon.org/2010/01/22/techies-and-normals/"&gt;normals as Chris Dixon would put it&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons for this trend. First, there is a movement towards great design. Second, there is a wave to reinvent and reimagine core applications of the mobile phones. The apps shipped with the standard OS were ports of their desktop counterparts. Only now, after using these cloned applications for a while, do we understand how email, phone, calendar, etc should evolve. Third, &lt;a href="http://tomtunguz.com/machine-learning-in-consumer-products"&gt;machine learning technologies make magical experiences possible like priority inbox or Google Now.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, developing a product for a different segment demands a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, alternate customer acquisition techniques are required. Unlike productivity nuts whose unrelenting persistence of even minor time savings drives product experimentation and usage, normals discover products by chance or through word of mouth. Large scale distribution deals like carrier bundling, embedding in the operating system and mass media channels seem to me to be much more effective for reaching this audience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the value proposition must be clear, simple and immediate. Normals have far less patience. In other words, this user segment demands better designed applications. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last, the user feedback from productivity nuts and normals will vary dramatically. The first will demand ever more sophisticated features and integrations while the second will oppose functionality in pursuit of simplicity. Picking anything in between will develop a product that fails to meet either need well. Product must clearly prioritize one&amp;#39;s segments needs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opportunity for startups targeting normals is massive. But approaching the market requires a new mindset, different product prioritization and alternate marketing tactics. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In what other ways must startups serving normals evolve? &lt;a href="http://branch.com/b/mobile-productivity-for-normal-people/invite_link/DUK9SOfmKbMhSA"&gt;Join us on this Branch.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/ehFaV81qKmM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/productivity-for-normal-people</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/10th-anniversary-of-copelands-beneath-medicine-tree</id>
    <published>2013-03-22T07:39:52-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T07:39:52-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/GAT-CkbAH3g/10th-anniversary-of-copelands-beneath-medicine-tree" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>10th Anniversary of Copeland's 'Beneath Medicine Tree'</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tylerhayes_24529652319834_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tylerhayes_24529652319834_raw.jpg" alt="copelandbmtuq9.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people&amp;#39;s first taste of Copeland came with &amp;#39;Beneath Medicine Tree&amp;#39;s single, &amp;ldquo;Downtown.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;#39;s a song about young love with a punchy chorus that can be hard to forget. A perfect choice of song to introduce the band in 2003 when it was still a time of loud and fast guitars, pounding drums, generally ruled by pop/punk. &amp;#39;Beneath Medicine Tree&amp;#39; was different, opening with the soft and delicate song, &amp;ldquo;Brightest.&amp;rdquo; For a lot of kids, this was something they hadn&amp;#39;t really been exposed to before, unsure if they loved or hated it. It&amp;#39;s possible the album came out just as musical tides were shifting, or maybe it was &amp;#39;Beneath Medicine Tree&amp;#39; that &amp;ndash; even slightly &amp;ndash; caused a shift in musical influence for a generation of then high school and college kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a raw and innocent aspect to the songs on &amp;#39;Beneath Medicine Tree&amp;#39; that only a debut album can produce. Jimmy Eat World&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;Clarity&amp;#39; is another album with a similar spark and likeness that just drips magic. The impact of &amp;#39;Beneath Medicine Tree&amp;#39; is hard to explain, but it sweeps you up and even though it&amp;#39;s not perfect, there aren&amp;#39;t any faults to be found. Lead singer, Aaron Marsh mentioned that Beneath Medicine Tree was an album he wanted to move people, 10 years later it still can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obvious from the album&amp;#39;s title, there&amp;#39;s an inherent sadness present throughout the songs, though nothing quite like &amp;#39;Eat, Sleep, Repeat&amp;#39; which is the band&amp;#39;s 3rd release. &amp;#39;Beneath Medicine Tree&amp;#39; was not a depressing sadness, but one of mourning wrapped in hope, surrounded by songs of optimism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Goldman, the record&amp;#39;s engineer, mentioned that &amp;ldquo;Love Is A Fast Song&amp;rdquo;, which appears on Copeland&amp;#39;s second album, &amp;#39;In Motion&amp;#39;, was originally the title track song for &amp;#39;Beneath Medicine Tree&amp;#39;. Scraped at the time because the song just wasn&amp;#39;t strong enough and ready, it became one of the stand out songs on their sophomore release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of Copeland, as the band was taking their final lap around the country, you could tell from the farewell tour that they were burnt out. Even though the band&amp;#39;s final album, &amp;#39;You Are My Sunshine&amp;#39;, was a refreshing release, it still didn&amp;#39;t have the enthusiasm and emotional spark that &amp;#39;Beneath Medicine Tree&amp;#39; did. The type of spark that usually only comes around once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the jazzy beat of &amp;ldquo;Coffee,&amp;rdquo; to the hypnotic ending of &amp;ldquo;When Finally Set Free&amp;rdquo; or the slow burn of &amp;ldquo;California,&amp;rdquo; the album truly is a classic.  And 10 years later it&amp;#39;s as strong as it was the day it came out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://open.spotify.com/artist/31HpswGOiF0Mc2wm11sIoN"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copeland Discography on Spotify&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rdio.com/artist/Copeland/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copeland Discography on Rdio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/artist/copeland/id16868"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copeland on iTunes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/GAT-CkbAH3g" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/10th-anniversary-of-copelands-beneath-medicine-tree</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:adii,2012:Post/hiring-goes-both-ways</id>
    <published>2013-03-21T23:58:14-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T23:58:14-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/ssKHWjr-OjU/hiring-goes-both-ways" />
    <author>
      <name>Adii Pienaar</name>
      <uri>http://adii.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Hiring Goes Both Ways</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I&amp;#39;ve been involved in hiring 30+ team members to WooThemes, of which 24 remains on the team today. If I had to distill all of that experience into one piece advice it would be this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When hiring someone that you really want to join your team, it&amp;#39;s critical that the individual wants to join the team as badly as you want them to join.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife always tells me that her dad used to &lt;em&gt;warn&lt;/em&gt; her about potential boyfriends when she was younger. He would always say: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Never chase after a boy or a bus.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This resonates with my experiences of growing our team; when I&amp;#39;ve aggressively chased a hire and compromised on what exactly I wanted (i.e. salary, exact job description, benefits, etc.), it generally meant that our relationship started on the wrong foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead we&amp;#39;ve had most success hiring the individuals that would do everything in their power to be part of our team. On paper, these individuals probably won&amp;#39;t be considered the best candidate, but in practice - due to their passion for our company, our team and our customers - they&amp;#39;ve exceeded all of our expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This also reminds me of how important hiring according to company culture is. I love &lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/HubSpot/the-hubspot-culture-code-creating-a-company-we-love"&gt;Dharmesh Shah&amp;#39;s words&lt;/a&gt; in this regards: &amp;ldquo;Culture is to recruiting what marketing is to product.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/ssKHWjr-OjU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://adii.me/hiring-goes-both-ways</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jamietie,2012:Post/cnn-says-it-doesnt-support-rapists-evidence-says-otherwise</id>
    <published>2013-03-21T20:15:39-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T20:15:39-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/vr2_zj6xIlk/cnn-says-it-doesnt-support-rapists-evidence-says-otherwise" />
    <author>
      <name>Jamie Kelly</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jamietie.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>CNN says it doesn't support rapists, evidence says otherwise</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apparently CNN is &lt;a href="http://www.thewrap.com/media/column-post/cnn-soft-rapists-steubenville-coverage-sparks-debate-81861?page=0,0"&gt;denying any slant toward the rapists&lt;/a&gt; in its coverage of the Steubenville, Ohio rape trial, and the reporter involved is offended anyone would think she supports rapists. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fair enough&amp;mdash;I seriously doubt she does support rapists, and I doubt that she thinks rape is a good thing. But it doesn&amp;#39;t change the fact that within a minute of appearing on camera, she talks about how emotional it was to watch two boys believe they were watching their lives crumble before their eyes. Let&amp;#39;s go to the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;amp;v=MvUdyNko8LQ#t=76s"&gt;video tape&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/MvUdyNko8LQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;(Start at 1:15)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m sure it was a very emotional moment, and there is some journalistic value in describing the defendants&amp;#39; reactions. But, as I &lt;a href="http://blog.jamietie.com/media-rape-culture-victim-blaming-and-stuebenville"&gt;pointed out before&lt;/a&gt;, this crosses that line. It makes her appear to be much more concerned with the impact of a rape on the men who committed it than on the young woman who was raped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And indeed, she highlights the pat, almost rote apology from Trent Mays (who apologized for taking and sending nude pictures of the young woman, not for raping her). CNN also showed Ma&amp;#39;Lik Richardson breaking down in the courtroom. Perhaps he is truly sorry. But being sorry doesn&amp;#39;t change the fact that he raped someone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, by emphasizing that the parties where Mays and Richardson raped the young woman were fueled by alcohol, she brings in one of the oldest  ways to blame the victim&amp;mdash;if she hadn&amp;#39;t been drinking none of this would have happened. In fact, alcohol is used both to blame the victim &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; excuse the behavior of the rapists&amp;mdash;they were drunk, as well. It&amp;#39;s a pretty tidy example of the double standard: She&amp;#39;s less sympathetic because she was drunk, but the rapists are more sympathetic because they were out of control and did something they might not have done while sober. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it doesn&amp;#39;t wash. What happened was rape. Full stop. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CNN would be wise to actually read the &lt;a href="https://www.change.org/petitions/cnn-apologize-on-air-for-sympathizing-with-the-steubenville-rapists"&gt;Change.Org petition&lt;/a&gt;, understand what they did wrong, and work toward being more supportive of victims and less supportive of rapists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/vr2_zj6xIlk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jamietie.com/cnn-says-it-doesnt-support-rapists-evidence-says-otherwise</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:hardaway,2012:Post/what-jonah-peretti-taught-me-about-journalismmake-it-emotional-social-shareable</id>
    <published>2013-03-21T15:07:50-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T15:07:50-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/hIix47ELmJw/what-jonah-peretti-taught-me-about-journalismmake-it-emotional-social-shareable" />
    <author>
      <name>Francine Hardaway</name>
      <uri>http://francinesblog.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>What Jonah Peretti Taught Me About Journalism:
Make it Emotional, Social, Shareable</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the highlights of my trip to SXSW, the music, film and interactive festival in Austin that ended last week, was hearing Jonah Peretti, founder of Buzzfeed, speak  Buzzfeed,although still a startup, gets 40 million unique visitors a month, 40% per cent of whom read it on mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is Peretti, who also co-founded Huffington Post, a great journalist? Nope. He&amp;#39;s a guy who. while a grad student at MIT Media Lab, experimented with how to make things go viral. Read his Wikipedia page; it’s hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His key target audience? The &amp;ldquo;bored at work&amp;rdquo; network. The bored at work network is made up of people who have to spend all day at a desk on a computer, but who aren&amp;#39;t necessarily working all the time. These people use their mental breaks to shop online, and also to share content. If Buzzfeed puts out some content that interests them &amp;ndash; say, a cat photo or a diet that gets you into a bikini in 24 hours &amp;ndash; this network will share it because they can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the rise of the smart phone, a second, even larger network emerged:  the bored in line network. 
Mobile used to be where viral died, but now its where viral lives. Even reporters are part of the bored at work network, often scanning online for story ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From his youthful experiments, Peretti concluded that if you want something to be seen by a large audience, half the time should be spent on the idea, and the other half on how to spread it. If content is attractive to people on social networks, it can get as much as 34x the traffic as it gets on the original site. So Buzzfeed went to the market with social and shareable content, becoming quickly known for its quirky cat videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Howeve, that wasn’t Peretti’s total intent. He wanted to have a place for long form serious journalism that was equally sharable, so he hired Ben Smith, the highly respected reporter from Politico, to be his political editor. Smith broke the story of Romney’s running mate, and now Buzzfeed has lots of serious journalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of news is good for social sharing? Scoops are good (everyone wants to be the first to know). So is any story that’s a matrix of fact and emotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So good sites should be like a Paris cafe: philosophy and politics are vociferously discussed, but dogs are allowed, and discussions stop to pet the dog. That’s why you like your Facebook news feed; it’s a combination of inspirational quotations, family news, and fascinating photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only certain topics, however, lend themselves to sharing. To make you share something, you have to identify with it in some emotional way. Nostalgia is social. Breaking news about things like the Jody Arias trial or a tsunami are social. Humor is inherently social, as are cute animals. Buzzfeed did a promotional campaign with Toyotus Prius called “25 Hybrid Animals You will Love.” It got millions of shares and views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, people, is the future of journalism: emotional, sharable, and social. Get used to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/hIix47ELmJw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://francinesblog.com/what-jonah-peretti-taught-me-about-journalismmake-it-emotional-social-shareable</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/the-best-places-to-write-online</id>
    <published>2013-03-21T13:52:24-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T13:52:24-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/gq_m4TB4q-o/the-best-places-to-write-online" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Writing Online</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It now seems foreign to consider writing in a full fledged word processor, only to copy it over to a CMS, then publish it online. There was a time when writing your blog post in Wordpress or another online editor just wasn&amp;#39;t acceptable, but that&amp;#39;s no longer the case. If you&amp;#39;re writing for the web, there&amp;#39;s a good chance that you&amp;#39;re also writing on the web. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing online is currently a blossoming space. The seed was planted, it grew, and finally it&amp;#39;s beginning to show some beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a subtle, but important, uprising happening both in the way people write online and why people write online. Services are coming of age, questioning their roots and beginning to shed the past in favor of a new level of experience. Money and success are also no longer results, but prerequisites to typing this connected content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;#39;blog&amp;#39; was only the spark, the catalyst, that put a vision is the minds of those with creative tendencies, blogging was accessibility, not the revolution. The revolution hasn&amp;#39;t happened yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals are finally coming together to out publish traditional publishers. As evident by &lt;a href="https://medium.com"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://svbtle.com/magazine"&gt;Svbtle&lt;/a&gt;, and the iOS app &lt;a href="http://the-magazine.org"&gt;The Magazine&lt;/a&gt;. Simplicity, beauty, and beyond all, compelling content is starting to transition power from a few groomed individuals, to those with passion and endurance. Wordpress has users that are keeping their software in business, but they haven&amp;#39;t converted those users into paid contributors for a single source, aiming to produce high quality content coming at you from every angle that you can think. They should, or they&amp;#39;re going to get left behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music discovery &amp;ndash; I believe &amp;ndash; needs to be curated by both machines and humans and writing is the same way. The machines sort, organize, and manipulate the data, while humans provide the answer to &amp;ldquo;Is this good?&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A year from now the world of online publishing is going to look a lot different , and very few see it coming.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/gq_m4TB4q-o" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/the-best-places-to-write-online</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:nate,2012:Post/i-cant-sing</id>
    <published>2013-03-21T09:26:58-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T09:26:58-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/wMxOU5V2jM8/i-cant-sing" />
    <author>
      <name>Nathan Kontny</name>
      <uri>http://ninjasandrobots.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>I Can't Sing</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t code. I can&amp;#39;t design. I can&amp;#39;t dance. I can&amp;#39;t get in shape. I can&amp;#39;t draw. I can&amp;#39;t give speeches. I can&amp;#39;t write. I can&amp;#39;t invent. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was 15 I had a friend named Patrick. We met in driver&amp;#39;s ed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you looked at him, you&amp;#39;d probably expect to find him in a moshpit, or playing insanely loud punk music. You&amp;#39;d be right. But the guy had the voice of an angel and sang in his high school choir. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One night, Collin and I pick him up from choir practice. 
Collin was our 16 year old friend who we often made drive us around. Poor Collin :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were driving to who knows where (some cafe to play chess and drink coffee or to Taco Bell) a song came on the radio that I liked. And I sang it a little. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That weird looking, punk rock, 15 year old kid gave me some advice that has helped shape every single thing I&amp;#39;ve accomplished since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He warned me that, as I sang, I was trying to imitate the musician on the radio, and I wasn&amp;#39;t doing a very good job of it. My voice just couldn&amp;#39;t do what we were listening to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I should try to cover the same song but do it in a way that suited my voice. My voice isn&amp;#39;t very strong at those high notes. If I was going to imitate anyone, try to imitate someone&amp;#39;s voice that works at this low pitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried Patrick&amp;#39;s advice, and I sang the song at a considerably lower pitch that was comfortable to me. I remember it sounded now more like Johnny Cash. The result was surprising. It wasn&amp;#39;t half bad, and it was much better than me trying to sing like that guy on the radio. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve never felt like a &amp;ldquo;web designer&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;#39;ve been building websites for 15 years, and I&amp;#39;ve done what I&amp;#39;ve needed to do, but I could never get my stuff to look even close to those beautiful creations I admire. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get past that, I&amp;#39;d end up buying some template somone else made. Or finding really good business partners who could design all the things I couldn&amp;#39;t. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last 12 months, however, running my third software company, I found myself alone trying to create a new project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t have a partner, or a designer or anyone else to help me. And I didn&amp;#39;t have any money to buy the help. A template wasn&amp;#39;t going to cut it this time. I was in a bind. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t have a Dribbble account full of my work. I don&amp;#39;t have a portfolio. I don&amp;#39;t know what awards designers win. I hear there are awards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I had to figure out what I can design. I had to figure out a way to design that suits me.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I can&amp;#39;t do a lot with color, or illustrations, or shadows, or logos, I&amp;#39;d have to go with very little of those things. It would have to be the basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still looked at people doing amazing work online for inspiration. But instead of trying to step into the shoes of my preconceived notion of a designer, I started noticing elements of projects that I could actually do myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t create an identity or logo like Aaron Draplin, but I sure could use Futura Bold and add a little space between the letters like he seems to be doing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up with what you see at &lt;a href="http://draftin.com"&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt;, software I&amp;#39;ve made to help me &lt;a href="http://draftin.com"&gt;write better&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has no logo. It has zero images. There&amp;#39;s one color on the homepage. Blue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank god or luck or hard work or whatever, I have stumbled on a large number of people that appreciate and love the user experience and user interface I&amp;#39;ve created. I&amp;#39;ve worked my ass off to accomplish this project. But I didn&amp;#39;t expect this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there are blemishes that you might see (and even more that I do). Mountains and mountains of things I need to improve and polish. And I&amp;#39;ll never think it&amp;#39;s as good as anything from my heros who I immediately think of when someone says: designer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow, along the way of getting here, I have figured out a way to design. I found some way to sing this song but with a voice that suits me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might not be able to sing like your preconceived model of how a singer sings, but I&amp;#39;ll never understand when someone tells me, &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;#39;t sing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess you probably didn&amp;#39;t have a friend like Patrick. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S. &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/natekontny"&gt;It would be awesome to meet you on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/wMxOU5V2jM8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ninjasandrobots.com/i-cant-sing</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:mitchellh,2012:Post/abandoning-rubygems</id>
    <published>2013-03-21T09:23:33-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T09:23:33-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/0kuixLVJqQc/abandoning-rubygems" />
    <author>
      <name>Mitchell Hashimoto</name>
      <uri>http://mitchellh.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Abandoning RubyGems</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Vagrant 1.1+ no longer supports &lt;a href="http://rubygems.org/"&gt;RubyGems&lt;/a&gt; as an installation method. Instead, you must install Vagrant 1.1+ using &lt;a href="http://downloads.vagrantup.com"&gt;pre-made packages or installers&lt;/a&gt;. For folks used to the gem-based installation, this has caused a mixture of confusion and disdain. In this post, I enumerate my reasons for abandoning RubyGems, and why it is better for the Vagrant community long-term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I initially released Vagrant as a RubyGem over 3 years ago. Vagrant is written in Ruby, and at the time I was already comfortable with making RubyGems, so I decided it was a natural distribution mechanism. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t regret this decision for a moment. The Ruby community is very open to cutting edge technologies, and I think that distributing as a RubyGem improved my initial adoption of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, however, I&amp;#39;ve grown and learned that RubyGems is no longer the best choice, for many reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;#39;m going to explain why installers make life better for Vagrant users. In a future post, I&amp;#39;ll explain how installers affect plugin developers and that ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Non-Rubyists&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the initial release of Vagrant in 2010, Vagrant has grown to be used by hundreds of companies and thousands of people. While I don&amp;#39;t have hard numbers to back this up, a majority of the Vagrant users I meet are not Ruby developers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to making installers, the top complaint I would receive about Vagrant was about RubyGems. As a Ruby person myself, I always considered RubyGems to be simple. But for anyone outside the Ruby community, I learned that the burden of having to learn RubyGems, install Ruby, and so on was a high enough barrier to entry that many people didn&amp;#39;t even try to install Vagrant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, packages that bundle all of Vagrant&amp;#39;s dependencies (including Ruby), make installing Vagrant extremely simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Bugs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vagrant has a lot of external dependencies: Ruby, RubyGems, OpenSSL, zlib, JSON, and more. With the RubyGems approach, users were left to manually install these dependencies, either from source or their package manager of choice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given this flexibility, I was unable to test Vagrant in every conceivable environment. I knew Vagrant worked on my system with my installed versions of dependencies, but didn&amp;#39;t know if it would work in every system. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, it was common to receive bugs where Vagrant was used with dependencies that were too old, had bugs, or were simply broken due to permission errors and so on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t care whether this is perceived as my fault or the user&amp;#39;s fault. I don&amp;#39;t blame users for not installing proper versions, especially if they just installed what their package repository had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is a &lt;strong&gt;huge problem&lt;/strong&gt; when Vagrant crashes due to a broken environment, and then people perceive this as an instability in Vagrant itself, when 9 times out of 10, it was due to a misconfigured environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With installers, I am able to ship Vagrant with all the dependencies it needs, and promise the user that Vagrant will work with those dependencies. This is especially helpful in Windows environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Flexibility&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I strictly control the environment, I&amp;#39;m able to improve and fine tune the dependencies Vagrant relies on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Vagrant 1.1, I replaced the old, slow pure-Ruby &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tar_%28computing%29"&gt;tar&lt;/a&gt; library i was using with &lt;a href="http://www.libarchive.org/"&gt;libarchive&lt;/a&gt;, a high performance, stable, and flexible application and library written in C. libarchive is now shipped with every Vagrant installer, so users don&amp;#39;t have to install another dependency, and don&amp;#39;t really need to care Vagrant is using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Vagrant 1.2, I replaced the downloader from using pure-Ruby HTTP to using &lt;a href="http://curl.haxx.se/"&gt;cURL&lt;/a&gt;. This is much faster and supports many more network protocols, such as FTP. Every installer will ship with cURL pre-installed within it. Again, users don&amp;#39;t need to care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future, I&amp;#39;ll be replacing the pure-Ruby SSH library with a more stable, well maintained SSH library written in C. Once again, users don&amp;#39;t need to care, but they&amp;#39;ll notice that SSH becomes more stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of these changes, I&amp;#39;m able to make significant dependency changes without the user noticing. In fact, all the user notices is that the Vagrant experience just got a lot better. Things got faster, things don&amp;#39;t crash, and Vagrant supports more features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Vagrant got a lot better because I was able to make changes I couldn&amp;#39;t safely make by distributing via RubyGems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/0kuixLVJqQc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://mitchellh.com/abandoning-rubygems</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:daslee,2012:Post/cheap-data</id>
    <published>2013-03-21T09:05:15-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T09:05:15-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/SVQ4DGnk_T8/cheap-data" />
    <author>
      <name>David Lee</name>
      <uri>http://daslee.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Cheap Data</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I went to a tech talk last night called &lt;a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/5760309240"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Genomics at Web Scale.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="https://www.counsyl.com/"&gt;Counsyl&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;[SV Angel is an investor in Counsyl.]&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is above my pay grade to critique but here goes. There&amp;#39;s a strain of thought in computer science that &amp;ldquo;data beats algorithms.&amp;rdquo; That is, having more data is better than having a superior algorithm. For example, &lt;a href="http://allthingsd.com/20120907/more-data-beats-better-algorithms-or-does-it/?goback=%2Egde_35222_member_161040415"&gt;some contend&lt;/a&gt; that the winners of the &lt;a href="http://www.netflixprize.com/"&gt;Netflix Prize&lt;/a&gt; had a relatively simple algorithm but won because they had more data. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cs.stanford.edu/people/ihaque/"&gt;Imran Haque&lt;/a&gt;, Counsyl&amp;#39;s Director of Research, tweaked this claim. He said that cheap, abundant data &lt;em&gt;leads&lt;/em&gt; algorithms. And by doing that, they can lead to technological (mainly software) breakthroughs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mid 1990&amp;#39;s, cheap text created by the Web led to better machine learning, machine translation technologies, AI technologies, PageRank and other breakthroughs. In the mid 2000&amp;#39;s, cheap image data created by cell phones, digital cameras and the like helped actualize arithmetic coding, effective computer vision and quite possibly to break throughs like self-driving cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imran said that the next breakthrough is cheap molecular data. The cost of sequencing one human genome (i.e., 6 billion bits!) cost $9MM in 2007 and $7K in 2013. These costs are &lt;a href="http://www.technologyreview.com/graphiti/427720/bases-to-bytes/"&gt;falling almost 5x faster than Moore&amp;#39;s Law since 2007.&lt;/a&gt; Because of this and advances in other fields like robotics, Imran&amp;#39;s claim is that this will be the most interesting area of computer science for the next 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5416116"&gt;Would love any thoughts/comments here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/SVQ4DGnk_T8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://daslee.me/cheap-data</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:dkr,2012:Post/on-the-pycon-incident</id>
    <published>2013-03-21T08:40:53-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T08:40:53-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/cZuc0Y0Tyr4/on-the-pycon-incident" />
    <author>
      <name>D. Keith Robinson</name>
      <uri>http://howtomakelightning.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>On The Pycon Incident</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent some time digging into the whole Pycon Incident and found it really disturbing. I normally don&amp;#39;t talk about this kind of thing, but the way it went down really struck me. As well, I&amp;#39;m not sure I wouldn&amp;#39;t have seen as much of this, if not for some new friends and co-workers, and wanted to make sure people knew this stuff was happening in our industry. I know I&amp;#39;ve learned a lot, and much of it very disturbing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not going to recap the specifics. If you want those, you&amp;#39;ll need to search and keep digging. I&amp;#39;ll warn you, there is a lot of opinion and reaction you&amp;#39;ll need to sort through to understand what happened. I wish there was a good, unbiased wrap up to send you to, but I couldn&amp;#39;t find one. (Update: I found &lt;a href="http://www.dailydot.com/society/pycon-dongle-joke-misogyny-sexism-adria-richards/"&gt;a pretty good one here&lt;/a&gt;.) I will, however, give my take having figured out a lot of the specifics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short version: Adria Richards, a developer evangelist, was sitting in a Pycon session when she overheard two guys telling a dirty joke. She snapped a photo of it and posted it on Twitter, calling them out. There was a &lt;a href="http://pycon.blogspot.com/2013/03/pycon-response-to-inappropriate.html"&gt;fairly calm, smart and measured reaction from the conference&lt;/a&gt;, but one of the guys was fired and a pretty massive Internet blow up over the whole thing. Most of which was direct squarely, and harshly, at Adria. (Update: turns out Adria was fired as well.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I go on, I just want to make it clear that this is my take, based on what I know which might be slightly incomplete. I mean, I wasn&amp;#39;t there, etc. I&amp;#39;m also not as educated as I now know I should be on women&amp;#39;s issues in tech, not that I think you need to be to get to the bottom of this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here&amp;#39;s how I see it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Was it ok for these guys to have this conversation?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Very debatable, but yes. It wasn&amp;#39;t a smart move to have it in a public place, and doubly so in a professional setting, but what two people talk about should be their own business most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Was the joke offensive?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Going to go with no, based on the definition of offense. The point being, I&amp;#39;m going to give them the benefit of the doubt and say they didn&amp;#39;t intend any offense, with the caveat that anyone overhearing is certainly within their rights to feel uncomfortable over hearing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Was Adria&amp;#39;s response to post their photo on Twitter appropriate?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; No. This was clearly not the best way to approach the situation, as I&amp;#39;m sure, in hindsight, she&amp;#39;d admit. Handling it in person, either face to face or via Pycon people, without escalating to the Internet, would have been the proper approach in my opinion. But, I don&amp;#39;t see anything horribly wrong with it either, it&amp;#39;s no worse an act than these guys telling dirty jokes in a public, professional setting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Should this guy have been fired?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; No. Seems like a knee-jerk over-reaction to me. Having said that, I don&amp;#39;t feel too bad for him. He should have known better, and people are fired for less all the time. And his reputation? That&amp;#39;s an easy one. If this had happened to me, I&amp;#39;d have personally and publicly apologized to Adria, made it clear that while no offense was intended, I fully understand why she might have been upset, taken my lumps and moved on. People make mistakes, and this was clearly a small one followed by a bunch of over-reactions. I think smart folks recognize that.  (Update: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5398681"&gt;looks like he&amp;#39;d posted an apology&lt;/a&gt; and I just hadn&amp;#39;t seen it, probably because it was buried with over-reactions and bullshit. And, in case it wasn&amp;#39;t clear, I don&amp;#39;t think he did anything actually deserving to be fired.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: Should Adria have been fired?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Clearly no. Nobody should have been fired over this. I thought maybe the guy involved might have a case, but this clearly seems like something with legal implications. I&amp;#39;m no lawyer, so I don&amp;#39;t know. Regardless, my guess is had there been no firing of anyone, this whole thing might have settled down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Internet&amp;#39;s response.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now we come to the heart of the matter, the reaction of the Internet to all of this. And, in my mind, there is no question to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;In no way, shape or form does Adria Richards deserve any of the poor treatment she&amp;#39;s getting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; And if you dig around, some pretty frightening stuff is out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the real problem here. It&amp;#39;s not about the joke or her reaction to it. It&amp;#39;s about how many people in this industry reacted to all this, and that, in my opinion, really needs to change.  Sure, she didn&amp;#39;t react appropriately, but that doesn&amp;#39;t excuse anything, it wasn&amp;#39;t THAT much of an over-reaction and those guys should have known better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t help but wonder if the gender roles were reversed here. Would this even be an issue? I mean, there are many cases of women being disparaged through photos, without any valid cause whatsoever, and while there is a bit of outrage, there is nothing remotely like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These men are being defended for making a mistake, and she&amp;#39;s being threatened and abused for it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;#39;t that seem backwards to you? Doesn&amp;#39;t it seem strange that the focus here is on Adria and what she did? Where are the people calling these dudes out for being stupid? Forget offensive for the moment, what they did was dumb, clearly against professional codes of conduct (and Pycon&amp;#39;s) and as such, what&amp;#39;s so wrong with her calling them out? Seriously, had this been me calling them out, would it have caused the same reaction? I highly doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve got a problem here. I&amp;#39;m not sure how to solve it, but clearly this kind of thing cannot be allowed to continue. I guess the first step for me is to pay more attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update and final addendum:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;#39;s been a little less than a day since I initially wrote this and quite a few things have come to light.  I can&amp;#39;t say I&amp;#39;d change my stance based on what I knew at the time, and honestly, had I known now what I new then, I&amp;#39;m not sure it&amp;#39;d change much either. I might be a bit harder on Adria going public, as I think about that more, it was a really bad move. I guess I just started thinking about all the horrible photos out there and thought, &amp;ldquo;what&amp;#39;s the big deal, it&amp;#39;s a stupid joke and now they&amp;#39;ve been outed.&amp;rdquo; Which &lt;strong&gt;would have been the case&lt;/strong&gt; if one of them hadn&amp;#39;t have been fired. Which was, just&amp;hellip;stupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I can say is that I was very nervous to post something like this on a sensitive issue. The reason I did was because I saw so much hate floating around, and here it was coming from an industry I love and I&amp;#39;m fiercely passionate about. It made me sad, but I wasn&amp;#39;t sure what to think. So I read and I wrote and it started to become clear.  In the end this isn&amp;#39;t about a dick joke, or an attention seeker, it&amp;#39;s about an immature industry&amp;#39;s inability to handle something like this. It&amp;#39;s about a fundamental lack of respect. And it&amp;#39;s about a world where, at any moment, we can publish whatever the hell we want to whomever we want and more often than not, don&amp;#39;t have to worry about being held accountable for it.  Many of us don&amp;#39;t choose to do so, for a variety of reasons. Many more do so responsibly, again for a variety of reasons.  Some, like Adria, publish without thinking through the consequences. Some publish hidden behind masks without fear of simple questioning, let alone consequence. They can always just fade away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in an always connected world. Our industry enables that, so we know how to take advantage of it. Most days this is awesome. But some days, some days it&amp;#39;s downright scary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I posted this because I felt like I hadn&amp;#39;t seen any even-handed reaction aside from the short post from Pycon itself.  Both parties were at fault for causing it, but the over-reaction that happened, frankly, could have and should have been avoided and it&amp;#39;s a fucking shame that it wasn&amp;#39;t.  With all this power and intellect we&amp;#39;ve got, we can&amp;#39;t seem to handle something like this? Sad. I still feel this way and that was the primary point I was trying to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But back to me being nervous. I&amp;#39;m pretty far removed from this. I don&amp;#39;t hold very much emotional stake in this particular game. I could have easily ignored it, and almost did. (Or so I thought, wow, it really blew up today.)  Regardless of their opinion I have to give it up for those people who did speak out and for whom an issue like this hits close to home. For those who didn&amp;#39;t, well, I&amp;#39;ve learned why you might not want to.  Part of me feels like I should have just written this out and kept it to myself and let those who really feel this speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I&amp;#39;m reminded of how this was handled. Of the companies and the firings and the flame wars, finger pointing and threats and hate and all the other bullshit. Clearly this industry needs help. We can do better. And, fuck it, I&amp;#39;m a part of this industry too, and I&amp;#39;m here to help how I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, I&amp;#39;m done. Here&amp;#39;s a picture of some cuddle buddies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/dkr_24550449597738_raw.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_dkr_24550449597738_raw.jpeg" alt="url.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/cZuc0Y0Tyr4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://howtomakelightning.com/on-the-pycon-incident</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/filesystem-wars</id>
    <published>2013-03-21T08:01:56-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T08:01:56-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/_jGt0q_yCuY/filesystem-wars" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Why the File System Wars Will Trigger a Wave of Consumer M&amp;A</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24549775061166_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24549775061166_raw.jpg" alt="Finished_Risk_Board_lrg.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You fool! You fell victim to one of the classic blunders - The most famous of which is &amp;ldquo;never get involved in a land war in Asia&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a land war being fought on the web and it&amp;#39;s for files and filesystems. Incumbents and startups alike are duking it out. And things are really starting to get interesting.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The startups, Dropbox and Evernote, reinvented the file system as a synchronized, cross platform file system abstracting the hardware and the data. Now they are moving up the stack. &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2013/03/dropbox-acquires-mailbox-to-help-grow-the-gmail-app-for-ios-quickly/"&gt;Dropbox&amp;#39;s acquisition of Mailbox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/12/14/dropbox-for-ios-updated-with-new-photo-gallery-and-design/"&gt;renewed focus on photographs&lt;/a&gt; and attachments and Evernote&amp;#39;s every growing battery of point applications like Skitch, Food, Hello and Peek aim to drive further file creation and user engagement within their notebooks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24549784378398_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24549784378398_raw.png" alt="ScreenCapture at Thu Mar 21 07:41:23 PDT 2013.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The incumbents, Microsoft and Apple, leverage their own advantages heavily.  Over the last few years, Microsoft and Apple, which own the most popular operating systems and the content creation applications, Microsoft Office and Apple iWork, have persistently revised their operating systems to unify the local and cloud filesystems (SkyDrive and iCloud). Google entered the fray seeking to displace Office with a web based document creation suite whose by-product was an online file system that evolved into Drive. &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2013/03/google-keepsave-whats-on-your-mind.html"&gt;Google&amp;#39;s recent Keep launch, a note taking application, is a shot across Evernote&amp;#39;s bow.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way, the core value proposition to users has changed. The old war cry, liberation from disaster recovery and data backup duties, has been replaced by the promise of device independent, scalable, searchable filesystems that use the power of the cloud to afford new capabilities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Google Drive, &lt;a href="http://support.google.com/drive/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=2691634"&gt;searching for Eiffel Tower will return photographs from a user&amp;#39;s of the famed Parisian monument using image recognition.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because end user applications and experiences differentiate these filesystems, I expect to see a flurry of acquisitions of next generation content creation tools that users love by these companies all in effort to create loyalty and build lock-in to a particular file system. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These might include photo creation tools, next generation presentation tools, developer API platforms enabling programmatic access to these file systems and potentially even content stores to compete with Google Play and iTunes. After all, movies and music and books also have to be stored in a file system. It may as well be the same one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For users the promise of the cloud filesystems battle is better applications and experience. For startups, it means the beginning of the M&amp;amp;A wave. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which startups do you think are most likely to be acquisition targets in the file system wars? &lt;a href="http://branch.com/b/why-the-file-system-wars-will-trigger-a-wave-of-consumer-m-a/invite_link/dldr9tZxKrMJDQ"&gt;Let me know what you think on this Branch.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/_jGt0q_yCuY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/filesystem-wars</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:adii,2012:Post/firing-your-customers</id>
    <published>2013-03-21T05:58:37-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T05:58:37-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/VBeVtkTxUnc/firing-your-customers" />
    <author>
      <name>Adii Pienaar</name>
      <uri>http://adii.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Firing Your Customers</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ll know from my writing in the past, that I&amp;#39;m a big advocate of &lt;a href="http://adii.me/make-customers-pay"&gt;making one&amp;#39;s customers pay&lt;/a&gt; (which is something I&amp;#39;ve become a little battle-hardened on over the years). I&amp;#39;m however also a firm believer in &lt;a href="http://adii.me/dont-compete-on-features"&gt;giving customers a superior experience&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; I&amp;#39;m more than happy to fight for my customers and &lt;a href="http://adii.me/dont-be-defensive-defend-your-livelihood"&gt;defend their livelihoods&lt;/a&gt; when needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere within that landscape of differing views on what constitutes good customer experiences and how I / we should interact with customers, I&amp;#39;ve developed a tendency to fire customers &lt;em&gt;when the situation requires it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a step back, I think it&amp;#39;s important to say that not all customers are created equally; in a very similar way to not all companies or products being equal either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, I don&amp;#39;t believe that the customer is always right (instead I now believe that it was a rookie error to even think like this from the beginning). I now believe that every customer interaction should be handled on the merits of that individual situation, with the underlying intention being to give every customer a fair opportunity to receive their desired outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m also reminded of all the signs that reads &lt;strong&gt;Rights of Admission Reserved&lt;/strong&gt;, which obviously had the intention of giving the holder of those rights some mechanism to exert influence on any given situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately - as a business owner - I have the choice of doing business with whom I wantl just as a prospective customer has the option of doing business with me or not doing business with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve always been very active in our support helpdesk at Woo and I consistently interact with hundreds of WooThemes customers (existing &amp;amp; prospective) every week. Firing any of these customers was never something I even considered for a second (heck, &lt;a href="http://adii.me/make-customers-pay"&gt;I was even offering people free support in the past&lt;/a&gt;), but then I had a couple of really bad experiences with a handful of customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;#39;s based on those experiences that I&amp;#39;ve decided that there&amp;#39;s two reasons for actually firing a customer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a customer is rude, swears at me (or anyone on my team), insults me (or anyone on my team) or irrationally calls my / our integrity into question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a customer simply isn&amp;#39;t a good fit for us. This can be due to a multitude of reasons, but it just sometimes becomes obvious sometimes that it&amp;#39;s better (for both parties) to sever the relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad customers are toxic; regardless of how many thousands of customers you have. It&amp;#39;s like having that one bad apple in the batch, which infects everything else. I&amp;#39;ve experienced first hand how a rude / irrational customer interaction can bring a whole team down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flipside, those experiences are just as bad for customers and the outcome is similarly as bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately I believe that the business-to-client relationship should be one of trust / respect and one that is mutually beneficial. As such, if this isn&amp;#39;t possible anymore, it&amp;#39;s better that there is no relationship, because a pure financial bond isn&amp;#39;t enough to keep a relationship going (*i.e. I&amp;#39;m no prostitute*).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/VBeVtkTxUnc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://adii.me/firing-your-customers</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:cadelllast,2012:Post/are-you-ready-for-deextinction</id>
    <published>2013-03-20T21:17:57-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T21:17:57-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/j57AY_D-ck4/are-you-ready-for-deextinction" />
    <author>
      <name>Cadell Last</name>
      <uri>http://theratchet.ca</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Are You Ready For De-Extinction?</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/R6w0jjL.png" alt="De-Extinction"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans have been &lt;a href="http://www.theadvancedapes.com/theratchet/2012/12/1/the-sixth-mass-extinction"&gt;fundamentally reshaping ecosystems and causing massive megafaunal extinction events since we emerged from East Africa ~75,000 years ago&lt;/a&gt;.  Over this time period iconic animals like the wooly mammoth, wooly rhinoceros, giant wombats, American horses, western camels, giant beavers, saber-toothed cats, and many other species suffered extinction.  It is estimated that the world lost at least 178 large mammals during our migratory emergence.  Ecosystems continued to collapse as we established ourselves globally and continued to extend our use (and misuse) of resources throughout the Holocene.  Today many of the animals that suffered extinction during this period (e.g, Tasmanian tiger, dodo, passenger pigeon) have become permanently associated with our species capacity to destroy ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if we could undo this damage?  What if we could bring all of these species back and revive the healthy megafaunal ecosystems that existed throughout the world before our emergence?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remarkable advances in synthetic and molecular biology within the past decade will allow us to bring back Paleolithic ecosystems.  Researchers can now take ancient DNA fragments (e.g., like preserved wooly mammoth DNA) and compare them with DNA from the extinct animals closest living relative (e.g., for the mammoth that would be the Asian elephant).  After the genetic comparisons have been made, McMaster University geneticist and biological anthropologist &lt;a href="http://www.anthropology.mcmaster.ca/faculty-1/poinarh"&gt;Hendrik Poinar&lt;/a&gt; claims the possibility of de-extinction is theoretically plausible: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can in theory use that information to modify existing chromosomes with what we imagine to be mammoth substitutions, the result would be an elephant-mammoth hybrid, and such a creature could theoretically be implanted into the womb of a mother elephant.  Get the formula right, and the offspring might be a mammoth in the eye of the beholder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of these scientific possibilities, &lt;a href="http://longnow.org/revive/"&gt;The Long Now Foundation’s Revive and Restore&lt;/a&gt; program held a &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/tedx/events/7650"&gt;de-extinction conference on March 15th 2013&lt;/a&gt; supported by TED and the National Geographic Society to begin discussing these scientific and ethical issues.  The fact that science has progressed so far as to enable the possibility of de-extinction may at first seem like a compelling enough reason to do it.  After all, who wouldn’t want to see iconic ice age mammals like the saber-toothed cat and wooly mammoth?  However, we immediately run into ethical questions that prove challenging to answer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biologist and de-extinction enthusiast &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/stewart_brand_the_dawn_of_de_extinction_are_you_ready.html"&gt;Stewart Brand stated that Revive and Restore held this recent TED conference&lt;/a&gt; in order to “open the discussion to the public.”  So in this article I want to list the pros and cons of de-extinction so that everyone can make an informed decision for themselves.  Whether you are scientifically literate or not, whether you have a love of science and nature or not, de-extinction would effect everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let the De-Extinction Revolution Begin!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.We have a responsibility to the biosphere&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stated at the start of this article, our species is largely responsible for the high extinction rates of the Middle Paleolithic, Upper Paleolithic, and Holocene.  Of course, extinction is a natural process and it is a driver of biological evolution.  However, in contemporary times the extinction rate is more than 1,000 times above the “normal” estimated background extinction rate before our emergence.  This means that there is overall declining biodiversity and ecosystems are suffering as a result.  Therefore, we have a responsibility to not only reverse these trends, but also to “re-wild” what we have destroyed.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.Increase ecological and biological diversity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many ecosystems today are unstable.  Some rainforests suffer from “empty-forest syndrome” and food chains in the oceans, seas, prairies, and mountains are collapsing as a result of extinction and climate change.  We could potentially revive and re-create vibrant ecosystems by bringing back species that used to play pivotal roles within various niches.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.Iconic, Beloved, Missed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Revive and Restore home page they claim that key revival criteria is how “iconic,” “beloved,” and “missed” currently extinct species are.  This may seem like a trivial reason, but many humans love and care for nature, and would love to see Paleolithic biosphere revived and restored.  Certain animals hold cultural capital and unique places within the population imagination.  For this reason many people would argue de-extinction is intrinsically good and morally justified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.Science!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding nature and the biological world is important for our own understanding of the universe and our planet.  If we started to recreate ecosystems specifically designed for currently extinct flora and fauna we would learn a great deal about how ecosystems function.  We would also learn about currently extinct animal behaviour that we cannot learn from fossils.  Selfishly, I think the evolutionary anthropologist in me would be interested in studying Paleolithic fauna because it would potentially help us better understand our own evolution.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep The Past In The Past&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.Many Paleolithic biospheres no longer exist&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a massive ecological problem with bringing back species from the Paleolithic: many of these species habitats no longer exist.  The last Ice Age ended 10,000 years ago.  This means that most of the species that suffered extinction as a result of our emergence lived in habitats and ecosystems that cannot be redesigned today.  This problem would be most pressing for Eurasian megamammals like the wooly rhinoceros and the wooly mammoth.  These species would be revived into a quickly warming world that may not be able to support them.  The consequences would likely be a quick “re-extinction.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.No country for wild carnivores&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second equally important question is whether there would be a country that would want to protect and maintain populations of vicious Ice Age carnivores like the saber-toothed cat.  Stanford University ethicist Hank Greely and de-extinction enthusiast claimed that it would be “neat to see [a saber-toothed cat].”  However, would they be destined to live their lives in zoos and labs?  Would we ever be able to establish a population in the wild?  As paleontologist &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Laelaps"&gt;Brian Switek&lt;/a&gt; pointed out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wildlife experts in and around Yellowstone National Park have enough trouble trying to get the public to accept the presence of wolves – carnivores that were extirpated from the area within recent history before being reintroduced two decades ago – and conservationists continue to struggle with the persistent conflict between jaguars and ranchers in South America.  Can you imagine the uproar over sabertoothed cats being returned to the western United States or South American grasslands? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.Lack of conservation funding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservationists struggle to make progress with limited funding.  Although many international organizations have managed to stabilize many animal populations that would otherwise be de-extinction candidates today, they still have not managed to significantly reduce the background extinction rate.  If we bring back currently extinct animals that may put even more stress on underfunded conservation organizations and prevent them from allocating resources effectively.  The result could be increased extinction of currently endangered species.      &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.Genomic engineering can serve more practical purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several population of megafauna today (e.g., cross-river gorilla, white rhinoceros) that are on the edge of extinction.  With genetic engineering we could help these populations stay afloat by adding genetic variation to populations in risk of a genetic bottleneck.  This would give conservationists a useful tool to help these populations rebound in the wild, as opposed to suffering from genetic inbreeding and eventually collapse.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let The Debate Begin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently on a revolutionary scientific frontier.  De-extinction is a real possibility right now.  What will we do?  Will we bring the Paleolithic into the Anthropocene?  As I have tried to illustrate, de-extinction raises very complex questions.  Undoubtedly there will be very passionate de-extinction enthusiasts and equally passionate de-extinction opposition.  I hope that this article helped inform you about some of the important questions that we will all be encountering this decade.  The fate of the biosphere is now in our hands. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/j57AY_D-ck4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://theratchet.ca/are-you-ready-for-deextinction</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:bradmccarty,2012:Post/reader-keep-and-a-dissection-of-googles-madness</id>
    <published>2013-03-20T20:48:59-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T20:48:59-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/IYUX604YgNI/reader-keep-and-a-dissection-of-googles-madness" />
    <author>
      <name>Brad McCarty</name>
      <uri>http://uptake.co</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Reader, Keep and a Dissection of Google's Madness</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m on a bit of a vacation this week from the world of tech, spending my time instead being Mr. Husband and Mr. Homeowner. I can&amp;#39;t help but chirp up, however, on the subject of Google&amp;#39;s newly-launched Evernote competitor, &lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/google/2013/03/20/google-launches-evernote-rival-keep-for-the-web-android-4-0-and-above/"&gt;Keep&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you&amp;#39;re not keeping up with the Angry Nerds crowd, people are pretty mad that Google decided to rather abruptly &lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/google/2013/03/14/google-to-axe-google-reader-on-july-1-as-part-of-larger-round-of-app-closures/"&gt;shut down its RSS service&lt;/a&gt; named Reader. The backlash of that is still ringing strong, with smart people like &lt;a href="http://gigaom.com/2013/03/20/sorry-google-you-can-keep-it-to-yourself/"&gt;Om Malik telling Google&lt;/a&gt; that he won&amp;#39;t be using Keep because he can&amp;#39;t trust that it won&amp;#39;t meet the same fate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t speak to Google&amp;#39;s long-term plans, but I do think that Keep will stick around. In the grand scheme of things, where Google makes more money by understanding user behavior, a service such as Keep makes perfect sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you&amp;#39;ve missed the news, Google&amp;#39;s amazing-service-du-jour is &lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/google/2012/12/05/google-now-adds-travel-destination-weather-local-events-song-id-by-voice-and-more/"&gt;Google Now&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s the &amp;ldquo;living in the future&amp;rdquo; app that many of us have been wanting. Though its results start off somewhat lackluster, the more that you use it, and the more that it knows about you, the more amazing it becomes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Now is impressive because of semantics. It knows what you&amp;#39;ve searched, where you are and what you&amp;#39;re doing (roughly). With this information, it can offer information, rather than just providing data. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semantics are the holy grail to Google. As Matt Cutts has often &lt;a href="http://www.mattcutts.com/blog/google-synonyms/"&gt;talked about&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most interesting challenges for search is understanding what someone means when a searched term is a synonym for another. Google, via Android (and also some iOS apps), your personal account and your history on both already knows a lot about you. But there are personal semantics that are missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; care about? What sorts of things do you find important enough to keep for later? If you save loads of articles that reference freshwater fish, and many more that talk about cooking or healthy lifestyles, Google is likely to be able to draw the connection that you enjoy eating fish and it can provide better contextual search results for you. While there&amp;#39;s a chance that you&amp;#39;re a fan of aquariums, the semantics make the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Keep, Google is opening the door to a layer of information about its users that it hadn&amp;#39;t previously been able to reach. Is Keep safe from the swinging axe of product death? Nobody can answer that just yet. But what&amp;#39;s definitely true is that, to Google, Keep is a much more important product than Reader. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, kids, when it comes to Google, you are the product being sold. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/IYUX604YgNI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://uptake.co/reader-keep-and-a-dissection-of-googles-madness</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:leemartin,2012:Post/papa-for-pope</id>
    <published>2013-03-20T19:25:04-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T19:25:04-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/xcCycGIc698/papa-for-pope" />
    <author>
      <name>Lee Martin</name>
      <uri>http://leemart.in</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Papa for Pope</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.papaemeritus.com"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_leemartin_24548993319996_raw.jpg" alt="Papa Emeritus II"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or How to Run a Papal Election Campaign&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One proven way to generate extra traffic in Internet marketing is to associate your campaign with major world events somehow. Maybe it&amp;#39;s the Superbowl, Oscars, or in the case of my last campaign, the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Papal_conclave"&gt;Papal Conclave&lt;/a&gt;. The trick is to react quickly and cleverly in an effort to become part of the massive conversation already happening organically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghost_(Swedish_band)"&gt;Ghost B.C.&lt;/a&gt; to have a presence in Austin at &lt;a href="http://sxsw.com"&gt;SXSW&lt;/a&gt; even though they weren&amp;#39;t performing. Trying to make an impression among all that noise and BBQ is not easy, but we were handed a, dare I say &lt;em&gt;blessing&lt;/em&gt;, when Pope Benedict XVI stepped down and forced an election for a new Pope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to craft a &amp;ldquo;Papa Emeritus II for Pope&amp;rdquo; campaign that existed in both the real and digital world via old school printed flyers and the website &lt;a href="http://www.papaemeritus.com"&gt;papaemeritus.com&lt;/a&gt;, which allowed fans to cast their vote for Papa and unlock the band&amp;#39;s newest track, &lt;a href="http://www.papaemeritus.com"&gt;Year Zero&lt;/a&gt;. The first thing we needed was an image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Poster&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thinking is that real world campaign &amp;ldquo;conversion&amp;rdquo; of a &lt;strong&gt;text-heavy&lt;/strong&gt; flyer design was going to be low within all that noise at SXSW, so I opted to design something much more iconic and dropped in a subtle web URL for good measure. The aesthetic and layout of the poster is an obvious bite of &lt;a href="http://www.obeygiant.com/"&gt;Shepard Fairey&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; massively successful &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barack_Obama_%22Hope%22_poster"&gt;Hope&lt;/a&gt; poster for President Barack Obama&amp;#39;s 2008 election campaign with a Ghost B.C. twist, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began by &lt;a href="http://instagram.com/p/WR5ph4hZfF/"&gt;sketching&lt;/a&gt; Papa Emeritus II from a source image with my 24 pack of Sharpies in an effort to abstract his most prominent features like his &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mitre"&gt;Mitre&lt;/a&gt;, white eye, and ghoulish scowl. This sketch served as a guide I could use in Illustrator to digitally draw all the shapes I needed to create Papa. I found an excellent &lt;a href="http://colorburned.com/55_seamless_lines_crosshatch_s/"&gt;pattern pack&lt;/a&gt; by Grant Friedman that assisted me in creating the cross-hatching which adds a nice lighting variation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I dropped the word &amp;ldquo;POPE&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;PAPA&amp;rdquo; in as 250pt &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Helvetica"&gt;Helvetica Bold&lt;/a&gt; and sent a print ready version of the flyer over to Austin for pasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Flyering&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_leemartin_24548994446220_raw.jpg" alt="Pope Flyers"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the night of Sunday, March 10th, our flyer crew hit the streets of Austin and what commenced was the best pasting campaign in the history of SXSW. They absolutely fucking killed it. &lt;a href="http://instagram.com/p/W3tt4art7K/"&gt;Papa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sunsetblood/status/311991028892712960"&gt;was&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://instagram.com/p/WxJDvujIIl/"&gt;everywhere&lt;/a&gt;. Even though I couldn&amp;#39;t make it to Austin, I immediatley started receiving countless &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/leemartin/status/311266348598693888"&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt;, texts, and photos from my friends who saw the poster. Hell, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasonfeinberg"&gt;Jason Feinberg&lt;/a&gt; even ripped one down as a souvenir since he&amp;#39;s such a fanboy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were so many great reactions on Twitter to the posters I couldn&amp;#39;t possibly post them all, but here are a few gems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/unclegrambo/status/312620022386270209" target="_blank"&gt;@unclegrambo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/brianslagel/status/312261488658223106" target="_blank"&gt;@brianslagel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/laura_hudson/status/311225037875183616" target="_blank"&gt;@laura_hudson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subliminal Marketing: &lt;strong&gt;Achieved.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Voting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to blanketing Austin in paper, we ran a complimentary Internet campaign at the same time from &lt;a href="http://www.papaemeritus.com"&gt;papaemeritus.com&lt;/a&gt;. The idea was to use the Papal Conclave tradition of casting paper ballots with the Latin heading &amp;ldquo;Eligo in Summum Pontificem&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;I elect as Supreme Pontiff&amp;rdquo;) to give all visitors the chance to channel their inner Cardinal and vote for Papa Emeritus II. This scheme also came with the added benefit of pulling an email address and some location data from the user for future mailings via the Facebook &lt;a href="http://developers.facebook.com"&gt;Graph API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the fan&amp;#39;s ballot was cast, it activated the Year Zero &lt;em&gt;ritual&lt;/em&gt; which allowed them to stream the band&amp;#39;s newest track. If you haven&amp;#39;t heard it yet, go &lt;a href="http://www.papaemeritus.com"&gt;right now&lt;/a&gt; to unlock it &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; be prepared to witness one of the most fucked up videos I&amp;#39;ve seen in a long time &lt;strong&gt;very soon&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;hellip; I seriously couldn&amp;#39;t watch it alone in my new apartment at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the site, we had an opportunity to react to the actual election progress on our &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thebandGHOST/status/311984815702425600"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/thebandghost/posts/574616922557108"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; by demanding a recount when Pope Francis was elected. Side note: my buddy &lt;a href="http://philipscottandrews.com/"&gt;Pip&lt;/a&gt; suggested we come out and say Pope Francis was actually Papa without his mask on, but I didn&amp;#39;t think I could get that one approved&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Post Mortem&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like the campaign could have been even bigger with more varied competing reactionary content, such as video, live stream from a fake papal election, or photoshopped photos of Papa in social situations. More parody, basically. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However,  it goes to show that some old school tactics with new school execution can be quite successful even in over saturated situations if you can develop the right imagery with the perfect timing and context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. You can expect more from our Ghost B.C. campaign in the next few weeks leading up to the &lt;a href="http://www.myplaydirect.com/ghostbc"&gt;Infestissimam&lt;/a&gt; release. &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/leemartin"&gt;Follow me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for the latest and please let me know if you have any questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/xcCycGIc698" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://leemart.in/papa-for-pope</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:kwindla,2012:Post/elegance-and-constraints</id>
    <published>2013-03-20T09:17:24-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T09:17:24-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/jJgfcXbEj-E/elegance-and-constraints" />
    <author>
      <name>Kwin Kramer</name>
      <uri>http://machine-theory.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>elegance and constraints</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A beautiful new exhibit at MoMa, &lt;a href="http://www.moma.org/visit/calendar/exhibitions/1319"&gt;Henri Labrouste: Structure brought to
Light&lt;/a&gt;, is very much worth a visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/kwindla_24548333153994_raw.jpg" title="Photo of the reading room at the Bibliothèque Nationale by Georges Fessy."&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_kwindla_24548333153994_raw.jpg" alt="LABROUSTE.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labrouste was one of the great architects of the 19th century. He was
trained in the then-traditional mode, a combination grand tour and
apprenticeship in Italy. During the prolific final twenty years of his
career, he created a new and contemporary language for public
buildings. He pioneered the use of cast iron and combined structural
innovation with detailed attention to decoration and form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MoMa exhibit concentrates on his two great libraries, the
&lt;a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:France,_Paris_II_Biblioth%C3%A8que_nationale_de_France,_BnF,_Site_Richelieu,_Salle_Labrouste_1854-1875.jpg"&gt;Bibliotèque Nationale&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sainte-Genevi%C3%A8ve_Library"&gt;Bibliotèque Sainte-Geneviève&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iron and Masonry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship between the stone outer perimeter wall, pierced by
large windows in its upper story, and the internal iron truss
structure was one of the great novelties of Labrouste&amp;#39;s library
design. They are at once independent and codependent. The fineness
of the iron arcades would be impossible without the stone box, which
stabilizes them, while the minimal thickness of the stone box is
possible because there is so little lateral thrust fromt he metal
frame. This enhances the luminosity of the interior. Other
architects were experimenting with mixtures of traditional and
innovative materials in rail stations and market halls, but
Labrouste was the first to endow iron with a new civic decorum and a
system of ornament that expresses the nature of the material and
follows its constructive logic. The iron arches are pierced only
where it is structurally possible to lighten the material, thus
producing a beautiful &amp;ndash; and perfectly rational &amp;ndash; lacy effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above text from the exhibit perfectly captures one idea &amp;ndash; one
ideal &amp;ndash; of architecture. And more than architecture, of engineering
and design in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computer programming is a relatively new vocation. Like all new
practitioners, programmers have liberally borrowed and repurposed
vocabulary as we&amp;#39;ve invented our profession. We sometimes call what we
do &amp;ldquo;software engineering.&amp;rdquo; And we refer to the functional
definitions of our software systems as &amp;ldquo;architecture.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are metaphors. There&amp;#39;s very little quantitative work in most
day-to-day professional programming. And our &amp;ldquo;architectures&amp;rdquo; are not
buildings and bridges; they are built from very different raw
materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, engineering and architecture are very good
metaphors. &amp;ldquo;Engineering&amp;rdquo; is about specifying and producing functional
artifacts. &amp;ldquo;Architecture&amp;rdquo; endeavors to create large-scale physical
artifacts that serve complex, multi-layered human needs. Both are,
fundamentally, the quest for deft definition and elegant management of
constraints. Form that follows, but is not dictated by, function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think of engineering and architecture as two flavors of a larger
pursuit: design. Design, in this sense, is about transcending the
zero-sum problem of working with multiple, overlapping, conflicting
contraints, about turning those constraints into opportunities, and
about creating beauty from these opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labrouste examined cast iron as a structural material and figured out
how to mate iron with stone so that the strengths of the two materials
complement each other. He created a new structural aesthetic from this
pairing. And he designed non-structural ornamentation that extended
this aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ID_AA_Carmack"&gt;John Carmack&lt;/a&gt;, a Labroustian figure to digital architects, has a nice
description of what he thinks makes a good programmer. Carmack &lt;a href="http://slashdot.org/story/99/10/15/1012230/john-carmack-answers"&gt;says&lt;/a&gt;
that programming requires managing design trade-offs at multiple
layers of abstraction. A good programmer does this multi-layered
design work well, iteratively, intuitively, and keeps a &amp;ldquo;map&amp;rdquo; of these
abstractions in her head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These multiple layers of abstraction are the site grading, plumbing,
stonework, wooden beams, lighting, furniture, finishes and
ornamentation of the computer programmer&amp;#39;s working world: the
microprocessors, disks, memory, input devices, graphics hardware, the
low-level software drivers, the operating system, the various software
libraries, the various parts of the new application being developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Labrouste, technical aspects of building and construction were
inseperable from ornamentation. He carefully planned for the reading
room&amp;#39;s heating and ventilation. He designed a hot-water heating
system for beneath the tables, at the readers&amp;#39; feet, and he
installed twenty-four radiators around the perimeter of the
room. These iron heating devices were given a sculptural treatment
that recalls Labrouste&amp;#39;s earlier designes for streetlights on the
Pont del la Concorde. Nor were the transverse beams in the book
stacks left unadorned; the ornamentation underscored the assembly of
bolted ironwork. Drawings such as these, at full scale, were made to
guide the manufacture of the building&amp;#39;s component parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;MoMa explanatory text for an exhibited elevation and plan of a
radiator for the reading room of the Bibliotèque Nationale.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labrouste&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://archive.org/details/Ms3910"&gt;construction diary&lt;/a&gt; for the Bibliotèque Sainte-Geneviève
has been made available online by that library and archive.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual,  &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/14/arts/design/henri-labrouste-at-the-museum-of-modern-art.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;_r=0"&gt;Michael Kimmelman&amp;#39;s review&lt;/a&gt; in
the New York Times is excellent and informative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/jJgfcXbEj-E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://machine-theory.com/elegance-and-constraints</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/the-future-is-here-its-just-not-evenly-distributed</id>
    <published>2013-03-20T07:54:46-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T07:54:46-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/ryGLhsJIQiw/the-future-is-here-its-just-not-evenly-distributed" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The Future Is Here, It's Just Not Evenly Distributed </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24548216964012_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24548216964012_raw.png" alt="minorityreport1.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An entrepreneur shared this quote with me a few weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future is already here – it&amp;#39;s just not evenly distributed.&lt;br&gt;
William Gibson, quoted in The Economist, December 4, 2003&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remembered it this morning when I drove past a Google self-driving car and then again a few minutes later when a Tesla whipped past me and a third time during the same commute when I dictated an email to my mobile phone. Sometimes living in the Bay Area does feel like the living in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to Gibson&amp;#39;s point, not every region can claim to have self-driving cars on its highways or electric car ownership or smart phone penetration rates as high as the Bay Area. Why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there are four main barriers to distributing the future better. These are the same four challenges startups must solve to succeed. And these needs actually determine the structure of most startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awareness:&lt;/strong&gt; many people simply don&amp;#39;t know about Square or Expensify or Google Now. They haven&amp;#39;t seen or used the products because they&amp;#39;re too busy or otherwise engaged. &lt;a href="http://tomtunguz.com/branding"&gt;Marketing and branding are the tools to drive education and awareness.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; new technologies cost money. With time and advances in manufacturing or cloud computing, newer technologies become more efficient to produce and deliver, but money will always be a barrier to adoption. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complexity:&lt;/strong&gt; my father-in-law is a brilliant surgeon and audiophile. We&amp;#39;ve just set up Sonos in his living room with Pandora and Rdio and a bunch of other music services. This weekend, I walked him through the set-up step by step over the phone and hearing him narrate the experience I realized how challenging technology can be for those who aren&amp;#39;t digital natives. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though those three products, Sonos, Pandora and Rdio are known for their simplicity, for many user they still aren&amp;#39;t simple enough. Complex product design limits adoption. That&amp;#39;s what Apple and Google do so well and why they attract hundreds of millions of users. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perceived value:&lt;/strong&gt; for a long time the benefits of newer technologies aren&amp;#39;t appreciated even after a customer/user might be aware. Either the cost/benefit analysis isn&amp;#39;t strong enough or the need isn&amp;#39;t yet apparent to the end user. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These four limits align well with the four major parts of a startup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awareness&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;Marketing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Cost&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Complexity&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;Product Design&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Perceived Value&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;Sales&lt;/strong&gt;.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A startup succeeds when it distributes the future better - and that means aiding awareness, reducing cost, eliminating complexity and selling the value of their product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/ryGLhsJIQiw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/the-future-is-here-its-just-not-evenly-distributed</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:micah,2012:Post/heart-startup</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T18:00:11-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T18:00:11-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/XkmWRM-dp_s/heart-startup" />
    <author>
      <name>Micah Baldwin</name>
      <uri>http://learntoduck.net</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Heart is Where The Startup Is</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The other day, I read Sarah Lacy&amp;#39;s post on &lt;a href="http://romotive.com"&gt;Romotive&lt;/a&gt; (a &lt;a href="http://techstars.com"&gt;Techstars&lt;/a&gt; Company!) moving to the bay area, &lt;a href="http://pandodaily.com/2013/03/15/more-bad-news-for-vegas-tech-fund-star-company-romotive-is-moving-to-the-bay-area/"&gt;More Bad News for Vegas Tech Fund&lt;/a&gt; and it stirred the same feelings I had when I moved &lt;a href="http://graphicly.com"&gt;Graphicly&lt;/a&gt; from Boulder to the Bay Area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the sentence that got me was in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KellerRinaudo"&gt;Keller&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s email to the Downtown Project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s my responsibility to make sure that Romotive is located where we are most likely to achieve this vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people who haven&amp;#39;t started a company think that there are simple decision points in deciding where that company should reside: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where do I want to live?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where the money at?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;#39;s not that simple. What Keller did was right, he listened to his business. His business told him where the best place was for them to achieve their goals, and unfortunately, it wasn&amp;#39;t Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dowsing"&gt;dowsers&lt;/a&gt;, great CEO&amp;#39;s have the ability to intrinsically listen to their companies, putting aside their egos and desires to do what is right for the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even as they bury themselves with metrics and analytics and report to boards and investors, they continue to listen to that ache in their stomachs that tells them what actions to follow through with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s like porn; you know it when you see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving a company is hard. There are people that can&amp;#39;t/won&amp;#39;t move. The community you are leaving looks at you askance and wonders why. your investors often came onboard because of where you were located.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not you; it&amp;#39;s me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I moved Graphicly to the Bay Area, I was pretty quiet about it. I didn&amp;#39;t think it was a big deal, and I still have people that ask me why I moved from Boulder, especially because Boulder is seen as such a startup mecca. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It honestly had nothing to do with Boulder, much like Romotive&amp;#39;s move has nothing to do with Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As founders, our only jobs are to put our companies in the best position to succeed. That means a focus on raising money, recruiting talent and articulating the vision of the business. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly, it means listening to the business and doing what is best for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kudos to Keller for listening, and more importantly, acting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/XkmWRM-dp_s" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://learntoduck.net/heart-startup</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:falon,2012:Post/early-stage-marketing</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T16:21:41-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T16:21:41-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/1D9aZkNbCI8/early-stage-marketing" />
    <author>
      <name>Falon Fatemi</name>
      <uri>http://falonfatemi.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Early Stage Marketing</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Depending on the nature of your product, you should not be investing in much marketing when you first launch. The main reason for this is to test out the performance of your product organically without any externalities affecting your data set. The only time you’ll have an opportunity to capture organic growth data is when you first launch and these metrics are critical in determining your next steps. The entire point of launching your product is to validate the core assumptions that your product is based on. It&amp;#39;s sometimes helpful to outline these assumptions and make sure you have the right tools implemented to track data against them post launch. That way you won&amp;#39;t let your emotions get in the way of data. I recommend writing out the company vision first, the problem you are solving, and they key value propositions that the product provides. These value propositions are essentially the assumptions that underly your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You shouldn’t have to invest in marketing &amp;ndash; if your product is good people will use it and will evangelize to their networks. Most of your marketing efforts should be spent focusing on tracking product/design metrics and user analytics such as engagement and traction.  Who is using your product? How are they using it? Are they telling their friends to sign up? What is the viral coefficient of the product? Is your design flow optimal for customer acquisition? You should be able to answer all of these questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once enough data has been gathered, generally over 2 - 3 months, you’ll be able to put together a robust marketing strategy that helps you drive towards growing the key metrics in your business. A brilliant marketing strategy will undoubtedly include a community development program that will transform your most active users into your biggest evangelists - your community will become your extended marketing team. More on that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools you can use:
- Mixpanel
- Flurry Analytics
- Localytics
- Kissmetrics
- UserVoice
- Olark
and many others ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/1D9aZkNbCI8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://falonfatemi.com/early-stage-marketing</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ben,2012:Post/that-time-i-climbed-kilimanjaro</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T15:59:11-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T15:59:11-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/NGXlAglOXxU/that-time-i-climbed-kilimanjaro" />
    <author>
      <name>Ben Yu</name>
      <uri>http://benyu.org</uri>
    </author>
    <title>That time I climbed Kilimanjaro (and got carried down in a stretcher)</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So this is just a short recounting of the time I decided to go to Africa and climb Kilimanjaro. I may decide to flesh it out once upon a future, and I may not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also not sure what the moral of the story really is. It’s either ‘don’t be an idiot’, or, ‘even if you’re an idiot all things usually turn out alright, so just go with the flow and wait for the stretcher’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How and why I went to Africa and what I did in the few weeks preceding my Kili climb is another story in itself. For now, suffice it to say that one day I suddenly found myself on a bus driving along the long road from Dar Es Salaam to Moshi. The story begins with my tragic choice of bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night before my hosts in Dar Es Salaam had thrown a huge party (aka Bingo at the Indian Restaurant Down The Street) celebrating their departure on the morrow for Sri Lanka. As a consequence, I stumbled to bed sometime around 2am. A traumatically short four hours later, I stumbled out of bed at 6am to catch my bus to Moshi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had heard horror stories about the abysmal state of bus driving in Tanzania before. The mortality rate seemed uncomfortably high on the lower tier buses, and so after much deliberation I decided to shell out the three or so extra dollars to upgrade to the very best luxury bus available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, this was a tragic mistake. Thoroughly deceived by the mildly warm ambient temperatures of about 200 Fahrenheit, I assumed a mere t-shirt and shorts would be sufficient climate protection on board the bus. Not so. Being a luxury bus, the contraption I entered had implemented a technological marvel that somehow managed to actively oppose the oppressive Tanzanian climate and maintain a steady temperature of about 50 degrees in the face of all odds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this probably seemed like paradise to every other passenger on board, to me it quickly became hell. With a solidly compromised immune system from last night’s sleep deprivation, the drastic shift in temperature proved too much for my fragile, delicate body to bear. Within a few hours I was freely shivering in the corner and feeling quickly nauseous. It was all I could do to concentrate on not throwing up, or crapping my pants, or fainting, or otherwise exemplifying poor Tanzanian luxury bus etiquette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six of the eight hours of the ride to Moshi were engaged in this way. By the time I arrived in Moshi, I had a healthy fever and a phlegmy cough. To date, this remains the fastest I have ever experienced a full transition from being healthy to thoroughly sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I had arranged accommodation before I made it to Moshi. After arriving sometime in the afternoon, I was picked up at the bus stop and spent the next few hours being driven up a mountain adjacent to Kilimanjaro before arriving at the aptly named Kilimanjaro View Lodge (it had a view of Kilimanjaro) where I was to stay the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happened next is a bit of a blur. After being warmly welcomed by Philip, the co-owner of the lodge, he brought up the guide who was to lead me up Kilimanjaro to advise me on my journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guide proceeded to thoroughly ascertain if I had everything I needed for the trip. I was exceedingly confident that I did. He was a little more skeptical. Glancing at the only bag I had brought on the trip, a meager 28L Deuter Futura backpack, he asked me if I had hiking boots. I replied that I had KSO Trek Vibrams, which would be more than adequate. He asked me if I had proper insulation. I had a two or three ounce down jacket and a similarly weighted windbreaker, which I again assured him would be fully sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trekking poles? No, but who needs those?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pants? Just the convertible pair I was wearing, though I did have a pair of waterproof pants I could throw over that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about a hat? A little wool beanie. It’ll be just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleeping bag? …of course not. But I have a cot, which is like, even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guide was really skeptical on this point. It took a lot of coaxing to convince him that my cot was Kili-worthy (spoiler: it was not).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I have to mention that I do feel guilty for all the trouble I put my guides through. And while I tipped them very generously, I feel bad about that too (more on that later). This is a cautionary tale. I was an idiot, and I did literally everything wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entirely unsatisfied, the guide eventually gave up and left me. Philip told me that he would return tomorrow morning to gather me before we went and got final supplies and began our hike. In the meantime, I could finally sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semi-delirious by now, I didn’t have to hear that twice, and immediately went to my cabin and fell asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True to Philip’s word, my guide arrived early the next morning with my porters and the cook in a janky little red car. I got in, we bumped down the mountain, stopped for some sunscreen, Diamox, and junk food, and made our way to the entrance gate for the route I was to climb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around noon when we finally arrived. The guide and I registered at the gate, paid our dues, and then, just as we were about to begin our climb, my guide seemed to deliberate with the porters and cook, and told me that we’d have to wait about thirty minutes before climbing. For some reason, this made perfect sense to my nonfunctional brain, and I didn’t ask any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should note here that no, my sickness did not, unfortunately, disappear overnight. In fact, I was much more sick than I had been the day before. I woke up with a fever literally coughing blood. But the excitement of climbing Kilimanjaro had gotten my adrenaline going, and against all odds I actually felt quite fine, save for the needing to keep fiercely bundled up in my down jacket despite it being about 90 degrees outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the story: after I busied myself for thirty minutes recording the endemic simian and giant scary ass crow population on my camera, the guide still hadn’t gotten back to me. Being juiced up on adrenaline and impatient to get started, I walked over and inquired what the holdup was. Reluctantly, the guide informed me that they had forgotten the cooking gear in the car…which was already well on its way back to Moshi. Hence, he’d have to go back and grab the gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not to worry – why don’t I just start climbing with the cook? He’d meet me at the first camp at night, and everything would be just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounded perfectly agreeable to me. My guide left, and the cook and I started to walk over to where they had left their packs. Leaving our packs unattended – bit of a mistake, that. Long before we got anywhere near them, we could see a horde of monkeys eagerly ripping through our possessions in search of precious nutrition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cook started shouting and ran at them to chase them away, and reluctantly they left. He inspected the packs, and there didn’t seem to be too much damage done yet. However, he informed me, it’d probably be best if he stayed with the packs until the porters came back so they could protect the packs. But not to worry again! – why don’t I just start climbing, and he’d be sure to catch up with me later?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, again, sounded like a wonderful idea to me. It was getting late, and I was already behind all the other climbers. I eagerly started up the mountain. “Pole pole!” the cook reminded me. He was reminding me to take it slow and keep a steady pace going up, lest altitude get the best of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuck that, I thought, as I nodded politely and smiled. I was late, and I felt great. The adrenaline had really gotten to me. I was going to book it up this mountain, and catch up with everyone else. The trail didn’t seem too steep at all, and despite not having exercised in ages, it seemed I could easily conquer it without strain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first few minutes, this proved true and I made it up the mountain at a remarkable pace. I even made it a personal goal to make sure that the cook wouldn’t catch up to me, and that I’d get to camp before he managed to overtake me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little while later, and I started passing my first hikers. I greeted them triumphantly in a self-satisfactory way, and kept pushing, priding myself increasingly on the number of hikers I managed to pass. Some guides eyed me suspiciously, and asked where my guides were. Back in town, I replied. They scoffed and told me I’d get lost. I just laughed inwardly and carried on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s when it hit me. Crap. I didn’t see this one coming, but bowel movements don’t lie. I really needed to take a shit. I looked around. There wasn’t much room off trail – it was pretty steep. I tried to push the crap back in and carry on. It wasn’t having any of it though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I couldn’t go any further and just had to step to the side of the trail and let it all out. Not very far, again. Essentially just a few feet off the trail next to a tree or two. I hoped I’d blend into the background and no one would really be able to see me. Porters passed by and waved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I dropped my pants and promptly discovered I had a pretty severe case of violent diarrhea. It was an immensely relieving sort of discovery though, so not all was bad. Finally I finished, as more porters walked by and pretended not to see me. I looked around for the toilet paper, and – ohh, that’s right. My guide had the toilet paper, and he’s in Moshi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bereft of a better option, I took some of the least questionable nearby jungle leaves and started wiping myself with them. They were wet, but it was better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got up, pretended once more to be dignified, and continued my trek up the mountain. I was feeling pretty good again, and so resumed passing as many people as I could at breakneck pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until the diarrhea struck again, of course. By now I knew the drill, so I went into the bushes and did my thing. This happened a couple more times as I moved up that day. Rinse and repeat, without the rinsing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last I passed what later turned out to be about half of all the trekkers that day, and met up with an Australian father-son duo. I would have passed them, but all of a sudden my borrowed adrenaline energy completely depleted and I hit a wall, barely able to move another inch, much less the final stretch to camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desperately I managed to keep pace with them and somehow made it to camp with even a little small talk sprinkled in, but as soon as I reached camp and signed in, I found the nearest log and sat down and didn’t move for about the next half hour until my cook arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He immediately spotted me, came over, and laughingly called me crazy for going so quickly. Then he gave me my lunch, which I had missed since I had kept ahead of the cook the entire hike, and I numbly attempted to make my way through it. My stomach was precariously on edge however, and it felt like any sudden or wrong move and I would be forced to eject all of my stomach’s contents, likely through my mouth, but also quite possibly through other orifices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow I managed to make my way through the entire little chicken drumstick and whatever else was in that little box (I think there was a biscuit, maybe? Something bready).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how my tent was setup and by whom, but at some point it was set up and I put up my cot and promptly attempted to sleep as darkness closed in. Still no sign of my guide. Oh well. I’d sleep and worry about it in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleep did not come as easily as I expected. In fact, it didn’t come at all. Why? My fucking vibrams. I had thought my clothing could keep me warm in the absence of a sleeping bag – how cold could it get in the middle Africa? – and for the most part I was right…save for my fucking feet. I had failed to take into account the fact that I had brought nothing but vibrams and a pair of overshoes, and neither of those things provided any warmth for my feet. I was certain my feet were actually going to freeze off that night. It was warm enough during the day, but at night, even at that first camp, it was frigidly code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow I managed to make it all the way through that first night – with no sleep, however – but when I woke up the next morning, I sheepishly informed my guide who had arrived sometime late last night that he was in fact right about the necessity of a sleeping bag, and that I might very well lose my feet without one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My guide was really the only reason I made it up that mountain. Incredibly resourceful. He somehow managed to procure a sleeping bag for me (something about one of the porters having one?), and we continued climbing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is to say, I went literally about eight meters up some large stone steps before practically collapsing and realizing I had failed to recuperate any energy at all and was in fact entirely exhausted and could go no further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I desperately asked my guide for a bit of rest, and everyone waited around as I sought to catch my breath. I looked pitiful. I was pitiful. And I felt pitiful. The thought of giving up and turning back flashed in my mind, and at first it seemed like the only real possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, I thought about how humiliatingly pathetic that would be. To have come all this way, to have flown to Africa, to have endured this crippling sickness, and to have made it all the way here to this mountain, only to turn back on the second day of a six day trek. It was beyond pathetic. It was beyond the scope of the definition of sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuck that. I resolved to myself that no matter what, I would somehow find a way up the mountain. And slowly but surely, I began to take start climbing once more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this day, I’m still not really sure how I made it through those next few days. I took some anti-diarrheal pills the first night, and by the second night my diarrhea was in control, so thankfully I never had to shit my pants in the presence of my guide and porters. Beyond that, it was just one step at a time, one night at a time, one meal I could barely stomach at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The food did not agree with me once on the entire trip. Every meal was a challenge in of itself. I just couldn’t stomach the food. It was some greasy bread with ketchup and some tea or something of the like. That’s mostly all I remember. But it was the antithesis of what pleased my stomach. I’m amazed I managed to stomach it all. The only thing that went down well was the fruit I believe, but there was a depressingly scarce amount of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, the next few days were a blur of exhaustion and precarious health. The trail was extremely demoralizing on certain days. We’d go up, and then we’d go all the way back down again. I couldn’t imagine ever getting to the top of this thing. When would it end?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But end it did, and at last we were at the final camp, the final reprieve before the push for the summit. There were no trees here, and it was quite chilly even during the day. My guide informed me we would be leaving just a bit past midnight in order to make it up in time for sunrise, so I’d best be going to sleep as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took his advice, but couldn’t sleep well. I tried listening to some Ellie Goulding on my Sansa Clip (I’d been carefully partitioning my mp3 player’s battery life throughout the climb and Ellie Goulding provided much needed inspiration to keep going). I put on all my winter gear – my gloves, my hat, my waterproof pants, my overshoes, my down jacket, my windbreaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True to my word, my guide woke me up at around 1am or so and handed me a pair of trekking poles he had managed to buy off another guide. Those trekking poles were the reason I made the final ascent. At some point my legs were no longer capable of stepping forward, and I would throw my trekking poles out in front of me with a strap around the handle looped around my wrists, and lean my weight on the poles and pull my feet up after the poles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lagged behind everyone else, and I desperately attempted to keep pace. I had a morbid fear of getting left behind. Only my guide and I were making this final ascent – the porters and the cook and stayed behind. He kept in front of me, as I lagged behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every part of me was freezing. My feet were numb and I couldn’t feel my toes at all. My hands were so cold I couldn’t hold the pole anymore – I had to keep my hands tightly balled up to keep the extremities from freezing off and hence could only rely on the poles being looped around my wrists. Eventually, I lost all feeling in my fingers as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow, miraculously, through sheer will and the good will of the mountain gods, I made it up the mountain. All the way. The sign said it all. Uhuru peak, 6900 meters above sea level (or something like that – check this later to make sure). My guide took some incredibly blurry pictures with his freezing hands (he didn’t seem to have brought gloves at all and had been just keeping his hands in his pockets), and we hastily made a retreat back to camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I remember is everyone passing me on the way back down the mountain. I distinctly remember the last person to pass me, a woman with trekking poles who was easily making it down the mountain as if it were her morning daily run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No such luck for me. I felt incredibly weak and tired, and every step took several seconds. I was lagging severely behind my guide, and at some point I was thoroughly worried I’d lose him and he’d leave me behind. I was by far the last one up the mountain, and I just couldn’t make it back down. My feet didn’t quite work anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later my guide would think that I had altitude sickness, but I’m not so sure. I think perhaps I just made had the wrong goal in mind: my goal had been to make it up the mountain, where it should have been to make it up the mountain and back down again. In any case, after what may have been anywhere from three to six hours but felt like an eternity, I told my guide that I really didn’t think I could make it down the mountain. I felt like I was out of options here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked around, and very fortunately there just happened to be another guide or scout or something skipping down the rocky slope. He conversed with him for a minute, and then the two of them grabbed me by each arm and helped me down the rest of the path to the camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At camp, he put me in a random cabin to rest and gave me some watermelon to eat. Delicious watermelon. I felt much better here, but still not well enough to physically exert myself. Eventually, my guide, my porters, my cook and I began the trek down the mountain and all I remember is that it seemed like the longest walk of my life. According to my guide, all we had to do was make it to the next camp where they had a stretcher, and they would be able to carry me down from there. It was only a little further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little further was forever. I was parched. My throat was felt incredibly dry. My feet were leaden. The path we came down was different from the path we went up, and so I had no idea where we were, and how much further we had to go. All I knew was that I wouldn’t be able to go much further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An excruciatingly long time later, and we finally made it to a grassy patch with a cabin where my guide managed to procure a stretcher, which literally consisted of a metal slab with some rope around it for securing me in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They put me on the stretcher and hoisted me up and began carrying me down the mountain. It was a tremendously bumpy ride, and I recall my head banging against the stretcher with every step. If I hadn’t been so shit-faced exhausted, it would likely have been the most uncomfortable stretcher ride of all time.  It also seemed remarkably dangerous to me – the path down was magnitudes steeper than the path up, and we were supposed to make it down the mountain in a single day, as opposed to the five days it took to make it up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, on some particularly steep steps it seemed as if they were essentially tossing me from the higher step to the lower step, and the people on the lower step were just hoping to catch me every time. In any case,  this did not concern me overly much at the time, though in retrospect it certainly should have, as a tumble down those steep rocky steps would have almost certainly meant my death, given how steep the off-trail slope was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I somehow managed to fall asleep somewhere along this stretcher ride, and when I awoke we were almost at the bottom of the mountain.  A short while later and we had made it to the exit. I remember blurrily something with a couple of white SUVs, having to pay someone to leave, and getting into an SUV and driving away, as well as some part where the car got stuck in some mud or something and for a solid twenty minutes or so of reversing and not reversing it seemed as if the car would never manage to get out. But somehow it did, and somehow we made it back. I also remember having to hike down the very end of the path, after we had to relinquish the stretcher. The cook, I believe, was listening to American music on his huge radio, and it was a foresty little trail we had to make it down. The guide, I believe, had gone ahead to fetch the car or something of that sort. We waited quite a good while after making it to the road for him to finally come back. It was a muddy road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, in more or less detail, is the full account of my travails on Kilimanjaro. For a month afterwards, I could not feel my fingers and toes. I saw a doctor about it, and he informed me that the quick changes in temperature often did this to people, and that it was nothing to worry about. While I was severely skeptical of his opinion at the time, I suppose he turned out to be right in the end, as my feeling slowly returned to me, though it was a month later and not the few days he had promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s much more to my travels in Tanzania to recount, but I’ll leave it at that for now. Not the best story I’ve told, but I’m riding on a plane back from Santiago right now and my thought has been constantly interrupted and bombarded by announcements and chatter, so I’m using that to excuse my less-than-stellar writing this time around. A story’s a story. Falser words have never been uttered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: Oh, and about this being short. Yeah, about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PSS: Ah right, and about me regretting even tipping my guides so much. So I tipped them enormously after the trip (withdrew 2x the amount to tip them too, the first time I withdrew my shillings I think I withdrew 400,000 shillings at the ATM and somehow the money disappeared. I still have no idea what happened to it. I probably just lost it&amp;hellip;d&amp;#39;oh. Anyway withdrew like over a million shillings or something to pay them or something like that), and then the day after that I saw my guide randomly crossing the street and he was bandaged up from head to toe and pretty much unrecognizable. According to Philip, that&amp;#39;s what happens when you tip too much. The guides celebrate, get wildly drunk, and then crash their motorcycles in the bushes. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/NGXlAglOXxU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://benyu.org/that-time-i-climbed-kilimanjaro</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:angus,2012:Post/how-to-read-a-book</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T10:31:34-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T10:31:34-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/w2RtmnBCevQ/how-to-read-a-book" />
    <author>
      <name>Angus Croll</name>
      <uri>http://blog.anguscroll.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>How to Read a Book</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although Ernest Hemingway&amp;#39;s brilliant 1927 story &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.asdk12.org/staff/grenier_tom/HOMEWORK/208194_Hills_Like_White_Elephants.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Hills like White Elephants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is only three pages long, there are tens of thousands of pages of academic analysis telling us how to read it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story itself is little more than tense, disjointed exchange between a man and a woman at a railway station somewhere between Barcelona and Madrid. Instinctive, melodic, enigmatic, irrefutable—the dialog is all we have, and it&amp;#39;s all we need. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried to eliminate everything unnecessary to conveying experience to the reader so that after he or she has read something it will become a part of his or her experience and seem actually to have happened. — Ernest Hemingway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hemingway gives us the bare minimum so that we might subconsciously fill the gaps with the logic and imagery of our own existence; he surely didn&amp;#39;t intend that blustering pedagogues and glorified cheat sheets should do it for us. And yet, at every turn there is a professor, a critic, or a study guide dishing up symbolism: the woman sees white elephants in the hills because the child she&amp;#39;s carrying is &amp;ldquo;the elephant in the room&amp;rdquo;; the train tracks are green on one side, barren on the other, evoking the differing attitudes of the main protagonists towards the woman&amp;#39;s pregnancy; the woman &amp;ldquo;recalls psalm 21 as she lifts up her eyes to the hills for help&amp;rdquo;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far from clarifying the original work, such absurdist pseudo-science only serves to obfuscate. A well written work of fiction speaks to something much deeper and more visceral than impersonal theorizing ever could. As the author&amp;#39;s work is coated by layer upon layer of scholarly inference, so the beauty, lucidity and intimacy of the original is smothered in the cold, hard varnish of academia. No wonder so many of us leave high school with no interest in literature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He knew everything about literature except how to enjoy it. — Joseph Heller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t know when the quest for the &lt;em&gt;message&lt;/em&gt; or the &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt; of a work of fiction became a thing. It might have been around the time the definition of literature morphed from a canon of work into a discipline. The idea that you have to study for four years in order to appreciate Hemingway (or Woolf, or Tolstoy, or Wilde) is, to me, as bizarre as the (related) notion that the goal of reading a novel should be to dredge up some profound and indispensable truth which the author has cunningly hidden in the depths of the subtext. Our schools and colleges are awash with self-proclaimed arbiters of authorial intent who would have us approach fiction as though it were a science built on absolute truths. If you ever encounter a multiple choice literature test, burn it. Right or wrong is the product of an education system gone badly awry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not read, as children do, to amuse yourself, or like the ambitious, for the purpose of instruction. No, read in order to live. — Gustave Flaubert&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was an actual book called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Read_a_Book" target="_blank"&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/a&gt; published in the 1940s. It focused almost entirely on non-fiction and encouraged the reader to analyze everything ad nauseam. In case you hadn&amp;#39;t guessed, this essay is exclusively about fiction (never let mere accuracy get in the way of a good title) and advocates entirely the opposite approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t subject the text to moralizing, rationalization or allegory. Don&amp;#39;t seek knowledge or erudition from fiction; in fact don&amp;#39;t ask anything of it. Keep your left brain in check, immerse yourself in the author&amp;#39;s world and in doing so gain new perspective on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read for pleasure. Don&amp;#39;t approach a novel as a necessary evil to be digested like broccoli or fish oil; it won&amp;#39;t make you smarter, a better conversationalist, get you that dream job or impress your friends. The joy of fiction is much bigger than that: the intimacy of the bond between reader and author, the recognition of self and others by way of the universal traits of the human condition, an encounter with genius on our own terms. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skip the synopsis on the back cover, it&amp;#39;s just mediocre advertising copyright. Ignore the critics, the professors and the study guides. What a book means to them says nothing about your life, and what a book means to you is none of their business. Literary interpretation is phony; the only truth is the text, and your emotional reaction to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revel in it. Lose yourself in it. Live it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/w2RtmnBCevQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.anguscroll.com/how-to-read-a-book</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jamietie,2012:Post/hypocrisy-cowardice-and-the-Cherokee-Scout</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T09:00:51-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T09:00:51-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/OyrD3tu4xjA/hypocrisy-cowardice-and-the-Cherokee-Scout" />
    <author>
      <name>Jamie Kelly</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jamietie.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Hypocrisy, cowardice and the Cherokee Scout</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;#39;t really surprise me when &lt;em&gt;Cherokee Scout&lt;/em&gt; editor Robert Horne &lt;a href="http://jimromenesko.typepad.com/my-blog/2013/03/north-carolina-editor-who-made-controversial-gun-request-resigns.html"&gt;resigned&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes you do something and it renders you ineffective. He did the right thing, and it cost him his job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least he can leave North Carolina with his head held high, and with some well-deserved kudos from his publisher:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We wish Robert well in all his future endeavors,&amp;rdquo; said David Brown, publisher of the Scout and Journal. &amp;ldquo;He&amp;#39;s a good man who has done a lot of positive things for the area that should be remembered.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brown on the other hand, gets to stay in North Carolina and hang his head in shame. That shame isn&amp;#39;t just because he &lt;a href="http://blog.jamietie.com/in-defense-of-publishing-data-on-gun-ownership"&gt;backed down and licked the sheriff&amp;#39;s boots when confronted with controversy&lt;/a&gt;. No, he gets even more shame because of the ad he posted today on &lt;a href="http://www.journalismjobs.com/Job_Listing.cfm?JobID=1477263"&gt;JournalismJobs.com&lt;/a&gt;. That ad begins:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you always wanted to be the editor so you can order the rest of the newsroom around while challenging the community with your extreme political views? Then this isn&amp;#39;t the job for you. Instead, we&amp;#39;re looking for an editor who knows how to tell good stories&amp;mdash;the kind people will always make time to read&amp;mdash;from breaking news to heartwarming features to in-depth reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High praise indeed for Horne, who&amp;#39;d been out the door for fewer than three weeks. It&amp;#39;s another sad but not surprising sign that community journalism&amp;mdash;the kind where so many reporters and editors learn their craft&amp;mdash;is often no longer concerned with standing up for the public&amp;#39;s right to know, no longer interested in holding elected officials to account, and no longer interested in the kind of journalism that can actually change a community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/jamietie_24545715367176_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_jamietie_24545715367176_raw.jpg" alt="cloud.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(The next front page story in the &lt;em&gt;Scout&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing for openness, access and accountability are not extreme political views. They are, or they should be, the very foundation of a local newspaper. Shame on Brown for betraying that, and shame on any other editor, publisher or owner who would do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And perhaps the saddest part is that the damage&amp;mdash;if, indeed, there was any&amp;mdash;is already done. Anything Brown does now won&amp;#39;t have any effect on the people who&amp;#39;d decided the paper wanted to come for their guns. All it does is tell the people who had supported the paper before and the rest of the journalism community, that there is no principle Brown will hold to, given the right amount of pressure. That&amp;#39;s a sad message to send and an even sadder one to receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/OyrD3tu4xjA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jamietie.com/hypocrisy-cowardice-and-the-Cherokee-Scout</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/data-biases</id>
    <published>2013-03-19T07:45:22-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T07:45:22-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/bM5W3UAbLDY/data-biases" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Which Data Biases Challenge Your Startup?</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24546681820170_raw.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24546681820170_raw.gif" alt="lies3.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Sinofsky, executive at Microsoft for 24 years &lt;a href="http://blog.learningbyshipping.com/2013/03/16/using-data-to-inform-strategy/"&gt;penned an insightful post on the five data biases plaguing product decisions.&lt;/a&gt; It can be easy for any founder, product manager, marketer or engineer accept a data point at face value as the rationale behind a decision. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But understanding the nuances and biases of the data, questioning the data, is often just as important as the result. The corollary point argued in his post is data isn&amp;#39;t strategy - data can&amp;#39;t be blindly used to inform product design and decision making because the data might be &amp;ldquo;lies, damned lies and statistics&amp;rdquo;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve highlights five data biases seen often in his career:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representation.&lt;/strong&gt;  No data can represent all people using (or who will use) a product. So who was represented in the data?&lt;br&gt;
Forward or backward looking.  When looking at product usage, the data looks at how the product was used but not how it will be used down the road (assuming changes).  Is the data justifying the choice or informing the e
choice?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contextual.&lt;/strong&gt;  The data depends on context in which it is collected, so if the user interface is sub-optimal or drives a certain pattern the data does not necessarily represent a valid conclusion.  Did the data consider that the collection was itself flawed?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Counter-intuitive.&lt;/strong&gt; The data is viewed as counter-intuitive and does not follow the conventional wisdom, so something must be wrong.  How could the data overlook what is obvious?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Causation or correlation.&lt;/strong&gt; With data you can see an end state, but it is not always clear what caused the end-state.  If something is used a lot, crashes a lot, or is avoided there might be many reasons, most not readily apparent or at least open to debate, that cause that end-state.  Is the end-state coincident with the some variables or do those variables cause the end-state?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my day to day, the correlation or causation one is most common. When evaluating a businesse&amp;#39;s performance it&amp;#39;s easy to assume that one metric (new feature release) causes another to increase (engagement) but making that leap isn&amp;#39;t always correct.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which data biases do you encounter most often? &lt;a href="http://branch.com/b/which-data-biases-challenge-your-startup/invite_link/3qYqdlra6yEwnw"&gt;Tell me in this Branch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/bM5W3UAbLDY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/data-biases</feedburner:origLink></entry>
</feed>
