<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xml:lang="en-US">
  <id>tag:svbtle.com,2012:/feed</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://svbtle.com" />
  
  <title>Svbtle Featured</title>
  <updated>2013-03-18T02:30:24-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Svbtle.com</name>
    <uri>http://svbtle.com</uri>
    <email>hello@svbtle.com</email>
  </author>
  <generator>Svbtle.com</generator>
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/svbtle" /><feedburner:info uri="svbtle" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><entry>
    <id>tag:adii,2012:Post/youre-born-an-entrepreneur</id>
    <published>2013-03-18T02:30:24-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T02:30:24-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/koAlbaZoD4E/youre-born-an-entrepreneur" />
    <author>
      <name>Adii Pienaar</name>
      <uri>http://adii.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>You're Born An Entrepreneur</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Saturday morning, I was attending (i.e. my 16-month old son can&amp;#39;t drive; so I was the chaperone) a first birthday party for friends&amp;#39; twins and I got speaking to someone that I met there. The conversation quickly turned to entrepreneurship and how it can&amp;#39;t be taught; instead you&amp;#39;re either born with critical characteristics that makes you an entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/16/bring-out-the-beast/"&gt;I then read this&lt;/a&gt;, this morning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Startups, like professional football, are best done by the most desperate people on the planet. Products don’t just walk out the door on their own. Sooner or later, to ship something amazing, you have to dig deep and bring out your beast. A horse running wild is a rare sight, but it takes your breath away every time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This struck a chord with me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last 11-odd years that I&amp;#39;ve been building businesses (the initial attempts - when I was still at school - can&amp;#39;t really be called businesses and should probably be labeled as &lt;em&gt;projects&lt;/em&gt;), I&amp;#39;ve often considered my drive to be a curse and &lt;a href="http://adii.me/passion-work"&gt;my passion to be a beast that needs to be fed&lt;/a&gt;. I regularly compromised on all the aspects of my life (going out for drinks for friends, working on weekends, spending time with my family etc.) in the short-term in the pursuit of something greater in the long-term. And for most of that pursuit, I didn&amp;#39;t even know what that &lt;em&gt;something greater&lt;/em&gt; even was. (I&amp;#39;ve only recently distilled this to my passion for &lt;a href="http://adii.me/2-things-i-love"&gt;helping other entrepreneurs&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the average person, this probably constitutes irrational and abnormal behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can also remember a conversation I had with a friend back in the day when we were at varsity. My friend kept talking about business and how he was gonna be this hot shot entrepreneur one day. At one stage, I asked him when he&amp;#39;ll work on his first business and he replied: &amp;ldquo;One day when I&amp;#39;m older.&amp;rdquo;. Today he is doing really well in a corporate job, where he is climbing the ladder with some great pace. To this day, he also hasn&amp;#39;t shown any inclination to be an entrepreneur. &lt;em&gt;This has never made sense to me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brain has been wired in such a way that I can easily compute the risk &amp;amp; reward of any decision. My personality is such that I chase after the impossible and (when it comes to business at least) I&amp;#39;m fearless in that pursuit. I live for the adrenaline of being challenged, being out-of-my-depth and not really knowing what tomorrow holds (and how I will overcome that). I&amp;#39;m fueled by my ambition to change the world and my drive to learn something new every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was born this way. This is who I am.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the only version of me that I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heck, don&amp;#39;t get me wrong. Some days I wish I can switch off all of this and I can just be &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; (whatever that means). But I can&amp;#39;t; I don&amp;#39;t know where that switch is and whether it even exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I wake up every morning and I get back onto the rollercoaster. This is just what I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/koAlbaZoD4E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://adii.me/youre-born-an-entrepreneur</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jamietie,2012:Post/media-mishandling-of-a-rape-verdict</id>
    <published>2013-03-17T18:26:14-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T18:26:14-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/IGVQrCmn78I/media-mishandling-of-a-rape-verdict" />
    <author>
      <name>Jamie Kelly</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jamietie.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Media mishandling of a rape verdict</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Steubenville, Ohio, rape case has been media catnip for months now&amp;mdash;it has so many elements that make it compelling: cover-ups, fallen teenagers, social media misbehavior, &amp;amp;c. It draws people in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s been less focus on the victim, which is unsurprising&amp;mdash;it seems that a lot of network and cable journalists and talking heads are more interested in the impact of the rape on the culture of the town (which is very interesting, but secondary), and on the effect on the football team, particularly the two players accused of rape. That is less interesting, unless we talk about how the team culture enabled and protected them&amp;mdash;made them feel that of course they could sexually assault a young woman. But that hasn&amp;#39;t been the narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rawstory.com/rs/2013/03/17/cnn-grieves-that-guilty-verdict-ruined-promising-lives-of-steubenville-rapists/"&gt;One CNN anchor&lt;/a&gt; today spoke about how the verdict possibly ruined the boys&amp;#39; lives, and how it was sad to see so much potential be waster. She didn&amp;#39;t mention what it must have been like for a 16-year-old girl to wake up with no recollection of the night before, and then realized that she&amp;#39;d been raped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the fact is, the verdict and the sentence didn&amp;#39;t ruin the boys&amp;#39; lives. First, they both had fairly lenient sentences, and are guaranteed to be out of custody before their 21st birthday. Second, if anything ruined their lives it was &lt;strong&gt;their own actions&lt;/strong&gt;. They made a choice to assault the victim. Their actions before and after the assault belong to them alone, and focusing on how the verdict ruined their promising lives subverts that fact. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea about the character of the boys in question, and neither do the anchors or journalists covering the trial. What we do know&amp;mdash;what has been proved in court beyond a reasonable doubt&amp;mdash;is that they raped a 16-year-old girl, and spread pictures of the assault. CNN and everyone else should be more concerned about the impact the assault, threats, and trial had on the victim than on the perpetrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/IGVQrCmn78I" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jamietie.com/media-mishandling-of-a-rape-verdict</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:EAKoester,2012:Post/stop-creepy-cofounder-dating-and-start-convincing-someone-you-are-awesome-enough-to-work-with</id>
    <published>2013-03-17T11:50:35-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T11:50:35-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/BprvwF0L40E/stop-creepy-cofounder-dating-and-start-convincing-someone-you-are-awesome-enough-to-work-with" />
    <author>
      <name>Eric Koester</name>
      <uri>http://ekoester.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Stop creepy cofounder 'dating' and start convincing someone you are awesome enough to work with</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a phone call a couple weeks back with someone who was looking for a cofounder (not an uncommon thing, right?)  I asked what he&amp;#39;s been doing to find a cofounder and his response nearly made me spit out my coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I posted a few ads on job sites,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; he said.  &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Then I&amp;#39;m interviewing the people who reply to see if they&amp;#39;d be a good cofounder.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What?  Are you serious?  Like seriously serious? WTF?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please Stop Being Creepy&lt;/strong&gt;
Listen, let me explain this to you quite simply:  you don&amp;#39;t hire a cofounder.  You convince someone awesome that you are worth working on something together.  Key word &amp;ldquo;convince.&amp;rdquo;  Not key words like &amp;ldquo;connive&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;surprise&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;manipulate&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;hire&amp;rdquo;.  None of those words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t go to the &amp;ldquo;cofounder store&amp;rdquo; and pick up a lovely Rubyist, with a side of adaptive design.  You don&amp;#39;t stand on the street corner on Wall Street and yell, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Anyone good with metrics, data and financial instruments?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s start here:  Don&amp;#39;t be creepy.  You know what creepy is&amp;hellip; it&amp;#39;s doing things like posting ads on job sites, then sneakily hope you can convince someone to be a cofounder when they apply for a non-existent job in your non-existent startup.  Turns out a relationship built on lies&amp;hellip; yeah, those usually don&amp;#39;t turn out well.  Rule #1: Stop being the skeezy, creepy dude at the bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that&amp;#39;s out of the way (which should be a basic test, but obviously it wasn&amp;#39;t), I want you to reimagine how you find a cofounder:  Pretend you are single and are hoping to find the love of your life.  Remember how that goes?  You meet lots of frogs to find a prince or princess charming.  You talk to friends, you may go on Match.com, you go out to bars or church.  You are looking for things in common.  You want to have great conversation, enjoy the same things, be on the same page with stuff, and generally dig each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t walk into a bar and yell, &amp;ldquo;Hey, who wants to get married.&amp;rdquo;  Well, unless you are super f-ing creepy, then maybe you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Convince Someone You Are Awesome&lt;/strong&gt;
Here&amp;#39;s three things to try to show someone you are worth working on something with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Work on a short-term, test project together.  Go to a Startup Weekend with someone, attend a Hackathon, or just work on something simple for a week (hell, try to build a desk together&amp;hellip; I don&amp;#39;t really care.)  Just actually try out working together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Attend a bunch of meetings together.  A good working dynamic is crucial &amp;ndash; and there is no better way to test that than to attend a meeting together with someone outside the &amp;ldquo;team.&amp;rdquo;  If you guys &amp;#39;crush it&amp;#39;, then that&amp;#39;s a good first step&amp;hellip; then do 10 more.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Collaborate on something for several weeks.  Co-write a series of blog posts, work on some code together, build a simple website or co-consult with a prospect.  You&amp;#39;ll learn a ton about how you communicate &amp;ndash; and treat both sides with the respect that you&amp;#39;d want to receive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, each of these activities above is a &amp;ldquo;date&amp;rdquo; with the goal of finding someone worth getting hitched to&amp;hellip; and it may take a lot of dates or maybe a few.  But remember how hard you worked to impress a gal or a guy when you were interested in them &amp;ndash; do the same with cofounder candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every meeting, every lunch, every conference is a place you might meet someone worth spending more time with&amp;hellip; and that time may eventually lead to a cofounder.  Remember, each meeting is a potential cofounder interview: they are interviewing you for your awesomeness quotient and you are doing the same.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, please please please stop asking me if you know of a cofounder you should meet.  A cofounder is NOT a mail order bride.  It&amp;#39;s work and you should plan to spend some time finding someone amazing.  If you rush it and try and force the issue, something will break&amp;hellip; probably one of you and ultimately the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this doesn&amp;#39;t seem to make sense, do me a favor and watch 40 Year Old Virgin.  Don&amp;#39;t be the guy in the first half of the movie please&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post script (from a Twitter discussion with my good friend Tony Wright):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1 in the &amp;ldquo;How to Convince Someone You are Awesome&amp;rdquo; is to actually BE demonstrably awesome&amp;hellip; that means you don&amp;#39;t just show off, talk a big game, highlight what was done in the past or point people to your amazing LinkedIn profile.  Like actually be awesome in context&amp;hellip; and show while working on something together to a potential cofounder.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/BprvwF0L40E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ekoester.com/stop-creepy-cofounder-dating-and-start-convincing-someone-you-are-awesome-enough-to-work-with</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/exclusive-soundsupply-receives-funding-from-lightbank</id>
    <published>2013-03-17T07:47:14-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T07:47:14-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/5Q_JWaWDFOE/exclusive-soundsupply-receives-funding-from-lightbank" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Exclusive: Soundsupp.ly Receives Funding From Lightbank</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://soundsupp.ly"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soundsupply&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a new company, formed in early 2012, that takes the &amp;#39;deal site&amp;#39; approach to selling music. Called &amp;ldquo;Drops,&amp;rdquo; Soundsupply creates bundles of 10 digital albums, charges $15 for them, and gives people a 10 day window to purchase the deal. The company has just taken on seed funding from Lightbank, the same people responsible for Groupon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The currently undisclosed amount of funding received will give Tim and Eric Mortensen, the two founding brothers, the opportunity to make Soundsupply their full time responsibility, trying to grow the originally bootstrapped company into an influential music destination. Though the retail experience may be the obvious angle for Soundsupply, music discovery is also at the forefront of focus and one the founders are passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company has already created 6 Drops, with the 7th being released March 18th. No bands have been announced for Drop 7 yet, but I&amp;#39;ve heard it is set to include Cursive&amp;#39;s newest album, &amp;#39;I Am Gemini&amp;#39;. One of the highlights that makes the service attractive to bands is the ability to actually make some money and gain exposure, all within a 10 day window. Past Drops have proven finically rewarding to the point of at least a few artists receiving a 90x return over their Spotify royalties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of bundling digital music is a simple and brilliant one that begs other bigger players in music retail to clone the experience. As a first mover, Soundsupply really needs to capitalize on mind and market share, giving users little doubt they are the pioneers and can grab the big names and best music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new influx of cash, you&amp;#39;ll begin to see things like an improved site design, making navigation easier, along with improvements to the download service and other small refinements. Long term, the guys behind Soundsupply are still open to exploring different aspects of the changing music industry. While bundling music may be the start, they aren&amp;#39;t opposed to tweaking the formula and thinking big picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hypebot.com/hypebot/2012/06/sound-supply-co-founder-talks-sound-drop-3-and-more.html"&gt;Here&amp;#39;s my June 2012 Hypebot interview with Co-Founder Tim Mortensen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/5Q_JWaWDFOE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/exclusive-soundsupply-receives-funding-from-lightbank</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tedgonder,2012:Post/books-that-have-changed-my-life</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T23:59:46-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T23:59:46-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/FOEwyBaMXEA/books-that-have-changed-my-life" />
    <author>
      <name>Ted Gonder</name>
      <uri>http://blog.tedgonder.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Books that Have Changed My Life</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Charlie Jones said &amp;ldquo;The only difference between where you are today, and where you&amp;#39;ll be a year from today, are the books you read and the people you meet.&amp;rdquo; Since I started reading voluntarily at the age of 14, books have had a huge influence on my life. Most of the books below are ones I&amp;#39;ve read multiple times, dog-eared dozens of pages in, and given as gifts. They and their authors have shaped who I&amp;#39;ve become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time Management, Career, Behavior, and Health&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mastery-Robert-Greene/dp/0670024961"&gt;Mastery&lt;/a&gt;, by Robert Greene&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Start-up-You-Yourself-Transform/dp/0307888908/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363502986&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=startup+of+you"&gt;The Startup of You&lt;/a&gt;, by Reid Hoffman and Ben Casnocha&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/4-Hour-Workweek-Anywhere-Expanded-Updated/dp/0307465357/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503001&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=4+hour+workweek"&gt;The 4-Hour Workweek&lt;/a&gt;, by Tim Ferriss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss?url=search-alias%3Dstripbooks&amp;amp;field-keywords=4+hour+body"&gt;The 4-Hour Body&lt;/a&gt;, by Tim Ferriss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Power-Full-Engagement-Managing-Performance/dp/0743226755/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503023&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=power+of+full+engagement"&gt;The Power of Full Engagement&lt;/a&gt;, by Tony Schwartz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Philosophy, Pyschology, and Worldview&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Meditations-Marcus-Aurelius/dp/1613823037/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503058&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=meditations+marcus+aurelius"&gt;Meditations&lt;/a&gt;, by Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Letters-Penguin-Classics-Lucius-Annaeus/dp/0140442103"&gt;Letters from a Stoic&lt;/a&gt;, by Seneca&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Tao-Te-Ching-Lao-Tzu/dp/1613822421/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503081&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=tao+te+ching"&gt;Tao te Ching&lt;/a&gt;, by Lao Tzu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/As-Man-Thinketh-James-Allen/dp/1482325632/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503096&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=as+a+man+thinketh"&gt;As a Man Thinketh&lt;/a&gt;, by James Allen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mans-Search-Meaning-Viktor-Frankl/dp/0807014273/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503114&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=man%27s+search+for+meaning"&gt;Man’s Search for Meaning&lt;/a&gt;, by Viktor Frankl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Secret-Psychology-How-Fall-Love/dp/0452288185/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503129&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=how+we+fall+in+love"&gt;How We Fall in Love&lt;/a&gt;, by Paul Dobransky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/50th-Law-Robert-Greene-Cent/dp/B0072B5MJE/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503147&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=the+50th+law"&gt;The 50th Law&lt;/a&gt;, by Robert Greene and 50 Cent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Books that Have Inspired Me to Lead and Serve&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Rules-Radicals-Saul-Alinsky/dp/0679721134/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503217&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=rules+for+radicals"&gt;Rules for Radicals&lt;/a&gt;, by Saul Alinsky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mountains-Beyond-Farmer-Random-Readers/dp/0812980557/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503229&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=mountains+beyond+mountains"&gt;Mountains Beyond Mountains&lt;/a&gt;, by Tracy Kidder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Acts-Faith-American-Struggle-Generation/dp/080700622X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503240&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=acts+of+faith"&gt;Acts of Faith&lt;/a&gt;, by Eboo Patel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Fountainhead-Ayn-Rand/dp/0452273331/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503257&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=the+fountainhead"&gt;The Fountainhead&lt;/a&gt;, by Ayn Rand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/One-Day-All-Children-Unlikely/dp/1586481797/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503273&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=one+day+all+children"&gt;One Day All Children&lt;/a&gt;, by Wendy Kopp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Our-America-Death-South-Chicago/dp/0684870444/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503289&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=our+american+life+and+death+on+the+southside+of+chicago"&gt;Our America: Life &amp;amp; Death on the South Side of Chicago&lt;/a&gt;, by LeAlan Jones &amp;amp; Lloyd Newman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Gang-Leader-Day-Sociologist-Streets/dp/014311493X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503312&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=gang+leader+for+a+day"&gt;Gang Leader for a Day: A Rogue Sociologist Takes to the Streets&lt;/a&gt;, by Sudhir Venkatesh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Monster-Autobiography-L-Member/dp/0802141447/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503328&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=monster+gang+l.a."&gt;Monster: The Autobiography of an L.A. Gang Member&lt;/a&gt;, by Sanyika Shakur&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Autobiography-Malcolm-X/dp/0345902335/ref=sr_1_2?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503350&amp;amp;sr=1-2&amp;amp;keywords=autobiography+of+malcolm+x"&gt;The Autobiography of Malcolm X&lt;/a&gt;, by Malcolm X&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Leadership-Dojo-Foundation-Exemplary-Leader/dp/1583942017/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503372&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=leadership+dojo"&gt;The Leadership Dojo: Build Your Foundation as an Exemplary Leader&lt;/a&gt;, by Richard Strozzi-Heckler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Search-Warrior-Spirit-Fourth-Disciplines/dp/1583942025/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503389&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=in+search+of+the+warrior+spirit"&gt;In Search of the Warrior Spirit: Teaching Awareness Disciplines to the Green Berets&lt;/a&gt;, by Richard Strozzi-Heckler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Warriors-Path-Second-Philosophy-Mythology/dp/158394219X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503401&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=on+the+warriors+path"&gt;On the Warrior’s Path&lt;/a&gt;, by Daniele Bolelli&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Heart-Fist-Education-Humanitarian-Making/dp/B0098RLDT8/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503415&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=heart+and+the+fist"&gt;The Heart and the Fist: the Education of a Humanitarian, the Making of a Navy SEAL&lt;/a&gt;, by Eric Grietens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Power-Love-Theory-Practice-Social/dp/1605093041/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503429&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=power+and+love"&gt;Power and Love&lt;/a&gt;, by Adam Kahane&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Books that Just Plain Spoke to Me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Fight-Club-Novel-Chuck-Palahniuk/dp/0393327345/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503515&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=fight+club"&gt;Fight Club&lt;/a&gt;, by Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Lullaby-Chuck-Palahniuk/dp/0385722192/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503527&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=lullaby"&gt;Lullaby&lt;/a&gt;, by Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Million-Little-Pieces-James-Frey/dp/0307276902"&gt;A Million Little Pieces&lt;/a&gt;, by James Frey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Million-Miles-Thousand-Years-Learned/dp/1400202981/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363501407&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=a+million+miles+in+a+thousand+years"&gt;A Million Miles in a Thousand Years&lt;/a&gt;, by Donald Miller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/White-Fang-Dover-Thrift-Editions/dp/048626968X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503564&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=white+fang"&gt;White Fang&lt;/a&gt;, by Jack London&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Call-Wild-Jack-London/dp/1613823495/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363503580&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=call+of+the+wild"&gt;The Call of the Wild&lt;/a&gt;, by Jack London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/FOEwyBaMXEA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.tedgonder.com/books-that-have-changed-my-life</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tedgonder,2012:Post/quotes-that-have-changed-my-life</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T23:34:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T23:34:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/fXW3U2V4-ZM/quotes-that-have-changed-my-life" />
    <author>
      <name>Ted Gonder</name>
      <uri>http://blog.tedgonder.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Quotes that Have Changed My Life</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you follow me on Facebook, Twitter, or Linkedin, you know I&amp;#39;m always posting quotes. I&amp;#39;m a total quote junkie. It&amp;#39;s how I get through the day. Here are the ones I&amp;#39;ve printed out and taped to mirrors, written on my hands for inspiration on sad days, crammed into the front covers of Moleskines, and have memorized for opportune recitation. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you’re going through hell, keep going.” 
- Winston Churchill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It takes conviction and vulnerability to believe in something, and absolutely no balls to tear it down.&amp;rdquo; 
- Eileen Guo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is not the critic who counts: not the man who points out how the strong man stumbles or where the doer of deeds could have done better. The credit belongs to the man who is actually in the arena, whose face is marred by dust and sweat and blood, who strives valiantly, who errs and comes up short again and again, because there is no effort without error or shortcoming, but who knows the great enthusiasms, the great devotions, who spends himself for a worthy cause; who, at the best, knows, in the end, the triumph of high achievement, and who, at the worst, if he fails, at least he fails while daring greatly, so that his place shall never be with those cold and timid souls who knew neither victory nor defeat.&amp;rdquo;
- Theodore Roosevelt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The individual has always had to struggle to keep from being overwhelmed by the tribe. If you try it, you will be lonely often, and sometimes frightened. But no price is too high to pay for the privilege of owning yourself.” 
- Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All courses of action are risky, so prudence is not in avoiding danger (it&amp;#39;s possible), but calculating risk and acting decisively. Make mistakes of ambition and not mistakes of sloth. Develop the strength to do bold things, not the strength to suffer.&amp;rdquo; 
- Niccolo Machiavelli&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Commitment is what transforms a promise into reality. It is the words that speak boldly of your intentions. And the actions which speak louder than the words. It is making the time when there is none. Coming through time after time after time, year after year after year. Commitment is the stuff character is made of; the power to change the face of things. It is the daily triumph of integrity over skepticism.&amp;rdquo; 
- Abraham Lincoln&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My belief is in the blood and flesh as being wiser than the intellect. The body-unconscious is where life bubbles up in us. It is how we know that we are alive, alive to the depths of our soul and in touch somewhere with the vivid reaches of the cosmos.&amp;rdquo; 
- D. H. Lawrence”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To study the Way is to study the Self
To study the Self is to forget the Self
To Forget the Self is to be Awakened with All Things”
-Dogan, sixteenth-century Zen monk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Few are willing to brave the disapproval of their peers, the censure of their colleagues, the wrath of their society. Moral courage is a rarer commodity than bravery in battle or great intelligence. Yet it is the one essential, vital quality for those who seek to change a world that yields most painfully to change.” 
- Robert F. Kennedy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When you wake up in the morning, tell yourself: the people I deal with today will be meddling, ungrateful, arrogant, dishonest, jealous and surly. They are like this because they can&amp;#39;t tell good from evil. But I have seen the beauty of good, and the ugliness of evil, and have recognized that the wrongdoer has a nature related to my own - not of the same blood and birth, but the same mind, and possessing a share of the divine. And so none of them can hurt me. No one can implicate me in ugliness. Nor can I feel angry at my relative, or hate him. We were born to work together like feet, hands and eyes, like the two rows of teeth, upper and lower. To obstruct each other is unnatural. To feel anger at someone, to turn your back on him: these are unnatural.” 
- Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/fXW3U2V4-ZM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.tedgonder.com/quotes-that-have-changed-my-life</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:youssef,2012:Post/terrible-copywriting-on-applecom</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T21:49:53-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T21:49:53-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/PxHWHx-oiAQ/terrible-copywriting-on-applecom" />
    <author>
      <name>Youssef Sarhan</name>
      <uri>http://sefsar.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Terrible copywriting on Apple.com</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542929772910_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542929772910_raw.png" alt="Screen shot 2013-03-17 at 03.20.26.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple just updated their iPhone page with a &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/why-iphone/"&gt;Why iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; tab. Undoubtedly created to swoon any potential customers that may be debating between the recently announced Samsung Galaxy S4 and not-so-new iPhone 5. With examples, I plan to demonstrate where Apple could have improved their copywriting. Copywriting is an important but often neglected discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542931503052_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542931503052_raw.png" alt="opening_lead.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, beginning a sentence with &amp;#39;and&amp;#39; (a conjunction) is not recommended. This is because &amp;#39;and&amp;#39; is used to link or compare two points, separating them with a period can create an awkward cadence. However, perhaps in this case the line-break forgives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue here is about sentiment, &amp;#39;and&amp;#39; coming after &amp;#39;There&amp;#39;s iPhone&amp;#39; is like some sort of vague comparison with their competitors. The next 5 sentences confirm this, first by opening with a question, then an uncertain answer, then another sentence beginning with a conjunction, then two more awkward redundant sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They should have stopped at the headline, because the rest is junk. There is no need for the extra sentences, the phones and apps are enough at this point. In fact, had they left out the extra sentences it would have taken on an entirely new and better meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have ran with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s iPhone.&lt;br&gt;
Then there&amp;#39;s everything you can do with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if to suggest that just owning an iPhone is something special. This would have appropriately set the tone, and nicely segued the reader into more detailed information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542932091526_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542932091526_raw.png" alt="award.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up is some award that looks like a Jukebox that no one outside of the US has ever heard of before. It&amp;#39;s great that people think Apple has a nice product, but I really don&amp;#39;t care what these guys think of it. &amp;#39;J.D. Power and Associates&amp;#39; means nothing to me. It occupies no point of reference in my mind, and thus means nothing to me. Apple should know their audience. If anything, this brings in to question Apple&amp;#39;s judgement of what they value, or more importantly, what they think I value. This should be some footnote, if even. So far, I&amp;#39;ve no inclination to buy an iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542932709430_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542932709430_raw.png" alt="battery.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is simple. They are use the same word to describe a good thing and a bad thing. &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/9fgowvzfQ9U?t=3m18s"&gt;Great&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#39;s not smart, it&amp;#39;s not witty, it&amp;#39;s bad, it&amp;#39;s muddled. It doesn&amp;#39;t leave the right impression. Be clear. That&amp;#39;s all you have to do, ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/youssef_24542933544828_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_youssef_24542933544828_raw.png" alt="power.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, using the same word to describe a good thing and a bad thing. There&amp;#39;s no need for it. Just be clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a bunch of other things, but it&amp;#39;s late and I&amp;#39;m tired. Whoever wrote this copy probably shouldn&amp;#39;t write copy for Apple anymore. Finally, notice how there are no black iPhones featured on the entire page, they are all White. I wonder if there&amp;#39;s a strategic reason for that, probably not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/PxHWHx-oiAQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sefsar.com/terrible-copywriting-on-applecom</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:dalton,2012:Post/sine-waves</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T15:25:52-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T15:25:52-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/u5VGLEJhUoM/sine-waves" />
    <author>
      <name>Dalton Caldwell</name>
      <uri>http://daltoncaldwell.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Sine waves</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One thing I have noticed studying web traffic logs is that daily human behavior at scale resembles a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sine_wave"&gt;sine wave&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/dalton_24542448166944_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_dalton_24542448166944_raw.png" alt="Wave.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, my mind&amp;#39;s eye has constructed an image of the daily ebb and flow of web traffic resembling the ebb and flow of ocean tides. I&amp;#39;ve learned that code tends to break at the &amp;ldquo;high tide&amp;rdquo;, and the best time to do site maintenance is at &amp;ldquo;low tide&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why does human behavior at scale look like a sine wave? It&amp;#39;s because of our daily cycles of waking and sleeping. In other words, we have a 24 hour cycle because of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Circadian_rhythm"&gt;circadian rhythms&lt;/a&gt;, which occur because of the cycles of darkness and light caused by planetary movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And why do we have a tidal system? It&amp;#39;s largely caused by the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tide"&gt;gravitational pull of the moon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It only recently occurred to me that the unconscious link I felt between tides and web traffic wasn&amp;#39;t a lazy &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Folk_science"&gt;cognitive crutch&lt;/a&gt;, rather, they are both causally related to planetary movement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, this minor insight was a helpful reminder: everything is connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/u5VGLEJhUoM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://daltoncaldwell.com/sine-waves</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:lautenbach,2012:Post/the-second-screen-obsession</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T08:30:22-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T08:30:22-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/mIfCDEzBoA0/the-second-screen-obsession" />
    <author>
      <name>Bradley Lautenbach</name>
      <uri>http://blog.bradleylautenbach.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The second screen obsession</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hollywood has grown fixated on the second screen. The &amp;ldquo;second screen&amp;rdquo; refers to the other thing we&amp;#39;re paying attention to while watching television or movies &amp;ndash; this could be a phone, tablet, or computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The industry fixates on the second screen because it feels threatened, and rightly so. In an era of alt-tab attention spans, fewer people are coming to long-form content by traditional means if they are coming at all. Between the actual dollars, and the perceived mental commitment, the cost of consuming content that is longer than your regular cat video on YouTube is not negligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, over the last 30+ years, as distribution channels have expanded (the movie multiplex, the 500+ cable television channels), quantity of content has increased while quality of content has decreased. Fortunately for Hollywood, this bad content didn&amp;#39;t have much to compete with in order to capture an audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the late 1990s, we saw wide-spread consumer adoption of the Internet. And the rise of file sharing. And the slow-and-then-fast disruption of the recorded music industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hollywood watched this happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came broadband. And suddenly it was easy to share and stream the larger video files that dialup couldn&amp;#39;t support. And Hollywood started to worry, mostly, and incorrectly, about piracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came Facebook. And suddenly there was a whole new type of content that was, in many cases, far more compelling than Hollywood&amp;#39;s. This content is always fresh, and, most importantly, it is free. This is social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the iPhone. And suddenly consumers could take this new stream of social content with them wherever they went - including the couch and the movie theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now we have arrived at the present model of consumer behavior where viewers are watching Hulu in one tab while they&amp;#39;re Facebooking in another, they&amp;#39;re playing Angry Birds on the couch while they&amp;#39;ve got ESPN on on the television, and they&amp;#39;re texting each other while they&amp;#39;re in the movie theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, bizarrely, Hollywood&amp;#39;s reaction to this is: LET US OWN THIS NEW SCREEN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus is born the &amp;ldquo;innovation group&amp;rdquo; at BigMediaCo. Thus do ex-producers decide to launch startups to &amp;ldquo;capture the second screen experience.&amp;rdquo; Thus does an entire industry begin to wonder if this Silicon Valley place might become &amp;ldquo;a thing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every few weeks, I get pitched a second screen opportunity, mostly by people who are content creators in Hollywood. Most of these businesses provide access to bonus content related to the first-screen experience, allow viewers to socialize with other people who are also consuming the first-screen experience, or, most commonly, create new revenue streams related to the first-screen experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;#39;s started to make me wonder&amp;hellip; are we stupid?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job of Hollywood is to create content (read: tell a story) that so delights an audience that the audience is willing to pay to consume this content. Why is Hollywood spending any time creating experiences to further distract the audience? Rather than fixate on the shiny new thing, shouldn&amp;#39;t Hollywood be doubling down on finding and telling incredible stories? Wouldn&amp;#39;t we put our second screens down in a heartbeat if we were actually being delighted by the content on the first screen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media has made it nearly impossible to recoup the investment in bad content. Mediocre opening weekends of a bad movie thanks to a big marketing spend are no longer possible. Twitter kills a bad movie after the first few screenings on Friday. But content is still king. And good content spreads itself. Social media has also spawned a whole new consumer behavior: Incredible television can now be discovered and binge-viewed season-by-season online. (see: Downton Abbey).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s pause. Let&amp;#39;s not take our eye off the ball. Let&amp;#39;s not pretend that the second screen is going to solve some underlying structural problems in the entertainment industry. Let&amp;#39;s instead be confident that we can tell wonderful stories, delight our audiences, and that in return our audiences will reward us with dollars and, more importantly, their undivided attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. .. .. ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are rare cases where the &amp;ldquo;second screen&amp;rdquo; becomes an innvoative part of telling the story, for one example, check out the movie, &lt;a href="http://www.fastcocreate.com/1682579/the-second-screen-comes-to-the-movies-with-app-enhanced-film-app"&gt;&amp;ldquo;App.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/mIfCDEzBoA0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.bradleylautenbach.com/the-second-screen-obsession</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/the-wrong-time-and-place-why-wii-was-nintendos-biggest-failure</id>
    <published>2013-03-16T08:22:08-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T08:22:08-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/yguc_smXiIA/the-wrong-time-and-place-why-wii-was-nintendos-biggest-failure" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The Wrong Time And Place: Why Wii Was Nintendo's Biggest Failure</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s curious the products that swing between highs and lows. Some have so much initial success that competitors race to rip it off. While other products are so disregarded at first, only to come back big later. It&amp;#39;s funny how timing can lead to disingenuous results, catapulting a company off course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Nintendo reporting such terrible sales of the Wii U in January and February, you can&amp;#39;t help but wonder if the Wii really scratched the average person&amp;#39;s itch for gaming or if it hit the market at just the right time. Nintendo stated early on that the Wii was a blue ocean move, meaning, with this product they were hanging a hard left and sailing to a place where motion control was king and there weren&amp;#39;t any sharks for miles. Everything about the Wii &amp;ndash; including its name &amp;ndash; was a bold move when the company first announced the console, and it paid off. You could barely get your hands on one for months and months after it was released, by all accounts the Wii was a blockbuster hit. At the time you&amp;#39;d be hard pressed to find someone calling it a failure, even looking back, few would use that word to describe the iconic white box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To continue the movie metaphors, of course Nintendo was going to follow up with a sequel rather than a completely new franchise, but they shouldn&amp;#39;t have. The company let past success dictate future moves rather than fully assessing the market they would be releasing a new product into. Obviously Nintendo saw tablets and similar devices coming or they would&amp;#39;t have put a massive one at the center of their gaming experience. The fault was that they desperately wanted to recreate the Wii&amp;#39;s success, rather than pull another blue ocean move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bolder move than the Wii U would have been to completely flip the tables and infiltrate the cellphone gaming market. Partnering with Apple or Samsung, or both, they could have had the upper hand to dictate lucrative terms and potentially get their franchise games onto every handset being sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who says that once you&amp;#39;re a hardware company you have to always stay a hardware company? Who says that you can&amp;#39;t switch back and forth over time as the circumstances arise. It&amp;#39;s still early for Mircosoft as a computer manufacture, but they needed to &amp;ldquo;grease&amp;rdquo; the windows tablet market and so they&amp;#39;re building the Surface. Barnes and Noble needed a compelling way to transition into the digital age and the Nook was born. Microsoft won&amp;#39;t necessarily always be a computer hardware company from here on out. If OEMs can build compelling devices and push the sales of Microsoft&amp;#39;s software, I have no doubt they&amp;#39;ll exit that hardware business. The better follow up to the Wii would have been if Nintendo transitioned itself into more of a software company willing to become ubiquitous on different platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;#39;s the desire for official Nintendo games to come to iOS and Android that&amp;#39;s coloring my opinions, but it seems like the writing is on the wall for some form of mobile gaming to eventually and completely push consoles to the side. At that time, software will be all Nintendo has left to cling to and they&amp;#39;ll be forced to make choices that aren&amp;#39;t their own, on terms that aren&amp;#39;t as favorable as once could have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake, the Wii was a big deal, so big in fact that it likely clouded Nintendo&amp;#39;s judgement on their future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/yguc_smXiIA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/the-wrong-time-and-place-why-wii-was-nintendos-biggest-failure</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:sash,2012:Post/what-its-like-to-die</id>
    <published>2013-03-15T10:27:54-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T10:27:54-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/KYMxPDgEGiM/what-its-like-to-die" />
    <author>
      <name>Sash MacKinnon</name>
      <uri>http://sashmackinnon.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>What it's like to die</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Six months ago, I died. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no recollection of the event, but I&amp;#39;ve heard the story retold so many times that I may as well have seen it all. I was at the gym in my apartment complex with my roommate, Sam. I was running on the treadmill when I turned and told him I was going to faint. I collapsed and fell onto the still-moving belt, which tore the skin off my knee and pushed me onto the floor. Sam was shocked. He called for help. A personal trainer and her client ran over, called an ambulance, and assisted Sam in giving me CPR while my body slowly drained of color. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My heart had gone into ventricular fibrillation. &amp;ldquo;Vfib&amp;rdquo;, as I heard numerous doctors call it, is an type of arrhythmia&amp;ndash;a series of irregular electrical signals in the ventricle chamber of the heart. Instead of beating normally, the walls quiver erratically, like they&amp;#39;re having a seizure . The heart quickly becomes unable to pump blood to other organs. I had suffered from what is officially, and somewhat morbidly, termed &amp;ldquo;Sudden Cardiac Death&amp;rdquo;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paramedics arrived and walked slowly down the length of the pool to the gym. This was procedure, they later told me; they didn&amp;#39;t want to run and cause alarm. When they reached me, they defibrillated my heart  by strapping patches to my abdomen and running a strong electrical current through my body. I was told that after the first administration my heart had remained in arrhythmia. After the second, it started beating regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those 4 minutes and 30 seconds, I was clinically dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next two days in a coma while the doctors cooled by body to 32 degrees in order to avoid brain damage. During this time I developed a pulmonary embolism and pneumonia. Whenever I visit a doctor now they are always surprised&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;each of those alone could have killed you, it&amp;#39;s a miracle you survived all three!&amp;rdquo; I survived by sitting through hours of MRIs with oxygen in my nose, three IV&amp;#39;s in my arm and ten pills a day for weeks. Sam and my two mothers, Laurie and Kerrie, rarely left my side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stories you hear about people dying usually end with tunnels, lights, flashbacks, God, and big epiphanies. That isn&amp;#39;t what happened to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finally regaining enough consciousness to understand my situation, I sat for hours staring at the hospital walls. I didn&amp;#39;t have any life changing realizations. I wasn&amp;#39;t regretful. In fact, I couldn&amp;#39;t think of anything in my life I wanted to change at all. Being trapped alone in that sterile room with wires hanging off my chest only made me think about everything in my life I wanted back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people I tell this story to think I&amp;#39;m unlucky because I had a cardiac arrest at 21 years old. But I don&amp;#39;t think so. Only five percent of people who suffer ventricular fibrillation out of the hospital survive. Of those that do survive, more than half of them have brain damage. That means only two and a half percent fully recover. Not only did I fully recover, but I did so in the company of the people closest to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is one lesson I took away from the experience, it is not to &amp;ldquo;live life to the fullest&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;have no regrets&amp;rdquo;. It is to feel lucky. Feeling lucky means you are appreciating the things in your life that sometimes go unnoticed. It means you are achieving more than think you deserve. Feeling lucky requires a certain humility we often lose sight of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it took losing everything to remember how lucky I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/KYMxPDgEGiM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sashmackinnon.com/what-its-like-to-die</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/outsourcing</id>
    <published>2013-03-15T08:19:47-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T08:19:47-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/f_m-LPNaVbA/outsourcing" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>A Startup's Guide to Outsourcing</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24540499571202_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24540499571202_raw.jpg" alt="barn raising.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the life of a startup, the question of outsourcing can arise frequently whether for PR, marketing, product design, sales or engineering. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outsourcing can be very attractive: consultants bring new points of view, relevant experience and (potentially) immediate results. Of course, consultants charge high fees and after their contract expires they leave with their knowledge and insights in tow. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founders may be challenged when deciding when and what to outsource. To simplify the decision, reflect on your startup&amp;#39;s key competencies needed to win your market. Like people, startups must focus on a few key skills to be successful. &lt;a href="http://tomtunguz.com/exploiting-your-startups-strength"&gt;Typically, startups win share by focusing on their strength: product design, sales effectiveness, marketing deft or technology advantages.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startups never should outsource their main advantage or the skill required to win in the market. If a team of founders believes product design will revolutionize mobile social networking, the team would blunder to outsource that design. Instead, the startup must cultivate a team to master that discipline. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other terrible candidates for outsourcing include long term projects without clear success metrics. The high churn rates of the PR industry reflect this reality. Most PR firms strive to win business, work diligently for a few quarters and then wane as ideas for stories become exhausted and new clients arrive. In my experience, hiring PR firms for particular launches and events works well. Otherwise, anointing an internal storyteller and empowering that person to achieve long term goals achieves success more reliably and at less cost. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startups should leverage consultants for narrowly defined, non-core initiatives when developing an expertise isn&amp;#39;t valuable to the business. For example, AirBnB didn&amp;#39;t need to build an internal team of cameramen to photograph the insides of homes all over the world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consultants offer tremendous leverage to a business and work best when tasked with ancillary, commodity services not required by a startup to win their market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your lessons from outsourcing? &lt;a href="http://branch.com/b/what-are-your-lessons-from-outsourcing-at-a-startup/invite_link/ThU0gpEEdAb53g"&gt;Join the conversation on Branch.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/f_m-LPNaVbA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/outsourcing</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:adii,2012:Post/dont-compete-on-features</id>
    <published>2013-03-15T02:09:07-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T02:09:07-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/qgnlxr9fJwU/dont-compete-on-features" />
    <author>
      <name>Adii Pienaar</name>
      <uri>http://adii.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Don't Compete On Features</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had quite a few &lt;a href="https://clarity.fm/#/adii"&gt;Clarity calls&lt;/a&gt; this past week with entrepreneurs asking for advice on how they should go about building &amp;amp; branding their new startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My best advice at the moment: &lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;#39;t try compete on features.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most markets that you can enter right now, are already quite saturated and you&amp;#39;re likely to face existing competition. Due to the very low barrier to entry to build a new SaaS / web / mobile app, you&amp;#39;ll also find that the competition&amp;#39;s offering is mostly the same as your solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that there&amp;#39;s simply no competitive advantage in trying to &lt;em&gt;out-feature&lt;/em&gt; your competitors and such a strategy is very unlikely to get you the traction you need to build a sustainable business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead here&amp;#39;s two alternatives to build a competitive advantage for your startup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Branding.&lt;/strong&gt; Tom Tunguz rightly says that &lt;a href="http://tomtunguz.com/branding"&gt;branding is the next essential startup competency&lt;/a&gt;. In a crowded space, it&amp;#39;s important to stand out and doing so why your branding is the lowest hanging fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Customer Service / Experience.&lt;/strong&gt; Delivering the most awesome experience imaginable to your customers will a) make them loyal to you; and b) make them tell their friends. This is a competitive advantage that you can leverage to grab market share away from your competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve applied both of these strategies at WooThemes to great success; especially considering that all of our code is open source and freely available elsewhere. Our 400 000+ customers however keeps coming back to us, because they know (due to our branding / reputation) that we&amp;#39;re awesome at supporting our products (delivering an awesome experience).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/qgnlxr9fJwU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://adii.me/dont-compete-on-features</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:francis,2012:Post/to-think-like-midas</id>
    <published>2013-03-15T02:00:32-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T02:00:32-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/xqvCM5fT6xQ/to-think-like-midas" />
    <author>
      <name>Francis Pedraza</name>
      <uri>http://francispedraza.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>To think like Midas</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to Greek myth, the god Dionysus gave Midas, a king of ancient Phrygia in the 8th century, the power of turning everything he touched into gold. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year, Forbes publishes a list of top technology investors called the &lt;a href="http://www.forbes.com/lists/midas/2012/midas-list-top-tech-investors.html"&gt;Midas list&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also would like to borrow the metaphor by calling the superhuman we imagined in the last post, “&lt;a href="http://francispedraza.com/who-then-can-see-the-future"&gt;Who, then, can see the future?&lt;/a&gt;”, Midas. If an investor had the ability to see the future, he would indeed be like Midas, every bet he would make would turn into gold. Within just the first year of business, he would have established a reputation so formidable that if he opened a fund, almost regardless of the terms, he would have a line of LPs wrapped around the building with checks in hand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where am I going with this? Why do I entertain these fantasies?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fiction’s not for babies, y’all. There’s just something in a myth&amp;hellip; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To return to the thread of my argument, I’m interested in learning how to think intelligently about the future. In other words, I would like to think like Midas. Great entrepreneurs think like investors, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who, then, can glimpse the future, if not Midas? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mind trained to study the past. The past is full of clues. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For it was once the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Of Great Men &amp;amp; Marxists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The disciplines of philosophy and history have an intimate relationship. If, in the &lt;a href="http://francispedraza.com/the-smallest-market-is-about-to-become-the-largest-market"&gt;market to come&lt;/a&gt;, philosophers are to be kings, then historians are to be queens. When it comes to the philosophy of history, there are two schools of thought: the “marxist” school and the “Great Man” school. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Marxist” historians, it’s worth noting, aren’t necessarily marxists, but they share with them a historical point of view: the vast majority of things that happen in society (and indeed, in the universe) are beyond the control of any one individual. Individuals are rounding errors in the grand scheme of things. What truly matters are large impersonal forces like capital structures, class movements, information flows, technological progress and the cultural evolution of ideas (Hegel’s &lt;em&gt;zeitgeists&lt;/em&gt;). As a result, they tend to think of long-run outcomes as fairly determinist. There is a certain inevitability to the waves that crash with the tides of time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the “Great Man” school fills its pages with the stories of the likes of Julius Caesar, Napoleon Bonaparte, George Washington or Steve Jobs. Remarkable individuals do not resign to fate, they hammer their destiny into stone through brute force of will. Like Achilles, they seek immortality through their deeds, or like Martin Luther King, they rally their fellow men behind a beatific vision. To understand history, you must understand the characters in the story, and these are heroes and villains of ambition, cunning and genius. History does not happen to them, they happen to history. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s imagine these two schools of thought expressed as investment strategies. The marxists, with a little irony, would invest in trends. The “great man” historians, would invest, (wait for it), in great men - in promising individuals. They would pride themselves as great judges of character and talent.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which strategy would perform better against the Midas index? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Trends and Megatrends&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are trends, and then there are megatrends. At any given point in time, there are many, many trends in the world. Usually, though, there are just a few megatrends. The difference is temporal and structural. What I mean by that is: a trend may come and go, and if it has a lasting effect, it is residual or gradual or incremental to what was already there before, but a megatrend, on the other hand, comes and completely alters the landscape, things change and don’t go back to normal, and the new normal is structurally different. Think of them like waves and tsunamis. Waves can crash on a beach for millennia. While the coastline will change, it will change slowly. If a tsunami comes, it alters all in its path. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, there are megatrends reshaping our world. The problem is we don’t have the historical perspective to see them. To use another metaphor: we can’t see the forest through the trees. Take, for example, the last ten years. There has been revolution after revolution in hardware and software, yet, “what’s next?” is the ever elusive question. That’s what Midas could see, but we can’t. Midas only bets on megatrends, while we run around chasing trends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Resolving the Paradox&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s truth in the paradox, as Kierkegaard might say, between the Marxists and the Great Men. The Marxists have a point. There are trends and megatrends shaping our world, and compared to them, individuals have very little agency. We are just a part of these broader movements, which loom powerful, impersonal, and beyond our control. Yet, despite that, time and again, it seems that certain individuals have a disproportionate impact on events. How do they do it? To resolve the paradox, let’s study the interplay between some great men and the trends of their day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would the Republic have fallen without Caesar? There’s reasons suggesting that it would. Through the class struggles between patricians and plebeians, so many checks and balances had emerged that the political system had become dysfunctional, and nobody could get anything done except in a crisis. Already the thread of culture had began, in the amphitheaters that were the precursors to the Colosseum, that taught Rome to celebrate the values of the victor in war. If might makes right, then the successful generals, who had in so short a time had amassed an empire sprawling in every direction, had a sympathetic audience in the capitol - and none had been more successful than the champion of the Gallic campaigns, Julius Caesar. If to the victor go the spoils, then Caesar had spoils in plenty: autonomy and sovereignty as the governor of the newly conquered Gallic provinces, he was entitled to a large income. Finding himself with legions, wealth and popularity, he looked to Rome. Perhaps before he looked to Rome, Pompey and the Senate looked to him, and trembled. His power had made him a threat to their power, and they ordered him to lay down his military command. Which he disobeyed by crossing the Rubicon and taking control of the city and its politics, becoming de-facto dictator, and ending, except in name, the Republic. While his remaining days were short, they were long enough to sketch the blueprint for a new order, which would survive even his assassination. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this story you have all the elements of a classic Marxist explanation: class struggles, cultural evolution, a structural imbalance of power. It’s not hard to weave a narrative that explains the fall of the Republic in such a way that Caesar is just an incidental detail, and that a similar figure would have emerged sooner or later, precipitating a similar chain of events. Perhaps that’s right. But, what was not inevitable, what was unexpected, if you will, is not that the Republic fell, but that the Empire emerged, and emerged the way it did, bearing Caesar’s image, with his idiosyncratic respect for the formalities of the Republic, with his populist flair. His way of doing business set broad parameters for the emperors to come. When they strayed too far from it, when they asserted their power too nakedly or circumvented process too blatantly, they upset a delicate precedent set by their namesake and found themselves tripping over the lingering remnants of old checks and balances. Here, the legacy of the Great Man. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Republic was going to fall. That was the megatrend. But the way it fell, and the nature of what emerged - that was the great man. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how the paradox is resolved: &lt;em&gt;there are megatrends and there are great men who see them coming, make them happen and shape them in the process.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Stamp on Events&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s briefly run through a few more examples. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would the 13 American colonies have split from Great Britain without one or more of the Founding Fathers? Perhaps - it was a megatrend. There were lots of deep structural reasons why that geopolitical relationship was strained, and so maybe it was inevitable that something would have happened, but what was not inevitable was the unique nature of the Revolution and the character and Constitution of the nation that it birthed. These the Great Men shaped. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would we still have laptops and tablets and smartphones today without Steve Jobs? Almost certainly. But in the late 70s, when the megatrend was little more than the rickety Homebrew Computer Club, he saw that these devices called computers, which filled huge rooms and could barely do basic math operations, would soon become very powerful and very small and take on a variety of form factors and would gobble up a myriad of functions currently occupied by analog devices, from clocks to scales to calendars to notepads and more, and that this would change everything. In his mind, it was inevitable - far before most people, even most people in the technology industry, caught on. Three, nearly four, decades later he was still riding the megatrend. Would we have had these devices? Yes. But we wouldn’t have had Apple, with its humanist values and care for design and craft and user experience. Steve was one of the Great Men of his generation who made the megatrend happen, and the unique expressions Apple gave to it were, and are, beautiful - and clearly, they have put their stamp on the future of technology, and shown us what is possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we have agency in a world where the vast majority of things are beyond our control? It’s an art, and it’s a little bit like surfing. The wave comes, the surfer sees it coming, paddles in its direction, and catches it in time for the energy of the wave to carry him along with it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s different about this, though, is that the great man can, at least to some extent, shape the megatrend, whereas the surfer cannot shape the wave. By making it happen, being its agent, if you will, he also gives it its unique expression - its name, it’s flavor, its voice. He fills in the details, and the details are important. They are the difference between the shape of a body and the statue of David. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wave, like the megatrend, is just a form of energy. Energy can be redirected: targeted, channeled, focused. There’s a physics to it. A wave is not a very malleable form of energy, and if you try moving it, it will probably move you. But there are ways of capturing tidal energy to create electricity, and with electricity, you can do lots of interesting things. It’s like Tai Chi, a form of martial arts which doesn’t focus on strikes, but on redirecting the energy of your opponent. Don’t resist, give away - like water. Very taoist. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Events may come and go, but individuals put their stamp on them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Touch to Gold&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the myth, to turn things into gold, Midas had to touch them; seeing them wasn’t enough. There’s a lesson there. Even an investor who can see the megatrend coming - who can, in a sense, glimpse the future - does not know exactly how it will manifest, and who will emerge to shape it, and what legacy it will leave in its wake. This is not the role of the investor, this is the role of the entrepreneur - the Great Man (or Woman) in the story - who not only sees the megatrend, but will actually touch it, every day, by building a company that will be its final expression. Yes, and thereafter, the company becomes the megatrend incarnate. It’s birth foretold, it’s destiny still unfolding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Predicting the future is as hard as it is valuable: extremely. In Greek mythology, even the Fates could only glimpse the future as through a fog. Sometimes, a few of the other gods, chiefly Apollo - or even, on rare occasion, a mortal - would receive a vision or a prophecy, which only the very gifted could interpret. Maybe even our imaginary “Midas” investor was a contradiction in terms - as the future cannot always be seen, even by the gods. And when it can, it is only the megatrends which rise above the fog. Only the outline and not the story. Only the block of stone and not the statue. Only the industry and not the company. The future cannot be seen, only glimpsed. Such that, even in the land of myth, if an investor could glimpse the future, he could not make money so easily, for glimpsing megatrends is not enough. You have to touch things to turn them into gold. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be continued&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.s. Apologies in advance to women. You can be Great too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/xqvCM5fT6xQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://francispedraza.com/to-think-like-midas</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:cadelllast,2012:Post/another-earth</id>
    <published>2013-03-14T20:19:15-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T20:19:15-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/O8-F_VgMdQU/another-earth" />
    <author>
      <name>Cadell Last</name>
      <uri>http://theratchet.ca</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Another Earth</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/a3jV3nJ.png" alt="Another Earth"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Astronomy is often referred to as the most intellectually humbling academic subject.  When you study astronomy you are confronted with scale, size, and time that is completely alien to the human mind.  We evolved to understand spatial scales of kilometers, not light-years, and to understand temporal scales of decades, not billions of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite this, it is always important to contextualize the human experience with astronomical knowledge.  And &lt;a href="http://www.theadvancedapes.com/theratchet/2012/12/22/top-science-discoveries-2012#"&gt;last year was a year of particularly insightful discoveries relevant to understanding our species place within the universe&lt;/a&gt;.  In 2012, astronomers discovered: a) the &lt;a href="http://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/kepler/news/smallest-exoplanets.html"&gt;first earth-sized planets&lt;/a&gt;, b) an &lt;a href="http://www.theadvancedapes.com/theratchet/2012/10/19/discovery-of-first-earth-sized-exoplanet-in-context"&gt;earth-sized planet in the nearest star system to earth&lt;/a&gt;, and c) the &lt;a href="http://news.sciencemag.org/sciencenow/2012/12/another-earth-just-12-light-year.html"&gt;first earth-sized planet within the habitable zone of its parents star&lt;/a&gt;.  These discoveries represent major milestones in the development of human knowledge.  They allow us to better-contextualize our planets relationship to the rest of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, these discoveries provide the first empirical evidence that earth-like planets are likely very common in the Milky Way galaxy (and probably in most other galaxies as well).  As soon as astronomers had the technology and methods developed to detect planets as small as earth, they started detecting them.  In the coming years I expect that we will become overwhelmed with headlines similar to: “another earth-like planet detected.”  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, a &lt;a href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2013/03/130312152047.htm"&gt;paper accepted yesterday&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Astrophysical Journal Letters&lt;/em&gt; provided a statistical analysis indicating that we should find some of those earth-like planets in our cosmic neighbourhood.  Ravi Kopparapu, lead author of the study claims: “we now estimate that if we were to look at 10 of the nearest small stars we would find about four potentially habitable planets, give or take.  That is a conservation estimate.”  Since there are eight M-stars (small stars) within 10 light-years of Earth, we should conservatively expect to find three Earth-sized planets in the habitable zones of their parent star.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, these estimates are very surprising.  Last decade we had no data on likely frequency of earth-like planets and relatively little data on frequency of exoplanets.  I was someone who thought exoplanets would be very common (which they are), but I thought earth-like planets would be relatively rare.  But it looks like that guess was off.  And if current estimates are accurate, and there are three Earth-like planets within 10 light-years of Earth, we should expect some BIG discoveries in the next two decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?  Because of the launch of the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Webb_Space_Telescope"&gt;James Webb Space Telescope&lt;/a&gt; (JWST).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/CANiQ6U.png" alt="JWST"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember a few years ago I went to a special presentation at McMaster University with my granddad and a friend about the first image ever recorded of an exoplanet.  I was excited, but I knew before the presentation started that what we were going to be observing would be a grainy pixel on a dark black screen.  Even our best telescopes are very poor at directly detecting exoplanets (which is why all exoplanet discoveries are made indirectly by either a) detecting the light they bend when they cross their parent star(s) or b) their gravitation effects on their parent star(s)).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when the JWST (successor to the Hubble Space Telescope) is launched in 2018, we will be able to directly detect exoplanets within 25 light-years of our star system.  This means that if Kopparapu and others are correct we are going to be able to see images of other earth-like planets in the 2020s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll let that thought sink in a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait!  It gets better.  The JWST can also determine the chemical composition of planets.  This means that not only will we get detailed images of other Earth-like planets soon but also we will likely be able to tell if those planets are home to life.  This is because life creates, transforms, and regulates the biosphere, radically altering a planets chemical composition.  Obviously we will not be able to identify species and get specific biological information, but we would likely be able to tell if they were carbon-based life forms that depended on oxygen and hydrogen for survival (for example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this doesn’t get you interested in scientific discovery and the future of human understanding, I don’t know what will.  The discoveries of the past two years in astronomy definitely help us conceptualize our place within the Milky Way.  However, these discoveries make me even more excited for what is just around the corner.  We are on the technological edge of making the most profound discoveries in the history of science: finding another earth.  And if you think about how much &lt;a href="http://theratchet.ca/technology-for-the-world"&gt;seeing a picture of our planet from space did to our understanding of life and our place within the universe&lt;/a&gt;, just wait until you see &lt;strong&gt;another Earth&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/O8-F_VgMdQU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://theratchet.ca/another-earth</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:francis,2012:Post/who-then-can-see-the-future</id>
    <published>2013-03-14T18:17:42-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T18:17:42-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/txg3owcCpeI/who-then-can-see-the-future" />
    <author>
      <name>Francis Pedraza</name>
      <uri>http://francispedraza.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Who, then, can see the future?</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s put a twist on a favorite childhood question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you were an investor (so financial profit was your primary motive)&lt;/em&gt;, and you could choose a superpower, which would you take? Would you scale walls, or fly, or see faraway objects? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the choice, I think you would be wise to answer: &lt;em&gt;D) None of the above.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my last post, “&lt;a href="http://francispedraza.com/the-philosopher-kings"&gt;The Philosopher Kings&lt;/a&gt;”, I argued that the single skill that would come to differentiate successful captains of industry - the superheroes, if you will - from their otherwise talented and competent peers - us mere mortals - would be their &lt;em&gt;ability to think intelligently about the future&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;D) None of the above&lt;/em&gt; then &lt;em&gt;E) Other. Fill in the _____.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s fill in the blank with &lt;em&gt;the ability to see the future&lt;/em&gt; and imagine, for a moment, what we could do. Even if you could only gaze ten seconds ahead, or, for that matter, even one second ahead, you could make an endless amount of money. That is, of course, until the SEC finds out and bans you from trading with such an unfair advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends who work at banks on Wall Street tell me that the most expensive real estate in the world is the server room next to the New York Stock Exchange’s routing system, because if you can transact orders even a fraction of a second faster than the rest of the market, you can provide liquidity with high frequency trading and make a spread by buying from the sellers and selling to the buyers. Even if the spread is tiny, if you can do it enough times and with enough volume, over time you can make a fortune. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you could gaze even farther ahead, say a week, or a month, you would have an even larger and more unfair advantage. You would choose the security - a stock, for example - which you knew was going to make the most dramatic move, and invest in it heavily, and with as much leverage the market would lend you, and then you’d make a fortune. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the days tell you their secrets, you become a trader on Wall Street. If the years tell you their secrets, you become a venture capitalist on Sand Hill Road. You provide every round of financing to the next Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an interesting thought experiment, because the more you think about it, the more you realize how little hard information about the future you need to possess to become rich, and that the more information you have, the fewer and more targeted and more leveraged your investments would become. You wouldn’t need to have a portfolio. Portfolios are for investment managers who know they’ll have some winners and some losers, so they spread the risk around. Instead, as a rational profit-seeking actor, you would put everything you’ve got (or as much as they’ll let you) into the biggest winners in a descending order until you have no capital left to invest. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder how long it would take someone with this superpower to amass the first trillion dollar fortune. Less than ten years, certainly. Perhaps less than five. Or maybe, even then, I underestimate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why entertain this fiction? Because it is a practical fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It makes my point for me. Information about the future is valuable. Infinitely more so than gold. The prophet is the goose that lays the golden eggs. Only a fool would butcher that goose for dinner. Only a fool would trade that information for bullion. Yet it’s so easy to be a fool, and fools there are in legion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if there were a way for us, mere mortals, to drink a drop of some magical elixir that gave us that superpower for just a moment? What if it were possible for you and I to glimpse the future, if only through the fog? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a way. It’s there for the taking. And are we fools not to seize at the opportunity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, by proxy: the ability to think intelligently about the future is as close as we can come to actually seeing the future, and that is certainly close enough to reap the benefits, although not close enough to be error-proof. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who, then, can glimpse the future? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Midas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be continued&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/txg3owcCpeI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://francispedraza.com/who-then-can-see-the-future</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:steveklabnik,2012:Post/deleuze-for-developers-will-smooth-spaceopen-source-suffice-to-save-us</id>
    <published>2013-03-14T10:43:09-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T10:43:09-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/H3NhZGnXdmI/deleuze-for-developers-will-smooth-spaceopen-source-suffice-to-save-us" />
    <author>
      <name>Steve Klabnik</name>
      <uri>http://words.steveklabnik.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Deleuze for Developers: will {Smooth space,Open Source} suffice to save us?</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you truly want to understand technology today, then you should at least be familiar with the philosophy of Gilles Deleuze. Unfortunately for technologists, Deleuze is rooted firmly in a philosophical tradition and a writing style that they probably find opaque. In this blog series, I plan on explaining Deleuze’s philosophy in terms that programmers can understand. This is the third in the series. You can find the first &lt;a href="/deleuze-for-developers-assemblages"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deleuze and Guattari employ the notion of &amp;#39;smooth space&amp;#39; quite a bit in &lt;em&gt;A Thousand Plateaus&lt;/em&gt;. I saw this quote about it the other day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;never believe that a smooth space will suffice to save us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve recently been giving a lot of thought to &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cultural_hegemony"&gt;&amp;#39;cultural hegemony&amp;#39;&lt;/a&gt;
and its applicability to the web, specifically along the lines of
Google. Basically, cultural hegemony is the idea that you don&amp;#39;t just
have dominance through laws or economics, but through culture. So, for
example, Google submitted SPDY to become HTTP 2.0: it&amp;#39;s going through
the standards process, it&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;open,&amp;#39; but it also gives Google a lot of
cultural leverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;#39;s this connection there between smooth space and open source, and the battle between the Nomads and the State Apparatus. We&amp;#39;ll cover that second bit in a while, but for now: what is &amp;#39;smooth space&amp;#39;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The spatial metaphor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to understand about these concepts is that Deleuze and
Guattari is (I think of them as a singular entity&amp;hellip;) a big fan of
spatial metaphors. Essentially, we can project our problem domain onto
a 2 or 3 (or more) dimensional space, and then use tools to analyze
that space. I was first introduced to this technique by Manuel de
Landa, who has a great lecture called &amp;ldquo;Deleuze and the use of the
genetic algorithm in archetecture&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=50-d_J0hKz0"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;)(&lt;a href="http://www.cddc.vt.edu/host/delanda/pages/algorithm.htm"&gt;text&lt;/a&gt;). A quick rundown:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;#39;s talk about the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eight_queens_puzzle"&gt;N queens problem&lt;/a&gt;. We have a chess board
with one space, and we place one queen on it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(warning, lots of ASCII (+ unicode) art to follow)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.-.
|♕|
.-.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This board is legal. It&amp;#39;s a solution to the &amp;#39;1 queen problem&amp;#39;: one
queen, a 1x1 board. What about 2 queens? We have no solutions. (2 and
3 don&amp;#39;t. :/ All other natural numbers do.) First we place a queen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.---.
|♕| |
-----
| | |
.---.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; but there&amp;#39;s no legal place for the second one. Bummer. We can
determine that there&amp;#39;s no solution by using a simple brute force with
backtracking: place the queen in the upper right, then try to place
the second below it. That&amp;#39;s not legal, so we backtrack and place it on
the right. That&amp;#39;s not legal, so we backtrack and put it in the bottom
corner. Oh no! That didn&amp;#39;t work, so let&amp;#39;s move our first queen: now
it&amp;#39;s in the bottom right, and we try to place the second in the upper
right: fail! So we backtrack&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, this is a lot of steps for a small board. Once you get
up to a &amp;#39;real&amp;#39; chess board, there are 4,426,165,368 possible
placements, but only 92 solutions. A needle in a haystack! And we&amp;#39;re
using a lot of steps to determine if there&amp;#39;s even one possible
placement. We need something better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One answer is genetic algorithms. So we can take our board&amp;#39;s current
state and assign it a score. When we place a new queen, if it makes
our score better, we keep it, and if it doesn&amp;#39;t, we lose it. Now we&amp;#39;ve
taken our 2x2 board and projected it onto a 2-axis linear space.
Imagine a plot where queens are on the x axis and score is on the y
axis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                      .dAHAd.
                    .adAHHHAbn.
      .dAHAd.     .adAHHHHHHAbn.
    .adAHHHAbn.  .adAHHHHHHHHAbn.
   dHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHb
  dHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we want to keep going with our solution as long as it slopes up:
we&amp;#39;ve found that our answers are at the maximum of each curve. Yay
calculus! But here&amp;#39;s the thing: this curve only has two possible
maxima: we will have more. And it might not be in 2-d space, it might
be in 5-d space. And we can only &amp;#39;use math&amp;#39; to find the maximum if we
generate the &lt;em&gt;entire&lt;/em&gt; curve, which seems computationally out of our
reach. So how do we find the maximum without generating the whole
curve? Genetic algorithms!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such is &amp;#39;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simulated_annealing"&gt;simulated annealing&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#39; Without getting too into it,
let&amp;#39;s just say that there&amp;#39;s a &amp;#39;cooling factor&amp;#39; that controls how
tolerant we are of going back down a slope. So at first, we wildly go
all over the search space, but then, as we progress, we tighten up our
cooling factor, and we stop being so wild. Eventually, we&amp;#39;ll arrive at
a solution that&amp;#39;s very likely to be the true global maxima/minima.
Neat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Discrete vs. Continuous&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we know that the enemy is open to attack, and also know that our men are
in a condition to attack, but are unaware that the nature of the ground makes
fighting impracticable, we have still gone only halfway towards victory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sun Tzu, &amp;ldquo;the Art of War&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting feature of this particular projection is that it
transforms our problem from a discrete problem into a continuous one.
One great tactic for when you&amp;#39;re losing: change the battlefield. Our
genetic algorithm tool needs a continuous space to operate, but our
problem is that our chess board is discrete. What do I mean by this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discrete_space"&gt;discrete space&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; is one in which the points are separated from one
another in some way. As an example, &amp;#39;integers&amp;#39; form a discrete
topology: there&amp;#39;s a &amp;#39;gap&amp;#39; between 1, 2, 3, and 4. You can see this by
drawing a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Number_line"&gt;number line&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;--(-2)--(-1)--(0)--(1)--(2)--&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real numbers form a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuity_%28topology%29"&gt;continuous topology&lt;/a&gt; rather than a discrete
one, there is no space between them. A &amp;#39;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Real_line"&gt;real line&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;-------------------------&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &amp;#39;scoring&amp;#39; mechanism allows us to change the battlefield, it forms
a function (isomorphism) to convert our discrete topology into a
continuous one. We can now bring our continuous tooling to bear on a
problem that was previously inaccessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Striated vs Smooth Space&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Military tactics are like unto water; for water in its natural course runs
away from high places and hastens downwards. So in war, the way is to avoid
what is strong and to strike at what is weak. Like water, taking the line of
least resistance. Water shapes its course according to the nature of the
ground over which it flows; the soldier works out his victory in relation to
the foe whom he is facing. Therefore, just as water retains no constant
shape, so in warfare there are no constant conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sun Tzu, &amp;ldquo;the Art of War&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay. NOW we&amp;#39;re ready to talk about smooth and striated space. They
have a number of names for this concept, and the one that&amp;#39;s most
direct from where we currently are is &amp;#39;Riemann space / Euclidean
space&amp;#39;. Smooth -&amp;gt; Riemann, Euclidean -&amp;gt; Striated. Another isomorphism.
;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euclidean_geometry"&gt;Euclidean geometry&lt;/a&gt; is pretty much the foundation of a metric ton of
our math. It&amp;#39;s what&amp;#39;s now known as algebra and geometry: lots of
integers, discrete spaces. This cube starts at (1,2,4) and has a side
length of 5. Cartesian coordinates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along comes &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Friedrich_Gauss"&gt;Gauss&lt;/a&gt;, who was incredibly intelligent. He had this
student named &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bernhard_Riemann"&gt;Riemann&lt;/a&gt;, who ran with the ideas Gauss had and
started &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Riemannian_geometry"&gt;Riemannian Geometry&lt;/a&gt;. Riemann&amp;#39;s geometry is
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-Euclidean_geometry"&gt;non-Euclidean&lt;/a&gt;: if Euclid described lines, Riemann described
curves. Einstein would later base the theory of relativity on
Riemannian geometry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, who cares? Well, think about it this way: You&amp;#39;re in a car, driving
down a straight road. It goes for miles, with no turns or other
streets. You&amp;#39;re operating in a smooth space: you can easily go from
one place to another. Now, someone comes along and puts up stop signs
every block. You must (for now) stop at these signs. Now you&amp;#39;re
operating in a striated space: your movement is restricted. Now you&amp;#39;re
moving from point to point on a line. It&amp;#39;s a very different
experience, and you also didn&amp;#39;t have anything to do with the stop
signs&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to D&amp;amp;G, &amp;#39;the state machine&amp;#39; (one instance of which is the
State) attempts to take space that is smooth and striate it. This is
often a means towards imperialism, as the striation happens through
quantification. Take, for example, the sea: a smooth space, you can
impose latitude and longitude on top of it, simultaneously quantifying
and striating it. This allows you to navigate the waters, and conquer
the sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also the position that many web startups take: &amp;#39;friendship&amp;#39;
was a smooth space before social networks came along. They quantified
and striated that space, turning &amp;ldquo;I have many friends&amp;rdquo; into &amp;ldquo;I have
200 friends and you have 100 friends.&amp;rdquo; This quantification allows for
commodification: now Facebook can sell ads. It&amp;#39;s also why startups
don&amp;#39;t often have a &amp;#39;business model&amp;#39; at first: they first need to
conquer and striate their space before they find the commodity.
Sometimes you just hit dirt and go bust, sometimes you find a more
precious commodity, then refine and sell it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#39;nomads&amp;#39; are entities which navigate and live in smooth spaces. Maybe
my twitter bio makes a bit more sense now. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How do you create a smooth space?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might remember Riemann from the &amp;#39;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Riemann_sum"&gt;Riemann sum&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39; in Calc I. The
brilliance of the Riemann sum is that it first striates, then
re-smooths the space. You start off first with a curve, and then
approximate the area under it by dividing it into a number of
evenly-sized bits. This first bit was necessary in a world without
calculus: we didn&amp;#39;t have the tooling or concepts to actually tackle
the real area, so we mapped that problem to one we did know how to
solve. As the number of bits goes up, and their width goes down, more
and more of the space under the curve is captured by our algorithm.
Finally, once we&amp;#39;re able to take that first step away from (striated)
algebra and move into (smooth) calculus, we&amp;#39;re able to move about on
the curve for reals. We&amp;#39;re back to smooth space again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This interplay between smooth and striated spaces often happens, and
there&amp;#39;s really no part of our world today that&amp;#39;s completely smooth or
entirely striated. D&amp;amp;G posit that the left should be attempting to
create as much smooth space as possible, and that capitalism is
constantly attempting to striate space. That said, smooth space is
necessary, but not sufficient: capitalism, in its hunger and lust for
acquisition and totalitization, has managed to navigate some smooth
spaces. I&amp;#39;ll just quote straight from &amp;#39;a thousand plateaus&amp;#39;, 492. It&amp;#39;s
a little hard, but this is getting long enough as is. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only does the user as such tend to be an employee, but capitalism
operates less on a quantity of labor than by a complex qualitative process
bringing into play modes of transportation, urban models, the media, the
entertainment industries, ways of perceiving and feeling &amp;ndash; every semiotic
system. It is though, at the outcome of the striation that capitalism was
able to carry to an unequaled point of perfection, circulating capital
necessarily recreated, reconstituted, a sort of smooths pace in which the
destiny of human beings is recast. &amp;hellip; at the level of world capitalism, a
new smooth space is produced in which capital reaches its &amp;#39;absolute&amp;#39; speed,
based on machinic components rather than the human component of labor. The
multinationals fabricate a kind of deterritorialized smooth space in which
points of occupation as well as poles of exchange become quite independent of
the classical paths to striation. .. the essential thing is instead the
distinction between striated capital and smooth capital, and the way in which
the former gives rise to the latter through complexes that cut across
territories and States, and even the different types of States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part about &amp;#39;users&amp;#39; is very much drawing a parallel to “If
you’re not paying for the product, you are the product.” When they
talk about the &amp;#39;speed&amp;#39; of capital, think of HFT. Multinational
corporations have managed to overcome the striation that a State has
imposed. McDonalds is only partially affected by US laws. They operate
&amp;#39;outside&amp;#39; of states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this way, simply being smooth will not suffice to save us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you liked this blog post, you may enjoy &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/philosophy-in-a-time-of-software"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Philosophy in a time of software&lt;/a&gt;, a moderated Google Group to discuss the intersection of philosophy and technology. This post started out as an email to that list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/H3NhZGnXdmI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://words.steveklabnik.com/deleuze-for-developers-will-smooth-spaceopen-source-suffice-to-save-us</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:hardaway,2012:Post/serendipitous-takeaways-from-sxsw</id>
    <published>2013-03-14T10:27:15-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T10:27:15-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/5VnUkntMDTo/serendipitous-takeaways-from-sxsw" />
    <author>
      <name>Francine Hardaway</name>
      <uri>http://francinesblog.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Serendipitous Takeaways from SXSW</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I agreed to go back to SXSW with some trepidation, because this is my seventh year, and the event has gotten larger and larger. At first, I knew or knew of most of the attendees, and going to Austin was a way to put faces to Twitter handles. Twitter, like me, was new to SXSW in 2007. Now, the conference has over 25,000 attendees at the interactive conference alone, and I&amp;#39;m lucky to find my old friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But something has happened for me this year: the serendipity of new friends. The three things I learned at SXSW had nothing to do with meeting people I already knew, but rather in learning about things I didn&amp;#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the WP Engine dinner the other night, I was sitting on the left of Werner Vogels, the CTO of Amazon, who was telling us about the lengths to which Amazon invests to make things convenient for its customers and the extent to which the company still reflects Jeff Bezos&amp;#39; vision. It was a behind the scenes look at a disruptive company&amp;#39;s vision and how it scales from category to category. Amazon has gradually changed the face of retailing, from books to luxury fashion to toilet paper and created almost instantaneous fulfillment through its free shipping service Prime. And now the company is facilitating e-publishing with Kindle and CreateSpace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way, it has revolutionized the away startups are brought to market through Amazon Web Services. I saw that when I attended the LeanStartup track. This year it was in a huge ballroom for a crowd in the thousands, because the cost of doing a software startup has been dramatically lowered by AWS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I found out that Ping Fu, whose memoir I had recently read, was speaking about the recent merger of her company, GeoMagic, with 3-D Systems, an early pioneer in 3-D printing. I didn&amp;#39;t understand much about 3-D printing, but now i do. Not only did I get to see Ping Fu&amp;#39;s own 3D printed shoes, but I saw people carrying around the lightweight portable 3-D Systems printer Ping says will go mainstream this year after nearly twenty years in development. It will usher in an era of mass-customization, or one-off manufacturing; in the near future your shoes will always fit perfectly, as Invisalign braces do now. Invisalign was one of the first GeoMagic customers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to race out of Ping&amp;#39;s presentation because my schedule told me Adam Curry, co-host of the amazing No Agenda show, was speaking in another venue. No Agenda, a completely donor-supported (no advertising) unbiased look at the news of the week, has become legendary in its iconoclasm over the fast five years. A scathing look at events covered by the mainstream media only as talking points, it is a profound new model for authentic journalism. Curry turned his back on a lucrative career on MTV to become a thought-provoking online podcaster, and the No Agenda Show now supports two families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is so much ainnovation showcased at SXSW. Perhaps the most mind-blowing thing I saw was an app called Augment, which takes augmented reality to the next commercial step by helping you take a photo of a piece of furniture and lay it on a background to get a 3-D view of how it will look in a room. It looks like CAD drawing, but it&amp;#39;s a free app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I&amp;#39;ll take away from this year: the value of investment in obsessive customer service; the mainstreaming of 3-D printing and its effect on manufacturing, and a promising new model for journalism. SXSW certainly augmented my reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/5VnUkntMDTo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://francinesblog.com/serendipitous-takeaways-from-sxsw</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:daslee,2012:Post/its-business-man</id>
    <published>2013-03-14T08:59:29-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T08:59:29-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/tPiOIwQhuCE/its-business-man" />
    <author>
      <name>David Lee</name>
      <uri>http://daslee.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>It's business, man</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a depressing day for me. I&amp;#39;ve been a fan of the New England Patriots (and other Boston sports teams) for over 30 years. And I just can&amp;#39;t root for them anymore. [Endnote]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting aside the fact that no grown-ass man should be this depressed about  a sporting event, it&amp;#39;s a cold, hard reminder that professional sports is a business. It&amp;#39;s run by billionaires who happen to be (in most cases) die-hard sports fans. I&amp;#39;m pissed off at him and the ownership now, but Robert Kraft, the owner of the Patriots is &lt;a href="http://nesn.com/2013/01/robert-krafts-purchase-of-patriots-required-leap-of-faith-but-results-show-thinking-with-heart-sometimes-pays-off/"&gt;not only the best owner in all of sports but also a die-hard Patriots fan.&lt;/a&gt; His decision to buy the Patriots was a dumb business decision (at the time) driven by his inner sports fan. Every Patriots fan is grateful for what he did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve written and talked before about the parallels between engineers and athletes. Others have made the same points so I won&amp;#39;t rehash them here. I think it all starts from the basic idea that professional athletes and top engineers/founders all have a talent that can be learned by many but mastered by  few. There are some parts God-given talent, hard work and circumstances. But ultimately only very few the first part. The rest of us can only be fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vinod Khosla was quoted recently as saying (and I paraphrase) that &lt;a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/tomiogeron/2013/03/10/vinod-khosla-to-entrepreneurs-venture-capitalists-are-not-your-friends/"&gt;investors aren&amp;#39;t your friends&lt;/a&gt;. And I cannot agree more.  It sounds overly harsh and this wasn&amp;#39;t his point but they&amp;#39;re called &amp;ldquo;investors&amp;rdquo; for a reason - they have a job to make money. If they didn&amp;#39;t have that job, then they&amp;#39;d be &amp;ldquo;donors&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;patrons&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;sponsors.&amp;rdquo; They are not unlike Robert Kraft - a sports fan who is in the sports business. As an aside, I&amp;#39;m a huge believer in the saying that it&amp;#39;s better to make friends through business than doing business with friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a physics major but I&amp;#39;m no physicist. I have a graduate degree in engineering but I&amp;#39;m no engineer. I realized that in my mid-20&amp;#39;s and made the career switch. I wanted to be an advisor to people who were building companies using awe-inspiring technology.  I would be a fan. And the best part of my job (and most investors would agree 100%) is being a fan -  a spectator to unbelievably talented people create great things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After a few glasses of wine and sitting alone with Ron Conway one night, I asked him why he continues to work at his current pace. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;#39;re looking into the future!&amp;rdquo; he bellowed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But legally I am a fiduciary first. I signed a legal contract to be basically a legal custodian of other people&amp;#39;s money. I can be a fan and irrationally support our portfolio companies - but only to a limit. We at SV Angel say that we will &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; put the interests of the founders first. Ahead of investors&amp;#39;, corporate partners&amp;#39; and our limited partners&amp;#39;.  One part of this is based in the idea that they are the athletes and we are the fans. Without them, all the other stuff doesn&amp;#39;t exist. That&amp;#39;s the &amp;ldquo;feel-good&amp;rdquo; part. The reality is that we also do it because it&amp;#39;s our business model - not because we&amp;#39;re good guys. We do it in the same way that &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;#39;t be evil&amp;rdquo; is Google&amp;#39;s business model and &amp;ldquo;Putting customers first&amp;rdquo; is Amazon&amp;#39;s. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Endnote] The Patriots &lt;a href="http://espn.go.com/nfl/story/_/id/9048556/wes-welker-agrees-terms-denver-broncos"&gt;didn&amp;#39;t resign one of their top players Wes Welker&lt;/a&gt;. It was the right business move. But after seeing the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=wes+welker+hits&amp;amp;oq=wes+welker+hits&amp;amp;gs_l=youtube.3..0.926.3998.0.4121.15.9.0.6.6.0.186.734.8j1.9.0...0.0...1ac.1.RpA0sBQGpNQ"&gt;hits that he&amp;#39;s taken over the years&lt;/a&gt; and now knowing that &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/nfl/2013/01/10/junior-seau-brain-disease/1822603/"&gt;those hits probably have taken years off of his life&lt;/a&gt;, it doesn&amp;#39;t feel right in this instance that he&amp;#39;s not appreciated and paid for his past service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/tPiOIwQhuCE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://daslee.me/its-business-man</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/6-bands-that-pivoted-4-that-didnt</id>
    <published>2013-03-14T08:52:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T08:52:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/tLsEVxEZGm4/6-bands-that-pivoted-4-that-didnt" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>6 Bands That Pivoted, 4 That Didn't</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tegan &amp;amp; Sara&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;s last album &amp;ndash; The Con &amp;ndash; was an indie folk rock dream while this year&amp;#39;s model is full of 80&amp;#39;s pop. On &amp;#39;Heartthrob&amp;#39; you can literally see montage scenes play as the album starts with &amp;ldquo;Closer.&amp;rdquo; This change in style doesn&amp;#39;t appear to be anything other than the sisters exploring new territory, rather than chasing a fad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/9e9NSMY8QiQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If preppy-rock is a genre then &lt;strong&gt;Ra Ra Riot&lt;/strong&gt; mastered in on their 2010 album, &amp;#39;The Orchard&amp;#39;. 2013&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;Beta Love&amp;#39; yielded a different genre style though, one with a lot more beeps and boops. I would never accuse a band of changing their style to get in on a trend, but from a glance, it sort of seems like it. Still, the band did the songs justice and put out a great release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/oRo7Ed4yfvo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passion Pit&lt;/strong&gt; went the opposite way of most bands and actually used less computerized effects on the new album than the previous one. It didn&amp;#39;t hurt their career, but rather now appears to be the defining point, raising their popularity by leaps and bounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/na1OdO30Yp8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sleeping At Last&lt;/strong&gt; has silently reigned the last few years with appearances popping up all over, including on the Twilight soundtrack and more recently in SoulPancake&amp;#39;s Kid President &amp;#39;Pep Talk&amp;#39; video. Sleeping At Last pivoted after 2003&amp;#39;s major label release, &amp;#39;Ghosts&amp;#39;, to get to the mellow spot they&amp;#39;re currently at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Dfo2YMekN78" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Killers are one of the best examples of bands that successfully pivoted to a wildly different style. After going from &amp;#39;Hot Fuss&amp;#39; to &amp;#39;Sam&amp;#39;s Town&amp;#39; and bringing the fans along, the band felt permission to do any type of music they wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/gGdGFtwCNBE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hellogoodbye&lt;/strong&gt; rose up on the back of &amp;ldquo;Here In Your Arms&amp;rdquo; a semi electronic auto-tuned song from an album filled with similar tracks. Pivoting to a more rock based sound on &amp;#39;Would It Kill You?&amp;#39; and added plenty of ukulele. Expect their new album out this year to continue running from the auto-tune era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6-KQ1tp_qOQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Postal Service&lt;/strong&gt; - Just kidding, we know the music scene would have pivoted around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Those that didn&amp;#39;t pivoted and created side projects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Instead of using their existing famed band to promote a new style, these artists chose to use a new band/name to try something new.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon Foreman&lt;/strong&gt; has put out a handful of solo acoustic EPs and also formed Fiction Family with Sean Watkins of Nickel Creek fame. All the material obviously has a familiar tone given Foreman&amp;#39;s distinct voice and approach, but none of his side project material fits in Switchfoot&amp;#39;s wheelhouse and the choice to do solo work was probably the right one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/AEh2w1M8ZZY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it was Fall Out Boy&amp;#39;s hiatus that kept &lt;strong&gt;Patrick Stump&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;s dance/pop material out of the pop/punk group, or maybe it was another factor, but either way it was a good thing. Stump&amp;#39;s hit, &amp;ldquo;This City&amp;rdquo; blew up big and quick, only fall as equally as fast. Fall Out Boy is now, of course, back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/aGGIQQKKD0Y" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one knew about The Format and their dog problems, but &lt;strong&gt;Fun.&lt;/strong&gt; won a Grammy for best new group. The difference? Maybe timing, maybe big pop anthems, switching up members? I don&amp;#39;t think anyone will ever know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/irSF0OGDX5k" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Mxpx front man, Mike Herrera, is a touring maniac and when the other members other the long time pop/punk band needed some time off he was off starting a new country band called &lt;strong&gt;Tumbledown&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/gz7dtbDy9UE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/tLsEVxEZGm4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/6-bands-that-pivoted-4-that-didnt</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/google-reader</id>
    <published>2013-03-14T07:04:45-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T07:04:45-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/ljETQnhs9r4/google-reader" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Social Proof: The Most Formidable Force Driving Content</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24538861475118_raw.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24538861475118_raw.gif" alt="311296-keep-calm-and-save-google-reader.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world of socially curated news, there is no place for RSS. &lt;a href="http://tomasztunguz.com/2012/04/19/rss-is-dead-social-streams-have-killed-it/"&gt;I wrote last year:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social streams solve the problem most RSS readers faced: the inbox with 1000+ items to read and no way to sift through them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Socially curated news syndicated through social networks (Facebook, Twitter) and content networks (LinkedIn, Quibb, HackerNews)  solves the relevance problem that RSS never could address. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.quora.com/Google-Reader-Shut-Down-March-2013/Why-is-Google-killing-Google-Reader/answer/Brian-Shih"&gt;Brian Shih, former Google Reader PM, wrote an excellent, passionate post-mortem on the product on Quora&lt;/a&gt;, where he underscores the importance of the social forces at play on Google Reader. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the reason Google always wanted to pull the Reader team off to build these other social products was that the Reader team actually understood social &amp;hellip; But after switching the sharing features over to G+ (the so called &amp;ldquo;share-pocalypse&amp;rdquo;) along with the redesigned UI, my guess is that usage just started to fall - particularly around sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To succeed as a content producer or as a content consumption product, embracing and mastering social proof and sharing is critical. Ignore these forces at your peril. Google Reader wasn&amp;#39;t the first to fall at the hands of social distribution nor will it be the last. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless Google Reader is wholly reinvented with social proof and sharing at its core, any effort to extend Google Reader&amp;#39;s life is only a temporary stay of execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/ljETQnhs9r4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/google-reader</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:adii,2012:Post/doing-it-yourself</id>
    <published>2013-03-14T01:39:49-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T01:39:49-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/DB_vAlze8hU/doing-it-yourself" />
    <author>
      <name>Adii Pienaar</name>
      <uri>http://adii.me</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Doing It Yourself</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In business, you&amp;#39;ll often find references to risk &amp;amp; reward and how those two things are intertwined: &lt;em&gt;the greater the risk, the greater the (potential) reward.&lt;/em&gt; And vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, you&amp;#39;ll also find that doing something yourself is &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; more profitable compared to involving others. This extends to things like hiring a team or entering into a JV / partnership (the margins go down) to taking on co-founders or shareholders (the profit sharing - &lt;em&gt;relative percentage at least&lt;/em&gt; - goes down).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet many (most?) of us still involve others in our endeavours, because of the risks involved with doing it ourselves. Doing it yourself, involves quite a few potential &amp;ldquo;risks&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Success is dependent on yourself;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#39;s gonna be a lot of hard work; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your initial investment (and thus your exposure to the risk) is much higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All very reasonable considerations when thinking about the risks vs reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had a conversation with &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/hnshah"&gt;Hiten Shah&lt;/a&gt; about a new strategy I&amp;#39;ve been toying with and he asked me a very simple question: &lt;em&gt;What&amp;#39;s the real risk involved with the pursuit of the strategy?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My immediate answer would&amp;#39;ve been &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;#39;t want to lose the money if this doesn&amp;#39;t work out&amp;rdquo;. But then I remembered &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/today/post/article/20130304212600-1213-how-to-think-about-risk-when-investing-in-your-career"&gt;an article about risk&lt;/a&gt; that Reid Hoffman recently published. This line specifically stood out for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So we are all risk takers. But we are not all equally intelligent about how we do it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point here is that every single time that WooThemes has done something ourselves (without relying on a 3rd party) it&amp;#39;s been more profitable / rewarding / beneficial to us (as a founders, as a team and as a company).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all of these situations the &lt;em&gt;up-front risk&lt;/em&gt; (or perception thereof) delayed our decision to pull the trigger on something new and in some cases it put us into eternal limbo. When we stepped out of that state, put our necks out there and executed on a risky idea, it&amp;#39;s been well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just do it. &lt;em&gt;Yourself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/DB_vAlze8hU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://adii.me/doing-it-yourself</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jared,2012:Post/brevity-in-design</id>
    <published>2013-03-13T17:10:34-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-13T17:10:34-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/l_XJeCVwpvY/brevity-in-design" />
    <author>
      <name>Jared Erondu</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jarederondu.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Brevity in Design</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many articles have been written on the benefits in store for designers who write. I can testify that they&amp;#39;re endless. Over time, the line that separates writing from speaking, coding and design gradually fades away. Eventually, you realize that they&amp;#39;re simply different &lt;em&gt;forms&lt;/em&gt; of communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you execute any of these four actions, you&amp;#39;re conveying a message. A good writer, speaker, hacker, or designer is measured by how well they&amp;#39;re able to convey this message. There are many rulers that could be used for this measurement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality&lt;/strong&gt;: No grammatical errors? Good powerpoint? Clean code? Solid UI/UX?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value&lt;/strong&gt;: Worth writing? Worth saying? What value does it bring to the code? What value does it bring to the interface?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;/strong&gt;: How long will the article be applicable? How long will the speech carry weight? Is the code future-proof? Is the design future-proof?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;and Brevity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In writing, it&amp;#39;s the ability to impart an idea in a short amount of words. &lt;a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com"&gt;Seth Godin&amp;#39;s blog&lt;/a&gt; is a perfect example. Everyday, he delivers a rich piece of advice in what most blogs will consider a mere paragraph. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In speaking, it&amp;#39;s the ability to verbalize an idea in a short amount of time. One presenter may take two hours to deliver a lesson while another may take 20 minutes to deliver the same. The first will bore the audience to sleep, the other will likely keep their attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In coding, it&amp;#39;s the ability to identify what line of code will render the other ten useless and give the same effect. What may take a novice 60 strings of JS may take an experienced coder just 4. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;hellip;and in design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continue to shorten my articles, I&amp;#39;m also &amp;ldquo;shortening&amp;rdquo; my designs. And by that, I mean finding the best way to do something. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In design, brevity is finding the best way to perform an action in the fewest steps &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; losing efficiency or the message. And it requires building a visual hierarchy–understanding what the most important actions are for your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m currently working on &lt;a href="http://evomail.io"&gt;Evomail&lt;/a&gt;, an upcoming iOS mail client. So my most important actions are composing/replying, archiving/deleting, flagging, and switching between accounts. This is where drawers and gestures come in handy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#39;s most important now? Show that on top. What will be used infrequently? Show that later. How many steps are needed to access them–are they all necessary? Could removing this or adding that drop the action time by one step or second? These are the questions I ask myself when designing. I make my first design pass, then revisit later to &amp;ldquo;shorten.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;To be concise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not suggesting that we only look for the short route in doing things. Sometimes the long way is the best way. Rather, I&amp;#39;m suggesting we look for the most efficient and concise way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mastering brevity is an art of its own. It involves linguistics. In writing and speaking, it&amp;#39;s word choice. In coding, it&amp;#39;s the code languages. In design, it&amp;#39;s the many design languages, styles, and &lt;a href="http://blog.wells.ee/less-aesthetic-more-design"&gt;aesthetics&lt;/a&gt; (yes, flat and skeuomorphic). Then from there, it&amp;#39;s wit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/erondu"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/l_XJeCVwpvY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jarederondu.com/brevity-in-design</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/the-story-with-twitter-and-music</id>
    <published>2013-03-13T14:21:08-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-13T14:21:08-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/KD416MUzuAU/the-story-with-twitter-and-music" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The Story With Twitter And Music</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1035_3-57573859-94/twitter-acquires-we-are-hunted-readies-standalone-music-app/"&gt;Reports out of CNET today&lt;/a&gt; indicate that Twitter purchased music discovery site &lt;strong&gt;We Are Hunted&lt;/strong&gt; sometime last year with the idea of building their own music app. We Are Hunted is both a builder of music products and apps as well as a destination for discovering what music is currently being talked about online. Stepping back for a second, the obvious first question, why is Twitter so interested in music?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter&amp;#39;s first jump into 3rd party services was when they created their own image hosting service a few years back. Even then it just made sense that Twitter wanted control over a media format that has always been heavily traded on the service. Twitter&amp;#39;s recent venture into video with their Vine app also makes sense, but creating an app to discover music still leaves more than a few questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We Are Hunted is a data driven site. The service looks at what music people are talking about online by looking at blogs and different mediums, collects the data and then ranks rising artists. A Moneyball take on the music industry. Looking back over my interviews with We Are Hunted founder, Stephen Phillips, some of the pieces begin to align with why Twitter would want them, why Twitter wants music and the big picture for all these questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Twitter is getting into music, We Are Hunted was the right company to acquire. Twitter has data. They don&amp;#39;t have &lt;em&gt;as much&lt;/em&gt; personal data as say Facebook, but I&amp;#39;m willing to bet they have just as much media related data as Facebook. Twitter lends itself to recommending music, movies, books and other items. Putting that firehose of music data into We Are Hunted&amp;#39;s algorithms could be a powerful resource for creating a better Pandora. A music service run on the stream of all the users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pillips has stated before that We Are Hunted&amp;#39;s reason for existence is to help people find their next favorite artist, to be the best discovery service in the world. With the acquisition by Twitter, that now is an accomplishable goal. In early 2012, &lt;a href="http://www.hypebot.com/hypebot/2012/07/we-are-hunted-founder-on-spotify-app-music-discovery.html"&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; if Phillips felt any pressure from other discovery services, he said no. &amp;ldquo;Music discovery is not a zero sum game. People use a whole range of sites to discover new music. People’s needs and expectations of discovery services are as eclectic as their musical tastes. It is a huge, huge space, and no one service will ever satisfy it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Twitter is getting ready for an IPO, they could want different revenue sources &amp;ndash; beyond ads &amp;ndash; in the pipeline and music could be that first step. There are plenty of monetization aspects for music, but stretching your imagination, Twitter&amp;#39;s real interest in music could be pinned on the commerce aspect. Plenty of companies are currently experimenting with selling items on Twitter, which they then take a cut of the sales. Google has been more overt in their desire to control the wallet because it&amp;#39;s a lucrative business. If this is Twitter&amp;#39;s end game, it eventually puts them in direct competition with Google, Paypal, credit cards, and Square. Remember, Square founder Jack Dorsey is also a founder of Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s also the theory that Twitter just likes music and wants to offer people a good way to discover new artists. But with all the changes to the API and Twitter cutting off developers in unusual ways, it&amp;#39;s hard not to see those moves as them building to something pretty big. Something big like merchant services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though music is often thought of as a tired and old form of media compared to video, companies continue to fight for music dominance like its the key to bigger success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/KD416MUzuAU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/the-story-with-twitter-and-music</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/branding</id>
    <published>2013-03-13T08:16:12-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-03-13T08:16:12-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/QpFNFQ1axdY/branding" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Why Branding Is the Next Essential Startup Competency</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24537372621948_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24537372621948_raw.jpg" alt="Coca-Cola-728x409.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much is the most valuable brand in the world, Coca-Cola worth? &lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/most-valuable-brands-in-the-world-2012-10?op=1"&gt;$77.8B.&lt;/a&gt; That&amp;#39;s 45% of the company&amp;#39;s market cap. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often times, winners create advantages in a market through brands. These brands evoke emotions within consumers: feelings of trust (Visa), of aspiration (Nike), of adventure (RedBull). And if the brand is strong enough, it replaces the generic term: tissues/Kleenex, internet search/Google, glass cleaner/Windex. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Silicon Valley, we tend to believe that better products win markets. It&amp;#39;s atypical to overhear a conversation at Blue Bottle Coffee or at YCombinator about brand building - brand attributes, values, positioning. Instead, our exchanges focus more on technology and more recently, design. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But over the next several years, marketing, branding and positioning, all under-appreciated disciplines in the valley will become markedly more important. As barriers to entry continue to fall driven by cloud technologies, competition among startups will increase and the startups that reach their target customer bases with the best messaging, building the most effective brands, will win. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know storytelling will be the differentiator. Look at every commodity industry to see the value of branding. Nike makes running shoes. Kleenex manufactures tissues. But they each sell something else - they sell an idea. Nike sells excellence: &amp;ldquo;Just Do it.&amp;rdquo; Kleenex sells &amp;ldquo;taking care of family.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24537384208224_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24537384208224_raw.jpg" alt="kleenex.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s logical that cash conscious startups should limit their investment to measurable marketing tactics. But as startups scale and as technologies commodify faster and faster, branding building investments should become a key part of the marketing efforts of the business. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the brand may become half the value of the company and the true differentiator in the market place. That&amp;#39;s nothing to sneeze at. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which startups have the best branding? &lt;a href="http://branch.com/b/why-branding-is-the-next-essential-startup-competency"&gt;Join the conversation on this Branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/QpFNFQ1axdY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/branding</feedburner:origLink></entry>
</feed>
