<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xml:lang="en-US">
  <id>tag:svbtle.com,2012:/feed</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://svbtle.com" />
  
  <title>Svbtle Featured</title>
  <updated>2013-04-15T22:05:51-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Svbtle.com</name>
    <uri>http://svbtle.com</uri>
    <email>hello@svbtle.com</email>
  </author>
  <generator>Svbtle.com</generator>
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/svbtle" /><feedburner:info uri="svbtle" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>svbtle</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><entry>
    <id>tag:ben,2012:Post/thiel-fellowship-closing-ceremony-speech</id>
    <published>2013-04-15T22:05:51-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T22:05:51-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/9D1nj-ZeWg8/thiel-fellowship-closing-ceremony-speech" />
    <author>
      <name>Ben Yu</name>
      <uri>http://benyu.org</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Thiel Fellowship Closing Ceremony Speech</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have come to the conclusion that I suck at blogging on demand and that if I make myself write a post on Monday I will generally tend to wait until the last minute to write it. To counter this, I&amp;#39;m going to try writing every other day and only posting the best two pieces on Monday and Friday. If that still fails, I&amp;#39;ll try every day and Tynan can tell me &lt;a href="http://tynan.com/erryday"&gt;I told you so.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, in the meantime, as it&amp;#39;s midnight CST here on Monday, here&amp;#39;s the short semi-prepared speech I gave this weekend at the Thiel Fellowship Closing Ceremonies (we all gave a two minute quip about our two years).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of surprising things I learned as a Thiel Fellow, but one of the most striking is how quickly two years go by.  Most of my life’s seemed interminably slow, and when I accepted the fellowship two years seemed like forever. But here I am, two years later, and it feels like it’s gone by in the blink of an eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a few theories as for why that is.  One of them is that strangely enough, the fact that the Fellowship seems to have passed so quickly is an indication of just how much experience it managed to cram into two short years. Looking back, the entirety of the fellowship feels like one long day of building things, learning, and meeting incredible people. There was no time to realize that time was passing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In two years, I managed to fail at one startup, learn a ton of lessons, meet an amazing cofounder on an equally amazing trip to Antarctica organized by an also equally amazing mentor, discover, develop, and invent transdermal caffeine, patent transdermal caffeine, and am now in the process of building our new venture with the launch of our flagship product Sprayable Energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’ve learned a few things along the way. One is a simple one – perseverance and determination, along with experience, goes a long way.  Especially in startups, progress in the short term is incredibly difficult to measure, as it’s more often than not not linear or even sequential. One minute we might be on top of the world, and the next in a massive ditch. And a few minutes after that, we might be on top of the world again. So I’ve learned to not put so much weight on the short term and optimize for the long term, and we’ll see what happens in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another lesson was less apparent to me, and that’s that oak trees come from acorns. Richard Hamming gave a great talk called You and Your Research – in it, he noted that great work never came about as the result of trying for the great thing straight off – it always resulted from starting small, and planting the little seeds that ultimately grew into mighty oaks. So I guess what I’ve learned here again is to aim for the long term – I’m very impatient, but there’s no point in trying to build a skyscraper without first setting the foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I’d like to thank all my fellow fellows and everyone else in the network for being awesome friends and mentors and helping make this experience something I’ll never forget.  And I want to thank my family for always being right behind me, supporting me the entire way. And I’d like to say a word of encouragement to all the incoming fellows – I’m super excited to see what you all do, and we’ll all get there in the end :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/9D1nj-ZeWg8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://benyu.org/thiel-fellowship-closing-ceremony-speech</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jbrandonbb,2012:Post/what-is-the-purpose-of-life-anyway-or-why-i-feel-like-the-brother-of-the-guy-in-the-national</id>
    <published>2013-04-15T19:13:59-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T19:13:59-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/6FaNa8eXpFA/what-is-the-purpose-of-life-anyway-or-why-i-feel-like-the-brother-of-the-guy-in-the-national" />
    <author>
      <name>John Brandon</name>
      <uri>http://byjohnbrandon.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>What is the Purpose of Life Anyway, or Why I Feel like the Brother of the Guy in The National</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I feel like I’m the brother of the lead singer in the alt-rock band The National. He has a beard, I have a beard. (Well, sometimes. And by “sometimes” I mean often.) He has made a movie about how he went on tour as an assistant tour manager. I feel like I’m also a bystander, covering things with a casual bipartisan interest. We’re both members of the crowd, linked in an inextricable way to something famous and unattainable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just today I talked to an engineer from a company called Detroit Electric. It’s not a utility. They’re making a sports car that can go 190 miles on a charge, which is like having an expensive (and drive-able) smartphone. Brilliance reveals itself in short phrases. The engineer had The Bill Gates Pause where you can almost see neurons connecting inside his head, processing a millions things but only giving you a snippet. They pause because, like God, if they gave us everything at once we would die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand how the brother of the guy in The National feels. You’re sidelined while the superstar gets the attention. The band, quite curiously, has two sets of brothers and then the lead singer. When I read on Pitchfork that the lead singer fully understands he’s the only one with a brother not in the band, I felt a strong pang of recognition. (I will tell you the story of my own brother someday, but it won’t be sarcastic in any way.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journalism is about revealing greatness. As writers, we’re not creating as much as divulging. We stand in front of the open window of innovation and say, see &amp;ndash; here is a ticket to bountiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to an event in Las Vegas not long ago where this became strikingly clear. We all struggle with a desire to be famous &amp;ndash; that’s why Facebook exists. We have something to say, and we feel other people would be interested in hearing it. I suppose this is what it means to be human, e.g.,  expressing a desire to be heard. As the film critic Roger Ebert, recently passed, once said: we all have a desire for someone  to document us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The invitation to the event made me think my attendance was a matter of solemn duty. My presence was requested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I showed up with a friend of mine, perennially positioned as my photographer. We greeted the host and found our place. Within a few minutes, the host said there was someone she wanted me to meet. I told my friend, grab your camera. We chit-chatted for awhile, and &amp;ndash; being incapable of being anything but inquisitive, I started asking questions. &amp;ldquo;Ah, yes. I bet that was a memorable experience.&amp;rdquo; I jotted down a few notes, then felt a soft tap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone else needed by attention. I felt a glint of import. I rattled through a few more questions; we snapped a few more pictures. Then it hit me. I had not been invited to partake of the event. I had been invited to cover the partakers. I was there to make sure the invited guests felt invited. I was the person doing the covering; I was not the covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be a difficult role. There is power in the selection process, but it is a limited power. Once, at a car event in LA, I started asking questions about a new model coming out from Nissan. The engineer could tell when I was asking questions that could help him. It was a seven passenger model, something like a minivan but not as ridiculous. So I asked about safety, and legroom, and surround-sound. Then I switched gears. I asked about the molding on the side, the carbon fiber accents &amp;ndash; the inner-workings. I had strayed off message. Owing to my penchant to explore something until it is no longer explorable, I had (excuse the pun) driven too far away from the landing site. He cut me off and moved on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is that? Because there is a role to play. In tech journalism in particular, we are not uncovering a secret slavery operation in Congo. We’re not wiretapping for a drug ring. It’s one shiny object after another, strung up on URLs like Christmas lights for a season, only to be removed and replaced by other shiny objects. Make it too ornate and people get confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that’s why I do this blog. Granted, part of it is that I can be wholly unedited. There’s freedom in knowing I am not covering anything. At the same time, it is a way to combat the impertinence of reviewing yet another inkjet printer. You can only say so many things about toner cartridges, although I hear Brother International has some big news on that front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/6FaNa8eXpFA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://byjohnbrandon.com/what-is-the-purpose-of-life-anyway-or-why-i-feel-like-the-brother-of-the-guy-in-the-national</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:nate,2012:Post/lead-with-pain</id>
    <published>2013-04-15T10:06:24-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T10:06:24-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/oGdom-LKe4g/lead-with-pain" />
    <author>
      <name>Nathan Kontny</name>
      <uri>http://ninjasandrobots.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Lead with Pain</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I want more people to read my blog. I spend all this time writing; I don&amp;#39;t want it to bore people. I want it to be more interesting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So part of the way I&amp;#39;m trying to accomplish that is to become a better storyteller. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I learn more about storytelling and I look at what good storytellers do, I notice many of them don&amp;#39;t just lead with &amp;ldquo;once upon a time&amp;rdquo;. They lead with pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes they&amp;#39;ll even start a story in the middle. They&amp;#39;ll open with the main character on their knees, grovelling with a gun to their head. And as the hammer of the gun pulls back. Bam. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re back to the beginning before this painful event has even occurred yet. But they&amp;#39;ve got us hooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method of storytelling maybe even seems cliché. So many movies and TV shows use it. It works. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then it surprises me how few of us incorporate this method into our own stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people start a blog post with something like, &amp;ldquo;I went to the store the other day,&amp;rdquo; and they quickly lose my interest. I realize I&amp;#39;m going to have to dig to find out how this relates to anything I&amp;#39;m trying to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if they begin with a description of pain that they&amp;#39;ve gone through, maybe even fixed, now they&amp;#39;ve got my attention. I sit up. I take notice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I craft new things now, I spend a lot of time figuring out that statement of pain I&amp;#39;ll lead with in the first sentence or paragraph. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t just do this for blog posts. I&amp;#39;m doing this for my product landing pages. READMEs for open source projects. Emails. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amy Hoy has written some great stuff on launching products. If you read over this post, &lt;a href="http://unicornfree.com/2012/shut-up-and-take-my-money-or-how-to-pitch-so-people-will-listen"&gt;Shut Up and Take my Money&lt;/a&gt;, you might notice Amy has similarly discovered the power in leading with pain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She used to talk about a new product she was working on like this: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potential customer at cocktail party&lt;/strong&gt;: So, what’s Charm?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Me&lt;/strong&gt;: Charm is a new, end-to-end customer support tool. It solves the problem of passing around email as a specification of work&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when she started leading with a pain that she and her potential customer might share: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potential customer&lt;/strong&gt;: So, what’s Charm?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Me&lt;/strong&gt;: Do you get a lot of support email? Yeah, me too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People started paying a lot more attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S. &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/natekontny"&gt;It would be awesome to meet you on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/oGdom-LKe4g" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ninjasandrobots.com/lead-with-pain</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/equipping-your-champions</id>
    <published>2013-04-15T07:34:48-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T07:34:48-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/_PYnEyFVxPI/equipping-your-champions" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Founders, Equip Your Champions</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24588656872344.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/tom_24588656872344_small.jpg" alt="carabiners.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a founder, you&amp;#39;re always selling. You&amp;#39;re selling yourself, your team, your product, your company. But your pitch is likely missing one of two key components. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pitch needs to accomplish two goals to be effective. Most pitches solve the first, but omit the second. First, the pitch must convince the audience who might be investors, employees, recruits, or customers of some premise. Second, the pitch has to equip your champions, now convinced of your argument, to sell on your behalf. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No enterprise software is ever bought unilaterally. No candidate is ever hired in isolation. No investment decision is ever made by one person in a VC firm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whomever you&amp;#39;re pitching will need to convince another person or group of people. So your pitch should be structured to enable those champions to be effective by providing a be simple, relatable and intriguing argument to build momentum within whatever organization is making the decision whether a VC fund, a family or a business. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you structure such an argument? One approach I&amp;#39;ve found that works well is a three pronged argument delivered in less than a minute. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A change is inevitable, that change implies a big opportunity, and this is the right team or product to help us take advantage of that change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your sales pitch, ideally at the end of the pitch, equip your champion with an argument like this. It will empower your champion to be more effective and help you close that sale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/_PYnEyFVxPI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/equipping-your-champions</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:cadelllast,2012:Post/3d-printing-is-here</id>
    <published>2013-04-14T09:23:17-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-14T09:23:17-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/8F6WCAo-qTY/3d-printing-is-here" />
    <author>
      <name>Cadell Last</name>
      <uri>http://theratchet.ca</uri>
    </author>
    <title>3D Printing Is Here</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/cadelllast_24587739058716.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/cadelllast_24587739058716_small.jpg" alt="Mojo_Engineer-removing-part-small-e1343959687750.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week my friend and I had an interesting discussion on the nature of &amp;ldquo;revolutions&amp;rdquo;.  We both agreed that when historians look back at our era (1990-2010) they will say that we were living through the &amp;ldquo;internet revolution.&amp;rdquo;  However, did it &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; like we lived through a revolution?  Well, even though the internet fundamentally changed everything we do, the transition to a world built around the internet didn&amp;#39;t feel like a revolution to me.  It just sort of felt normal.  Of course, part of that has to do with my age (I&amp;#39;m 26 so I grew up with the revolution).  However, this brings up an interesting aspect of revolution: we seem to impose revolution on the past.  We construct the narrative of revolution.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take for example the two most famous historical revolutions: the agricultural and the industrial.  For someone living through either revolution, they would not have known they were actually living through what we now see as a significant turning point in the narrative of human existence.  In fact, both of those revolutions happened at imperceptibly slow paces compared to the internet revolution.  The agricultural revolution diffused so slowly that it developed in five different geographic regions independently.  The industrial revolution only had one diffusion center, however its global spread took centuries.  The internet revolution arguably took about 10-20 years (even though some would argue it won&amp;#39;t be complete until the end of this decade when almost every human will be online and connected).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I digress. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I wrote a post explaining that we should anticipate a &lt;a href="http://theratchet.ca/robot-sex-revolution"&gt;robot revolution&lt;/a&gt; in the 2020s-2030s that will change the world more than the internet did between 1990-2010.  However, I&amp;#39;m getting ahead of myself again because I think we should realize that we are on the cusp of an equally revolutionary moment in history &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;: the 3D printing revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you accuse me of using the word revolution too liberally, let me first list the developments in the world of 3D printing this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design for &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-21121061"&gt;first 3D printed building&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;production of &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-edinburgh-east-fife-21328109"&gt;first 3D printed stem cells&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creation of &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/wiredscience/2013/02/3-d-food-printer-space/"&gt;first 3D printed meals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;production of &lt;a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/health/healthnews/9883441/Scientists-create-artificial-ear-using-3D-printing-and-living-cell-gels.html"&gt;first 3D printed artificial ear&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creation of &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/autopia/2013/02/3d-printed-car/"&gt;first 3D printed automobiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;production and implant of &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-2289726/Patient-75-cent-SKULL-replaced-3D-printed-implant-groundbreaking-operation.html#ixzz2MyroZhti"&gt;first 3D printed skull&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;production of &lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/science/sciencenow/la-sci-sn-faux-synthetic-tissue-3d-printer-self-assembling-20130404,0,6286611.story"&gt;first 3D printed human tissue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creation of &lt;a href="http://singularityhub.com/2012/04/07/on-demand-robots-from-a-3d-printer/"&gt;first 3D printed robots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;opening of &lt;a href="http://3dprintingindustry.com/2013/01/21/3d-print-museum-opens-in-beijing-china/"&gt;first 3D print-only museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all things that have happened &lt;em&gt;this year&lt;/em&gt; and it is only April!  Is it safe to say that 2013 is going to be remembered as the year of the 3D printer?  Actually, maybe it will be remembered for the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-21614176"&gt;introduction to 4D printing&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1999, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ray_Kurzweil"&gt;Ray Kurzweil&lt;/a&gt; explained that dynamic systems evolve exponentially.  He called this type of evolution the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accelerating_change#Kurzweil.27s_The_Law_of_Accelerating_Returns"&gt;Law of Accelerating Returns&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.kurzweilai.net/the-law-of-accelerating-returns"&gt;you can read more about this law here&lt;/a&gt;).  The Law of Accelerating Returns has profound implications for the future of technological evolution, especially when applied to something like 3D printing.  However, I don&amp;#39;t think you have to be a technological evolution expert to understand that the human future will be fundamentally transformed by 3D printing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my perspective all the developments in 3D printing this year indicate that we are on the cusp of a revolution.  What does our world look like when manufacturing becomes decentralized?  Many experts predict that affordable, easy-to-use 3D printers will be in peoples homes in 10-20 years.  These printers could be used for replacing spare parts, making food/meals, creating clothing, furniture, cars &amp;hellip; organs?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many 3D printing enthusiasts propose that you will only be constrained by your own imagination.  &lt;a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1351910088/3doodler-the-worlds-first-3d-printing-pen"&gt;Check out the 3Doodler&lt;/a&gt; as an example of the type of creative products that will emerge over the next few decades.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This decentralization of manufacturing will almost certainly change the global economy in ways that are hard to predict.  Will there be jobs for anyone in the manufacturing sector?  What type of value will physical objects have when production is inexpensive?  How will 3D printing (and advanced Watson-like A.I.) transform hospitals?  Will individual people be able to create established companies that required hundreds of people to build in the past (e.g., automobile, clothing companies, etc.).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also need to contemplate more sinister sides to this revolution.  How will we protect biological information?  Will someone be able to manufacture and print a deadly virus or bacterium?  What about the possibility of an individual 3D printing weapons of mass destruction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the developments in 3D printing this year force us all to contemplate questions like this (both positive and negative).  In terms of the future of manufacturing, we may get a glimpse of what this revolution will look like if we analyze what is happening in media today.  I feel as though the internet revolution decentralized media mediums, enabling individuals to build their own empires.  &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BoraZ"&gt;Bora Zivkovic&lt;/a&gt; brilliantly explored the dynamics of this transition well in a &lt;a href="http://blogs.scientificamerican.com/incubator/2013/04/02/how-to-break-into-science-writing-using-your-blog-and-social-media-sci4hels/"&gt;recent Scientific American article on science writing&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[In the 20th century] very few people could afford to own printing presses, radio and TV studios, etc. Running all that complicated equipment required technical expertise and professional training. Thus media became locked up in silos, hierarchical, broadcast-only with little-to-none (and then again centrally controlled) means for feedback. There was a wealthy, vocal minority that determined what was news, and how to frame it, and the vast majority was consuming the news in silence. Today, all one needs is some source of electricity (e.g., a small battery in your smartphone) and some means of accessing the Internet. The act of publishing is reduced to clicking on the “Publish” button. Yes, this still leaves some people out of the media, especially in the developing countries, but compared to just twenty years ago, vastly larger numbers of people now have access to the means of production of news. The obstacles to access – money, technical skills for running the machinery – are now much, much lower, almost free. This turns everything on its head! Silos are breaking down, economics of media are severely disrupted, former gatekeepers are squealing in distress, old hierarchies are broken down (and replaced by new hierarchies), and now everyone has to learn new “media hygiene” practices: who to trust, how to filter the information, how to organize it for one’s self. The new ecosystem now contains both the traditional outlets and the individuals, “people formerly known as the audience“, as equal players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several examples of dominant media outlets today that would not have been possible before the internet revolution.  I feel as though we will be able to say the same about automobile, clothing, computer, robotics, biotech companies, etc. in the 2030s.  So if you are in business (or want to get into business), understanding how the &lt;a href="http://www.kurzweilai.net/the-law-of-accelerating-returns"&gt;Law of Accelerating Returns&lt;/a&gt; applies to the 3D printing industry could be &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll end by adding that my roommate (who is in business) always tells me that the worlds of science and business don&amp;#39;t communicate enough.  I agree, but when I study &lt;a href="http://theratchet.ca/chimpanzee-fire-1"&gt;chimpanzee behaviour&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="http://theratchet.ca/another-earth"&gt;future of exoplanet detection&lt;/a&gt; there may not be any relevance to the business world.  However, people who study technological evolution can definitely help inform those in business (and vice versa).  So if you are interested in learning more about what some leading theorists think about how the next few decades of technological change will transform business (and our planet), check out &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ceEog1XS5OI"&gt;this panel discussion&lt;/a&gt; hosted by Big Think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you think 3D printing will change our world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://hubski.com/pub?id=79750"&gt;Discuss this article on Hubski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/8F6WCAo-qTY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://theratchet.ca/3d-printing-is-here</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:owen,2012:Post/facebook-home-hasnt-failed-its-actually-genius</id>
    <published>2013-04-13T20:45:16-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T20:45:16-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/30Nyqb4JfBI/facebook-home-hasnt-failed-its-actually-genius" />
    <author>
      <name>Owen Williams</name>
      <uri>http://owened.co.nz</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Facebook Home hasn't failed, it's just getting started.</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/owen_24586398627984.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/owen_24586398627984_small.jpg" alt="att-htc-first-android-facebook.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected when something interesting is released, the posts begin to roll in about how it&amp;#39;s a failure. We&amp;#39;ve already got a ton of articles with titles like &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://seattletimes.com/html/businesstechnology/2020769323_ptechfacebookreviewxml.html"&gt;steer clear of Facebook Home&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/facebook/2013/04/12/facebook-home-suffers-from-poor-early-reviews-as-46-give-it-a-1-star-rating-on-google-play/"&gt;Facebook Home suffering from poor Google Play reviews&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and in traditional Forbes fashion &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/gregsatell/2013/04/08/why-the-facebook-phone-will-fail-and-why-it-really-doesnt-matter/"&gt;Why The Facebook Phone Will Fail and Why It Really Doesn&amp;#39;t Matter&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sometimes wish the media wasn&amp;#39;t so quick to jump to conclusions. Yes, &lt;a href="http://www.gsmarena.com/htc_chacha-3787.php"&gt;historically a Facebook phone hasn&amp;#39;t panned out well&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, &lt;a href="http://blogs.computerworld.com/windows-phone/22020/microsoft-android-too-complicated-facebook-home-old-and-way"&gt;Microsoft apparently thinks they already did that&lt;/a&gt;. The thing about all of this is that &lt;em&gt;none of these people are the target market.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we look at this from the perspective of the Android community then yes, Facebook Home is a stupid idea because it dumbs down Android. But, for everyone else out there that doesn&amp;#39;t care about tinkering with their phone it&amp;#39;s perfect. There&amp;#39;s nothing to it, just scroll through your feed and interact or send a text. You&amp;#39;ve got the capability to install Android applications if you want and that&amp;#39;s a bonus, but the two big parts of many potential buyer&amp;#39;s life is front and center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those potential buyers? Teenagers. Young adults. The Facebook generation that is stuck interacting 24/7. They&amp;#39;re sharing as soon as they wake up and go to sleep. This market doesn&amp;#39;t like making phone calls. One of the biggest criticisms of Facebook Home is that it &lt;a href="http://business.financialpost.com/2013/04/12/review-facebook-home-at-centre-stage-of-phone-makes-other-apps-harder-to-reach/"&gt;makes other apps hard to reach&lt;/a&gt;. I agree, but the teenagers I know really only use Facebook and SMS anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook Home isn&amp;#39;t targeted at those who go and manually download it from the Play Store. The application has bad reviews because it&amp;#39;s never It&amp;#39;s not destined for any member of the Android community or even those who currently use a smartphone. It&amp;#39;s targeted at a new generation of young people who don&amp;#39;t actually use their phone as a &lt;em&gt;phone&lt;/em&gt; anymore. It&amp;#39;s intended as a preinstalled experience that some will intentionally seek to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of declaring Facebook Home &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo; by our standards, let&amp;#39;s wait to see how the HTC First does in the market. That&amp;#39;ll speak much louder than existing Android users. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A $99 phone that does 100% of what teenagers need is better for parents who might have otherwise been buying them an iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/30Nyqb4JfBI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://owened.co.nz/facebook-home-hasnt-failed-its-actually-genius</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ben,2012:Post/there-are-no-shortcuts</id>
    <published>2013-04-13T00:51:13-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T00:51:13-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/bP0RUy_NOIs/there-are-no-shortcuts" />
    <author>
      <name>Ben Yu</name>
      <uri>http://benyu.org</uri>
    </author>
    <title>There are no shortcuts</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The sparking foundation for this belief is the tech startup I tried to found with no technical background. It failed, I learned lots of &amp;#39;lessons&amp;#39;, and I realized I needed to get technical and bring something to the table before trying again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while later, I chanced upon the &lt;a href="http://www.cs.virginia.edu/%7Erobins/YouAndYourResearch.html"&gt;You and Your Research&lt;/a&gt; talk by Richard Hamming, and it made a lasting impact on me. I&amp;#39;ve been thinking and referring to it for probably over a year now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main takeaway: Oak trees come from acorns. In the talk, Hamming goes on to note the &amp;#39;Nobel Prize effect&amp;#39; - the fact that no great work is generally done by a recipient of a Nobel Prize or similar distinction after receiving the award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are famous it is hard to work on small problems. This is what did Shannon in. After information theory, what do you do for an encore? The great scientists often make this error. They fail to continue to plant the little acorns from which the mighty oak trees grow. They try to get the big thing right off. And that isn&amp;#39;t the way things go. So that is another reason why you find that when you get early recognition it seems to sterilize you. In fact I will give you my favorite quotation of many years. The Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton, in my opinion, has ruined more good scientists than any institution has created, judged by what they did before they came and judged by what they did after. Not that they weren&amp;#39;t good afterwards, but they were superb before they got there and were only good afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so there are two lessons here. One, which I learned from firsthand experience, is that you can&amp;#39;t try to build a house without a foundation, no matter how fast you want that house built and how too impatient you are to do it right. It will inevitably come crashing down - hopefully, if you&amp;#39;re very lucky, very quickly, and if you&amp;#39;re unlucky, somewhere down the line after you&amp;#39;ve already moved in and it crushes you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the time to do things right - a shortcut will end up costing much more time in the long run as things come crashing to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, optimize for the long run. Constantly aiming for the short term, particularly in the frantic and ever-changing startup world (hoping to build a lot of hype, raise a lot of money, and get acquired in two years), tends to encourage the taking the illusory shortcuts which have the fate of failure stamped on them from the very outset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, as Hamming said it best, it&amp;#39;s okay not to go for the big thing straight off - take the time to plant the seeds and have the determination to nurture the seedling as it grows over many long years. If you want to grow a huge oak tree, &lt;em&gt;the only way to do it is to plant a tiny acorn and wait for it to grow&lt;/em&gt;. If you try anything else you&amp;#39;re wasting your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So perhaps, there&amp;#39;s no need to try to be the next Google or the cure to cancer straight off - take your time and start small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And since this is a post rife with pithy and trite statements: The best time to plant a tree was 20 years ago. The second best time is now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;ll take time. There&amp;#39;s no getting around that. So get going - now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/bP0RUy_NOIs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://benyu.org/there-are-no-shortcuts</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:youssef,2012:Post/twitter-music-leak</id>
    <published>2013-04-12T14:10:24-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T14:10:24-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/OzdfRhwPYWE/twitter-music-leak" />
    <author>
      <name>Youssef Sarhan</name>
      <uri>http://sefsar.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>LEAKED: Twitter's Music App will integrate Spotify, Rdio, iTunes, Soundcloud, Vevo and Youtube</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, I came across &lt;a href="http://music.twitter.com"&gt;http://music.twitter.com&lt;/a&gt;. Naturally, I inspected the HTML source just to see if there were any :hidden gems. There were none, bar one curious line of code that caught my eye. The image for the &amp;#39;Sign In&amp;#39; button linked to the &lt;em&gt;/_login/&lt;/em&gt; directory — and so my journey began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;background: url(/_login/btn-login-states.png) no-repeat 0 0;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I visited &lt;em&gt;/_login/&lt;/em&gt; I was presented with a page that looks something like a 404.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/youssef_24584349199392_small.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following my curiosity, I inspected the source of this new page. This time, the CSS document was a lot different. It contained the entirety of the App&amp;#39;s UI. A quick scan revealed a whole lot of words that implicate a very clear picture of what Twitter intends to do with this new Music product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it&amp;#39;s an App, which I guess was obvious; but it seems there will be a mobile app and desktop app (web), as indicated in the page footer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!--a href=&amp;quot;/download&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Get the App&amp;lt;/a--&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users will be able to connect with Spotify, Rdio, iTunes, Soundcloud, Vevo and Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.iconmusic-spotify-connect-btn{background-position:-4431px -0px;height:32px;width:179px}

.iconmusic-player-source-rdio{background-position:-2801px -0px;height:19px;width:30px}

.iconmusic-player-source-itunes{background-position:-2751px -0px;height:19px;width:30px}

.iconmusic-player-source-soundcloud{background-position:- 2851px -0px;height:14px;width:92px}

.iconmusic-player-source-vevo{background-position:-2963px -0px;height:9px;width:53px}

.youtube-vid player{position:absolute;padding:10px;height:200px}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music controller even looks like a CD. oooh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/youssef_24584356587078_small.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users –or should that be customers?– will be able to buy songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.iconmusic-player-btn-buy{background-position:-1167px -0px;height:49px;width:49px}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be &lt;em&gt;explicit&lt;/em&gt; content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/youssef_24584359038372_small.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users will be able to follow other users, presumably this will be unrelated to their Twitter followers/following lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.iconmusic-profile-large-following-btn{background-position:-2046px -0px;height:36px;width:70px}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be charts and shows, whatever they are. Perhaps charts will work similar to trending topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.iconmusic-menu-charts{background-position:-142px -0px;height:28px;width:28px}

.iconmusic-menu-shows{background-position:-190px -0px;height:19px;width:29px}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Font is Proxima Nova, distinct from Twitter&amp;#39;s use of Helvetica.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;html,body{font-family:ProximaNova-Bold,HelveticaNeue,&amp;#39;Helvetica Neue&amp;#39;,Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif;font-weight:bold;font-size:14px;}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users will be able to compose Tweets from the music app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.iconmusic-compose-tweet-btn-bg{background-position:-3305px -0px;height:27px;width:65px}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artists will have Biographies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.artist-bio{height:484px;width:484px}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often spot things &lt;a href="http://sefsar.com/nokia-faked-the-still-photos-too"&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt;, so if you liked this post you can &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/ys"&gt;follow me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Twitter have since replaced the CSS file with &lt;a href="https://music.twitter.com/e/error.css"&gt;this file&lt;/a&gt;. They have also removed all unnecessary image assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/OzdfRhwPYWE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://sefsar.com/twitter-music-leak</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:EAKoester,2012:Post/appmarket-fit-if-you-arent-on-my-homescreen-your-app-is-probably-a-tombstone</id>
    <published>2013-04-12T12:11:56-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T12:11:56-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/3mxHKTnfbxY/appmarket-fit-if-you-arent-on-my-homescreen-your-app-is-probably-a-tombstone" />
    <author>
      <name>Eric Koester</name>
      <uri>http://ekoester.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>App-Market Fit: If You Aren't On My Homescreen, Your App Is Probably a Tombstone</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine asked me last week, &amp;ldquo;So, what apps do you use?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a good question, so I whipped out my iPhone and started looking through.  I was shocked to see I have 102 apps on my phone.  Wow, that&amp;#39;s a lot of apps, I thought to myself.  Then I started scrolling through and realized how many of them I hadn&amp;#39;t touched in&amp;hellip; well, since I could last remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dead apps.  Tombstones of a great app description and a non-compelling solution.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Row after row of dead apps.  And surprisingly, all of them lived on screens after my homescreen.  The homescreen. Turns out it&amp;#39;s home to all of those apps I&amp;#39;d say I use either daily, weekly or really frequently during short infrequent bursts.  iMessage, Google Maps, App Store, Twitter, Facebook, Evernote, Couple, Zaarly, Instagram, Tripit and even Tetris (my guilty pleasure while wasting a few minutes).  Go one screen in and it&amp;#39;s a wasteland.  I did a count and of the ~90 apps not on my homescreen, two I&amp;#39;d used in the past week (Weather &amp;amp; LinkedIn) and four in the last month (Timehop, Bank of America - to deposit a check, Taxi Magic &amp;amp; ParkMobile - to &amp;#39;feed the meter&amp;#39;). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whoa.  Six apps out of nearly a hundred I could even recall touching in the past month.  A few others I thought I&amp;#39;d use in the future (OpenTable and maybe Flipboard, Uber or Lyft).  It&amp;#39;s shocking if you really think about it&amp;hellip; I&amp;#39;d say 95% of my app activity is locked onto the home screen.  I&amp;#39;m not sure I&amp;#39;d consider myself normal from a smart phone usage pattern, but I wonder if the simplicity of the home screen really is a key.  I can honestly say if Apple &lt;em&gt;forced&lt;/em&gt; me to only have 16 apps, I could do it&amp;hellip; no problem and no issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there a lesson in here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you can build a mobile app that your users will and are consistently putting on their homescreen, I don&amp;#39;t think you have App-Market Fit.  Even sixteen apps seems like a lot to incorporate into my life.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking my apps by category, here&amp;#39;s what I saw:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Five (5) &lt;strong&gt;Communication Apps&lt;/strong&gt; (iMessage, Couple, Twitter, Tweetbot, Facebook)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Two (2) &lt;strong&gt;Photo Apps&lt;/strong&gt; (Camera, Instagram)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Two (2) &lt;strong&gt;Travel Apps&lt;/strong&gt; (Google Maps, Tripit)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Two (2) &lt;strong&gt;Productivity Apps&lt;/strong&gt; (Calendar, Evernote)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; One (1) &lt;strong&gt;Game&lt;/strong&gt; (Tetris)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Three (3) &lt;strong&gt;Utility Apps&lt;/strong&gt; (Settings, App Store, Folder with Calculator+Clock)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;strong&gt;My Own Company&amp;#39;s App&lt;/strong&gt; (Zaarly)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i50.tinypic.com/2ez21sm.png" alt="My Homescreen"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commonalities are that these apps help me communicate, consume content, capture content and live more productively.  I&amp;#39;d say all are part of my &amp;#39;smart-phone&amp;#39; powered life.  I&amp;#39;m not a huge folders guy (in fact the folder on my homescreen is the only one).  And I&amp;#39;m a very frequent user of the four bottom bar apps (phone, mail, Safari and Music), and I can&amp;#39;t foresee any of the apps above replacing those four (I even tried Mailbox and was &amp;#39;meh&amp;#39; about it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would it take to get your app onto my homescreen?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, you&amp;#39;d probably have to bump one of my Twitter clients or the Settings Apps.  Do-able.  You&amp;#39;d probably be fighting with Open Table, which is &amp;ldquo;On Deck&amp;rdquo; in my brain.  If I was living in SF again, I&amp;#39;d say you&amp;#39;d be fighting with Lyft or Uber.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are building a new app or have an app targeted at smart phone users, I think you need to have a &amp;#39;home screen&amp;#39; strategy.  It&amp;#39;s great to have 96 apps on my phone, but I am really only patronizing the first 16, plus their four compatriots in the bottom bar.  And unless you can convince your users to bump another app and put a spot for you in the &amp;#39;home&amp;#39;, I&amp;#39;m not convinced you can capture mindshare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there are a few apps that are doing a good job at capturing Home Screen real estate based on what I hear from friends. The taxi and ride apps such as Uber, Lyft, Sidecar and TaxiMagic are common for frequent taxi takers, but still seem part of the tech set for the most part. Instagram and Path are both common ones I see (Path more in the startup/tech scene though).  Pandora and Spotify seem common homescreen music apps, and I see a few fitness apps such as MyFitnessPal and Nike on home screens.  Yelp, Foursquare and Open Table are each players for real estate.  And games continue to be a common one, but there seems to be little commonality there other than Words With Friends, Angry Birds and Plants vs. Zombies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a strategy to get on my homescreen?  Is it something you activity &amp;ldquo;teach&amp;rdquo; your users, ask for or recommend?  Are there any companies that have done a great job at getting on that home screen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no data to back this up, but I&amp;#39;d bet that 80-90% of any app&amp;#39;s Daily Active Users have that app on the home screen.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is missing from the list?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better address book could snag a spot &amp;ndash; Brewster is trying that route.  Hotel Tonight and Hipmunk could snag a spot for travel, but I don&amp;#39;t find myself booking travel on my phone much.  I also see a spot potentially for online document management, which is currently being fought by DropBox and Google Drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And listen, if you think by blasting me with a bunch of push notifications (glares over at Groupon and Living Social apps) that I&amp;#39;m going to put you on the homescreen, you are sadly mistaken.  ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart phones are inherently an extension of the owner.  My apps are personal to me, but I do think it is common that we spend 90% of our time with 5-10% of our apps.  And as you think about your app, figure out how to make something your community and your audience love.  If you build and market something mainstream, you&amp;#39;ll find yourself in the app graveyard and then you&amp;#39;ve got a bunch of downloads and an inactive community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So just what would it take for me to get an app onto your homescreen?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/3mxHKTnfbxY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ekoester.com/appmarket-fit-if-you-arent-on-my-homescreen-your-app-is-probably-a-tombstone</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:teej,2012:Post/the-great-grocery-game</id>
    <published>2013-04-12T01:24:25-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T01:24:25-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/MVGODg3LaKU/the-great-grocery-game" />
    <author>
      <name>TJ Murphy</name>
      <uri>http://teejm.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>The Great Grocery Game</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was about 9 o&amp;#39;clock in the morning, early Saturday, with the sun shining and my refrigerator totally empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to buy groceries.  Luckily I live in San Francisco, a city filled with startups who can&amp;#39;t wait to outsource the minutiae of everyday life.  At the tap of a button a complete stranger will come over to my house and live life on my behalf.  It&amp;#39;s both disturbing and beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so many choices it can be hard to know which one to pick.  So instead of take a gamble, I decided to put them to the test. Three delivery services, head-to-head, in a race to purchase and deliver an identical order of groceries on a Saturday afternoon.  Game on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Experiment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by compiling my grocery list.  I took my last 12 trips to Safeway and built a comprehensive database of every item I had purchased.  From that I crafted a standard basket - the order that I felt was representative of a normal trip.  After a few adjustments to make sure I didn&amp;#39;t get too much food, I ended up with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breakfast&lt;/strong&gt;: Milk, Cereal, Yogurt, Donuts, Bacon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Produce&lt;/strong&gt;: Strawberries, Avocado&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snacks&lt;/strong&gt;: Crackers, Soda, Guacamole Mix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dinner&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicken Breast, Frozen Dinner, Wine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this list may seem simple, it includes some hidden landmines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Milk - I left a note to check expiration dates and pick up the freshest carton.  I always pull my milk from the back to ensure the longest shelf life in my fridge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guacamole mix - I asked for McCormicks, a specialty brand that&amp;#39;s out of the way and hard to find.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avocado - I left a note to purchase a ripe avocado.  You&amp;#39;d be surprised how many people don&amp;#39;t know how to tell if an avocado is ripe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strawberries - These can be very hit or miss. If you pick the package on top you could end up with a bunch of nasty fruit.  A rational shopper will check for the best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my cart assembled it was time to order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Ordering Process&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When ordering on Postmates or Instacart, you start by choosing the store.  You then go through a loop of picking a category, scrolling through the list to find your item, and then adding it to your cart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The merchandising in these apps is terrible.  Sometimes the item you want is right at the top of the list.  Other times you have to scroll through 15 screens of junk to find what you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search in these apps can be painful.  Typing in a brand will bring up every single item under that brand name across the store.  When you get in to store brands there&amp;#39;s no way you&amp;#39;ll find what you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest value to Instacart over Postmates is the ability to &lt;strong&gt;schedule ahead&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;plan out substitutes&lt;/strong&gt;.  Instacart let&amp;#39;s you take any order and pick the day it will show up where Postmates restricts you to just &amp;ldquo;Get It Now&amp;rdquo;.  You can also pick and choose what alternative items you want on Instacart in the event your favorites are out of stock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ordering on Exec was much simpler in comparison.  Getting an Exec Errand is just a simple text box to fill out.  My typical grocery store process involves my wife texting me a list and me going to the store so it was easy to just copy &amp;amp; paste the list in.  Having simple text is great for fuzzy search.  For example, I asked Exec for the cheapest bacon on sale and I ended up with a much higher quality product at the same price as the others.  The big issue is specificity.  For certain items we struggled with how to word our request such that it was perfectly clear what we wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took my standard cart and entered it into each app without triggering delivery, double checking each to make sure they were at parity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Cost&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each service has a very different cost structure.  No one service is the best at any pricepoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postmates&lt;/strong&gt; has a dynamic pricing model based on time, demand, distance, and order size.  I paid $12 for delivery on this order, though I&amp;#39;ve seen the price be as low as $7.50.  They also charge a flat 5% fee on top of the purchase price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exec&lt;/strong&gt; has a model that&amp;#39;s purely labor based.  The more time your Exec spends working, the more you pay.  Their rate is $25/hour with a 45 minute minimum.  On top of that, you pay 50¢/mile for travel and a 3% fee on any purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instacart&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;s pricing is the most ambiguous.  They charge a flat delivery fee based on order size: $7.99 for under $35 and $3.99 otherwise.  Often on the weekends they will offer free delivery for orders over $60.  Where it gets tricky is that you pay the retail price for grocery items plus an unspecified fee on top.  So if you&amp;#39;re shopping at Safeway where discounting is rampant, it&amp;#39;s not clear just how much more you&amp;#39;re paying.  For my order, the Instacart cost for any food item was ~20% over what I would pay at the checkout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;My Costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: right; font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Items&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Food Cost&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Fees&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Delivery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="font-weight: bold; background: #fef5e8; text-align: center; color: #581500;"&gt;Total&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: right;"&gt;Postmates&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;13 &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;$44.34 &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;$2.22 &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;$12.00&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="background: #fef5e8; color: #581500;"&gt;$58.56&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: right;"&gt;Exec&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;14 &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$50.71 &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$19.50 &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="background: #fef5e8; color: #581500;"&gt;$70.21&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: right;"&gt;Instacart&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;11 &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$33.71 &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$6.44 &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;$3.99&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="background: #fef5e8; color: #581500;"&gt;$44.14&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Cost By Order Size&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This graph helps show how the costs change with order size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/teej_24583578882282_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.svbtle.com/teej_24583578882282_raw.png" alt="cost-graph.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Timeline&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When noon on Saturday rolled around, I started the race.  I triggered each app simultaneously to delivery my groceries as soon as possible.  I kept a record of every call, text, and push notification I received and compiled them together.  This timeline tracks all communication I received along the way.
&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/teej_24575461499826_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_teej_24575461499826_raw.png" alt="grocery-timeline.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Each event is an SMS or Push Notification unless otherwise specified&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Results&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the orders came in I went through each item and cataloged them along the following criteria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I get the item I wanted?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When items were unavailable, did I get an acceptable replacement?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did they follow my special instructions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the item of a quality I would I have purchased myself?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how did they do?  As expected, each service had no problem fulfilling the easy items on my list. Though, for about half of my grocery list, there were problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Exec&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/teej_24583453108488_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.svbtle.com/teej_24583453108488_raw.jpg" alt="exec.JPG"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exec was the first order to arrive with a total delivery time of &lt;strong&gt;65 minutes&lt;/strong&gt;.  Exec makes no promises on delivery time and if they run over, it costs you directly.  Of all three services, they were the only ones able to fill my 14 item order. Overall the order quality was top notch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/span&gt; The strawberries, milk, and guacamole mix came in perfect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/span&gt; The donuts I wanted were out.  He messaged me through the app and I told him a suitable replacement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #FFCC33; font-weight: bold;"&gt;~&lt;/span&gt; The exec thought the frozen dinner I wanted was out and asked about a replacement.  I realized my description of the item was not specific enough, as he bought the completely wrong thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/span&gt; The avocado was not ripe. I was never asked about a replacement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Postmates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/teej_24583453535682_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.svbtle.com/teej_24583453535682_raw.jpg" alt="postmates.JPG"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postmates was the second order to arrive with a total delivery time of &lt;strong&gt;75 minutes&lt;/strong&gt;.  Postmates promises a 60 minute delivery, making them 15 minutes late.  My postmate was the only competitor who was a woman, a detail that weighed heavily in their favor.  She did a fantastic job on the produce, blowing away everyone on her handling of my avocado request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/span&gt; The strawberries and milk were great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/span&gt; Text messaged me that there were no ripe avocados available in singles, but there were in a 3 pack.  I told them to pick any suitable single avocado.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #FFCC33; font-weight: bold;"&gt;~&lt;/span&gt; Text messaged me that the frozen chicken was unavailable, but substituted it with an unnecessarily expensive alternative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/span&gt; The guacamole mix was substituted with a cheaper variety without consulting me.  This is the variety right next to the avocados in the store.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/span&gt; Postmates did not have bakery items listed and did not have functionality for custom requests.  Therefore I did not get any donuts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Instacart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/teej_24583453863660_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.svbtle.com/teej_24583453863660_raw.jpg" alt="instacart.JPG"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instacart was the third order to arrive with a total delivery time of &lt;strong&gt;111 minutes&lt;/strong&gt;.  They promise delivery within a 3 hour window, so this delivery was well within the normal range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/span&gt; The milk was not the freshest available, expiring 4 days earlier than the others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/span&gt; The strawberries were of very poor quality as judged by my wife, the Chief Strawberry Eater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/span&gt; Instacart reported that the Guacamole mix was sold out and did not supply a substitute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/span&gt; The avocado was not ripe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #FFCC33; font-weight: bold;"&gt;~&lt;/span&gt; I got a text message that some items had been substituted.  The chicken had been swapped out for a larger size (1.5lb) and higher coset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/span&gt; Instacart does not deliver alcohol so I did not receive wine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;—&lt;/span&gt; Instacart handles custom requests but I failed to place one for the donuts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center; font-style: italic;"&gt;Quality&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center; font-style: italic;"&gt;Accuracy&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;Item&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Postmates&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Exec&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instacart&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Postmates&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Exec&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Instacart&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16oz Cinnamon Toast Crunch&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 Quart, 1% Lucerne Milk&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1lb Strawberries&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1x Avocado&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;McCormick Guacamole Mix&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2 Liter Coke Zero&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Safeway Wheat Crackers&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Eat Right Sesame Chicken Frozen Dinner&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #FFCC33; font-weight: bold; font-size: 24px; line-height: 18px;"&gt;~&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Chobani Non-fat Strawberry&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Chobani Non-fat Raspberry&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1lb Chicken Breast, Boneless Skinless&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #FFCC33; font-weight: bold; font-size: 24px; line-height: 18px;"&gt;~&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #FFCC33; font-weight: bold; font-size: 24px; line-height: 18px;"&gt;~&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1 Bottle Cupcake Sauvignon Blanc&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;3x Boston Crème Bakery Donuts&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;—&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #DD5A3C;"&gt;✘&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;—&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1 Package Bacon&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style="text-align: center; color: #8EC549;"&gt;✔&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;13/13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; font-weight: bold;"&gt;14/14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;9/11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;11/14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center; font-weight: bold;"&gt;12/14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;8/13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Postmates&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Exec&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Instacart&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Postmates&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Exec&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Instacart&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postmates was hands down the best &lt;strong&gt;value per dollar&lt;/strong&gt;.  With their inexpensive delivery fees and great accuracy, I feel like I had a great experience relative to the amount I paid.  It&amp;#39;s hard to say whether this was due to the startup or because the competitor was a female and thus had more attention to detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exec excelled at &lt;strong&gt;speed and accuracy&lt;/strong&gt;.  I was stunned by how fast they put my order together and how spot on the items were.  My Exec communicated promptly; I never felt like I was out of the loop.  However, the one thing they messed up on they got majorly wrong, partially due to me not being specific enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instacart wins at &lt;strong&gt;convenience and price&lt;/strong&gt;.  My wife liked the fact that Instacart &amp;ldquo;got the job done without getting in your way&amp;rdquo;.  They try to frontload all of the decision making so you won&amp;#39;t be bothered when the job is happening.  And despite their cloudy pricing model they came out cheapest for small-to-medium shopping trips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward I&amp;#39;ll use Exec for all my same-day trips and in the event I need complicated shopping orders. I&amp;#39;ll continue to use Instacart for small, simple orders that I want to plan in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;d like to use &lt;strong&gt;Postmates&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.postmates.com/invitation/c8WoO"&gt;click here to sign up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;d like to use &lt;strong&gt;Exec&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href="https://iamexec.com/j/c6976fa37696aacf1957c89356433f4c"&gt;click here to sign up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;d like to use &lt;strong&gt;Instacart&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href="http://inst.cr/t/cSkFJ3"&gt;click here to sign up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Special thanks to my wife for helping me organize and coordinate this experiment and to Kim MacVaugh for playing along.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/MVGODg3LaKU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://teejm.com/the-great-grocery-game</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jbrandonbb,2012:Post/tools-of-the-trade-or-why-you-need-to-keep-a-nail-clipper-handy-at-all-times</id>
    <published>2013-04-11T19:23:07-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T19:23:07-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/_U6e8JrtIFE/tools-of-the-trade-or-why-you-need-to-keep-a-nail-clipper-handy-at-all-times" />
    <author>
      <name>John Brandon</name>
      <uri>http://byjohnbrandon.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Tools of the Trade, or Why You Need to Keep a Nail Clipper Handy at All Times</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Journalism is an ancient profession dating back to the early heliomongrel days. (I made that word up, but it sounds old. Also, vaguely veterinarian.) Reporters tapped out articles using a stone tablet, which meant editors did not exist (air five, anyone?). Thankfully, as professions go, journalism has progressed to where it can now serve as an adequate form of income and not just an opportunity for people to flog you or hang you on a pole outside of their hut for making an error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, for anyone new to the field, things can be a little daunting. Let&amp;#39;s say you have just registered for a blog. Now what? Do you buy a fedora and a spiral notebook? (No.) Do you start pelting Apple with e-mails asking if you can test an iPad? (Please don&amp;#39;t.) Do you take a speed-typing class so you can blog every 14 seconds about inane subjects? (Not really, but apparently people have done that.) It&amp;#39;s often hard to know exactly what you should do first &amp;ndash; or second, after you have bought a MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a big believer in mentoring, and by &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; I mean I have had too many tacos. Over the years, I have tried to aid the burgeoning career of young writers, mostly by telling them how incredibly difficult it is to get Apple to respond to my e-mails. I will admit I sometimes make up random tips to see if they have any discernment or wherewithal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wait outside the office of the Microsoft PR organization. Pick out the oldest person in the group after they get done with a meeting, and slip them some money to see if they will tell you anything about the next version of Windows. Also, pant heavily even if you are not out of breath.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few have been arrested using this tactic. Some are still in prison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t claim to be an expert in the field. I think the Columbia Journalism Review is a gadget blog. Last week, I tried to explain what I do in professional terms to someone who was interested in getting a job at a nationally-known magazine or world-famous newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I keep FedEx busy,&amp;rdquo; I said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the last month, I purposefully tried to run a snowmobile out of gas to see whether the gauge was accurate, then I installed a thermostat in my hallway. One of my editors asked me to wear nail polish to test a laser keyboard for accuracy and to see if it reacted more to skin tone or finger movement (thankfully, my wife did that test). I wrote a review of the new Vampire Weekend. I played ping-pong with my son. He won.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;#39;m a professional router installer. My side job is writing about them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;#39;m a whiz at processing e-mail.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shaking his head, he walked away with a look that would make the expression &amp;ldquo;deer-in-the-headlights&amp;rdquo; offensive to deer. He&amp;#39;s now planning for a future in social work or the legal profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;#39;m here to help where I can. So I have decided to make a list of the tools you need if you have just started out in this wonderful line of work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. A good nail clipper &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As Gandalf would say, keep them tidy, keep them trim. (I mean if he was talking about fingernails, not the the Ring of Power.) Amazingly, if you do trim your fingernails on a regular basis, you will find you can type faster and more accurately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Extra seat cushions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 They comes in handy. See, you will be sitting for long periods of time. Think: months. I have not moved from my chair since 2004. Once, when I was at the airport with my wife, I overheard a marketing executive describe to a colleague what it would be like to speak at an upcoming conference. He had two pieces of advice. First, he said, make sure you lead off with a joke. Second, speak loudly because most of the journalists are fat, tired, and old. I thought, my gosh he nailed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Coffee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 I have been known to beg for free coffee on Twitter. I have even named specific brands. It is really more like a jet fuel for the mind, an elixir to stir up the mind and promote creativity. If you do not already drink coffee, please consider the field of law enforcement or retail sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Donuts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 They kind of go with the coffee, right? In just about every movie I&amp;#39;ve ever scene where there is a journalist involved there is almost always a donut co-star. You&amp;#39;ll be working late at night, wishing you were doing some sort of investigative bio or uncovering a secret criminal conspiracy and not live-blogging a Samsung event. Donuts help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. A time machine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 These help with deadlines. Check with Iran, they just invented one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Wikipedia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 This is one of your most indispensable tools. There are millions of people involved with the site and they all have advanced degrees, at least if you consider &amp;ldquo;having a Gmail account&amp;rdquo; an advanced degree. Some of this encyclopedia is accurate. Part of the joy of using it is discovering what was written by a professional ghost writer on behalf of the profile subject and what was written by a monkey with a good spell checker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Beer&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. A dictionary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 Spelling is kind of importent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. A large mirror&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 A like to keep one of these so I can check and see if I&amp;#39;m still breathing. Yup, we&amp;#39;re good. Pressed up against a tight deadline, like a baboon with his face plastered against a glass wall, I like to check and see if all the blood has drained out of my head. Once, I was working so late and typing so fast, I didn&amp;#39;t notice I had fallen asleep. When I woke up, the article I was working on was better than most of the stuff I do when I&amp;#39;m awake. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Sigur Rós&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 I hate to think of this Icelandic band as a &amp;ldquo;tool&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; especially when there&amp;#39;s another band with that name. But having a droning percussive ambient rock band handy is good for your productivity level. Also, they sing in gibberish so it&amp;#39;s not distracting like, say, punk rock or Bob Dylan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any other tips? Let me know by e-mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/_U6e8JrtIFE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://byjohnbrandon.com/tools-of-the-trade-or-why-you-need-to-keep-a-nail-clipper-handy-at-all-times</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:lexi,2012:Post/when-you-are-your-product</id>
    <published>2013-04-11T12:18:16-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T12:18:16-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/DaSeONlBUOs/when-you-are-your-product" />
    <author>
      <name>Lexi Lewtan</name>
      <uri>http://blog.lexilewtan.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>When You Are Your Product</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I became obsessed with the future of work a few years ago, when I was an Associate at Techstars. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the youngest associate, I was often asked to be a company&amp;#39;s intern, which turned into a conversation discussing if I knew interns. I quickly became the sherpa between the tech startup scene and my experience-hungry friends. Then, when I ran out of friends, I scaled through NYU clubs and became the product between NYU and the tech startup community. I wanted to build product, but I also wanted to move fast - so I became the product I needed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, my job is to evangelize and hire for Betaworks products. I&amp;#39;m essentially employed to become the machine I&amp;#39;ve wanted to build for three years, but on a much bigger scale. And once again, I&amp;#39;ve become the product I&amp;#39;ve wanted to build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I create perfect pipelines of every cold email, referral, and potential hire in Streak, which I then share with whoever I want.  I use latent, API filled internal databases to collect up-to-date information on every person and project I come across. And I create perfect shareable marketing materials (in my case job descriptions and specs) so that the buzz can grow around each role beyond my human voice. But there&amp;#39;s so much more to do, and I&amp;#39;m still not a real-time Linkedin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m becoming more automated in my process every day (which is in some ways the leanest form of MVP and in others the messiest). But I&amp;#39;m never going to be able to feel when every talented person is ready to do something that bigger, or to match that person to their perfect process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But having performed around a thousand  experiments that show what&amp;#39;s a real human behavior versus a hypothetical one, I no longer question whether or not the problem&amp;#39;s real. It is, and its buildable, and it&amp;#39;s coming -  and I know the whole competitive landscape, because I try every single one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuck serendipity, and fuck connections, and fuck job boards. I&amp;#39;m going to crack this thing. But for now, back to work - and email me if you&amp;#39;re interested in betaworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to comment &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5534406"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/DaSeONlBUOs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.lexilewtan.com/when-you-are-your-product</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:nate,2012:Post/draft-write-better-report-and-many-other-handy-tools-added</id>
    <published>2013-04-11T11:45:24-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T11:45:24-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/tsONCIPZQrA/draft-write-better-report-and-many-other-handy-tools-added" />
    <author>
      <name>Nathan Kontny</name>
      <uri>http://ninjasandrobots.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Draft: Write Better Report. Plus many other handy tools added.</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are many neat &lt;a href="https://draftin.com/"&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt; announcements today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Context aware comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image hosting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter publishing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Character count&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard shortcuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And the coolest thing. A Write Better Report. Easily see reasons why your published writing is or isn&amp;#39;t getting traffic.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Write Better Report&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I promised, Draft isn&amp;#39;t just an online editor. My goal is to make us better writers by investigating the tasks we have as writers and making those tasks simpler and easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One mistake I keep seeing people make, when they publish their writing, is that they don&amp;#39;t pay enough attention to attributes that might affect how much traction that writing will get. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#39;ll publish 2000 word posts, when their audience would prefer 500. Or they publish on Friday night, when no one might be paying attention and Monday morning might be a better idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make this type of analysis a lot easier to understand, and help people, including myself, learn what makes our writing get more attention than other writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#39;ve launched a feature that&amp;#39;s a little experimental, but I&amp;#39;ve had so much fun using it, I wanted to let you use it already. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any publishers setup in Draft&amp;#39;s settings, you&amp;#39;ll get a Reports button on your home page. (Setup a Twitter account, for example, to get this button.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/0b19uq8DRKiSPbQHOqct" alt=""&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you click that button you can get a report like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/tdpYJIwcRZ6IJQdEjgLf" alt=""&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the report tells you is how many Tweets on average your published writing is getting, broken up by various data points: when you published, what day, post length, and reading level. And you can see what attribute is outperforming others. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Draft is using the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flesch%E2%80%93Kincaid_readability_test"&gt;Flesch reading level&lt;/a&gt;. The higher the number the lower the reading level. From Wikipedia, &amp;ldquo;90.0–100.0 is easily understood by an average 11-year-old student. 0.0–30.0 is best understood by university graduates.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way you can see if the audience that likes to follow your writing might prefer your days when your writing is more or less sophisticated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use Draft&amp;#39;s publishing features to publish to Wordpress and Tumblr, your data will automatically be available in this report. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you publish somewhere else or want to add previously published stuff, I&amp;#39;ve got you covered. You can manually record publications you made. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just go to edit or view a Draft document (or create a new one) and click the Manually Publish menu item. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/6Gq8gDCASTGcyLSRYtG2" alt=""&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Record what, where, and when you published this document. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/a4xCeI04QRWLEzfFfsrU" alt=""&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you add some data points, you might see some trends in your writing. Maybe you shouldn&amp;#39;t publish on the weekends? Maybe publish in the mornings? Maybe you should make your writing a little easier to understand? Maybe it&amp;#39;s too short? Or too long?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a lot of neat possibilities to explore with this report. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Context aware comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the comment bubble in the lower right corner. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/i04rGyhdQRmaAZXPlJVQ" alt=""&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also add comments with the new action menu at the top right. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/yHwuO678RRaTea8TLxCD" alt=""&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comments are context aware. If you quote text from your document you&amp;#39;ll see it underlined in your comment. Hover over that quote, and you&amp;#39;ll see where that text is in your document. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/WaQAKqUvR2Wdnc7h0E3A" alt=""&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Image Hosting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now easily add images to your documents. Just use the menu again at the top right, or Shift+Ctrl+I. Pick an image from every cloud service or your local computer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Draft will host your image for you and properly format the image to embed it nicely within your text. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Twitter Publishing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use Draft to write and collaborate on your Tweets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to Places to Publish in your Settings to add as many Twitter accounts as you like. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new character count feature below, you can make sure to keep the Tweets under 140 characters (yes, it is aware of url shortening on Twitter&amp;#39;s side in its count).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Character Count&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on the word count at the bottom right of the page to flip it into a character count. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/Dw8sTycJRay1r2CqBzaS" alt=""&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#39;s really neat about the count is that the setting will carry over to collaborators. So if you are working on a 500 character email in character mode, your collaborator will also get put into character mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Keyboard Shortcuts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Added keyboard shortcuts for common formatting: &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;italics&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://draftin.com"&gt;links&lt;/a&gt;. As well as images and comments. Take a peak again at the action menu for what they all are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Improved collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before this week if you had a collaborator, they could only see one version of your document. After they made edits, their version wasn&amp;#39;t updated with your latest, making back and forth collaboration difficult. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s all been fixed. If you make further edits to your document after your collaborator is done, let them know to take another look at your document, and they&amp;#39;ll automatically be updated to your latest version. If they had any changes that you didn&amp;#39;t accept, they will be moved to a backup draft. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;#39;s it. :) It&amp;#39;s been one month since I publicly launched &lt;a href="https://draftin.com/"&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt;, and the feedback and use has exceeded everything I expected. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much. I hope you enjoy these new features. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stay up to date on Draft, my Twitter account is a good place: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/natekontny"&gt;https://twitter.com/natekontny&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or the official Draft Twitter account: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gooddraft"&gt;https://twitter.com/gooddraft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/tsONCIPZQrA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://ninjasandrobots.com/draft-write-better-report-and-many-other-handy-tools-added</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:bubs,2012:Post/being-bold</id>
    <published>2013-04-11T08:24:19-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T08:24:19-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/En0Jn3Vi4Wg/being-bold" />
    <author>
      <name>Darius "Bubs" Monsef</name>
      <uri>http://bubs.co</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Being Bold.</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;About a year ago, I emailed my investors and told them we were refocusing our company in a new direction&amp;hellip;  one reply really stood out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have learned that acting from your heart and being bold about it sets the stage for greatness.&amp;rdquo; George Zachary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While pivots tend to have a negative association, our current company wasn&amp;#39;t failing and by many measures it was very successful. COLOURlovers had more than 2 million registered users, was a 5x Webby Awards nominee for Best Community, doing $500k in annual revenue and had organic year over year growth&amp;hellip; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, I never intended to build COLOURlovers, it was a weekend project that didn&amp;#39;t die when monday rolled around.  Over the past 7 years it has connected with tens of thousands of people on a deep level&amp;hellip; largely I believe because we made being creative super simple and accessible.  I&amp;#39;m very passionate about the community we created and that empowerment of creativity we enabled, but if I&amp;#39;m honest, wearing the King of Color crown never fit right. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had the pleasure of being invited to speak at color conferences &amp;amp; workshops, but my talks are never directly about color and more about creativity.  I run the worlds largest color website &amp;amp; community&amp;hellip; and I&amp;#39;m not all that passionate about color.  What I am and have always been passionate about is the creative process and using technology to enhance that process for millions of people.  Again, if I&amp;#39;m honest, what we were doing was touching on my passion but I felt we could do more.  I felt we could really make a dent in the universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we are now building with &lt;a href="http://creativemarket.com/?utm_source=bubsco&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_campaign=being-bold"&gt;Creative Market&lt;/a&gt; is by far a bolder vision that without being cliche, I believe can truly change an industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We launched the marketplace 6 months ago and the response has been awesome. Not just in the personal feedback we get from our sellers &amp;amp; buyers, but for our company too.  We&amp;#39;ve had an evolution purpose internally and it&amp;#39;s been rejuvenating.  The revenue numbers help with inspiration too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what we&amp;#39;ve launched and the story we&amp;#39;ve told to date is just a piece of the bold vision we are pursuing.  This week we announced our platform and along with it a big part of the rest of our story.  CreativeMarket.com, in itself is doing things to improve, evolve and enhance the stock media &amp;amp; digital content market.  We&amp;#39;ve simplified licensing for buyers, gave sellers the most fair cut of sales compared to our competitors and brought all the different types of content we buy under one roof and enjoyable experience.  But, in an always-online world where every piece of creative software has an asset that can make somebody&amp;#39;s life easier, what we are doing with a platform will change everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try not to make bold predictions about the future, but I&amp;#39;m confident that not so long from now every app &amp;amp; creative software will have a living breathing marketplace built right into it&amp;hellip; and we&amp;#39;re working hard to cement ourselves into the foundation of this in-app commerce evolution.  It&amp;#39;s pretty crazy when you think about it; you fire up word or pages and the first thing you are presented with is an assortment of template types to help you get started&amp;hellip; because starting with a blank canvas is always the hardest part.  But those templates are limited and stagnant.  You can import images &amp;amp; clipart into your work with a similarly stale library that was packaged and shipped with your app years ago.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a designer, the broken creative process in Photoshop has always been very painful.  You leave the app to go hunting across the web for images, fonts, actions, brushes, etc. often finding shady sources with unclear licenses.  We asked 1,000+ members of Creative Market who use Creative Suite how much they spend each year on assets they use and on average they spend $150/yr.  Multiply that by the 40M customers Adobe has and there is a big $6B annual opportunity without an App-Store equivalent. So we just launched it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://creativemarket.com/photoshop-extension?utm_source=bubsco&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_campaign=being-bold"&gt;The Creative Market Photoshop Extension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the real story behind this extension launch isn&amp;#39;t just what this means for Photoshop, but the platform that is powering this extension&amp;hellip; the idea that this fluid in-app commerce can exist for all kinds of creative software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing stock media companies are largely that, media companies that saw most of their technological evolution happen when they put their CDs online 10 years ago.  Creative Market is a tech company in its DNA and we&amp;#39;re revealing the beginnings of what is coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making big changes &amp;amp; announcing your plans to the world can be a scary process, but I do believe George&amp;#39;s words and am acting from the heart, being bold and chasing for greatness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5532590"&gt;Continue the conversation on HackerNews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/En0Jn3Vi4Wg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://bubs.co/being-bold</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/itunes-smart-playlists</id>
    <published>2013-04-11T06:47:36-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T06:47:36-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/OVeeyXgILv8/itunes-smart-playlists" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>iTunes Smart Playlists</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;iTunes smart playlists are integral to the way I listen to purchased music. I currently only use two smart playlists, but they help me track music coming into my library and make sure I&amp;#39;m listening to the newest stuff. I originally created the two lists &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;1 Week&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Last Month&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; because the iTunes library can be a black hole for thousands and thousands of songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1 Week playlist shows only songs I&amp;#39;ve added to my library in the last 7 days and the Last Month playlist does the same, but for the last 30 days. These aren&amp;#39;t too different from the default &amp;ldquo;Recently added,&amp;rdquo; but I needed to split it up and tweak it. As you can see from the playlist configuration picture, I weed out podcasts, only keep checked items, and keep it live updating. This keeps the playlist just music and makes it a good travel, sync-able, option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tylerhayes_24579705887352_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tylerhayes_24579705887352_raw.png" alt="1week.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also keep a smart playlist for each year. All the music released in 2013 has its own playlist, an easy way to remember what came out this year versus last and so forth. It&amp;#39;s handy just a few months into the year, but the reason I originally made it years back was to help with making my best-of-the-year lists in December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another smart playlist I don&amp;#39;t currently use, but have in the past is &amp;ldquo;Discovering old favorites.&amp;rdquo; Basically the idea that you have a lot of forgotten favorites lurking beneath the surface of your library. The smart playlist for this looks something like, &amp;ldquo;Find all the songs with over X amount of plays &amp;ndash; maybe 30 &amp;ndash; that haven&amp;#39;t been listened to in over a year.&amp;rdquo; This type of playlist could contain a lot of songs, which is why I stopped using it, but for some people it may be the type of discovery they&amp;#39;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if only Rdio and other streaming service would add a niche feature like smart, user configurable, playlists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have a smart playlist you live by, let me know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/OVeeyXgILv8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/itunes-smart-playlists</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/your-startups-pricing-plan</id>
    <published>2013-04-11T06:10:58-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T06:10:58-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/gxi9u5Jj4SE/your-startups-pricing-plan" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>How To Price and Sell Your Startup's Product</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24582345886656_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24582345886656_raw.jpg" alt="old_cash_register.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every SaaS business must to decide how to charge for the service. Pricing plans are some of the most difficult decisions to make. Equally important to the price is determining the point at which the customer pays - the conversion point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a four different models that I&amp;#39;ve experienced: up front payment, freemium, limited free trials, money back guarantee. Picking the right one depends on a number of different factors. Below is a table that summarizes these four approaches.
&lt;table&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pricing Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Value&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Complexity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End User Buys&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avg Seat $&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freemium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Increases with time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Simple&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Yes or No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Low&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited Free Trial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Increases with time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Complex&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Low/Medium&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Up Front Payment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Immediate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Simple&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Money Back Guarantee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Immediate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Complex&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style="padding: 5px;"&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Freemium&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freemium is a strategy for products whose value proposition is simply conveyed and whose value increases with time. Evernote&amp;#39;s value compounds with the data the user enters into the database. Expensify&amp;#39;s utility increases with the number of expense reporters on the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freemium businesses must target markets with very large user bases because the conversion to paid rates vary between 2 to 4%. To drive $50M in annual revenue at that conversion rate and $100/year subscription, you would need 17M users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the end users are buyers (typically in consumer services). Other times (for enterprise customers), end users are sales prequalifiiers who create a groundswell within an organization to convert to paid. Given enough users of a product in an organization, the enterprise can be upsold to a company wide license. Freemium distribution enables a company to acquire those users inexpensively.
&lt;h2&gt;Limited Free Trial&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main difference between freemium and trial products is product complexity: trial products are more complex and need time for the user to gain a deeper understanding of the value. CRM tools like Salesforce and 37Signal&amp;#39;s HighRise both use limited trials. The goal with these marketing mechanisms is to drive customers to explore the product for a brief period of time and then force a conversion. Allow too much time to pass and the customer will forget the value proposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These kinds of products tend to require significant user behavior change so these products must market a promise and then use the conversion to paid event to enforce that behavior change (carrot + stick).  Because of the behavior change, these products are marketed to decision makers who select the software for their teams: product managers, tech leads and heads of sales. Many of the tests I&amp;#39;ve seen have indicated shorter trial periods are better: 7 days is better than 14 days is better than 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Up Front Payment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To pursue up front payment, you need an established brand with a clear value proposition and you sell the product to the end-user. Adobe&amp;#39;s Creative Suite is a canonical example. Customers know what the software can do and if they need it, customers will pay for it. The same is true for AutoCad, MS Office, and operating systems. Most of these products are high cost per seat products. Because they are well-known in the market, they command a price premium.
&lt;h2&gt;Money Back Guarantee&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For products lacking an established brand, but offering an immediate value proposition and charging a high average seat value, there is no better solution than the money back guarantee. It mitigates the customers commitment phobia but establishes a billing relationship at the outset. This pricing strategy requires contact with a sales or account management team which implies a higher cost of sales. Ideally, higher conversion rates mitigate these costs. In other words, the up front commitment is a sales pre-qualifier. Your sales team will have fewer, higher quality leads. Plus, your sales team will have direct product feedback to share with the product team.  &lt;a href="http://www.rightnow.com/crm-news-7154.php"&gt;Oracle offers this for many of their products &lt;/a&gt;as &lt;a href="http://montclairadvisors.com/blog/2011/12/sbp-eloqua/"&gt;do Eloqua.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While each product and target market have some unique attributes, consider the time to value, complexity of the product, product complexity and your sales model (freemium vs sales) when you do price your startup&amp;#39;s product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/gxi9u5Jj4SE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/your-startups-pricing-plan</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:jamietie,2012:Post/why-the-ap-was-right-to-stop-saying-illegal-immigrant</id>
    <published>2013-04-10T10:44:16-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-10T10:44:16-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/6LL_sCJePkY/why-the-ap-was-right-to-stop-saying-illegal-immigrant" />
    <author>
      <name>Jamie Kelly</name>
      <uri>http://blog.jamietie.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Why the AP was right to stop saying "Illegal immigrant"</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://blog.ap.org/2013/04/02/illegal-immigrant-no-more/"&gt;Associated Press announced&lt;/a&gt; this month that from now on, &amp;ldquo;illegal immigrant&amp;rdquo; is no longer the correct style. It&amp;#39;s a change that&amp;#39;s been a long time coming, and one that could have a major impact on the debate over immigration. And it&amp;#39;s the correct move because it offers reporters a chance to clarify and inform, rather than inflame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps not surprisingly, not everyone is thrilled with the change. At the New Republic, &lt;a href="http://www.newrepublic.com/article/112867/associated-presss-illegal-immigrant-change-makes-no-sense"&gt;John McWhorter writes&lt;/a&gt; that it&amp;#39;s a crime against logic, because people who enter the U.S. without proper permission are, &lt;em&gt;prima facie&lt;/em&gt;, illegal immigrants, and that we use adjectives like &amp;ldquo;convicted&amp;rdquo; to describe people already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His argument that the basis of the change is the slogan that &amp;ldquo;A person shouldn&amp;#39;t be called illegal&amp;rdquo; is a straw man, though. The change in style has the effect of being more humane, but there are other good reasons, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the AP already recommends using language that describes rather than damns. A good example: someone uses a wheelchair, they aren&amp;#39;t confined to a wheelchair. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that applies to crimes, as well. For the most part, despite what McWhorter says, in most cases, someone wouldn&amp;#39;t be referred to as a &amp;ldquo;drunk driver.&amp;rdquo; Before trial a reporter would write that a person was accused of drunken driving, and after conviction, that a person was convicted of drunken driving. The larger point is that the word illegal should be applied to the &lt;em&gt;action that is against the law&lt;/em&gt;, which is what the AP now recommends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stylebook no longer sanctions the term &amp;ldquo;illegal immigrant&amp;rdquo; or the use of &amp;ldquo;illegal&amp;rdquo; to describe a person. Instead, it tells users that &amp;ldquo;illegal&amp;rdquo; should describe only an action, such as living in or immigrating to a country illegally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of illegal immigrant&amp;mdash;or worse simply &amp;ldquo;illegal,&amp;rdquo; which despite McWhorter&amp;#39;s protests is a slur, and a clear one at that, because it refers not to an action but the entirety of a person&amp;#39;s existence&amp;mdash;a reporter would write about someone entering the U.S. illegally. Changing that doesn&amp;#39;t imply approval of the act, it just brings the language more in line with the rest of the AP&amp;#39;s style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are extreme cases in which a description is applied to a person instead of an action. Mcwhorter gives the example of a serial killer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To frame it as that illegal immigrant is a “slur” requires that on principle we apply the same judgment to, say, serial killer (what about the times in between murders when he isn’t killing anyone?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, of course, no reporter would call someone a serial killer until that person had been convicted. And that&amp;#39;s without mentioning the not-so-subtle false equivalence between serial murder and illegal immigration. Both actions are against the law, but there is an enormous difference of scale, and one is a criminal action, while the other is against civil law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best reason for the change is that it allows a clarification of what, exactly, is going on. Just as journalists are not supposed to convict people accused of crimes with their words, they are now supposed to attribute any accusation of someone entering the country illegally, as well as to clarify the specifics of each case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not describe people as violating immigration laws without attribution.&lt;br&gt;
Specify wherever possible how someone entered the country illegally and from where. Crossed the border? Overstayed a visa? What nationality?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are all important questions, and they help actually inform people. And despite protestations from &lt;a href="http://ideas.time.com/2013/04/09/viewpoint-banning-the-term-illegal-immigrant-wont-change-the-stigma/"&gt;McWhorter in &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; about political correctness&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;a phrase so overused that it is essentially meaningless and can be marshaled against any effort to make language more humane and accurate&amp;mdash;that information, provided in clear, accurate language, is essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both articles, McWhorter presupposes that any change in language about immigration must be an effort to change the way people think about immigration, and to question the rightness of immigration law as it now stands, But that isn&amp;#39;t necessarily the case. Some of the key aims of journalism&amp;mdash;fairness, accuracy, and clarity&amp;mdash;are all served by this change, and that&amp;#39;s enough to make it the correct decision, without delving into the debate over immigration itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immigration is a serious topic, and it deserves a serious discussion. By removing loaded terms and pejoratives from news stories, the new AP policy will help facilitate that serious discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/6LL_sCJePkY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.jamietie.com/why-the-ap-was-right-to-stop-saying-illegal-immigrant</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:peteforde,2012:Post/i-know-the-solution-but-its-illegal</id>
    <published>2013-04-10T07:30:30-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-10T07:30:30-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/apUqnQGkQZY/i-know-the-solution-but-its-illegal" />
    <author>
      <name>Pete Forde</name>
      <uri>http://hackertourism.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>I know the solution, but it's illegal</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you have two car dealerships, and one of them offers financing&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;which one do you think will sell more cars?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/peteforde_24580299743676_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_peteforde_24580299743676_raw.jpg" alt="Red vs. Blue"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many start-ups are match-makers that become irrelevant as soon as the buyer and seller party are acquainted. There is value created in these &amp;ldquo;marketplaces&amp;rdquo; but founders are stumped when it comes to capturing any of that value for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My proposal: &lt;strong&gt;make it possible to finance the purchase of goods via instant approval financing, presented as a first-class option&lt;/strong&gt; alongside Visa and PayPal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s say a founder is passionate about something enough that they create a directory of every place to obtain it, complete with recommendations and reviews. Blood, sweat and tears are emitted and a community emerges. They make no attempt to cheapen the experience through advertising, bait-and-switch membership requirements or elaborate tracking schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founder can approach every vendor listed in their directory with an opportunity to expand their customer base to include people who don&amp;#39;t have cash in hand. They would be paid instantly and never have the hassle of dealing with financial institutions themselves. In exchange, they would agree to give up some percentage of their gross profit on the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course the vendors don&amp;#39;t have to agree to participate, at the expense of implicit second-class treatment in the directory. There are many people who simply can not complete a transaction unless the option of credit is on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of system already exists: &lt;a href="http://www.pay4later.com/"&gt;Pay4Later&lt;/a&gt; is a successful company providing this service to UK retailers today. The company was &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/07/27/post-credit-crunch-pay4later-lets-uk-online-retailers-offer-customers-finance/"&gt;covered on TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt; back in 2010, and my [admittedly cursory] investigation into their developer documentation suggests that they are the real deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most compelling evidence is that they have competition: Hitachi offers &lt;a href="http://www.hitachicapital.co.uk/pbf/"&gt;PaybyFinance&lt;/a&gt; and there are others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, there&amp;#39;s no comparable service that I can find for US or Canadian companies. It&amp;#39;s a tightly regulated industry and a legitimate company would have to spend millions of dollars in legal fees to get the regulators to consider a new way of doing things. Regulators don&amp;#39;t see the glow of opportunity through the fog of unknowable risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toronto&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.financeit.ca/en"&gt;FinanceIt&lt;/a&gt; would seem to be poised to offer instant approval financing online, but they have no intention of doing so thanks to the rigid inflexibility of the powers that be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically companies like &lt;a href="http://wonga.com/"&gt;Wonga&lt;/a&gt; (260% APR) and &lt;a href="http://moneymart.com/"&gt;MoneyMart&lt;/a&gt; (up to 599.64% APR) could get into this space, but nobody should want that. You can&amp;#39;t care about your users and send them into the jaws of sociopathic usurers in the same breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not like the technology for a new player to offer reasonable loans online is beyond us. According to AngelList, there are &lt;a href="https://angel.co/fraud-detection"&gt;21 &amp;ldquo;fraud detection&amp;rdquo; startups&lt;/a&gt;. Companies like &lt;a href="https://siftscience.com/"&gt;SiftScience&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.the41.com/"&gt;41st Parameter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://signifyd.com/"&gt;Signifyd&lt;/a&gt; all market powerful tools designed to eliminate risk from transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a market opportunity worth billions. It&amp;#39;s just that it&amp;#39;s illegal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;#39;s been a way to build it, there&amp;#39;ll be a way to destroy it
Things are not all that out of control&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stereolab - &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Z-ufNCiK48"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Crest&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do large middle-men stay relevant in the Google era? Usually through banding together and hiring lawyers and lobbyists to intimidate and pay off politicians that will uphold protectionist laws. You can see the fear Uber puts into the taxi industry, and the laughable, red-faced rage of car dealerships throwing temper-tantrums when Tesla only sells their cars online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trade organizations that exist to keep anti-competitive laws in place aren&amp;#39;t suggesting that their member companies are doing anything precious or special. They can only rely on making sure that people are afraid of change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow, it&amp;#39;s sanctioned behaviour for certain kinds of companies to demand legal protection from competition. This is nepotistic counter-innovation in it&amp;#39;s most ugly state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stifling competition to ensure profit? Legal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lacking the monopoly scale of eBay or Craigslist, any attempt to introduce additional process overhead to an existing, well-understood flow — whether it be brokered communication, transaction fees or even just a simple account creation — is often a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web has done an excellent job of purging the world&amp;#39;s bottom-feeding middle-men. The travel, real-estate, and used vehicle industries will never be the same, &lt;a href="http://www.hipmonk.com/"&gt;thank goodness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This market efficiency has come at a terrible cost to those who would seek to make a profit in benevolent arbitrage. Those brave souls who want help someone find what they are looking for are stuck between a rock and a hard place. Advertising makes your site look cheap and generates pennies a month unless you&amp;#39;re operating at a large scale. Few visitors will complete even a free account creation process and fewer still would dutifully report successful financial transactions made. Once the potential customer leaves to go to a 3rd party site, you&amp;#39;re unlikely to hear from either the buyer or seller ever again. There&amp;#39;s no mechanism for oversight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instant-approval financing would be one possible way for a marketplace to add value. Too bad: it&amp;#39;s not legal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without substantial progress towards dismantling the status quo, most value-added listings directory founders would be best advised to keep their day jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="http://www.drivetrainagency.com/"&gt;Dan Grigsby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dvanliere"&gt;Diederik van Liere&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.tattoohero.com/"&gt;Steve Tannahill&lt;/a&gt; for reading drafts of this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/peteforde/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. And remember: &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/60345640"&gt;don&amp;#39;t buy stuff you can&amp;#39;t afford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/apUqnQGkQZY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://hackertourism.com/i-know-the-solution-but-its-illegal</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/startup-judo-the-secrets-you-should-know-before-starting-a-company</id>
    <published>2013-04-10T07:20:27-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-10T07:20:27-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/E6yCsdMIyNE/startup-judo-the-secrets-you-should-know-before-starting-a-company" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Startup Judo - The Secret You Should Know Before Starting a Company</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24580865301372_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24580865301372_raw.jpg" alt="judo.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his Stanford GSB lectures,&lt;a href="http://blakemasters.tumblr.com/post/22866240816/peter-thiels-cs183-startup-class-11-notes-essay"&gt; Peter Thiel spoke about secrets&lt;/a&gt;. But he defined secrets for startups in a different way than one might expect. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A secret is not an unknown. Rather, it’s something just not widely believed to be achievable or feasible. In other words, it&amp;#39;s an insight, a thesis that isn&amp;#39;t widely held. Exploiting that secret should be the aim of every entrepreneur. Leveraging the secret means disruption and ultimately success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you start a company, find this kind of secret - an insight that will help you maximize leverage against your competitors and that doesn&amp;#39;t oppose strength with strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think about it like Judo. There are two basic tenets of judo:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First: never to oppose strength with strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second: maximize leverage.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;#39;t compete with Google by building a better search engine. Google will put 100x the engineering team, leverage their 1,000x greater click data and out spend you on marketing by 10,000x. Don&amp;#39;t oppose strength with strength. Startups shouldn&amp;#39;t rely on more manpower, bigger ad budgets or data access advantages in fields where there is a large incumbent. During its infancy, Google won with distribution. Most internet companies believed search wasn&amp;#39;t valuable. Google thought differently. They offered to power all the major portals&amp;#39; search engines and eventually dethroned them. This was Google&amp;#39;s secret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question, then, is what to leverage. Startups&amp;#39; advantage is speed which means they can explore new technologies (mobile apps, Node, Meteor, Cassandra, RedShift) which build better products, new distribution channels (mobile and tv app stores, virality, OpenGraph) which reach customers more cost effectively or novel product designs (Path, Dropbox, Expensify).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies are now using distribution as their secret - mobile app stores and Facebook Open Graph enable startups to access hundreds of millions of users in ways that incumbents simply aren&amp;#39;t prepared to leverage. Expensify uses mobile app stores to acquire hundreds of thousands of SMBs in ways that their market&amp;#39;s incumbent, Concur (market cap $3B), simply can&amp;#39;t copy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find your secret and you&amp;#39;ll be well on your way to disrupting a huge market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NB: Thiel does mention other kinds of secrets. For example, PayPal&amp;#39;s financial losses due to fraud which are secrets in the traditional sense. It&amp;#39;s important to think about the judo principles when deciding whether to keep these secret. Simply put, if a competitor can gain leverage by using the secrets you disclose, keep them closely held.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/E6yCsdMIyNE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/startup-judo-the-secrets-you-should-know-before-starting-a-company</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:cwebbdesign,2012:Post/promise-deferred-objects-in-javascript-pt2-practical-use</id>
    <published>2013-04-10T07:08:06-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-10T07:08:06-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/jPyEVEiU4jw/promise-deferred-objects-in-javascript-pt2-practical-use" />
    <author>
      <name>Chris Webb</name>
      <uri>http://blog.mediumequalsmessage.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Promise &amp; Deferred Objects in JavaScript Pt.2: in Practice</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="http://blog.mediumequalsmessage.com/promise-deferred-objects-in-javascript-pt1-theory-and-semantics" title="Promise and Deferred Objects in JavaScript Pt.1: Semantics and Theory"&gt;part 1 of this post&lt;/a&gt;, I spent a lot of time looking at the theory of promises and deferreds: what promises are and how they behave. Now it&amp;#39;s time to actually explore some ways to use promises and deferreds in JavaScript and dive into some best practices. I&amp;#39;ll start with some basic uses and examples of promises and then will dive into a number of specifics pertaining to using promises in jQuery. While the exact specifics of the API may vary from your chosen library, there is enough overlap in concepts to illustrate the use of promises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The code samples will use jQuery in spite of jQuery&amp;#39;s deviations from the Promise/A proposal, which is particularly noticeable in the case of error handling and when working with other promise libraries. Since part 1 discussed and included links to in-depth articles on the topic, I will refrain from saying anything else about it in this post. The use of jQuery is still wide-spread and their implementation serves as an introduction for many to the use of promises both of which lead me to believe that it is valuable to have an understanding of working with promises in jQuery. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Sequencing Patterns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A deferred is an object representing work that is not yet done and a promise is an object representing a value that is not yet known. In other words, promises / deferreds allow us to represent &amp;#39;simple&amp;#39; tasks and can be easily combined to represent complex tasks and their flows, allowing for fine-grained control over sequencing. This means we can write asynchronous JavaScript parallel to how we write synchronous code. Additionally, promises make it relatively simple to abstract small pieces of functionality shared across multiple asynchronous tasks &amp;mdash; consider as an example loading animations, progress animations etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s begin with a global view of three common sequencing patterns that promises make possible: stacked, parallel and sequential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stacked&lt;/strong&gt;: bind multiple handlers anywhere in the application to the same promise event.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  var request = $.ajax(url);

  request.done(function () {
      console.log(&amp;#39;Request completed&amp;#39;);
  });

  // Somewhere else in the application
  request.done(function (retrievedData) {
      $(&amp;#39;#contentPlaceholder&amp;#39;).html(retrievedData);
  });
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parallel tasks&lt;/strong&gt;: ask multiple promises to return a promise which alerts of their mutual completion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  $.when(taskOne, taskTwo).done(function () {
      console.log(&amp;#39;taskOne and taskTwo are finished&amp;#39;);
  });
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sequential tasks&lt;/strong&gt;: execute tasks in sequential order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var step1, step2, url;

url = &amp;#39;http://fiddle.jshell.net&amp;#39;;

  step1 = $.ajax(url);

  step2 = step1.then(
    function (data) {
        var def = new $.Deferred();

        setTimeout(function () {
            console.log(&amp;#39;Request completed&amp;#39;);
            def.resolve();
        },2000);

      return def.promise();

  },
    function (err) {
        console.log(&amp;#39;Step1 failed: Ajax request&amp;#39;);
    }
  );
  step2.done(function () {
      console.log(&amp;#39;Sequence completed&amp;#39;)
      setTimeout(&amp;quot;console.log(&amp;#39;end&amp;#39;)&amp;quot;,1000);
  });
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These patterns can be combined or used separately building up complex tasks and workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Common Use Cases&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many examples of promise use cases pertain to Ajax requests and UI animations. In fact jQuery even returns promises by default from Ajax requests. This makes sense given that promises are ideal for asynchronous tasks whose completion needs to be handled in a unique way. However, that doesn&amp;#39;t mean that the use of promises should be limited to these use case. In fact, promises tend to be a tool worth considering anytime you might otherwise reach for a callback. That said, let&amp;#39;s have a look at some ways we can use promises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ajax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of using promises with Ajax requests can be found throughout this post, so I will skip an example here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can create a promise based timeout function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  function wait(ms) {
      var deferred = $.Deferred();
      setTimeout(deferred.resolve, ms);

     // We just need to return the promise not the whole deferred.
     return deferred.promise();
  }

  // Use it
  wait(1500).then(function () {
      // Do something brilliant here!
  });
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animation &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously the following animation is completely useless, but it serves as an example of how promises and animations can be used together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  var fadeIn = function (el) {

      var promise = $(el).animate({
          opacity: 1
      }, 1500);

      // Dynamically create and return an observable promise object which will be resolved when the animation completes.
     return promise.promise();
  };

var fadeOut = function(el) {

    var promise = $(el).animate({
        opacity: 0
    }, 1500);

    // Dynamically create and return an observable promise object
      return promise.promise();
};

// With the setup out of the way, we can now do one of the following.

// Parallel
$.when(
    fadeOut(&amp;#39;div&amp;#39;), 
    fadeIn(&amp;#39;div&amp;#39;)
).done(function () {
    console.log(&amp;#39;Animation finished&amp;#39;);
    $(&amp;#39;p&amp;#39;).css(&amp;#39;color&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;red&amp;#39;);
});

// OR
// Chained
fadeOut(&amp;#39;div&amp;#39;).then(function (el) {
    fadeIn(el); // returns a promise
}).then(function (el) {
    fadeOut(el); // returns a promise
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synchronizing parallel tasks with $.when()&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
      var promiseOne, promiseTwo, handleSuccess, handleFailure;
      
        // Promises
        promiseOne = $.ajax({ url: '../test.html' });
        promiseTwo = $.ajax({ url: '../test.html' });
          
          
        // Success callbacks
        // .done() will only run if the promise is successfully resolved
        promiseOne.done(function () {
            console.log('PromiseOne Done');
        });
        
        promiseTwo.done(function () {
            console.log('PromiseTwo Done');
        });
      
        // $.when() creates a new promise which will be:
        // resolved if both promises inside are resolved
        // rejected if one of the promises fails
        $.when(
            promiseOne,
            promiseTwo
        )
        .done(function () {
            console.log('promiseOne and promiseTwo are done');
        })
        .fail(function () {
            console.log('One of our promises failed');
        });
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decoupling events and application logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also use events to trigger resolution / failure of promises, passing values through at the same time which allows us to decouple application, DOM and event logic ( &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://jsfiddle.net/cwebbdesign/NEssP/2/"&gt;jsfiddle here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var def, getData, updateUI, resolvePromise;

// The Promise and handler
def = new $.Deferred();

updateUI = function (data) {
    $(&amp;#39;p&amp;#39;).html(&amp;#39;I got the data!&amp;#39;);
    $(&amp;#39;div&amp;#39;).html(data);
};
getData = $.ajax({
          url: &amp;#39;/echo/html/&amp;#39;, 
          data: {
              html: &amp;#39;testhtml&amp;#39;, 
              delay: 3
          }, 
          type: &amp;#39;post&amp;#39;
    })
    .done(function(resp) {
        return resp;
    })
    .fail(function (error) {
        throw new Error(&amp;quot;Error getting the data&amp;quot;);
    });


// Event Handler
resolvePromise = function (ev) {
    ev.preventDefault();
    def.resolve(ev.type, this);
    return def.promise();
};

// Bind the Event
$(document).on(&amp;#39;click&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;button&amp;#39;, resolvePromise);

def.then(function() {
    return getData;   
})
.then(function(data) {
    updateUI(data);
})
.done(function(promiseValue, el) {
    console.log(&amp;#39;The promise was resolved by: &amp;#39;, promiseValue, &amp;#39; on &amp;#39;, el);
});


// Console output: The promise was resolved by: click on &amp;lt;button&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Gotcha&amp;#39;s: understanding .then() in jQuery&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to demonstrate a couple &amp;ldquo;gotcha&amp;#39;s&amp;rdquo;, these final examples will walk through part of my learning process when I first started playing with promises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s assume the following two utility functions for the following examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// Utility Functions
function wait(ms) {
      var deferred = $.Deferred();
      setTimeout(deferred.resolve, ms);
      return deferred.promise();
}
function notifyOfProgress(message, promise) {
    console.log(message + promise.state());
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first attempt at chaining promises together looked something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// Naive attempt at working with .then()

// Create two new deferred objects
var aManualDeferred = new $.Deferred(),
    secondManualDeferred = aManualDeferred.then(function () {
        console.log(&amp;#39;1 started&amp;#39;);

        wait(3500).done(function () {
            console.log(&amp;#39;1 ended&amp;#39;);
        });
    });

// After secondManualDeferred is resolved
secondManualDeferred.then(function () {
    console.log(&amp;#39;2 started&amp;#39;);

    wait(2500).done(function () {
        console.log(&amp;#39;2 ended&amp;#39;);
    });
});

// Resolve the first promise
aManualDeferred.resolve();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon executing this, the console output is what I would have expected had I not used promises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1 started
2 started
2 ended
1 ended
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jQuery API says that .then() is chainable and returns a new promise, so my expectation was that whatever I wrapped in .then() and chained together would occur sequentially and wait for any tasks to finish before moving to the next. Clearly that&amp;#39;s not what happened. Why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How does .then() actually work?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking in the jQuery source code, we find that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.then() always returns a new promise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.then() must be passed a function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If .then() is not passed a function:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the new promise will have the same behaviour as the original promise ( &lt;em&gt;which means it is immediately resolved/rejected&lt;/em&gt; ),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the input inside .then() will be executed but is ignored by .then()&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if .then() is passed a function which returns a promise object:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the new promise will have the same behaviour as the returned promise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
    var deferred = $.Deferred(),
        secondDeferred = deferred.then(function () {
          return $.Deferred(function (newDeferred) {
            setTimeout(function() {
              console.log('timeout complete');
            newDeferred.resolve();
          }, 3000);
        });
      }),
      thirdDeferred = secondDeferred.then(function () {
          console.log('thirdDeferred');
      });

    secondDeferred.done(function () {
        console.log('secondDeferred.done');
    });
    deferred.resolve();
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if .then() is passed a function which returns a value, the value becomes the value of the new object&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
    var deferred = $.Deferred(),
        filteredValue = deferred.then(function (value) {
          return value * value;
        });

    filteredValue.done(function (value) {
        console.log(value);
    });

    deferred.resolve(2); // 4
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably already see ( &lt;em&gt;if you didn&amp;#39;t see it right away&lt;/em&gt; ) why my version didn&amp;#39;t work.
I didn&amp;#39;t explicitly return a promise from .then() so the new promise created by .then() had the same values as the promise it was chained to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Avoiding the descent into callback hell&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know we need to pass .then() a function for it to be able to do it&amp;#39;s job and we know we need to return a promise from .then(). So we could do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// Anti-pattern - Return to callback hell

var aManualDeferred = new $.Deferred();

aManualDeferred.then(function () {
    console.log(&amp;#39;1 started&amp;#39;);

    return wait(3500).then(function () {
        console.log(&amp;#39;1 ended&amp;#39;);
    }).then(function () {
        console.log(&amp;#39;2 started&amp;#39;);

        return wait(2500).done(function () {
            console.log(&amp;#39;2 ended&amp;#39;);
        });
    });
});

// Resolve the first promise
aManualDeferred.resolve();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works. Unfortunately, it&amp;#39;s starting the decent back into callback hell which is one of the things that promises are supposed to help us avoid. Luckily, there are a number of ways to handle this without decending into the territory of deeply nested functions. How we choose to solve it, is of course dependent on our particular situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Avoiding extensive use of unnamed promises&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could for example do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// A chain
// Create new deferred objects
var aManualDeferred = $.Deferred();

aManualDeferred.then(function () {
    console.log(&amp;#39;1 started&amp;#39;);

    // We need to return this, we return a new promise which is resolved upon completion.
    return wait(3500);
})

.then(function () {
    console.log(&amp;#39;1 ended&amp;#39;);
})

.then(function () {
    console.log(&amp;#39;2 started&amp;#39;);
    return wait(2500);
})

.then(function () {
    console.log(&amp;#39;2 ended&amp;#39;);
});

// Resolve the first promise
aManualDeferred.resolve();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version admittedly reads very nicely but has the disadvantage of only one named promise which doesn&amp;#39;t really give us the fine-grained control over each step in the process that is desirable in many situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Unwinding promises and their handlers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming we want to avoid deeply nested functions and that we should name our promises to give us access to each step of the process, here is a final version:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var aManualDeferred, secondManualDeferred, thirdManualDeferred;

// Create two new deferred objects
aManualDeferred = $.Deferred();

secondManualDeferred = aManualDeferred.then(function () {
    console.log(&amp;#39;1 started&amp;#39;);

    // We need to return this, we return a new promise which is resolved upon completion.
    return wait(3500);
})
.done(function () {
    console.log(&amp;#39;1 ended&amp;#39;);
});

thirdManualDeferred = secondManualDeferred.then(function () {
    console.log(&amp;#39;2 started&amp;#39;);
    return wait(2500);
})
.done(function () {
    console.log(&amp;#39;2 ended&amp;#39;);
});

// Check current state
thirdManualDeferred.notify(
    notifyOfProgress(&amp;#39;thirdManualDeferred &amp;#39;, thirdManualDeferred)
);

// Resolve the first promise
aManualDeferred.resolve();

// Console output
// aManualDeferred pending
// secondManualDeferred pending
// 1 started
// 1 ended
// 2 started
// 2 ended
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantage gained by this version is that we now have 3 steps which we can clearly refer to giving the advantage of being able to ask each promise for it&amp;#39;s state to send notifications of progress, or later manage our sequencing as needed without having to re-write the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Context and passing data&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Ajax example earlier, we saw that we can pass a value to .resolve() and .fail(). If a promise is resolved with a value, it returns that value as itself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var passingData = function () {
    var def = new $.Deferred();

    setTimeout(function () {
        def.resolve(&amp;#39;50&amp;#39;);
    }, 2000);

   return def.promise();               
};

passingData().done(function (value) {
      console.log(value);
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also set &amp;#39;this&amp;#39; when we resolve a promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// Create an object
var myObject = {
    myMethod: function (myString) {
        console.log(&amp;#39;myString was passed from&amp;#39;, myString);
    }
};

// Create deferred
var deferred = $.Deferred();

// deferred.done(doneCallbacks [, doneCallbacks ])
deferred.done(function (method, string) {
    console.log(this); // myObject

    // myObject.myMethod(myString);
    this[method](string);
});

deferred.resolve.call(myObject, &amp;#39;myMethod&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;the context&amp;#39;);

=&amp;gt; myString was passed from the context

// We could also do this:
// deferred.resolveWith(myObject, [&amp;#39;myMethod&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;resolveWith&amp;#39;]);
// but it&amp;#39;s somewhat annoying to pass an array of arguments.

// =&amp;gt; myString was passed from resolveWith
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Best Practices&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve attempted to illustrate some best practices along the way but for the sake of clarity, allow me to recap them under one heading. Quite frankly most of these amount to applying other best-practices when using promises: in particular: DRY and the Single Responsibility Principle. In &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;name your promises&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var step2 = step1.then()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;separate handler functions from the promise logic by calling a named function from .then() and separate functionality into reusable bits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var someReusableFunctionality = function () {
    // do something
};

step2.then(someReusableFunctionality);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;when it&amp;#39;s logical, return a promise instead of a deferred so that nobody else can inadvertantly resolve/reject the promise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;step2.then(function() {
    // we don&amp;#39;t want to give resolution / rejection powers 
    // to the wrong parties, so we just return the promise.
    return deferred.promise();
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;don&amp;#39;t descend into nested callback hell or nested promise hell&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By following these best practices, we can reap the most benefit from promises. We can craft decoupled applications with readable code, gain fine-gained control over asynchronous event sequencing, handle values that don&amp;#39;t exist yet as if they do and operations that haven&amp;#39;t completed yet as if they have.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;jQuery Reference&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;d like to wrap-up with an overview of the jQuery API since my code examples have focused on jQuery&amp;#39;s implementation of promises. If you&amp;#39;re using a different implementation of promises, you may want to skip to the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deferred.always(), deferred.done(), deferred.fail() return the deferred object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deferred.then(), deferred.when(), .promise() return a promise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$.ajax() and $.get() return promise objects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;instead of using .resolveWith() and .rejectWith(), you can call resolve with the context you want it to inherit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pass the deferred.promise() around instead of the deferred itself as the deferred object itself cannot be resolved or rejected through it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://api.jquery.com/jQuery.Deferred/" title="jQuery documentation .Deferred()"&gt;$.Deferred()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A constructor that creates a new deferred object. Accepts an optional init function which will be executed immediately after the deferred is created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deferred.always()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Returns the deferred object and executes attached functions upon resolution or rejection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$.get(&amp;quot;test.php&amp;quot;)

// Execute regardless of resolution or success
.always(function() {
    alertCompletedRequest();
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deferred.then()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Adds handlers which will be called on resolved, rejected or in progress and returns a promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$.get(&amp;quot;test.php&amp;quot;)

// Execute regardless of resolution or success
.then(function() {
    alertSuccess(),
    alertFailure(),
    alertProgress();
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deferred.when()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Returns a new promise based on the completion of multiple promises. If any promise is rejected, .when() is rejected and if all promises are resolved, it is resolved. It is noteworthy that a non-promise can be passed to .when() and it will be treated as a resolved promise. Also of note is that it will return a single value only if all other promises resolve to a single value or an array, otherwise it resolves to an array.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deferred.resolve(optionalArgs)&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;deferred.reject(optionalArgs)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Resolve or reject the deferred object and call handler functions ( &lt;em&gt;.done(), .fail(), .always(), .then()&lt;/em&gt; ) with any supplied arguments and pass their context to the handler they call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$(&amp;#39;body&amp;#39;).on(&amp;#39;button&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;click&amp;#39;, function() {

    // Can be passed a value which will be given to handlers
    deferred.resolve();
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deferred.promise()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Returns the promise object of the deferred. If passed a target, .promise() will attach promise methods to the target instead of creating a new object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deferred.state()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Useful for debugging and querying the state the deferred object is in. Returns: pending, resolved or rejected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deferred.always()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Functions or an array of functions called regardless of reject and failure.
&lt;strong&gt;deferred.done()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Functions or array of functions called upon resolution of the deferred object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deferred.fail()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Functions or array of functions called upon rejection of the deferred object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$.ajax()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Performs an Ajax request and returns a promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managing asynchronous JavaScript and writing decoupled applications can be challenging. I hope by now you have a better understanding of what promises are, how you can use them and how to avoid some of the common pitfalls. There&amp;#39;s still a lot of ground I haven&amp;#39;t covered in these two posts and for that I refer you to your libraries docs and the resources mentioned at the end of both posts. Of course, if you have questions or feedback feel free to get in touch on &lt;a href="https://alpha.app.net/cwebbdesign"&gt;app.net&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.twitter.com/cwebbdesign"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author&amp;#39;s note&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
In putting together these two posts, I am deeply indebted to the work of others. @dominic&amp;#39;s article &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/domenic/3889970"&gt;You&amp;#39;re Missing the Point of Promises&lt;/a&gt; and the exchange between @dominic and @rwaldron on &lt;a href="http://bugs.jquery.com/ticket/11010"&gt;jQuery&amp;#39;s .then()&lt;/a&gt; really fueled my deep dive into how promises work. Trevor Burnham&amp;#39;s book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AKM4RVG/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00AKM4RVG&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=mediumequalsm-20" title="Async JavaScript"&gt;Async JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;, Brian Cavalier&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://blog.briancavalier.com/" title="Async Programming"&gt;Async Programming&lt;/a&gt;, Jesse Hallet&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://sitr.us/2012/07/31/promise-pipelines-in-javascript.html" title="Promise Pipeline in JavaScript"&gt;Promise Pipeline in JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;, and of course the &lt;a href="http://wiki.commonjs.org/wiki/Promises/A" title="Promises/A"&gt;Promises/A&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://promises-aplus.github.com/promises-spec/" title="Promises/A+"&gt;Promises/A+&lt;/a&gt; proposals were also invaluable resources. Finally, special thanks to &lt;a href="http://weblog.bocoup.com/" title="Rick Waldron"&gt;Rick Waldron&lt;/a&gt; and the author of jQuery&amp;#39;s .then() implementation &lt;a href="http://jaubourg.net/" title="Julian Aubourg"&gt;Julian Aubourg&lt;/a&gt; for answering my questions in preparing this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Further Resources&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AKM4RVG/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00AKM4RVG&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=mediumequalsm-20" title="Async JavaScript"&gt;Async JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Articles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.briancavalier.com/async-programming-part-1-its-messy" title="Async Programming Part 1: It&amp;#39;s messy"&gt;Async Programming Part 1: It&amp;#39;s messy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.briancavalier.com/?sort=&amp;amp;search=async%20programming%20part%202-" title="Async programming part 2: Promises"&gt;Async Programming Part 2: Promises&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sitr.us/2012/07/31/promise-pipelines-in-javascript.html"&gt;Promise Pipelines in JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kendoui.com/blogs/teamblog/posts/13-03-28/what-is-the-point-of-promises.aspx" title="Whats the point of promises?"&gt;What&amp;#39;s the point of promises&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://api.jquery.com/category/deferred-object/" title="jQuery Documentation: Deferred Object"&gt;jQuery Documentation: Deferred Object&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/jquery/jquery/blob/master/test/unit/deferred.js"&gt;jQuery - deferred.js test suite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/112684535680414429306?rel=author"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/jPyEVEiU4jw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.mediumequalsmessage.com/promise-deferred-objects-in-javascript-pt2-practical-use</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tylerhayes,2012:Post/sonos-is-living-in-the-future-and-the-past</id>
    <published>2013-04-10T07:03:59-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-10T07:03:59-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/-Mt4vYRAPVY/sonos-is-living-in-the-future-and-the-past" />
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Hayes</name>
      <uri>http://liisten.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Sonos Is Living In The Future and The Past</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;#39;t love Sonos more and yet, sometimes it seems the company is a bit frustrating. Their wireless speakers are fantastic in almost every regard, but what drives me crazy is this company that dreams in the future with their hardware, doesn&amp;#39;t often keep up their software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sonos player on Mac doesn&amp;#39;t yet fully support retina, even after almost a year. Their iPhone app didn&amp;#39;t support the iPhone 5&amp;#39;s bigger screen for quite awhile and Sonos&amp;#39; website also isn&amp;#39;t fully retina either, with their logo being the biggest offender. This should be embarrassing for a company that makes a product advanced enough that a lot of people have trouble wrapping their mind around how it works initially. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sonos is engaged in recruiting new services to work with their speakers, often finding companies before they&amp;#39;ve hit critical mass. Beyond the obvious &amp;ndash; making speakers &amp;ndash; having a swath of services is Sonos&amp;#39; biggest strength. The company has taken the bold approach to include as many services as possible as streaming sources rather than to create their own music service and compete with top players. I wish more companies would focus on a specific area and partner with non-competing, complimentary, partners to provide a better experience than try and do everything themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sonos software is the weak link for the company. Even the latest beta software not yet released leaves something to be desired. Their apps are beginning to look long in the tooth and will need a complete resign sooner rather than later. This is important because it&amp;#39;s how people interact with the mind blowing hardware. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally in the music game, the company has recently jumped heavily into the home theater space. Imagine a sound bar supported by wireless surround speakers that can also, at anytime, switch to instantly stream different songs and also be moved to different rooms. That&amp;#39;s what Sonos speakers are currently capable of doing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do I care and why should you care? The software you interact with constantly will eventually be a determining factor to whether you add another speaker to your collection or return the first one you buy. The situation isn&amp;#39;t currently terrible by any means, but it has been the one nagging issue for the last year of my ownership. It was always the part of the experience that made me question where my expectation level was at. Whether it means hiring more software engineers or something else, I&amp;#39;d love to see Sonos jump ahead of the eventual problem, rather than let it fully catch up to them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/-Mt4vYRAPVY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://liisten.com/sonos-is-living-in-the-future-and-the-past</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:putorti,2012:Post/whats-your-mission</id>
    <published>2013-04-10T00:55:44-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-10T00:55:44-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/KKJTLaLZ-WA/whats-your-mission" />
    <author>
      <name>Jason Putorti</name>
      <uri>http://jasonputorti.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>What's your mission?</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/10/causes-acquires-votizen/"&gt;The last few months have been quite a ride for me.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll save the lessons learned (and there are many) for a later date, but the question I&amp;#39;ve been asked the most since January is, &amp;ldquo;how long are you staying at Causes?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question probably has something to do with the &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2009/12/01/bessemer-jason-putorti-designer/"&gt;last time I was part of an acquisition&lt;/a&gt;, but a lot is different this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, I didn&amp;#39;t find out about the acquisition of Votizen by reading TechCrunch in the morning. This was a deliberate decision I had a large role in, along with my co-founder and the rest of the company. Everyone had a say, and I&amp;#39;m proud that nearly all of us made the decision to go along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, in 2007 I joined Mint as lead designer because I saw an amazing opportunity. I saw a compelling value proposition that most startups were missing back then (and still are). There was an opportunity to build an amazing brand, and I could learn a lot about startups that I could apply later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it sold, I felt I had done what I had set out to do. Although I felt the larger mission of the company—to help people understand their money—was unfinished, I didn&amp;#39;t see the same kind of risk-taking and innovation as likely to happen at Intuit.  I wouldn’t be able to have the impact in the world that I became an entrepreneur to have. My days became filled with design-by-committee conference calls where people were compelled to say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to justify being on the payroll.  We also spent our entire existence &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2009/02/19/quicken-online-cant-believe-mint-is-doing-so-well-sends-threatening-letter/"&gt;positioning ourselves against them&lt;/a&gt; so it was tough to feel good about joining in. The culture of our startup and the culture of Intuit were not well matched in my opinion, and it seemed that the mission had long since bled out of that place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s also the matter of appreciation. Everyone wants to feel like they have value to an organization. I heard later from more than one Intuit employee that they were excited to have me, but nobody from Intuit reached out. It wasn&amp;#39;t clear to me what Intuit truly valued about the company, but it clearly wasn&amp;#39;t me–and that&amp;#39;s okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly though, I wasn&amp;#39;t passionate enough about personal finance. My mission wasn&amp;#39;t to transform money management, though it felt good to help people. I worked in the problem space for a few years, but I became swept up in electoral politics during the 2008 election. I had an interest in elections ever since the first one I could vote in ended via Supreme Court decision. Carnegie Mellon was a campaign stop for Al Gore in 2000, for John Kerry in 2004, and finally the wide open primary of 2008 was too compelling of a story to ignore. I saw my &lt;a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/id/22342301/ns/meet_the_press/t/meet-press-transcript-dec/"&gt;very first episode of Meet the Press with Tim Russert&lt;/a&gt; and I was hooked. It was something that I couldn&amp;#39;t shake, and I began to think about the problems in the space and play around with building products in my spare time, sacrificing fun and relationships in the process. I couldn&amp;#39;t &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; build something in politics, and over the next year I found my mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you figure out what that is, and believe it&amp;#39;s possible, the rest of the decisions become a lot easier. Your mission becomes what defines your success. So I asked myself, where is it that I can go that gives me the best chance of success as I define it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not interested in being a founder for the sake of the title, or hacking on an inconsequential project just to build, or raising money because I can. I&amp;#39;m interested in making voters so powerful that no amount of money or top-down advertising will make any difference in an election. Social media has created a new era of many-to-many communications on a massive scale, which has yet to fully break down our politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m now working with a lot of &lt;a href="http://www.causes.com/team#jameswindon"&gt;incredible&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.causes.com/team#mattmahan"&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; with a &lt;a href="http://allthingsd.com/20120312/al-gore-and-sean-parker-blame-tv-and-money-for-ruining-politics-and-say-social-media-ought-to-fix-it/"&gt;common vision&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;#39;ve spent months now re-imagining the product, and integrating the never-realized Votizen roadmap. Long gone is &lt;em&gt;Causes on Facebook&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;birthday wish&lt;/em&gt;,  and in its place is emerging a new, powerful platform for citizen-driven change. I&amp;#39;m valued, appreciated, there&amp;#39;s culture alignment with Votizen, and—most importantly—I&amp;#39;m making a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How long will I stay?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve told many people I&amp;#39;ve run into over the years, that entrepreneurs are irrational people. You can have a safer income, and usually a higher one, doing a lot of other things. Success is incredibly rare. Starting a business &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; changing the base of political power in America takes that to a whole new level, but that&amp;#39;s me. As long as I&amp;#39;m crazy enough to think I can do this, I&amp;#39;m going to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you&amp;#39;re contemplating a change of scenery, ask yourself where you can have the greatest impact on your mission. It could be a small startup, or your own if nobody else will let you pursue the innovation you want to see in the world. It could be a large company that will give you the resources to get you where you need to go, or if your mission is the same as mine, &lt;a href="http://j.mp/14i2miL"&gt;It could be right here, sitting next to me.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/KKJTLaLZ-WA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://jasonputorti.com/whats-your-mission</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:maccman,2012:Post/sublime-text</id>
    <published>2013-04-09T10:55:22-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-09T10:55:22-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/BQbco4qz0HY/sublime-text" />
    <author>
      <name>Alex MacCaw</name>
      <uri>http://blog.alexmaccaw.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Setting up Sublime Text 2</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently decided it was finally time to part ways with TextMate, my trusty companion for these last few years, and start the hunt for a new editor. After a quick &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maccman/status/302501982181158913"&gt;Twitter poll&lt;/a&gt; the unanimous advice was that I should try &lt;a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/2"&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_maccman_24579541812330_raw.png" style="float: right; margin: 0px 0 10px 15px;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks of using Sublime Text I can safely say that it&amp;#39;s the best editor I&amp;#39;ve used. It&amp;#39;s fast, extendable and hasn&amp;#39;t ever crashed on me. That said, that no editor is perfect and Sublime Text does require a fair bit of initial configuration. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you&amp;#39;ve &lt;a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/2"&gt;downloaded &amp;amp; installed the editor&lt;/a&gt;, the first step to configuring Sublime Text 2 is to install the package manager. I&amp;#39;m hoping in future versions of the editor this package manager will come bundled, but for now it requires a separate installation. Run Sublime Text, Press &lt;code&gt;ctrl `&lt;/code&gt; (control backtick) to open the editor&amp;#39;s console, and paste in the &lt;a href="http://wbond.net/sublime_packages/package_control/installation"&gt;code listed here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the manager is set up, you can install packages with &lt;code&gt;⌘⇧p&lt;/code&gt; (command shift p) and typing &lt;code&gt;Install Package&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Theme - Soda&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sublime&amp;#39;s initial look leaves a lot to be desired. However, luckily there&amp;#39;s a &lt;a href="https://github.com/buymeasoda/soda-theme/"&gt;beautiful theme called Soda&lt;/a&gt;. To install Soda, open the package manager (&lt;code&gt;⌘⇧p&lt;/code&gt;), type &amp;#39;Install Package ↵&amp;#39;, and then &amp;#39;Theme - Soda ↵&amp;#39;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/maccman_24578065447092_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_maccman_24578065447092_raw.png" alt="Screen Shot 2013-04-08 at 12.07.47 PM.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To activate the theme, open Sublime&amp;#39;s preferences &lt;code&gt;⌘,&lt;/code&gt; (command comma), which is a JSON file, and set the &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;theme&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; key to &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Soda Light.sublime-theme&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; (Remember to check commas).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  &amp;quot;theme&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Soda Light.sublime-theme&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have to restart the editor, or at least open a new window, for the theme to activate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Extending the editor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few other packages to install:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/titoBouzout/SideBarEnhancements"&gt;SideBarEnhancements&lt;/a&gt; - Adds useful file operations to the sidebar, such as &amp;#39;New file&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;New folder&amp;#39; etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/alienhard/SublimeAllAutocomplete"&gt;AllAutocomplete&lt;/a&gt; - Allows autocompletion across open files.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/SublimeText/TrailingSpaces"&gt;TrailingSpaces&lt;/a&gt; -Strips trailing whitespace from files.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the same steps as before to install the packages, &lt;code&gt;⌘⇧p&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Install package&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tabs &amp;amp; Spaces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default indentation style uses tabs instead of spaces, and it&amp;#39;s likely that you&amp;#39;ll want to switch this (unless you solely program in a language where that&amp;#39;s the convention, such as Go). Open Sublime&amp;#39;s preferences (Settings - User or &lt;code&gt;⌘,&lt;/code&gt;) and add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  &amp;quot;tab_size&amp;quot;: 2,
  &amp;quot;translate_tabs_to_spaces&amp;quot;: true
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re anything like me, and dread trailing white space, then you should install the &lt;a href="https://github.com/SublimeText/TrailingSpaces"&gt;TrailingSpaces&lt;/a&gt; package.  You&amp;#39;ll need to change the default preferences for the plugin too. Open TrailingSpace&amp;#39;s preferences (Preferences -&amp;gt; Package Settings -&amp;gt; TrailingSpaces -&amp;gt; Settings - User), and add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  &amp;quot;trailing_spaces_include_current_line&amp;quot;: false
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also add this to your global user preferences (&lt;code&gt;⌘,&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; &amp;quot;trim_trailing_white_space_on_save&amp;quot;: true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Key bindings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a key binding I used the whole time in TextMate: &lt;code&gt;⌘ ctrl r&lt;/code&gt; to reveal the currently opened file in the sidebar. You can add this to Sublime by opening the key bindings preferences (Preferences -&amp;gt; Key Bindings - User) and adding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[
  {&amp;quot;keys&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;ctrl+super+r&amp;quot;], &amp;quot;command&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;reveal_in_side_bar&amp;quot;}
]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sublime&amp;#39;s fuzzy search (&lt;code&gt;⌘ t&lt;/code&gt;) is incredibly fast and convenient, and it&amp;#39;s my primary way of navigating around my projects. As well as navigating by file name, you can go to a particular line in a file by typing &lt;code&gt;:123&lt;/code&gt; (colon line number) or to a particular method by typing &lt;code&gt;#name&lt;/code&gt; (hash method name).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Command line&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly Sublime Text doesn&amp;#39;t come with a easily accessible binary, since this is probably the primary way developers will open the editor. That said, you can easily add support by creating a symlink:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ln -s &amp;quot;/Applications/Sublime Text 2.app/Contents/SharedSupport/bin/subl&amp;quot; /usr/bin/subl
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also use an alias in my &lt;code&gt;~/.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt; file, allowing me to easily open a directory from the terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alias e=&amp;#39;subl . &amp;amp;&amp;#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Icon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sublime&amp;#39;s default icon is fairly ugly, but there are a few replacements on Dribbble. One of my favorites is by &lt;a href="http://dribbble.com/shots/872166-Sublime-Text-2-Replacement-Icon?hex=332924&amp;amp;list=color&amp;amp;percent=30&amp;amp;variance=50"&gt;Elliot Jackson&lt;/a&gt;. To install it, download the &lt;a href="http://cl.ly/Lp3Q"&gt;icns file&lt;/a&gt; and replace the application&amp;#39;s icon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ mv ~/Downloads/st2.icns /Applications/Sublime\ Text\ 2.app/Contents/Resources/Sublime\ Text\ 2.icns 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/maccman_24578205497280_raw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_maccman_24578205497280_raw.png" alt="sublime-text-2.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pasting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One suggestion from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jasbarry"&gt;Jason Barry&lt;/a&gt; is to use  &amp;#39;Paste and Indent&amp;#39; for ⌘V instead of the standard &amp;#39;Paste&amp;#39;. This adjusts your indentation to automatically match the context it&amp;#39;s pasted in. To do this, put the following in your Key Bindings - User file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[
  { &amp;quot;keys&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;super+v&amp;quot;], &amp;quot;command&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;paste_and_indent&amp;quot; }, 
  { &amp;quot;keys&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;super+shift+v&amp;quot;], &amp;quot;command&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;paste&amp;quot; } 
]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;More packages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few more packages you may find useful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git - Git blame/branch support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CoffeeScript - .coffee syntax highlighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eco - .eco syntax highlighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stylus - .styl syntax highlighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sass - .sass syntax highlighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/SublimeLinter/SublimeLinter"&gt;SublimeLinter&lt;/a&gt; - lint code as you type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/jisaacks/GitGutter"&gt;GitGutter&lt;/a&gt; - show Git diffs in the gutter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#39;s a fair bit of setting up required for an editor, most of which you&amp;#39;d think would be the default configuration. Sublime Text 2 definitely needs a bit of polishing from a product perspective. The default website, icon, and theme are ugly to say the least, and it would be convenient to be able to install the editor through the App Store. A GUI for configuration would be a good idea as storing preferences in JSON files may appeal to programmers, but it definitely alienates designers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said it&amp;#39;s early days for the editor, and the core framework has clearly been built extremely well. It&amp;#39;s ridiculously fast, stable and very extendable. I love it and absolutely recommend you try it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/BQbco4qz0HY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://blog.alexmaccaw.com/sublime-text</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:cadelllast,2012:Post/intelligent-life-in-the-milky-way</id>
    <published>2013-04-09T09:06:15-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-09T09:06:15-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/pJDNvbI41SI/intelligent-life-in-the-milky-way" />
    <author>
      <name>Cadell Last</name>
      <uri>http://theratchet.ca</uri>
    </author>
    <title>Intelligent Life in the Milky Way</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/1ekrmff.png" alt="Milky way"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years astronomers have been making considerable progress on estimating the number of Earth-like planets we should expect within our own galaxy.  The most &lt;a href="http://mnras.oxfordjournals.org/content/early/2013/03/26/mnras.stt318"&gt;recent study by a team of astronomers at the University of Auckland&lt;/a&gt; claim that there are &lt;a href="http://www.extremetech.com/extreme/152573-astronomers-estimate-100-billion-habitable-earth-like-planets-in-the-milky-way-50-sextillion-in-the-universe"&gt;approximately 100 billion&lt;/a&gt;.  This estimate increases the likely number of Earth-like planets by 82 billion.  A study published by astronomers from Harvard Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics in January posited that there were &lt;a href="http://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/billions-of-earthlike-planets-found-in-milky-way/"&gt;approximately 17 billion Earth-like planets&lt;/a&gt;.  In my opinion, I think the 100 billion estimate is probably more reliable.  The study produced by the Harvard Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics collected data from measuring dimming of planets orbital periods, whereas the study produced from the University of Auckland collected data from gravitational microlensing.  Gravitational microlensing is a more effective method for finding smaller planets with Earth-like orbital periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, whether there are approximately 17 or 100 billion Earth-like planets in the Milky Way (or more) the important point is that astronomers now have reason to believe that there are a &lt;strong&gt;ton&lt;/strong&gt; of Earth-like planets.  This definitely puts a previously contentious issue to rest in the world of astronomy.  In the 1990s and 2000s we had very little to no idea how common Earth-like planets would be.  Obviously, these data have tremendous implications for our search of extraterrestrial intelligent life.  As a result, these data raise some of the biggest questions we can ask as a species.  And in this post, I would like to analyze them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short: if we now know that there are several billions of Earth-like planets in our galaxy alone, why is it so quiet out there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Possibility 1. We are the first&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our universe is &lt;a href="http://www.theadvancedapes.com/theratchet/2013/3/26/comprehending-deep-time"&gt;13.82 billion years old&lt;/a&gt;.  That is very old.  However, our universe has not been habitable for this period of time.  The universe has gone through stages of development that astronomers and cosmologists understand fairly well.  Throughout the early stages of this development life could not have existed.  Furthermore, the first galaxies and star systems were composed of stars that were much larger, less stable, and had shorter lifespans than second and third generation galaxies and star systems.  This has important implications for the search for intelligent life because although we have only one case example of how life evolves (that would be us!) I still feel that it is a reliable indicator that biological evolutionary processes require billions of years to produce highly complex life forms.  If that is a valid assumption of the time scales required for biological evolution to produce complex life forms then the first galaxies and star systems would not have been ideal candidates for the development of intelligent life.  Many of the early stars lasted for 10-100 million years.  Complex life requires stable star systems that last for billions of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Milky Way galaxy is approximately 8 billion years old.  If life requires at least 2-4 billion years to produce highly complex life it is still plausible that many planets in our galaxy possess complex life forms and healthy biospheres.  However, we also know from our one known case example of life that intelligent life is very rare.  Trillions of multi-cellular species have inhabited our planet.  Only 1 has evolved meta-awareness and the ability to understand the processes that allowed for its existence.  Again, if this is characteristic of biological evolution we should expect most Earth-like planets (that remain stable for more than 1 billion years) to produce a biosphere with no self-aware intelligent species.  If this is the case, it is definitely &lt;strong&gt;plausible&lt;/strong&gt; that we are the first (at least in the Milky Way).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How plausible do I think this situation is?  I actually think it is highly plausible.  Selection for high intelligence is rare in nature.  Brains are the most expensive organs.  The Milky Way may have billions of biospheres, but only 1 biosphere with an intelligent civilization. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Possibility 2. Intelligent Civilizations have a short life span&lt;/strong&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our civilization is very young on the scale of deep time.  To &lt;a href="http://www.theadvancedapes.com/theratchet/2013/3/26/comprehending-deep-time"&gt;accurately conceptualize how young&lt;/a&gt; we must turn to the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmic_Calendar"&gt;Cosmic Calendar&lt;/a&gt;.  If the entire history of the universe were conceptualized within one calendar year, modern, sedentary, agricultural human civilization would arrive 13 seconds before New Year&amp;#39;s Eve on December 31st.  In this astonishingly short period of time we have completely transformed our planet, landed on another celestial object, and started to explore our solar system with robots.  &lt;a href="http://www.theadvancedapes.com/theratchet/2012/10/19/an-idea-to-change-all-ideas"&gt;This pace of change is accelerating&lt;/a&gt;.  If the cultural and technological evolutionary processes that have enabled us to do this are characteristic of intelligent species, we should suspect intelligent civilizations to develop very quickly on galactic scales.  We should also suspect them to be &lt;strong&gt;very loud&lt;/strong&gt;.  Already, within barely a century of using global communications technology our radio waves have reached hundreds of other star systems (&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MlOjSQeO1Dg"&gt;check out a this brilliant atlas depicting the extent of our radio emissions&lt;/a&gt;).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am trying to emphasize an important point here.  If intelligent civilizations &lt;strong&gt;are common&lt;/strong&gt; and develop on many Earth-like planets, they must have short life spans because we have not heard them yet.  As Ross Anderson of Aeon Magazine has pointed out: &amp;ldquo;no impressive feats of macro-engineering shine out from our galaxy’s depths.&amp;rdquo;  But if intelligent civilizations develop often and have long life spans (on scales of deep time) we should expect to see such feats of macro-engineering.  Could it be that intelligent civilizations have very short life spans?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robin Hanson of The Future of Humanity Institute believes that there must be a &amp;ldquo;great filter&amp;rdquo; between the development of life and a galactic-sized civilization.  He suspects that if microbial life is very common in the universe (which it probably is), then the great filter must be between a civilization like ours and a larger-scale multiple star-system civilization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How plausible do I think this situation is?  Actually, I don&amp;#39;t think this is the most plausible situation.  I think that once a civilization like ours exists it would take an &lt;strong&gt;extreme catastrophe&lt;/strong&gt; to eradicate it entirely.  Almost all potential natural disasters that could erase a civilization like our own would not cause &lt;strong&gt;complete extinction&lt;/strong&gt;.  And complete extinction is what would be necessary to prevent further development of our species on the scale of deep time.  Perhaps I am being naive regarding this assertion.  There may be some great filter and maybe it is the development of nuclear arms.  Maybe it is the development of advanced nanotechnology and A.I.  Maybe it is something that will exist in a century or two.  However, at the moment I think it is more plausible to suspect that intelligent civilizations are rare with long life spans, as opposed to common with short life spans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Possibility 3. Space Expansion Hypothesis incorrect; Transcension Hypothesis correct&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long-time many astronomers, cosmologists, and futurists assumed that the natural trajectory for an intelligent civilization was expansion into space.  In my opinion this is a foolish assumption.  Of course it is possible (in fact plausible) that expansion is the natural tendency for intelligent civilizations like our own.  However, we cannot discount the possibility that intelligent civilizations do not expand; they transcend.  This hypothesis posits that the reason we do not see any &amp;ldquo;impressive feats of macro-engineering&amp;rdquo; in space is  because intelligent civilizations turn inwards.  Intelligent civilizations may start to compress space, time, energy, and matter (STEM compression) to the point that virtual minds inhabit nano-scales (as opposed to minds inhabiting the macro-scale).  Eventually this compression should lead to the ability to exploit the extra-dimensions of space, and perhaps allow intelligent civilizations to escape this universe into a different (or neighbouring) one.  If you would like to read an article by the futurist who proposed transcension: &lt;a href="http://accelerating.org/articles/transcensionhypothesis.html"&gt;read this&lt;/a&gt;.  If you would like a quick video explaining the idea: &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nQOyJUDTKdM"&gt;watch this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment the Transcension Hypothesis is quite controversial and untested.  To many the ideas seems ludicrous.  But many ideas seem radical when they are first proposed.  John Smart, who proposed the hypothesis, believes that if Transcension is the fate of intelligent civilizations, we should suspect mini black holes in the habitable rings of spiral galaxies.  These mini black holes would be the remnants of &amp;ldquo;transcended civilizations.&amp;rdquo;  If true, this would certainly explain Fermi&amp;#39;s Paradox and account for the eerie silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How plausible do I think this scenario is?  To me, this is the most difficult one to make a firm conclusion on.  At the moment, I am still convinced that the Space Expansion Hypothesis is correct.  But I do not want to assume that it is correct.  In the future we may find out more about how intelligent civilizations evolve.  If the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technological_singularity"&gt;technological singularity&lt;/a&gt; is a &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo; (which I&amp;#39;m pretty sure it is) then we have no clue what our civilization will look like in 100, 200, or 500 years.  We may explode into space, or we may explode into the nanoscale.  Either way, at the moment I&amp;#39;m going to say that we should suspect robotic expansion to be the expected trajectory of intelligent civilizations.  So this would make both possibilities 1 and 2 more plausible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Possibility 4. Intelligent Life Ignores Us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arthur C. Clarke famously stated that: &amp;ldquo;any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic.&amp;rdquo;  Certainly that is true.  It would literally be unimaginable for someone 200 years ago to conceive of a smart phone (for example).  If there are intelligent civilizations out there (perhaps &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kardashev_scale"&gt;Type II or III or even IV level&lt;/a&gt; civilizations), then they would certainly possess technologies and produce patterns that were impossible for us to imagine.  This raises two possibilities:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A) If they wished to remain invisible to us then they could certainly achieve that goal.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B) They could produce patterns that we are unable to detect or recognize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In situation A) they could know we exist and not care.  Or they could know we exist and wish to just observe us from a distance and see what we do.  Whatever a civilization (Types II-IV) like this wanted to do they could.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In situation B) organizations like SETI are just unable to detect the types of signals or recognize the types of patterns produced by advanced civilizations.  This is an intriguing possibility to me.  Consider the fact that we do not know what most of the universe is composed of (e.g., dark matter and energy).  If we can&amp;#39;t even understand all natural patterns and phenomena in the universe, why should we suspect to be able to detect patterns and phenomena of advanced galactic civilizations?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How likely do I think these scenarios are?  I think that any opinion on these scenarios can only be made by a gut reaction or perhaps a marginally educated guess.  I personally think both situations are unlikely.  I will say that I think situation A) is more unlikely than situation B).  I think it is more likely that advanced civilizations are doing things that we can&amp;#39;t detect.  I don&amp;#39;t think there is some advanced Milky Way federation of civilizations that are observing us from a distance.  Finally, I will add that I think possibilities 1, 2, and 3 are more likely than these possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Possibility 5. Faster-than-light travel is impossible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final possibility is that the universe has a speed limit and there is no way to get around this speed limit.  If this is the case then expansion into space makes very little sense and intelligent civilizations would give up on this idea.  Instead they simply continue to inhabit their home planet until global catastrophe eradicates them (whether that be self-inflicted or natural).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, light travels very quickly.  In fact, light travels so quickly that it can circle our planet 7 times in 1 second.  However, even if an intelligent civilization developed a space craft that could travel this quickly, it would still take 4 years to travel to the nearest star system.  Developing a civilization connected over these distances would not be feasible, especially when you consider that our galaxy is 100,000 light years across.  However, I suppose it would be possible under this scenario for civilizations to expand and disperse.  There could be rings of civilizations that diffuse outwards to new planets and then remain disconnected from one another (or &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; loosely connected &amp;ndash; perhaps tweeting back and forth every couple hundred years). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How plausible do I think this situation is?  I actually think this is the least likely of all the scenarios.  We are not even a Type I civilization and we have already proposed several theoretical models that explore the possibility of faster-than-light speed travel.  A few of these ideas include &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Worm_holes#Faster-than-light_travel"&gt;wormholes&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alcubierre_drive"&gt;Alcubierre drive&lt;/a&gt;.  Wikipedia has great articles on both if you want to learn more about them.  My point is simply that just because we currently have a poor (or limited) understanding of how to circumvent the speed-of-light we should not expect a more advanced civilization to find this problem insurmountable.  I would not be so foolish as to claim it impossible that speed-of-light really is an impossible speed limit to pass.  However, I think it is unlikely to be. I think it is a problem that an intelligent civilization could solve if given enough time.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications of 100 Billion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The implications of 100 billion Earth-like planets in our galaxy is profound (it may have even more profound implications for the universe as a whole).  The knowledge that Earth-like planets are abundant forces us to confront big questions about extraterrestrial life.  The point of this article was to explore these questions with some level of depth.  I believe that everyone&amp;#39;s opinion on what the implications are will be slightly different.  In my opinion, current evidence presents us with five potential scenarios for advanced intelligent life.  In this article I have tried to rank them from 1-5 (with 1 being the most probable and 5 being the least probable).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are the first (at least in our galaxy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligent civilizations have a short life span&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space Expansion Hypothesis incorrect; Transcension Hypothesis correct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligent life ignores us&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faster-than-light travel is impossible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://hubski.com/pub?id=78767"&gt;Discuss this article on Hubski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/pJDNvbI41SI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://theratchet.ca/intelligent-life-in-the-milky-way</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:tom,2012:Post/a-startups-three-visions</id>
    <published>2013-04-09T07:09:01-07:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-09T07:09:01-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/svbtle/~3/-KsX-Xf_WgE/a-startups-three-visions" />
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Tunguz</name>
      <uri>http://tomtunguz.com</uri>
    </author>
    <title>A Startup's Three Visions</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://img.svbtle.com/tom_24579297892278_raw.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://d23f6h5jpj26xu.cloudfront.net/inline_tom_24579297892278_raw.jpg" alt="Ice-Climbing-on-Mount-Aco-008.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three types of vision that a successful startup needs: product vision, business vision and team vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product vision&lt;/strong&gt; is the dream. It&amp;#39;s how your company changes the world. It&amp;#39;s the problem that you&amp;#39;re solving and the solution to that problem. Product visions don&amp;#39;t end on launch day. They extend for years through the company&amp;#39;s growth. A product vision isn&amp;#39;t a certain feature or even a completed product. It&amp;#39;s the state of having solved a problem for a user or providing an experience for a user. The best product visions last for decades. Think Apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business vision&lt;/strong&gt; is the go-to-market: it&amp;#39;s the way the product arrives in customers hands. Each company&amp;#39;s business vision is a unique. It might be a flavor of freemium. It might be enterprise direct sales. It could be viral ecommerce. But it&amp;#39;s not just a buzzword. It&amp;#39;s the process to mechanize the revenue engine for the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team vision&lt;/strong&gt; is also called culture. Culture is the feeling of the workspace, the language in meetings and the values extolled by the company both internally and externally. Team vision also encompasses organizational structure - how the company is constructed to solve its customers problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exceptional founders possess all three kinds of vision. More often, founding teams forge these three visions by complementing each other&amp;#39;s strengths. Sometimes advisors or board members can help clarify visions. But it&amp;#39;s problematic for an outsider to engender them altogether because these visions are more than ideas or dreams. They must be present every day in every decision made, every feature built, every marketing message delivered. These visions must begin in the founding team or the management team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, these visions may need to be tweaked with time if the market place impacts them, particularly product and business visions. A product might need to be redesigned to better suit meets customer needs. A distribution strategy may not work for a product because the ecosystem may have changed. But the essence of the vision shouldn&amp;#39;t change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you build your startup&amp;#39;s team, look for co-founders who can transform those visions into reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/svbtle/~4/-KsX-Xf_WgE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
  <feedburner:origLink>http://tomtunguz.com/a-startups-three-visions</feedburner:origLink></entry>
</feed>
