<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Over Yonderlust</title>
	
	<link>http://overyonderlust.com</link>
	<description>Shaun and Erica - Couple adventure travel our way.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 14:52:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<feedburner:info uri="overyonderlust" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/feedburner/vGXl" /><feedburner:info uri="feedburner/vgxl" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>feedburner/vGXl</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>Our Essential Beach Packing List</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~3/MK-NTlI7HKQ/</link>
		<comments>http://overyonderlust.com/beach-packing-list-essential/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 18:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Erica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Caribbean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://overyonderlust.com/?p=7962</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;ve come a long way, baby! After celebrating our 2 year &#8220;on the road&#8221; anniversary, it is really amazing to see how much we have grown. Experiences, mistakes, and general blunders have given us an invaluable database of knowledge &#8211; especially when it comes to packing. Our most recent trip has us spending a month [...]</p><p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/beach-packing-list-essential/">Our Essential Beach Packing List</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="61/365 Having a flexible life is awesome. Our pet sitting gig rules. Going to set sail after they come home too! #365days by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8598249971/"><img alt="61/365 Having a flexible life is awesome. Our pet sitting gig rules. Going to set sail after they come home too! #365days" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8377/8598249971_c9a92235b9_z.jpg" width="300" height="300" /></a><a title="69/365 This water is a tease. I'm afraid of growing a third arm if I go in. #365days by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8622386017/"><img alt="69/365 This water is a tease. I'm afraid of growing a third arm if I go in. #365days" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8112/8622386017_302e1209a4_z.jpg" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>We&#8217;ve come a long way, baby! After celebrating our 2 year &#8220;on the road&#8221; anniversary, it is really amazing to see how much we have grown. Experiences, mistakes, and general blunders have given us an invaluable database of knowledge &#8211; especially when it comes to packing.</p>
<p>Our most recent trip has us spending a month in the jungles and beaches of Guatemala, Belize, and Mexico. Besides the fact that Latin America feels like home, Shaun and I were a little more prepared about what to expect when it came to wearing clothes. What happened was a new minimalism that really caught us off guard. After <a title="Our Cliche Packing List" href="http://overyonderlust.com/our-cliche-packing-list/" target="_blank">packing for Latin America</a> last time, we had to take into consideration we were going to be in the Andes. For our <a title="The New NEW Packing List" href="http://overyonderlust.com/packing-list-the-new-new/" target="_blank">European packing list</a>, we had to pack for the cold. This time? All relaxation and all beaches.</p>
<p>On to our choices:</p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Packing-List-Caribbean-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7963" alt="beach packing list" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Packing-List-Caribbean-1.jpg" width="640" height="352" /></a></p>
<p><em><strong>Erica Essentials</strong></em></p>
<p>8 pairs of underwear (Learned from Latin America that 3 is NOT enough)<br />
2 bras<br />
1 sports bra<br />
2 bathing suits<br />
2 pairs shorts<br />
1 pair jeans (I like jeans and will continue to pack them)<br />
1 skirt<br />
3 tank tops<br />
1 shirt<br />
1 pair flip flops<br />
1 pair hiking shoes<br />
1 pair tieks (For a nice night out.)<br />
1 hoodie (Nice buses are COLD)<br />
3 pairs socks</p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Packing-List-Caribbean-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7964" alt="beach packing list" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Packing-List-Caribbean-2.jpg" width="640" height="325" /></a></p>
<p><em><strong>Scant Shaun</strong></em></p>
<p>4 pairs boxers (3 Ex-Officio)<br />
3 Shirts<br />
1 Button Down shirt<br />
1 pair trunks<br />
2 pairs shorts<br />
1 pair jeans<br />
1 hat<br />
4 pairs socks<br />
1 belt<br />
1 pair flip flops<br />
1 pair skate shoes (Don&#8217;t ask.)<br />
Sunglasses</p>
<p><em><strong>Not Pictured:</strong></em></p>
<p>Erica&#8217;s Hat and Sunglasses<br />
2 Ponchos<br />
1 Umbrella<br />
2 Rain Covers for backpacks<br />
2 Headlamps<br />
First Aid Kit<br />
Pocket Knife<br />
Sarong<br />
Ginger Candy (for Shaun&#8217;s seasickness &#8211; we have yet to try it out)<br />
1 Waterbottle<br />
1 Texas koozy<br />
1 Burning Man koozy<br />
Tissues<br />
1 Journal<br />
2 Dry Sacks (20L and 2L)<br />
2 Travel Towels<br />
Sunscreen<br />
Bug Repellent<br />
Mascara<br />
Eye-liner</p>
<p><em><strong>Tech Bag: (25L Dakine Burnside Backpack)</strong></em></p>
<p>1 15&#8243; MacBook Pro<br />
1 HP Envy 14 (14&#8243;)<br />
Nikon D300S<br />
18-50mm lens<br />
50mm lens (It was hard narrowing it down to 2 lenses!)<br />
2 batteries<br />
1 battery charger<br />
1 Go Pro Hero 1<br />
1 Go Pro Hero 3<br />
X-Shot 2.0<br />
2 iPhone 4S<br />
Kindle 3G</p>
<p>After throwing our clothes and gear into our bags, we stumbled upon a VERY good problem to have. My Deuter Fox 40L and Shaun&#8217;s Deuter ACT lite 65+10L were just WAY too much. Shaun&#8217;s clothes were swimming in an almost entirely empty backpack and mine wasn&#8217;t nearly packed tight enough. We had reached the &#8220;promised land&#8221; of packing.</p>
<p>….Now to figure out how to make our technology day pack NOT the heaviest thing we are carrying around.</p>
<p>You live and learn, right? I&#8217;m curious to see where we will be in 2 more years.</p>
<p>(Side note: Shaun&#8217;s sees us in a private jet with rolling suitcases. I applaud him for thinking big.)</p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/beach-packing-list-essential/">Our Essential Beach Packing List</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~4/MK-NTlI7HKQ" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://overyonderlust.com/beach-packing-list-essential/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://overyonderlust.com/beach-packing-list-essential/</feedburner:origLink><feedburner:origLink>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OverYonderlust/~3/XIV_OuS8XdI/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Things To Do in Zanzibar on a Backpacker’s Budget</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~3/Ay_8I3qe1qY/</link>
		<comments>http://overyonderlust.com/10-things-to-do-in-zanzibar-on-a-backpackers-budget/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 20:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Guest</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zanzibar]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://overyonderlust.com/?p=7944</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Today we bring you something a bit different. Emma Spire of Backpacking Spirit has brought you a little bit of Africa&#8230; Zanzibar to be exact. *swoon* How exotic! When people think of Zanzibar – a small island off the East Coast of Africa, they often think of honeymooners, five star resorts and a big hole [...]</p><p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/10-things-to-do-in-zanzibar-on-a-backpackers-budget/">10 Things To Do in Zanzibar on a Backpacker’s Budget</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Today we bring you something a bit different. Emma Spire of Backpacking Spirit has brought you a little bit of Africa&#8230; Zanzibar to be exact. *swoon* How exotic!</strong></em></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">When people think of Zanzibar – a small island off the East Coast of Africa, they often think of honeymooners, five star resorts and a big hole in their wallets. What a lot of people don’t know, however, is that Zanzibar is an Island open to travellers on any budget – even the shoestring backpackers’ budget….</span></p>
<p>I travelled to Zanzibar last year, and I can safely say that I found my personal slice of paradise on the island; perfect white sand beaches melt into crystal clear azure waters, the culture and history is so abundant it seeps into your bones, and the range of cheap activities is enough to keep even the most active backpacker busy!</p>
<p>Below I have compiled a list of 10 things to do in Zanzibar on a backpacker’s budget – all of the activities below will cost you <strong>less than $20</strong>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" alt="Karibu Zanzibar" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Karibu-Zanzibar.jpg" width="482" height="362" /></p>
<h2>1. Prison Island</h2>
<p>Prison Island is only a 20 -30 minute boat trip from Zanzibar. This island is steeped in history; it was once used as a place where slaves were detained and after this period, it was turned into a camp where people with deadly diseases were sent. Nowadays, however, this stunning little island is a nature reserve for giant tortoises and a place to see the ruins that once functioned as the prison. Prison Island makes for a fun and cheap day trip from Zanzibar.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" alt="Prison Island" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Prison-Island.jpg" width="482" height="362" /></p>
<h2>2. Beaches</h2>
<p>Zanzibar’s eastern beaches are amongst the world’s best. These quiet, beautiful and pristine beaches will not disappoint! The top 5 beaches to visit are as follows:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7949" alt="Beaches" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Beaches.jpg" width="482" height="362" /></p>
<p><strong>Nungwi:</strong> Nungwi is a village located at Zanzibar’s North West tip. It is a popular stop for backpackers though it has no-where near the same floods of tourists as many other backpacker spots, namely South East Asia and therefore enjoys Zanzibar’s trademark tranquillity. Nungwi beach is a beautiful spot and is an excellent choice for swimming due to the tide which doesn’t venture out too far.</p>
<p><strong>Kendwa:</strong> This village is located next to Nungwi and is within walking distance. Kendwa has pristine white beaches and azure waters with an excellent selection of bars and restaurants on the waterfront.</p>
<p><strong>Pongwe:</strong> A picture perfect beach located south of Kendwa and Nungwi; this is a quiet beach exempt from the backpacking crowd of Nungwi and Kendwa.</p>
<p><strong>Paje:</strong> This beach is located on the South East of Zanzibar and also draws the attention of travellers. Paje is a popular beach for water sports.</p>
<p><strong>Matemwe:</strong> A stunningly quiet beach which offers a small selection of cafes and guest houses. Palm trees sway in the Zanzibari breeze and local villagers go about their daily lives in this sleepy beachside sanctuary.</p>
<h2>3. Stone Town</h2>
<p>With stunning white washed buildings and culture galore, Stone Town is the heart of Zanzibar and is thought to be the only functioning ancient town left in East Africa. With its multitude of historic sites, markets and tours, Stone Town will see that every day you spend there is packed with activities! When in Stone Town check out Mercury’s restaurant; this restaurant pays tribute to Freddy Mercury who was born in Zanzibar in 1946. There are interesting relics from the Queen band member scattered throughout the bar.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7950" alt="Stone Town" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Stone-Town.jpg" width="477" height="318" /></p>
<h2>4. Slave Market</h2>
<p>The slave market is located in Stone Town. This ancient site is a sad, poignant yet interesting place to visit to learn about Zanzibar’s history of the slave trade.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7952" alt="Slave Market" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Slave-Market.jpg" width="482" height="362" /></p>
<h2>5. Darajani Market</h2>
<p>The Darajani located in Stone Town is famous for its vibrancy, colourfulness and range of vendors. This exciting market is well worth a visit and will give you a great taster into local life.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7953" alt="Darajani Market" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Darajani-Market.jpg" width="482" height="362" /></p>
<h2>6. Snorkelling and diving</h2>
<p>Zanzibar is excellent for its diving and snorkelling. There are many different locations on the island where you can take a trip; a recommended snorkel trip is to Pemba Island from Nungwi. You will sail to Pemba on a typical Zanzibari dhow boat which is an experience in itself…</p>
<p>The beautiful little island of Pemba makes quite the picture is you sail close to it. You will snorkel close to the shores of the island; most trips will include lunch and light refreshments.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7954" alt="Snorkelling and Diving" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Snorkelling-and-Diving.jpg" width="490" height="404" /></p>
<h2>7. Forodhani Gardens</h2>
<p>Located in Stone Town, the Forodhani Gardens are situated right on the coast and make for a perfect evening stroll; here, locals prepare tasty local dishes and there is a great atmosphere as locals and backpacker’s alike come to taste the delights of the local cuisine.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7955" alt="Forohani Gardens" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Forohani-Gardens.jpg" width="477" height="318" /></p>
<h2>8. Palace Museum &amp; House of Wonders</h2>
<p>The palace museum is also known as Sultan’s Palace, and is referred to as Beit-el-Sahel and it is one of the most prominent historic buildings in Stone Town and well worth a visit. The Palace Museum is situated in the waterfront; it was built in the 19th century to house the Sultan’s family. After the 1964 revolution the site was used as a Government building and re-named to “The People’s Palace.” Nowadays it serves as a museum and showcases relics of the past Sultan family.</p>
<p>The House of wonders is also a very prominent building in Stone Town and functions as one of the main landmarks. It is a fascinating exhibition of Zanzibari and Swahili culture.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7956" alt="Palace Museum and House of Wonders" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Palace-Museum-and-House-of-Wonders.jpg" width="482" height="362" /></p>
<h2>9. Spice Tour</h2>
<p>Zanzibar is famous for its spice industry, and therefore spice tours are readily available. Don’t miss out on a spice tour when in Zanzibar – it’s a great way of learning more about one of the Island’s major industries.</p>
<h2>10. The Old Fort</h2>
<p>The Old Fort is Stone Town’s oldest building. This historic building is located on the seafront opposite the Forodhani Gardens. The Old Fort was built in the 17th century and its purpose was to defend the island from attacks from the Portuguese. Today, The Old Fort is a place to see the remains of the former fort, and the courtyard in the centre sells local merchandise and there is also an amphitheatre where events are held most evenings.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7957" alt="The Old Fort" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/The-Old-Fort.jpg" width="477" height="318" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-7958" alt="Emma Spires" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Emma-Spires.jpg" width="185" height="264" /><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>About the Author</strong></span></p>
<p><em>Emma Spires is a backpacker with a serious case of itchy feet! Her first trip was a solo adventure at aged 17 to Ghana, West Africa, to participate in a Volunteering project. Nine years later, she has covered every continent in the world, but still has not cured those itchy feet!</em></p>
<p><em>Her website, <a href="http://www.backpacking-spirit.com/">Backpacking Spirit</a> provides travellers with first-rate travel tips, advice and inspiration; it is also a place where you can find reviews and recommendations for backpacking supplies, packing check lists, and backpacking stories from travellers around the world. Emma’s site <a href="http://www.backpackingspiritblog.com/">Backpacking Spirit Blog</a> is a site that follows Emma’s journey as she backpacks every continent in the world; the highs, the lows, and everything in between!</em></p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/10-things-to-do-in-zanzibar-on-a-backpackers-budget/">10 Things To Do in Zanzibar on a Backpacker’s Budget</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~4/Ay_8I3qe1qY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://overyonderlust.com/10-things-to-do-in-zanzibar-on-a-backpackers-budget/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://overyonderlust.com/10-things-to-do-in-zanzibar-on-a-backpackers-budget/</feedburner:origLink><feedburner:origLink>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OverYonderlust/~3/27RXJw5kzFM/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Worst Travel Day EVER</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~3/tr-gAxTzdDo/</link>
		<comments>http://overyonderlust.com/worst-travel-day-ever/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 16:52:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Erica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://overyonderlust.com/?p=7914</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Flying from Berlin to Austin this past March was probably one of the worst (if not THE worst) travel day that has befallen us. Now, on a normal, regular priced ticket, I’m sure this flight shouldn’t have taken more than 15 hours to get from point A to point B. My cheapskate self put us [...]</p><p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/worst-travel-day-ever/">Worst Travel Day EVER</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_7915" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><img class="size-full wp-image-7915" alt="travel day" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/photo13.jpg" width="640" height="480" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Sad pandas sitting in Heathrow.</p></div>
<p>Flying from Berlin to Austin this past March was probably one of the worst (if not THE worst) travel day that has befallen us.</p>
<p>Now, on a normal, regular priced ticket, I’m sure this flight shouldn’t have taken more than 15 hours <a title="Road Warriors: Traveling Through Central America" href="http://overyonderlust.com/road-warriors-traveling-through-central-america/" target="_blank">to get from point A to point B</a>. My cheapskate self put us on a 19 hour, 2 layover trip that had stopovers in both Heathrow and JFK.</p>
<p>Welcome to my hell (in neat, awesome bullet points!).</p>
<ul>
<li>Woke up after <strong>3 hours of sleep</strong>. We must love our friends in Berlin to have stayed out so late the night prior.</li>
<li>Shaun was a bit groggy and noticed he was sniffling and had <strong>extreme sinus pressure</strong>. This is something you want to avoid at all costs when on a trans-ANYTHING flight.</li>
<li>During our 3 hours of sleep, <strong>1 inch of snow had accumulated</strong> on the ground. We trudged our way to the U-Bahn with our rolling suitcases.</li>
<li>We arrived at the U-Bahn stop for the airport bus and <strong>it ran late</strong>, leaving us open to the elements and the extreme snowfall (to be fair, any snowfall is extreme for us Austin peeps).</li>
<li>After checking into the slightly confusing Tegel airport, we went through our <strong>first security checkpoint</strong>.</li>
<li>At the gate, we notice that <strong>none of the planes</strong> had started the de-icing process.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/276253_Papel-de-Parede-Meme-Jackie-Chan_1280x1024.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7916" alt="276253_Papel-de-Parede-Meme-Jackie-Chan_1280x1024" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/276253_Papel-de-Parede-Meme-Jackie-Chan_1280x1024-1024x819.jpg" width="600" height="479" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li>We board onto the plane and sit for a while. The captain notifies us that we are <strong>14th in line for the de-icing station</strong>. They have to physically drag the plane to a station and have no clue how long it will take.</li>
</ul>
<div id="attachment_7937" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><img class="size-large wp-image-7937" alt="de-icing plane" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/photo14-1024x768.jpg" width="600" height="450" /><p class="wp-caption-text">I should have known how the day was going to end when I took this picture&#8230;</p></div>
<p style="text-align: center;">
<ul>
<li>I get seated in front of an unruly 5 year old who is kicking and <strong>violently shaking my seat</strong>. Shaun takes the middle seat and sits in front of the screaming 2 year old. Normally I don’t mind kids on flights but this parent had no control. I remind myself to take my birth control later on.<img class="alignright size-full wp-image-7919" alt="travel day" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/images.jpg" width="259" height="194" /></li>
<li><strong>Shaun’s head explodes</strong> on the flight.</li>
<li>We <strong>miss our connection</strong> in London.</li>
<li>After standing in long, windy line at the “Missed Connections” desk, new tickets are assigned to us for a flight to Dallas, TX departing in 3 hours (which would only put us an hour behind of our original arrival time in Austin!). I had to tell the lady what major airports flew home and we had to avoid NYC and Chicago as well due to <strong>impending Blizzard</strong>.</li>
<li>Re-check in and go through our <strong>second security checkpoint</strong>.</li>
<li>We get<strong> taken advantage of</strong> as there have been no other money exchange booths available to us and get 22 USD for 26 EUR. *OUCH*</li>
<li>As we sit on the plane waiting to be taxied out to the runway, another plane was being taxied behind us and their t<strong>ow car broke down</strong>&#8230; DIRECTLY BEHIND US.</li>
<li>After no response from the airport, airline, or maintenance, we had to <strong>sit and wait for someone</strong> to rescue this random tow car.</li>
<li>After 1 1/2 hours a mechanic shows up and <strong>takes 2 minutes</strong> to get the car started and moved.</li>
<li><strong>Shaun’s head explodes</strong> on the plane and we miss the connection in Dallas.</li>
<li>As we exit the plane, the airline already had new tickets printed giving us 30 more minutes of time. *armpump*</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_7926" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 287px"><img class="size-full wp-image-7926 " alt="Photo by Evan Sheline" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/images3.jpg" width="277" height="182" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Evan Sheline</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>We run. I give Run, Lola, Run a run for the money. I continue to run even after <strong>my asthma kicks in</strong>.</li>
<li>Hopes are dashed as we come to the <strong>ridiculously long immigration line</strong> (to get back INTO the country) and no one really cares to help us get expedited.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7927" alt="" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/GreatSCott.jpg" width="225" height="224" /></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>I break down</strong>. Tears start flowing. We have reached 24 hours of travel. People in the immigration line stare while trying to figure out what is wrong with me.</li>
<li>We get let back into the USA and RUN to pick up our bags. Hopes are dashed again as we arrive at the <strong>ridiculously long customs line</strong>, with no less than 6 “S” turns. Shaun had to fight to get expedited with 5 minutes left before our boarding time.</li>
<li>We have to <strong>re-check our bags</strong> after leaving customs.</li>
<li>We realize our departure terminal is on the <strong>opposite side of the airport</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/FU.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7928" alt="FU" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/FU.jpg" width="261" height="193" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li>We run to the closest security checkpoint. A security worker tells us that the line is really long and that we should <strong>run to the next checkpoint</strong> as there will be fewer people.</li>
<li>We arrive at our <strong>third security checkpoint</strong>, throw our stuff on the belt, take off our shoes and wait.</li>
<li>The TSA decide to turn on and start using the full body scanner. They stop all processing while they <strong>wait for the machine to warm up</strong>.</li>
<li>We scan, grab our stuff, and run to the Skylink (the train to take you to other terminals) and <strong>barely make it inside the train</strong> as the doors close behind us.</li>
<li>We get off at Terminal C and run to the gate.</li>
<li>The <strong>gate had been moved</strong> to Terminal A.</li>
<li>We run back to the Skylink and once again <strong>barely make it inside the train</strong> as the doors close behind us.</li>
<li>We arrive in Terminal A huffing and puffing, having run as fast as we could to the gate.</li>
<li>The plane had already boarded and <strong>the gate doors are shut</strong>. 4 other people who arrived late from a delayed Minnesota flight were trying to convince the airline workers to allow them to board, to no avail.</li>
<li>I try to <strong>hold back more tears</strong> as we join the pleading.</li>
<li>Due to the fact we had just come off an international flight, they decide to open the doors for us and the Minnesota people (who are extremely appreciative that we helped get them on the plane).</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/foreveralone.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7931" alt="foreveralone" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/foreveralone.jpg" width="400" height="464" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li>We plop down in the first available seats, wheezing.</li>
<li>I fall asleep on the 35 minute flight to Austin (5 minutes added due to <strong>crazy lightning storm</strong>) while <strong>Shaun’s head explodes</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/head-explode.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7932" alt="head-explode" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/head-explode.jpg" width="500" height="421" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li>We sit at the luggage carousel, crossing our fingers that our baggage also made it onto the plane. We had been through the biggest ordeal out of everyone on the plane.</li>
<li>We do a victory dance when our luggage arrives.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Freddie.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7933" alt="Freddie" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Freddie.jpg" width="259" height="194" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Other passengers of our flight begin applauding</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p>It took us 26 hours 15 minutes from door to door and my mental state would be considered shoddy at best by the time we arrived in warm, balmy Austin, Texas. You can imagine my glee when my very awesome roomie was all smiles and on time to pick us up. I think any other issues and I would have gone postal.</p>
<p>Note to self: You have the money to pay a little extra for peace of mind. This was then solidified on our current trip to Guatemala when we missed our connection in Ft. Lauderdale and were handed a 2 day layover. WOMP WOMP</p>
<p>I’m scared that Shaun will want to start taking over the plans&#8230;</p>
<p>Who am I kidding?! <img src='http://overyonderlust.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif' alt=':P' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p>What are your bad travel experiences? Do you avoid certain modes of transportation, or do you think it is something we all “just have to deal with”?</p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/worst-travel-day-ever/">Worst Travel Day EVER</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~4/tr-gAxTzdDo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://overyonderlust.com/worst-travel-day-ever/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://overyonderlust.com/worst-travel-day-ever/</feedburner:origLink><feedburner:origLink>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OverYonderlust/~3/5sdrfCEE6ss/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Round Up – 365 Days Project: 64-70</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~3/--m9qhxxnD0/</link>
		<comments>http://overyonderlust.com/365-days-project-64-70/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 17:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Erica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Exposure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://overyonderlust.com/?p=7908</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Yes, yes, I know I fail when it came to keeping up with the Weekly Round Up of our 365 Days Project but here we are! This past week we have been boatsitting/dogsitting in Rio Dulce, Guatemala, trying to take it easy after a crazy time in Berlin. But seriously, I never EVER suggest going [...]</p><p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/365-days-project-64-70/">Weekly Round Up &#8211; 365 Days Project: 64-70</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, yes, I know I fail when it came to keeping up with the <a title="Weekly Round Up – 365 Days Project: 46-52" href="http://overyonderlust.com/365-days-project-46-52/" target="_blank">Weekly Round Up</a> of our 365 Days Project but here we are! This past week we have been boatsitting/dogsitting in Rio Dulce, Guatemala, trying to take it easy after a crazy time in Berlin. But seriously, I never EVER suggest going from a climate that is below freezing to one that has a heat index of 40C/100F with 100% humidity. WOW, what a change!</p>
<p>So without further ado, I bring you&#8230; US!</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 622px"><a title="64/365 Make sure to make some time for yourself when traveling. Our mini-vacation has really taken the stress off of all the freelance work we do. Sometimes you just have to slow down. #365days by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8607169167/"><img alt="365 Days Project" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8257/8607169167_c66da59e1d_z.jpg" width="612" height="612" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">64/365 Make sure to make some time for yourself when traveling. Our mini-vacation has really taken the stress off of all the freelance work we do. Sometimes you just have to slow down. #365days</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 622px"><a title="65/365 I am happiest when I'm near the water. Michelada ordered and things about to get even better. #365days by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8612296248/"><img alt="365 Days Project" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8262/8612296248_d8c9ee3848_z.jpg" width="612" height="612" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">65/365 I am happiest when I&#8217;m near the water. Michelada ordered and things about to get even better. #365days</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 622px"><a title="66/365 Boat living... Not being able to stand in your dining room. Shaun has injured himself multiple times now when forgetting how low the ceiling is. #365days by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8615553786/"><img alt="365 Days Project" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8126/8615553786_6a3a1fdd7c_z.jpg" width="612" height="612" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">66/365 Boat living&#8230; Not being able to stand in your dining room. Shaun has injured himself multiple times now when forgetting how low the ceiling is. #365days</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 622px"><a title="67/365 DAY DRINKING! That is all. #365days by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8617855674/"><img alt="365 Days Project" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8249/8617855674_cd84cd950f_z.jpg" width="612" height="612" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">67/365 DAY DRINKING! That is all. #365days</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 622px"><a title="68/365 We are taking our R&amp;R very seriously. It is helping what appeared to be burnout. #365days by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8620898362/"><img alt="365 Days Project" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8253/8620898362_2260983d8d_z.jpg" width="612" height="612" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">68/365 We are taking our R&amp;R very seriously. It is helping what appeared to be burnout. #365days</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 622px"><a title="69/365 This water is a tease. I'm afraid of growing a third arm if I go in. #365days by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8622386017/"><img alt="365 Days Project" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8112/8622386017_302e1209a4_z.jpg" width="612" height="612" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">69/365 This water is a tease. I&#8217;m afraid of growing a third arm if I go in. #365days</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 622px"><a title="70/365 Our favorite time of the day- PALETA TIME! #365days #beattheheat by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8625856650/"><img alt="365 Days Project" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8243/8625856650_1cc9a29fde_z.jpg" width="612" height="612" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">70/365 Our favorite time of the day- PALETA TIME! #365days #beattheheat</p></div>
<p>Make sure to follow us on <a href="http://instagram.com/overyonderlust" target="_blank">Instagram</a> for our daily pictures of where we are NOW! There are a lot of pics I don&#8217;t post to Facebook or Twitter. <img src='http://overyonderlust.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif' alt=':P' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/365-days-project-64-70/">Weekly Round Up &#8211; 365 Days Project: 64-70</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~4/--m9qhxxnD0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://overyonderlust.com/365-days-project-64-70/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://overyonderlust.com/365-days-project-64-70/</feedburner:origLink><feedburner:origLink>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OverYonderlust/~3/E3Ish5xWR2M/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Momentos: Berlin</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~3/o9nTEVFU2Ac/</link>
		<comments>http://overyonderlust.com/momentos-berlin/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 14:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Erica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://overyonderlust.com/?p=7903</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Our time in Berlin went so quickly! Even though we were there during one of the darkest and coldest winters on record, I still fell madly in love with it. I can only imagine what summer would do to me &#8211; put me into a full blown Berlin trance? We recently invested in the newest [...]</p><p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/momentos-berlin/">Momentos: Berlin</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our time in Berlin went so quickly! Even though we were there during one of the darkest and coldest winters on record, I still fell madly in love with it. I can only imagine what summer would do to me &#8211; put me into a full blown Berlin trance?</p>
<p>We recently invested in the newest Go Pro (Hero 3 Black Edition) since my new computer can handle video now. We&#8217;re a little rusty on the video front but you gotta hop back on the horse, right? This isn&#8217;t all of Berlin (obviously), but a few moments that we felt were really important to us. I hope you enjoy and we&#8217;ll get back to making those <a title="Episode 19 – Puenting: Banos, Ecuador" href="http://overyonderlust.com/episode-19-puenting-banos-ecuador/" target="_blank">awesome adventure travel videos</a> (hoping to get some awesome diving footage in Mexico!).</p>
<p>Happy Friday!</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/QFOnOLJi7Ug" height="480" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/momentos-berlin/">Momentos: Berlin</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~4/o9nTEVFU2Ac" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://overyonderlust.com/momentos-berlin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://overyonderlust.com/momentos-berlin/</feedburner:origLink><feedburner:origLink>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OverYonderlust/~3/jhCtTNDuyJ0/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Teufelsberg: A Graffiti Paradise at an Abandoned Spy Station</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~3/VL25-LgxjL0/</link>
		<comments>http://overyonderlust.com/teufelsberg-graffiti-abandoned-buildings/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 17:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Erica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://overyonderlust.com/?p=7887</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>“I know! Let’s go hike through the snow, up a mountain, to an abandoned spy building to see some graffiti!” I think I started turning a bit nutty while in Berlin. Who was this person and what did they do with warm weather Erica? Was I really willing to go through an impending snowstorm to [...]</p><p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/teufelsberg-graffiti-abandoned-buildings/">Teufelsberg: A Graffiti Paradise at an Abandoned Spy Station</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-32 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8617157796/"><img alt="abandoned buildings Berlin Graffiti-32" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8531/8617157796_20125cbec6_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p>“I know! Let’s go hike through the snow, up a mountain, to an abandoned spy building to see some graffiti!”</p>
<p>I think I started <a title="Don’t Hassel the Hoff in Berlin" href="http://overyonderlust.com/dont-hassel-the-hoff-in-berlin/" target="_blank">turning a bit nutty while in Berlin</a>. Who was this person and what did they do with warm weather Erica? Was I really willing to go through an impending snowstorm to head to Teufelsberg? Apparently I was.</p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-31 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8617162054/"><img alt="abandoned buildings" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8254/8617162054_17b82c1024_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p>It must have rubbed off on me here as Berliners are some of the most resilient people I’ve ever seen. Dog walks, jogs, hikes, and beer runs will take place in the heaviest snowfall. Nothing will stop these people from having a social life!</p>
<p>In preparation, we got some advice from people living in Berlin about how to get there. It is somewhat of an off the beaten path location and there aren’t really any specific directions on getting to Teufelsberg if you’re planning on walking it.</p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-35 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8617144340/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-35" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8531/8617144340_d964159050_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p>“Oh, once you get off at Gruneswald, you will see it. Just walk in that direction.”</p>
<p>So we did&#8230; except&#8230; you can’t see anything BECAUSE THERE IS A GIANT FOREST IN FRONT OF YOU. The hill isn’t that big!</p>
<p>After some wandering, we figured out that when you get off of the S-Bahn stop you need go under the highway and through the park. There is a map that will give you an idea of where it is. Just keep walking and once you have made it mostly through the giant forest, you can catch a glimpse of the tower to confirm that you’re going the right way or give you new bearings to follow. Soon after you will cross a paved road at the base of the hill. From there you just meander your way to the top on the gazillion intertwining walking trails. There is no wrong way and they all generally head you in the right direction. It should take you no longer than 30-45 minutes from the train station to the gate.</p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-36 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8616035495/"><img alt="abandoned buildings Berlin Graffiti-36" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8401/8616035495_66138f3b35_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p>Once you get to the top you have two choices:</p>
<p>1. Yell for someone at the front gate to let you in. They charge you 7 EUR and will give you an hour to explore and/or do a tour. No one is really sure if these guys are official or if these graffiti artists are taking it upon themselves to make extra money. They even give you a stamp on your hand so the other “security” people in the abandoned buildings don’t give you hell.</p>
<p>2. Break in. There are many holes in the gate around the property that you can slip into. Note that they are always patching them up so you either have to a) bring bolt cutters or b) revert to number 1. The guy who eventually let us in initially threatened us with a 90 EUR fine for trespassing when he saw us meandering around the perimeter (there was no one at the front when we arrived). Luckily he turned out to be a really nice guy who let us explore unsupervised.</p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-30 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8617030330/"><img alt="Teufelsberg abandoned buildings" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8390/8617030330_3d0a59bb7b_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p>However, the biggest plus about making the trek on a snowy weekday is that we were the ONLY people at Teufelsberg. We had this abandoned playground to ourselves.</p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-33 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8616049161/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin abandoned buildings" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8404/8616049161_a18e04d988_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p>If you come, plan for at least an hour. There is so much to see &#8211; it is a photogasm waiting to happen. Just make sure to avoid certain buildings due to toxic gas leaks and rotting wooden boards that could give way at any time and you have your own paradise.</p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-29 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8615932067/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti abandoned buildings" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8522/8615932067_526c0b2ca2_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p>And while the biggest draw is the graffiti, one of the best parts awaits you at the top of the tower. After climbing 6 or 7 floors in pitch black staircases, you come to an acoustic dome (where they would do all the spying). This place will echo for 9+ seconds. It really screws with your head when you can hear yourself breathing as if you’re standing next to yourself.</p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-34 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8616044563/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-34" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8537/8616044563_a01ebafc3b_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p>It was when we got up here that we noticed how bad the snowstorm was becoming. High winds and horizontal snow got me a little concerned. Between the <a title="White Knuckles and Seal Poop: The Great Snowstorm" href="http://overyonderlust.com/iceland-weather/" target="_blank">snowstorm in Iceland</a> and this snowy fiasco, I turned to Shaun in horror and said, “This is how people get killed. Why do we keep doing things like this?!” We headed back down in a hurry and rushed to the front gate.</p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-22 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8617017388/"><img class="aligncenter" alt="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-22" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8109/8617017388_321bbacc29_c.jpg" width="531" height="800" /></a></p>
<p>This is when we realized that maybe it wasn’t a good thing that we were the only ones here. The exit gate was locked. There was no one in sight. After 10 minutes of shouting “HELLOOOOOO!” Shaun took it upon himself to look for a sign of life as the snowflakes accumulated on our jackets. After dragging away an artist in full painting gear (he looked straight out of Contagion), we left, full of smiles as we lifted our faces to the sky to catch snowflakes on our tongues, happily kicking up snow on our way back.</p>
<p>I didn’t regret a thing.</p>
<p>Have you ever been determined to have an adventure &#8211; no matter the outcome?</p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-24 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8617008788/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-24" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8251/8617008788_165da25a6c_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-14 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8614337346/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin abandoned buildings" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8248/8614337346_6339d96445_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-1 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8614265126/"><img alt="abandoned buildings Berlin Graffiti-1" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8406/8614265126_538437721a_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-18 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8616986998/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-18" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8110/8616986998_15fea4924e_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-17 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8616986770/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-17" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8263/8616986770_df3e10f824_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-16 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8616986456/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-16" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8241/8616986456_6f2fe2231f_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-11 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8614314866/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-11" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8405/8614314866_87566d9c27_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-10 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8613199683/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-10" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8398/8613199683_1b93dcdee3_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-6 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8613177535/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-6" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8385/8613177535_acac81e197_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-3 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8614272602/"><img alt="Teufelsberg Berlin Graffiti-3" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8264/8614272602_80743dfff8_c.jpg" width="800" height="531" /></a></p>
<p>***And a HUGE thanks to Kirsten Alana of <a href="http://www.aviatorsandacamera.com/">Aviators and a Camera</a> for reminding me about this awesome place and getting me off my butt to take pics.***</p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/teufelsberg-graffiti-abandoned-buildings/">Teufelsberg: A Graffiti Paradise at an Abandoned Spy Station</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~4/VL25-LgxjL0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://overyonderlust.com/teufelsberg-graffiti-abandoned-buildings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://overyonderlust.com/teufelsberg-graffiti-abandoned-buildings/</feedburner:origLink><feedburner:origLink>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OverYonderlust/~3/LqCf5Sl_Kdc/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Diving For Sunken Treasure – Gypsy Punk in Berlin</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~3/a1wfkgMGbyY/</link>
		<comments>http://overyonderlust.com/gypsy-punk-diving-for-sunken-treasure/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 17:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Erica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://overyonderlust.com/?p=7875</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>It is hard for me to justify heading out to a show on a weekend night. Coming from Austin, Texas, I thought I had heard it all. I had become incredibly jaded, I didn’t think there was anything new out there for me, and I felt dated in a sea of young twenty somethings when [...]</p><p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/gypsy-punk-diving-for-sunken-treasure/">Diving For Sunken Treasure &#8211; Gypsy Punk in Berlin</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-1 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8561939675/"><img alt="Gypsy punk Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-1" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8370/8561939675_a1541bc72e_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>It is hard for me to justify heading out to a show on a weekend night. Coming from Austin, Texas, I thought I had heard it all. I had become incredibly jaded, I didn’t think there was anything new out there for me, and I felt dated in a sea of young twenty somethings when heading out.</p>
<p>Little did I know I would giggle like a 15 year old fangirl when I got to see my friend’s band &#8211; <em>Diving For Sunken Treasure</em> &#8211; at Kaffee Burger in Berlin. The spark ignited again.</p>
<p><a title="Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-29 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8563149514/"><img alt="Gypsy punk Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-29" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8527/8563149514_95643378fa_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>We walked in a bit early and I could tell this place had character. The vibe was fantastic. With cheap German beer in hand, I could tell it was going to be a great night. Before we knew it it was PACKED with people shoulder to shoulder &#8211; and all sorts of people at that! Punk rock kids, hipsters, hippies, general populace&#8230; (don’t ask me where we fit in there)</p>
<p>And with the first chord the crowd went nuts. Screams, cheers, and whistles were heard while everyone broke into dance. A huge smile came across my face.</p>
<p>This&#8230; THIS is what I’ve been waiting for.</p>
<p>My trigger finger went crazy and I took a bazillion photos. They had charisma. They had talent. It was really REALLY good.</p>
<p>I wish I could take them back with me to Austin and showcase them at SXSW.</p>
<p>I wanted the world to hear them.</p>
<p>So I’m doing what I can do and sharing the love.</p>
<p><a title="5 Reasons We Want to Move to Berlin" href="http://overyonderlust.com/move-to-berlin-5-reasons/" target="_blank">I found my heart in Berlin</a>. I hope you can see why.</p>
<p>Enjoy some pics from the show and play the following YouTube video to get some moody awesomeness flowin’. <img src='http://overyonderlust.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif' alt=':D' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/SwtLwzrXLBA" height="480" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><a title="Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-19 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8562006791/"><img alt="Gypsy punk Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-19" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8523/8562006791_b37489ccae_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-11 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8563086064/"><img alt="Gypsy punk Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-11" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8532/8563086064_e247d7b6cc_z.jpg" width="300" height="451" /></a><a title="Gypsy punk Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-10 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8561975291/"><img alt="Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-10" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8251/8561975291_83b71576a0_z.jpg" width="300" height="451" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-6 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8563068136/"><img alt="Gypsy punk Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-6" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8376/8563068136_576e28a350_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-8 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8561968329/"><img alt="Gypsy punk Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-8" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8527/8561968329_64acae213f_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-22 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8563123630/"><img alt="live music Berlin Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-22" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8242/8563123630_8e847da380_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-26 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8562029973/"><img alt="bands in Berlin Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-26" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8110/8562029973_6394219894_z.jpg" width="300" height="451" /></a><a title="Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-25 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8562026133/"><img alt="Gypsy Punk Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-25" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8526/8562026133_fc4815ec58_z.jpg" width="300" height="451" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-23 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8562019017/"><img alt="Punk bands berlin Diving For Sunken Treasure Berlin-23" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8389/8562019017_d5d221bb48_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>&#8230;and while the bottom video is not normally what they sound like, I&#8217;m kinda obsessed.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/v8bmjrtsxoY" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><em><strong>Diving For Sunken Treasure:</strong></em><br />
<a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Diving-For-Sunken-Treasure/118311238190377?ref=ts&amp;fref=ts" target="_blank">Facebook</a><br />
<a href="http://www.divingforsunkentreasure.com/" target="_blank">DivingForSunkenTreasure.com </a><br />
<a href="http://www.flight13.com/details/102871/diving-for-sunken-treasure-motherfucker-jazz-bar?locale=en" target="_blank">Album Download</a></p>
<p>ALSO:<br />
HAPPY BIRTHDAY BASTI! xoxo Thanks for inviting us to your show it was AWESOME!</p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/gypsy-punk-diving-for-sunken-treasure/">Diving For Sunken Treasure &#8211; Gypsy Punk in Berlin</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~4/a1wfkgMGbyY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://overyonderlust.com/gypsy-punk-diving-for-sunken-treasure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://overyonderlust.com/gypsy-punk-diving-for-sunken-treasure/</feedburner:origLink><feedburner:origLink>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OverYonderlust/~3/eEw7GObamQU/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Discovering Cambodia’s Deserted Beaches</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~3/tzH3AMFFBrg/</link>
		<comments>http://overyonderlust.com/discovering-cambodias-deserted-beaches/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Erica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cambodia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://overyonderlust.com/?p=7836</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>While we are here in Guatemala, soaking in the sun, I know many of you guys are looking for a winter reprieve from the crazy snow that has somehow lasted this long. Here is a bit of sunshine to brighten up your day by Tammy of Tammy and Chris On the Move. “You need me [...]</p><p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/discovering-cambodias-deserted-beaches/">Discovering Cambodia’s Deserted Beaches</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/bamboo-island-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7844" alt="Best Beaches Cambodia" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/bamboo-island-2.jpg" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: center;"><em>While we are here in Guatemala, soaking in the sun, I know many of you guys are looking for a winter reprieve from the crazy snow that has somehow lasted this long. Here is a bit of sunshine to brighten up your day by Tammy of Tammy and Chris On the Move.<br />
</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">“You need me to shave your legs lady?” Whether you are a man or a woman, these words will inevitably be the first thing you will hear when you step foot on a Cambodian beach. If you decline, the hawkers will touch your leg to proof that there are indeed a few stubbles you should have removed. Welcome to Cambodia, the country of wonders, diplomatic sales women, but also beautiful beaches!</p>
<p dir="ltr">Most people who come to Cambodia only visit the ruins of Angkor Wat and maybe the Killing Fields in Phnom Penh. Only few people know that Cambodia has some lovely and deserted beaches though and despite the fact that on some of them you will bump into a few hawkers, these beaches are well worth discovering.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Cambodia has three beach communities: Sihanoukville, Kep and Koh Kong. The largest one is Sihanoukville which has the best beaches. But whilst the mainland beaches of Kep and Koh Kong are not as nice as those in Sihanoukville they offer their own charms and visiting the offshore islands around these communities is a highlight of any trip in my opinion.</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Koh-Kong.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7843" alt="Best Beaches Cambodia" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Koh-Kong-1024x682.jpg" width="640" height="426" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr">Sihanoukville has seven beaches as well as some offshore islands. Locals and foreigners alike flock here to cool off in the Gulf of Thailand, although you will find that most locals tend to go to Ocheteaul or Hawaii beach.  These beaches are filled with beach stands that offer cheap local Khmer food and you will find a lot of families with children here.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The backpacker hangout is Serendipity beach which is lined with beach restaurants and bars. A number of places open up right up to the beach sand so this is the perfect place for dining, drinking and gazing into the ocean. It is fairly crowded though and full of young backpackers so if you would like to go somewhere a bit more serene you can check out Otres beach, which is also cleaner and you won’t be hassled by hawkers all the time. It has got some very nice and laid-back bars and restaurants, but is a bit out of town.</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/serendipity-beach.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7839" alt="Best Beaches Cambodia" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/serendipity-beach.jpg" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr">If you want a bit more style then Sokha beach is your best bet. This is a private beach and part of the fancy Sokha Beach Resort. This is by far the cleanest, whitest and least busy beach on mainland Sihanoukville. We had lunch in the hotel and then used the beach all afternoon, but I am sure we could have also just gone to the beach without having ordered any food. Despite the hotel being fairly posh the food is actually quite cheap, so I found this to be the perfect escape for an afternoon.</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Sokha-beach.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7837" alt="Best Beaches Cambodia" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Sokha-beach-1024x682.jpg" width="639" height="425" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr">My favourite beaches in Cambodia however are the beaches on the offshore islands, in particular Bamboo Island and Koh Rong off Sihanoukville and Rabbit Island off Kep. You can get to these islands by boat quite easily. Bamboo Island and Rabbit Island are about 1 hour from the mainland and Koh Rong about 2.5 hours. The boat trip is well worth the effort as all islands only have a few bungalows for rent at the moment and the bays are lined with beautiful white and deserted beaches.  Fish and marine-life crowded waters make it great places for snorkeling and diving too. There is no electricity at night, which makes it the perfect spot for people wishing to fulfill their cast-away fantasies.</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/bamboo-island.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7845" alt="Best Beaches Cambodia" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/bamboo-island.jpg" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/koh-rong.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7841" alt="Best Beaches Cambodia" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/koh-rong.jpg" width="639" height="447" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/rabbit-island1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7848" alt="Best Beaches Cambodia" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/rabbit-island1.jpg" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr">There is a lot of development work going on in all beach communities at the moment and islands and beach towns are flocking up new resorts all the time, so I’d go and visit soon before Cambodia’s beaches are as busy as their Thai sisters.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/profile-pic.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7838 alignleft" alt="profile pic" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/profile-pic.jpg" width="150" height="150" /></a>About the author: </strong></em>Tammy is one part of Tammy &amp; Chris on the move travel blog. They are a couple hailing from Germany and England, meaning between them they are efficient and polite, but unable to talk about football or 20th century history. In October 2011 they decided to stop pushing pens around the British civil service to work on human rights issues in Cambodia, and travel around Asia as much as they can.</p>
<p dir="ltr">You can follow their adventures on their <a href="http://tammyandchrisonthemove.blogspot.com/">blog</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/TammyChrisOnTheMove">facebook</a> or <a href="https://twitter.com/TammyOnTheMove">twitter</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">[insert photo: profile pic]</p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/discovering-cambodias-deserted-beaches/">Discovering Cambodia’s Deserted Beaches</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~4/tzH3AMFFBrg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://overyonderlust.com/discovering-cambodias-deserted-beaches/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://overyonderlust.com/discovering-cambodias-deserted-beaches/</feedburner:origLink><feedburner:origLink>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OverYonderlust/~3/fpeRuWaleDI/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>The Secret Level of Nostalgia: The Computer Game Museum in Berlin, Germany</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~3/Jbx_3fME2ME/</link>
		<comments>http://overyonderlust.com/computer-game-museum/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 13:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Shaun</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Information]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://overyonderlust.com/?p=7733</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>With a bowl of Captain Crunch in my lap and Darkwing Duck on the TV, this Saturday morning began like any other in the early 90s. I was so involved with my weekend ritual that I didn’t hear the phone ring. Fortunately, I did hear my Mom yelling that the phone call was for me. [...]</p><p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/computer-game-museum/">The Secret Level of Nostalgia: The Computer Game Museum in Berlin, Germany</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With a bowl of Captain Crunch in my lap and Darkwing Duck on the TV, this Saturday morning began like any other in the early 90s. I was so involved with my weekend ritual that I didn’t hear the phone ring. Fortunately, I did hear my Mom yelling that the phone call was for me. I walked out of the living room peering over my shoulder at the television, wishing this call had been during a commercial.</p>
<p>I picked up the receiver of the dark red rotary phone and said “Hello?”, not hiding the fact I was clearly annoyed. “COME OVER RIGHT NOW!” the voice on the other end yelled. I recognized it as my friend Chris. “I still have to do my chores. I’ll come over later.” I replied, still unenthusiastic about the prospect. “I JUST FIGURED OUT THIS SECRET ON MARIO WHERE I RUN BEHIND THE LEVEL AND GET THIS FLUTE-” before he could say any more I cut him off screaming “I’LL BE RIGHT OVER!”</p>
<p>Never in my life had I done my chores so fast.</p>
<p>So when we heard about the Computerspielemuseum (Computer Game Museum) in Berlin, Germany, the excitement of my childhood returned in an instant and we bumped it to the top of our &#8216;must do&#8217; list.</p>
<p>Unlike finding most points of interest while traveling, getting to the Computer Game Museum is super easy. They have a map <a title="The Computer Game Museum website" href="http://computerspielemuseum.de/">on their website</a>, however, once you get to the Weberwiese stop on the U5 line you will begin seeing visual aids that will point you in the right direction and put a smile on your face.</p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Follow-Me.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7734" alt="computer game museum" src="http://overyonderlust.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Follow-Me.jpg" width="480" height="640" /></a></p>
<p>The nostalgia began snowballing as soon as I walked in and was greeted by one of my favorite heros of all time:</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 650px"><a title="Video Game Museum Berlin-37 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8561927791/"><img alt="Link statue, legend of zelda statue" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8231/8561927791_38616969be_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Link, not Rayman.</p></div>
<p>Seeing as many visitors are not lifetime gamers, the museum does a great job at showing the history and progression of video games through such exhibits as the Wall of Hardware and Game Milestones.</p>
<p><a title="Video Game Museum Berlin-2 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8561813865/"><img alt="Wall of Hardware" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8380/8561813865_a529b5a646_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Video Game Museum Berlin-11 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8562960474/"><img alt="Game Milestones" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8369/8562960474_5d055c21e8_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>Although, the best thing about the Computer Game Museum is that almost everything is interactive. This is a hands-on experience unlike any other.</p>
<p><a title="Video Game Museum Berlin-15 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8562970874/"><img alt="3d game" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8505/8562970874_95ce5b44df_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Video Game Museum Berlin-13 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8561857781/"><img alt="Virtual reality" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8515/8561857781_b165e76b78_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Video Game Museum Berlin-25 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8563001142/"><img alt="Pacman" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8112/8563001142_eb719b05e9_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>And their collection is as impressive as it is extensive. They even have such amazing rarities as the PainStation- a game which pits two players against each other in a pong-esque matchup. However, the difference here is if the other player scores a point, you have to endure electric shocks, intense heat, or being whipped by rubber tubes. The game ends when the loser can no longer handle the punishments and pulls their hand away.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 650px"><a title="Video Game Museum Berlin-21 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8561882805/"><img alt="PainStation" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8229/8561882805_caf7a48671_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Erica refused to play due to the warnings of third degree burns, paralysis, and hematoma.</p></div>
<p>But the best section of the museum, and the one that you should spend the most time in, is the arcade. Loaded with all the classics, here you can get down on some of the best early arcade games- such as Galaga, Gauntlet, Frogger, Space Invaders, Asteroids, Centipede, and Donkey Kong, to name a few.</p>
<p><a title="Video Game Museum Berlin-32 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8563021004/"><img alt="Centipede arcade game" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8523/8563021004_9f5e31ae2f_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Video Game Museum Berlin-16 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8561865707/"><img alt="Classic arcade" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8242/8561865707_836c252411_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="Video Game Museum Berlin-27 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8563007016/"><img class="aligncenter" alt="Donkey Kong arcade game" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8384/8563007016_e4190d2a8a_z.jpg" width="425" height="640" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Video Game Museum Berlin-28 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8563010006/"><img alt="Donkey Kong arcade game" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8369/8563010006_a362aed045_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>With all of the exhibits and information, the Computer Game Museum itself is the perfect analogy of what gaming has accomplished over the years- education, progression, and expression through enjoyable entertainment. Be sure to check out the Computerspielemuseum the next time you&#8217;re in Berlin.</p>
<p><em><strong>Computerspielemuseum</strong></em></p>
<p>Karl-Marx-Allee 93a<br />
10243 Berlin</p>
<p>Hours:<br />
Monday 10:00 a.m. &#8211; 8:00 p.m.<br />
Tuesday &#8211; CLOSED<br />
Wednesday 10:00 a.m. &#8211; 8:00 p.m.<br />
Thursday 10:00 a.m. &#8211; 8:00 p.m.<br />
Friday 10:00 a.m. &#8211; 8:00 p.m.<br />
Saturday 10:00 a.m. &#8211; 8:00 p.m.<br />
Sunday 10:00 a.m. &#8211; 8:00 p.m.</p>
<p>Admission: 8 € (regular), € 5 (students, retired, etc.), 15 € (family ticket), 3 € (school groups)</p>
<p>**Hours and admission costs are subject to change. Schedule and pricing at time of post are shown above.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=Karl-Marx-Allee+93a,+10243+Berlin&amp;aq=&amp;sll=52.51769,13.442&amp;sspn=0.007612,0.019805&amp;t=h&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hq=&amp;hnear=Karl-Marx-Allee+93A,+10243+Berlin,+Germany&amp;z=14&amp;ll=52.51769,13.442&amp;output=embed" height="350" width="425" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<small><a style="color: #0000ff; text-align: left;" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=embed&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=Karl-Marx-Allee+93a,+10243+Berlin&amp;aq=&amp;sll=52.51769,13.442&amp;sspn=0.007612,0.019805&amp;t=h&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hq=&amp;hnear=Karl-Marx-Allee+93A,+10243+Berlin,+Germany&amp;z=14&amp;ll=52.51769,13.442">View Larger Map</a></small></p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/computer-game-museum/">The Secret Level of Nostalgia: The Computer Game Museum in Berlin, Germany</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~4/Jbx_3fME2ME" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://overyonderlust.com/computer-game-museum/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://overyonderlust.com/computer-game-museum/</feedburner:origLink><feedburner:origLink>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OverYonderlust/~3/wHbR3iDn5EY/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Phallic. Fun. Fein. The Currywurst Museum.</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~3/0FZYAVAo-A0/</link>
		<comments>http://overyonderlust.com/currywurst-museum/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 20:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Erica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://overyonderlust.com/?p=7714</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Phallic. Fun. Fein. The Currywurst Museum. Nothing says a good time like a good ol’ sausage couch. I’m not sure exactly what we were thinking but it definitely wasn’t this. Currywurst is a cultural staple in Germany. With humble beginnings in Berlin, Herta Heuwer was able to attain curry, ketchup, and Worcestershire sauce from British [...]</p><p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/currywurst-museum/">Phallic. Fun. Fein. The Currywurst Museum.</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="47/365 Playing with sausage at the curry wurst museum. Had a freaking BLAST. #365days by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8549329608/"><img alt="47/365 Playing with sausage at the curry wurst museum. Had a freaking BLAST. #365days" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8105/8549329608_314aa381d1_z.jpg" width="612" height="612" /></a></p>
<p>Phallic. Fun. Fein. The Currywurst Museum.</p>
<p>Nothing says a good time like a good ol’ sausage couch.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-4 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555707546/"><img alt="Berlin-4" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8522/8555707546_f93e6c6887_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>I’m not sure exactly what we were thinking but it definitely wasn’t this.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-19 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8554537439/"><img alt="Berlin-19" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8516/8554537439_9b8a169224_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>Currywurst is a cultural staple in Germany. With humble beginnings in <a title="5 Reasons We Want to Move to Berlin" href="http://overyonderlust.com/move-to-berlin-5-reasons/" target="_blank">Berlin</a>, Herta Heuwer was able to attain curry, ketchup, and Worcestershire sauce from British troops on the black market during World War II. Little did she know it would turn into the craze that it is today. I’m pretty sure she didn’t envision a building decorated in inflatable ketchup and curry wallpaper.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-11 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555677560/"><img alt="Currywurst Museum Berlin-11" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8523/8555677560_831240546a_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>Everything you ever wanted to know about currywurst can be found here. Take your time, interact, explore.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-7 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555698830/"><img alt="Museum Berlin-7" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8086/8555698830_ac44a537d5_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>Pick up a ketchup bottle and it will play a jingle.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-2 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555713616/"><img alt="Currywurst Museum Berlin-2" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8525/8555713616_81d9016b84_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>Look at a map of Berlin to find all of the currywurst vendors.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-5 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8554594437/"><img alt="Currywurst Museum Berlin-5" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8388/8554594437_bcaf7105aa_z.jpg" width="415" height="276" /></a><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-6 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555702178/"><img alt="Currywurst Museum Berlin-6" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8232/8555702178_1d6d5c2b3c_z.jpg" width="185" height="276" /></a></p>
<p>Write about how currywurst changed your life in the massive guest book. Shaun did.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-10 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555680916/"><img alt="Currywurst Museum Berlin-10" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8243/8555680916_a64ef8e6e4_z.jpg" width="610" height="405" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-9 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555688792/"><img alt="Other Museum Berlin-9" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8373/8555688792_c24789bb71_z.jpg" width="300" height="450" /></a><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-12 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555673902/"><img alt="Alternative Museum Berlin-12" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8372/8555673902_3269ce7cf9_z.jpg" width="300" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>Hug a huge french fry. It was cuddly.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-13 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555670738/"><img alt="Museum Berlin-13" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8107/8555670738_9c767d25de_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>Virtually prepare some sausage for sale.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-16 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555658274/"><img alt="Bratwurst Museum Berlin-16" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8091/8555658274_65dcb53a25_z.jpg" width="415" height="275" /></a><a title="Sausage Museum Berlin-17 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8554544735/"><img alt="Currywurst Museum Berlin-17" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8229/8554544735_b9cc2c5e11_z.jpg" width="181" height="275" /></a></p>
<p>Learn the entire lifecycle of your paper currywurst plate from tree to compost.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-20 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8554534567/"><img alt="Sausage Museum Berlin-20" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8376/8554534567_a1a55039be_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>Play with plastic sausage.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-21 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8554530223/"><img alt="Museum Berlin-21" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8226/8554530223_4eed485966_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-23 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555634912/"><img alt="Museum Berlin-23" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8377/8555634912_af8371193d_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>Ogle.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-25 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555627356/"><img alt="Berlin, Germany" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8512/8555627356_2f2c7a1ec2_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>Eat.</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-29 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8554502779/"><img alt="Museum Berlin-29" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8384/8554502779_07508655ef_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>And while it was a bit pricey for about an hour of childish giggles, it was TOTALLY worth it. I mean, when else are you going to be able to get pictures like this?</p>
<p><a title="Currywurst Museum Berlin-15 by Piratepenpen, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/piratepenpen/8555663932/"><img alt=Museum Berlin-15" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8374/8555663932_022fe11877_z.jpg" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p><em><strong>Deutsches Currywurst Museum Berlin</strong></em></p>
<p>Admission: 9€ (with a small currywurst sample) and 13€ with a 3 plate sampler.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=Deutsches+Currywurst+Museum+Berlin,+Sch%C3%BCtzenstra%C3%9Fe,+Berlin,+Germany&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=currywurst+museum&amp;sll=27.698638,-83.804601&amp;sspn=10.706838,19.226074&amp;t=h&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hq=Deutsches+Currywurst+Museum+Berlin,+Sch%C3%BCtzenstra%C3%9Fe,+Berlin,+Germany&amp;hnear=&amp;radius=15000&amp;ll=52.50883,13.391162&amp;spn=0.071946,0.071946&amp;output=embed" height="400" width="610" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<small><a style="color: #0000ff; text-align: left;" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=embed&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=Deutsches+Currywurst+Museum+Berlin,+Sch%C3%BCtzenstra%C3%9Fe,+Berlin,+Germany&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=currywurst+museum&amp;sll=27.698638,-83.804601&amp;sspn=10.706838,19.226074&amp;t=h&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hq=Deutsches+Currywurst+Museum+Berlin,+Sch%C3%BCtzenstra%C3%9Fe,+Berlin,+Germany&amp;hnear=&amp;radius=15000&amp;ll=52.50883,13.391162&amp;spn=0.071946,0.071946">View Larger Map</a></small></p>
<p><a href="http://overyonderlust.com/currywurst-museum/">Phallic. Fun. Fein. The Currywurst Museum.</a> is a post from: <a href="http://overyonderlust.com">Over Yonderlust</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/feedburner/vGXl/~4/0FZYAVAo-A0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://overyonderlust.com/currywurst-museum/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://overyonderlust.com/currywurst-museum/</feedburner:origLink><feedburner:origLink>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OverYonderlust/~3/_g76SvpLtZU/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.994 seconds. --><!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-13 05:56:39 --><!-- Compression = gzip -->
