<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Words for Worms</title>
	<atom:link href="http://wordsforworms.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://wordsforworms.com</link>
	<description>An Irreverent Book Blog For the Masses</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 22:00:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='wordsforworms.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Words for Worms</title>
		<link>http://wordsforworms.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://wordsforworms.com/osd.xml" title="Words for Worms" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://wordsforworms.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Eleanor &amp; Park: It&#8217;ll Take You Back Faster Than a Whiff of Unwashed Gym Suit.</title>
		<link>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/04/04/eleanor-park-itll-take-you-back-faster-than-a-whiff-of-unwashed-gym-suit/</link>
		<comments>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/04/04/eleanor-park-itll-take-you-back-faster-than-a-whiff-of-unwashed-gym-suit/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Words for Worms</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Young Adult Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eleanor & Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gym class]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hand holding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[high school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rainbow Rowell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YA fiction]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wordsforworms.com/?p=1691</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sup Bookworms?! I say &#8220;sup&#8221; because that was the thing to say when I was in high school. During high school,  I absolutely refused to use the term on the grounds that contractions should use apostrophes. I also wrote song lyrics out on the backs of all the notes I passed between classes and pasted [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1691&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sup Bookworms?!</p>
<p>I say &#8220;sup&#8221; because that was the thing to say when I was in high school. During high school,  I absolutely refused to use the term on the grounds that contractions should use apostrophes. I also wrote song lyrics out on the backs of all the notes I passed between classes and pasted magazine photo collages of grunge rockers onto my notebooks. (A 16 year old girl is a 16 year old girl, no matter her taste in music.)</p>
<p>I know what you&#8217;re thinking. &#8220;Yes, Katie. We KNOW you were a cantankerous teenager. You <a title="Confession Friday: The Perks of Being A Wallflower and Katie’s Teen Angst" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/09/14/the-perks-of-being-a-wallflower/" target="_blank">wrote about it once</a>, plus, you&#8217;re a blogger. An awkward adolescence is a prerequisite, right?&#8221; I swear I have a point. The point is, I just read <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Eleanor-Park-Rainbow-Rowell/dp/1250012570" target="_blank">Eleanor &amp; Park</a> </em>by Rainbow Rowell and it took me back to high school faster than whiff of unwashed gym suit.</p>
<div id="attachment_1692" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 212px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/eandp.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1692  " alt="I listened to a discman on the bus... Because I went to high school in the 90s." src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/eandp.jpg?w=202&#038;h=304" width="202" height="304" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I listened to a discman on the bus&#8230; Because I went to high school in the 90s.</p></div>
<p>Here&#8217;s the deal. It&#8217;s 1986. Eleanor is the new girl in school. She&#8217;s on the curvy side and has wild red hair. Her first day of school, she is denied a seat on the bus by everyone (in a move of calculated cruelty that is innate to the teenage of the species) EXCEPT a half Korean kid named Park. Eleanor and Park don&#8217;t fall in love immediately. In fact, they don&#8217;t even speak. They only begin to break the ice when Park notices that Eleanor has been reading his comic books out of the corner of her eye.</p>
<p>Eleanor&#8217;s got a whole lot of crap going on in her home life. She and her 4 siblings live in squalor with their abusive stepfather and their once vibrant mother (who like many abused women has become a shell of her former self.) Eleanor is in no position to be starting a relationship, but as she and Park progress from friendship to hand holding, she knows she&#8217;s a goner.</p>
<p>THIS BOOK! It does for YA novels what <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0193676/" target="_blank">Freaks and Geeks</a> </em>did for high school on television. My high school experience was not <em>Gossip Girl </em>or <em>Friday Night Lights. </em>My high school experience was a whirlwind of awkward encounters and intense relationships that never materialized. Where hand holding could be <b>MAJOR</b>. It was so refreshing to read about an imperfect heroine who wasn&#8217;t conventionally beautiful. Sure, Eleanor has her good features, but she&#8217;s not a girl who is drop-dead-gorgeous without realizing it (cough, cough, <a title="Campy Vamps: My Secret Shame" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/08/15/campy-vamps-my-secret-shame/">Bella Swan</a>.) And Park? Park is a short Asian kid who experiments with guy-liner. I challenge you to find me another YA leading man who is 5&#8217;4. Even Harry Potter was tall!</p>
<div id="attachment_1694" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 406px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/freaks-geeks.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1694 " alt="Well, NOW they're the cool kids. Source." src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/freaks-geeks.jpg?w=396&#038;h=223" width="396" height="223" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Well, sure, NOW they&#8217;re the cool kids. <a href="http://www.curatormagazine.com/nick-olson/freaks-geeks-and-subverting-the-politics-of-fashion/" target="_blank">Source</a>.</p></div>
<p>No, I didn&#8217;t listen to The Cure on my walkman on the bus, mostly because I didn&#8217;t go to high school in 1986. (I listened to The Counting Crows on my discman. Very skippy, the discman.) Even though my gym suit was definitely less horrifying than Eleanor&#8217;s polyester onesie, I dreaded gym class. My junior year, I was hit in the head with EVERY SINGLE BALL we used. I only wish I were exaggerating. I was beaned with a soccer ball, basketball, volleyball, hockey puck, tennis ball, football, softball, and the absolute pinnacle of my humiliation? Badminton birdie. I wasn&#8217;t subject to intense bullying (although I still do not have good thoughts about that girl with the slicked back ponytail and sinister eyeliner who always laughed at magnetic melon&#8230;) I didn&#8217;t have a messy home life either, but this book isn&#8217;t about winning the screwed up teen experience award. This book is about capturing the essence of being 16. It&#8217;s about first love and identity crises and confusion and the occasional glimmer greatness beneath the awkward.</p>
<p>I chewed through this book in two days and had to let it marinate in my brain juices before I could form coherent thoughts. Katie + <em>Eleanor &amp; Park </em>= Love. The soundtracks may change, but high school will always be the same. Rainbow Rowell gets that, and for that, I salute her. (Insert well timed slow clap.)</p>
<p>Alright bookworms. Please tell me I&#8217;m not alone here. Let&#8217;s take this opportunity to share our most horrifying gym class experiences. It&#8217;ll be like group therapy. Ready? Go!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1691/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1691/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1691&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/04/04/eleanor-park-itll-take-you-back-faster-than-a-whiff-of-unwashed-gym-suit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d13100a03f9d0fc63e2c99c0ba2c7f2?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wordsforworms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/eandp.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I listened to a discman on the bus... Because I went to high school in the 90s.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/freaks-geeks.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Well, NOW they&#039;re the cool kids. Source.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#8217;ve Got a Crush on You! And you, and you, and you, too!</title>
		<link>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/04/02/ive-got-a-crush-on-you-and-you-and-you-and-you-too/</link>
		<comments>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/04/02/ive-got-a-crush-on-you-and-you-and-you-and-you-too/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 13:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Words for Worms</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Classics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coming of Age]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dystopian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anniversaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthdays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fictional Character Crushes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top ten tuesday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wordsforworms.com/?p=1683</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hey There Bookworms, Before I get into today&#8217;s Top Ten Tuesday list, I want to take a moment to give a shout-out to the Hubs. That&#8217;s right, today Jim turns 31. Happy Birthday! The thing that makes this birthday extra super special is that it is ALSO the anniversary of our first date. The TENTH [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1683&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey There Bookworms,</p>
<p>Before I get into today&#8217;s Top Ten Tuesday list, I want to take a moment to give a shout-out to the Hubs. That&#8217;s right, today Jim turns 31. Happy Birthday! The thing that makes this birthday extra super special is that it is ALSO the anniversary of our first date. The TENTH anniversary. (For a first date that took place on a 21st birthday, it was shockingly wholesome.) Yay, Jim! Happy Birth-iversary! I totally still have a crush on you.</p>
<div id="attachment_1684" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 380px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_3818.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1684  " alt="First photo of us as a couple, a mere 10 days after that first date. Which reminds me... Happy Almost Anniversary to Meresa and Scott! (Yeah. He went to a wedding with me after a week and a half. Keeper.)" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_3818.jpg?w=370&#038;h=275" width="370" height="275" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">First photo of us as a couple, a mere 10 days after that first date. Which reminds me&#8230; Happy Almost Anniversary to Meresa and Scott! (Yeah. He went to a wedding with me after a week and a half of dating. Keeper.)</p></div>
<p>You know what the best part about a stable relationship is? Jim&#8217;s not even a tiny bit threatened by the fact that I&#8217;ve got crushes on other boys. Sure, it helps that all the boys are fictional characters&#8230; Like any bookworm, I have an active imagination. Since <a href="http://brokeandbookish.blogspot.com/p/top-ten-tuesday-other-features.html" target="_blank">The Broke and The Bookish </a>asked so nicely, today I shall list my Top Ten Fictional Character Crushes.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/ttt3w.jpeg"><img class="size-full wp-image-827 aligncenter" alt="TTT3W" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/ttt3w.jpeg?w=660"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">1. <strong>Fred and/or George Weasley</strong>. So, here&#8217;s the thing. I hate to admit to this, but, I didn&#8217;t read <em>Harry Potter </em><em></em>until after the first movie came out. This means, among other things, that my mental images of characters were tainted going into the series. I LOVE the Weasley twins, and the movie twins are pretty cute. I know they&#8217;re shorter and rounder in the books, but they&#8217;re so funny and awesome. Laughter is a big deal to me, and I&#8217;m pretty sure a Weasley twin would keep me in stitches. (Maybe not as well as Jim, though. His sense of humor is incredibly absurd and he frequently makes me laugh until my tummy hurts.)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">2. <strong>Jamie Fraser.</strong> I know, I know. I rave about <em>Outlander </em>constantly, but SWOON, Jamie! He&#8217;s strong and smart and he speaks lots of languages and he looks hot in a kilt. Plus, he&#8217;s so head over heels for Claire, it&#8217;s redonk. I mean, really.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">3. <strong>Jon Snow.</strong> <em></em>The new season of <em>Game of Thrones </em>started up the other night. I watched season 1, but for whatever reason I fell off the wagon after that. I&#8217;m considering jumping back on. I mean, I&#8217;ve read all the books, you know? And. JON SNOW. Ned Stark&#8217;s bastard child is one hot piece of ice, if you know what I&#8217;m saying. Really though. I love book Jon. I love TV Jon. Long live Jon Snow!<em></em></p>
<div id="attachment_1685" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 406px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jonsnow.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1685 " alt="Celibacy on The Wall? What a waste! Source." src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jonsnow.jpg?w=396&#038;h=223" width="396" height="223" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Celibacy on The Wall? What a waste! <a href="http://forums.allkpop.com/threads/vorisy56.166025/" target="_blank">Source.</a></p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">4. <strong>Mr. Darcy.</strong><em></em> <em></em>Oh yeah, I just pulled out the old <em>Pride and Prejudice </em>card. How could I not? I mean, he&#8217;s MR. DARCY. Proud. Prejudiced. Secretly in love with the feisty Elizabeth Bennett. Be still my heart!</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">5. <strong>Gus. </strong>You remember, the dreamboat cancer patient from <em><a title="The Fault In Our Stars (Is That We Haven’t Enough Tissues) by John Green" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2013/01/02/the-fault-in-our-stars-is-that-we-havent-enough-tissues-by-john-green/" target="_blank">The Fault In Our Stars</a>? </em>Sure, he didn&#8217;t speak the way any REAL teenager would. He was far too smart and witty and self assured. But. That&#8217;s what <em>Tiger Beat </em>dreams are made of.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">6. <strong>Charlie.</strong> Yep. My teenage self had a big old crush on Charlie from <em><a title="Confession Friday: The Perks of Being A Wallflower and Katie’s Teen Angst" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/09/14/the-perks-of-being-a-wallflower/" target="_blank">The Perks of Being a Wallflower</a>. </em>I loved his brilliant socially stunted antics. And his wounded puppy psyche. Sigh.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">7. <strong>Marius</strong> <strong>Pontmercy. <em></em></strong>I think every girl on the planet imagines that she&#8217;s Eponine when they listen to <em></em>&#8220;On My Own<em>.&#8221; </em>Who among us has never tasted the bitter pill of unrequited love?! <em><a title="Do You Hear The People Sing? (Give Them ALL THE OSCARS!)" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/12/30/do-you-hear-the-people-sing-give-them-all-the-oscars/" target="_blank">Les Miserables</a> </em>the book gives Marius a much juicier backstory than the musical. It certainly doesn&#8217;t hurt Marius&#8217;s swoonworthiness that Eddie Redmayne played the part in the movie&#8230;</p>
<div id="attachment_1686" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 370px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/les-mis-eponin-marius.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1686 " alt="Oh, Eddie. You only love me when I'm gutshot and bleeding out in the gutters of Paris... Source" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/les-mis-eponin-marius.jpg?w=360&#038;h=240" width="360" height="240" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Oh, Eddie. You only love me when I&#8217;m gutshot and bleeding out in the gutters of Paris&#8230; <a href="http://static3.refinery29.com/bin/entry/3b5/x/992221/les-mis-eponin-marius.jpg" target="_blank">Source</a></p></div>
<p>8. <strong>Stu Redman. </strong>Why yes, I DO have a thing for the no-nonsense leader of the &#8220;good-guy&#8221; pack from <em><a title="The Stand by Stephen King… Or Katie vs. Taylor Swift" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/10/18/the-stand-by-stephen-king-or-katie-vs-taylor-swift/" target="_blank">The Stand</a>. </em>He is immune to the super flu, plus he&#8217;s got a cowboy vibe. I don&#8217;t know, maybe I was swayed by the fact that Lieutenant Dan played him in the mini series. The heart wants what the heart wants!</p>
<p>9. <strong>Roger MacKenzie.</strong> <em></em><em></em>Yeah. He&#8217;s from <em>Outlander </em>too. Roger is one dishy time traveler. Green eyed, Scottish accented, folk song crooning, tall drink of water. Mmmmhmmm.</p>
<p>10. <em></em><strong>Jim.</strong> Yes, I am cheating and making my husband into a fictional character. Public display of affection, blog style. Oh. Fictional Jim may or may not also be Batman. Or just own tasteful Batman statues. XOXO.</p>
<p>Bookworms, tell me. Who are your bookish fictional character crushes? We&#8217;re equal opportunity here. Dudes, ladies, whatever floats your boat. Share the lurve!</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1683/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1683/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1683&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/04/02/ive-got-a-crush-on-you-and-you-and-you-and-you-too/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>80</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d13100a03f9d0fc63e2c99c0ba2c7f2?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wordsforworms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_3818.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">First photo of us as a couple, a mere 10 days after that first date. Which reminds me... Happy Almost Anniversary to Meresa and Scott! (Yeah. He went to a wedding with me after a week and a half. Keeper.)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/ttt3w.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">TTT3W</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jonsnow.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Celibacy on The Wall? What a waste! Source.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/les-mis-eponin-marius.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Oh, Eddie. You only love me when I&#039;m gutshot and bleeding out in the gutters of Paris... Source</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sorry, No Blog Today. April Fools! (The Shoemaker&#8217;s Wife by Adriana Trigiani)</title>
		<link>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/04/01/the-shoemakers-wife-by-adriana-trigiani/</link>
		<comments>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/04/01/the-shoemakers-wife-by-adriana-trigiani/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Words for Worms</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ellis Island]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italian Alps]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wordsforworms.com/?p=1675</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Howdy Bookworms, I hope those of you who celebrate Easter have recovered from your chocolate bunny and jelly bean comas on this fine morning. It&#8217;s April Fool&#8217;s Day, but I&#8217;m not a fan of the holiday. I am a terrible liar, and I&#8217;m also embarrassingly gullible. Not a good combination. Plus, pranks have a way [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1675&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Howdy Bookworms,</p>
<p>I hope those of you who celebrate Easter have recovered from your chocolate bunny and jelly bean comas on this fine morning. It&#8217;s April Fool&#8217;s Day, but I&#8217;m not a fan of the holiday. I am a terrible liar, and I&#8217;m also embarrassingly gullible. Not a good combination. Plus, pranks have a way of turning mean, and I&#8217;m not a fan of meanness either. So. Let&#8217;s talk about&#8230; A book! (I know, you&#8217;re shocked!)</p>
<p>This month for Wine and Whining Book Club (I consistently get crap from the book club&#8217;s membership for what I&#8217;ve named it, but I like homonyms and alliterations, so I shan&#8217;t be changing it) we selected <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Shoemakers-Wife-Novel-Adriana-Trigiani/dp/0061257109" target="_blank">The Shoemaker&#8217;s Wife</a> </em>by Adriana Trigiani. <em>The Shoemaker&#8217;s Wife </em>is the tale of an unlikely couple re-united from their small Italian mountain town in New York City.</p>
<div id="attachment_1677" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 229px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/theshoemakers-wife.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1677 " alt="I'm really not sure who the broad on the cover is..." src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/theshoemakers-wife.jpg?w=219&#038;h=333" width="219" height="333" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I&#8217;m really not sure who the broad on the cover is&#8230;</p></div>
<p>Circumstances conspire to send the (for all intents and purposes) orphaned Ciro away from his home in a convent the Italian Alps to become an apprentice shoemaker in America. Unfortunately, his exit from town is untimely as he is separated from his new found lady love, Enza. Shortly after Ciro&#8217;s departure, Enza and her family fall on hard times and she and her father make the decision to emigrate to America as well. Their emigration takes place during the early 1910s, so their journey reads like the quintessential Ellis Island tale.</p>
<p>Ciro and Enza&#8217;s path to finding each other again is not an easy one. They both have their share of adventures. Enza is a talented seamstress but stuck in Hoboken in a Cinderella-esque situation. Ciro is distracted by a high maintenance local beauty and turns out to be a kick ass boot maker. Their trials and tribulations give you a great picture of the times in which they live, and they talk enough about pasta to make you hungry.</p>
<p>Spoilers are the bane of my existence, because it&#8217;s so difficult to talk about books without giving EVERYTHING away. I will say this much&#8230; While I enjoyed this book overall, there was a critical scene that reminded me a LOT of a scene in another one of Trigiani&#8217;s books, <em><a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60057.Lucia_Lucia" target="_blank">Lucia, Lucia</a>. </em>Consider this your SPOILER ALERT. Now. The goings on of <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0460649/" target="_blank"><em>How I Met Your Mother </em></a>aside, people being ditched at the altar is NOT a common thing. Things rarely get to the point of tuxedos and gowns being donned when weddings fall apart. The fact that this occurred in both of the Trigiani books disappoints me, I mean, calling off a wedding a couple months ahead of time is infinitely more realistic. It&#8217;s certainly more dramatic to pull the jilted at the altar routine, but it&#8217;s almost too easy&#8230; That&#8217;s probably an unfair assessment, but I&#8217;m a giant snob-a-saurus rex.</p>
<p>Safe to read again. If this is your first Trigiani novel, and you like historical fiction, you&#8217;ll love it! So, Bookworms, are you ever frustrated by authors recycling story lines? Getting repetitive? Anybody else run into that?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1675/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1675/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1675&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/04/01/the-shoemakers-wife-by-adriana-trigiani/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d13100a03f9d0fc63e2c99c0ba2c7f2?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wordsforworms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/theshoemakers-wife.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I&#039;m really not sure who the broad on the cover is...</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here Comes The Bride (Through an Archway of Machetes)</title>
		<link>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/30/here-comes-the-bride-through-an-arch-of-machetes/</link>
		<comments>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/30/here-comes-the-bride-through-an-arch-of-machetes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Words for Worms</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fairy Tales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Psychological]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flower Girl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machete]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Psychobabble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shirless Ryan Gosling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wedding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zombie Apocalypse]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wordsforworms.com/?p=1667</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dearly Beloved, We are gathered here today so I can make my case for being the Florist/Flower Girl for the online wedding of Lyssa of Psychobabble and Shirtless Ryan Gosling. I used to work in a flower shop, and while they only let me wash buckets and answer phones, I&#8217;m TOTALLY QUALIFIED to be an [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1667&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dearly Beloved,</p>
<p>We are gathered here today so I can make my case for being the Florist/Flower Girl for the online wedding of <a href="http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/youre-invited-to-an-online-wedding/" target="_blank">Lyssa of Psychobabble and Shirtless Ryan Gosling</a>. I used to work in a flower shop, and while they only let me wash buckets and answer phones, I&#8217;m TOTALLY QUALIFIED to be an online wedding florist.</p>
<p>People always assume that all little girls get the opportunity to be a flower girl at some point in their lives. I&#8217;m here to tell you that THEY ARE WRONG. I was never a flower girl. It&#8217;s a travesty. Feast your eyes on 5-year-old me:</p>
<div id="attachment_1633" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 204px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6728-e1363916693322.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1633   " alt="I was effing ADORABLE!" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6728-e1363916693322.jpg?w=194&#038;h=260" width="194" height="260" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I was effing ADORABLE!</p></div>
<p>Obviously I&#8217;m not over this slight. I need this for my mental health and well being, damnit! Let&#8217;s begin. Lyssa and Ryan have chosen to have a jungle theme for their botanical elements. This is incredibly lucky, because what I really want to portray in this wedding is RAMPANT FECUNDITY. When couples marry, they are encouraged by society to, in the immortal words of Ross from <em>Friends, </em>&#8220;consummate like bunnies.&#8221; With this in mind, I have chosen antherium for Lyssa&#8217;s bouquet with an orchid boutonierre for Ryan.</p>
<div id="attachment_1668" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 169px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/antherium-bouq.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1668 " alt="Antherium are exceptionally phallic." src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/antherium-bouq.jpg?w=159&#038;h=252" width="159" height="252" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Antherium are exceptionally phallic. Oh, yes, <a href="http://notthehardestpart.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">Emily? Maid of Honor</a>? You&#8217;ll be required to fan Lyssa with the bouquet once she passes it off to you.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1669" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 269px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/orchid.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1669 " alt="And. Well. Orchids are pretty darn suggestive. " src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/orchid.jpg?w=259&#038;h=173" width="259" height="173" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">And. Well. Orchids are pretty darn suggestive.</p></div>
<p>In addition to the pornographic florals, I&#8217;ve decided to create an extra feature that will not only compliment the theme, but also protect the wedding party from Zombie attack. That&#8217;s right. The perimeter of the venue will be surrounded by tiger pits! I will have trenches dug, much in the way one would dig a moat. However, a moat would be USELESS because Zombies DON&#8217;T BREATHE and are therefore impervious to water barriers. The pits will be filled with bamboo spikes! Bamboo is the epitome of jungle-ness, and it&#8217;s also really sharp. Those spears will impale any marauding herds of the undead while allowing the guests to party unscathed. (There will be retractable walkways so no guests are accidentally impaled&#8230; Unless you get REALLY mad at your drunk uncle&#8230;)</p>
<p>Instead of tossing rice or blowing bubbles for Lyssa and Ryan&#8217;s grand exit, the guests will instead line up and create an archway for the couple to walk through with their party favors. You guessed it! The party favors are MACHETES! A necessity in both the jungle and the Zombie Apocalypse. I can guarantee there&#8217;s not a mason jar project on Pinterest that can compete with a freaking machete.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not JUST the florist, remember? I&#8217;m also the flower girl, because the universe conspired against me and WASTED my childhood cuteness on ballet lessons. Ugh. Anyway. I&#8217;ve chosen the most SPECTACULAR dress, that fits the jungle theme perfectly:</p>
<div id="attachment_1670" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 193px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/katieflowergirl.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1670 " alt="The word you're looking for is &quot;glorious.&quot;" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/katieflowergirl.jpg?w=660"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The word you&#8217;re looking for is &#8220;glorious.&#8221; You&#8217;re also REALLY impressed with my sexy photoshop skills.</p></div>
<p>I implore you, dear readers, please leave a comment to let Lyssa know that I&#8217;m the right choice for all her flower needs! I&#8217;m a whirling dervish of flowers, tulle, and general bad-assery. Help me achieve my dreams!</p>
<div id="attachment_1671" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 386px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/lyssapants.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1671 " alt="This needs to happen. NEEDS TO!" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/lyssapants.jpg?w=376&#038;h=359" width="376" height="359" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This needs to happen. NEEDS TO!</p></div>
<p>Now, Shirtless Ryan Gosling, you may kiss the Flower Girl. Wait, I mean&#8230; No. I meant that. I really did.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1667/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1667/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1667&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/30/here-comes-the-bride-through-an-arch-of-machetes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d13100a03f9d0fc63e2c99c0ba2c7f2?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wordsforworms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6728-e1363916693322.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I was effing ADORABLE!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/antherium-bouq.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Antherium are exceptionally phallic.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/orchid.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">And. Well. Orchids are pretty darn suggestive. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/katieflowergirl.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The word you&#039;re looking for is &#34;glorious.&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/lyssapants.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">This needs to happen. NEEDS TO!</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>So Far? 30 Is AWESOME!</title>
		<link>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/29/so-far-30-is-awesome/</link>
		<comments>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/29/so-far-30-is-awesome/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Words for Worms</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freshly Pressed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[giveaway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penguin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turning 30]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wordsforworms.com/?p=1660</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Welcome Bookworms, Old and New! Remember last week how I was freaking out about turning 30? So far, 30 has been kind of awesome. But. First things first. We have a WINNER of the $30 Amazon gift card. Thanks to EVERYONE for your tweets and likes and whatnot. I tallied up the entries and plugged [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1660&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome Bookworms, Old and New!</p>
<p>Remember last week how I was <a title="My Birthday, Your Presents" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/22/1632/" target="_blank">freaking out about turning 30</a>? So far, 30 has been kind of awesome. But. First things first. We have a WINNER of the $30 Amazon gift card. Thanks to EVERYONE for your tweets and likes and whatnot. I tallied up the entries and plugged them into a random number generator. The WINNER is&#8230; Jen Hartling! Jen is not only a dedicated bookworm, she also writes her own CERTIFIED AWESOME book blog, The <a href="http://therelentlessreader.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">Relentless Reader</a>. May the odds be <em>ever </em>in your favor!</p>
<p>Why is 30 rocking my world? LET ME TELL YOU! I took my birthday off of work and my husband took me to the Shedd Aquarium in Chicago. He earned himself INFINITY brownie points by taking me to MEET A PENGUIN. Not only did he set me up with a penguin encounter (which is a thing they offer&#8230; Click <a href="http://www.sheddaquarium.org/premium_experiences.html" target="_blank">HERE</a> if you&#8217;re interested) but he arranged it so that we were the only two people in the penguin encounter. They&#8217;re typically done in groups of ten, but Jim in all his weasel-y wisdom managed to get us a private meet and greet with penguin #413. (I am certain he spent too much money doing this, but I had THE BEST TIME so I can&#8217;t be upset.)</p>
<div id="attachment_1661" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 327px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0201.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1661  " alt="Can you tell I was REALLY excited?! " src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0201.jpg?w=317&#038;h=236" width="317" height="236" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Can you tell I was REALLY excited?!</p></div>
<p>The penguins at the Shedd are identified by number, they don&#8217;t have individual names (I KNOW!) In my head, Penguin #413 was Josie. Josie was super friendly and curious. She pooped twice, she pecked at my jeans, and she stepped on my galoshes several times. Sometimes she would take a deep breath and puff herself up like a penguin balloon. The trainer claimed Josie was re-setting her feathers, but I think she was just showing off her deep breathing abilities. Also, did you know penguins can sneeze? Yeah. They totally can. She has little nostril thingies on her beak that get clogged with salt from the water and the fishes, so she &#8220;sneezes&#8221; to clear them. AND! They don&#8217;t even have to monitor what they feed the penguins. Josie and her Magellenic counterparts are perfect self regulators. They fatten up temporarily during molting season, but that&#8217;s it. When the trainer offered her fish she didn&#8217;t want, she just shook her little head. Amazing.</p>
<div id="attachment_1662" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 327px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_9718.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1662  " alt="I got to pet Josie!!!!" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_9718.jpg?w=317&#038;h=236" width="317" height="236" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I got to pet Josie!!!!</p></div>
<p>I got to pet Josie on her back (which felt a lot like beagle fur- soft yet oily) AND her flipper (which felt very rubbery.) Jim got to pet Josie on the foot (which was speckled and thus impossibly adorable) and the belly.</p>
<div id="attachment_1663" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 327px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_2329.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1663  " alt="So fun!!!" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_2329.jpg?w=317&#038;h=236" width="317" height="236" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">So fun!!!</p></div>
<p>Yeah, so my decade is really starting on an upswing. But that isn&#8217;t all. I was FRESHLY PRESSED this week. It&#8217;s an enormous honor and I can hardly believe the powers that be at WordPress noticed my little corner of weird, but I&#8217;m beyond thrilled by it. THRILLED, I tell you! I think 30 and I are going to get along just fine. (As long as I keep getting carded at the liquor store.)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1660/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1660/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1660&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/29/so-far-30-is-awesome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d13100a03f9d0fc63e2c99c0ba2c7f2?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wordsforworms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0201.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Can you tell I was REALLY excited?! </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_9718.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I got to pet Josie!!!!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_2329.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">So fun!!!</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>And Now I Want To Ride A Bear: Odd and the Frost Giants by Neil Gaiman</title>
		<link>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/28/and-now-i-want-to-ride-a-bear-odd-and-the-frost-giants-by-neil-gaiman/</link>
		<comments>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/28/and-now-i-want-to-ride-a-bear-odd-and-the-frost-giants-by-neil-gaiman/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Words for Worms</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wordsforworms.com/?p=1655</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Splendid Thursday, Bookworms. Remember back when I read American Gods and I was all &#8220;I need more Neil Gaiman in my life?&#8221; Well. I made good on my promise to myself. During a Kindle sale I noticed another Gaiman title and snapped it up at a bargain price. This novel? Odd and the Frost Giants. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1655&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Splendid Thursday, Bookworms.</p>
<p>Remember back when I read <a title="Mythology vs. Technology: American Gods by Neil Gaiman" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/10/16/mythology-vs-technology-american-gods-by-neil-gaiman/" target="_blank"><em>American Gods</em></a> and I was all &#8220;I need more Neil Gaiman in my life?&#8221; Well. I made good on my promise to myself. During a Kindle sale I noticed another Gaiman title and snapped it up at a bargain price. This novel? <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Odd-Frost-Giants-Neil-Gaiman/dp/0061671738" target="_blank">Odd and the Frost Giants</a>. </em>Neil Gaiman writes for a variety of age groups. Me being me, I paid absolutely no attention to whether or not this was an adult book or a children&#8217;s book. Luckily, Gaiman&#8217;s whimsy is so delightful it really doesn&#8217;t matter.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/odd-and-the-frost-giants.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1597" alt="odd-and-the-frost-giants" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/odd-and-the-frost-giants.jpg?w=222&#038;h=363" width="222" height="363" /></a></p>
<p><em>Odd and the Frost Giants </em>centers on a young Viking boy named Odd. Odd is aptly named (although in Viking lore the name is meant to be lucky) because he&#8217;s the &#8220;odd&#8221; man out. His father died and his mother remarried a major tool. Also, Odd managed to chop a tree down which landed on his leg and thus needs to use a crutch to get around. I really can&#8217;t discuss this book much further without getting spoiler-happy. It&#8217;s really short, y&#8217;all. So. If you want to avoid spoilers, you can stop reading now.</p>
<p>Is it safe? Good. Okay. So. Odd has had quite enough of his crappy stepfather&#8217;s antics and decides to run away. He makes it out to his old hut (because they&#8217;re Vikings and they live in huts surrounding the Mead Hall, yo) only to meet up with a weird trio of animals. A bear, a fox, and an eagle follow him home. Odd lets them in, gives them some salmon, and goes to sleep. (I guess Odd figured if the bear had just eaten he wouldn&#8217;t be interested in devouring him? I realize I shouldn&#8217;t question the judgement of children&#8217;s characters, but really, Odd. What would your mother say?)</p>
<p>As it turns out, the animals aren&#8217;t REALLY animals. They&#8217;re Odin, Thor, and Loki who are trapped in animal form. Which explains why the bear didn&#8217;t eat him. They figure all of this out and Odd decides to join them on their quest to get back into their normal bodies.</p>
<div id="attachment_603" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 236px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/odin-viking-gods.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-603   " alt="How is Odin supposed to get his swagger on when he's stuck in the body of a bird, for heaven's sake?" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/odin-viking-gods.jpg?w=226&#038;h=343" width="226" height="343" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">How is Odin supposed to get his swagger on when he&#8217;s stuck in the body of a bird, for heaven&#8217;s sake?</p></div>
<p>Oh yeah. And because of Odd&#8217;s busted leg slowing down the trio, Thor (who is stuck in the form of a bear) totally lets him ride on his back. I wonder if God-Bears are stinky. Would immortality keep you from smelling like a gross bear? Let&#8217;s say that this is the case. Because I would totally ride a bear, if it smelled decent. Who am I kidding? I&#8217;d ride a stinky bear too. I&#8217;d get a fancy bear saddle and a Viking helmet. Glorious. (I realize this paragraph is probably going to lead to me getting a LOT of hits from people looking for animal porn. Sigh.)</p>
<p>This book was totally entertaining. Norse mythology and all that. It&#8217;s for kids, so maybe it&#8217;d make for a good chapter book bedtime story for those of you with youngins at home? A nice change of pace from <em>Captain Underpants</em> or what-have-you. So, Bookworms. The question I pose to you is this: if you could ride any wild animal, what would you choose, and why? Bonus points for creativity and stench reduction implements.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1655/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1655/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1655&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/28/and-now-i-want-to-ride-a-bear-odd-and-the-frost-giants-by-neil-gaiman/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d13100a03f9d0fc63e2c99c0ba2c7f2?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wordsforworms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/odd-and-the-frost-giants.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">odd-and-the-frost-giants</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/odin-viking-gods.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">How is Odin supposed to get his swagger on when he&#039;s stuck in the body of a bird, for heaven&#039;s sake?</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top Ten Tuesday: Most Recommended Books</title>
		<link>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/26/top-ten-tuesday-most-recommended-books/</link>
		<comments>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/26/top-ten-tuesday-most-recommended-books/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 13:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Words for Worms</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Frightening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tear Jerkers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Ten Tuesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books I Recommend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top ten tuesday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wordsforworms.com/?p=1648</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Greetings, Bookworms! It&#8217;s Tuesday, and you know what THAT means. No, no, it is not time for tacos. (But dangit, now I want tacos!) It&#8217;s time for Top Ten Tuesday with The Broke and The Bookish! Today they&#8217;ve asked me to list out the ten books I recommend most often. So. Without further ado&#8230; 1. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1648&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Greetings, Bookworms!</p>
<p>It&#8217;s Tuesday, and you know what THAT means. No, no, it is not time for tacos. (But dangit, now I want tacos!) It&#8217;s time for Top Ten Tuesday with <a href="http://brokeandbookish.blogspot.com/p/top-ten-tuesday-other-features.html" target="_blank">The Broke and The Bookish</a>! Today they&#8217;ve asked me to list out the ten books I recommend most often. So. Without further ado&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/toptentuesday.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-898" alt="toptentuesday" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/toptentuesday.jpg?w=660"   /></a></p>
<p>1. <a href="http://www.dianagabaldon.com/books/outlander-series/" target="_blank"><em>Outlander </em></a>by Diana Gabaldon. I have foisted this series upon countless friends. I love to recommend it because it&#8217;s got a little bit of something for everyone. It&#8217;s one of those rare finds where I&#8217;m confident most of my pals will enjoy it. There are few things as awkward as giving someone a book and hearing they hated it, you know? <em>Outlander </em>has a little sci fi, some historical fiction, a touch of steamy romance novel, and, well, Jamie Fraser. (Siiiigh)</p>
<p>2. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Harry-Potter-Paperback-Box-Books/dp/0545162076" target="_blank"><em>Harry Potter </em></a>by JK Rowling. This is kind of a throwaway answer because it&#8217;s not like it&#8217;s possible for someone to have never heard of Harry Potter. However. Anyone who seems skeptical about the series? I implore them to read it. Like&#8230; I&#8217;m sincerely concerned about people who don&#8217;t enjoy HP. How can you not like MAGIC and WHIMSY and AWESOMENESS?!</p>
<div id="attachment_1233" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 200px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_8219.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1233   " alt="My patronus is a penguin. Demetors don't stand a CHANCE against the impossible cutness... And pecking." src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_8219.jpg?w=190&#038;h=254" width="190" height="254" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My patronus is a penguin. Demetors don&#8217;t stand a CHANCE against the impossible cutness&#8230; And pecking.</p></div>
<p>3. <a title="Books That Scare Me: The Handmaid’s Tale by Margaret Atwood" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/10/31/books-that-scare-me-the-handmaids-tale-by-margaret-atwood/" target="_blank"><em>The Handmaid&#8217;s Tale </em></a>by Margaret Atwood. This book is amazing and I think everyone should read it. Everyone. I&#8217;ve loaned out my copy on multiple occasions. It&#8217;s a cautionary tale for the ages, my friends.</p>
<p>4. <em><a title="Pope Joan: More Than Myth?" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/08/29/pope-joan-more-than-myth/" target="_blank">Pope Joan </a></em>by Diana Woolfolk Cross. Some of the best historical fiction I&#8217;ve ever read. It&#8217;s about an accidental lady Pope. Timely, what with a new Pope being elected and all.</p>
<p>5. <a title="Do You Hear The People Sing? (Give Them ALL THE OSCARS!)" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/12/30/do-you-hear-the-people-sing-give-them-all-the-oscars/" target="_blank"><em>Les Miserables </em></a>by Victor Hugo. Occasionally, people will ask me for recommendations on classics I really enjoyed. I won&#8217;t lie, it&#8217;s a long ass book, but it&#8217;s totally worth the read. If you&#8217;re familiar with the musical already, it gives you a great back story on Fantine, which is fabulous. Oh and did you know that Gavroche and Eponine are siblings? I know. I. KNOW! Crazy right? You need to read this.</p>
<div id="attachment_1084" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 151px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/les-miserables-176x300.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1084" alt="les-miserables-176x300" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/les-miserables-176x300.jpg?w=141&#038;h=240" width="141" height="240" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Cosette is still little more than a plot catalyst, though.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">6. <em><a title="The Book Thief by Markus Zusak: A Good Read, A Dignified Cry" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/11/26/the-book-thief-by-markus-zusak-a-good-read-a-dignified-cry/" target="_blank">The Book Thief</a> </em>by Markus Zusak. I try to get people to read this all the time. It&#8217;s another one of those that I&#8217;ve found is almost universally appealing. This one, of course, requires you to have an entire box of tissues on hand as you engage in the catharsis of bawling your eyes out. Worth it.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">7. <a title="Song of Achilles: Yes, There’s a Centaur!" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/11/28/song-of-achilles-yes-theres-a-centaur/" target="_blank"><em>Song of Achilles </em></a>by Madeline Miller. This book tells the most incredible love story. Miller did such a great job of drawing her characters&#8217; personalities that you get completely engrossed in their love story. You follow Achilles and Patroclus from childhood and watch their relationship grow and mature. Just beautiful. And yeah. It&#8217;s about two dudes. Which is a nice change of pace from what I normally read, you know? (You probably need tissues for this one too.)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">8. <a title="My BFF and The Pillars of the Earth by Ken Follett" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/11/15/the-pillars-of-the-earth/" target="_blank"><em>Pillars of the Earth </em></a>by Ken Follett. It&#8217;s just really well drawn historical fiction. I love it to pieces. It&#8217;s another chunkster, but it moves fast. Don&#8217;t be intimidated by its length, you&#8217;ll enjoy yourself! (And then you&#8217;ll be really grateful that you have indoor plumbing and floors that aren&#8217;t dirt and stuff, because the Middle Ages were DIRTY, y&#8217;all.)</p>
<div id="attachment_1650" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 370px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/eddie-in-pillars.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1650 " alt="Starz did a mini series based on the book. Eddie Redmayne played Jack. You're welcome. (Image from Oprah.com)" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/eddie-in-pillars.jpg?w=360&#038;h=247" width="360" height="247" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Starz did a mini series based on the book. Eddie Redmayne played Jack. You&#8217;re welcome. (Image from <a href="http://www.oprah.com/entertainment/The-Pillars-of-the-Earth-Cast-and-Character-Guide/4" target="_blank">Oprah.com</a>)</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">9. <a title="Gone with the Wind" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/09/26/gone-with-the-wind/" target="_blank"><em>Gone With The Wind </em></a>by Margaret Mitchell. No, having seen the movie is NOT the same thing. Not at all. It leaves out Scarlett&#8217;s first two children, for heaven&#8217;s sake! (That&#8217;s really not a spoiler, they aren&#8217;t major plot points, and the fact that they aren&#8217;t makes Scarlett all the more Scarlett-y.)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">10. <a title="Zombie Apocalypse" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/08/27/zombie-apocalypse/" target="_blank"><em>World War Z</em></a> by Max Brooks. I don&#8217;t read a whole lot of zombie literature, but I thought this book rocked in a big way. I&#8217;m a huge fan of <em>The Walking Dead </em>(TV series, I haven&#8217;t read the comics) so the zombie lore intrigues me. I thought this book gave an awesome and realistic account of how a zombie apocalypse might go down. You&#8217;ll probably have nightmares. Fair warning.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">There we are- ten books I recommend to people on the regular. What are some of your favorite titles to pass around?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1648/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1648/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1648&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/26/top-ten-tuesday-most-recommended-books/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>71</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d13100a03f9d0fc63e2c99c0ba2c7f2?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wordsforworms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/toptentuesday.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">toptentuesday</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_8219.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">My patronus is a penguin. Demetors don&#039;t stand a CHANCE against the impossible cutness... And pecking.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/les-miserables-176x300.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">les-miserables-176x300</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/eddie-in-pillars.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Starz did a mini series based on the book. Eddie Redmayne played Jack. You&#039;re welcome. (Image from Oprah.com)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Road Tripping with Swamplandia!</title>
		<link>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/25/road-tripping-with-swamplandia/</link>
		<comments>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/25/road-tripping-with-swamplandia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Words for Worms</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Audio Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audio books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karen Russell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Alligator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swamplandia!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Terrible Fine Motor Skills]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wordsforworms.com/?p=1637</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello my Beautiful Bookworms! Thank you ALL for the fabulous birthday wishes and making me want to eat ALL THE CAKE. You&#8217;ve still got a few days to enter the giveaway, so be sure to enter for $30 Amazon bucks- international entries welcome! Also, I&#8217;ve guest posted today on my friend Chrissy&#8217;s site. If you&#8217;re [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1637&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello my Beautiful Bookworms!</p>
<p>Thank you ALL for the fabulous birthday wishes and making me want to eat ALL THE CAKE. You&#8217;ve still got a few days to enter the giveaway, so be sure to enter for $30 Amazon bucks- international entries welcome! Also, I&#8217;ve guest posted today on my friend <a href="http://www.quirkychrissy.com/" target="_blank">Chrissy&#8217;s site</a>. If you&#8217;re so inclined, I encourage you to check it out.</p>
<p>Last weekend, I took a trip to attend my <a title="Beware the Ides of March: A Letter to My “Nephew” on his Fifth Birthday" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/15/beware-the-ides-of-march-a-letter-to-my-nephew-on-his-fifth-birthday/" target="_blank">&#8220;nephew&#8217;s&#8221; birthday party</a>. When I take a long drive, I like to listen to books on tape. They keep me alert better than listening to music, plus, I mean, BOOKS. I took this trip with a book I&#8217;ve been meaning to read for a while, Karen Russell&#8217;s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Swamplandia-Vintage-Contemporaries-Karen-Russell/dp/0307276686" target="_blank"><em>Swamplandia! </em></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/swamplandia.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1639" alt="swamplandia" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/swamplandia.jpeg?w=277&#038;h=277" width="277" height="277" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Are you aware that Florida boasts the most oddball theme parks per capita in the world? I may have made up that statistic, but I think I could be right. <em>Swamplandia! </em>is the account of a fictional family owned theme park on an island off the coast of Florida, known as (appropriately) Swamplandia. The Bigtree family is a &#8220;tribe&#8221; of alligator wrestlers. They renamed themselves &#8220;Bigtree&#8221; to sound more native, but their clan originated in Ohio. As PT Barnum would tell you, there&#8217;s a sucker born every minute. People believe what they want to believe, so if they prefer to think of alligator wrestlers as endowed with magical Native American gator charming talents, the Bigtrees are happy to oblige their delusions.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The family alligator wrestling matches are only one of the attractions. The main event is watching the family matriarch, Hilola Bigtree, dive into the gator pit and swim through unscathed. It&#8217;s a fantastic spectacle and crowd favorite. The gators are all referred to as &#8220;Seth,&#8221; I&#8217;m assuming, because &#8220;Sawtooth&#8221; was already taken. (No, they never really explained why they chose Seth. But yes, Grandpa was named Sawtooth.) Sadly, as we learn about Swamplandia&#8217;s glory days, we also learn of its demise.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Hilola Bigtree, headliner and matriarch, falls victim to cancer. Grandpa Sawtooth falls victim to Alzheimer&#8217;s. Chief Bigtree falls victim to his pride. Young Osceola falls victim to obsession. Kiwi falls victim to his limited home-school education. Ava, our 14 year old protagonist, falls victim to everyone else&#8217;s bad decisions.</p>
<div id="attachment_1642" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 279px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/redseth.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1642  " alt="Image courtesy of genius book blogger and generous soul Andi of Estella's Revenge." src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/redseth.jpg?w=269&#038;h=200" width="269" height="200" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image courtesy of genius book blogger and generous soul Andi of <a href="http://estellasrevenge.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">Estella&#8217;s Revenge</a>.</p></div>
<p>So. What did I think? I&#8217;ve got mixed feelings on this novel. On the one hand, I LOVED the language. The writing was gorgeous, and the actors reading the audio book were fantastic. That said, I think sometimes the story fell by the wayside so the language could shine. Some people wouldn&#8217;t be bothered by this, but as you know, I&#8217;m a story girl. I felt parts of the novel were more drawn out than necessary (particularly Louis Thanksgiving&#8217;s extremely detailed back story&#8230;) On the upside, I now have a fantastically vivid mental image of Florida&#8217;s swamplands. Overall, the prose reminded me of Gabriel Garcia Marquez&#8217;s magical realism, only set in North America. With alligators and stuff. Also a theme park based on Hell. Complete with saltwater drinking fountains. (Kudos for imagination!)</p>
<p>For reasons I will not disclose to you, as they might be considered &#8220;spoilers,&#8221; a red gator makes an appearance in this novel. I really wanted to know if such a thing existed in nature. As it turns out, they&#8217;re not really a thing. Which means, of course, that there aren&#8217;t a whole lot of readily available images (unless you happen to email a cool blogger like Andi and she lets you borrow her stuff.) I actually thought it might be a good idea to try and make my own art! I convinced <a href="http://www.filing-jointly.com/" target="_blank">Lauren of Filing Jointly</a>&#8230;Finally to help me with the project and&#8230; well&#8230; This happened:</p>
<div id="attachment_1645" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 287px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_5146.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1645   " alt="I drew a really horrible alligator." src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_5146.jpg?w=277&#038;h=207" width="277" height="207" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I drew a really horrible alligator and embellished it with a voice bubble for extreme fierceness.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1646" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 287px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1646  " alt="And then Lauren drew an alligator who thinks he's a stegosaurus." src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo.jpg?w=277&#038;h=207" width="277" height="207" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">And then Lauren drew an alligator who thinks he&#8217;s a stegosaurus. (Which, in spite of its dino-ness is infinitely better executed than my doodle&#8230;)</p></div>
<p>And now we know why Katie and Lauren don&#8217;t have promising futures in the lucrative world of alligator caricatures. Luckily, there&#8217;s not much of a market for that sort of thing in Illinois. It&#8217;s really the deer and skunk caricature niche that&#8217;s our bread and butter, so. You know. It&#8217;s cool.</p>
<p>Have any of you read <em>Swamplandia!? </em>What did you think? Did it spur you to do anything unusual, say, sketch a species-confused alligator? Tell me about it!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1637/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1637/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1637&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/25/road-tripping-with-swamplandia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d13100a03f9d0fc63e2c99c0ba2c7f2?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wordsforworms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/swamplandia.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">swamplandia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/redseth.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image courtesy of genius book blogger and generous soul Andi of Estella&#039;s Revenge.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_5146.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I drew a really horrible alligator.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">And then Lauren drew an alligator who thinks he&#039;s a stegosaurus.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Birthday, Your Presents</title>
		<link>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/22/1632/</link>
		<comments>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/22/1632/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 13:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Words for Worms</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[giveaway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turning 30]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wordsforworms.com/?p=1632</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hey There Bookworms, Today I turn 30 years old. I say &#8220;today&#8221; even though technically I&#8217;m writing this in the evening on March 21st. By the time this posts, I will already be 30. Though I made my entrance into this world at 4:02 am, I don&#8217;t make it a habit to either a. get [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1632&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey There Bookworms,</p>
<p>Today I turn 30 years old. I say &#8220;today&#8221; even though technically I&#8217;m writing this in the evening on March 21st. By the time this posts, I will already be 30. Though I made my entrance into this world at 4:02 am, I don&#8217;t make it a habit to either a. get up that early or b. stay up that late. So. I&#8217;m 30. More or less.</p>
<p>How do I feel about this? Not great. I really didn&#8217;t think turning 30 would be a big deal to me, but I&#8217;m kind of freaking out. I STILL don&#8217;t know what I want to be when I grow up. As you can see, my initial career ambition didn&#8217;t exactly work out&#8230;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6728-e1363916693322.jpg"><img class="wp-image-1633 aligncenter" alt="" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6728-e1363916693322.jpg?w=238&#038;h=318" width="238" height="318" /></a></p>
<p>But you know. Life happens. Thighs happen. You improvise. So. I am 30. And I have a choice. I can continue to wallow and mourn my lost youth, OR I can CELEBRATE! Guess who&#8217;s celebrating and looked freaking adorable in a tutu at 5? THIS GIRL!</p>
<div id="attachment_1456" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 269px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/birthday-cake-clip-art-4.png"><img class=" wp-image-1456   " alt="There will be cake. Oh yes, there will be cake." src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/birthday-cake-clip-art-4.png?w=259&#038;h=254" width="259" height="254" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">There will be cake. Oh yes, there will be cake.</p></div>
<p>I may not be able to send cake to each and every one of you GORGEOUS bookworms, but I can sponsor a giveaway. This giveaway is open to EVERYONE (except people from North Dakota. Just kidding. I love you, North Dakota.) I am giving away an Amazon gift card in the amount of&#8230; THIRTY DOLLARS! (Because I&#8217;m 30, see?) Anyway, since it&#8217;s an Amazon gift card, anybody with an email address is eligible to win. International entries are totally welcome (just like I promised, Rhian. Tell your Aussie pals.)</p>
<p>You can enter by:</p>
<p>1. Leaving a comment on this blog telling me what your favorite kind of cake is (anyone who says they don&#8217;t like cake is disqualified. Lie to me y&#8217;all. It&#8217;s my birthday!)</p>
<p>2. &#8220;Like&#8221; my Facebook page: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/WordsForWorms" target="_blank">https://www.facebook.com/WordsForWorms</a></p>
<p>3. Follow me on Twitter: @KatieBelle1121</p>
<p>4. Share this blog post with your Facebook Friends</p>
<p>5. Tweet this post</p>
<p>That&#8217;s five potential entries! I&#8217;ll choose a winner one week from today. Wahoo 30!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1632/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1632/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1632&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/22/1632/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>84</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d13100a03f9d0fc63e2c99c0ba2c7f2?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wordsforworms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6728-e1363916693322.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/birthday-cake-clip-art-4.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">There will be cake. Oh yes, there will be cake.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top Ten Tuesday: The Shelf of Shame</title>
		<link>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/19/top-ten-tuesday-the-shelf-of-shame/</link>
		<comments>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/19/top-ten-tuesday-the-shelf-of-shame/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 13:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Words for Worms</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Classics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Ten Tuesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books I bought but haven't read]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top ten tuesday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wordsforworms.com/?p=1625</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Greetings, Bookworms! You know when you&#8217;re in a bookstore, browsing, and you get sucked in by picking up a title in the bargain bin? How about when you have grand intentions of bettering yourself and pick up a pile o&#8217; classics only to watch them collect dust on your shelves? We&#8217;ve all got the shelf [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1625&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Greetings, Bookworms!</p>
<p>You know when you&#8217;re in a bookstore, browsing, and you get sucked in by picking up a title in the bargain bin? How about when you have grand intentions of bettering yourself and pick up a pile o&#8217; classics only to watch them collect dust on your shelves? We&#8217;ve all got the shelf of shame. And the ladies at the <a href="http://brokeandbookish.blogspot.com/p/top-ten-tuesday-other-features.html" target="_blank">Broke and the Bookish</a>? They want us to own up to it. Today&#8217;s Top Ten Tuesday: Stuff I Bought But Never Read.</p>
<p><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/toptentuesday.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-898" alt="toptentuesday" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/toptentuesday.jpg?w=660"   /></a>1. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Madame-Bovary-ebook/dp/B0084A6XBS/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363655836&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=madame+bovary" target="_blank"><em>Madame Bovary</em></a> by Gustave Flaubert. Sometimes (okay, a lot of times) I get self important and think that I will be able to appreciate even the most highbrow of classics. That&#8217;s when I buy things like <em>Madame Bovary </em>and then watch them moulder on my shelves for an eternity. I mean, I SHOULD like this. A doctor&#8217;s wife has adulterous affairs? I mean, hello <a title="The Greatest Sleep Aids Disguised as Books" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/08/24/the-greatest-sleep-aids-disguised-as-books/" target="_blank"><em>Anna Karenina</em></a>. How&#8217;s it going, <a title="Banned Books Week: Lady Chatterley’s Lover by DH Lawrence" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/10/04/banned-books-week-lady-chatterlys-lover-by-dh-lawrence/" target="_blank"><em>Lady Chatterley</em></a>? Why did I never get down with <em>Madame Bovary</em>? No idea.</p>
<p>2. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Heart-of-Darkness-ebook/dp/B0084AMNWQ/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363655803&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=heart+of+darkness" target="_blank"><em>Heart of Darkness </em></a>by Joseph Conrad. This is always on smart people&#8217;s lists of favorite books. I&#8217;m highly susceptible to peer pressure whilst making decisions inside the Barnes and Noble&#8230; Amazon doesn&#8217;t judge me the way a hipster cashier would!</p>
<p>3. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Mayor-of-Casterbridge-ebook/dp/B0084AYLK8/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363655757&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=the+mayor+of+casterbridge" target="_blank"><em>The Mayor of Casterbridge </em></a>by Thomas Hardy. I bought this because <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Tess-of-the-dUrbervilles-ebook/dp/B0084B0CKA/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363655867&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=tess+of+the+d%27urbervilles+kindle+free" target="_blank"><em>Tess of the d&#8217;Urbervilles </em></a>was so fantastic. However&#8230; The lack of female main character and/or the really unappealing portrait of what I assume to be the &#8220;mayor&#8221; on the cover has kept me from actually bending the spine of this one.</p>
<p>4. <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Count-Cristo-Illustrated-Edition-ebook/dp/B007M5QT10/ref=sr_1_2?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363655965&amp;sr=1-2&amp;keywords=count+of+monte+cristo+kindle+free" target="_blank">The Count of Monte Cristo </a></em>by Alexandre Dumas. I really do want to read this&#8230; It&#8217;s just so THICK. I&#8217;m not easily intimidated by big books, but this sucker is the size of <a title="Do You Hear The People Sing? (Give Them ALL THE OSCARS!)" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/12/30/do-you-hear-the-people-sing-give-them-all-the-oscars/" target="_blank"><em>Les Miserables,</em></a> but lacks a magnificent soundtrack to play in my head&#8230; And no Gavroche.</p>
<div id="attachment_1626" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 472px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_3298.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1626" alt="IMG_3298" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_3298-e1363656351913.jpg?w=462&#038;h=344" width="462" height="344" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Classics&#8230; Of Shame.</p></div>
<p>5. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Secret-History-Pink-Carnation-ebook/dp/B000PC0SFK/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363656574&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=the+secret+history+of+the+pink+carnation" target="_blank"><em>The Secret History of the Pink Carnation</em></a> by Lauren Willig. It&#8217;s historical fiction with a pretty cover. I couldn&#8217;t be expected to resist the purchase, and yet&#8230; Still unread.</p>
<p>6. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Shakespeares-Wife-P-S-ebook/dp/B0013TPVII/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363656765&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=shakespeare%27s+wife" target="_blank"><em>Shakespeare&#8217;s Wife </em></a>by Germaine Greer. It&#8217;s historical fiction about, uh, Shakespeare&#8217;s wife. You know. Anne Hathaway. The one that didn&#8217;t win an Oscar. I found it in a bargain bin. I really loved the movie <em>Shakespeare in Love, </em>so perhaps I just don&#8217;t want to hear the sad tale of the wife who was left behind when the dashing Joseph Fiennes fell for a not-yet-openly-pretentious Gwyneth Paltrow. Siiigh.</p>
<p>7. <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Meaning-Night-Confession-ebook/dp/B0015VTPDG/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363657072&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=the+meaning+of+night" target="_blank">The Meaning of Night </a></em>by Michael Cox. I bought this because it&#8217;s historical fiction. I&#8217;ve been putting off reading it because it&#8217;s about a Victorian era murderer. I&#8217;m not big on crime novels, even historical ones. I frequently question my bargain bin judgement.</p>
<div id="attachment_1627" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 472px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7873.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1627 " alt="You can see the bargain stickers! " src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7873.jpg?w=462&#038;h=344" width="462" height="344" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">You can see the bargain stickers!</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">8. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Ladder-Years-A-Novel-ebook/dp/B003E8AIEI/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363657500&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=ladder+of+years" target="_blank"><em>Ladder of Years </em></a>by Anne Tyler. I bought this with <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Dinner-Homesick-Restaurant-Ballantine-ebook/dp/B004GTLKIW/ref=sr_1_2?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363657478&amp;sr=1-2&amp;keywords=dinner+at+the+homesick+restaurant+by+anne+tyler" target="_blank"><em>Dinner At The Homesick</em> <em>Restaurant </em></a>because I thought they sounded smart and fabulous. I read <em>Dinner At The Homesick Restaurant </em>and didn&#8217;t love it, so I didn&#8217;t bother with the other one on the shelf.</p>
<p>9. <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/A-Taxonomy-Barnacles-Novel/dp/0312426518/ref=sr_1_cc_1?s=aps&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363657557&amp;sr=1-1-catcorr&amp;keywords=a+taxonomy+of+barnacles" target="_blank">A Taxonomy of Barnacles </a></em>by Galt Niederhoffer. Yeah. I bought this solely for the AWESOME title. I didn&#8217;t even read the abstract. Maybe I should. Maybe I will. Who knows?</p>
<p>10. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/House-Sand-Fog-Andre-Dubus/dp/0393338118/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363657643&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=house+of+sand+and+fog" target="_blank"><em>House of Sand and Fog </em></a>by Andre Dubus III. There was an Oprah sticker, and I am not immune to the influence of The Oprah. I don&#8217;t know why I haven&#8217;t read it. STOP JUDGING ME, OPRAH!</p>
<div id="attachment_1628" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 472px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_4883.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1628" alt="IMG_4883" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_4883-e1363657878210.jpg?w=462&#038;h=344" width="462" height="344" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Haven&#8217;t read these. Scandalous.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">Alright, Bookworms. You know you&#8217;ve got some of these bad boys on your shelves. I want to hear about them so I don&#8217;t feel so alone. Spill it!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1625/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/wordsforworms.wordpress.com/1625/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=wordsforworms.com&#038;blog=39235200&#038;post=1625&#038;subd=wordsforworms&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/19/top-ten-tuesday-the-shelf-of-shame/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>263</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d13100a03f9d0fc63e2c99c0ba2c7f2?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wordsforworms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/toptentuesday.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">toptentuesday</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_3298-e1363656351913.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3298</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7873.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">You can see the bargain stickers! </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_4883-e1363657878210.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_4883</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
