<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>CaptainAwkward.com</title>
	<atom:link href="http://captainawkward.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://captainawkward.com</link>
	<description>Advice. Staircase Wit. Faux Pas. Movies.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 14:09:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='captainawkward.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>CaptainAwkward.com</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://captainawkward.com/osd.xml" title="CaptainAwkward.com" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://captainawkward.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Asheville, North Carolina is Meeting Up April 30</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/26/asheville-north-carolina-is-meeting-up-april-30/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/26/asheville-north-carolina-is-meeting-up-april-30/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 18:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Meetups]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5339</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From Dr. Jillenstein: Hello Awkwardeers of Western North Carolina! Please join me for an Awkward Army Meetup on Tuesday, April 30, at the French Broad Chocolate Lounge in Asheville, NC. Delicious chocolate desserts and drinks are available and reasonably priced at this all-ages location. The first floor is fully accessible, there are gender-neutral bathrooms, and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5339&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div>From Dr. Jillenstein:</div>
<div></div>
<blockquote>
<div>Hello Awkwardeers of Western North Carolina! Please join me for an Awkward Army Meetup on Tuesday, April 30, at the French Broad Chocolate Lounge in Asheville, NC. Delicious chocolate desserts and drinks are available and reasonably priced at this all-ages location. The first floor is fully accessible, there are gender-neutral bathrooms, and it&#8217;s right in downtown Asheville. I will be there from 7-9pm (or later if there is fun happening). I have curly hair &amp; glasses, will probably be knitting, and will have a sign that reads &#8220;Awkward Army Meet Here.&#8221; I&#8217;m on Twitter @Dr_Jillenstein and I created a Facebook event page here:<br />
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/153042931528036" target="_blank">https://www.facebook.com/events/153042931528036</a></p>
</div>
<p>Tuesday, April 30</p></blockquote>
</div>
<blockquote><p>7pm &#8211; 9pm (or later)<br />
French Broad Chocolate Lounge<br />
10 South Lexington Ave., Asheville, NC, 28801<br />
(just south of Patton Avenue, around the corner from Salsa&#8217;s)<br />
<a href="http://www.frenchbroadchocolates.com/" target="_blank">http://www.frenchbroadchocolates.com/</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Have a great time. Jill &amp; her husband are Chicago friends who recently relocated to North Carolina and are pretty much the best people.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5339/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5339/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5339&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/26/asheville-north-carolina-is-meeting-up-april-30/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>London Meetup + #462: When is it time to cut off communication with abusive family?</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/22/london-meetup-462-when-is-it-time-to-cut-off-communication-with-abusive-family/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/22/london-meetup-462-when-is-it-time-to-cut-off-communication-with-abusive-family/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Families]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manipulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotional abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Psychological abuse]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5336</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reminder, monthly London meetup is tomorrow. Sorry for not posting this sooner, guys! It&#8217;s been the week of 1000 meetings. Dear Awkward Army, London meetup this weekend, 23rd March!  All welcome. 11:00 am onwards, Leon restaurant, 36/38 Old Compton Street, London, W1D 4TT. The venue so far has worked out well, so I’m sticking with that.  [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5336&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Reminder, monthly London meetup is tomorrow. Sorry for not posting this sooner, guys! It&#8217;s been the week of 1000 meetings.</p>
<blockquote>
<div>
<div>
<div>Dear Awkward Army,</div>
<p>London meetup this weekend, 23rd March!  All welcome.</p>
<p>11:00 am onwards, Leon restaurant, 36/38 Old Compton Street, London, W1D 4TT.</p>
<p>The venue so far has worked out well, so I’m sticking with that.  They&#8217;ve also offered us 25% off all our food and drink.</p>
<p>Map: <a href="http://goo.gl/maps/i9COr" target="_blank">http://goo.gl/maps/i9COr</a></p>
<p>Leon have a variety of good food at very reasonable prices – for central London, anyway!  Menu here:<a href="http://www.leonrestaurants.co.uk/menu/" target="_blank">http://www.leonrestaurants.co.uk/menu/</a></p>
<p>This branch has an accessible toilet, and we’ll be on the ground floor in the back (around behind the food service counter).</p>
<p>I have long brown hair and glasses.  I will bring my plush Cthulhu to use as a table marker.  It looks like this: <a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/7cb0/" target="_blank">http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/7cb0/</a></p>
<p>My email address is kate DOT towner AT gmail DOT com</p>
<p>As discussed at previous meetups, I am happy to teach people to knit, so if you want to start or want help, bring something along!</p>
</div>
<p>By the way, I think it&#8217;s likely the April one will be on the 20th rather than the 27th, sorry about any confusion.</p>
</div>
<p>Cheers,</p>
<p>Kate</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></blockquote>
<p>And now, a letter.</p>
<p><em>Hey Cap (and friends!),</em></p>
<p><em>There&#8217;s a little bit of background to this, but I&#8217;ll try to keep it short.</em></p>
<p><em>I have issues with my family. I guess you could say I&#8217;m the &#8220;black sheep&#8221; in a way. I&#8217;m the middle child, the only creative person, the only one who could be described as liberal, and (perhaps most importantly) the only one to inherit my mother&#8217;s bad depression, with a side of social anxiety. Add to this a big old heap of emotional abuse from my father and, later, my stepmother (who is thankfully gone now).</em></p>
<p><em>When I was in high school, I went through a lot of trouble, including self-harm, that was more or less ignored, and I didn&#8217;t do very well in school despite having clear potential. It was only later when I asked my parents about it that they said yeah, they always sort of knew that I had depression, and knew that it was holding me back, but they didn&#8217;t want to bring it up with me at the time because&#8230;they haven&#8217;t given a solid answer. As far as I can tell, they kind of sacrificed my academic future on the altar of not having an awkward conversation with me.</em></p>
<p><em>A few months ago, I moved out of state to live with my boyfriend and see about continuing into college now that I have things more under control. But every time I talk to my parents or my brother and sister, it seems like they have nothing nice to say at all.</em></p>
<p><em>I love my brother and sister, but every time I chat with them, they seem to be always upset with me. &#8220;Why haven&#8217;t you called us? Why haven&#8217;t you called Dad? You need to call us more and not be so ungrateful. You don&#8217;t even want to be part of the family.&#8221; Even putting aside the fact that they know I have a lot of anxiety when it comes to talking on the phone, I don&#8217;t understand how being busy up here and not able to contact home every day counts as ungrateful.</em></p>
<p><em>Then, the other night, a minor disagreement on Facebook randomly spiraled into them accusing me of hating our father, of not wanting to be a part of the family, and of being selfish in even moving away. These overtures were common before I&#8217;d moved, but now it&#8217;s been magnified so that they&#8217;ve become outright vicious about it.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m out of a toxic environment, but now the environment is starting to follow me. How do I tell my brother and sister that I still love my family (I really do!), but they need respect my decisions and treat me like a person?</em></p>
<p>Oh goody, when your abuser recruits others to do their abusing for them.</p>
<p><span id="more-5336"></span></p>
<p>I want to review a few things about abuse (which includes neglect and/or emotional abuse). Well, I don&#8217;t want to. But I will. People can grow up in the same household <a title="Reader Question #6:  I’m worried about my sister.  She is still very close to our abusive parents." href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/01/19/reader-question-6-im-worried-about-my-sister-she-is-still-very-close-to-our-abusive-parents/">and have two totally different experiences of what happened</a>. Your brother and sister are probably being wound up by your dad, and investing in this story about how they are the Good Ones and you are the one who causes problems. And your leaving affects the stories they want to tell themselves about how they grew up. If they grew up in an awesome place, then why are you leaving it? And if they didn&#8217;t grow up in such an awesome situation, and you can just walk away from it, then they could theoretically walk away from it, too. But they aren&#8217;t, so are you like, judging them by making a different choice? Or leaving them alone to deal with JerkDad on their own, which is somehow &#8220;unfair&#8221;?</p>
<p>None of this surprises me, is what I&#8217;m saying. Abusers need to control the story about what happened, and will go to great lengths (including deputizing others and making them miserable by proxy) to keep that control, because it&#8217;s a way of controlling you. If your parents had gotten you help when they noticed you harming yourself, they risked that you would tell other people what it was really like in your house, which may have had real consequences for them or the imagined consequence of &#8220;someone somewhere thinks they are not very good parents.&#8221; Maybe you would have moved out, and been outside of their control. Maybe you would have gone off to school, and learned things, and been outside of their control. Maybe people in your town would have given them the side-eye at church. Or, maybe they saw you hurting yourself and they just didn&#8217;t give a shit, and now that you&#8217;re old enough to tell the story I and everyone reading this thinks maybe they weren&#8217;t very good parents. That cat is out of the bag, Letter Writer, so take care of yourself now that you are out of the house and have that agency for yourself.</p>
<p>Honestly, who knows or cares what their logic is. You don&#8217;t actually have to know in order to make good decisions for yourself.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what we do know:</p>
<p>1. Many people don&#8217;t get the whole &#8220;making a different choice than you is not an attack on you&#8221; thing. You left. They could leave too, if they wanted to. If they choose to stay? Great, enjoy that, then! Not actually a referendum on love or a reason for yelling.</p>
<p>2. Starting a conversation with someone who calls you with WHY DON&#8217;T YOU CALL MORE, JERK? is a good way to get people to call you even less, because why put up with the hassle? Telephones, roads, emails work both ways.</p>
<p>3. Living where you are living and putting some distance between you and your family is a good decision for you right now.</p>
<p>Your family doesn&#8217;t have to be horrible for that to be true, by the way. Some people grow really well while staying very close to and entwined with their families, but some people need to go off on their own and really break away for a while before they can come back and figure out an adult relationship with their folks. The stayers aren&#8217;t better people than the leavers, and the leavers don&#8217;t necessarily grow up better than the stayers &#8211; it&#8217;s just, whatever your situation is, you need to do what is right for you.</p>
<p>It sounds like your family sees you as a perpetual fuck-up. Guess what? For much of my adult life, mine did, too. They wouldn&#8217;t use &#8220;fuck-up&#8221;, they would use &#8220;We&#8217;re very worried about you,&#8221; or &#8220;We don&#8217;t understand your choices (to seem to fail at everything).&#8221; For a lot of my 20s, when I was really struggling with depression and figuring out what I wanted to do with my life, being around them for long periods of time would make me start to feel like a fuck-up. And then it would be self-fulfilling &#8211; I&#8217;d be so miserable and wound up that I would be in a reactive mode because I was so ashamed and on-edge all the time. If you&#8217;re constantly criticized, you start to react to people as if they mean to criticize you even before the words come out of their mouths, so it&#8217;s easy to launch the &#8220;<em>Why are you being so dramatic/exaggerating/blowing things out of proportion/I was <strong>just asking</strong>/jeez, overreact much?</em>&#8221; brigade and the you feel more like a fuck-up because you&#8217;re being gaslighted into believing that having normal reactions &#8211; stress, aversion, shoulders-up-around-ears, being on guard are somehow your own fantasies and not reactions to the <a title="Microaggression" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microaggression" target="_blank">constant criticism </a>that&#8217;s being leveled at you.</p>
<p>You know what was a great decision for me? Moving really, really far away and staying there, and seeing them in smaller doses.</p>
<p>I just spent a few days with my folks last month, and we&#8217;re on much better terms now and it was mostly a great visit. But by the end of it, my dad&#8217;s constant mansplaining had escalated to the point that he took my toast out of the toaster, put it back in &#8220;correctly,&#8221; called me &#8220;stupid&#8221; for not being able to find the correct drawer where knives were kept on the first try in a kitchen where I don&#8217;t live, and actually SCREAMED at me for microwaving food for what he deemed to be an incorrect amount of time. Screamed. Spit flying and hitting my face. Screamed.</p>
<p>And that was a &#8220;great&#8221; visit. And if he read this (I don&#8217;t think they read the blog, they&#8217;ve never mentioned it, and I&#8217;ve never mentioned it to them though I don&#8217;t hide my actual identity), he&#8217;d tell me I was overreacting and blowing the whole thing out of proportion. Because screaming about things like &#8220;where we keep the knives in a rental kitchen&#8221; is normal in his world, so normal that there is a 75% chance he does not remember it at all, and I was raised to think that was normal. I <a title="Men are too emotional to have a rational argument" href="http://www.thegloss.com/2012/11/12/career/bullish-life-men-are-too-emotional-to-have-a-rational-argument-994/" target="_blank">would be the &#8220;emotional&#8221; one for being mad</a> that someone screamed in my face (and having to walk out of the room and go cry privately and text my boyfriend because I honestly felt like I was going crazy), and he would be the rational one, because&#8230;he is a dude. A dude who gets so upset about microwave times that he screams. Rational!</p>
<p>And then I left, and I went to the <a title="Should I move away from my abusive family" href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/10/18/question-122-should-i-move-away-from-my-abusive-family/" target="_blank">small quiet room</a>, where no one screams at me, ever. And if someone in my life now screamed at me, they would not do it twice, because they would not be in my life anymore, because screaming at people over trivial shit is not okay. I learned that by leaving home, pretty much forever, which was not without costs and anxiety and working hard to schedule visits so that I can get in and out with a minimum of screaming. Going home &amp; maintaining that relationship means trying to always make sure I have a rental car, or schedule time with friends who live nearby so I have a break, and ALWAYS having my phone with me so I feel connected to people who don&#8217;t yell at me, and sometimes, honestly, Xanax. It means when they are nice and pleasant it makes me doubt my own reality, like, do I really need to keep my shields up? Am I being unfair? Ohhhhh wait, there is screaming about trivial stuff again, nope, it&#8217;s okay to keep my guard up. It also cost <strong>years of therapy</strong> to learn how to interact in a healthy way, keep my temper (or lose it more selectively), and be able to disassociate from what was happening and remind myself that their vision of me is not me. It also cost long periods of not interacting with them, with the explicit message &#8220;<em>If you are not nice to me, I will not be around</em>.&#8221; Eventually it worked and made everyone try very hard to be nicer. But I won&#8217;t ever lie and say it was easy.</p>
<p>Alphakitty said something really great <a title="Comment by Alphakitty" href="http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/18/461-my-partner-makes-hurtful-jokes-about-my-health-situation/#comment-49604" target="_blank">in a comment</a> yesterday:</p>
<blockquote><p>I think part of a mother/father’s power to hurt comes from the Pedestals of Infallibility young children are encouraged to put their parents on. Even once we grow up and learn that our parents are just people, with biases and baggage and all that, we still invest their opinions of us with greater Truth and weight than we would give anyone else’s opinion. It’s all swirled together with the “Mother/Father knows best,” and “we only want what’s best for you” (even though their values probably aren’t quite the same as yours, so their definition of “best” is not going to match yours), and an implication that “we know you better than anyone else, even you” (though parents’ opinions of their offspring are often a) outdated, based on behavior/characteristics the “child” has outgrown, and b) distorted by their own values and their need to believe certain things about their kids).</p></blockquote>
<p>Your parents, and your brother and sister, DON&#8217;T KNOW YOU BEST. And they don&#8217;t know what is best for you &#8211; they proved that when you needed help and mental health services and they just kind of forgot to hook you up with them. And this story that they have about how you are a fuck-up is not the only story, and not a story that everyone will have about you. And I think you were smart to get far, far away from them.</p>
<p>I think that now that you are away, you should do a couple of things:</p>
<p>1) Find (or continue) treatment for your depression.</p>
<p>2) Put your brother, sister, dad, and anyone else who makes you uncomfortable in social media jail. There are ways you can stay &#8220;friends&#8221; with someone on Facebook but make it so they can&#8217;t really see anything you post or do on Facebook. Or, consider unfriending them, or making a second profile where you connect with people you really want to. &#8220;<em>I love you, but I refuse to get in Facebook fights. From now on email me at _____.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>3) Filter their emails and phone calls so that you <a title="What is an introvert? #456 &amp; #457: Communication Expectations" href="http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/01/what-is-an-introvert-456-457-communication-expectations/" target="_blank">choose to interact with them at specific, regular times</a>. And possibly cut off all contact for a while, if it helps you gain some distance and perspective. For a long time, this is what I did: I would call or hang out periodically, and be pleasant as long as they were pleasant. When the first mean thing was said, I would leave the conversation and not interact again for a period of (generally) 1 month. 2 mean things? 2 months. 3 mean things? 3 months. It was not perfect, and it was very hard and painful and took a lot of psyching myself up and second-guessing on my part. But it was pretty essential in reminding myself: &#8220;<em>Whatever happened in the past,</em> <em>I do not have to stay in conversations with people who are rude to me.</em>&#8221; Sometimes I would just excuse myself, &#8220;<em>Sorry, out of time to talk, catch you soon!</em>&#8221; and sometimes I&#8217;d say &#8220;<em>This conversation is really starting to stress me out, so I&#8217;m going to end it now</em>&#8221; &#8211; it depended on how mean it was and my overall stress level.</p>
<p>4) Repeat &#8220;<em>I am not responsible for everything they feel&#8221;</em> until it sounds believable.</p>
<p>5) If you want to, say something like &#8220;<em>I am really happy and excited to start school. I am taking a break from communication for a while while I get settled, and I&#8217;ll be in touch when I&#8217;m ready</em>.&#8221; And then let them feel about it and react however they want. They will not like it, they will not understand, they will be mad, but it might still be <strong>what you need</strong> in order to feel okay.</p>
<p>6) It may never be okay. It will always hurt a bit and feel weird. That&#8217;s because abuse is destructive and it ruins everything, not because you are a bad mean ungrateful daughter. Your family is blaming you for things they did to you. Not okay.</p>
<p>7) The rest of your family might not believe you or see it your way. &#8220;<em>But that&#8217;s just how he is&#8230;&#8221; &#8220;But I deal with it, why can&#8217;t you?&#8221; &#8220;You&#8217;re exaggerating.&#8221; &#8220;It&#8217;s not that bad.&#8221; </em>Well, maybe it is that bad, for you, and they don&#8217;t have to agree for you to do what is right for you. It would be awesome if your sibs could be your allies, but if they aren&#8217;t, admit it and disengage. &#8220;<em>We think you&#8217;re the worst, so move back here and prove you love us, or we&#8217;ll think you&#8217;re the worst</em>&#8221; isn&#8217;t really a compelling proposition.</p>
<p>8) Kick ass at your studies and enjoy your new life.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5336/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5336/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5336&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/22/london-meetup-462-when-is-it-time-to-cut-off-communication-with-abusive-family/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>226</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#461: My partner makes hurtful jokes about my health situation.</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/18/461-my-partner-makes-hurtful-jokes-about-my-health-situation/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/18/461-my-partner-makes-hurtful-jokes-about-my-health-situation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 13:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manipulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dealing with health problems in a relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotional abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5328</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Captain Awkward: I have had a very complex life in the last couple of years. I have gone from having a fairly normal life in regards to health and then I went on dialysis. Since that point I now have a kidney transplant. My girlfriend currently has a really hard time wrapping her mind [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5328&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward:</em></p>
<p><em>I have had a very complex life in the last couple of years. I have gone from having a fairly normal life in regards to health and then I went on dialysis. Since that point I now have a kidney transplant.</em></p>
<p><em>My girlfriend currently has a really hard time wrapping her mind around the changes in lifestyle that I have to live. She almost finds my precautions somewhat unbearable.</em></p>
<p><em>What should I do? She also makes fun of my situation or lightheartedly jokes about it.</em></p>
<p>Unfortunately they don&#8217;t offer empathy transplants.</p>
<p>Was your girlfriend with you since before the changes? Because I would imagine that watching a partner go through dialysis and a kidney transplant would make it sink in that 1) Hey, you could have DIED 2) Following your doctors&#8217; recommendations carefully is  serious business. If she met you after the changes, maybe the seriousness of it hasn&#8217;t really sunk in. Which isn&#8217;t an excuse, but it gives you a place to start in deepening her perspective.</p>
<p>If you want to try to make things work with this person, I think there is both a Big Serious Talk to be had and some day-to-day scripts.</p>
<p>The daily script is, when she makes a joke, to say something like &#8220;<em>Whoa, that really hurts my feelings</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>After you say that, be quiet, and listen to what happens next. There is going to be a very awkward moment, and it is not your job to smooth it over &#8211; the awkwardness is the way that you get to the resolution. If she stops, apologizes, and changes her behavior, that&#8217;s a good sign. If you&#8217;ve been putting up with the jokes for a while, it may take a few tries for it to sink in &#8211; you are subtly changing the &#8220;rules&#8221; of how the relationship works and some people don&#8217;t get it right away. You can openly acknowledge the rule change with &#8220;<em>I know I usually let it go, but&#8230;.&#8221; </em>or<em> &#8220;I know you mean that as a joke, but&#8230;.&#8221; when you say things like that, it really hurts my feelings. Can we find another way to talk about x issue?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>If after saying that her jokes hurt your feelings, she doubles down on the joking, or starts justifying why it&#8217;s okay for her to make jokes that hurt your feelings, she is pressuring you to ignore your healthy routines, she calls you &#8220;too sensitive&#8221; and tells you to &#8220;toughen up,&#8221; or for whatever reason the conversation ends with <strong>you</strong> apologizing to <strong>her</strong> for bringing it up and being upset, here there be <a title="The House of Evil Bees" href="http://criminalreviews.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/a-captain-awkward-glossary/#evilbees" target="_blank">Evil Bees</a>.</p>
<p><span id="more-5328"></span></p>
<p>I would try that script several times before escalating to the Big Serious Talk. You will get some information about what you&#8217;re dealing with that will help you have the talk, and you&#8217;ll get some recent examples of the behavior that bugs you.</p>
<p>The big talk is telling her what you went through, how painful and scary it was, and why these lifestyle changes are very necessary for you, and asking her directly for her kindness and support and to lay off the hurtful jokes. There is also some asking to be done about her point of view, one way to start the talk is to maybe ask her how things are affecting her. &#8220;<em>I know we&#8217;ve been through some changes, and I get from the jokes that you make that you&#8217;re still really processing them. I know it was hard for you to see me go through that crisis. Can you tell me a little bit about what it&#8217;s been like for you? In a perfect world, where you get everything you want, how would our relationship work? Is there a way we can make the relationship work better for both of us?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s okay for a partner to belittle you for having needs, or make jokes about your health needs, or laugh off your very real concerns and issues, and this way of opening the conversation might seem way nicer than she deserves. My reasoning is this:  When you have to have a very difficult conversation, it helps to treat people as you want to be treated. You are modeling good behavior by being up front about your needs and asking her to articulate hers in the hopes that she will rise to the occasion.</p>
<p>In the most generous possible interpretation of her behavior maybe the jokes are her way of getting uncomfortable feelings out there that she didn&#8217;t ever feel safe to talk about when you guys were in full &#8220;gonna die, can&#8217;t talk now&#8221; mode.  A drastic change in diet or energy or what activities you do does affect the other person in the relationship, not to mention being a caregiver or watching someone you love go through a huge medical crisis.Whatever happened to her during that time was definitely happening to you way more, obviously, but *something* was happening to her and maybe she needs a safe place to talk about how scared she was. If she is a new partner and wasn&#8217;t with you during the time before the transplant, maybe she doesn&#8217;t fully understand what happened and how serious it was, and needs to be told explicitly what it&#8217;s like for you.</p>
<p>Your health needs and not-being-belittled-by-someone-who-says-they-love-you needs trump her feelings, obviously. But the best way to figure out if this is a My Girlfriend Is Bad At Communicating vs. My Girlfriend Lacks Empathy situation is to ask outright and give her the opportunity to surprise you with doing the right thing.  This talk might be a much needed way to process everything together and find a way forward. If it goes well, consider seeing a couples counselor where you can have an ongoing conversation about this and really work on communication.</p>
<p>Sadly, it may be the time you find out that you guys are really not on the same page. Maybe the changes in your lifestyle really are &#8220;unbearable&#8221; for your girlfriend. That is something she gets to decide, and she gets to leave and seek another partner. But she doesn&#8217;t get to hang around and be mean to you. If<em id="__mceDel"> </em>you open up and she makes fun of you, laughs it off, and keeps going with the jokes, realize that there are people out there who won&#8217;t treat you this way. And if she for one second implies that &#8220;someone in your condition&#8221; is lucky to have her and that you won&#8217;t be able to find anyone else, run (or wheel yourself, or crawl) for the nearest exit. That is a big, bad sign that she is emotionally abusing you, and that is 100% never okay.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5328/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5328/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5328&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/18/461-my-partner-makes-hurtful-jokes-about-my-health-situation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>106</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#460: Boundaries are good, even if other people don&#8217;t enjoy it when you set them.</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/15/460-boundaries-are-good-even-if-other-people-dont-enjoy-it-when-you-set-them/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/15/460-boundaries-are-good-even-if-other-people-dont-enjoy-it-when-you-set-them/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 20:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[manipulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saying no]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alcohol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boundaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coercion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intrusive questions]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5323</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a very smart post on moving on and setting boundaries with an ex from Jenn Vicious at In Our Words: &#8220;There’s this thing that sometimes happens when people break up but still care about each other: they want to continue working on things that were problems in their relationship. Don’t do that. My [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5323&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a very smart post on <a title="Ask Jenn Vicious: You're going to be a jerk; set boundaries anyway" href="http://inourwordsblog.com/2013/03/15/ask-jenn-vicious-youre-going-to-be-a-jerk-set-boundaries-anyway/">moving on and setting boundaries with an ex from Jenn Vicious at In Our Words:</a></p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;There’s this thing that sometimes happens when people break up but still care about each other: they want to continue working on things that were problems in their relationship. Don’t do that. <strong>My opinion on it is that if you break up with someone, then you are done working out the problems in your relationship.</strong> You are more likely to get to a place where you can genuinely care about each other as friends if you actually stop relying on each other for the same support you provided when you were together. You have to change your patterns of behavior, change the expectations you have of each other when you interact. It isn’t easy, but if you didn’t know that you needed to do it, you probably would have stayed in the relationship.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>(Bolding mine) That&#8217;s my opinion, too, which is why I <a title="Cohabitation Situations: Ambivalence Deliverance (#451) &amp; Eviction Prescription (#452)" href="http://captainawkward.com/2013/02/20/cohabitation-451ambivalence-deliverance-452-eviction-prescription/">say to not use the moment when you break up with someone to critique everything about them that you don&#8217;t like</a>. You don&#8217;t have to make a case to someone about why your heart moved on, you just have to tell them your decision and then figure out how to live with it. Also, it&#8217;s true that when what someone wants (you!) is fundamentally different from what you want (not them!) there is no magic way to extricate yourself without hurting them.</p>
<p>And now, a letter:</p>
<p><em>Hello Awkwards:</em></p>
<p><em> I&#8217;m a 22 year old single female student studying library and information science. I&#8217;m a gamer, computer &#8211; roleplaying and boardgames it&#8217;s all the same. </em></p>
<p><em> I also don&#8217;t drink alcohol. My family thinks it&#8217;s a bit weird but prefer it to an extreme in the other direction and don&#8217;t bother me about it anymore, strangers and friends however are a different story. Most assume that I&#8217;m either religious (in some strange way), on a cleanse (HA!), a recovering alcoholic or even pregnant.</em></p>
<p><em> The thing is that I just don&#8217;t like the taste and if/when they find this out it&#8217;s no longer accepted for me to abstain. It&#8217;s always just this one beer or drink or wine that is going to convert me. And I like hanging out with my friends when there&#8217;s drinking. I can watch out for everyone and still have an awesome time with just soda. Still someone always asks and I always have to explain and then be pestered. </em></p>
<p><em> &#8220;It&#8217;s to bitter&#8221; I will say and they will reply</em><br />
<em> &#8220;Ah but this drink/beer/wine is different, try it&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em> and no it&#8217;s not it maybe sweet compared to other but that doesn&#8217;t make it actually sweet or remove the aftertaste of alcohol.</em></p>
<p><em> And I never send out the signal that this is something I want solved. I don&#8217;t desperately want to get drunk, I&#8217;m not in dire need of a drunk Yoda to guide me in the way of the drink. And not to make light of others problems but when I have to compare to trying to convert others to your faith/sexuality just to make them stop trying to enrich your life it&#8217;s gone to far- can someone give a way I can try to convince people to leave it alone without referring to these sensitive and more serious issues?</em></p>
<p><em> Please help a frustrated absolutist</em></p>
<p><span id="more-5323"></span></p>
<p>Dear Frustrated Absolutist:</p>
<p>Try this:</p>
<p><strong>Person</strong>: &#8220;<em>Would you like some wine?&#8221;</em></p>
<p><strong>You:</strong> &#8220;<em>No, thanks. How is (subject change) going with you?&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t elaborate, don&#8217;t explain why, don&#8217;t justify it. You said in your letter that you feel like you always have to explain when you turn down alcohol, but you <strong>don&#8217;t</strong> actually have to explain. Be very casual and treat them like you expect nothing weird will happen, and most people will accept subject change and not even realize it. Of course, there will be exceptions, so if someone ask again, try this:</p>
<p><strong>Person:</strong> &#8220;<em>Are you sure you don&#8217;t want some? It&#8217;s really good.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p><strong>You:</strong> &#8220;<em>No thanks. So, tell me about (subject change).</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>Again, do not explain, justify, or elaborate. It is none of their business why you don&#8217;t drink, and elaborating on why invites them to try to make the case that it&#8217;s not that bad or tastes like angel sweat stirred by a unicorn. If the person still doesn&#8217;t get the hint, and if you like absurdity and are snappy with a comeback, try:</p>
<p><strong>Person</strong>: &#8220;<em>Why, are you pregnant or something?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p><strong>You:</strong> &#8220;<em>Hahaha, yes, ever since I was kidnapped by demons. They warned me that alcohol could really speed up The Summoning of The Dark One, so I&#8217;m trying to lay off until the Day of The Blood Harvest is complete. So, about (subject change)&#8230;</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>or</p>
<p><strong>Person:</strong> &#8220;<em>But why?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p><strong>You:</strong> &#8220;<em>It makes my personality implant malfunction, and trust me, you DON&#8217;T want to meet </em>(stage whisper<em>) Leviticus, the Hands-y Science Professor.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>or</p>
<p><strong>Person:</strong> &#8220;<em>But you should totally drink! It&#8217;s fun and refreshing!</em>&#8220;</p>
<p><strong>You:</strong> &#8220;<em>I believe you! I&#8217;m starting to run out of subject changes, though, so I would *really* like the next one to take.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>If you are not so snappy with a comeback, or want an all-purpose strategy, here is my actual recommended strategy if someone gets pushy about why you won&#8217;t drink:</p>
<p><strong>Be done talking to that person for the time being.</strong> You said no TWICE. &#8220;No&#8221; is a complete sentence. If someone is just not hearing your &#8220;no&#8221; and steamrollering over it, one possible solution is to just walk away from the conversation. There are lots of people to talk to at parties. You can decide how much of an issue you want to make of it. You can go &#8220;<a title="#336: Gracefully exiting from conversations." href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/08/27/336-gracefully-exiting-from-conversations/">gracefully</a>&#8220;or <a title="Reader Question #20:  Captain Awkward’s Emporium of Cutting Remarks" href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/02/23/reader-question-20-captain-awkwards-emporium-of-cutting-remarks/">ungracefully</a> , i.e., &#8220;<em>Hey, good talking to you&#8221;</em> and excuse yourself from the conversation, or &#8220;<em>I&#8217;ve said &#8216;no thanks&#8217; twice now. Is there a problem?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>Sometimes it&#8217;s good to engage with people and explain to them sincerely why what they are doing is out of line, as in, &#8220;<em>Hey, do we really have to have this conversation again? Because it&#8217;s exhausting and boring. Stop trying to convince me of something I already know and get to decide for myself.</em>&#8220;  Other times, the most self-caring thing you can do is to get yourself away from people &amp; conversations that stress you out, and save your energy for people who make you feel good. Other times, you can just blink at them incredulously and remain silent until they fill the awkward silence with something less intrusive and terrible. &#8220;<em>I&#8217;m sorry, <a title="Don Draper saying &quot;What&quot;" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WsJSRP7cZVo" target="_blank">what</a>?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p><strong>Because:</strong> The problem is not you not wanting to drink, or why you don&#8217;t want to drink. The problem is people hearing &#8220;no thanks&#8221; and taking that as the opening stage in a negotiation. And I think it is good for everyone to recognize when that is happening and have strategies for shutting the conversation down.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re not weird for not drinking. They are weird for taking &#8220;I don&#8217;t drink&#8221; as an invitation to sell you on drinking.<strong> Analogous</strong>: Someone is not weird for being a vegetarian, or having celiac disease, or being a vegetarian with celiac disease. The person who hears &#8220;<em>I&#8217;m a vegetarian and I have celiac</em>&#8221; and responds with &#8220;<em>But have you <strong>tried</strong> this sandwich of ground animal parts on a whole wheat bun? I think it&#8217;s really going to change your whole outlook on things!</em>&#8221; is committing a massive, massive faux pas. And that faux pas is <strong>coercion. </strong>Which we need less of, both <a title="Hiatus, Holiday Open Thread, &amp; #389: Friendly Social Coercion is Still Coercion" href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/10/23/hiatus-holiday-open-thread-389-friendly-social-coercion-is-still-coercion/">generally</a> and <a title="#398: I’m tired of explaining my medical condition and food choices to “helpful” folks." href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/11/25/398-im-tired-of-explaining-my-medical-condition-to-helpful-folks/">around food/drink specifically</a>. Whenever someone behaves like that, I wonder, are they really THAT insecure about what they like? If the people in your life love drinking so much, they can do it without your validation or participation. <strong>Someone making a different choice than you would make is not invalidating your choices. </strong></p>
<p>Now, your friends and family should know that you don&#8217;t drink, and they should be respectful about that. Which means, warning you if something has alcohol in it, and not making you explain yourself about it, or, if someone is badgering you about it they should also step in and say &#8220;<em>Yeah, she doesn&#8217;t drink. So, howabout (subject change)?</em>&#8221; as well. If they make fun of you or shame you, shut it down, not because you should drink but because people shaming you about choices that have nothing to do with them is shitty. <strong><br />
</strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5323/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5323/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5323&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/15/460-boundaries-are-good-even-if-other-people-dont-enjoy-it-when-you-set-them/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>399</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/14/open-thread/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/14/open-thread/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 18:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5312</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sorry for the light posting. My students are all in the middle of making films, so my job is pretty busy right now, and I took on an additional super-cool project. If you&#8217;re in Chicago, come see By The Way, Meet Vera Stark at the Goodman Theatre this spring. It&#8217;s a play about the African [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5312&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_5313" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/theflameofneworleans.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5313" alt="Still from The Flame of New Orleans" src="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/theflameofneworleans.jpg?w=300&#038;h=233" width="300" height="233" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Still from The Flame of New Orleans, with Marlene Dietrich and Theresa Harris</p></div>
<p>Sorry for the light posting. My students are all in the middle of making films, so my job is pretty busy right now, and I took on an additional super-cool project. If you&#8217;re in Chicago, come see <a title="Goodman Theatre By The Way, Meet Vera Stark" href="http://www.goodmantheatre.org/season/by-the-way-meet-vera-stark/" target="_blank">By The Way, Meet Vera Stark</a> at the Goodman Theatre this spring. It&#8217;s a play about the African American actresses who played maids in Hollywood in the 1930s, written by Pulitzer-prize winning playwright <a title="Lynn Nottage" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lynn_Nottage" target="_blank">Lynn Nottage</a>. I&#8217;m line-producing  and working as the First Assistant Director for the film-within-the-play that opens the second act.</p>
<p>My colleague <a title="Vaun Monroe: Reel Soul" href="http://www.indiewire.com/feature/reel-soul-vaun-monroe" target="_blank">Vaun Monroe </a>is directing, and we&#8217;re collaborating with the Goodman&#8217;s amazing cast and crew of designers and set builders and props people. We&#8217;re shooting black &amp; white, 35mm film in the style of 1930s melodramas like <a title="Jezebel Trailer" href="http://www.tcm.com/mediaroom/video/72819/Jezebel-Re-issue-Trailer-.html" target="_blank">Jezebel</a>* or <a title="The Flame of New Orleans" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0033606/" target="_blank">The Flame of New Orleans </a>(We have a film historian on our crew &#8211; How awesome is that? &#8211; and I&#8217;m pretty sure our <a title="Brian Levin" href="http://www.brian-levin.com/" target="_blank">cinematographer</a> said something about using <a title="diffusion filters" href="http://books.google.com/books?id=fR--7yVROI4C&amp;pg=PA84&amp;lpg=PA84&amp;dq=pantyhose+cinematography+diffusion+filters&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=rnkcb8fSux&amp;sig=TdU9nVpVJypMsA73crSnOg8nqvg&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=WRJCUfPkEMWzygGSk4C4Ag&amp;ved=0CEkQ6AEwAg#v=onepage&amp;q=pantyhose%20cinematography%20diffusion%20filters&amp;f=false" target="_blank">pantyhose filters</a> to get <a title="Marlene Dietrich" href="http://www.doctormacro.com/Images/Dietrich,%20Marlene/Annex/NRFPT/Annex%20-%20Dietrich,%20Marlene_NRFPT_37.jpg" target="_blank">1930s glamour closeups</a>).</p>
<p>For those of you who don&#8217;t know what a line producer or a 1st AD does, I make the budget and the schedule, recruit the crew, negotiate costs for rentals, make the contracts, manage the money, and on the day of the shoot I make sure everything happens on schedule and all of the paperwork is filled out. Chief problem-solver and get-shit-done person, basically, or, the person who translates the stuff the creative team says at meetings into to-do lists, or, the person who must always keep her cell phone on. It&#8217;s a great honor to be involved in the project, and I love the script and the work. But it&#8217;s not a writerly mode of existence, for sure.</p>
<p>Commander Logic also has her hands full&#8230;<strong>with a new baby</strong>! That&#8217;s kind of a way bigger deal than a short movie, but I have not met said baby yet so do not have a 200 word synopsis of said baby ready to go.<a title="Commander Logic made a person" href="https://twitter.com/cdrLogic/status/310149410698981378"> From what I gather from the Twitter</a>, &#8220;sleepy&#8221; and &#8220;small for a human, large for a baby&#8221; are what we have going on.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s make this an open thread. Seen any good movies lately? Have a question for the commentariat?</p>
<p><strong>Edited to Add:</strong> Are you working on anything cool we should know about?  Based on a comment in the thread, I&#8217;m deciding to allow self-promotion of blogs/creative projects/crowdfunding/Etsy stores<strong> in this thread only, by regular readers only </strong>with a few caveats. Spam will still be deleted. If you never comment here but are de-lurking just to self-promote for commercial purposes, maybe refrain. Please don&#8217;t just post links without descriptions &#8211; introduce us to the work and let us know what we&#8217;ll find at the link, give content notes. Definitely warn if it&#8217;s NSFW.</p>
<p>A lot of us make art, and if we do this right it could be a cool repository of the art this community makes.</p>
<p>*ALL of Bette Davis&#8217;s reactions need to be animated .gifs. All of them.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5312/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5312/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5312&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/14/open-thread/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>337</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/theflameofneworleans.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Still from The Flame of New Orleans</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Non-therapy help for your brain + meet awkward people in New York City</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/13/5307/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/13/5307/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 21:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5307</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi everyone. If I ever get done grading midterm projects and catch up on sleep I&#8217;ll post an actual letter. In the meantime, Kate Donovan has posted a list of non-therapy mental health resources and is seeking additional recommendations. Go check it out. And New York wanted to remind everyone about this weekend&#8217;s meetup: Hi Captain, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5307&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone. If I ever get done grading midterm projects and catch up on sleep I&#8217;ll post an actual letter.</p>
<p>In the meantime, <a title="Brain Self-Help: An Incomplete List" href="http://freethoughtblogs.com/ashleymiller/2013/03/12/brain-self-help-an-incomplete-list-of-resources/">Kate Donovan has posted a list of non-therapy mental health resources</a> and is seeking additional recommendations. Go check it out.</p>
<p>And New York wanted to remind everyone about<a title="NYC Meetup" href="http://captainawkward.com/2013/02/25/nyc-meetup-march-16/" target="_blank"> this weekend&#8217;s meetup</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<div>Hi Captain,</div>
<div></div>
<div>Would you mind posting a reminder on the website about this weekend&#8217;s meetup in Brooklyn? It&#8217;s at Maimonides of Brooklyn at 525 Atlantic Avenue. (<a href="http://www.mob-usa.com/" target="_blank">http://www.mob-usa.com</a>) Please RSVP to <a href="mailto:awkwardnyc@gmail.com" target="_blank">awkwardnyc@gmail.com</a> so we can update the reservation if necessary, and feel free to bring board games. You&#8217;ll know me by my tiger-shaped hat.</div>
<div>See you there!</div>
<div>Xenophile</div>
<div></div>
</blockquote>
<div>Thanks for setting this up, Xenophile.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5307/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5307/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5307&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/13/5307/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#459: Do I have to destroy my health to be in grad school?</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/09/459-do-i-have-to-destroy-my-health-to-be-in-grad-school/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/09/459-do-i-have-to-destroy-my-health-to-be-in-grad-school/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 18:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sweet Machine</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Disability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to say no]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Academia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enforcing boundaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grad school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rutger Hauer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saying no]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[setting boundaries]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5297</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m in grad school for creative writing. It&#8217;s hard. Right now, I&#8217;m taking three classes, which means that I&#8217;m reading 500-plus pages a week, in addition to commenting on my classmates&#8217; writing and producing a poem every week. Plus, I&#8217;m teaching a basic composition course for struggling writers, and a literature course (for the first [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5297&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>I&#8217;m in grad school for creative writing. It&#8217;s hard. Right now, I&#8217;m taking three classes, which means that I&#8217;m reading 500-plus pages a week, in addition to commenting on my classmates&#8217; writing and producing a poem every week. Plus, I&#8217;m teaching a basic composition course for struggling writers, and a literature course (for the first time ever), so I&#8217;m writing lesson plans and grading essays for nearly 60 students. AND I work ten hours a week to supplement my stipend enough to buy things like toiletries, books and the occasional beer on a Friday night. Also, I need to clean my apartment and do laundry and run errands sometimes. And in addition to all of THAT, I&#8217;m expected to participate in meetings, go to outside lectures, and attend all the readings by my classmates and visiting writers. And I WANT to, because oh my god I love school. School is the best thing ever. I work my ass off and I LOVE IT. This is not really about grad school.</em></p>
<div id="attachment_5302" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 260px"><a href="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/millay_magn.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5302" alt="Millay" src="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/millay_magn.jpg?w=250&#038;h=300" width="250" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">What people think an MFA is like.</p></div>
<p><em>Except it kind of is. I have Polycystic Ovary Syndrome, which causes, among other things, crushing migraines and extreme fatigue. And there&#8217;s no cure for it, because ovaries, ew. Mostly, I manage. But there are days when I can barely drag myself around, and did I mention all the stuff I&#8217;m supposed to be doing? Sometimes I can&#8217;t do it all. Sometimes my whole body feels like a bag of wet sand that I&#8217;m not strong enough to lift. Sometimes I have to lie down and rest before I die. So I miss the reading, or the lecture, or the lunch meeting.</em></p>
<p><em><span id="more-5297"></span>I apologized to a friend for missing her reading, and she ranted about how much it sucks that people don&#8217;t go to stuff. And the professors who went to everything and did everything and walked uphill in the snow both ways while carrying their dissertation on their backs give us VERY SERIOUS TALKS on why we must do everything. They mean well, but it hurts me. There&#8217;s a kind of gleeful masochism in grad school where being overworked and sleep-deprived is a point of pride. Long story short, I feel guilty, but also mad.</em></p>
<p><em>I don&#8217;t go around telling people about my health, because it&#8217;s personal. But I&#8217;ve built up a reputation as someone who&#8217;s dedicated and hardworking, and I&#8217;d hate to think people assume that I just can&#8217;t be bothered to show up to things. Do I woman up and tell people about my defective gonads? Tell them to fuck off? How do I balance my health needs with my need to be a good grad student?</em></p>
<p><em>Signed,</em></p>
<p><em>My Candle Burns at Both its Ends</em></p>
<p>Dear Lovely Light-Giver,</p>
<p>Sweet Machine, fellow MFA-survivor and chronic migraineur, reporting for duty. I have so much to say to you that I am not sure I know how to say it, but let me start by declaring, in the sincerest way, I KNOW THAT FEEL BRO</p>
<p>It sounds like you have your medical situation taken care of, in terms of having doctors and knowing your stuff, so I am going to ask one question and then shush: do you see a neurologist for your migraines? Even if you&#8217;re managing your PCOS through a ladybits doctor, a headache specialist might help. It took a while, but I have gone from basically having 3-4 migraine days a week to having maybe 1 (and some milder headache days), with the help of Big Pharma and my neurologist. Now that I&#8217;ve got that tidbit out of the way, I&#8217;m going to ask the Awkward Army to<strong> kindly refrain from making &#8220;have you tried this&#8221; suggestions in comments</strong>. There are two reasons: 1) That&#8217;s not what this letter is about, and 2) People with chronic illnesses or medical conditions usually <em>have </em>tried everything you can suggest. (See also: saying to fat people &#8220;Have you tried diet and exercise?&#8221; WHY YES. YES I HAVE. THANK YOU, DR OZ.)</p>
<div id="attachment_5301" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rutgerhauer.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5301" alt="Grad school." src="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rutgerhauer.jpg?w=300&#038;h=134" width="300" height="134" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">What an MFA is really like.</p></div>
<p>So here is the thing about grad school, which I have completed (oh god) eight years of. Grad school is a black hole of selfhood. Grad school is a monster that wants to take every shred of your time and your identity and your well-being and store those shreds in a place you can&#8217;t access. Grad school will, if you let it, become your whole life and then demand more like it&#8217;s young scary/sexy Rutger Hauer. Grad school does not want you to be a person; it wants you to be a body in a seat in a lecture/reading/office/library chair, and it never wants to let you go.</p>
<p>I personify grad school because it&#8217;s really not that any one person wants you to sacrifice your self and sanity for this experience. Your profs are concerned with making events worthwhile for visiting speakers and such; your friend is upset that she&#8217;s expected to go to all these readings but not everyone showed up for hers; your students think you live in your office and sleep at your desk and love, beyond all reckoning, to grade their shitty essays. Individually, it&#8217;s all a bit much but based on the right things: passion, community, fairness. In toto, it&#8217;s a godawful nightmare of stress, which, oh hey, is a huge migraine trigger. And this all goes double for an arts degree, because it is Your Art and Your Passion and You Are So Lucky To Get To Do This and You Should Be Grateful.</p>
<p>Now, most grad students would really, really, really benefit from some kind of artificially enforced boundary that says &#8220;you get to stop working now [at 8:00 every night/on Saturdays/when it's time to watch more Buffy].&#8221; But you have an actually enforced boundary: your body&#8217;s needs. You have a chronic medical condition that, while manageable, means you need rest. This is a fact. Your body and your brain both need down time in order to function, and if you don&#8217;t take that time they will fucking well let you know about it. This is not you being lazy or weak or fragile; this is you having a trick knee and needing to take the elevator sometimes when you&#8217;d rather take the stairs. The secret is that <em>everyone </em>needs to take the elevator sometimes, but for people without a chronic illness, it&#8217;s usually a more visible situation: I broke my leg skiing and I need the elevator till the cast is off. For <a title="But you don't look sick" href="http://www.butyoudontlooksick.com/" target="_blank">chronic and invisible illnesses</a>, you need the elevator sometimes and no one but you knows why.</p>
<p>You say you&#8217;ve developed a reputation for being dedicated and hardworking, but you don&#8217;t sound like you believe it. I&#8217;d suggest that you start by trying to believe it! Start with that assumption and work forward. Think about yourself with the same kindness which you bestow on your friends and colleagues. If someone doesn&#8217;t come to a reading, is your first thought &#8220;What a dick,&#8221; or is your first thought, &#8220;Oh, I hope he doesn&#8217;t have the flu that&#8217;s going around&#8221;? Assume everyone is working on assumption #2. Now let&#8217;s think about specifics: your school probably has a disability services office of some kind. You may not think of your condition as a disability, which is fine, but the people who work there may be able to talk you through university policy about absences/substitute teachers/disclosure of information and the like. As for individual professors you work with, there are a few options. You are under <em>no obligation</em> to discuss your gonads, as you put it. But if you have a sympathetic advisor, you might tell them that you have a medical condition that means you get frequent migraines and need to rest regularly as part of your health management. You may find that people are more sympathetic than you expect. (My own version of this has kind of an epic back story involving ER trips and brain scans, but the short version is I didn&#8217;t know my constant headaches were migraines until a couple of years ago; I just thought I was a fucking wuss. When I got a proper diagnosis and realized that my &#8220;oh, it&#8217;s Wednesday&#8221; headache was most people&#8217;s &#8220;I might be having a stroke&#8221; headache, I felt way way better about saying &#8220;Hey, I have to rest today&#8221; and taking care of myself.) Of course, the simpler option is simply to say &#8220;I&#8217;m sick&#8221; when you need to skip something; it happens, everyone gets sick, and much as the black hole monster of grad school wants to deny it, you actually do get to stay home and rest when you&#8217;re sick.</p>
<p>I am rambling because I feel so passionately about this &#8212; the &#8220;gleeful masochism&#8221; of academia is in fact a profoundly ableist cultural norm. You can do grad school and practice your art and your craft and teach struggling students how to write without sacrificing yourself on the altar of Unstoppable Grad Student Who Can Do It All. You get to have a private life. You get to have a fallible body. You get to be an adult human being who can tell another adult human being, &#8220;I am sorry that I cannot attend this lecture, as I&#8217;m sick today.&#8221; You get to do all that and you still get to be a poet.</p>
<p>Sincerely,</p>
<p>Sweet Machine, MFA, PhD, D. Migraine Lore, M. Div. IBS recipes</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='620' height='379' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/ERfK6G_7SvY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5297/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5297/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5297&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/09/459-do-i-have-to-destroy-my-health-to-be-in-grad-school/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>211</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb3f946269ce1412c97f29ab9995db68?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sweet Machine</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/millay_magn.jpg?w=250" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Millay</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rutgerhauer.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Grad school.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#458: Things are great, so we don&#8217;t have to ever talk about feelings, right?</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/08/458-things-are-great-so-we-dont-have-to-ever-talk-about-feelings-right/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/08/458-things-are-great-so-we-dont-have-to-ever-talk-about-feelings-right/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 16:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Captain Awkward's Dating Guide for Geeks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Overthinking It]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feelings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks and recreation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[romance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5021</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Captain Awkward: My boyfriend and I are in our mid-twenties and have been together for about half a year. He treats me well, takes an interest in what I do and enjoy and is generally a good boyfriend. We have a lot of similar characteristics and the same silly sense of humor. When we [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5021&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_5285" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/lesliebinder.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5285" alt="Leslie Knope holding a big binder that says &quot;Bowling Comment&quot;" src="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/lesliebinder.png?w=300&#038;h=169" width="300" height="169" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;I made you this compilation of my thoughts and feelings. The agenda for our conversation is on Page 3. Please call my office to schedule our relationship discussion.&#8221;</p></div>
<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward:</em></p>
<p><em>My boyfriend and I are in our mid-twenties and have been together for about half a year. He treats me well, takes an interest in what I do and enjoy and is generally a good boyfriend. We have a lot of similar characteristics and the same silly sense of humor. When we first got together it was supposed to be a casual thing, but it ended up escalating into something more serious almost immediately. Right now we are together almost five days of the week and almost never go out alone. We sleep in a tangled pile. We are comfortable with just being in the same room doing our own thing. I have never pressured him into anything and neither has he, everything just happened. It feels SO nice and natural. He seems to enjoy it too.</em></p>
<p><em> I am developing some Serious Feelings for him and I can definitely imagine a future with this man, but I am not sure about what he wants from our relationship. I would definitely want to be with someone who wants to have a family and this is not something up for compromise. My problem is that both him and I are absolutely terrible at talking about emotional things. I even have trouble saying „I like you“ out loud, asking „where do you see this relationship going“ is something I feel is beyond me. I’ve tried to find a good moment to force myself to bring up this topic with him, but can’t seem to find one (or I can’t make myself to open my mouth). I’m also afraid that he will not be able to answer my questions for the same reasons (I know I’d have trouble with it). I don’t want to lose him and yet I don’t want to waste my time in a relationship that will not lead anywhere. </em></p>
<p><em> So I guess my question is, how do I get over this unnatural fear I have of talking about my feelings/relationship goals? Suppose I get over it, how do I make the conversation comfortable enough for him? Do you think it’s viable if we’re both funny the same way?</em></p>
<p><em>Miss Wordless</em></p>
<p><span id="more-5021"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_5286" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/letsdothisbinder.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5286" alt="Ann Perkins holds a binder with &quot;Let's Do This&quot; and a picture of a happy uterus." src="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/letsdothisbinder.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Not everyone appreciates the &#8220;I made you this binder of feelings &amp; reasons&#8221; approach.</p></div>
<p>Dear Miss Wordless:</p>
<p>If you are happy, you are not &#8220;wasting time&#8221; in a relationship that &#8220;will not lead anywhere.&#8221; You are learning to be in a relationship and enjoy the day to day of getting a lot of your needs met by someone cool and nifty who likes you and likes spending time with you. That ain&#8217;t nothing, and you should not feel guilty about enjoying yourself for as long as you are enjoying yourself. There is no one right way to be in a relationship, and if the two of you like to keep it light and seem to have similar styles of communication and humor, that can be great.</p>
<p>Being funny (and funny together) is really important and a great way of connecting. But if you&#8217;re going to be with someone your whole life and really do that whole in sickness and in health, for richer or for poorer, through illness and births and death and all the stresses and joys of living every part of this complex and amazing life you&#8217;ve been given, you will need more than funny.</p>
<p>Dark times come to us all. If you are very, very lucky, when you reach those dark times you will have someone who loves you to hold your hand and <a title="#190: The Sandwich Means “I Love You”: A Valentine." href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/02/13/190-the-sandwich-means-i-love-you-a-valentine/" target="_blank">wrap you in their love and support</a>, and remind you of your own worth. This love doesn&#8217;t have to necessarily come from a romantic partner to be real and true. Sometimes love is a sandwich. Sometimes it&#8217;s killing the giant bug that crawled out of a crack in the ceiling. Sometimes the toilet in the place you&#8217;re staying in on vacation is backed up, and love means driving you to a safe pooping sanctuary. B<a title="On vulnerability" href="http://www.ted.com/talks/brene_brown_on_vulnerability.html" target="_blank">eing vulnerable</a> is scary and hard sometimes. It carries risk of rejection. But it&#8217;s the only way that we can we connect with each other beyond the surface level and reap all the rewards of being truly seen and truly seeing someone else&#8217;s heart.</p>
<p>Fortunately you don&#8217;t have to lay out all of your thoughts/feelings/hopes/dreams at once. You don&#8217;t have to go right into deep heartfelt talks about THE FUTURE. Relationships don&#8217;t have to feel &#8220;intense&#8221; to be true and important and truly loving. You can use this relationship that is working and where you get along very well and spend all your time together to practice being vulnerable a little at a time and see what happens.</p>
<p>I think one thing that will help you learn to let your feelings cross the brain-mouth barrier is to practice being present in the moment and saying what&#8217;s on your mind in the moment.</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>I think I might love you but I don&#8217;t want to say so in case you don&#8217;t want a family or see us having a permanent future together</em>&#8221; is a lot for anyone to unpack in a relationship where you haven&#8217;t talked about feelings before. NOTHING is wrong with having any or all of those feelings, and you don&#8217;t or shouldn&#8217;t have to make your feelings smaller or more convenient in order to be with someone. But there is a lot of pressure and anxiety tied up in expressing them all at once and with such a strong future-emphasis. So start small, and start in the present, and start with expressing true thoughts and feelings you are having in a way that does not put pressure on the other person to feel any particular thing themselves.</p>
<ul>
<li>&#8220;<em>I am glad you came over tonight.&#8221;</em></li>
<li><em>&#8220;Thank you for making dinner.&#8221;</em></li>
<li><em>&#8220;I love sleeping next to you.&#8221;</em></li>
<li>&#8220;<em>I am feeling very happy right now.&#8221;</em></li>
<li>&#8220;<em>That feels really good.</em>&#8220;</li>
<li>&#8220;<em>That doesn&#8217;t feel good, can we stop?</em>&#8220;</li>
<li>&#8220;<em>I feel sad.&#8221;</em></li>
<li>&#8220;<em>I feel nervous.</em>&#8220;</li>
</ul>
<p>See what reactions you get. Does he smile? Does he reciprocate? Does he open up a bit? Does he make you feel glad and comfortable that you said something about how you were feeling? Then things are good.</p>
<p>Maybe next you can practice asking for specific things.</p>
<ul>
<li>&#8220;<em>Will you rub my back?&#8221;</em></li>
<li><em>&#8220;Can you make dinner tonight?&#8221;</em></li>
<li><em>&#8220;Can we do (that sex thing I like)?&#8221;</em></li>
<li><em>&#8220;Is there&#8217;s something you&#8217;d like to do today?</em>&#8220;</li>
<li>&#8220;<em>Does this feel good?</em>&#8220;</li>
<li><em>&#8220;I&#8217;d like to have a night to myself to catch up on reading. Can we talk tomorrow instead?&#8221;</em></li>
<li><em>&#8220;Will you be my date to x event?&#8221;</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Practice being honest about your feelings about what is happening <strong>now</strong> and checking in about his. Start with low-stakes, true things.</p>
<p>You say &#8220;we spend five days of the week together and almost never go out alone.&#8221; So one other suggestion I have to make things feel a bit less risky is that you do something to get back in touch with your solo life &#8211; spend a little solo time with your friends, make sure you do a hobby or art or sport or working at a goal that is yours alone and that brings you in touch with other people. I don&#8217;t know if it&#8217;s winter where you live, but I do know how tempting it is to curl up in the bundle of two and not motivate to go out and do things with others. That can be so great and comfortable, but right now if you&#8217;re feeling uncertain about relationship stuff s it can be good to get back in touch with the fact that a lot of people like you and want you to be happy.</p>
<p>These are the most basic baby steps, and I can&#8217;t script out your whole story for you. Maybe you have another year ahead of you before you can say &#8220;<em>I&#8217;m in love with you&#8221;</em> or blurt out &#8220;<em>I want to have kids and I am hoping you want to have kids with me and that we can do that together</em>&#8221; after an episode of Parks &amp; Rec. This is a good news/bad news situation &#8211; until you&#8217;re comfortable enough to talk about having kids with the purported father of those kids, you&#8217;re not ready to have kids.</p>
<p>I want to leave you with three thoughts.</p>
<p>1) There is no way to know ahead of time what someone else thinks and feels and wants. There is no code for figuring it out and therefore guarantee that they will be on the same page as you before you speak up. Despite an entire magazine industry devoted to &#8220;Top Signs He&#8217;s Ready To Commit&#8221; written by <a title="Marie Claire’s Rich tells you how to keep a guy’s attention." href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/09/11/marie-claires-rich-tells-you-how-to-keep-a-guys-attention/" target="_blank">people who have degrees in preserving the status quo from Dipshit University</a>, the tools you have at your disposal for sussing out another adult&#8217;s plans, hopes, and feelings are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Saying what you want and seeing how they respond.</li>
<li>Asking what they think and seeing what they say.</li>
</ul>
<p>Your question, and its mention of &#8220;sleeping in a tangled pile&#8221; (lovely image, by the way) and asking if I think it&#8217;s viable because your senses of humor match was a little bit about asking for top! signs! this will work out! I mean, yeah, it sounds like the guy is into being in your company, and &#8220;actions speak louder than words,&#8221; but I think it&#8217;s okay to want the words, too. (See .gif, below).</p>
<p>2) If you are a lady, that does not means that you have to do all the work of figuring out feelings and the future. You are not this guy&#8217;s FeelingsTutor. You&#8217;re the one who wrote, so probably you will be the one to start saying things like &#8220;I really like you.&#8221; If he&#8217;s a good guy and into you, he will make it very safe and comfortable to trust him with those things, and he will say stuff back, even if it&#8217;s hard for him, too. If you start opening up and suddenly feel like you&#8217;re dating a Michael Cera character (like an onion, with each layer made of more Michael Cera) who only has one emotional mode, abort!</p>
<p><a href="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ben-leslie-proposal.gif"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-5287" alt="Parks and Rec's Ben proposing to Leslie by saying &quot;I am deeply, ridiculously in love with you.&quot;" src="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ben-leslie-proposal.gif?w=300&#038;h=168" width="300" height="168" /></a>3) If you really know that you want to have kids someday, you gotta speak up about it sometime. Whatever that heart&#8217;s desire is &#8211; if it&#8217;s to live on a boat for a while or move to Finland or start a theater company or go back to school &#8211; you have to be able to say it out loud to the people who you want to really know you.</p>
<p>By saying it out loud*, you do take a risk. You risk that people will laugh at you, or not be on board. You risk that this person right in front of you will not be on Team You while you go after the things you want. You risk pain and disappointment.</p>
<p>By NOT saying it loud, you also risk never, ever getting what you want. Not because some evil nemesis put their evil boot down on your neck and stood in your way, but because you stayed silent, the people around you never knew what you wanted, and you never gave them a chance to actually be on your side or walk away from your side. And then time happened. Your silence + time + fear came in and stole your dreams from you, and then it was too late.</p>
<p>Every good thing that ever happens to us because someone said &#8220;Yes, let&#8217;s try it.&#8221; There is no love without courage, so be of good courage. Take your faults and walk into Camazotz. Take your passion and make it happen. Say &#8220;<em>I really care about you and want you to stay in my life</em>&#8221; to your boyfriend, and see what happens.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*can mean voice, text, email, letter, skywriting, or any form of expression.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5021/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5021/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5021&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/08/458-things-are-great-so-we-dont-have-to-ever-talk-about-feelings-right/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>98</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/lesliebinder.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Leslie Knope holding a big binder that says &#34;Bowling Comment&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/letsdothisbinder.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ann Perkins holds a binder with &#34;Let&#039;s Do This&#34; and a picture of a happy uterus.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ben-leslie-proposal.gif?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Parks and Rec&#039;s Ben proposing to Leslie by saying &#34;I am deeply, ridiculously in love with you.&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is an introvert? #456 &amp; #457: Communication Expectations</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/01/what-is-an-introvert-456-457-communication-expectations/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/01/what-is-an-introvert-456-457-communication-expectations/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 20:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Families]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Overthinking It]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communication styles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frequency of communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[introverts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[talking about feelings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5274</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello Captain Awkward team! Since I started college, my mother has been driving me crazy regarding calls home. Specifically, the frequency of my calls home. I am introverted and don&#8217;t express attachment and affection openly. In the beginning of college, if I didn&#8217;t call every single day to reassure her I was not dead in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5274&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_5275" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pondlifephone.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5275" alt="Doctor Who on the phone." src="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pondlifephone.jpg?w=300&#038;h=168" width="300" height="168" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Hello Bruce? I have these ideas about the nature of the universe and advisability of vigilantism that I&#8217;d like to talk through with you.&#8221;</p></div>
<p><em>Hello Captain Awkward team!</em></p>
<p><em>Since I started college, my mother has been driving me crazy regarding calls home. Specifically, the frequency of my calls home. I am introverted and don&#8217;t express attachment and affection openly. In the beginning of college, if I didn&#8217;t call every single day to reassure her I was not dead in a ditch somewhere, she&#8217;d go crazy. If I don&#8217;t pick up the phone when she calls within the 3rd ring, she thinks I&#8217;m ignoring her. She once even called campus police to report me as missing, all because I took a prolonged sleep to recover from an allnighter and didn&#8217;t think it was that big of a deal to call her! She&#8217;s gotten a lot better now but calls every 2 to 3 days is still very demanding for me, especially during midterms when I barely even have time to eat.</em></p>
<p><em>If I don&#8217;t call her for a week, she&#8217;ll get angry and then refuse to pick up her phone when I do call. So then, I don&#8217;t bother to call her (it&#8217;s immature behavior in my opinion) until she caves in and calls me, all upset because &#8220;You don&#8217;t love me anymore and don&#8217;t call me!&#8221; Gee I wonder why. I told her to get texting (she doesn&#8217;t have it) or check her email since I like reading over talking but she says those mediums aren&#8217;t good because &#8220;They aren&#8217;t as human as talking on the phone. Also, if you were kidnapped, texts and emailed could be falsified by your kidnappers so I won&#8217;t call the police in time to save you!&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;d rather be able to call her once a week, which is more reasonable for my schedule. She, however, sees this as me not appreciating and loving her anymore. She has a great fear of being a failure as a mother (I&#8217;m the eldest child) since she had a horrible relationship with her own mother. I&#8217;ve tried to reason with her but she just complains and whines about how I don&#8217;t love her enough to take the effort to call her. Her solutions are also ridiculous; she suggested I call her every time I use the bathroom, which is gross to me and a bad idea for a klutz who has dropped phones into the toilet multiple times.</em></p>
<p><em>It doesn&#8217;t help very much that I hardly see her since my school is far away. She also doesn&#8217;t understand I don&#8217;t run in crowds that would likely get me kidnapped. Since I am currently going through a bout of being ignored, do you have any suggestions for improving the situation once she gives in and calls me?</em></p>
<p>Hello, Tired Introvert:</p>
<p>First, being introverted and &#8220;preferring not to express attachment and affection openly&#8221; are <span style="text-decoration:underline;">two different things</span>.</p>
<p><span id="more-5274"></span></p>
<p><strong>Introverted</strong> = You need a lot of time alone, and being around people too much can sap your energy. If you are around people for long periods of time, you will likely need a lot of alone time to recharge.</p>
<p><strong>Not expressing affection &#8220;openly&#8221;</strong>= It&#8217;s own separate thing. Consider it a preference, or a habit. A tendency. You don&#8217;t like to talk about emotional stuff. That&#8217;s not a good thing or a bad thing, it just is. But it&#8217;s not because you are an introvert. Neurotypical introverts (this one included) can express themselves just fine in words, get along with people just fine, make friends just fine, and even have highly interactive jobs just fine. We just need to balance those interactions with plenty of alone time to recharge. It takes practice sometimes, or doesn&#8217;t come naturally sometimes, or is downright hard and scary sometimes, sure, but it is a skill or mode of expression that can be learned. This isn&#8217;t just for you, Letter Writer, but I don&#8217;t want to see any more &#8220;<em>I am an introvert, so I <strong>can&#8217;t</strong> ________&#8221;</em> questions.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get to your actual question, which is about how to set boundaries with your mom.</p>
<p>You can deliver this script in the form of an email, if you like.</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Mom, we need to come up with a new plan for how to handle phone calls, because the way things are now is really stressing me out. I want us to be able to catch up and be involved in each other&#8217;s lives, but I need it to be a more scheduled, regular thing and not cause so much anxiety and fighting. Let&#8217;s schedule a weekly time to talk. _____ day at _____ time works for me.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>She&#8217;ll probably reply with the usual &#8220;YOU DON&#8217;T LOVE ME&#8221; stuff.</p>
<p>Say, &#8220;<em>Wow, that&#8217;s really not true. But I&#8217;ll talk to you on _____ at ______ time</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Then call her at the agreed-upon time. If she sulks and ignores you, say &#8220;<em>Well, mom, I was really looking forward to catching up. I guess I&#8217;ll call you (next week) at (usual time)</em>.&#8221; And then do it. If you have time, send her a periodic text or voice mail or piece of physical mail to let her know what&#8217;s going on as well.</p>
<p>And don&#8217;t pick up the phone any other time she calls. Let it go to voice mail. If your phone allows you to set things so her calls automatically go to voicemail, turn that thing on. &#8220;<em>She thinks that if I don&#8217;t pick up by the third ring, I&#8217;m ignoring her.</em>&#8221; Yep, you&#8217;ll be ignoring her.</p>
<p>If she calls 10,000 times and you pick up on the 10,001st time, you&#8217;re teaching her that it takes 10,001 calls to get your attention. If you do want to respond somehow, email her later that day- &#8220;<em>Got your phone call, sorry, I don&#8217;t have time to talk &#8211; what&#8217;s up?</em>&#8221; Lesson: You won&#8217;t talk on the phone at all hours, but you will respond quickly in case there is an actual emergency.</p>
<p>If she calls campus police to check on you, let them check. Say &#8220;<em>I&#8217;m fine, but my mom freaks out if she doesn&#8217;t hear from me every day. Sorry she bothered you.</em>&#8221; It&#8217;s not the end of the world. Checking on students for worried parents is part of their job.</p>
<p>The kidnapping thing&#8230;.just&#8230;.wow. I mean, she is right that voice verification is considered Proof of Life, but her anxiety about you being far away is HER anxiety, and she needs to find other ways to deal with that and channel it.</p>
<p>One time when I was studying abroad, I went on a solo trip during a school break and my mom freaked out about the fact that I was going to be traveling alone. And then I said &#8220;<em>Everyone on my program is leaving for the break, so if I stayed here I would also be alone.</em>&#8221; Kind of broke her brain, that one did. She used to also do bed-checks at very early morning hours, to make sure I was actually sleeping in my bed when I was supposed to be. Since this was in the ancient era before cell phones, she would call on the shared phone, which would wake my roommate up as well as me. Since this was also in the days before caller ID, my roommate had the great idea to treat it like an obscene phone call. She blew a whistle into the phone and then said &#8220;STOP CALLING FREAK, WE DON&#8217;T WANT TO SUCK YOUR FEET.&#8221; (The gross thing is, we *were* getting obscene phone calls. Some guy would call the Georgetown freshman dorms pretending to be your roommate&#8217;s dad, and then it would get&#8230;icky).</p>
<p>Parents worry, and depending on how long you&#8217;ve been at school your mom might need some time to adjust to you being away, but making a plan to check in regularly and then sticking to that plan (and texting her/emailing her in advance if the plan is going to change) should go a long way to settle her down.</p>
<p>She won&#8217;t like it. She will resist, and do everything she can to test the boundaries, and you&#8217;ll probably hear a lot more mean/anxious/guilt-inducing words, but eventually I think she will figure out that her kid loves her and will call her once/week for a meaningful amount of time and use email the rest of the time. Your mom is a grownup, and she can figure out how to deal with her anxiety/fill her time/find meaningful human contact on her own.</p>
<p>Also, &#8220;<em>I&#8217;m worried that I&#8217;ll be a failure as a parent, so take my calls all the time and reassure me that I am not</em>&#8221; is TOO MUCH to put on your kids, jeez. Maybe a trip to the student counseling center is in order for you sometime when you get a moment, because that is a lot of outsized expectations to digest.</p>
<div id="attachment_5277" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/batman.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5277" alt="Batman on the Batphone" src="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/batman.jpg?w=300&#038;h=300" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Yeah, this is kind of an emergencies-only line.&#8221;</p></div>
<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward,</em></p>
<p><em>I find myself in an unusual position. I&#8217;m a person who is extremely extroverted, talks a lot, discusses all my feelings, needs, wants, and typically hashes things through with my &#8220;Team You&#8221; to handle my life&#8217;s issues. I wear my feelings on my sleeve, want to make friends with everyone and their rubber duck, and am generally an explosion of silliness and glitter.</em></p>
<p><em>My problem, however, is that for the first time, I&#8217;m dating an introvert. A SHY introvert! Earlier in life, I figured out that I may be overwhelming at times. Usually I can pick up on cues with introverted friends of mine, and tend to pipe down/give them space. However, because this is a romantic relationship, I&#8217;ve run into issues that I haven&#8217;t run into before.</em></p>
<p><em>It&#8217;s very difficult to know my partner&#8217;s feelings. He tells me that he finds great difficulty in articulating his thoughts, and tends to stumble over his words a lot. He has mentioned that he&#8217;s had issues in previous relationships because he has times where he &#8220;shuts down.&#8221; And let me tell you, Capt&#8217;n, I&#8217;ve experienced it once, and it was horrifically painful. I felt like he didn&#8217;t care anymore! I kinda cajoled him into talking about it, because goshdarnit, you can&#8217;t not talk about problems! He says that it&#8217;s not that he doesn&#8217;t care anymore, it&#8217;s just that he gets an overload of stimuli at certain times and he becomes irritated because of it. The best solution I could come up with was for him to give me a code word when he&#8217;s in this mood, and I can just vacate and give him his space. He didn&#8217;t want to do this though! He said he didn&#8217;t want to hurt my feelings by indicating that he wants me to go away (which is how he feels this solution would come across).</em></p>
<p><em>He is currently seeing a therapist and is getting medical treatment for his depression. He has a lot of issues that he&#8217;s working through, this particular issue included.</em></p>
<p><em>He genuinely is a sweet, funny, and caring person, but I struggle with not knowing his moods or mindsets. I&#8217;ve asked him to talk to me more, and he tries, but I know it&#8217;s out of his comfort zone. </em></p>
<p><em>I understand that since he is an introvert he may well have different needs than me. I&#8217;d love to have some tips about how to make sure someone is getting what they need even when they don&#8217;t really tell me (and how to get what I need too!). What can I do to help my extreme extroversion and his introversion/shyness work together harmoniously?</em></p>
<p><em>Yours,</em><br />
<em>Extrovert McExtroversion</em></p>
<p>Dear Extrovert McExtroversion:</p>
<p>I think the code word was a great suggestion. I mean, which is worse &#8211; telling you he wants to be alone for a bit to cool off/figure out what he wants to say using a prearranged signal, or totally shutting down and making you play guessing games about his moods and what he needs? He might not be good at using all his words, but one word? He can&#8217;t give you one word, or like, a hand signal<strong> </strong>that says &#8220;<em>Circle back to me in an hour?</em>&#8221; Option One probably won&#8217;t hurt your feelings. Option Two is <strong>actually hurting your feelings</strong> and making things harder for you.</p>
<p>By not giving you that, he&#8217;s basically setting you up for what he (says that he) least wants: A period of guessing games where you try to suss out what&#8217;s going on and ask him a lot of questions and he gets more and more shut down and avoidant.</p>
<p>Also, to echo the first question from today, being an introvert and being avoidant of emotional conversations (or being an extrovert and good at emotional conversations) are not the same thing. Obviously you can be both introverted and have trouble communicating about emotions. You can be extroverted and talk about everything except emotions. Having trouble understanding and communicating about emotions can be part of being non-neurotypical and require real help  to figure out and navigate when relating to other people &#8211; it can feel like and be an actual disability. But introverted tendencies do not cause and are not even directly correlated to trouble with communication skills.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m glad your partner is working with a therapist and trying out some stuff, and one of the things he should maybe try working on is recognizing when he gets in &#8220;don&#8217;t talk to me&#8221; mood and sending out some kind of clear signal that you can respond to.</p>
<p>I totally get the difference between being a processor who shows their work in figuring out emotional things and being someone who considers quietly and would prefer to speak aloud only when a decision has been made. It&#8217;s like if The Doctor were dating Batman. The Doctor needs to let Batman know &#8220;<em>I want to hear what you have to say even if you aren&#8217;t sure about it, &#8216;haven&#8217;t decided yet&#8217; would be an acceptable answer if that&#8217;s where you really are with things</em>&#8221; and Batman needs to let The Doctor know &#8220;<em>Hey, could you think out loud somewhere else right now? I have important brooding to do</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>I realize I just picked two of the least emotionally healthy characters in pop culture for that example, so for a less dysfunctional example, I give you this great post by Commander Logic about how s<a title="Our Relationship Communication Skills are Awesome....Too Awesome?" href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/08/09/326-our-relationship-and-communication-skills-are-awesome-too-awesome/#more-3770">howing more of the work doesn&#8217;t always mean *doing* more of the work</a>.</p>
<p>You asked for tips. <strong><em>&#8220;I&#8217;d love to have some tips about how to make sure someone is getting what they need even when they don&#8217;t really tell me (and how to get what I need too!)&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;m hoping readers can help here, because my tips are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Behave normally &#8211; like, be nice and kind to him, tell him when something is working and when something isn&#8217;t, ask him how his day was, tell him how yours was, tell him when you appreciate and enjoy something, and treat him as you would like to be treated. If you do that, are you enjoying the relationship? Then it&#8217;s working.</li>
<li>If you feel like he&#8217;s avoiding something &#8211; doesn&#8217;t really want to talk, being really monosyllabic, not wanting to be touched, seems upset (I&#8217;m picturing a cat hiding under the couch here), ask him <strong>once</strong>: &#8220;<em>Is there something you want to talk about or anything I can do?</em>&#8221; and if there isn&#8217;t, go do something else with your time. Call up Team You, go out, get those needs you have met elsewhere. That communicates both &#8220;<em>I care enough to try to pick up your signals</em>&#8221; and &#8220;<em>I don&#8217;t need you to fill my every need</em>&#8221; and also &#8220;<em>So if there is something you were really wanting to happen or on your mind, you can just tell me</em>.&#8221; If this starts to feel lonely and depressing instead of caring and like taking a needed break from each other, maybe this isn&#8217;t the relationship for you.</li>
<li>I don&#8217;t know how often you hang out, but schedule some time together that is not talkative. Reading together in the same room. Watching a movie together. My best roommates ever have understood that mornings = quiet time. A few weeks ago, Commander Logic and I had a very awesome chatty lunch where we caught up. Then we went to her place and each disappeared into our work, speaking only very occasionally over the course of three hours. It was great.</li>
<li>Assume that if there is some deep-seated need he has that he will find some way to communicate it to you. I think it is very productive to be polite and considerate and respect people&#8217;s stated boundaries. I think it is very unproductive and exhausting to try to read your partner like he&#8217;s the weather or a Magic 8 ball or a palm and try to perfectly anticipate his needs. If he&#8217;s not saying stuff, then assume there is no Stuff. If he&#8217;s loudly Not Saying Stuff (by sighing a lot and obviously hoping that you&#8217;ll ask him about Stuff, and then claiming there is No Stuff when you do ask), then still assume there is No Stuff until he tells you WTF the Stuff is.</li>
<li>Get your needs met by asking for what you need. &#8220;<em>Partner, when you&#8217;re in shut-down mode, it feels really scary to me and I am afraid of saying or doing something to make it worse. Can you give me some signal &#8211; a code word, a gesture &#8211; that tells me that&#8217;s what&#8217;s happening so I can clear off for a bit? That would make me feel a lot better and give you the space to process. Also, when you come out of that mode, it would mean a lot to me if you would seek me out and show me some affection.</em>&#8221; It sounds like you are already good at this, so, keep awesome-ing.</li>
</ul>
<p>Commander Logic has good advice on how to start speaking up when it&#8217;s hard for you <a title="Sense and Sensibility and Saying Stuff Out Loud" href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/05/29/260-sense-and-sensibility-and-saying-stuff-out-loud/">here</a>, and I know in comments she has posted the Occasional Check-In &#8220;Name that Need!&#8221; Ritual that she and HusbandLogic do when they get crungry (cranky + hungry) or flaily and words start to fail them:</p>
<p>Are we&#8230;.hungry? Tired? In a kissing mood? Wanting to talk? Wanting to be quiet? Needing to use the bathroom? Too cold? Too hot? Coffee? Whiskey? Coffee with whiskey in it, then makeouts, then sleep? Awesome! Name that need!</p>
<p>Sometimes the Self is a tired, cranky toddler and needs to be coaxed gently to the table and fed for its own good, and a partner can help that. Sometimes what I have to express out loud is &#8220;<em>I am too hungry to make a decision about where to eat, please just pick something and I will be grateful</em>&#8221; or &#8220;<em>I am having a lot of feelings at the same time right now, need more time to process, let&#8217;s change subject now</em>.&#8221; Once in the early stages of dating I sent my boyfriend a text that just said &#8220;FEELINGS&#8221; and he texted back &#8220;Returned, with interest&#8221; and I smiled the whole rest of the day.</p>
<p>Your boyfriend is a person, not a project, and you are neither his parent or his Pygmalion. The whole relationship shouldn&#8217;t be about you coaxing affection and conversation out of him. That&#8217;s not an introvert/extrovert thing, that&#8217;s a do we fit? thing. So if it&#8217;s mostly working, let it work. If it&#8217;s mostly not working, ask for what would work for you and see if he can find a way to get you there.</p>
<p>Recommended resources about introversion:</p>
<ul>
<li><a title="Caring for Your Introvert" href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2003/03/caring-for-your-introvert/302696/" target="_blank">Caring for Your Introvert</a>, Jonathan Rauch</li>
<li><a title="Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World that Can't Stop Talking" href="http://www.thepowerofintroverts.com/" target="_blank">Quiet: The Power of Introverts</a> In A World That Can&#8217;t Stop Talking, Susan Cain. Her TED talk is <a title="Susan Cain: The Power of Introverts" href="http://www.ted.com/talks/susan_cain_the_power_of_introverts.html" target="_blank">here</a>.</li>
</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5274/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5274/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5274&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/01/what-is-an-introvert-456-457-communication-expectations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>242</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pondlifephone.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Doctor Who on the phone.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/batman.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Batman on the Batphone</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Post! What to expect when you call a helpline/hotline.</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/01/guest-post-what-to-expect-when-you-call-a-helplinehotline/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/01/guest-post-what-to-expect-when-you-call-a-helplinehotline/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 17:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Helpline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Support group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telephone line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Violence and Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volunteer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5271</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Back when we changed the format for submitting questions, I strongly encouraged people who were currently experiencing a crisis to call a hotline or helpline and talk to a friendly person rather than wait for me to sort through the bulging email box and get to their question. The questioners who wanted help  composing their [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5271&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div></div>
<p>Back when we changed the format for submitting questions, I strongly encouraged people who were currently experiencing a crisis to call a hotline or helpline and talk to a friendly person rather than wait for me to sort through the bulging email box and get to their question. The questioners who wanted help  composing their suicide notes, the questioners who had possibly just been sexually assaulted and wanted me to tell them if they really had been, the questioners who were literally holding ice packs to their faces in the aftermath of partner violence were definitely 100% Above My Pay Grade. It was unhelpful and dangerous for them to wait; it was overwhelming for me to try to run a crisis hotline out of my email.</p>
<p>The excellent PFC Marie pointed out that the prospect of calling a hotline was daunting and wouldn&#8217;t have necessarily occurred to her when she was in crisis mode, and suggested that we find someone who had worked on one to demystify the process. Thankfully, one of our community members stepped forward. Their experience is obviously not universal to every kind of hotline/helpline, but hopefully it will help people feel less nervous about picking up the phone. Hopefully other volunteers will weigh in and give a diversity of experiences and what to expect. The poster has asked to remain anonymous for this post, which is kind of the point of hotlines when you think about it.</p>
<div></div>
<div>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</div>
<div><span id="more-5271"></span></div>
<div>
<p>I currently volunteer with a helpline that focuses on survivors of sexual abuse. I have previously volunteered at a more general purpose helpline. I can only speak from my experiences, which are only from the volunteer side of the phone, and only within the UK (thus the &#8216;helpline&#8217; terminology!). Perhaps if the Captain is willing, this post can provide an opportunity for more perspectives from volunteers and callers in the comments.</p>
<p>OK, so to start with, for the most part helplines understand that calling them can be pretty daunting, and so often make a lot of effort to have information up on the web explaining their policies for handling calls (such as confidentiality, anonymity, not judging callers and so on, as well as other more practical details like freephone numbers and how long you can call for). If you&#8217;re considering calling or recommending a service and have the luxury of time to investigate, looking through their site is usually a decent first port of call. It also gives you a chance to look for something specific to your needs and preferences, such as an explicitly feminist organisation, or a local one, or one that specialises in suicide/bereavement/workplace issues/LGBT stuff/etc.</p>
<p>But you wanted the inside scoop, so&#8230; let&#8217;s go <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p>On the practical side first: phones are almost always staffed by &lt;em&gt;volunteers&lt;/em&gt;. The level of training provided can vary from a couple of short training sessions up to a quite intensive and thorough course, but you don&#8217;t end up a qualified therapist or anything remotely like it. Volunteer turnover tends to be pretty high, as this kind of volunteering is both emotionally demanding and time consuming. So your experiences could potentially vary a lot between organisations, and even within them.</p>
<p>Most organisations offer some combination of listening and information, by phone, email, IM and/or face to face. Some may offer additional services such as support groups, accompaniments to police stations or hospitals, safe housing, and other wondrous things, but I have no personal experience with those (and I imagine they vary immensely from place to place), so I&#8217;ll leave them aside in this post and concentrate on the &#8216;listening and information&#8217; side.</p>
<p>&#8216;Information&#8217; will usually be a case of giving you the details of other services you&#8217;ve said you want &#8211; for example low cost counselling, housing, sexual health care, other phone lines, etc. Depending on the training and policies of the place you&#8217;ve rung, the volunteer may also be able to talk you through things like exactly what&#8217;s involved getting a medical check up, reporting to the police, and other options that you may be considering and want to know more about.</p>
<p>Note: I can&#8217;t emphasise enough that policies really do vary. Some places are set up solely to provide specialist information (e.g. legal advice lines), while others &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; provide listening and won&#8217;t do the kind of thing I&#8217;ve described above. OK, onwards.</p>
</div>
<p>&#8216;Listening&#8217; means that we let you, the caller, direct the conversation to wherever you want to go &#8211; we don&#8217;t intrude with our own agendas, terminology, and interpretations. (If you seem unsure about how to start, we might ask &#8216;would it help if I asked you some questions?&#8217;. We won&#8217;t just go barging in). We&#8217;ll take what you say seriously, and not minimise it. We also won&#8217;t flinch or be shocked at anything you say, and we won&#8217;t leave you to deal with our second-hand distress. And unlike the Captain and crew here, we won&#8217;t weigh in with our advice and opinions. We &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; believe you, empathise, affirm that any Not Okay things you describe are indeed Not Okay, and support you.</p>
<p>&#8216;Listening&#8217; covers a lot of ground. It could be as simple as wanting to tell your story aloud and be heard and understood, whether for the first time or the hundredth. You could want to talk through some courses of action you&#8217;re considering. You could want reassurance that you&#8217;re not imagining things, going crazy, overreacting. You could want to problem solve, or be talked down from something, or simply kept occupied and distracted for a while, or just to not be alone while you cry.</p>
<p>You could not have a clue what you want exactly, and that&#8217;s fine too. We&#8217;ll work it out together.</p>
<p>In the end, it comes down to two people having a conversation, within a little bubble of safety constructed out of privacy and anonymity and the super clear boundaries that automatically come with the context. And that can be incredibly valuable &#8211; if I didn&#8217;t think that, I wouldn&#8217;t do it. But at the same time, we own no magic wands unavailable to mere mortals. In fact, in many ways we&#8217;re more limited in our ability to directly help than a good friend on Team You. We do our best to provide you with as much helpful information and support and encouragement as we can, and then we hope that that puts you, as the expert on your own life, in a good position to make whatever choices are best for you.</p>
<p>That doesn&#8217;t always feel like enough. We often wish we could do more, on all counts. Why can&#8217;t we give you sandwiches! Or somewhere to stay! Or &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;something&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;! But while our status as sympathetic but anonymous strangers to each other is limiting in some ways, it&#8217;s freeing in others. It allows us to just be there and listen in a way that someone who has direct involvement in a situation rarely can, and you can feel free to talk to us without worrying about the effects it will have on your life. It&#8217;s a unique dynamic, which can&#8217;t replace (or be replaced by) other important things in life, like friendships or therapy.<br />
So that&#8217;s the theoretical side of it. Now I want to get a little bit more personal.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re hesitating to call, then most of all I want you to know that we truly do want you to.</p>
<p>From the volunteer&#8217;s perspective, we&#8217;re sitting in that chair because we <strong>want</strong> the phone to ring. There are natural fluctuations in the number of calls you happen to receive on any given day, and that&#8217;s fine &#8211; some days are just going to be busier than others. But for the record, there are few experiences as utterly deflating here as clearing a space in your calendar to come in, dutifully prepping your aftercare in advance&#8230; and then having the phone be dead the whole time you&#8217;re there. You sit there staring at the phone, alternating trying to will it to ring with THE POWER OF YOUR MIND with trying to <strong>trick</strong> it into ringing by pointedly ignoring it. (And then comes the inevitable dance of: Wait, what&#8217;s wrong with me that I <strong>want</strong> someone to call me about something horrible? What am I, some kind of emotional vampire? I mean, perhaps no one calling because no one&#8217;s in distress! Oh wait, not that thing, the other thing. Fidget fidget). Busy shifts are the times you feel like you&#8217;ve actually done some good in the world, not to mention put your own personal time and activist energy to good use.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a &#8216;my situation can&#8217;t possibly be bad enough to merit a call to a HOTLINE, that&#8217;s only for REALLY SERIOUS EMERGENCY situations which is definitely not what I have&#8217; kind of a creature, I want to reach out to you and say&#8230; no. That&#8217;s seriously not how it works. There is no Minimum Trauma Height for this ride. I have never in my entire time on the phones begrudged a call for not meeting the required awfulness quotient.  I very strongly believe that everyone deserves to be able to have a conversation about something that&#8217;s bothering them, and to be able do so safely, on their terms, and without repercussions. Regardless of what your situation is and whether you consider it to be That Bad or not.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re not helpful to every person in every situation, but if we are, that&#8217;s more than enough for me to be truly glad that we&#8217;re speaking.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5271/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5271/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5271&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/01/guest-post-what-to-expect-when-you-call-a-helplinehotline/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>90</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
