<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>CaptainAwkward.com</title>
	<atom:link href="http://captainawkward.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://captainawkward.com</link>
	<description>Advice. Staircase Wit. Faux Pas. Movies.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 14:10:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='captainawkward.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>CaptainAwkward.com</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://captainawkward.com/osd.xml" title="CaptainAwkward.com" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://captainawkward.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>#467: How do I help my partner communicate better with his family?</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/16/467-how-do-i-help-my-partner-communicate-better-with-his-family/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/16/467-how-do-i-help-my-partner-communicate-better-with-his-family/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 14:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Families]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forced teaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sibling]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5374</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Cap&#8217;n, I don&#8217;t know how best to help my DH. This message follows us having a long, slightly drunk but happy and loving chat about his life. DH&#8217;s family history is complicated. His upbringing includes some things which, when we talk about them, he agrees were &#8220;probably abuse&#8221;, but explains that he&#8217;s somewhat normalised [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5374&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dear Cap&#8217;n,</em></p>
<p><em>I don&#8217;t know how best to help my DH. This message follows us having a long, slightly drunk but happy and loving chat about his life.</em></p>
<p><em>DH&#8217;s family history is complicated. His upbringing includes some things which, when we talk about them, he agrees were &#8220;probably abuse&#8221;, but explains that he&#8217;s somewhat normalised what happened to him, and tends to say it totally matter-of-factly, as though this were just how things are. His feelings &#8211; or lack of &#8211; are complicated by guilt. DH was born a sickly child, with complex medical needs that put a lot of strain on the family. His parents divorced partly due to the stress of it all. He did not cope well with his deformities or medical needs and his childhood was a mixture of being a bullying victim, being a bully, having serious anger issues and acting out. I&#8217;m sometimes amazed by the wonderful, loving, mentally balanced person he&#8217;s become without therapy or help.</em></p>
<p><em>DH doesn&#8217;t seem to know what sort of relationship he wants with his parents. He is amicable with them, visits his mother about once a month, enjoys talking to his father&#8230; but he won&#8217;t initiate contact, and he gets anxious if, for example, his mum tries to ask him to visit on short notice. At the same time, he&#8217;s just naturally bad at maintaining relationships and has asked me to help him keep in better contact with his gran and siblings. He&#8217;s never confronted either parent and even apologised to his father recently for being a &#8220;difficult child&#8221;.</em></p>
<p><em>At the same time, the abuse has only come out over a long time in small parts. and by the time I started to get the picture, we&#8217;d been together years and had started to build closer relationships with his parents. His mum in particular, who is always very kind and concerned and helpful, and I don&#8217;t know how to feel about her, or the FIL, or any of it. To be fair, DH doesn&#8217;t isn&#8217;t certain how he feels. He&#8217;s given me permission to ask his big sis for more info on their childhood, because his memory can cause him problems. She lives abroad though, and I&#8217;d feel weird asking by email.</em></p>
<p><em>Because of his relationship and memory difficulties, it&#8217;s my job to help him maintain contact with loved ones. But I don&#8217;t know how to do this where his parents are concerned. I don&#8217;t want to pressure him to get closer than he feels comfortable, but I also don&#8217;t want to be the woman that drives him from his family into hers, as his father&#8217;s second wife has started doing with him.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;d love some advice please!</em></p>
<p>This statement: &#8220;<em>Because of his relationship and memory difficulties, it&#8217;s my job to help him maintain contact with loved ones</em>.&#8221; from your letter set off my Yikes-o-meter. Yikes!</p>
<p>Here is my advice:</p>
<p>Do not volunteer to be the carrier for his communication and relationship with his family, or to sort out these memories. Do not email his sister. It is only &#8220;your job&#8221; if you choose it, and you get to choose to not make it your job.</p>
<p>You can be a sounding board.</p>
<p>You can be a listening ear.</p>
<p>You should not be an ambassador or a manager. And you don&#8217;t have to feel any particular thing. HE doesn&#8217;t have to feel any particular thing.</p>
<p>Even in much less extreme situations (history of abuse, memory problems, disability) men sometimes expect that women will do the emotional work of the relationship, up to and including remembering everyone in HIS family&#8217;s birthday and buying presents/sending cards/keeping in touch. I think this sets a bad precedent, where his messed up family issues are now something that are the present stuff of your relationship. I&#8217;m sure he feels great after this chat you guys had; he just transferred all responsibility for sorting out his messy past over to you and now you&#8217;re writing me for advice on how to do it when really HE could write in for advice (not necessarily here, but somewhere) on how to do it.</p>
<p>This is HIS family.</p>
<p>This is HIS history.</p>
<p>This is HIS thing to solve.</p>
<p>I think it is admirable that you want to help your husband, and admirable that he wants to get back in touch with people and start sorting things out. And I think there is no one perfect way that he has to feel about a history of abuse. It is possible for people to have very dysfunctional relationships as children that grow into much more mellow relationships as people age, get power and autonomy, and generally mellow out.</p>
<p>But it is on HIM to contact his sister, sort out his memories, and deal with them (with the help of a professional, if necessary), and keep in better touch with his gran and his siblings. &#8220;Terrible at maintaining relationships&#8221; isn&#8217;t an actual condition, it&#8217;s a series of choices that have turned into a habit.</p>
<p>The best way to get in touch with people you haven&#8217;t talked to in a while is to send a greeting. People love getting mail that isn&#8217;t bills, so maybe write a postcard. &#8220;<em>Dear _____, I hope you are well. I read/saw/ate/experienced this thing recently that made me think of you and remember the time that we _________. (Wife) and I are doing well, here is a thing that is new with me. Have a happy (upcoming holiday, season of the year), Love, Husband</em>.&#8221; Keep it light, and remember, if communication has really lapsed, the other people don&#8217;t know what to say or how to begin either, and will be grateful for you breaking the ice. Make the effort, say something brief and kind, and then keep sending responses when they respond back. It is honestly that simple: If you want to, you will do it. If you don&#8217;t want to, then don&#8217;t do it, but don&#8217;t expect your partner to magically make it happen for you. Either admit that you don&#8217;t want to do it and make peace with that, or work on the &#8220;I want to want to, I just haven&#8217;t figured it out yet&#8221; stuff with a therapist.</p>
<p>You can help by dropping stuff in the mail, or picking up postcards, or hunting down addresses, or even helping him come up with things to say, but you shouldn&#8217;t manage the entire process.</p>
<p>The problem of making an adult relationship with imperfect relatives is not unique to this guy, it&#8217;s something we all have to figure out for ourselves.</p>
<p>My advice is that your mantra becomes &#8220;<strong><em>I am always here to listen, and I will support any decision you make, but I am not comfortable (emailing your sister, sorting out your past, taking the lead on how you interact with your family).&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;m sure the community will have alternate perspectives to my initial &#8220;AW HELL NAW&#8221; reaction, I hope it will be helpful.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5374/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5374/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5374&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/16/467-how-do-i-help-my-partner-communicate-better-with-his-family/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>London Meetup April 20</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/london-meetup-april-20/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/london-meetup-april-20/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 14:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Meetups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meetups]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5369</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[London is meeting up again. Dear Awkward Army, London meetup next weekend, 20th April!  All welcome. 11:00 am onwards, Cafe in the Crypt, St Martin-in-the-Fields Church, Trafalgar Square, London WC2N 4JJ. The previous venue is closing, and this one has been recommended. The cafe is underground, and is accessed via stairs or lift, next to the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5369&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>London is meeting up again.</p>
<blockquote>
<div>
<div>
<div>Dear Awkward Army,</div>
<p>London meetup next weekend, 20th April!  All welcome.</p>
<p>11:00 am onwards, Cafe in the Crypt, St Martin-in-the-Fields Church, Trafalgar Square, London WC2N 4JJ.</p>
<p>The previous venue is closing, and this one has been recommended.</p>
<p>The cafe is underground, and is accessed via stairs or lift, next to the church on the left if you&#8217;re looking with your back to Trafalgar Square or the National Portrait Gallery. They have accessible toilets.</p>
<p>Map here: <a href="http://goo.gl/f1MnW" target="_blank">http://goo.gl/f1MnW</a></p>
<p>I have long brown hair and glasses.  I will bring my plush Cthulhu to use as a table marker.  It looks like this: <a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/7cb0/" target="_blank">http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/7cb0/<br />
</a></div>
<div>
<p>My email address is kate DOT towner AT gmail DOT com</p>
<p>As discussed at previous meetups, I am happy to teach people to knit, so if you want to start or want help, bring something along!  I am an intermediate rather than advanced knitter but I will do my best.</p>
</div>
<p>Next meetup is probably going to be the 1st of June, due to me having no free time in May.</p>
<p>We have a new Facebook group here to make it easier for people to keep track: <a href="http://www.facebook.com/groups/549571375087294/" target="_blank">http://www.facebook.com/groups/549571375087294/</a></p>
</div>
<p>Cheers,</p>
<p>Kate</p></blockquote>
<p>Have a great time. It&#8217;s awesome to see a regular thing happening.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5369/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5369/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5369&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/london-meetup-april-20/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#466: Possessive friend is weirding me out/A constructive conflict review.</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/466-possessive-friend-is-weirding-me-out/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/466-possessive-friend-is-weirding-me-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rejection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jealousy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The African Violet of Broken Friendship]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5362</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Captain Awkward, My friend N alternately acts like she feels threatened by me and like she wants to be me. It&#8217;s really creepy but I don&#8217;t know how to address it without sounding jealous and paranoid. I met her three years ago. We became close quickly, and she had a crush on me, which [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5362&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward,</em></p>
<p><em>My friend N alternately acts like she feels threatened by me and like she wants to be me. It&#8217;s really creepy but I don&#8217;t know how to address it without sounding jealous and paranoid.</em></p>
<p><em>I met her three years ago. We became close quickly, and she had a crush on me, which I suspect was a nice distraction from the awful breakup she was going through. She invited me on a camping trip hoping to hook up with me, but was surprised that bringing a second woman along meant she was no longer the only woman in an otherwise all-male group, and she was no longer the group&#8217;s tomboy because I have more camping experience. Several guys hit on me, including her ex. She spent the whole weekend sulking and making passive aggressive comments.</em></p>
<p><em>I thought her resentment would subside when I started dating someone, but she became really possessive of my boyfriend. They&#8217;ve never dated, but sometimes play-fight when they drink. My boyfriend and I both practice martial arts, and our rather hilarious how-did-you-two-meet story involves a fight club. Often when N and I are meeting someone new, I mention my boyfriend&#8217;s name. The other person asks, &#8220;Oh, who&#8217;s that?&#8221; Before I can answer, much less tell our story, N interrupts me with, &#8220;That&#8217;s her boyfriend, who ***I*** introduced her to, who I fight in the street! I&#8217;m a street fighter!&#8221; and she tells the story of that time she tried to fight my boyfriend, but fell and twisted her ankle and he carried her home. Then she talks about herself at length. If this new person is male, she doesn&#8217;t let me get a single word in edgewise. If a guy hits on me, she pouts and starts up the passive-aggression. She also tries to one-up me on comics trivia, which she only got into after meeting me.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve tolerated this because she&#8217;s a great friend when sober. But lately, we only see each other at parties, and her behavior is getting more obnoxious. Recently she interrupted me talking about work to tell the &#8220;street fighting&#8221; story to people who had already heard it a million times, while positioning her chair in front of me so that her back was to me and I was physically excluded from the group. Later she glared at me, sat on my boyfriend&#8217;s lap, and talked about how great he is.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve asked my boyfriend to deliberately invite me back into conversations when she excludes me, and to not make physical contact with her. I don&#8217;t know what to say to her though, and our once-close friendship is becoming a sad competition where no one wins.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8211;Not-Single, Not-White Female</em></p>
<p><span id="more-5362"></span></p>
<p>How deep do you want to go into working this out?</p>
<p>I ask because their are two paths you can go by.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Path #1:</span></p>
<p>&#8220;<em>N, I&#8217;m really not feeling our friendship lately, and I&#8217;d prefer that we not hang out anymore. I realize that this isn&#8217;t good news, but it&#8217;s the best decision for me. I will do my best not to make it weird at (group events), as in, let&#8217;s say a quick hello and then keep the interaction to a minimum.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>If that seems too permanent, try &#8220;<em>let&#8217;s take a break from hanging out</em>.&#8221; This won&#8217;t land well, no matter how you say it, but if that&#8217;s how you feel it&#8217;s better and less cruel than drifting away and waiting for her to catch on.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Path #2:</span></p>
<p><em>&#8220;The specific thing (specific thing) you did the other night kind of weirded me out. What&#8217;s going on with that?&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Rules for constructive conflict when you want to repair a relationship:</p>
<ul>
<li>Keep it to one or two specific recent incidents, not an entire list of grievances.* Not because those grievances aren&#8217;t real, but listing all of them can be overwhelming and immediately put the person on the defensive. Over time you can work on the whole gestalt of the relationship. The first time you bring up a conflict, keep it simple and short.</li>
<li>Emphasize how whatever it is affected your specific recent feelings (Don&#8217;t speak in generalities or patterns or get into the history of competitiveness &#8211; it makes no one look or feel good).</li>
<li>Do not make any assumptions or suggestions as to why. Facts only. &#8220;<em>The thing you did hurt my feelings/bothers me. Your friendship is valuable to me, so I thought you should know and have a chance to apologize or explain/so I thought we should talk about it and see if we can&#8217;t work it out</em>.&#8221; Bonus: This makes the other person do the work of piecing it together and offering an explanation.</li>
</ul>
<p>Her answer might lead you back to Path 1, but if you think it might be worth delving into, give it a try and see what she says. It is unlikely she will admit jealousy or vulnerability, but you can tell whether this is salvageable by her response.</p>
<p><strong>Salvageable:</strong> &#8221;<em>Whoa, sorry, now that I think of it that was really out of line. I will not do that anymore.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p><strong>Unsalvageable</strong>: &#8220;<em>God, why are you so paranoid and jealous?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>Because these behaviors are centered around your boyfriend, it&#8217;s good to give him a heads up, and his reaction will also be telling.</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Boyfriend, I think I am going to take a break from hanging out with N. She is getting on my nerves</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>or</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Boyfriend, I am going to ask N. to stop telling the fight club story (for example). It&#8217;s crossed a line into making me really uncomfortable</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>You don&#8217;t have to get into his behaviors, again, stick with facts and don&#8217;t overexplain yourself or justify. His reaction will also be telling.</p>
<p><strong>Supportive</strong>: &#8220;<em>That&#8217;s sad, but you do what you need to and I will back you up.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><strong>Unsupportive:</strong> &#8220;<em>Why u so jealous and unfair?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>Things I would let go:</p>
<ul>
<li>Comics trivia. Does it matter how we get into comics trivia? If we find out that we love comics trivia, we get to be just as into it as the person who first invited us there. In fact, let go of the entire question of who was in what group first.</li>
<li>The entire question of interrupting when you get hit on by someone. There&#8217;s no way to control what other people (hitters-on) do or feel, and no way to bring this up that makes you look good, i.e., talking about this will make it seem like you actually <strong>are</strong> in competition for male attention and keeping score about such things. Are you? If her behavior is as rude/interrupty/obvious/strange as you say, people can tell what&#8217;s up and make their own decisions about how they want to engage her. A dedicated hitter-on will circumvent her.</li>
<li>Her past crush on you, unless she brings it up. Sometimes we have crushes on people we&#8217;d really like to be like. The graceful thing to do is to pretend it never happened and let her save face.</li>
<li>Who is better at camping.</li>
</ul>
<p>That leaves: Interrupting and one-upping you in conversation (God hates a story-topper), telling the fight club story over and over again (this might genuinely be an oversight that can be corrected with a &#8220;I don&#8217;t want to embarrass you, but did you realize you tell that story every single time? It might be time to let that one rest,&#8221; ignoring you/shutting you out whenever a dude is around or physically shunning you out of a conversation by placing her back to you (this behavior is truly annoying), and behaving territorially around your boyfriend (which I imagine is hard behavior to pin down, but you know it when you see it.)</p>
<p>The things on the bulleted list, in my opinion, cross over into the &#8220;Someone is getting on my nerves, now <strong>everything about them</strong> is part of the story of how they get on my nerves&#8221; territory. You&#8217;re over-justifying somewhat, and I think fairness and good sense mean doing some healthy separation between behaviors she is doing &#8220;at you&#8221; and behaviors that she is not. I think it&#8217;s also important to remember that while these behaviors have been going on for a while and in some cases date back to the beginning of your friendship, when you are trying to have constructive conflict with someone the clock restarts when you bring up the problem. Someone who is actually your friend gets some time to react and try to change the behavior.</p>
<p>The grievances on the bulleted list do have their uses in asking a question: If these issues date back to the beginning of the friendship, do you actually like her and want her in your life?  If no, then script #1 is the way to go.</p>
<p>There is no awesome way to handle this where everyone gets out unscathed and with their feelings and self-image totally intact, but remember, IT&#8217;S ALREADY WEIRD. I trust you that something is off here. You are just putting a name to a weirdness you didn&#8217;t make. Friends don&#8217;t always behave perfectly, and sometimes they tread on your toes without realizing it, and a cool friend will recognize when she&#8217;s been given an opportunity to make things right. If she responds favorably things may be salvageable with a little time to heal bruised egos. If she doubles down on the behavior that&#8217;s bothering you, it only confirms that you made the right decision to put some distance in the relationship.</p>
<p>*I am talking about constructive conflict in interpersonal relationships, not activism. There is a difference between repairing a friendship between equals and seeking justice, where the historical record of abuses is necessary no matter how uncomfortable it makes someone. If someone is your friend, the suggested advice is a way to ask for what you need while taking care of their feelings a little bit. In a situation with extreme power imbalances and a history of injustice, the oppressed person does not have to take care of the feelings of the oppressor, and indeed &#8220;tone policing&#8221; or &#8220;I would give you justice if you just asked more nicely&#8221; is a <a title="Derailing for Dummies: Google Cache" href="http://birdofparadox.wordpress.com/derailing-for-dummies-google-cache-reconstruction/" target="_blank">derailing tactic</a>. I just want to be clear about that from the get-go.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5362/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5362/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5362&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/466-possessive-friend-is-weirding-me-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#465: Life after Darth</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/14/465-life-after-darth/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/14/465-life-after-darth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 18:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Darth Vader Boyfriend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manipulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rejection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breakup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[darth vader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Explaining the world 1 Star Wars reference at a time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5359</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi there, An online friend and I were innocent email buds. One day, we start DMing which leads to texting/phone call. It gets sexual. Tells me he has a live in girlfriend but doesn&#8217;t ever say &#8220;maybe we shouldn&#8217;t go there.&#8221; It progresses to constantly talking, texting, gchatting. 2 weeks after we started he flew [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5359&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_5360" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 348px"><a href="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/darth-vader-in-love.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5360  " alt="A man and woman dressed as Darth Vader holding hands on a crowded street." src="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/darth-vader-in-love.jpg?w=338&#038;h=360" width="338" height="360" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image from <a href="//www.likecool.com/Darth_Vader_in_Love--Pic--Gear.html'">likecool.com</a></p></div>
<p><em>Hi there,</em><br />
<em>An online friend and I were innocent email buds. One day, we start DMing which leads to texting/phone call. It gets sexual. Tells me he has a live in girlfriend but doesn&#8217;t ever say &#8220;maybe we shouldn&#8217;t go there.&#8221; It progresses to constantly talking, texting, gchatting. 2 weeks after we started he flew here for a weekend.</em></p>
<p><em>Knew he had a gf, he told me they had major issues ever since she moved in. I asked him to please break up with her and figure that out ASAP. He went home and 2 days later he told me he would regret leaving if he didn&#8217;t try to fix their relationship. But wanted to try with me too. The waffling about what he wanted continued for 4 months. We saw each other again, talked constantly. We&#8217;d both try to cut each other off at points, it NEVER stuck.</em></p>
<p><em>Throughout I would threaten to tell her, push him to leave. I regret all the manipulation. In the fall, he decided that he couldn&#8217;t handle it. He cut it off, came crawling back. I let him. He&#8217;d become my emotional crutch. I fell into deep depression, constantly beating myself up. </em></p>
<p><em>Finally he said I severely hurt him by threatening to tell her, he could never really forgive me, give me a real chance. I said I&#8217;m done, cut off contact. Though did demand he tell her. I wanted him to get left. He did tell her, they have stayed together so far.</em></p>
<p><em>So was left feeling insane and sad. I did some controlling things that I&#8217;m not proud of. Jerkbrain: I&#8217;m an awful person who not only hurt this man but someone else too. I acted absolutely unreasonable on more than one occasion with this situation.</em></p>
<p><em>How I can start to forgive myself? Some people may always think I&#8217;m seriously shitty and I have to get over that but having a really hard time being okay with everything. Especially because I really did care for him. We had some seriously intense emotional and physical chemistry and I really thought I loved him at one point. I know this pit of despair may eventually dissipate but I am so ashamed of myself and tired of feeling like I&#8217;m the bad one.</em></p>
<p><em>And her friends have openly cried for revenge against me and told me I should be scared. They have stayed together so I guess I can understand why I&#8217;m the target and not him but it&#8217;s really frustrating that that&#8217;s the tactic. Which is my other question, how do I reconcile my desire for justice against him? I am just so pissed that he&#8217;s essentially had no consequences.</em></p>
<p><em>Thanks.</em></p>
<p><span id="more-5359"></span></p>
<p>Good news, there are a few people in this story who deserve the &#8220;bad one&#8221; title more than you.</p>
<p>#1 is Cheater McCheaterson, who can&#8217;t just fucking cheat but has to also drag you along on the entire rollercoaster of his dysfunctional relationship and its aftermath. He was the one with a girlfriend, and he was the one with a greater responsibility to her, either to pass on a relationship with you if that was their agreement and his choice, or to make a clean break with her. He was totally capable of telling you &#8220;<em>You are awesome, but I have a girlfriend, so I don&#8217;t think we should chat so much</em>.&#8221; He was totally capable of telling her, &#8220;<em>I met someone and I want to explore that, even if it means we break up</em>.&#8221; He chose neither of those things, because he wanted to have a girlfriend and a relationship with you and ride everything out for as long as possible. It&#8217;s not shocking that things got messy, and he doesn&#8217;t have to be bad or evil to get in over his head, but he did not help this situation. I don&#8217;t think your threatening to tell his girlfriend (or even actually telling her) would have made much of a difference in the end. It&#8217;s a weak position where the only strong play you really have is to get the hell out of there and leave them to each other.</p>
<p>#2, #3, #4 are anyone who tells you you should &#8220;be scared&#8221; because you fell in love with a dude who spun you a lot of confusing lies and empty promises.</p>
<p>The Darth Vader boyfriend or girlfriend isn&#8217;t necessarily evil or deliberately malicious. We&#8217;ve talked a lot here about <a title="Friday Questions about Darth Vader &amp; FEELINGS______." href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/03/16/friday-questions-about-darth-vader-feelings______/">warning signs</a>, and those are certainly red flags for when you are getting involved with someone, but for me the characteristic that makes something a Darth Vader situation can only be seen afterward, when you see how much you strayed from yourself (your own best interests, your own ethics, your own standards for how you want to be treated) and how often you <strong>made excuses</strong> for the other person&#8217;s behaviors to preserve the relationship. My Darth Vader was not awesome in his behavior, and was quite manipulative, but what makes me look back with shame and horror was my own total desire to be manipulated and hear only what I wanted to hear and also behaviors that tended toward, frankly, stalking. Darth Vaders, however they work, create an altered headspace where we are not our best selves. And while we are always responsible for our actions, we have to find a way to forgive ourselves in order to get free of that headspace.</p>
<p>Right now, the only things that fix this are time, distance, and sitting with some uncomfortable truths until you gain something like perspective and can tell a story about this that doesn&#8217;t hurt.</p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Cut off contact completely with this guy and everyone who knows him, including these friends of his girlfriend. Use whatever e-blocking tools you have to do, but do whatever you can to make sure you travel in completely separate worlds. You can&#8217;t worry about threats if you don&#8217;t know that threats are happening because everyone involved in this story is dead to you.</p>
<p><strong>Most importantly:</strong> <strong>Don&#8217;t try to be friends. </strong></p>
<p>You&#8217;re not friends, and you won&#8217;t be friends. The best part of you wants to find a way to preserve the good in all of this, and to make everything feel less wasted and wrong. Like, if you can be friends, it will all have been worth it. Something can be saved! Beware this instinct. Mostly what gets saved is his ability to believe that he&#8217;s not a bad guy, and his ability to reach out to you for emotional support and keep you engaged in his drama. What gets lost is your ability to put it behind you, by getting as angry as you need to get before you can heal. It keeps the little jolts of attention, and let&#8217;s face it, addiction going as the texts and messages come in or leave you bereft when they don&#8217;t come in.</p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Repeat this until you believe it: <strong>Having great chemistry does not by itself make someone a good partner for you.</strong> People have to be kind, and considerate, and respect boundaries, and when it comes down to it, they have to choose you.</p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t a story about how you would be together if it wasn&#8217;t for this lady and her threatening friends, this is a story about a guy who liked you well enough but didn&#8217;t want to be with you. You were actually involved, even if you didn&#8217;t have some kind of official relationship status called &#8220;girlfriend&#8221; or &#8220;primary partner&#8221; or whatnot. It is a break-up, so <a title="Reader Question #16:  The Golden Retriever/Kwisatz Haderach of Love" href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/02/09/reader-question-16-the-golden-retrieverkwisatz-haderach-of-love/" target="_blank">mourn it like a break-up</a>. Give yourself permission to feel sad, and bereft, and royally fucked over by fates.</p>
<p>Chemistry (love, lust, that instant recognition that here be your people, &#8220;intensity&#8221;) does mess with people, and people treat it like some inexorable force that temporarily abrogated all decision-making skills and swept them away. You aren&#8217;t the first person to be here, nor is he, nor was I when it was my turn to be in these shoes, but eventually the cloud clears and the question of &#8220;should we actually be together&#8221; comes up. Are you actually together? Would this wishy-washy guy who didn&#8217;t choose you in the end actually make a good partner? The answer to both of these is no. If you were supposed to be together, you would be together, and it would have gone easier than this.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not the kindest or most comfortable thought, but it&#8217;s important to get yourself out of the headspace of &#8220;<em>If only&#8230;.!&#8221;</em> and worry over the good times you had and try to stretch them to cover you now. <strong>Feeling</strong>: We were so great together! If only! <strong>Fact:</strong> But he didn&#8217;t choose me, and we are not together.</p>
<p>The first time you teach yourself to put the factual wet blanket on those feelings, it really hurts. Because you are basically taking The Golden Retriever of Love to the vet and &#8220;sending it to live on a nice farm where there are horses&#8221; or whatever your parents told you was the euphemism for &#8220;we killed the dog when you were at school.&#8221; Murdering hope fucking HURTS. But this guy has shown you again and again that he is not a good repository for those hopes, and having hope where he is concerned does not help you. Over time, if you can get in the habit of nixing the obsessive &#8220;But if only!&#8221; thoughts as soon as they come up, the fact of &#8220;<em>But we&#8217;re not together</em>&#8221; gets a friend, and that friend is &#8220;<em>And I only want to be with people who really want to be with me, and who will come at me correct.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p><strong>Step 3</strong>: Letting go also means letting go of the desire for revenge. The desire for his life to fracture the way it feels your has is understandable, but it keeps you engaged with him. It doesn&#8217;t seem fair, but it is actually entirely, cruelly, beautifully fair: .His reward or punishment is exactly the same as everyone&#8217;s &#8211; he has to live in his own skin and find a way to move forward with his life.</p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> It&#8217;s not a good idea to tell his girlfriend what happened, no matter how much you may want her to know, but tell SOMEONE. Deal with this overall cloud of depression you&#8217;ve got going on by dealing with it as depression. Get counseling. Tell someone the whole story, the highs, the lows, the hopes, the feeling that something beautiful was completely twisted and wasted, the missing piece in your day that used to be filled by this drama and how nothing feels right afterwards. A therapist or counselor can sort through what happened and help you take ownership of only what is yours (what can be learned from and changed in the future) and let go of what belongs to other people (his responsibility toward his girlfriend). Speak, and get it out of your system. Be good to yourself.</p>
<p><strong>Step 5</strong>: Let time do its work.</p>
<p><a title="Love after Love" href="http://www.poemhunter.com/poem/love-after-love/">This</a> is what a good outcome looks like. Not you back together, not him suffering, just someday, you will tell a story about this time that goes like this:</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>I got involved with a very charismatic guy who had a girlfriend, and things got very messy both between us and for my own mental health. I&#8217;m not proud of the way that any of us behaved, but mostly I&#8217;m really glad that it&#8217;s over.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>And you won&#8217;t have to go into the details or chew them over, because it will be well and truly in the past.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5359/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5359/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5359&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/14/465-life-after-darth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>80</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/darth-vader-in-love.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A man and woman dressed as Darth Vader holding hands on a crowded street.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LA Times: &#8220;How not to say the wrong thing.&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/08/la-times-how-not-to-say-the-wrong-thing/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/08/la-times-how-not-to-say-the-wrong-thing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 17:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5356</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Movie is in the can (and about to be on its way to the lab in LA for processing)! So I will be back to being a blogger soon. In the meantime, a friend (and friend of the blog) posted this piece by Susanna Silk and Barry Goldman on Facebook today, and despite some ableist [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5356&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Movie is in the can (and about to be on its way to the lab in LA for processing)! So I will be back to being a blogger soon.</p>
<p>In the meantime, a friend (and friend of the blog) posted <a title="LA times: &quot;How Not To Say The Wrong Thing&quot;" href="http://touch.latimes.com/#section/-1/article/p2p-75241622/">this piece by Susanna Silk and Barry Goldman </a>on Facebook today, and despite some ableist wording in the opening line I think it&#8217;s a very, very helpful way to think about how to treat people who have undergone trauma or who are in crisis. What do you think?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5356/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5356/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5356&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/08/la-times-how-not-to-say-the-wrong-thing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>148</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#464: My mom died and my dad started having sex with men. A LOT of men. Should I talk to him about it?</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/01/464-my-mom-died-and-my-dad-started-having-sex-with-men-a-lot-of-men-should-i-talk-to-him-about-it/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/01/464-my-mom-died-and-my-dad-started-having-sex-with-men-a-lot-of-men-should-i-talk-to-him-about-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 14:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Families]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mother]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worry]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5351</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Captain Awkward, My mom died suddenly and unexpectedly 2 months ago. My parents had been married almost 40 years. A month after her passing, I accidentally discovered that my dad has been sleeping with multiple men he meets on the internet, at the gym, etc., and that he is also having sex in public [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5351&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward,</em></p>
<p><em>My mom died suddenly and unexpectedly 2 months ago. My parents had been married almost 40 years. A month after her passing, I accidentally discovered that my dad has been sleeping with multiple men he meets on the internet, at the gym, etc., and that he is also having sex in public restrooms. I don&#8217;t believe that my mom knew that this was going on, but I realize that that is a possibility. </em></p>
<p><em>It was not a complete shock to me that my dad is gay or bisexual, as the thought had crossed my mind before, and after my mom died I had even considered that he might bring home a boyfriend in a couple of years. I imagined myself being very supportive and understanding in that scenario, but this sudden discovery at such an emotional time has really thrown me for a loop. The high-risk behavior is freaking me out and making me angry, if I&#8217;m honest. I just lost one parent, and I don&#8217;t want to lose another! Furthermore, the thought that he was likely putting my mom at risk, too, really upsets me.</em></p>
<p><em>I cannot stop worrying about how this might play out. I&#8217;m worried that he is putting himself in harm&#8217;s way and risking arrest, etc. I&#8217;m worried that the community that has been supporting him through the loss of my mom would disappear if this came out in the wrong way. Similarly, I worry about how my mom&#8217;s extended family, to whom we are very close, would react if this were suddenly revealed. I feel like I&#8217;m not able to progress through the normal grieving process for my mom because I am so wrapped up in the stress of this situation and keeping this secret. So, here are my questions:</em></p>
<p><em>1) Should I tell him that I know? Should I tell him how much I know?</em></p>
<p><em>2) If I do tell him, how do I do it and what do I say? Is it even appropriate for me to share my concerns for his health and well-being considering his sex life is not really any of my business?</em></p>
<p><em>Sincerely, </em></p>
<p><em>Daughter with a Dilemma</em></p>
<p><span id="more-5351"></span></p>
<p>Dear Daughter,</p>
<p>A little time has gone by since you first sent this in. I am so, so sorry for your loss and cannot even imagine the shock and grief that goes with losing your mom so suddenly.</p>
<p>While I realize that this may not make you feel any better, if at all possible, I think the best course is for you to let the stuff with your dad go, and not do or say anything to him about it until or unless he tells you what&#8217;s going on.</p>
<p>Even if it&#8217;s risky.</p>
<p>Even if it&#8217;s uncharacteristic.</p>
<p>Even if you don&#8217;t understand it.</p>
<p>Even if you have worries and fears and anger about it.</p>
<p>His extended family and community might not be happy with his behavior if they found out, but that is <strong>his</strong> issue to manage.</p>
<p>He owns his own body and his own sexuality, including any risks that come with his behavior.</p>
<p>And he owns his own <strong>grief</strong> and grieving process.</p>
<p>Thinking the words &#8220;my dad&#8221; and &#8220;<a title="Peaches: Fuck the Pain Away" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KHcMqOQt4NY" target="_blank">fuck the pain away</a>&#8221; in the same sentence is not a whole bunch of fun for you, and I&#8217;m sorry &#8211; I wish he were being more discreet and that you didn&#8217;t know. But unless he does something in a way that makes it 100% obvious that you know, put up that Plausible Deniability Screen, the one your parents probably used for you when you became sexually active and the one that all roommates everywhere use to pretend that sound doesn&#8217;t carry inside a shared house.</p>
<p>Imagine for a moment that you are a kinky person, and that your kink is to tie eggplants to your feet and rub them against the feet of people who have mushrooms tied to their feet. Wracked by grief, you&#8217;ve been having more vegetable-on-vegetable action of late and have been a little less than discreet about where you find your ratatouille. Your dad finds out what you&#8217;re up to, and he confronts you about your safety, the way people might see you in the family and community, and heaps a whole bunch of shame and worry upon your private business, etc. How would you feel? Would you feel loved and cared for? Would it be a wakeup call for you? Would that conversation leave either of you feeling better? I know you are genuinely very concerned about him, but any time &#8220;safety issues&#8221; + &#8220;what will people think?&#8221; + &#8220;behavior I don&#8217;t like or agree with/moral upset&#8221; get combined together you risk falling into concern-trolling. I think many of us have done sexual things that our family members would not approve of and find risky, and I think at those  times we had our reasons, and I don&#8217;t think anyone could have talked us out of them or made things better with their disapproval.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m deliberately trying to choose a ridiculous kink as an example so I don&#8217;t inadvertently stumble into anyone&#8217;s actual kinks, and I don&#8217;t want to dodge the very real safety issues that might be at play here, but all nearly all sexual contact carries some risk. You&#8217;re not psyched about the string of anonymous partners, but you also wouldn&#8217;t be psyched if they were women, and you also probably wouldn&#8217;t be happy if he found a new girlfriend or long-term boyfriend and started to look serious about settling down with someone right now. It&#8217;s <span style="text-decoration:underline;">all</span> too much, too soon.</p>
<p>So the axioms at play are:</p>
<ul>
<li>His sexual choices are his to make.</li>
<li>Adults should give each other a wide berth when it comes to privacy.</li>
<li>People come out when it&#8217;s right for them, not necessarily when it&#8217;s right for you.</li>
</ul>
<p>It&#8217;s good that you&#8217;ve considered the possibility that he is gay. When the time is right, and some more time has passed, you can have the sweet talk that my Godmother had with me when it had been a long time since I&#8217;d mentioned a dude or brought one home:</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Jennifer, I just want you to know that&#8230;<strong>anyone</strong> you loved, we would also love. So if you ever wanted to bring &#8230;<strong>someone</strong> home, we would welcome&#8230;<strong>that person</strong></em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>I wasn&#8217;t gay, I was just single (and we don&#8217;t fly <a title="My Sluthood, Myself" href="http://yesmeansyesblog.wordpress.com/2010/07/26/my-sluthood-myself/" target="_blank">Socially Unacceptable Brief Slutty Encounters </a>home to Massachusetts for the holidays, or, at least I don&#8217;t), but it was good to know, right?</p>
<p>Your dad will need you to be that cool daughter someday. But he also needs you to be that cool daughter <strong>now</strong>, and give him some time and space about private stuff, and to reach out to him (spend time with him, recommend that he see a counselor, check in on him, tell him you love him) about the common ground you share.</p>
<p>I think you should talk to <strong>someone</strong> about this. Grief, anger, worry, the pressure of keeping a secret all mixed up together is a powerful and messy combo, and some counseling for yourself where you can get as angry as you need and lay out all your concerns and figure out how to tackle them might be a very helpful step. A counselor will let you talk through worst-case scenarios but will also remind you that the worst case scenarios are not always so. Maybe he wasn&#8217;t putting your mom at risk. Maybe he really did wait until she died to seek this kind of contact, and this is something that has been pent up for years. Maybe they did have an understanding. That is 100% between them; you are not the guardian of your parents&#8217; marital fidelity.</p>
<p>If word is getting out, and people bring concerns up to you, an all-purpose mantra is &#8220;<em>Grief is unpredictable. You should probably talk to my dad directly about that.</em>&#8221; You don&#8217;t have to manage your dad&#8217;s image for him. That can be a hard thing to let go of, but I think it is good for you if you learn (maybe slowly, with help of a counselor) that you don&#8217;t have to control how other people see your dad.</p>
<p>Hopefully you can find a way to put this down under some kind of Year of Grieving seal and forgive your dad for not managing his grief the way you want him to. Maybe there is an honest talk in your future where he tells you what&#8217;s up and you can say &#8220;<em>Yeah, I knew when you did x, and I was really worried about you, but I wanted to give you your privacy. Can we talk about that?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>Finally, if you do end up talking about it, just freaking talk about it. Don&#8217;t drop hints about &#8220;discretion.&#8221; Don&#8217;t drop hints, period. &#8220;<em>Dad, I wish I didn&#8217;t know this, but I do. I heard/saw/unavoidably have to know that you did x, and it&#8217;s making me concerned about you. I want to respect your privacy, and you don&#8217;t have to talk to me about what&#8217;s going on, but I wish you would talk to someone about it, and I really want you to be safe and okay.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t envy you, or your dad. The Year(s)of Grieving stretch out in front of you no matter what you choose, so I wish you kindness, strength, patience, and love.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5351/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5351/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5351&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/01/464-my-mom-died-and-my-dad-started-having-sex-with-men-a-lot-of-men-should-i-talk-to-him-about-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>154</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#463: Help me stop being mean.</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/28/463-help-me-stop-being-mean/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/28/463-help-me-stop-being-mean/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 17:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geek Social Fallacies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[activism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being mean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bullying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[changing habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liz Lemon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mean Girls]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5344</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Captain Awkward: I am trying to not make this question sound like a pity party, but will probably slip up somewhere. Apologies in advance and gratefulness for making this the space you do. I feel like I am just plain mean a lot of the time.  It&#8217;s confusing because I try to be really [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5344&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward:</em></p>
<p><em>I am trying to not make this question sound like a pity party, but will probably slip up somewhere. Apologies in advance and gratefulness for making this the space you do.</em></p>
<p><em>I feel like I am just plain mean a lot of the time. </em></p>
<p><em>It&#8217;s confusing because I try to be really caring and positive and encouraging to my friends, there&#8217;s just this fucking mean streak too. I also work in Profession where Being Kind and Supportive is a huge part of my job and I don&#8217;t have any trouble there. The few times my friends have been my clients (which is ethically fine in this field) I have felt lucky because I feel like they finally got to see me at my best.</em></p>
<p><em>But outside of that I feel like there&#8217;s just this continuous stream of negativity that slips into conversations even with people I love, and I dig at people in subtle and not-subtle ways and don&#8217;t even notice it until the words have already flown out of my mouth. </em></p>
<p><em>I think it is a defense mechanism because I don&#8217;t do it as much when I&#8217;m around people I feel comfortable with, but when I&#8217;m in a new social setting or around people I&#8217;m not sure like me I am just like&#8230;negative thought machine word vomit spout. It used to be way worse, but it is still often enough to sting and be totally inappropriate. </em></p>
<p><em>I avoid getting involved with people who I can tell are no-bullshit and have good boundaries because I feel like they would automatically dislike me because of it, which sucks because I really respect people who have those skills and I am working on them myself. Simultaneously, I try to avoid becoming close with people who aren&#8217;t necessarily good at standing up for themselves, because I&#8217;m afraid of hurting their feelings.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m also really hard on myself, like 24/7 negative self-talk, which I know is my stuff to deal with, and I&#8217;m working on getting back in therapy. I guess what I&#8217;m wondering about is how to deal with Jerkbrain: Externalized so I&#8217;m not always hurting people I care about and feeling like I have to avoid social situations so I don&#8217;t ruin them for the people who are there to enjoy them, not be insulted.</em></p>
<p><em>I already know that what I&#8217;m doing is shitty and I am trying to find tools to be able to stop, because shaming myself about it is, surprise, totally ineffectual. Tips? Tricks? Personal red flags to look for? Mantras to repeat under my breath in bathrooms at parties? </em></p>
<p><em>Thanks,</em></p>
<p><em>Jerk but Trying</em></p>
<p>Dear Trying Jerk:</p>
<p>The negative self-talk and the negative other-talk are connected. So yes, please go back to therapy.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been in the headspace you describe, for sure. I believe the clinical term is &#8220;total misery.&#8221;</p>
<p><span id="more-5344"></span></p>
<p>The biggest thing I did to get out of it may sound cheesy and strange: I gave up &#8220;complaining&#8221; for Lent one year way back when Lent was something I still agnostically tried to celebrate. I wrote about it at the (now very defunct) <a title="The Girl Who Ate Everything" href="http://thegirlwhoateeverything.wordpress.com/2010/03/16/burgers-and-blasphemy/">food blog</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>I had just turned 26.  I worked ridiculous hours and was stressed past all recognition.  And I was addicted to complaining in a work environment that was hooked on complaining and my work people were also my social people whose favorite thing to do was get together after work and complain. At least there we had liquor.</p>
<p>We wanted to change everything, so complained about the changes we would make if we were in charge, but when our bosses tried actually changing stuff, we complained about that too.  I don’t remember exactly how I decided, but somewhere in there I realized the complaining was slowly killing me and I gave it up for Lent.  Here were the rules:</p>
<ol>
<li>I would not initiate complaining.</li>
<li>If people started to complain, I’d change the subject or politely extricate myself from the conversation.</li>
<li>I would not tell people what I was doing or harsh on them for complaining –The goal was to change my outlook, not to give up complaining in favor of being a jerk to everyone.</li>
</ol>
<p>I won’t say I was perfect but I will say I did pretty well at consistently re-routing my brain away from pointing out the flaws in everything to finding solutions.  I think I became nicer to other people and to myself.  And then I quit that job, dumped my unsuitable love partner, and moved across the country to start a new life within the following 4 months.  The energy I released by complaining was incredibly productive when channeled into actually changing things&#8230;</p></blockquote>
<p>A ban on complaining didn&#8217;t mean I had to react positively to actual bad news, i.e., death, taxes, romantic disappointment, injustice. To live in the world means being aware all the time of things that are unfair and wrong, and I don&#8217;t think we do ourselves or each other any favors by pretending things are okay when they are not okay. Activism requires a certain amount of complaining.</p>
<div>Also, at the time, I was pretty big into <a title="The Artist's Way" href="http://www.amazon.com/Artists-Way-Spiritual-Creativity-Anniversary/dp/1585421464">The Artist&#8217;s Way</a> and the whole Morning Pages thing (3 pages longhand every morning, the digital equivalent would be <a title="750 Words" href="http://750words.com">750words.com</a>), and in the morning pages I could say anything I wanted, including a litany of complaints and things I hated about myself. By having a safe place to vomit it all out, I could keep my cool throughout the day. Nowadays I still keep journals and having them switch over to all complaints, all the time is a good sign that I&#8217;m about to go into a depressive slide.</div>
<p>The complaining ban was meant to stop the constant complaining that I was doing at work and about work that was spilling into everything. The expense report system is wack! They are making a tiny change to this software I use and I don&#8217;t like it! I wanted to go on that assignment and they sent someone else! I hate my body! I never have any free time! What am I really supposed to be doing with my life? The bus was full! My feet stink! This coffee is burnt! They are out of my favorite brand of toilet paper! The cat puked on the floor again! Why am I paid $30,000 year to rewrite stuff that some old dude gets $200,000 year to write very badly? This job requires an expensive degree but doesn&#8217;t pay me enough to make the student loan payments! (Welp, we&#8217;re back to legit activism with that last one).</p>
<p>I know complaining isn&#8217;t exactly the same as being mean to people, but I was hypercritical of everything: work, myself, other people. My inner critic was in full outward mode, and I was definitely mean to people in some pretty shameful ways. Like High School-aged Liz Lemon, I thought being a smartass and having a mean mouth was the one thing I had going for me, and there are ways it made me feel less powerless and allowed me to feel like I was defending myself against bullies or a shitty status quo. In high school, that logic is understandable if not entirely forgivable: The Cool Kids are mean to me, therefore if I can be as mean as them I can be as cool as them! It was a fallacy at the time, and it sure as hell doesn&#8217;t age well.</p>
<p>So, Letter Writer, to bring this back to you and now and not some 13-year old experiment, I think:</p>
<p>1. Negative talk comes out of negative feelings that need to be dealt with at length in some safe space &#8211; a therapist&#8217;s office, a journal, with close friends.</p>
<p>2. However, you don&#8217;t have to change the feelings to start to change the habit, and negative talk (negative self-talk, criticism, complaining) is also a <strong>habit</strong>. When it&#8217;s in full force, it becomes your first instinct to react negatively.</p>
<p>We know some stuff about changing habits, and one of the biggest things to know is that sustained effort is better than perfection. How you treat yourself when you inevitably slip up is everything. People who will actually change the habit forgive themselves for slipping up, give themselves credit for doing what they can, and try again later. Perfectionists see any slip-up as a total failure and a reason to derail the entire affair. So if your mean self comes out, when you catch it: stop it, apologize, and then move away from those people and/or stop talking so much. Maybe you&#8217;ll have a shame spiral ( I would probably have a shame spiral), because that shit I just said about forgiving oneself and giving credit and trying again later is seriously the hardest thing for a recovering perfectionist to do. What matters is that you keep trying to stop saying negative things about yourself and others. <strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><br />
</span></strong></p>
<p>The other thing we know about changing habits is that it feels hard at first (when I gave up complaining, I felt like 85% of my personality went away) but it feels better the more you do it. Don&#8217;t expect it to feel good immediately, but over time, expect your actions to affect your feelings positively.</p>
<p>3. Negative talk has a place &#8211; in acknowledging hurt and wrong, in figuring out that a situation is bad for you, in figuring out what steps to take next. It&#8217;s toxic when it gets all over other people the way you describe in your letter, and also when it becomes what you do <strong>instead of</strong> taking action. If it&#8217;s robbing you of momentum and sapping your energy, it&#8217;s crossed the line into unhelpful. This is stuff to work on when you actually do find a therapist, but a good habit when you&#8217;re in &#8220;complain/criticize&#8221; mode is to try to figure out what parts of what is upsetting you is inside your control and what is outside your control. The stuff that&#8217;s inside your control will lend itself to action, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height:13px;">Ask the person directly to stop doing the thing that&#8217;s bothering you.</span></li>
<li>Start looking for a new job/roommate/college major/career/life plan.</li>
<li>Ask your crush out already, or break up with the person who is bringing you down.</li>
<li>Make a needed schedule change/doctor&#8217;s appointment/reorganize the spice cabinet/home repair.</li>
<li>Write  letter to the editor or find some activist or volunteer outlet.</li>
<li>Stop hanging out with x person or change the subject when x topic comes up.</li>
<li>Stop reading/watching stuff that makes you feel bad, for example, one way to cut down on body shame and body snarking is to stop reading women&#8217;s magazines that are full of diet advice and Photoshopped idealized bodies.</li>
<li>Break any of the above down into tiny steps. One tiny step in the direction of actually resolving something that is bothering you is better than complaining.</li>
</ul>
<p>The things you are criticizing other people for sound like things that are outside your control, because what someone wears/listens to/who they date/what they eat or whatever you are criticizing isn&#8217;t really your business, at all.</p>
<p>4. Make apologies and amends where you can, but remember, apologies only count if you stop doing the bad thing and you don&#8217;t make them about yourself. <em>&#8220;I&#8217;m sorry I was so mean, there is this thing going on where I hate myself and I feel like I can&#8217;t help it</em>&#8221; = not actually an apology. &#8220;<em>I&#8217;m sorry, that was really out of line</em>&#8221; = an apology.</p>
<p>5. Practice some self-care. This means taking care of yourself around eating, sleeping, your living space, going to the doctor when you&#8217;re sick, getting a haircut when you need one, looking for a new job if you hate your current one.</p>
<p>It might also mean spending more time with people who make you feel good and comfortable and taking a break from social scenes that stress you out. Maybe your outbursts are borne of defensiveness and not liking yourself very much right now, or patterns you were raised with that come out in times of stress. Consider also the idea that part of this is your gut reactions to spaces that don&#8217;t feel good and people that don&#8217;t feel good. Maybe your <a title="#391: How To Train Your Rageasaurus" href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/11/07/391-how-to-train-your-rageasaurus/">Rageasaurus</a> is trying to protect you. I don&#8217;t want to say &#8220;No new things or people&#8221;, but I do want to say that if you are going to be around people you don&#8217;t know well or outside of your comfort zone:</p>
<ul>
<li>Give yourself a time limit &#8211; one hour, one set, one drink, meet one new person and talk to them &#8211; and then give yourself permission to leave while things still feel good.</li>
<li>If drinking is a factor in what&#8217;s going on, watch yours. Keep it to one, or don&#8217;t drink at all.</li>
<li>Slow down, overall. Listen more than you talk. Stop trying to hard to make people like you (or have an opinion about you either way). Stop working so hard at this.</li>
</ul>
<p>6. <strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">NO yucking other people&#8217;s yum</span>.</strong> If you don&#8217;t know what to say, compliments and questions are a good place to start. &#8220;<em>I like your bag, where did you get it?</em>&#8221; &#8220;<em>How do you know the hosts?&#8221;</em> &#8221;<em>This is delicious, how did you make it?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>In an answer full of tangents, allow me to rant about taste and the way we talk about pop culture and suggest an alternative way of talking about taste. Because this is a common, sort of socially acceptable way that I see adults being mean to each other.</p>
<p>We have to learn a better way of talking about things that other people like that we don&#8217;t like.</p>
<p>There are a ton of Geek/Pop Culture discussions when people are meeting the first time that go like this:</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>What kind of _____ do you like?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p><em>&#8220;I like ____.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Really? They SUCK. Here are 11,000 reasons why that thing you like sucks</em>.&#8221; (Subtext: And you also suck for liking it. And I am smarter than you and my opinions are better than yours.Consider yourself DOMINATED. <strong>Side Note:</strong>  If you start paying attention to the way people have these conversations, you&#8217;ll start noticing how often &#8220;girly&#8221; things are devalued. Whether or not you personally like the work of Stephanie Meyer, Lena Dunham, Amanda Palmer, or Beyoncé (and let me, with full moderator powers, make it clear how much I really do not care what your personal opinions of their particular works are. Like them, or don&#8217;t, as long as you do it <strong>elsewhere</strong>), much of the criticism that comes their way and the way of their fans is laden with misogyny, racism, and body-policing that does not get applied to men in similar prominent creative roles.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>Postulate Time:</strong></span></p>
<p>Stuff can be &#8220;good&#8221; (technically accomplished, made with talent &amp; dedication) and you can still not like it. Stuff can be &#8220;bad&#8221; and entertaining/enjoyable at the same time.</p>
<p>A lot of people get really caught up in the stuff they listen to and watch and buy to the point where it becomes their identity. In a capitalist society, this is encouraged and rewarded. The question isn&#8217;t &#8220;<em>Do you prefer a Mac or a PC?</em>&#8221; it&#8217;s &#8220;<em><strong>Are</strong> you a Mac or a PC?</em>&#8221; So people get very defensive, and yes, mean, when that identity is challenged in any way. Or they get overly invested in the meaningfulness of taste as a source of connection when someone likes the same stuff. As <a title="Geek Relationship Fallacies" href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/04/16/geek-relationship-fallacies/">Commander Logic says</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Look, the Jedi and the Klingon CAN be lovers. And LotR purists can make out with LotR movie fans (right after we pause (or not) to sing a requiem for Glorfindel&#8230; What’s important in a relationship is not your media, it’s your actions and respect.</p>
<p>This is another human being who is allowed to have thoughts and opinions that are different from yours. They are allowed to not give a shit if Greedo or Han shot first.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Ranting about pop culture is fun. Sometime if we&#8217;re at a party, ask me about the movie <em>Rent</em>.  Criticism is valuable and entertaining &#8211; in blog posts, in Tweets, in scholarly articles, in reviews &#8211; and <a title="Marie Claire’s “Rich”:  Good girls get to meet your mom.  Bad girls are too confident and hard to control….like dirty snow." href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/03/13/marie-claires-rich-good-girls-get-to-meet-your-mom-bad-girls-are-too-confident-and-hard-to-control-like-dirty-snow/">snark has its place</a>.</p>
<p>However, that place is not the first time you meet someone, or with someone you don&#8217;t know well, or with someone that isn&#8217;t comfortable having super-fun pop culture ranty times with you. And that time is not right after someone says &#8220;<em>I really like ___!</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>So if a lot of your conversations are going the way of the example, and you are the one acting as the Sole Arbiter of Taste and Style, try this approach.</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>What kind of x do you like?&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;I like x!&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;They&#8217;re not really my thing/I haven&#8217;t really gotten into them/I don&#8217;t know much about them, but what&#8217;s your favorite (song, book, movie, painting, example)?&#8221;</em></p>
<p>The stuff you like will still be cool without you defending it or proving its superiority in this exact moment; truth and beauty are durable. Also, you can still feel whatever you want about what the other person likes. I mean, I do not understand Juggalos, but if I&#8217;m hanging at a party and there is an actual Juggalo there I want to find out all about that, don&#8217;t you? I&#8217;m pretty sure the Juggalos are pretty comfortable with the fact that most people aren&#8217;t also Juggalos and tired of having the &#8220;<em>Juggalos: Cool or Not Cool?</em>&#8221; discussion. You&#8217;re not going to accidentally become a Juggalo because you failed to fully critique the one you met that time at a your cousin&#8217;s wedding, so relax and let people be themselves.</p>
<p>This way you can actually have a conversation and find out a little bit more about someone else, which is the point of social interactions with new people. There&#8217;s this fallacy that &#8220;authenticity&#8221; always means talking about things with the most negative, critical eye.  Not sharing every opinion that you have does not equal &#8220;being fake&#8221; or &#8220;lying.&#8221; Every dinner party doesn&#8217;t have to turn into a Platonic discussion of What is the Good?</p>
<p>I&#8217;m sure the community will have many helpful suggestions and tales of reformed Mean People, and I really do wish you luck in changing this aspect of your personality. The fact that you are self-aware and wanting to change it is a big, big step in the right direction, so practice giving yourself some credit for reaching out and asking how.</p>
<p>Much love,</p>
<p>Captain Awkward</p>
<p>President of Recovered Mean Sad People Anonymous &amp; Also A Member</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5344/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5344/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5344&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/28/463-help-me-stop-being-mean/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>219</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Asheville, North Carolina is Meeting Up April 30</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/26/asheville-north-carolina-is-meeting-up-april-30/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/26/asheville-north-carolina-is-meeting-up-april-30/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 18:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Meetups]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5339</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From Dr. Jillenstein: Hello Awkwardeers of Western North Carolina! Please join me for an Awkward Army Meetup on Tuesday, April 30, at the French Broad Chocolate Lounge in Asheville, NC. Delicious chocolate desserts and drinks are available and reasonably priced at this all-ages location. The first floor is fully accessible, there are gender-neutral bathrooms, and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5339&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div>From Dr. Jillenstein:</div>
<div></div>
<blockquote>
<div>Hello Awkwardeers of Western North Carolina! Please join me for an Awkward Army Meetup on Tuesday, April 30, at the French Broad Chocolate Lounge in Asheville, NC. Delicious chocolate desserts and drinks are available and reasonably priced at this all-ages location. The first floor is fully accessible, there are gender-neutral bathrooms, and it&#8217;s right in downtown Asheville. I will be there from 7-9pm (or later if there is fun happening). I have curly hair &amp; glasses, will probably be knitting, and will have a sign that reads &#8220;Awkward Army Meet Here.&#8221; I&#8217;m on Twitter @Dr_Jillenstein and I created a Facebook event page here:<br />
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/153042931528036" target="_blank">https://www.facebook.com/events/153042931528036</a></p>
</div>
<p>Tuesday, April 30</p></blockquote>
</div>
<blockquote><p>7pm &#8211; 9pm (or later)<br />
French Broad Chocolate Lounge<br />
10 South Lexington Ave., Asheville, NC, 28801<br />
(just south of Patton Avenue, around the corner from Salsa&#8217;s)<br />
<a href="http://www.frenchbroadchocolates.com/" target="_blank">http://www.frenchbroadchocolates.com/</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Have a great time. Jill &amp; her husband are Chicago friends who recently relocated to North Carolina and are pretty much the best people.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5339/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5339/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5339&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/26/asheville-north-carolina-is-meeting-up-april-30/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>London Meetup + #462: When is it time to cut off communication with abusive family?</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/22/london-meetup-462-when-is-it-time-to-cut-off-communication-with-abusive-family/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/22/london-meetup-462-when-is-it-time-to-cut-off-communication-with-abusive-family/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Families]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manipulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotional abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Psychological abuse]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5336</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reminder, monthly London meetup is tomorrow. Sorry for not posting this sooner, guys! It&#8217;s been the week of 1000 meetings. Dear Awkward Army, London meetup this weekend, 23rd March!  All welcome. 11:00 am onwards, Leon restaurant, 36/38 Old Compton Street, London, W1D 4TT. The venue so far has worked out well, so I’m sticking with that.  [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5336&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Reminder, monthly London meetup is tomorrow. Sorry for not posting this sooner, guys! It&#8217;s been the week of 1000 meetings.</p>
<blockquote>
<div>
<div>
<div>Dear Awkward Army,</div>
<p>London meetup this weekend, 23rd March!  All welcome.</p>
<p>11:00 am onwards, Leon restaurant, 36/38 Old Compton Street, London, W1D 4TT.</p>
<p>The venue so far has worked out well, so I’m sticking with that.  They&#8217;ve also offered us 25% off all our food and drink.</p>
<p>Map: <a href="http://goo.gl/maps/i9COr" target="_blank">http://goo.gl/maps/i9COr</a></p>
<p>Leon have a variety of good food at very reasonable prices – for central London, anyway!  Menu here:<a href="http://www.leonrestaurants.co.uk/menu/" target="_blank">http://www.leonrestaurants.co.uk/menu/</a></p>
<p>This branch has an accessible toilet, and we’ll be on the ground floor in the back (around behind the food service counter).</p>
<p>I have long brown hair and glasses.  I will bring my plush Cthulhu to use as a table marker.  It looks like this: <a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/7cb0/" target="_blank">http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/7cb0/</a></p>
<p>My email address is kate DOT towner AT gmail DOT com</p>
<p>As discussed at previous meetups, I am happy to teach people to knit, so if you want to start or want help, bring something along!</p>
</div>
<p>By the way, I think it&#8217;s likely the April one will be on the 20th rather than the 27th, sorry about any confusion.</p>
</div>
<p>Cheers,</p>
<p>Kate</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></blockquote>
<p>And now, a letter.</p>
<p><em>Hey Cap (and friends!),</em></p>
<p><em>There&#8217;s a little bit of background to this, but I&#8217;ll try to keep it short.</em></p>
<p><em>I have issues with my family. I guess you could say I&#8217;m the &#8220;black sheep&#8221; in a way. I&#8217;m the middle child, the only creative person, the only one who could be described as liberal, and (perhaps most importantly) the only one to inherit my mother&#8217;s bad depression, with a side of social anxiety. Add to this a big old heap of emotional abuse from my father and, later, my stepmother (who is thankfully gone now).</em></p>
<p><em>When I was in high school, I went through a lot of trouble, including self-harm, that was more or less ignored, and I didn&#8217;t do very well in school despite having clear potential. It was only later when I asked my parents about it that they said yeah, they always sort of knew that I had depression, and knew that it was holding me back, but they didn&#8217;t want to bring it up with me at the time because&#8230;they haven&#8217;t given a solid answer. As far as I can tell, they kind of sacrificed my academic future on the altar of not having an awkward conversation with me.</em></p>
<p><em>A few months ago, I moved out of state to live with my boyfriend and see about continuing into college now that I have things more under control. But every time I talk to my parents or my brother and sister, it seems like they have nothing nice to say at all.</em></p>
<p><em>I love my brother and sister, but every time I chat with them, they seem to be always upset with me. &#8220;Why haven&#8217;t you called us? Why haven&#8217;t you called Dad? You need to call us more and not be so ungrateful. You don&#8217;t even want to be part of the family.&#8221; Even putting aside the fact that they know I have a lot of anxiety when it comes to talking on the phone, I don&#8217;t understand how being busy up here and not able to contact home every day counts as ungrateful.</em></p>
<p><em>Then, the other night, a minor disagreement on Facebook randomly spiraled into them accusing me of hating our father, of not wanting to be a part of the family, and of being selfish in even moving away. These overtures were common before I&#8217;d moved, but now it&#8217;s been magnified so that they&#8217;ve become outright vicious about it.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m out of a toxic environment, but now the environment is starting to follow me. How do I tell my brother and sister that I still love my family (I really do!), but they need respect my decisions and treat me like a person?</em></p>
<p>Oh goody, when your abuser recruits others to do their abusing for them.</p>
<p><span id="more-5336"></span></p>
<p>I want to review a few things about abuse (which includes neglect and/or emotional abuse). Well, I don&#8217;t want to. But I will. People can grow up in the same household <a title="Reader Question #6:  I’m worried about my sister.  She is still very close to our abusive parents." href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/01/19/reader-question-6-im-worried-about-my-sister-she-is-still-very-close-to-our-abusive-parents/">and have two totally different experiences of what happened</a>. Your brother and sister are probably being wound up by your dad, and investing in this story about how they are the Good Ones and you are the one who causes problems. And your leaving affects the stories they want to tell themselves about how they grew up. If they grew up in an awesome place, then why are you leaving it? And if they didn&#8217;t grow up in such an awesome situation, and you can just walk away from it, then they could theoretically walk away from it, too. But they aren&#8217;t, so are you like, judging them by making a different choice? Or leaving them alone to deal with JerkDad on their own, which is somehow &#8220;unfair&#8221;?</p>
<p>None of this surprises me, is what I&#8217;m saying. Abusers need to control the story about what happened, and will go to great lengths (including deputizing others and making them miserable by proxy) to keep that control, because it&#8217;s a way of controlling you. If your parents had gotten you help when they noticed you harming yourself, they risked that you would tell other people what it was really like in your house, which may have had real consequences for them or the imagined consequence of &#8220;someone somewhere thinks they are not very good parents.&#8221; Maybe you would have moved out, and been outside of their control. Maybe you would have gone off to school, and learned things, and been outside of their control. Maybe people in your town would have given them the side-eye at church. Or, maybe they saw you hurting yourself and they just didn&#8217;t give a shit, and now that you&#8217;re old enough to tell the story I and everyone reading this thinks maybe they weren&#8217;t very good parents. That cat is out of the bag, Letter Writer, so take care of yourself now that you are out of the house and have that agency for yourself.</p>
<p>Honestly, who knows or cares what their logic is. You don&#8217;t actually have to know in order to make good decisions for yourself.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what we do know:</p>
<p>1. Many people don&#8217;t get the whole &#8220;making a different choice than you is not an attack on you&#8221; thing. You left. They could leave too, if they wanted to. If they choose to stay? Great, enjoy that, then! Not actually a referendum on love or a reason for yelling.</p>
<p>2. Starting a conversation with someone who calls you with WHY DON&#8217;T YOU CALL MORE, JERK? is a good way to get people to call you even less, because why put up with the hassle? Telephones, roads, emails work both ways.</p>
<p>3. Living where you are living and putting some distance between you and your family is a good decision for you right now.</p>
<p>Your family doesn&#8217;t have to be horrible for that to be true, by the way. Some people grow really well while staying very close to and entwined with their families, but some people need to go off on their own and really break away for a while before they can come back and figure out an adult relationship with their folks. The stayers aren&#8217;t better people than the leavers, and the leavers don&#8217;t necessarily grow up better than the stayers &#8211; it&#8217;s just, whatever your situation is, you need to do what is right for you.</p>
<p>It sounds like your family sees you as a perpetual fuck-up. Guess what? For much of my adult life, mine did, too. They wouldn&#8217;t use &#8220;fuck-up&#8221;, they would use &#8220;We&#8217;re very worried about you,&#8221; or &#8220;We don&#8217;t understand your choices (to seem to fail at everything).&#8221; For a lot of my 20s, when I was really struggling with depression and figuring out what I wanted to do with my life, being around them for long periods of time would make me start to feel like a fuck-up. And then it would be self-fulfilling &#8211; I&#8217;d be so miserable and wound up that I would be in a reactive mode because I was so ashamed and on-edge all the time. If you&#8217;re constantly criticized, you start to react to people as if they mean to criticize you even before the words come out of their mouths, so it&#8217;s easy to launch the &#8220;<em>Why are you being so dramatic/exaggerating/blowing things out of proportion/I was <strong>just asking</strong>/jeez, overreact much?</em>&#8221; brigade and the you feel more like a fuck-up because you&#8217;re being gaslighted into believing that having normal reactions &#8211; stress, aversion, shoulders-up-around-ears, being on guard are somehow your own fantasies and not reactions to the <a title="Microaggression" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microaggression" target="_blank">constant criticism </a>that&#8217;s being leveled at you.</p>
<p>You know what was a great decision for me? Moving really, really far away and staying there, and seeing them in smaller doses.</p>
<p>I just spent a few days with my folks last month, and we&#8217;re on much better terms now and it was mostly a great visit. But by the end of it, my dad&#8217;s constant mansplaining had escalated to the point that he took my toast out of the toaster, put it back in &#8220;correctly,&#8221; called me &#8220;stupid&#8221; for not being able to find the correct drawer where knives were kept on the first try in a kitchen where I don&#8217;t live, and actually SCREAMED at me for microwaving food for what he deemed to be an incorrect amount of time. Screamed. Spit flying and hitting my face. Screamed.</p>
<p>And that was a &#8220;great&#8221; visit. And if he read this (I don&#8217;t think they read the blog, they&#8217;ve never mentioned it, and I&#8217;ve never mentioned it to them though I don&#8217;t hide my actual identity), he&#8217;d tell me I was overreacting and blowing the whole thing out of proportion. Because screaming about things like &#8220;where we keep the knives in a rental kitchen&#8221; is normal in his world, so normal that there is a 75% chance he does not remember it at all, and I was raised to think that was normal. I <a title="Men are too emotional to have a rational argument" href="http://www.thegloss.com/2012/11/12/career/bullish-life-men-are-too-emotional-to-have-a-rational-argument-994/" target="_blank">would be the &#8220;emotional&#8221; one for being mad</a> that someone screamed in my face (and having to walk out of the room and go cry privately and text my boyfriend because I honestly felt like I was going crazy), and he would be the rational one, because&#8230;he is a dude. A dude who gets so upset about microwave times that he screams. Rational!</p>
<p>And then I left, and I went to the <a title="Should I move away from my abusive family" href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/10/18/question-122-should-i-move-away-from-my-abusive-family/" target="_blank">small quiet room</a>, where no one screams at me, ever. And if someone in my life now screamed at me, they would not do it twice, because they would not be in my life anymore, because screaming at people over trivial shit is not okay. I learned that by leaving home, pretty much forever, which was not without costs and anxiety and working hard to schedule visits so that I can get in and out with a minimum of screaming. Going home &amp; maintaining that relationship means trying to always make sure I have a rental car, or schedule time with friends who live nearby so I have a break, and ALWAYS having my phone with me so I feel connected to people who don&#8217;t yell at me, and sometimes, honestly, Xanax. It means when they are nice and pleasant it makes me doubt my own reality, like, do I really need to keep my shields up? Am I being unfair? Ohhhhh wait, there is screaming about trivial stuff again, nope, it&#8217;s okay to keep my guard up. It also cost <strong>years of therapy</strong> to learn how to interact in a healthy way, keep my temper (or lose it more selectively), and be able to disassociate from what was happening and remind myself that their vision of me is not me. It also cost long periods of not interacting with them, with the explicit message &#8220;<em>If you are not nice to me, I will not be around</em>.&#8221; Eventually it worked and made everyone try very hard to be nicer. But I won&#8217;t ever lie and say it was easy.</p>
<p>Alphakitty said something really great <a title="Comment by Alphakitty" href="http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/18/461-my-partner-makes-hurtful-jokes-about-my-health-situation/#comment-49604" target="_blank">in a comment</a> yesterday:</p>
<blockquote><p>I think part of a mother/father’s power to hurt comes from the Pedestals of Infallibility young children are encouraged to put their parents on. Even once we grow up and learn that our parents are just people, with biases and baggage and all that, we still invest their opinions of us with greater Truth and weight than we would give anyone else’s opinion. It’s all swirled together with the “Mother/Father knows best,” and “we only want what’s best for you” (even though their values probably aren’t quite the same as yours, so their definition of “best” is not going to match yours), and an implication that “we know you better than anyone else, even you” (though parents’ opinions of their offspring are often a) outdated, based on behavior/characteristics the “child” has outgrown, and b) distorted by their own values and their need to believe certain things about their kids).</p></blockquote>
<p>Your parents, and your brother and sister, DON&#8217;T KNOW YOU BEST. And they don&#8217;t know what is best for you &#8211; they proved that when you needed help and mental health services and they just kind of forgot to hook you up with them. And this story that they have about how you are a fuck-up is not the only story, and not a story that everyone will have about you. And I think you were smart to get far, far away from them.</p>
<p>I think that now that you are away, you should do a couple of things:</p>
<p>1) Find (or continue) treatment for your depression.</p>
<p>2) Put your brother, sister, dad, and anyone else who makes you uncomfortable in social media jail. There are ways you can stay &#8220;friends&#8221; with someone on Facebook but make it so they can&#8217;t really see anything you post or do on Facebook. Or, consider unfriending them, or making a second profile where you connect with people you really want to. &#8220;<em>I love you, but I refuse to get in Facebook fights. From now on email me at _____.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>3) Filter their emails and phone calls so that you <a title="What is an introvert? #456 &amp; #457: Communication Expectations" href="http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/01/what-is-an-introvert-456-457-communication-expectations/" target="_blank">choose to interact with them at specific, regular times</a>. And possibly cut off all contact for a while, if it helps you gain some distance and perspective. For a long time, this is what I did: I would call or hang out periodically, and be pleasant as long as they were pleasant. When the first mean thing was said, I would leave the conversation and not interact again for a period of (generally) 1 month. 2 mean things? 2 months. 3 mean things? 3 months. It was not perfect, and it was very hard and painful and took a lot of psyching myself up and second-guessing on my part. But it was pretty essential in reminding myself: &#8220;<em>Whatever happened in the past,</em> <em>I do not have to stay in conversations with people who are rude to me.</em>&#8221; Sometimes I would just excuse myself, &#8220;<em>Sorry, out of time to talk, catch you soon!</em>&#8221; and sometimes I&#8217;d say &#8220;<em>This conversation is really starting to stress me out, so I&#8217;m going to end it now</em>&#8221; &#8211; it depended on how mean it was and my overall stress level.</p>
<p>4) Repeat &#8220;<em>I am not responsible for everything they feel&#8221;</em> until it sounds believable.</p>
<p>5) If you want to, say something like &#8220;<em>I am really happy and excited to start school. I am taking a break from communication for a while while I get settled, and I&#8217;ll be in touch when I&#8217;m ready</em>.&#8221; And then let them feel about it and react however they want. They will not like it, they will not understand, they will be mad, but it might still be <strong>what you need</strong> in order to feel okay.</p>
<p>6) It may never be okay. It will always hurt a bit and feel weird. That&#8217;s because abuse is destructive and it ruins everything, not because you are a bad mean ungrateful daughter. Your family is blaming you for things they did to you. Not okay.</p>
<p>7) The rest of your family might not believe you or see it your way. &#8220;<em>But that&#8217;s just how he is&#8230;&#8221; &#8220;But I deal with it, why can&#8217;t you?&#8221; &#8220;You&#8217;re exaggerating.&#8221; &#8220;It&#8217;s not that bad.&#8221; </em>Well, maybe it is that bad, for you, and they don&#8217;t have to agree for you to do what is right for you. It would be awesome if your sibs could be your allies, but if they aren&#8217;t, admit it and disengage. &#8220;<em>We think you&#8217;re the worst, so move back here and prove you love us, or we&#8217;ll think you&#8217;re the worst</em>&#8221; isn&#8217;t really a compelling proposition.</p>
<p>8) Kick ass at your studies and enjoy your new life.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5336/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5336/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5336&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/22/london-meetup-462-when-is-it-time-to-cut-off-communication-with-abusive-family/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>236</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#461: My partner makes hurtful jokes about my health situation.</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/18/461-my-partner-makes-hurtful-jokes-about-my-health-situation/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/18/461-my-partner-makes-hurtful-jokes-about-my-health-situation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 13:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manipulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dealing with health problems in a relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotional abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5328</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Captain Awkward: I have had a very complex life in the last couple of years. I have gone from having a fairly normal life in regards to health and then I went on dialysis. Since that point I now have a kidney transplant. My girlfriend currently has a really hard time wrapping her mind [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5328&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward:</em></p>
<p><em>I have had a very complex life in the last couple of years. I have gone from having a fairly normal life in regards to health and then I went on dialysis. Since that point I now have a kidney transplant.</em></p>
<p><em>My girlfriend currently has a really hard time wrapping her mind around the changes in lifestyle that I have to live. She almost finds my precautions somewhat unbearable.</em></p>
<p><em>What should I do? She also makes fun of my situation or lightheartedly jokes about it.</em></p>
<p>Unfortunately they don&#8217;t offer empathy transplants.</p>
<p>Was your girlfriend with you since before the changes? Because I would imagine that watching a partner go through dialysis and a kidney transplant would make it sink in that 1) Hey, you could have DIED 2) Following your doctors&#8217; recommendations carefully is  serious business. If she met you after the changes, maybe the seriousness of it hasn&#8217;t really sunk in. Which isn&#8217;t an excuse, but it gives you a place to start in deepening her perspective.</p>
<p>If you want to try to make things work with this person, I think there is both a Big Serious Talk to be had and some day-to-day scripts.</p>
<p>The daily script is, when she makes a joke, to say something like &#8220;<em>Whoa, that really hurts my feelings</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>After you say that, be quiet, and listen to what happens next. There is going to be a very awkward moment, and it is not your job to smooth it over &#8211; the awkwardness is the way that you get to the resolution. If she stops, apologizes, and changes her behavior, that&#8217;s a good sign. If you&#8217;ve been putting up with the jokes for a while, it may take a few tries for it to sink in &#8211; you are subtly changing the &#8220;rules&#8221; of how the relationship works and some people don&#8217;t get it right away. You can openly acknowledge the rule change with &#8220;<em>I know I usually let it go, but&#8230;.&#8221; </em>or<em> &#8220;I know you mean that as a joke, but&#8230;.&#8221; when you say things like that, it really hurts my feelings. Can we find another way to talk about x issue?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>If after saying that her jokes hurt your feelings, she doubles down on the joking, or starts justifying why it&#8217;s okay for her to make jokes that hurt your feelings, she is pressuring you to ignore your healthy routines, she calls you &#8220;too sensitive&#8221; and tells you to &#8220;toughen up,&#8221; or for whatever reason the conversation ends with <strong>you</strong> apologizing to <strong>her</strong> for bringing it up and being upset, here there be <a title="The House of Evil Bees" href="http://criminalreviews.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/a-captain-awkward-glossary/#evilbees" target="_blank">Evil Bees</a>.</p>
<p><span id="more-5328"></span></p>
<p>I would try that script several times before escalating to the Big Serious Talk. You will get some information about what you&#8217;re dealing with that will help you have the talk, and you&#8217;ll get some recent examples of the behavior that bugs you.</p>
<p>The big talk is telling her what you went through, how painful and scary it was, and why these lifestyle changes are very necessary for you, and asking her directly for her kindness and support and to lay off the hurtful jokes. There is also some asking to be done about her point of view, one way to start the talk is to maybe ask her how things are affecting her. &#8220;<em>I know we&#8217;ve been through some changes, and I get from the jokes that you make that you&#8217;re still really processing them. I know it was hard for you to see me go through that crisis. Can you tell me a little bit about what it&#8217;s been like for you? In a perfect world, where you get everything you want, how would our relationship work? Is there a way we can make the relationship work better for both of us?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s okay for a partner to belittle you for having needs, or make jokes about your health needs, or laugh off your very real concerns and issues, and this way of opening the conversation might seem way nicer than she deserves. My reasoning is this:  When you have to have a very difficult conversation, it helps to treat people as you want to be treated. You are modeling good behavior by being up front about your needs and asking her to articulate hers in the hopes that she will rise to the occasion.</p>
<p>In the most generous possible interpretation of her behavior maybe the jokes are her way of getting uncomfortable feelings out there that she didn&#8217;t ever feel safe to talk about when you guys were in full &#8220;gonna die, can&#8217;t talk now&#8221; mode.  A drastic change in diet or energy or what activities you do does affect the other person in the relationship, not to mention being a caregiver or watching someone you love go through a huge medical crisis.Whatever happened to her during that time was definitely happening to you way more, obviously, but *something* was happening to her and maybe she needs a safe place to talk about how scared she was. If she is a new partner and wasn&#8217;t with you during the time before the transplant, maybe she doesn&#8217;t fully understand what happened and how serious it was, and needs to be told explicitly what it&#8217;s like for you.</p>
<p>Your health needs and not-being-belittled-by-someone-who-says-they-love-you needs trump her feelings, obviously. But the best way to figure out if this is a My Girlfriend Is Bad At Communicating vs. My Girlfriend Lacks Empathy situation is to ask outright and give her the opportunity to surprise you with doing the right thing.  This talk might be a much needed way to process everything together and find a way forward. If it goes well, consider seeing a couples counselor where you can have an ongoing conversation about this and really work on communication.</p>
<p>Sadly, it may be the time you find out that you guys are really not on the same page. Maybe the changes in your lifestyle really are &#8220;unbearable&#8221; for your girlfriend. That is something she gets to decide, and she gets to leave and seek another partner. But she doesn&#8217;t get to hang around and be mean to you. If<em id="__mceDel"> </em>you open up and she makes fun of you, laughs it off, and keeps going with the jokes, realize that there are people out there who won&#8217;t treat you this way. And if she for one second implies that &#8220;someone in your condition&#8221; is lucky to have her and that you won&#8217;t be able to find anyone else, run (or wheel yourself, or crawl) for the nearest exit. That is a big, bad sign that she is emotionally abusing you, and that is 100% never okay.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5328/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5328/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5328&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/03/18/461-my-partner-makes-hurtful-jokes-about-my-health-situation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>106</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
