<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>CaptainAwkward.com</title>
	<atom:link href="http://captainawkward.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://captainawkward.com</link>
	<description>Advice. Staircase Wit. Faux Pas. Movies.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 13:12:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='captainawkward.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>CaptainAwkward.com</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://captainawkward.com/osd.xml" title="CaptainAwkward.com" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://captainawkward.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>#474: How do I get my coworker to shut up?</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/19/474-how-do-i-get-my-coworker-to-shut-up/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/19/474-how-do-i-get-my-coworker-to-shut-up/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 12:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chatty people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coworkers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shutting down conversations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5407</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Captain Awkward, I need advice on how to tell a work friend politely to just shut up.  He’s a very nice guy &#8211; super friendly and sociable, which is kind of the problem. You see, he is WAY too talkative. He sometimes says things that are completely out of left field, and he tends [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5407&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward,</em></p>
<p><em>I need advice on how to tell a work friend politely to just shut up. </em></p>
<p><em>He’s a very nice guy &#8211; super friendly and sociable, which is kind of the problem. You see, he is WAY too talkative. He sometimes says things that are completely out of left field, and he tends to go on for AGES, often getting wrapped up in completely useless details. When he starts talking, everyone else has to be quiet and listen to his long and winding tale until he gets to the end, at which point we are all relieved and can get on with the conversation.</em></p>
<p><em>He is utterly lacking a social gauge and has no idea of how much it’s appropriate to say and for how long it’s OK to speak. I’d compare it to the social component of Asperger’s, but strangely this guy also loves to socialise. Anyway, it’s a big problem at work because everything has to stop while he tells a story – yesterday he talked at me for 10 minutes straight, totally unprompted, about the six Chinese holidays where people visit their parents, listing them in order.</em></p>
<p><em>I don’t know how to let him know that this is an issue for me (and other people in the office), or what to say when he starts to ramble. He seems to miss all the hints, strong and subtle. I feel like a script or two would really help me out.</em></p>
<p><em>Sincerely,</em><br />
<em>Tired Listener</em></p>
<p><span id="more-5407"></span></p>
<p>Dear Tired Listener:</p>
<p>No more hints. And no more worries about exiting conversations <a title="#336: Gracefully exiting from conversations." href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/08/27/336-gracefully-exiting-from-conversations/">gracefully</a>.</p>
<p>And while interrupting people is generally rude, you get a pass with people who won&#8217;t ever stop talking and who don&#8217;t (for whatever reason, not all annoying behavior leads back to a diagnosis) gauge whether their audience wants to hear what they have to say.</p>
<p>Next time he starts one of these things, interrupt him.</p>
<p><em>&#8220;(Coworker), this seems like a long story, and frankly, I don&#8217;t have time to listen to it.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>And then turn back to your work.</p>
<p>Variations:</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Coworker, sorry, I&#8217;m not interested in hearing about that right now.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Coworker, sorry, I&#8217;ve totally stopped following what you are saying. Anyway, I have to get back to work.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Coworker, was there a point to this? I&#8217;m actually trying to focus on (work problem).&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Coworker, were you talking to someone in particular? Because if you were talking to me, I am trying to focus on work and I can&#8217;t listen to you right now.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Do not invoke &#8220;everyone&#8221; or &#8220;the group.&#8221; It doesn&#8217;t matter if everyone else feels as you do, and that&#8217;s not helpful from a logic standpoint of convincing someone to change a behavior. The brave, classy thing to do is to speak only to your own experience. Keep it short, keep your tone even and light, like you expect that he will be reasonable and do the cool thing.</p>
<p><a title="Reader Questions #8, #9, #10, and #11:  Short Answer Friday" href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/01/21/reader-questions-8-9-10-and-11-short-answer-friday/">Leaving the room </a>is another technique that you can employ. <em>&#8220;Oops, can&#8217;t listen right now, need to check the fax machine/get a drink of water/use the restroom/go ask someone in another department a question/fish something out of my car/make a phone call</em>.&#8221; Get a lot of exercise and stretch your legs, a lot. Up your water intake to the actually recommended amount. Your coworkers will jealously watch you go.</p>
<p>Is Talkative Coworker gonna be confused and sad at first? Yep. You&#8217;ve always listened to his stories before, and you might see him escalate his behavior temporarily to try harder to be heard. I had a person in my friend circle a while back who was like this &#8211; long stories made entirely of &#8220;middle&#8221;, to the point where I wondered sometimes if it wasn&#8217;t performance art to demonstrate the <a title="The Boring Baroque Response" href="http://www.howstuffworks.com/vsd2.htm">boring baroque response</a>, constant talking, and no ability to see when everyone around was tuning out or silently begging them to stop. The only things that worked were &#8220;<em>(Name), can this be quiet time now?</em>&#8221; or &#8220;<em>(Name), I&#8217;ve totally lost the thread of this story</em>&#8221; or &#8220;<em>(Name), I&#8217;m going to have to cut you off there, I am not really interested in hearing about this right now,&#8221;</em> or, honestly, staying on the other side of parties from them and leaving rooms when they entered them. This person only responded to interruption + total bluntness. They didn&#8217;t get offended (though sometimes would launch into a long explanation of the history and psychology of why they think they talk so much, and <strong>that</strong> would have to be cut off), and they sure as hell didn&#8217;t change their ways, so part of remaining friends with this person was always going to entail dealing with this.</p>
<p>Go ahead and let your coworker be hurt/sad/confused. If he didn&#8217;t learn that this behavior is not welcome before now, he has to learn now, and being blunt and direct is actually the most respectful way you can deal with him. If he asks you if something is wrong, be honest. &#8220;<em>I like you fine, but sometimes your stories go on for a while, and it&#8217;s really distracting when I am trying to work. I&#8217;m sorry I let it go on so long without saying anything. I don&#8217;t want to hurt your feelings or be rude, but I do need to be honest when I need to tune out and get back to work.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>If you want to remain on friendly terms, once a day ask him how he is doing and budget a good 10 minutes to listening to him before saying &#8220;<em>That&#8217;s great! Now I have to get back to work.</em>&#8221; If at all possible, do this in the break room or a space other than your desk. &#8220;<em>Coworker, I&#8217;m going to grab some tea. Want to walk with me and tell me that story you started earlier?&#8221;</em> It sends a message that you don&#8217;t hate him, you just need work to be about work. And it sets up a ritual &#8211; walking to the kitchen, brewing tea, and walking back you are totally into his stories, but when you get back to your desk story time is over.</p>
<p>If bringing headphones will help you and is allowed, by all means use them for now while you are trying to reset the relationship.</p>
<p>I realize that this might put a temporary damper on the other friendly socializing that goes on around the office, but I think your coworkers will pick up the hint and the example from you and agree to &#8220;Quiet Time Tuesdays&#8221; or whatever.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5407/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5407/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5407&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/19/474-how-do-i-get-my-coworker-to-shut-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#473: A gentle breakup is still a breakup.</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/19/472-sorry-you-were-dumped/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/19/472-sorry-you-were-dumped/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 11:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rejection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5391</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Captain Awkward, A few months ago I started seeing a kind, wonderful man who I fell hard for, quickly. We had a wonderful time together and he was very involved in planning dates, initiating physical affection, starting conversations, etc. After about a month, before we&#8217;d had sex, he told me he was not ready [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5391&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward,</em></p>
<p><em> A few months ago I started seeing a kind, wonderful man who I fell hard for, quickly. We had a wonderful time together and he was very involved in planning dates, initiating physical affection, starting conversations, etc. After about a month, before we&#8217;d had sex, he told me he was not ready for a relationship (although he was the one who asked me out) because he realized he was not as recovered from his divorce as he thought. I don&#8217;t know the full details (I figured I had plenty of time to get them as we got to know each other better) but I do know he&#8217;s in his late 20s, was in that relationship for nine years, and was divorced less than one year when we met. </em></p>
<p><em> I understand and accept that explanation. Being a few years younger, and never divorced, I know that I can&#8217;t possibly put myself in his shoes or begrudge him his decision. I thanked him for being honest, told him I&#8217;d enjoyed our time together, and have not contacted him since. That was literally all I said. I started seeing other people; however, I haven&#8217;t been able to forget him and that over-the-moon feeling I had when we spent time together. I&#8217;ve been in long and short relationships, a few of them fantastic, but I have never felt that way about anyone, and I can&#8217;t stop thinking about him. I haven&#8217;t been able to go on more than a couple dates with anyone I&#8217;ve met since, although they&#8217;ve all been interesting, interested, and treated me amazingly.</em></p>
<p><em> I feel like I may have made a mistake in not letting him know how I feel or letting him know that I have no intention of pressuring him into a serious relationship, I just want to spend more time with him and have fun together. I&#8217;ve always believed that if someone likes you, they will make it happen, but I also know that this situation is a little more complicated. At this point, I have little to no expectation that he will want to get back with me, but I&#8217;ve been longing to contact him just so that I can say I did try for something I badly want. My heart can&#8217;t quite accept that something so promising can go away just like that, and I don&#8217;t want to always regret never giving it a shot. Will I feel better if I say something, and at least have closure, or will I be embarrassing myself and destroying my pride? If not, how do I move on from the knowledge that I may have met the right one at the wrong time?</em></p>
<p><em> Pining</em></p>
<p><span id="more-5391"></span></p>
<p>Dear Pining:</p>
<p>This guy doesn&#8217;t want to be with you. &#8220;<em>Not ready for a relationship right now</em>&#8221; almost always means &#8220;<em>I don&#8217;t want a relationship WITH YOU.&#8221;</em> Timing matters sometimes, yes, and people reconnect sometimes, yes, but if he were feeling the same connection to you that you were feeling to him, timing would not matter and you would be together. Yes, he dated you. Yes, he initiated hanging out and physical affection. You offer these details as proof that he really wanted something to happen, and yes, he really wanted to date you for a while and figure out if there was a lasting connection there. Chemistry is great, but it isn&#8217;t everything, and <a title="#465: Life after Darth" href="http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/14/465-life-after-darth/">it can fool us badly</a>. It sucks when everything seems to be going well, the person is giving you all these signs that they like you, and you are responding the way you are supposed to to that attention, and then, *poof.* See Shirley Jackson&#8217;s short story <a title="The Daeomon Lover" href="http://literaryfictions.com/poetry-corner/the-daemon-lover-by-shirley-jackson/">The Daemon Lover </a>for a good illustration of that emotional landscape. But if the shoe were on the other foot, as it is with the nice men you&#8217;ve been dating since, you know that kisses aren&#8217;t contracts, and a few dates is not a forever commitment, it is a period where you are evaluating and deciding if you want another person in your life. He decided. He decided, &#8220;No.&#8221;</p>
<p>The best way to get over pining like this is to stop indulging the &#8220;<em>If onlys&#8230;</em>.&#8221; (If only we had met a few months later! If only he weren&#8217;t so recently out of a relationship! I forgive him! We can make it work!) and remind yourself of the (admittedly cruel) fact: He had the opportunity to choose me, and he chose otherwise. Those &#8220;if onlys&#8221; are lies we tell ourselves, about how this was supposed to work out but cruel fate intervened, when the truth is that this was about a series of decisions.</p>
<p>If someone I&#8217;d gone on a few dates with and broken things off with reached out to me and explained how they didn&#8217;t want to bug me or pressure me into anything, but they couldn&#8217;t stop thinking about me and that memories of our brief time with them were ruining their ability to date other people, and could we just spend some time together?, I would respond politely like this:</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>That is very flattering, but sadly, I think I made the right decision for me. I wish you well, though!&#8221;</em></p>
<p>And then I would block all electronic means of communication and dread running into them again. Because that is way too much pressure to ever have even the possibility of a casual, fun, hangout, it is not actually flattering, and I don&#8217;t want that much power over another person&#8217;s happiness.</p>
<p>Letter Writer, you did the cool thing. You are in the middle of doing the cool thing! Which is to accept rejection as rejection and try to move on. If things are meant to work out with this guy &#8211; he has a change of heart, or you guys just drift back into each other&#8217;s lives &#8211; it will happen. Because your interests and social circles and lives will carry you back together. I hope it happens and I am proved very, very, very wrong. But you can&#8217;t plan for that, and you can&#8217;t decide that. You have to accept that he has already decided. You are being so sweet to try to be understanding and &#8220;forgive&#8221; him his reasons, but you don&#8217;t get extra credit for that, and he doesn&#8217;t owe you anything.</p>
<p>He can&#8217;t give you closure. You make that for yourself.</p>
<p>I am so sorry, that sucks, and I have been there, and there is no cure but letting more time pass and pulling yourself out of &#8220;If only&#8230;&#8221; land. Treat it like a breakup and grieve it like a breakup. If dating isn&#8217;t making you feel good, throw yourself into other parts of your life and give it a break for a while. It will be there when you want it again.</p>
<p>Because there are more dudes on earth, Horatio. He is not the right one at the wrong time, because he is not the right one (if he were, you would be together and it would be easier than this). The things about you that attracted this guy and the series of great guys who treat you well are still present in you, and you have more information now about the kind of person you are looking for. You are right not to waste time getting more deeply involved with people who don&#8217;t excite you the way this guy did (which is what he did when he broke things off with you, and well within his rights). The next time something like this comes along, you&#8217;ll recognize it and value it, and hopefully it will <a title="Statistically Accurate Love Song" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IeZMIgheZro">one of the possible right ones </a>at the right time.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5391/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5391/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5391&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/19/472-sorry-you-were-dumped/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#470, #471 and #472: Correcting Names</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/18/470-correcting-names/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/18/470-correcting-names/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Families]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boundaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[names]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nicknames]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speaking up]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5381</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Person, My friends have gotten into the habit of calling me by a nickname, which would be wonderful if they had asked first, but otherwise I&#8217;m okay with it. The problem comes when they introduce me to people using that nickname, leading those people to think that it&#8217;s my real name and so they [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5381&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dear Person,</em></p>
<p><em>My friends have gotten into the habit of calling me by a nickname, which would be wonderful if they had asked first, but otherwise I&#8217;m okay with it. The problem comes when they introduce me to people using that nickname, leading those people to think that it&#8217;s my real name and so they use it too. So now I have a dozen people all calling me by a nickname and I can&#8217;t help but flinch inwardly when they use it. I want them to call me by my actual name but I don&#8217;t know how to tell them that and I don&#8217;t know how to broach the subject of not introducing me with it to my friends either. To be quite honest, I&#8217;d prefer a few of my friends to stop calling me by it too but I don&#8217;t know how to tell them to stop without making them feel bad about it. I&#8217;m also worried that bringing it up at all will be disregarded or made fun of because to them it&#8217;s just a name and doesn&#8217;t have any meaning while to me it means a whole frakking lot. Is there any way to fix this?</em></p>
<p>There is a way to fix this. There is no way to do it without risking making your friends feel bad.</p>
<p>But right now, YOU feel bad. Because having someone consistently mess up or diminish your name is <a title="Post Bourgie: What's In A Name? Kind of A Lot" href="http://www.postbourgie.com/2013/02/26/whats-in-a-name-kind-of-a-lot/">dehumanizing</a>.</p>
<p>And how your friends feel about misnaming you is firmly under the heading of Their Shit To Deal With On Their Own Time. Embarrassed? Sad you didn&#8217;t correct them before? Justified and wanting to argue that what they do is ok? Whatever they feel, it is not your problem, and it will pass soon.</p>
<p>This is important, and it&#8217;s important that you give yourself permission to speak up about it!</p>
<p>So, the way to do this is to wait until one of them uses the nickname, and say &#8220;<em>Hey, that reminds me. I&#8217;d prefer to go by (Actual Name) from now on, thanks.&#8221; </em>And when they introduce you to someone new, hold out your hand and say<em> &#8220;Actually, my name is (Real Name). (Nickname) is just a nickname that I&#8217;ve been trying to get out from under.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>If they ask why, or make a big deal about how you didn&#8217;t say anything before, they are derailing. Don&#8217;t offer any explanation. Explanation implies that this is up for negotiation. &#8220;<em>Whatever, don&#8217;t worry about the past, just, in the future, call me (Actual Name) and everything will be cool. Thank you.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>This offers an interesting and useful test for new people that you meet. Cool new people, the kind you want in your life, will immediately switch to your actual name and make a conscious effort to use it. Douche-y new people, the kind you don&#8217;t want in your life, will see your name as a vulnerable spot and start poking it by using the nickname.</p>
<p>With your old friends, give it a little bit of time to sink in &#8211; habits die hard &#8211; but if people consistently misname you, switch to a boundary enforcement strategy of one correction + leaving (or asking other person to leave) conversation if things don&#8217;t improve.</p>
<p>#471 and 2 below the jump.</p>
<p><span id="more-5381"></span><em>Dear Captain Awkward, </em><br />
<em>I hope you can help with this situation with my mother. I am an adult in my thirties and do not live at home. Prior to this, my relationship with her was OK, although there were some problems. </em></p>
<p><em>Before Christmas I told her that I wanted to change my name to a gender-neutral one. Since then, things have gone downhill between us. I understand and accept that she feels hurt at this decision, however I do not feel her behaviour is reasonable and don&#8217;t know how to deal with it. </em></p>
<p><em>We communicate via email, and almost every reply I receive says how much I have hurt her, how sad she is and what was wrong with my last email. Sometimes there is bonus nonsensical statements mixed in as well which come out of nowhere. </em></p>
<p><em>What hurts the most is that she does not listen to what I say. She makes up her own reasons for my decision (which have no basis in reality) and accuses me of doing things I&#8217;m not and then getting hurt at them (such as wanting to disown her). If I say how I feel, I get long emails telling me why I am wrong and why my feelings are wrong. I am always the one in the wrong!</em></p>
<p><em>If I call her out on anything, she says I have &#8220;misconstrued&#8221; what she said if there is proof, or out right denies saying it. </em></p>
<p><em>Briefly some of the other things she is doing is acting like I am responsible for her feelings, being passive aggressive, refuses to tell me how sick family members are doing, blaming me for her health problems, threatening to sue my doctor, telling me I can not be gay because of my disability, refusing to use my new name, sending excessive numbers of emails (5 in half an hour last night!), saying she would never hurt me because she loves me, etc.</em></p>
<p><em>I have seen a counsellor, read books and have been trying to phrase everything correctly/politely/assertively, but it&#8217;s not helping. I no longer feel anxious when checking my email or panicking when I see an email from her but still spend hours pondering how to reply to each email. </em></p>
<p><em>I am not the best at this sort of thing as I&#8217;m standing up to her for the first time. I tend to avoid conflict and admit I do not answer every email. Sometimes they are so offensive I can not think of any response other than incoherent screaming. </em></p>
<p><em>I want to remain in contact with her if possible, but it feels it would be so much easier to refuse any contact at all. Please help?</em></p>
<p>Dear LW #471</p>
<p>Hello, this is a rough one, because mother-child bond and what someone is named is primal stuff, and it will take some time for things to be okay (or to find a new normal) after she has treated you so poorly..</p>
<p>However, an ironclad boundary exists:</p>
<p><strong>Your mom&#8217;s complex feelings about your name change are not your problem, and you can exempt yourself from taking care of her around this.</strong></p>
<p>Stop explaining why or trying to convince her. Let her feel how she wants. As long as she processes those feelings away from you, and as long as she addresses you by your name, let everything else go. She doesn&#8217;t have to like it. She doesn&#8217;t have to &#8220;accept&#8221; it, or whatever. She does have to call you by your name and stop being mean to you.</p>
<p>If cutting off contact is the best way to take care of yourself, then that option remains open for you. And it doesn&#8217;t have to be permanent &#8211; a break could be what both of you need right now.</p>
<p>If emails are a problem, set up an email filter, and take a break from even looking at it for a good while. Like, a month. Or several months. Or, never.</p>
<p>If your goal is to eventually rebuild a relationship, I don&#8217;t think it will work to totally freeze her out, so choose some periodic form of interaction. A phone call every few weeks. A post card in the mail. Keep it short and light. &#8220;<em>Hi mom, hope you are well, saw x thing and thought of you, Love, Your New Name.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>And then you reward contact that is respectful (friendly in turn, uses your name) and ignore contact that is disrespectful or overwhelming for you. Delete emails that are mean. End phone conversations at the first mean word. Ignore communications directed at OldName.</p>
<p>Underlying message: &#8220;<em>I am trying very hard to stay in touch with you and create a series of positive interactions, even though things are hard between us now</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>The message will either be received and respected, or not, at which point you have the option of pulling back contact altogether or reopening a discussion where you clearly lay out the risks.</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Mom, I am not going to apologize for or further discuss changing my name, and I do not want to hear any more of your thoughts about that. I want to have a good relationship with you and stay in touch with you, but if we keep rehashing this discussion or you keep saying hurtful things (or misnaming me), I am going to have to take a break from communicating with you.  I don&#8217;t want to do that, but I also can&#8217;t keep absorbing the hurtful things you say. Can you agree to use (correct name) and to make the rest of the subject off-limits? I sure hope so, because I love you very much.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>It is unfair and emotionally draining, and a lot of work, so make sure you are practicing excellent self care in the interim. Keep your expectations low &#8211; a &#8220;win&#8221; here is her having an innocuous conversation with you about something else where she uses your new name without scare quotes around it. This tactic of selectively responding to communications is imperfect, but <a title="#357: Dispatches from the Mean Old People Internet" href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/09/19/357-dispatches-from-the-mean-old-people-internet/">it allowed me to preserve a loving relationship with my elderly Grampa even when his political opinions </a>(and the many-fonted emails) became quite ugly and extreme.</p>
<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward:</em></p>
<p><em> I changed my first name about six months ago for vague gender reasons, and by now I&#8217;ve told pretty much everyone I reasonably can. But I still run into acquaintances sometimes who haven&#8217;t heard, like people I had class with ages ago or parents I used to babysit for, and they&#8217;ll call me my old name.</em></p>
<p><em> I usually just say hello back and ignore the name thing, and usually it happens one time and doesn&#8217;t really matter, but sometimes I end up running into them again and again and each time it gets more awkward. How should I handle this situation?</em></p>
<p>Dear LW #472:</p>
<p>Correct them!  The first time out, &#8220;<em>Hey, I go by _____  now</em>.&#8221; The second time out, &#8220;<em>I forgot to mention it last time we saw each other, but I go by ______ now</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>They&#8217;ll get the picture, and most people will follow your lead that this is happy news and not that big a deal. People don&#8217;t want to accidentally call you the wrong name, and they would not want it to be this awkward and worrisome for you. Most of them will appreciate being corrected and go with the flow.</p>
<p>There have been a lot of great writing in the feminist/womanist blogosphere lately under the heading &#8220;Let&#8217;s Talk About Names&#8221; &#8211; I&#8217;d start with posts at <a title="Are Woman Human?" href="http://arewomenhuman.me/">Grace&#8217;s site</a>, like Flavia&#8217;s <a title="Let's Talk About Names: Flavia" href="http://arewomenhuman.me/2013/03/29/lets-talk-about-names-flavia/">beautiful essay</a>, and the posts at <a title="Flyover Feminism" href="http://flyoverfeminism.com/">Flyover Feminism.</a></p>
<p>I haven&#8217;t read even close to all the posts in the series, but the posts I have read so far remind me how names are tied up with people&#8217;s human rights and rights to self-determination. Letter Writers, this isn&#8217;t small stuff, so stand up for your names without apology.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5381/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5381/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5381&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/18/470-correcting-names/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>187</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#468 and #469: &#8220;Hey, knock it off&#8221;, or, Constructive Conflict, Continued.</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/17/468-and-469-hey-knock-it-off-or-constructive-conflict-continued/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/17/468-and-469-hey-knock-it-off-or-constructive-conflict-continued/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 12:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geek Social Fallacies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How Not To Be]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to say no]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manipulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Overthinking It]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rejection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roommates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saying no]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Interactions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boundaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[setting boundaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the art of no]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5379</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Jolly&#8217;s great comment to Monday&#8217;s post is going to be very relevant to these seemingly very different questions: &#8220;You also don’t necessarily have to bring some of these things up in one big confrontation about The Whole Pattern Of Her Sucking. You could just make a point of standing up for yourself when she does [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5379&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jolly&#8217;s <a title="Comment on My Possessive Friend is Weirding Me Out" href="http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/466-possessive-friend-is-weirding-me-out/#comment-50967">great comment to Monday&#8217;s post</a> is going to be very relevant to these seemingly very different questions:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;You also don’t necessarily have to bring some of these things up in one big confrontation about The Whole Pattern Of Her Sucking. You could just make a point of standing up for yourself when she does the trampling behavior in the future. Next time she interrupts you, interrupt her back with a big, assertive, “EXCUSE ME, N, YOU ACCIDENTALLY INTERRUPTED ME WHEN I WAS IN THE MIDDLE OF A STORY. ANYWAY, BOYFRIEND AND I…” She physically nudges you out of a circle? Cut her off with a tap on the shoulder and a big, “EXCUSE ME, N, BUT YOU JUST PUSHED ME COMPLETELY OUT OF THE CONVERSATION. I AM MOVING HERE, HOW ABOUT YOU SIT HERE.” Don’t sound angry, just be very direct and assertive. You see what she is doing, everyone else sees what she is doing, good chance she also sees what she is doing, and just thinks she is being sneaky. Or maybe she has no idea. But either way, there is nothing wrong with a strong verbal reminder every time she attempts to trample completely over you, to let her know that she is “accidentally” being completely obnoxious. 50/50 whether she will embarrass herself in a huffy rage, or quietly correct her behavior. Either way, it will probably go some way to keeping her from continuing this kind of garbage.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Yes. It is hard for more reserved people to get into the habit of speaking up in the moment &#8211; we&#8217;d mostly prefer to observe quietly, analyze later, and plan our next social interaction as if it&#8217;s a military campaign. But learning to speak up in the moment is a great, great habit to develop, and it is above all a <strong>habit</strong> &#8211; developed over time, requires practice, doesn&#8217;t have to be perfectly executed to be effective. Let&#8217;s dive in.</p>
<p><span id="more-5379"></span></p>
<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward:</em></p>
<p><em>My roommate is the worst listener I&#8217;ve ever met. If not listening (or not conveying that she&#8217;s listening) were an olympic sport, she&#8217;d have more gold medals than Michael Phelps (hyperbolic, I know, but actually.) </em></p>
<p><em>I avoid conversation with her because when we do talk, she talks over me. Sometimes I&#8217;ll make a statement, and as soon as I&#8217;m done speaking she&#8217;ll ignore me and move on to a new topic. When she is listening to me, sometimes she&#8217;ll try to guess the end of my sentence, and start speaking over me. </em></p>
<p><em>I feel like this is somewhat related to her patronizing or condescending behavior. She has taken on the identity of &#8220;The Caring, Maternal One&#8221; in our shared group of friends. To her, this means badgering people about how much they&#8217;ve had to drink when we go out, and why smoking is evil and unhealthy. While sometimes rants like this are useful, hers are always unwarranted, and seem to come from a place of superiority. She is covertly judgmental of my behavior when I drink. She&#8217;ll make comments like &#8220;I&#8217;m so proud you didn&#8217;t drink too much!&#8221; all because of one experience where I drank too much and spent the night vomiting. I was pretty embarrassed about it at the time, and learned from the experience. I don&#8217;t think bringing it up over and over is warranted. </em></p>
<p><em>Maybe I should add that roommate has ADD, and takes prescribed medication for it. While I know that a lot has been said here about how mental illness/related issues are not an excuse for hurtful behavior, I was wondering if that might have something to do with her inability to focus on what I&#8217;m saying? Maybe this isn&#8217;t related at all? Perhaps some lovely person who has more insight into these issues could enlighten me. </em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve lived with my roommate all this year, and we&#8217;re living together next year (this is set in stone&#8211;the housing forms are signed). Generally we get along fine, but I feel like I spend a lot of time feeling frustrated by these issues. Thus far I&#8217;ve kind of been ignoring it, and recognizing that we just have to live together, we don&#8217;t have to be BEST FRIENDS 4EVAH. Should I bother to bring it to her attention? How should I go about this?</em></p>
<p><em>Talked At And Over (#468)</em></p>
<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward:</em></p>
<p><em>Hello, </em></p>
<p><em>I am in a longterm poly relationship with a man. We are really solidly together, and supportive of each other&#8217;s outside dating life. </em></p>
<p><em>A few years back we met Friend, and husband and her flirted like nobodies business. This was cool. </em></p>
<p><em>She then got jealously possessive of Husband. If he talked women, or flirted, Friend would behave poorly. She even shoved a woman off of his lap once, making it a &#8220;joke&#8221;. She started introducing herself as our wife to folks. She is straight, and I am generally female identified, so that caught me off guard. </em></p>
<p><em>I told Husband it bothered me. He was supportive, and thought, perhaps it was because she wanted to be in a relationship, and acknowledged his attraction/flirting. He put it all on the table and asked her out. He did so in a very low key way to make sure he was open to her rejection, and still voiced his value in her friendship. </em></p>
<p><em>Instead of saying no, Friend came to me presenting the situation as if Husband was cheating. I told her she had been flirting with him, so he decided to ask if she wanted more than that. She avoided any real response, and I had to tell Husband her reaction. We assumed that would be the end of it. </em></p>
<p><em>She still came over to hang out, but unilaterally treated Husband venomously, to the point that folks in our friend group wanted to know what was going on. </em></p>
<p><em>We stopped hanging out with her, and &#8220;just didn&#8217;t have time&#8221;. She could be great to me, but it&#8217;s not fun watching someone spit snark, passive aggressive comments, and just say mean crap to someone you love, so I didn&#8217;t want to hang with her either. </em></p>
<p><em>She&#8217;s just showed up out of the blue like nothing has happened. We decided that perhaps her own troubled dating history didn&#8217;t allow her to reject someone without making them a villain. Husband swallowed the hurt of having her be so nasty to him, and moved on. </em></p>
<p><em>The problem? Now she&#8217;s back to flirting with him, being overly jealous of his attention to other women, and being actively sulky when he point blank refuses to flirt back. She&#8217;s introducing herself as our wife again, despite repeated corrections, and actually crawled on a bed in front of Husband making sexually explicit comments.</em></p>
<p><em>We haven&#8217;t addressed this with her at all, because she is poor at communicating, and quite honestly, we are both gun shy about her reaction. Flirting is off the menu, and she can be a friend, but nothing more. She just won&#8217;t stop even when we correct the situation. </em></p>
<p><em>Any scripts either of us could use?</em></p>
<p><em>Bewildered Bystander (#469)</em></p>
<p>Both of these questions should be filed under &#8220;Setting boundaries with people who are bad at understanding boundaries, and who will probably not respond well to having a big talk about it<em>.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>&#8220;When you ____, I feel _____&#8221; conversations are for relationships that you are very invested in, and where you think there is a reasonable chance of the other person Getting The Clue Already.</p>
<p>Sometimes, after you&#8217;ve had that talk, or when you don&#8217;t think that talk will work, it&#8217;s not worth delving that far into it. It&#8217;s a pretty common fallacy among educated sorts that if we could just make people understand the things we know, they would see the world as we do and behave as we would. It&#8217;s frustrating because sometimes it works beautifully, but other times we just have to say &#8220;self-awareness is not transitive&#8221; and figure out how much emotional energy we want to invest in getting oblivious people to wise up and change their ways. It is freeing to realize that it really doesn&#8217;t matter if they understand why their behavior is wrong, and understand where we&#8217;re coming from when we ask them to change it. It matters that they stop doing the bad thing.</p>
<p>So, #468, I don&#8217;t know if you will get your roommate to realize what she is doing and change her overall pattern of behavior, but I do think you can change the dynamic somewhat by catching her when she&#8217;s interrupting you and calling attention to the behavior. There is a several step process that you can try out.</p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Interrupt her right back, and say: &#8221;<em>Roommate, you interrupted me. Did you realize?</em>&#8221; And then launch back into your point as if you expect to be heard.</p>
<p>If she listens, great. Success!</p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> If she zones out or interrupts you again, after being reminded/corrected, <a title="#336: Gracefully exiting from conversations." href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/08/27/336-gracefully-exiting-from-conversations/">find a way to end the conversation</a>. She&#8217;s obviously not interested in having one. You can pick this up another day, when you have the energy to start over again.</p>
<p>If she catches on to what is happening, i.e.- &#8220;<em>Why are you walking away from me?</em>&#8221; say &#8220;<em>You interrupted me several times, and I got frustrated. It seems like we should pick up this conversation another time.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>You brought up her ADD &#8211; she may have genuine trouble focusing. In that case, if she spaces out, it is on her to say &#8220;I<em>&#8216;m sorry, I am having trouble focusing on what you just said. Can you start from the beginning?</em>&#8221; If your stories run long, and you guys agree to it, she might reasonably ask you to invoke the <a title="Question #182: The Three Sentence Rule, or, How do I get my partner to shut up about Karl Popper?" href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/02/02/question-182-the-three-sentence-rule-or-how-do-i-get-my-partner-to-shut-up-about-karl-popper/">Three Sentence Rule</a>. Some people can&#8217;t read social cues for legitimate reasons. But everyone can understand when a friend says &#8220;<em>Please don&#8217;t interrupt me, I don&#8217;t like it,&#8221; </em>and try to be more aware of their behavior.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not on you to lay out a multi-step process for her to stop interrupting you. You are not her Life Tutor. You gently called attention to the behavior, and when it continued, you took steps to enforce the boundary by removing yourself from the conversation. You made it clear that if she wants to have actual conversations with you, she needs to listen better.</p>
<p>It is better if you remain focused on the present, restart the clock with each interaction, and give it a little bit of time. If this goes well, she will start to catch herself.</p>
<p>As for the comments about your drinking/Mother Hen stuff, I agree, that is pretty frustrating. Employ a similar approach of calling out the behavior when it happens. &#8220;<em>Actually, that&#8217;s pretty patronizing.&#8221; &#8220;I would prefer to leave that incident firmly in the past.&#8221;</em> &#8221;<em>I don&#8217;t need to be monitored or congratulated for not drinking, thanks.</em>&#8221;  Use short, declarative sentences. Resist the urge to over-explain or justify. And then shut down further conversation. The point isn&#8217;t to make her understand your point of view, the point is to make it unproductive and unsatisfying for her to go down these conversational roads in the first place.</p>
<p>To preserve this as a workable roommate situation, I suggest finding some kind of mutual activity or ritual (like, a shared TV fandom) where you spend a set, scheduled, structured time together every week. You could even break it down to a daily thing &#8211; my former roommates were pretty great about a) NO MORNING TALKING (&lt;3!)  b) 15-20 minutes of &#8220;<em>How was your day?</em>&#8221; at the end of the day before separating to our introvert corners, and c) periodic roommate dinner or movie/live theater outings. What you are doing is finding some friendly, cordial, casual social glue that gives you a series of positive interactions to build on. What you are also doing is mentally resetting the relationship (and the expectations around said relationship) from &#8220;intimate friend&#8221; to &#8220;roommate with whom I wish to remain on good terms.&#8221; Once you&#8217;ve put in your set time every day/every week, give yourself permission to check out and invest your emotional energy and share your important stuff with close friends who don&#8217;t interrupt and talk down to you.</p>
<p>Letter Writer #469, it seems like you are already correcting this person, who I will not call a friend.</p>
<p>The suggested steps for you are very similar, though there is one extra step that for sure needs to happen:</p>
<p><strong>Recognize that this lady is not actually your friend, and that you don&#8217;t actually like her or being around her.</strong></p>
<p>Stop making excuses that she&#8217;s not that bad. She&#8217;s that bad. Dudes don&#8217;t have a monopoly on creepy. Inappropriate touching or flirting when you&#8217;ve been specifically asked not to do that stuff is downright creepy. Therefore you should minimize contact. If she&#8217;s part of the scene you&#8217;re in, whatever, 1) plenty of people who share a pastime or a scene aren&#8217;t bosom buddies and find a way to politely co-exist 2) <a title="#322 &amp; #323 “My friend group has a case of the Creepy Dude. How do we clear that up?”" href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/08/07/322-323-my-friend-group-has-a-case-of-the-creepy-dude-how-do-we-clear-that-up/">minimizing creepy behavior that&#8217;s allowed to persist within a scene</a> is actually good for everyone in the scene.</p>
<p>So.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t invite her to anything at your house.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t accept any of her invitations. And don&#8217;t make polite &#8220;<em>we&#8217;d love to but we just don&#8217;t have time</em>&#8221; excuses. Don&#8217;t give a reason. &#8220;<em>Want to do x with me?&#8221; &#8220;No thanks.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>If you need to have a breakup conversation, have the conversation. &#8220;<em>Hey, ______, we really tried to make things work when you started coming around again, but it&#8217;s really not working for us. Sorry, I realize that&#8217;s not good news, but we&#8217;d prefer not to hang out anymore</em>.&#8221; And then let her feelings about that be her feelings, expressed/processed in the Land That Is Elsewhere.</p>
<p>When you do run into her at, say, mutual friend&#8217;s events, say a quick &#8220;Heyhowyoubeen&#8221; and then go talk to people you like.</p>
<p>When she does a thing that you don&#8217;t like, make the boundary clear and explicit. &#8220;Please don&#8217;t touch me.&#8221; &#8220;I don&#8217;t want to talk about that.&#8221; &#8220;That makes me uncomfortable.&#8221;</p>
<p>It seems like you are already giving her verbal corrections, but the behavior is continuing, so here is one step I would add:</p>
<p>She gets <strong>one</strong> verbal correction. If she persists or does whatever it is again, LEAVE. Walk away from her. Leave the room. Leave the party. Leave. Or ask her directly to leave, or get the hosts of whatever it is to ask her to leave. You don&#8217;t have to actually explain yourself or get her to understand anything. If you want to say something, be terse and direct. &#8220;<em>I asked you not to that, and it&#8217;s making me very uncomfortable. I am going over there. Do not follow me</em>. <em>I would like you to leave now.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>I sense that you are polite, easily embarrassed people who want to help this person who you used to feel affection toward save face. You guys are straight shooters who have excellent communication skills and excellent boundaries. Unfortunately, she is trading on that reluctance to make a scene and your general good manners as a way to crap all over your boundaries. If a scene needs to be made, make the fucking scene already. &#8220;STOP.&#8221; &#8220;I DON&#8217;T LIKE THAT.&#8221; &#8220;YOU SHOULD LEAVE NOW.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sometimes, if you can establish a pattern of &#8220;Hey, knock it off&#8221; it can be a way to set up a &#8220;Listen, we need to talk&#8221; discussion where you delve deeper into patterns and issues. It&#8217;s especially useful in resolving certain kinds of conflicts <a title="Saying “No” At Work" href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/03/31/saying-no-at-work/">at work</a>, where you have to create a paper trail that proves that you asked someone directly to stop the behavior. But &#8220;Hey, knock it off&#8221; has a power of its own.</p>
<p>All communication styles can be abused by people who use them in bad faith, and it is good to consider others&#8217; feelings and the consequences of your words before opening your mouth. But for over-thinkers, we tend to want to manage every part of every interaction and other people&#8217;s feelings about that interaction. By far the most common question I get is. &#8220;Person is violating my boundaries in the following terrible ways. How do I get them to stop <strong>without hurting their feelings?</strong>&#8221; And the answer is: You ask them to stop, and you let their feelings be their own. The flip side of this question is &#8220;How do I ask someone out in a way that guarantees that they will be happy about it and won&#8217;t reject me and things will never get awkward?&#8221; Again, the answer is: You ask them out, and you let their reactions to that be their own. Other people&#8217;s feelings are important, but they are not the total boss of you. To be so self-effacing that you think that asking people to stop interrupting you, or to stop crawling all over you at parties, or to hang out sometime constitutes you doing them some kind of emotional violence is a kind of egotism &#8211; you are giving yourself WAY too much power to control the future and other people.</p>
<p>Sometimes people do react very badly to these requests, and they treat you as if you are doing them emotional violence. Sometimes you <strong>say</strong> &#8220;Hey, knock it off&#8221; and the other person <strong>hears</strong> &#8220;YOU TERRIBLE PIECE OF SHIT WHO CAN&#8217;T DO ANYTHING RIGHT.&#8221; That is their jerkbrain talking, not something you did. It doesn&#8217;t feel good to learn that you were hurting someone&#8217;s feelings or making them feel bad, but it&#8217;s incredibly manipulative to answer &#8220;Please don&#8217;t flirt with me, I am uncomfortable&#8221; with &#8220;You hate me and I can&#8217;t do anything right&#8221; and force the person whose boundaries you&#8217;ve been violating to comfort you and rebuild your self-image.  When someone reacts disproportionately to a simple request (like <a title="#247: Marrying into a family with awful boundary issues, or, secrets of dealing with Highly Difficult People" href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/05/14/247-marrying-into-a-family-with-awful-boundary-issues-or-secrets-of-dealing-with-highly-difficult-people/">Alice</a>), it&#8217;s hard to hang back and let them get as weird as they want to and then still stand up for the thing you need. When someone tells you that you are stomping on their boundaries, the hardest thing sometimes can be to separate what they say from the messages of your own jerkbrain and give an adult response that doesn&#8217;t vomit your feelings all over them. Both of these are emotional skillsets that are part of having adult relationships, and I think that even if they weren&#8217;t installed or nurtured from childhood, they can be learned.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t have a rubric for always knowing when and how, a lot of this is trial and error, but I do know that a) speaking up for yourself will usually not end the world, b) you can survive making a mistake, and  c) you can survive someone else&#8217;s displeasure. <strong>There is no prize for being the most world&#8217;s most accommodating person</strong>. And if there were a prize, it would be &#8220;hanging out with people who walk all over you, being afraid to speak up, and silently seething at them, forever.&#8221;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5379/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5379&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/17/468-and-469-hey-knock-it-off-or-constructive-conflict-continued/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>87</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#467: How do I help my partner communicate better with his family?</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/16/467-how-do-i-help-my-partner-communicate-better-with-his-family/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/16/467-how-do-i-help-my-partner-communicate-better-with-his-family/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 14:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Families]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forced teaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sibling]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5374</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Cap&#8217;n, I don&#8217;t know how best to help my DH. This message follows us having a long, slightly drunk but happy and loving chat about his life. DH&#8217;s family history is complicated. His upbringing includes some things which, when we talk about them, he agrees were &#8220;probably abuse&#8221;, but explains that he&#8217;s somewhat normalised [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5374&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dear Cap&#8217;n,</em></p>
<p><em>I don&#8217;t know how best to help my DH. This message follows us having a long, slightly drunk but happy and loving chat about his life.</em></p>
<p><em>DH&#8217;s family history is complicated. His upbringing includes some things which, when we talk about them, he agrees were &#8220;probably abuse&#8221;, but explains that he&#8217;s somewhat normalised what happened to him, and tends to say it totally matter-of-factly, as though this were just how things are. His feelings &#8211; or lack of &#8211; are complicated by guilt. DH was born a sickly child, with complex medical needs that put a lot of strain on the family. His parents divorced partly due to the stress of it all. He did not cope well with his deformities or medical needs and his childhood was a mixture of being a bullying victim, being a bully, having serious anger issues and acting out. I&#8217;m sometimes amazed by the wonderful, loving, mentally balanced person he&#8217;s become without therapy or help.</em></p>
<p><em>DH doesn&#8217;t seem to know what sort of relationship he wants with his parents. He is amicable with them, visits his mother about once a month, enjoys talking to his father&#8230; but he won&#8217;t initiate contact, and he gets anxious if, for example, his mum tries to ask him to visit on short notice. At the same time, he&#8217;s just naturally bad at maintaining relationships and has asked me to help him keep in better contact with his gran and siblings. He&#8217;s never confronted either parent and even apologised to his father recently for being a &#8220;difficult child&#8221;.</em></p>
<p><em>At the same time, the abuse has only come out over a long time in small parts. and by the time I started to get the picture, we&#8217;d been together years and had started to build closer relationships with his parents. His mum in particular, who is always very kind and concerned and helpful, and I don&#8217;t know how to feel about her, or the FIL, or any of it. To be fair, DH doesn&#8217;t isn&#8217;t certain how he feels. He&#8217;s given me permission to ask his big sis for more info on their childhood, because his memory can cause him problems. She lives abroad though, and I&#8217;d feel weird asking by email.</em></p>
<p><em>Because of his relationship and memory difficulties, it&#8217;s my job to help him maintain contact with loved ones. But I don&#8217;t know how to do this where his parents are concerned. I don&#8217;t want to pressure him to get closer than he feels comfortable, but I also don&#8217;t want to be the woman that drives him from his family into hers, as his father&#8217;s second wife has started doing with him.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;d love some advice please!</em></p>
<p>This statement: &#8220;<em>Because of his relationship and memory difficulties, it&#8217;s my job to help him maintain contact with loved ones</em>.&#8221; from your letter set off my Yikes-o-meter. Yikes!</p>
<p>Here is my advice:</p>
<p>Do not volunteer to be the carrier for his communication and relationship with his family, or to sort out these memories. Do not email his sister. It is only &#8220;your job&#8221; if you choose it, and you get to choose to not make it your job.</p>
<p>You can be a sounding board.</p>
<p>You can be a listening ear.</p>
<p>You should not be an ambassador or a manager. And you don&#8217;t have to feel any particular thing. HE doesn&#8217;t have to feel any particular thing.</p>
<p>Even in much less extreme situations (history of abuse, memory problems, disability) men sometimes expect that women will do the emotional work of the relationship, up to and including remembering everyone in HIS family&#8217;s birthday and buying presents/sending cards/keeping in touch. I think this sets a bad precedent, where his messed up family issues are now something that are the present stuff of your relationship. I&#8217;m sure he feels great after this chat you guys had; he just transferred all responsibility for sorting out his messy past over to you and now you&#8217;re writing me for advice on how to do it when really HE could write in for advice (not necessarily here, but somewhere) on how to do it.</p>
<p>This is HIS family.</p>
<p>This is HIS history.</p>
<p>This is HIS thing to solve.</p>
<p>I think it is admirable that you want to help your husband, and admirable that he wants to get back in touch with people and start sorting things out. And I think there is no one perfect way that he has to feel about a history of abuse. It is possible for people to have very dysfunctional relationships as children that grow into much more mellow relationships as people age, get power and autonomy, and create a series of positive interactions to build on.</p>
<p>But it is on HIM to contact his sister, sort out his memories, and deal with them (with the help of a professional, if necessary), and keep in better touch with his gran and his siblings. &#8220;Terrible at maintaining relationships&#8221; isn&#8217;t an actual condition, it&#8217;s a series of choices that have turned into a habit.</p>
<p>The best way to get in touch with people you haven&#8217;t talked to in a while is to send a greeting. People love getting mail that isn&#8217;t bills, so maybe write a postcard. &#8220;<em>Dear _____, I hope you are well. I read/saw/ate/experienced this thing recently that made me think of you and remember the time that we _________. (Wife) and I are doing well, here is a thing that is new with me. Have a happy (upcoming holiday, season of the year), Love, Husband</em>.&#8221; Keep it light, and remember, if communication has really lapsed, the other people don&#8217;t know what to say or how to begin either, and will be grateful for you breaking the ice. Make the effort, say something brief and kind, and then keep sending responses when they respond back. It is honestly that simple: If you want to, you will do it. If you don&#8217;t want to, then don&#8217;t do it, but don&#8217;t expect your partner to magically make it happen for you. Either admit that you don&#8217;t want to do it and make peace with that, or work on the &#8220;I want to want to, I just haven&#8217;t figured it out yet&#8221; stuff with a therapist.</p>
<p>You can help by dropping stuff in the mail, or picking up postcards, or hunting down addresses, or even helping him come up with things to say, but you shouldn&#8217;t manage the entire process.</p>
<p>The problem of making an adult relationship with imperfect relatives is not unique to this guy, it&#8217;s something we all have to figure out for ourselves.</p>
<p>My advice is that your mantra becomes &#8220;<strong><em>I am always here to listen, and I will support any decision you make, but I am not comfortable (emailing your sister, sorting out your past, taking the lead on how you interact with your family).&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;m sure the community will have alternate perspectives to my initial &#8220;AW HELL NAW&#8221; reaction, I hope it will be helpful.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5374/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5374/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5374&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/16/467-how-do-i-help-my-partner-communicate-better-with-his-family/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>121</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>London Meetup April 20</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/london-meetup-april-20/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/london-meetup-april-20/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 14:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Meetups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meetups]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5369</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[London is meeting up again. Dear Awkward Army, London meetup next weekend, 20th April!  All welcome. 11:00 am onwards, Cafe in the Crypt, St Martin-in-the-Fields Church, Trafalgar Square, London WC2N 4JJ. The previous venue is closing, and this one has been recommended. The cafe is underground, and is accessed via stairs or lift, next to the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5369&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>London is meeting up again.</p>
<blockquote>
<div>
<div>
<div>Dear Awkward Army,</div>
<p>London meetup next weekend, 20th April!  All welcome.</p>
<p>11:00 am onwards, Cafe in the Crypt, St Martin-in-the-Fields Church, Trafalgar Square, London WC2N 4JJ.</p>
<p>The previous venue is closing, and this one has been recommended.</p>
<p>The cafe is underground, and is accessed via stairs or lift, next to the church on the left if you&#8217;re looking with your back to Trafalgar Square or the National Portrait Gallery. They have accessible toilets.</p>
<p>Map here: <a href="http://goo.gl/f1MnW" target="_blank">http://goo.gl/f1MnW</a></p>
<p>I have long brown hair and glasses.  I will bring my plush Cthulhu to use as a table marker.  It looks like this: <a href="http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/7cb0/" target="_blank">http://www.thinkgeek.com/product/7cb0/<br />
</a></div>
<div>
<p>My email address is kate DOT towner AT gmail DOT com</p>
<p>As discussed at previous meetups, I am happy to teach people to knit, so if you want to start or want help, bring something along!  I am an intermediate rather than advanced knitter but I will do my best.</p>
</div>
<p>Next meetup is probably going to be the 1st of June, due to me having no free time in May.</p>
<p>We have a new Facebook group here to make it easier for people to keep track: <a href="http://www.facebook.com/groups/549571375087294/" target="_blank">http://www.facebook.com/groups/549571375087294/</a></p>
</div>
<p>Cheers,</p>
<p>Kate</p></blockquote>
<p>Have a great time. It&#8217;s awesome to see a regular thing happening.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5369/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5369/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5369&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/london-meetup-april-20/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#466: Possessive friend is weirding me out/A constructive conflict review.</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/466-possessive-friend-is-weirding-me-out/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/466-possessive-friend-is-weirding-me-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rejection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jealousy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The African Violet of Broken Friendship]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5362</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Captain Awkward, My friend N alternately acts like she feels threatened by me and like she wants to be me. It&#8217;s really creepy but I don&#8217;t know how to address it without sounding jealous and paranoid. I met her three years ago. We became close quickly, and she had a crush on me, which [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5362&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward,</em></p>
<p><em>My friend N alternately acts like she feels threatened by me and like she wants to be me. It&#8217;s really creepy but I don&#8217;t know how to address it without sounding jealous and paranoid.</em></p>
<p><em>I met her three years ago. We became close quickly, and she had a crush on me, which I suspect was a nice distraction from the awful breakup she was going through. She invited me on a camping trip hoping to hook up with me, but was surprised that bringing a second woman along meant she was no longer the only woman in an otherwise all-male group, and she was no longer the group&#8217;s tomboy because I have more camping experience. Several guys hit on me, including her ex. She spent the whole weekend sulking and making passive aggressive comments.</em></p>
<p><em>I thought her resentment would subside when I started dating someone, but she became really possessive of my boyfriend. They&#8217;ve never dated, but sometimes play-fight when they drink. My boyfriend and I both practice martial arts, and our rather hilarious how-did-you-two-meet story involves a fight club. Often when N and I are meeting someone new, I mention my boyfriend&#8217;s name. The other person asks, &#8220;Oh, who&#8217;s that?&#8221; Before I can answer, much less tell our story, N interrupts me with, &#8220;That&#8217;s her boyfriend, who ***I*** introduced her to, who I fight in the street! I&#8217;m a street fighter!&#8221; and she tells the story of that time she tried to fight my boyfriend, but fell and twisted her ankle and he carried her home. Then she talks about herself at length. If this new person is male, she doesn&#8217;t let me get a single word in edgewise. If a guy hits on me, she pouts and starts up the passive-aggression. She also tries to one-up me on comics trivia, which she only got into after meeting me.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve tolerated this because she&#8217;s a great friend when sober. But lately, we only see each other at parties, and her behavior is getting more obnoxious. Recently she interrupted me talking about work to tell the &#8220;street fighting&#8221; story to people who had already heard it a million times, while positioning her chair in front of me so that her back was to me and I was physically excluded from the group. Later she glared at me, sat on my boyfriend&#8217;s lap, and talked about how great he is.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve asked my boyfriend to deliberately invite me back into conversations when she excludes me, and to not make physical contact with her. I don&#8217;t know what to say to her though, and our once-close friendship is becoming a sad competition where no one wins.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8211;Not-Single, Not-White Female</em></p>
<p><span id="more-5362"></span></p>
<p>How deep do you want to go into working this out?</p>
<p>I ask because their are two paths you can go by.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Path #1:</span></p>
<p>&#8220;<em>N, I&#8217;m really not feeling our friendship lately, and I&#8217;d prefer that we not hang out anymore. I realize that this isn&#8217;t good news, but it&#8217;s the best decision for me. I will do my best not to make it weird at (group events), as in, let&#8217;s say a quick hello and then keep the interaction to a minimum.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>If that seems too permanent, try &#8220;<em>let&#8217;s take a break from hanging out</em>.&#8221; This won&#8217;t land well, no matter how you say it, but if that&#8217;s how you feel it&#8217;s better and less cruel than drifting away and waiting for her to catch on.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Path #2:</span></p>
<p><em>&#8220;The specific thing (specific thing) you did the other night kind of weirded me out. What&#8217;s going on with that?&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Rules for constructive conflict when you want to repair a relationship:</p>
<ul>
<li>Keep it to one or two specific recent incidents, not an entire list of grievances.* Not because those grievances aren&#8217;t real, but listing all of them can be overwhelming and immediately put the person on the defensive. Over time you can work on the whole gestalt of the relationship. The first time you bring up a conflict, keep it simple and short.</li>
<li>Emphasize how whatever it is affected your specific recent feelings (Don&#8217;t speak in generalities or patterns or get into the history of competitiveness &#8211; it makes no one look or feel good).</li>
<li>Do not make any assumptions or suggestions as to why. Facts only. &#8220;<em>The thing you did hurt my feelings/bothers me. Your friendship is valuable to me, so I thought you should know and have a chance to apologize or explain/so I thought we should talk about it and see if we can&#8217;t work it out</em>.&#8221; Bonus: This makes the other person do the work of piecing it together and offering an explanation.</li>
</ul>
<p>Her answer might lead you back to Path 1, but if you think it might be worth delving into, give it a try and see what she says. It is unlikely she will admit jealousy or vulnerability, but you can tell whether this is salvageable by her response.</p>
<p><strong>Salvageable:</strong> &#8221;<em>Whoa, sorry, now that I think of it that was really out of line. I will not do that anymore.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p><strong>Unsalvageable</strong>: &#8220;<em>God, why are you so paranoid and jealous?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>Because these behaviors are centered around your boyfriend, it&#8217;s good to give him a heads up, and his reaction will also be telling.</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Boyfriend, I think I am going to take a break from hanging out with N. She is getting on my nerves</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>or</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Boyfriend, I am going to ask N. to stop telling the fight club story (for example). It&#8217;s crossed a line into making me really uncomfortable</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>You don&#8217;t have to get into his behaviors, again, stick with facts and don&#8217;t overexplain yourself or justify. His reaction will also be telling.</p>
<p><strong>Supportive</strong>: &#8220;<em>That&#8217;s sad, but you do what you need to and I will back you up.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><strong>Unsupportive:</strong> &#8220;<em>Why u so jealous and unfair?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>Things I would let go:</p>
<ul>
<li>Comics trivia. Does it matter how we get into comics trivia? If we find out that we love comics trivia, we get to be just as into it as the person who first invited us there. In fact, let go of the entire question of who was in what group first.</li>
<li>The entire question of interrupting when you get hit on by someone. There&#8217;s no way to control what other people (hitters-on) do or feel, and no way to bring this up that makes you look good, i.e., talking about this will make it seem like you actually <strong>are</strong> in competition for male attention and keeping score about such things. Are you? If her behavior is as rude/interrupty/obvious/strange as you say, people can tell what&#8217;s up and make their own decisions about how they want to engage her. A dedicated hitter-on will circumvent her.</li>
<li>Her past crush on you, unless she brings it up. Sometimes we have crushes on people we&#8217;d really like to be like. The graceful thing to do is to pretend it never happened and let her save face.</li>
<li>Who is better at camping.</li>
</ul>
<p>That leaves: Interrupting and one-upping you in conversation (God hates a story-topper), telling the fight club story over and over again (this might genuinely be an oversight that can be corrected with a &#8220;I don&#8217;t want to embarrass you, but did you realize you tell that story every single time? It might be time to let that one rest,&#8221; ignoring you/shutting you out whenever a dude is around or physically shunning you out of a conversation by placing her back to you (this behavior is truly annoying), and behaving territorially around your boyfriend (which I imagine is hard behavior to pin down, but you know it when you see it.)</p>
<p>The things on the bulleted list, in my opinion, cross over into the &#8220;Someone is getting on my nerves, now <strong>everything about them</strong> is part of the story of how they get on my nerves&#8221; territory. You&#8217;re over-justifying somewhat, and I think fairness and good sense mean doing some healthy separation between behaviors she is doing &#8220;at you&#8221; and behaviors that she is not. I think it&#8217;s also important to remember that while these behaviors have been going on for a while and in some cases date back to the beginning of your friendship, when you are trying to have constructive conflict with someone the clock restarts when you bring up the problem. Someone who is actually your friend gets some time to react and try to change the behavior.</p>
<p>The grievances on the bulleted list do have their uses in asking a question: If these issues date back to the beginning of the friendship, do you actually like her and want her in your life?  If no, then script #1 is the way to go.</p>
<p>There is no awesome way to handle this where everyone gets out unscathed and with their feelings and self-image totally intact, but remember, IT&#8217;S ALREADY WEIRD. I trust you that something is off here. You are just putting a name to a weirdness you didn&#8217;t make. Friends don&#8217;t always behave perfectly, and sometimes they tread on your toes without realizing it, and a cool friend will recognize when she&#8217;s been given an opportunity to make things right. If she responds favorably things may be salvageable with a little time to heal bruised egos. If she doubles down on the behavior that&#8217;s bothering you, it only confirms that you made the right decision to put some distance in the relationship.</p>
<p>*I am talking about constructive conflict in interpersonal relationships, not activism. There is a difference between repairing a friendship between equals and seeking justice, where the historical record of abuses is necessary no matter how uncomfortable it makes someone. If someone is your friend, the suggested advice is a way to ask for what you need while taking care of their feelings a little bit. In a situation with extreme power imbalances and a history of injustice, the oppressed person does not have to take care of the feelings of the oppressor, and indeed &#8220;tone policing&#8221; or &#8220;I would give you justice if you just asked more nicely&#8221; is a <a title="Derailing for Dummies: Google Cache" href="http://birdofparadox.wordpress.com/derailing-for-dummies-google-cache-reconstruction/" target="_blank">derailing tactic</a>. I just want to be clear about that from the get-go.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5362/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5362/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5362&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/15/466-possessive-friend-is-weirding-me-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>80</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#465: Life after Darth</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/14/465-life-after-darth/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/14/465-life-after-darth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 18:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Darth Vader Boyfriend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manipulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rejection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breakup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[darth vader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Explaining the world 1 Star Wars reference at a time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5359</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi there, An online friend and I were innocent email buds. One day, we start DMing which leads to texting/phone call. It gets sexual. Tells me he has a live in girlfriend but doesn&#8217;t ever say &#8220;maybe we shouldn&#8217;t go there.&#8221; It progresses to constantly talking, texting, gchatting. 2 weeks after we started he flew [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5359&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_5360" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 348px"><a href="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/darth-vader-in-love.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5360  " alt="A man and woman dressed as Darth Vader holding hands on a crowded street." src="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/darth-vader-in-love.jpg?w=338&#038;h=360" width="338" height="360" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image from <a href="//www.likecool.com/Darth_Vader_in_Love--Pic--Gear.html'">likecool.com</a></p></div>
<p><em>Hi there,</em><br />
<em>An online friend and I were innocent email buds. One day, we start DMing which leads to texting/phone call. It gets sexual. Tells me he has a live in girlfriend but doesn&#8217;t ever say &#8220;maybe we shouldn&#8217;t go there.&#8221; It progresses to constantly talking, texting, gchatting. 2 weeks after we started he flew here for a weekend.</em></p>
<p><em>Knew he had a gf, he told me they had major issues ever since she moved in. I asked him to please break up with her and figure that out ASAP. He went home and 2 days later he told me he would regret leaving if he didn&#8217;t try to fix their relationship. But wanted to try with me too. The waffling about what he wanted continued for 4 months. We saw each other again, talked constantly. We&#8217;d both try to cut each other off at points, it NEVER stuck.</em></p>
<p><em>Throughout I would threaten to tell her, push him to leave. I regret all the manipulation. In the fall, he decided that he couldn&#8217;t handle it. He cut it off, came crawling back. I let him. He&#8217;d become my emotional crutch. I fell into deep depression, constantly beating myself up. </em></p>
<p><em>Finally he said I severely hurt him by threatening to tell her, he could never really forgive me, give me a real chance. I said I&#8217;m done, cut off contact. Though did demand he tell her. I wanted him to get left. He did tell her, they have stayed together so far.</em></p>
<p><em>So was left feeling insane and sad. I did some controlling things that I&#8217;m not proud of. Jerkbrain: I&#8217;m an awful person who not only hurt this man but someone else too. I acted absolutely unreasonable on more than one occasion with this situation.</em></p>
<p><em>How I can start to forgive myself? Some people may always think I&#8217;m seriously shitty and I have to get over that but having a really hard time being okay with everything. Especially because I really did care for him. We had some seriously intense emotional and physical chemistry and I really thought I loved him at one point. I know this pit of despair may eventually dissipate but I am so ashamed of myself and tired of feeling like I&#8217;m the bad one.</em></p>
<p><em>And her friends have openly cried for revenge against me and told me I should be scared. They have stayed together so I guess I can understand why I&#8217;m the target and not him but it&#8217;s really frustrating that that&#8217;s the tactic. Which is my other question, how do I reconcile my desire for justice against him? I am just so pissed that he&#8217;s essentially had no consequences.</em></p>
<p><em>Thanks.</em></p>
<p><span id="more-5359"></span></p>
<p>Good news, there are a few people in this story who deserve the &#8220;bad one&#8221; title more than you.</p>
<p>#1 is Cheater McCheaterson, who can&#8217;t just fucking cheat but has to also drag you along on the entire rollercoaster of his dysfunctional relationship and its aftermath. He was the one with a girlfriend, and he was the one with a greater responsibility to her, either to pass on a relationship with you if that was their agreement and his choice, or to make a clean break with her. He was totally capable of telling you &#8220;<em>You are awesome, but I have a girlfriend, so I don&#8217;t think we should chat so much</em>.&#8221; He was totally capable of telling her, &#8220;<em>I met someone and I want to explore that, even if it means we break up</em>.&#8221; He chose neither of those things, because he wanted to have a girlfriend and a relationship with you and ride everything out for as long as possible. It&#8217;s not shocking that things got messy, and he doesn&#8217;t have to be bad or evil to get in over his head, but he did not help this situation. I don&#8217;t think your threatening to tell his girlfriend (or even actually telling her) would have made much of a difference in the end. It&#8217;s a weak position where the only strong play you really have is to get the hell out of there and leave them to each other.</p>
<p>#2, #3, #4 are anyone who tells you you should &#8220;be scared&#8221; because you fell in love with a dude who spun you a lot of confusing lies and empty promises.</p>
<p>The Darth Vader boyfriend or girlfriend isn&#8217;t necessarily evil or deliberately malicious. We&#8217;ve talked a lot here about <a title="Friday Questions about Darth Vader &amp; FEELINGS______." href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/03/16/friday-questions-about-darth-vader-feelings______/">warning signs</a>, and those are certainly red flags for when you are getting involved with someone, but for me the characteristic that makes something a Darth Vader situation can only be seen afterward, when you see how much you strayed from yourself (your own best interests, your own ethics, your own standards for how you want to be treated) and how often you <strong>made excuses</strong> for the other person&#8217;s behaviors to preserve the relationship. My Darth Vader was not awesome in his behavior, and was quite manipulative, but what makes me look back with shame and horror was my own total desire to be manipulated and hear only what I wanted to hear and also behaviors that tended toward, frankly, stalking. Darth Vaders, however they work, create an altered headspace where we are not our best selves. And while we are always responsible for our actions, we have to find a way to forgive ourselves in order to get free of that headspace.</p>
<p>Right now, the only things that fix this are time, distance, and sitting with some uncomfortable truths until you gain something like perspective and can tell a story about this that doesn&#8217;t hurt.</p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Cut off contact completely with this guy and everyone who knows him, including these friends of his girlfriend. Use whatever e-blocking tools you have to do, but do whatever you can to make sure you travel in completely separate worlds. You can&#8217;t worry about threats if you don&#8217;t know that threats are happening because everyone involved in this story is dead to you.</p>
<p><strong>Most importantly:</strong> <strong>Don&#8217;t try to be friends. </strong></p>
<p>You&#8217;re not friends, and you won&#8217;t be friends. The best part of you wants to find a way to preserve the good in all of this, and to make everything feel less wasted and wrong. Like, if you can be friends, it will all have been worth it. Something can be saved! Beware this instinct. Mostly what gets saved is his ability to believe that he&#8217;s not a bad guy, and his ability to reach out to you for emotional support and keep you engaged in his drama. What gets lost is your ability to put it behind you, by getting as angry as you need to get before you can heal. It keeps the little jolts of attention, and let&#8217;s face it, addiction going as the texts and messages come in or leave you bereft when they don&#8217;t come in.</p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Repeat this until you believe it: <strong>Having great chemistry does not by itself make someone a good partner for you.</strong> People have to be kind, and considerate, and respect boundaries, and when it comes down to it, they have to choose you.</p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t a story about how you would be together if it wasn&#8217;t for this lady and her threatening friends, this is a story about a guy who liked you well enough but didn&#8217;t want to be with you. You were actually involved, even if you didn&#8217;t have some kind of official relationship status called &#8220;girlfriend&#8221; or &#8220;primary partner&#8221; or whatnot. It is a break-up, so <a title="Reader Question #16:  The Golden Retriever/Kwisatz Haderach of Love" href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/02/09/reader-question-16-the-golden-retrieverkwisatz-haderach-of-love/" target="_blank">mourn it like a break-up</a>. Give yourself permission to feel sad, and bereft, and royally fucked over by fates.</p>
<p>Chemistry (love, lust, that instant recognition that here be your people, &#8220;intensity&#8221;) does mess with people, and people treat it like some inexorable force that temporarily abrogated all decision-making skills and swept them away. You aren&#8217;t the first person to be here, nor is he, nor was I when it was my turn to be in these shoes, but eventually the cloud clears and the question of &#8220;should we actually be together&#8221; comes up. Are you actually together? Would this wishy-washy guy who didn&#8217;t choose you in the end actually make a good partner? The answer to both of these is no. If you were supposed to be together, you would be together, and it would have gone easier than this.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not the kindest or most comfortable thought, but it&#8217;s important to get yourself out of the headspace of &#8220;<em>If only&#8230;.!&#8221;</em> and worry over the good times you had and try to stretch them to cover you now. <strong>Feeling</strong>: We were so great together! If only! <strong>Fact:</strong> But he didn&#8217;t choose me, and we are not together.</p>
<p>The first time you teach yourself to put the factual wet blanket on those feelings, it really hurts. Because you are basically taking The Golden Retriever of Love to the vet and &#8220;sending it to live on a nice farm where there are horses&#8221; or whatever your parents told you was the euphemism for &#8220;we killed the dog when you were at school.&#8221; Murdering hope fucking HURTS. But this guy has shown you again and again that he is not a good repository for those hopes, and having hope where he is concerned does not help you. Over time, if you can get in the habit of nixing the obsessive &#8220;But if only!&#8221; thoughts as soon as they come up, the fact of &#8220;<em>But we&#8217;re not together</em>&#8221; gets a friend, and that friend is &#8220;<em>And I only want to be with people who really want to be with me, and who will come at me correct.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p><strong>Step 3</strong>: Letting go also means letting go of the desire for revenge. The desire for his life to fracture the way it feels your has is understandable, but it keeps you engaged with him. It doesn&#8217;t seem fair, but it is actually entirely, cruelly, beautifully fair: .His reward or punishment is exactly the same as everyone&#8217;s &#8211; he has to live in his own skin and find a way to move forward with his life.</p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> It&#8217;s not a good idea to tell his girlfriend what happened, no matter how much you may want her to know, but tell SOMEONE. Deal with this overall cloud of depression you&#8217;ve got going on by dealing with it as depression. Get counseling. Tell someone the whole story, the highs, the lows, the hopes, the feeling that something beautiful was completely twisted and wasted, the missing piece in your day that used to be filled by this drama and how nothing feels right afterwards. A therapist or counselor can sort through what happened and help you take ownership of only what is yours (what can be learned from and changed in the future) and let go of what belongs to other people (his responsibility toward his girlfriend). Speak, and get it out of your system. Be good to yourself.</p>
<p><strong>Step 5</strong>: Let time do its work.</p>
<p><a title="Love after Love" href="http://www.poemhunter.com/poem/love-after-love/">This</a> is what a good outcome looks like. Not you back together, not him suffering, just someday, you will tell a story about this time that goes like this:</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>I got involved with a very charismatic guy who had a girlfriend, and things got very messy both between us and for my own mental health. I&#8217;m not proud of the way that any of us behaved, but mostly I&#8217;m really glad that it&#8217;s over.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>And you won&#8217;t have to go into the details or chew them over, because it will be well and truly in the past.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5359/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5359/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5359&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/14/465-life-after-darth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>91</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://captainawkwarddotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/darth-vader-in-love.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A man and woman dressed as Darth Vader holding hands on a crowded street.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LA Times: &#8220;How not to say the wrong thing.&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/08/la-times-how-not-to-say-the-wrong-thing/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/08/la-times-how-not-to-say-the-wrong-thing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 17:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5356</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Movie is in the can (and about to be on its way to the lab in LA for processing)! So I will be back to being a blogger soon. In the meantime, a friend (and friend of the blog) posted this piece by Susanna Silk and Barry Goldman on Facebook today, and despite some ableist [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5356&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Movie is in the can (and about to be on its way to the lab in LA for processing)! So I will be back to being a blogger soon.</p>
<p>In the meantime, a friend (and friend of the blog) posted <a title="LA times: &quot;How Not To Say The Wrong Thing&quot;" href="http://touch.latimes.com/#section/-1/article/p2p-75241622/">this piece by Susanna Silk and Barry Goldman </a>on Facebook today, and despite some ableist wording in the opening line I think it&#8217;s a very, very helpful way to think about how to treat people who have undergone trauma or who are in crisis. What do you think?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5356/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5356/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5356&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/08/la-times-how-not-to-say-the-wrong-thing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>153</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>#464: My mom died and my dad started having sex with men. A LOT of men. Should I talk to him about it?</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/01/464-my-mom-died-and-my-dad-started-having-sex-with-men-a-lot-of-men-should-i-talk-to-him-about-it/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/01/464-my-mom-died-and-my-dad-started-having-sex-with-men-a-lot-of-men-should-i-talk-to-him-about-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 14:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Families]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mother]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worry]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5351</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Captain Awkward, My mom died suddenly and unexpectedly 2 months ago. My parents had been married almost 40 years. A month after her passing, I accidentally discovered that my dad has been sleeping with multiple men he meets on the internet, at the gym, etc., and that he is also having sex in public [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5351&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dear Captain Awkward,</em></p>
<p><em>My mom died suddenly and unexpectedly 2 months ago. My parents had been married almost 40 years. A month after her passing, I accidentally discovered that my dad has been sleeping with multiple men he meets on the internet, at the gym, etc., and that he is also having sex in public restrooms. I don&#8217;t believe that my mom knew that this was going on, but I realize that that is a possibility. </em></p>
<p><em>It was not a complete shock to me that my dad is gay or bisexual, as the thought had crossed my mind before, and after my mom died I had even considered that he might bring home a boyfriend in a couple of years. I imagined myself being very supportive and understanding in that scenario, but this sudden discovery at such an emotional time has really thrown me for a loop. The high-risk behavior is freaking me out and making me angry, if I&#8217;m honest. I just lost one parent, and I don&#8217;t want to lose another! Furthermore, the thought that he was likely putting my mom at risk, too, really upsets me.</em></p>
<p><em>I cannot stop worrying about how this might play out. I&#8217;m worried that he is putting himself in harm&#8217;s way and risking arrest, etc. I&#8217;m worried that the community that has been supporting him through the loss of my mom would disappear if this came out in the wrong way. Similarly, I worry about how my mom&#8217;s extended family, to whom we are very close, would react if this were suddenly revealed. I feel like I&#8217;m not able to progress through the normal grieving process for my mom because I am so wrapped up in the stress of this situation and keeping this secret. So, here are my questions:</em></p>
<p><em>1) Should I tell him that I know? Should I tell him how much I know?</em></p>
<p><em>2) If I do tell him, how do I do it and what do I say? Is it even appropriate for me to share my concerns for his health and well-being considering his sex life is not really any of my business?</em></p>
<p><em>Sincerely, </em></p>
<p><em>Daughter with a Dilemma</em></p>
<p><span id="more-5351"></span></p>
<p>Dear Daughter,</p>
<p>A little time has gone by since you first sent this in. I am so, so sorry for your loss and cannot even imagine the shock and grief that goes with losing your mom so suddenly.</p>
<p>While I realize that this may not make you feel any better, if at all possible, I think the best course is for you to let the stuff with your dad go, and not do or say anything to him about it until or unless he tells you what&#8217;s going on.</p>
<p>Even if it&#8217;s risky.</p>
<p>Even if it&#8217;s uncharacteristic.</p>
<p>Even if you don&#8217;t understand it.</p>
<p>Even if you have worries and fears and anger about it.</p>
<p>His extended family and community might not be happy with his behavior if they found out, but that is <strong>his</strong> issue to manage.</p>
<p>He owns his own body and his own sexuality, including any risks that come with his behavior.</p>
<p>And he owns his own <strong>grief</strong> and grieving process.</p>
<p>Thinking the words &#8220;my dad&#8221; and &#8220;<a title="Peaches: Fuck the Pain Away" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KHcMqOQt4NY" target="_blank">fuck the pain away</a>&#8221; in the same sentence is not a whole bunch of fun for you, and I&#8217;m sorry &#8211; I wish he were being more discreet and that you didn&#8217;t know. But unless he does something in a way that makes it 100% obvious that you know, put up that Plausible Deniability Screen, the one your parents probably used for you when you became sexually active and the one that all roommates everywhere use to pretend that sound doesn&#8217;t carry inside a shared house.</p>
<p>Imagine for a moment that you are a kinky person, and that your kink is to tie eggplants to your feet and rub them against the feet of people who have mushrooms tied to their feet. Wracked by grief, you&#8217;ve been having more vegetable-on-vegetable action of late and have been a little less than discreet about where you find your ratatouille. Your dad finds out what you&#8217;re up to, and he confronts you about your safety, the way people might see you in the family and community, and heaps a whole bunch of shame and worry upon your private business, etc. How would you feel? Would you feel loved and cared for? Would it be a wakeup call for you? Would that conversation leave either of you feeling better? I know you are genuinely very concerned about him, but any time &#8220;safety issues&#8221; + &#8220;what will people think?&#8221; + &#8220;behavior I don&#8217;t like or agree with/moral upset&#8221; get combined together you risk falling into concern-trolling. I think many of us have done sexual things that our family members would not approve of and find risky, and I think at those  times we had our reasons, and I don&#8217;t think anyone could have talked us out of them or made things better with their disapproval.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m deliberately trying to choose a ridiculous kink as an example so I don&#8217;t inadvertently stumble into anyone&#8217;s actual kinks, and I don&#8217;t want to dodge the very real safety issues that might be at play here, but all nearly all sexual contact carries some risk. You&#8217;re not psyched about the string of anonymous partners, but you also wouldn&#8217;t be psyched if they were women, and you also probably wouldn&#8217;t be happy if he found a new girlfriend or long-term boyfriend and started to look serious about settling down with someone right now. It&#8217;s <span style="text-decoration:underline;">all</span> too much, too soon.</p>
<p>So the axioms at play are:</p>
<ul>
<li>His sexual choices are his to make.</li>
<li>Adults should give each other a wide berth when it comes to privacy.</li>
<li>People come out when it&#8217;s right for them, not necessarily when it&#8217;s right for you.</li>
</ul>
<p>It&#8217;s good that you&#8217;ve considered the possibility that he is gay. When the time is right, and some more time has passed, you can have the sweet talk that my Godmother had with me when it had been a long time since I&#8217;d mentioned a dude or brought one home:</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Jennifer, I just want you to know that&#8230;<strong>anyone</strong> you loved, we would also love. So if you ever wanted to bring &#8230;<strong>someone</strong> home, we would welcome&#8230;<strong>that person</strong></em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>I wasn&#8217;t gay, I was just single (and we don&#8217;t fly <a title="My Sluthood, Myself" href="http://yesmeansyesblog.wordpress.com/2010/07/26/my-sluthood-myself/" target="_blank">Socially Unacceptable Brief Slutty Encounters </a>home to Massachusetts for the holidays, or, at least I don&#8217;t), but it was good to know, right?</p>
<p>Your dad will need you to be that cool daughter someday. But he also needs you to be that cool daughter <strong>now</strong>, and give him some time and space about private stuff, and to reach out to him (spend time with him, recommend that he see a counselor, check in on him, tell him you love him) about the common ground you share.</p>
<p>I think you should talk to <strong>someone</strong> about this. Grief, anger, worry, the pressure of keeping a secret all mixed up together is a powerful and messy combo, and some counseling for yourself where you can get as angry as you need and lay out all your concerns and figure out how to tackle them might be a very helpful step. A counselor will let you talk through worst-case scenarios but will also remind you that the worst case scenarios are not always so. Maybe he wasn&#8217;t putting your mom at risk. Maybe he really did wait until she died to seek this kind of contact, and this is something that has been pent up for years. Maybe they did have an understanding. That is 100% between them; you are not the guardian of your parents&#8217; marital fidelity.</p>
<p>If word is getting out, and people bring concerns up to you, an all-purpose mantra is &#8220;<em>Grief is unpredictable. You should probably talk to my dad directly about that.</em>&#8221; You don&#8217;t have to manage your dad&#8217;s image for him. That can be a hard thing to let go of, but I think it is good for you if you learn (maybe slowly, with help of a counselor) that you don&#8217;t have to control how other people see your dad.</p>
<p>Hopefully you can find a way to put this down under some kind of Year of Grieving seal and forgive your dad for not managing his grief the way you want him to. Maybe there is an honest talk in your future where he tells you what&#8217;s up and you can say &#8220;<em>Yeah, I knew when you did x, and I was really worried about you, but I wanted to give you your privacy. Can we talk about that?</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>Finally, if you do end up talking about it, just freaking talk about it. Don&#8217;t drop hints about &#8220;discretion.&#8221; Don&#8217;t drop hints, period. &#8220;<em>Dad, I wish I didn&#8217;t know this, but I do. I heard/saw/unavoidably have to know that you did x, and it&#8217;s making me concerned about you. I want to respect your privacy, and you don&#8217;t have to talk to me about what&#8217;s going on, but I wish you would talk to someone about it, and I really want you to be safe and okay.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t envy you, or your dad. The Year(s)of Grieving stretch out in front of you no matter what you choose, so I wish you kindness, strength, patience, and love.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5351/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/captainawkwarddotcom.wordpress.com/5351/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=captainawkward.com&#038;blog=18848858&#038;post=5351&#038;subd=captainawkwarddotcom&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/04/01/464-my-mom-died-and-my-dad-started-having-sex-with-men-a-lot-of-men-should-i-talk-to-him-about-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>154</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
