<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
 <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel> 
   <title>Skeptical Science</title>
   <description>Examining the science of global warming skepticism, clearing up the misconceptions and misleading arguments that populate the climate change debate.</description> 
   <link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/</link>
	 <atom:link href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
 <item> 
<title>David Rose Hides the Rise in Global Warming</title>
<description>&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;It seems like we have to debunk &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/global-cooling-january-2007-to-january-2008-intermediate.htm"&gt;this myth&lt;/a&gt; on a weekly basis, as it keeps popping up in the mainstream media.&amp;nbsp; So, yet again, &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; is global warming:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.skepticalscience.com/graphics/Nuccitelli_OHC_Data.jpg" alt="Fig 1" width="500" height="313" /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Figure 1: Land, &lt;span id="skstip21" class="skstip beginner"&gt;atmosphere&lt;/span&gt;, and ice heating (red), 0-700 meter ocean heat content (OHC) increase (light blue), 700-2,000 meter OHC increase (dark blue).&amp;nbsp; From &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/docs/Comment_on_DK12.pdf"&gt;Nuccitelli et al. (2012)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The overall warming of the Earth over the past 15 years was larger than over the previous 15 years.&amp;nbsp; Global warming has not stopped; it's not even slowed down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;A leading purveyor of the myth to the contrary is journalist &lt;a title="David Rose" href="http://www.vanityfair.com/contributors/david-rose"&gt;David Rose&lt;/a&gt;, of the British tabloid &lt;em&gt;The &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mail on Sunday&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Vanity Fair&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp; We've previously &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/misleading-daily-mail-prebunked-nuccitelli-et-al-2012.html"&gt;pre-bunked&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/rose-curry-double-down-denial.html"&gt;debunked&lt;/a&gt; his &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/media_v_reality.html"&gt;articles&lt;/a&gt; on the subject, but he appears oblivious to any criticism of his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;"No, the world ISN'T getting warmer (as you may have noticed),"&lt;/em&gt; wrongly begins &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2294560/The-great-green-1-The-hard-proof-finally-shows-global-warming-forecasts-costing-billions-WRONG-along.html"&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; published in last week's &lt;em&gt;Mail on Sunday&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Try saying 'there's no noticeable warming' to the &lt;a title="Australian heat records" href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/future_tense/2013/01/08/australia_heat_wave_new_color_added_to_weather_maps_fire_danger_catastrophic.html"&gt;Australians&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="2012 hottest year in US " href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/01/09/science/earth/2012-was-hottest-year-ever-in-us.html"&gt;Americans&lt;/a&gt; who suffered the greatest run of heat waves ever recorded; or the &lt;a title="2012 floods in UK" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2012_Great_Britain_and_Ireland_floods"&gt;British&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a title="Hurricane Sandy" href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2012-11-01/its-global-warming-stupid"&gt;New Yorkers&lt;/a&gt; who were flooded out of their homes during 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Global Surface Warming is Within the Predicted Range&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Rose's latest denial of global warming makes a great play of this &lt;a href="http://www.climate-lab-book.ac.uk/2013/updated-comparison-of-simulations-and-observations/"&gt;graphic created by Ed Hawkins&lt;/a&gt; of the University of Reading (which Rose modified, printed, and misrepresented without permission or attribution). &lt;strong&gt;[Update 2. 19:41 GMT, March 20th: The Mail has now attributed the figure to Ed Hawkins' site, provided a link and apologised. However they still misrepresent Ed Hawkins' original graphic.]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/Hawkins_modelvsobs.png"&gt;&lt;img src="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/Hawkins_modelvsobs.png" alt="hawkins graphic" width="500" height="202" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Comparison of observed global surface temperature changes (black) with 38 climate models in the &lt;span class="st"&gt;Coupled Model Intercomparison Project Phase 5&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a href="http://cmip-pcmdi.llnl.gov/cmip5/"&gt;CMIP5&lt;/a&gt;), including 25&amp;ndash;75% and 5-95% uncertainty ranges (gray).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Rose's first mistake is to claim that "&lt;em&gt;the speed of global warming has been massively overestimated&lt;/em&gt;."&amp;nbsp; Putting aside the fact that he's only looking at surface air temperatures, which only comprise a small percentage of global warming; &lt;a href="http://www.climate-lab-book.ac.uk/2013/updated-comparison-of-simulations-and-observations/"&gt;as Ed Hawkins noted&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"In the article David Rose suggests that this figure proves that the forecasts are wrong.&amp;nbsp; This is incorrect ... the observations are at the lower edge of the projected range"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Despite being on the lower end of that range, global surface temperatures are nevertheless within the 90% (5&amp;ndash;95%) confidence interval of model runs, and therefore have not been overestimated.&amp;nbsp; Note that we expect the data to fall outside the 90% range 10% of the time, so even if the observational temperatures were outside that envelope (which they are not), it wouldn't necessarily mean that global surface warming has been overestimated.&amp;nbsp; This is further illustrated by a simiar graphic created by &lt;a href="http://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2013/02/2012-updates-to-model-observation-comparions/"&gt;Gavin Schmidt at RealClimate&lt;/a&gt;, using the previous &lt;span class="st"&gt;Coupled Model Intercomparison Project&lt;/span&gt; collection of climate models, CMIP3, which shows that the observed surface temperatures are within the 95% model confidence interval (Figure 3), which is somewhat wider than the 90% confidence interval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/SchmidtCMIP3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/SchmidtCMIP3.jpg" alt="schmidt cmip3" width="500" height="403" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 3: Annual mean global surface air temperature anomalies from the &lt;a href="http://climexp.knmi.nl/selectfield_co2.cgi?id=someone@somewhere"&gt;CMIP3 models&lt;/a&gt; plotted against the surface temperature records from the &lt;a href="http://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2013/02/2012-updates-to-model-observation-comparions/"&gt;HadCRUT4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="ftp://ftp.ncdc.noaa.gov/pub/data/anomalies/annual.land_ocean.90S.90N.df_1901-2000mean.dat"&gt;NCDC&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://data.giss.nasa.gov/gistemp/tabledata/GLB.Ts+dSST.txt"&gt;GISTEMP&lt;/a&gt; products, baselined to 1980-1999 (as in the 2007 IPCC report).&amp;nbsp; The envelope in grey encloses 95% of the model runs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;So why are surface temperatures currently on the lower end of that 90% interval?&amp;nbsp; There may be several &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Why-The-Hottest-Decade-Was-Not-Hotter-.html"&gt;contributing factors&lt;/a&gt;, one being that there has been a &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/was-2012-hottest-la-nina-on-record.html"&gt;preponderance of La Ni&amp;ntilde;a events over the past decade&lt;/a&gt;, which cause a short-term cooling of surface temperatures.&amp;nbsp; Over this timeframe, more heat has accumulated in the deeper oceans &amp;mdash; heat which David Rose conveniently ignores by focusing exclusively on surface air temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Global Warming Continues Unabated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Rose's second error is contained in the article sub-heading, but he quickly contradicts it himself in the body of the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"No, the world ISN'T getting warmer ... there has been no statistically significant increase in the world&amp;rsquo;s average temperature since January 1997"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;These two statements say very different things.&amp;nbsp; Figure 1 obviously shows that the world &lt;strong&gt;IS&lt;/strong&gt; getting warmer&amp;nbsp;&amp;mdash; in fact, over the past decade it has accumulated the equivalent heat of 4 Hiroshima atomic bomb detonations &lt;em&gt;per second&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp; But even surface temperatures have most likely warmed over that timeframe, at a rate of about &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/trend.php"&gt;0.081 &amp;plusmn; 0.13&amp;deg;C per decade&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Calling that 'not warmer' is no different than saying 1 &amp;plusmn; 2 = 0.&amp;nbsp; It's just statistically and mathematically wrong.&amp;nbsp; The surface warming trend may be zero; but it could also be +0.21&amp;deg;C per decade.&amp;nbsp; Most likely surface temperatures have &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/trend.php"&gt;warmed 0.12&amp;deg;C since 1997&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;which is not zero&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Rose Misrepresents Climate Scientists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;" title="Piers Forster"&gt;Rose gathers some quotes from the few contrarian climate scientists who disagree with the &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/global-warming-scientific-consensus-intermediate.htm"&gt;97% consensus that humans are causing global warming&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Among these are &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Judith_Curry_blog.htm"&gt;Judith Curry&lt;/a&gt; and&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="http://www.desmogblog.com/david-whitehouse"&gt;David Whitehouse&lt;/a&gt;, the latter being associated with the climate contrarian lobby group &lt;a href="http://www.sourcewatch.org/index.php?title=Global_Warming_Policy_Foundation"&gt;Global Warming Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Whitehouse is not a climate scientist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Rose quotes Oxford's &lt;a title="Professor Miles Allen " href="http://www.eci.ox.ac.uk/people/allenmyles.php"&gt;Myles Allen&lt;/a&gt; saying that the odds of catastrophic 5&amp;deg;C surface warming this century have come down, but that's a far, far cry from saying the planet isn't warming or that we shouldn't be worried about it, &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2013/mar/20/response-mail-on-sunday-great-green-con-climate-change"&gt;as Allen has explained in a response on&lt;em&gt; The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;" title="Piers Forster"&gt;Rose also quotes &lt;a title="Piers Forster" href="http://www.see.leeds.ac.uk/research/icas/physical-climate-change-group/"&gt;Piers Forster&lt;/a&gt; as claiming that "&lt;em&gt;global surface temperatures have not risen in 15 years&lt;/em&gt;."&amp;nbsp; As shown above, this quote is factually wrong.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/piersforster/status/313372902512799744"&gt;Forster has also called Rose's article "terrible,"&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://bishophill.squarespace.com/blog/2013/3/18/reacting-to-rose.html"&gt;clarified his position on future warming&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"It's fine to say that current models overestimate the last decade of [surface] warming. They clearly do, and as I say in my quote I think we can rule out some high sensitivity values because of this. But to do a fair comparison you need to remove the effects of variability ... Even with a suggested ECS [equilibrium climate sensitivity] of around 2.5 C or so we can end up with a very significant &lt;span id="lw_1363553177_0" class="yshortcuts"&gt;climate change&lt;/span&gt; by 2100 if we don't do something&amp;mdash;therefore I think the tone of the article in terms of its implications for the IPCC, climate science and the climate itself are all wrong ... I would put the best estimate using this evidence around 2.5 C."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In short, Forster believes the scientific evidence puts equilibrium climate sensitivity (the total amount of warming, including feedbacks, once the planet reaches a new energy equilibrium) in the 2&amp;ndash;3.5&amp;deg;C range, most likely 2.5&amp;deg;C surface warming in response to a doubling of atmospheric CO2.&amp;nbsp; This would mean a significant and &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/climate-best-to-worst-case-scenarios.html"&gt;potentially very dangerous amount of climate change over the next century&lt;/a&gt; if we listen to Rose and don't take serious action to address the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Finally, Rose claims that James Annan believes that climate sensitivity is "&lt;em&gt;likely to be about half of the IPCC prediction in its last report in 2007&lt;/em&gt;."&amp;nbsp; This is a gross misrepresentation of Annan's views on the subject, which are very similar to Forster's, in that Annan thinks the higher end of the IPCC climate sensitivity range (above 4&amp;deg;C) is implausible and given too much weight.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The IPCC best estimate of equilibrium climate sensitivity&amp;nbsp; is 3&amp;deg;C in response to a doubling of atmospheric CO2 (&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/climate-sensitivity-advanced.htm"&gt;likely range of 2&amp;ndash;4.5&amp;deg;C&lt;/a&gt;), while &lt;a href="http://julesandjames.blogspot.com/2013/02/a-sensitive-matter.html?showComment=1359776188980#c4055746020692259831"&gt;Annan believes the most likely value is about 2.5&amp;deg;C&lt;/a&gt; and unlikely above 4&amp;deg;C.&amp;nbsp; Needless to say, 2.5 is quite a bit higher than half of 3, and is well within the IPCC likely range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://julesandjames.blogspot.jp/2013/03/another-interview.html"&gt;Annan has clarified his position on his blog&lt;/a&gt;, and expressed displeasure that Rose did not attempt to contact him before grossly misrepresenting his opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"he never attempted to contact me to check he had represented my views accurately&amp;nbsp;... The bit Rose adds about "the true figure likely to be about half of the IPCC prediction in its last report in 2007" is a complete fabrication of course, it's not something I can imagine having said, or being likely ... their range, or best estimate, is certainly not something I would disagree with by a factor of 2."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In short, Allen, Forster, and Annan's positions are that we're not doomed to catastrophic climate change just yet.&amp;nbsp; This is probably true, and is obviously very good news.&amp;nbsp; But their positions also mean that continuing to rely on fossil fuels as Rose advocates will result in very dangerous and potentially catastrophic consequences.&amp;nbsp; For Rose to claim these climate scientists' positions support his global warming denial is a gross distortion of their views, and it is not surprising that they have objected to these misrepresentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Long-Debunked Myths Thrown in for Good Measure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The second half of the article is ambiguous in that it appears to be written by &amp;mdash; or is in the words of &amp;mdash; &lt;a title="David Bellamy profile 1" href="http://www.desmogblog.com/david-bellamy"&gt;David Bellamy&lt;/a&gt;, the botanist and former televison presenter.&amp;nbsp; Here Bellamy is given a platform to complain he was kicked off TV due to his views on climate change, which contradicts &lt;a title="David Bellamy profile" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2002/sep/30/broadcasting.academicexperts"&gt;a previous admisssion&lt;/a&gt; that his departure was because of his political activities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;However, leaving that aside, with Bellamy's input we end with a &lt;a href="http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Gish_Gallop"&gt;Gish Gallop&lt;/a&gt; of hackneyed climate myths.&amp;nbsp; We'll not go into a detailed debunking in this post, but for the sake of thoroughness:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: justify;"&gt;the claim that CO2 lags behind temperature changes is &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/co2-lags-temperature-intermediate.htm"&gt;debunked here&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: justify;"&gt;the myth that the sun is causing global warming is &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/solar-activity-sunspots-global-warming-advanced.htm"&gt;debunked here&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: justify;"&gt;the myth that climate scientists were all predicting an impending ice age in the 1970s is &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/ice-age-predictions-in-1970s-intermediate.htm"&gt;debunked here&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: justify;"&gt;the myth that humans aren't causing global warming is &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/its-not-us-advanced.htm"&gt;debunked here&lt;/a&gt;; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the myth that renewable energy is too expensive is &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/renewable-energy-is-too-expensive.htm"&gt;debunked here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Rose and Bellamy also argue that the planet will survive global warming.&amp;nbsp; While that is true, the question is whether species living on the planet will survive it, and how difficult that survival will become.&amp;nbsp; The more and faster&amp;nbsp;global warming and climate change humans cause, the more difficult it will be for species (&lt;a title="'Climate Change, Migration, and Conflict'" href="http://www.americanprogress.org/wp-content/uploads/issues/2012/01/pdf/climate_migration.pdf"&gt;including humans&lt;/a&gt;) to adapt to those changes, and &lt;a title="Can animals and plants adapt to global warming?" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Can-animals-and-plants-adapt-to-global-warming.htm"&gt;the fewer species will surivive&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; As a botanist, we would have thought Bellamy should know this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Rose-Colored Denial Glasses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Ultimately David Rose has given us yet another textbook example of global warming denial, quite literally denying that the planet is warming.&amp;nbsp; In attempting to support this myth, Rose has grossly misrepresented the positions of most of the climate scientists he references in his article, as well as misinterpreting their data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In reality the planet is accumulating heat equivalent to 4 Hiroshima atomic bomb detonations per second, and that warming shows no signs of slowing, let alone stopping.&amp;nbsp; It's a physical reality that the Earth will continue to accumulate heat as long as we continue to increase the greenhouse effect by adding CO2 to the atmosphere.&amp;nbsp; Quite simply, global warming will not stop until we actually DO something to stop it.&amp;nbsp; We cannot change the laws of physics simply by denying them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Also see posts on this subject by &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/bad_astronomy/2013/03/18/global_warming_denial_debunking_misleading_climate_change_claims_by_david.html"&gt;Phil Plait at Bad Astronomy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.carbonbrief.org/blog/2013/03/scientists-set-straight-mail-on-sundays-latest-climate-contortion"&gt;Carbon Brief&lt;/a&gt;, and by &lt;a href="http://www.met.reading.ac.uk/~sgs02rpa/latest.html#ROSE"&gt;the University of Reading's Richard Allan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="linkscent-iconblock" style="padding: 0px ! important; margin: 0px ! important; float: none ! important; border: 0px solid #ff0000 ! important; background: none repeat scroll center center transparent ! important; width: auto ! important; height: auto ! important; display: block ! important; overflow: visible ! important; position: static ! important; text-indent: 0px ! important; z-index: auto ! important; max-width: none ! important; min-width: 0px ! important; max-height: none ! important; min-height: 0px ! important; left: auto ! important; top: auto ! important; bottom: auto ! important; right: auto ! important; line-height: 16px ! important; white-space: nowrap ! important;"&gt;&lt;img class="linkscent-icon" style="padding: 0px ! important; margin: 0px; float: none ! important; border: 0px solid #ff0000 ! important; width: 16px ! important; height: 16px ! important; display: none; overflow: visible ! important; position: absolute ! important; text-indent: 0px ! important; z-index: 2147483635 ! important; max-width: none ! important; min-width: 0px ! important; max-height: none ! important; min-height: 0px ! important; left: 510px; top: 870px; bottom: auto ! important; right: auto ! important; line-height: 16px ! important; white-space: nowrap ! important; visibility: visible; background: url('http://skepticalscience.com/favicon.ico') no-repeat scroll center center transparent ! important;" src="chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/pixel.gif" alt="" /&gt;&lt;img class="linkscent-icon" style="padding: 0px ! important; margin: 0px; float: none ! important; border: 0px solid #ff0000 ! important; background: url('chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/sprites.png') no-repeat scroll -16px -80px transparent; width: 16px ! important; height: 16px ! important; display: none; overflow: visible ! important; position: absolute ! important; text-indent: 0px ! important; z-index: 2147483635 ! important; max-width: none ! important; min-width: 0px ! important; max-height: none ! important; min-height: 0px ! important; left: 528px; top: 870px; bottom: auto ! important; right: auto ! important; line-height: 16px ! important; white-space: nowrap ! important; visibility: visible;" src="chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/pixel.gif" alt="" width="16" height="16" /&gt;&lt;img class="linkscent-icon" style="padding: 0px ! important; margin: 0px; float: none ! important; border: 0px solid #ff0000 ! important; background: none repeat scroll center center transparent; width: 16px ! important; height: 16px ! important; display: none; overflow: visible ! important; position: absolute ! important; text-indent: 0px ! important; z-index: 2147483635 ! important; max-width: none ! important; min-width: 0px ! important; max-height: none ! important; min-height: 0px ! important; left: 546px; top: 870px; bottom: auto ! important; right: auto ! important; line-height: 16px ! important; white-space: nowrap ! important; visibility: hidden;" src="chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/pixel.gif" alt="" /&gt;&lt;img class="linkscent-icon" style="padding: 0px ! important; margin: 0px; float: none ! important; border: 0px solid #ff0000 ! important; width: 16px ! important; height: 16px ! important; display: none; overflow: visible ! important; position: absolute ! important; text-indent: 0px ! important; z-index: 2147483635 ! important; max-width: none ! important; min-width: 0px ! important; max-height: none ! important; min-height: 0px ! important; left: 432px; top: 904px; bottom: auto ! important; right: auto ! important; line-height: 16px ! important; white-space: nowrap ! important; visibility: visible; background: url('http://llnl.gov/favicon.ico') no-repeat scroll center center transparent ! important;" src="chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/pixel.gif" alt="" /&gt;&lt;img class="linkscent-icon" style="padding: 0px ! important; margin: 0px; float: none ! important; border: 0px solid #ff0000 ! important; background: none repeat scroll center center transparent; width: 16px ! important; height: 16px ! important; display: none; overflow: visible ! important; position: absolute ! important; text-indent: 0px ! important; z-index: 2147483635 ! important; max-width: none ! important; min-width: 0px ! important; max-height: none ! important; min-height: 0px ! important; left: 450px; top: 904px; bottom: auto ! important; right: auto ! important; line-height: 16px ! important; white-space: nowrap ! important; visibility: hidden;" src="chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/pixel.gif" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="linkscent-iconblock" style="padding: 0px ! important; margin: 0px ! important; float: none ! important; border: 0px solid #ff0000 ! important; background: none repeat scroll center center transparent ! important; width: auto ! important; height: auto ! important; display: block ! important; overflow: visible ! important; position: static ! important; text-indent: 0px ! important; z-index: auto ! important; max-width: none ! important; min-width: 0px ! important; max-height: none ! important; min-height: 0px ! important; left: auto ! important; top: auto ! important; bottom: auto ! important; right: auto ! important; line-height: 16px ! important; white-space: nowrap ! important;"&gt;&lt;img class="linkscent-icon" style="padding: 0px ! important; margin: 0px; float: none ! important; border: 0px solid #ff0000 ! important; width: 16px ! important; height: 16px ! important; display: none; overflow: visible ! important; position: absolute ! important; text-indent: 0px ! important; z-index: 2147483635 ! important; max-width: none ! important; min-width: 0px ! important; max-height: none ! important; min-height: 0px ! important; left: 72px; top: 609px; bottom: auto ! important; right: auto ! important; line-height: 16px ! important; white-space: nowrap ! important; visibility: visible; background: url('chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/linkscentExternal.png') no-repeat scroll center center transparent ! important;" src="chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/pixel.gif" alt="" /&gt;&lt;img class="linkscent-icon" style="padding: 0px ! important; margin: 0px; float: none ! important; border: 0px solid #ff0000 ! important; background: none repeat scroll center center transparent; width: 16px ! important; height: 16px ! important; display: none; overflow: visible ! important; position: absolute ! important; text-indent: 0px ! important; z-index: 2147483635 ! important; max-width: none ! important; min-width: 0px ! important; max-height: none ! important; min-height: 0px ! important; left: 90px; top: 609px; bottom: auto ! important; right: auto ! important; line-height: 16px ! important; white-space: nowrap ! important; visibility: hidden;" src="chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/pixel.gif" alt="" /&gt;&lt;img class="linkscent-icon" style="padding: 0px ! important; margin: 0px; float: none ! important; border: 0px solid #ff0000 ! important; width: 16px ! important; height: 16px ! important; display: none; overflow: visible ! important; position: absolute ! important; text-indent: 0px ! important; z-index: 2147483635 ! important; max-width: none ! important; min-width: 0px ! important; max-height: none ! important; min-height: 0px ! important; left: 510px; top: 1577px; bottom: auto ! important; right: auto ! important; line-height: 16px ! important; white-space: nowrap ! important; visibility: visible; background: url('http://skepticalscience.com/favicon.ico') no-repeat scroll center center transparent ! important;" src="chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/pixel.gif" alt="" /&gt;&lt;img class="linkscent-icon" style="padding: 0px ! important; margin: 0px; float: none ! important; border: 0px solid #ff0000 ! important; background: url('chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/sprites.png') no-repeat scroll -16px -80px transparent; width: 16px ! important; height: 16px ! important; display: none; overflow: visible ! important; position: absolute ! important; text-indent: 0px ! important; z-index: 2147483635 ! important; max-width: none ! important; min-width: 0px ! important; max-height: none ! important; min-height: 0px ! important; left: 528px; top: 1577px; bottom: auto ! important; right: auto ! important; line-height: 16px ! important; white-space: nowrap ! important; visibility: visible;" src="chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/pixel.gif" alt="" width="16" height="16" /&gt;&lt;img class="linkscent-icon" style="padding: 0px ! important; margin: 0px; float: none ! important; border: 0px solid #ff0000 ! important; background: none repeat scroll center center transparent; width: 16px ! important; height: 16px ! important; display: none; overflow: visible ! important; position: absolute ! important; text-indent: 0px ! important; z-index: 2147483635 ! important; max-width: none ! important; min-width: 0px ! important; max-height: none ! important; min-height: 0px ! important; left: 546px; top: 1577px; bottom: auto ! important; right: auto ! important; line-height: 16px ! important; white-space: nowrap ! important; visibility: hidden;" src="chrome://interclue/content/cluecore/skins/default/pixel.gif" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1926</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1926</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 04:20:05 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>2013 SkS Weekly Digest #11</title>
<description>&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;SkS Highlights&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;If you liked "Gunfight at the OK Corral", you'll like the comment thread to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/oilprice-watts-interview.html"&gt;Watts Interview &amp;ndash; Denial and Reality Mix like Oil and Water&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;text by Dana and graphics by John Cook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;If you like eye-popping graphics, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/feb-2013-sea-ice-spiral.html"&gt;February 2013 Arctic &lt;span id="skstip3" class="skstip advanced" onmouseover="sksTip(this.id,'Sea ice');" onmouseout="sksTipCancel(this.id,'Sea ice');"&gt;Sea Ice&lt;/span&gt; Death Spiral Update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, text by Dana and graphics by Andy Lee Robinson, is&amp;nbsp; for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;If you like your science straight-up, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/drost-karoly-braganza-2012.html"&gt;Drost, Karoly, and Braganza Find Human Fingerprints in Global Warming&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;by Dana is the place to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;Toon of the Week&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img title="Gravity is a hoax!" src="http://www.skepticalscience.com//pics/2013Toon11.jpg" alt="2013 Toon 11" width="500" height="395" /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;Quote of the Week&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;"I don't think it's OK to walk past a mugging on the way to pay the mortgage. Climate scientists need to be good citizens too. Our science tells us we are killing people in poor parts of the world by putting our lights on and we need to make people think about that. Scientists need to start standing up for what they believe in. By staying quiet we are legitimizing it."&lt;/em&gt; -- Kevin Anderson of the Tyndall Centre for Climate Change Research at the University of Manchester, UK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://environmentalresearchweb.org/cws/article/opinion/52289"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are we heading for 6&amp;deg; temperature rise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Liz Kalaugher, Environmental Research Web, Feb 6, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;The Week in Review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/feb-2013-sea-ice-spiral.html"&gt;February 2013 Arctic Sea Ice Death Spiral Update&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;by Dana &amp;amp; Andy Lee Robinson (graphics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/2013-SkS-Weekly-News-Roundup_11.html"&gt;2013 SkS Weekly News Roundup #11&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;by John Hartz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/jurassic-global-warming.html"&gt;Death in Jurassic Park: global warming and ocean anoxia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;by John Mason&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/oilprice-watts-interview.html"&gt;Watts Interview &amp;ndash; Denial and Reality Mix like Oil and Water&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Dana &amp;amp; John Cook (graphiocs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/state-department-tar-sands-eis.html"&gt;State Department Downplays the Climate Impact of Keystone XL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Dana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/2013-SkS-News-Bulletin-3.html"&gt;2013 SkS News Bulletin #3: Alberta Tar Sands and Keystone XL Pipeline&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;by John Hartz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/renewables-policy-norway.html"&gt;Does Norway lack political commitment to renewables?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by GWS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/drost-karoly-braganza-2012.html"&gt;Drost, Karoly, and Braganza Find Human Fingerprints in Global Warming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Dana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/pdf_rebuttal_intro.html"&gt;Skeptical Science launches PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Doug Bostrom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;Coming Soon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Study, Same Result - Greenhouse Gases Dominate Global Warming&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;(Dana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ^ New! Abridged Skeptical Science Quick Reference Guide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Daniel Bailey)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fool's Gold of Current Climate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Dana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To frack or not to frack?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (gws)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tung and Zhou circularly blame ~40% of global warming on regional warming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Dumb Scientist)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 SkS News Roundup&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;(John Hartz)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;In the Works&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Klotzbach Revisited and John Christy's response, part 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (JosHag)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Klotzbach Revisited and John Christy's response, part 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (JosHag)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The radiative role of clouds &amp;ndash; which ones warm and which ones cool the Earth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (jenikhollan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A tale told in maps and charts: Texas in the National Climate Assessment&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;(Dana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New satellite confirms dramatic thinning of Arctic ice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (MarkR)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lomborg's Irresponsible Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Agnostic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s getting hotter &amp;ndash; despite cooling from cosmic rays&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (John Cook)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;SkS in the News&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mary-ellen-harte/climate-change-this-week_b_2850263.html?utm_hp_ref=green"&gt;Mary Ellen Harte at Huffington Post&lt;/a&gt; used Andy Lee Robinson's Arctic sea ice cubes graphic and referenced Dana's &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/cherrypicking-deny-continued-ocean-global-warming.html"&gt;Cherrypicking to Deny Continued Ocean and Global Warming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.weather.com/news/science/environment/climate-change-truth-20130315"&gt;Weather.com used several SkS rebuttals&lt;/a&gt; to debunk 10 common climate myths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gmagazine.com.au/features/3727/appy-days"&gt;Green Lifestyle Magazine&lt;/a&gt; endorsed the SkS smartphone app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/03/11/1193350/-ALEC-Koch-front-groups-swarm-Kansas-legislators-to-kill-wind-incentives"&gt;Daily Kos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://desmogblog.com/2013/03/11/onslaught-kochtopus-groups-threaten-kansas-clean-energy"&gt;DeSmogBlog&lt;/a&gt; referenced the SkS John Christy rebuttals on the Kansas renewable energy story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/03/11/1193153/-Test-driving-Reality-Drop-the-Climate-Reality-Project-s-siege-engine"&gt;Daily Kos&lt;/a&gt; also discussed the SkS contribution to the Reality Drop project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.hotwhopper.com/2013/03/watts-is-whopping-crazy-after-marcott.html"&gt;HotWhopper&lt;/a&gt; linked to the &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/don-easterbrook-heartland-distortion-of-reality.html%20"&gt;SkS debunking of Don Easterbrook's Heartland Distortions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://roymustard.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/hypocritical-john-mcclean-is-a-hypocrite/"&gt;Climate Wars&lt;/a&gt; used an SkS graphic to show John McLean's terrible climate prediction failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://uknowispeaksense.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/proponent-comment-of-the-day-march-12-2013/"&gt;uknowispeaksense&lt;/a&gt; referenced the SkS rebuttals database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;SkS Spotlights&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The purpose of the &lt;a href="http://gcfund.net/home.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Green Climate Fund&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to make a significant and ambitious contribution to the global efforts towards attaining the goals set by the international community to combat climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The Fund will contribute to the achievement of the ultimate objective of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). In the context of sustainable development, the Fund will promote the paradigm shift towards low-emission and climate-resilient development pathways by providing support to developing countries to limit or reduce their greenhouse gas emissions and to adapt to the impacts of climate change, taking into account the needs of those developing countries particularly vulnerable to the adverse effects of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1920</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1920</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 07:52:06 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>2013 SkS News Bulletin #4: Alberta Tar Sands and Keystone XL Pipeline</title>
<description>&lt;div class="greenbox" style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Big Oil attempts to end-run Keystone XL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Billionaire joins fight against Keystone XL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Canada's Plan to Get Rich by Trashing the Climate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Furor over Keystone XL pipeline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;German scientists quit oilsands project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Greenwashing the tar sands&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Is the US State Department being downright fraudulent?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone supporters hit back at Pelosi's export criticism&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone XL pipeline not&amp;nbsp;a climate change cure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Obama's opportunity to get serious on climate change&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Pelosi questions Keystone pipeline value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Rejection of Keystone XL would hurt Canada-U.S. ties&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;US Senators push for Keystone XL approval&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Big Oil attempts to end-run Keystone XL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The oil industry is planning an end-run around the President and State Department as they linger over the impending decision on whether to authorize the Keystone XL tar sands pipeline by pushing for Big Oil friendly Congressional approval of the project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.commondreams.org/headline/2013/03/16"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big Oil Attempts to End-Run Keystone XL with Congressional Approval&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;by Lauren McCauley, Common Dreams, Mar 16, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Billionaire joins fight against Keystone XL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Keystone XL pipeline faces a new, formidable and deep-pocketed foe: Tom Steyer, a California billionaire, has targeted the controversial Canadian project to funnel Alberta&amp;rsquo;s landlocked heavy crude to Texas refineries on the Gulf Coast.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/report-on-business/industry-news/energy-and-resources/billionaire-joins-fight-against-keystone-xl/article9938490/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Billionaire joins fight against Keystone XL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Koring, The Globe and Mail, Mar 19, 3013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Canada's Plan to Get Rich by Trashing the Climate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Like every other country in the world, Canada has promised to help keep global warming to less than 2 degrees C. However Canada's political and corporate leadership are committed to turning the country into a fossil-fuelled &amp;ldquo;energy superpower.&amp;rdquo; With a drug lord's just-providing-a-service hypocrisy Canada has openly declared it's future is tied to the profits from dumping hundreds of millions of tonnes of climate-heating carbon into the atmosphere every year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.desmog.ca/2013/03/14/blame-canada-part-2-canada-s-plan-get-rich-trashing-climate"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blame Canada Part 2: Canada's Plan to Get Rich by Trashing the Climate&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;by Stpehen Leahy, DeSmog Canada, Mar 14, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Furor over Keystone XL pipeline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Despite climate sweet talk from Alberta now, Keystone is a saga of missed opportunity and diplomatic failure, experts say.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://insideclimatenews.org/news/20130320/furor-over-keystone-pipeline-caught-us-and-canada-flat-footed-climate-change"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Furor Over Keystone Pipeline Caught U.S. and Canada Flat-Footed on Climate Change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by John Cushman, Inside Climate News, Mar 20, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;German scientists quit oilsands project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pressure over environmental concerns has forced Germany's largest scientific&amp;nbsp; organization to pull out of joint research with Alberta on better ways to&amp;nbsp; upgrade oilsands bitumen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;German scientists with the Helmholtz-Alberta Initiative will no longer work&amp;nbsp; on such projects, Bernd Schneider, lead scientific co-ordinator for the&amp;nbsp; Helmholtz Association, said Tuesday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ctvnews.ca/business/german-scientists-quit-oilsands-project-over-climate-concerns-1.1202087#ixzz2O6jwv4ML"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;German scientists quit oilsands project over climate concerns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Bob Weber,&amp;nbsp;The Canadian Press/CTV, Mar 19, 2013&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Greenwashing the Tar Sands&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is Part One of a three-part series on the political greenwashing of the tar sands in Canada.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.desmog.ca/2013/03/19/short-history-greenwashing-tar-sands"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Short History of Greenwashing the Tar Sands, Part&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;1 by Jeff Gailus, DeSmog Canada, Mar 19, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Is the US State Department being downright fraudulent?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;At least one of the several oil-friendly corporate authors was apparently paid by Trans-Canada, the corporate applicant for -- and the owner of -- the Keystone pipeline. And that's not all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.alternet.org/environment/state-department-being-downright-fraudulent-assessing-risks-keystone-xl-pipeline?page=0%2C0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is the State Department Being Downright Fraudulent in Assessing the Risks of the Keystone XL Pipeline?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by William Boardman, Alternet, Mar 18, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone supporters hit back at Pelosi's export criticism&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The energy industry is lashing out at a senior U.S. Democrat who suggested that oil flowing through the Keystone XL pipeline is destined for export, a criticism that strikes at the heart of the rationale for the controversial project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/globe-investor/keystone-supporters-hit-back-at-pelosis-export-criticism/article9843411/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keystone supporters hit back at Pelosi's export criticism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Nathan VanderKlippe, The Globe and Mail, Mar 15, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone XL pipeline not a climate change cure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Barack Obama has seen protesters from his motorcade for years: McCain and Romney&amp;nbsp; campaign supporters, health&amp;nbsp; care reform opponents and all manner of Tea Party acolytes. But when he left&amp;nbsp; Argonne National Laboratory in a cold rain outside Chicago on Friday, there was&amp;nbsp; another breed altogether: environmentalists bearing bright hand-painted signs&amp;nbsp; with messages like, &amp;ldquo;No XL Pipeline.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://swampland.time.com/2013/03/16/white-house-keystone-xl-pipeline-not-a-climate-change-cure/#ixzz2Np8Xq7mZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;White House: Keystone XL Pipeline Not A Climate Change Cure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Scherer, Time, Mar 16, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Obama's opportunity to get serious on climate change&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Presidents' Day weekend, I was among the &lt;a href="http://content.sierraclub.org/press-releases/2013/02/more-35000-march-washington-climate-action" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;35,000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; who attended the Forward On Climate rally in Washington, D.C. to urge President Obama to make good on the promise in his second inaugural address to "respond to the threat of climate change, knowing that failure to do so would betray our children and future generations." The rally took aim specifically at Keystone XL, the hotly contested 1,700 mile pipeline project that would carry tar sands oil from northern Alberta, Canada all the way to the Gulf of Mexico.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/joel-wolfram/keystone-xl-pipeline-_b_2909468.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reject Keystone XL: Obama's Opportunity to Get Serious on Climate Change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Joel Wolfram, The Huffington Post, Mar 19, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Pelosi questions Keystone pipeline value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A day after President Obama indicated that there will soon be a decision on the&amp;nbsp; Keystone XL pipeline, the top House Democrat questioned the value of the&amp;nbsp; controversial project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thehill.com/blogs/e2-wire/e2-wire/288199-pelosi-questions-value-of-keystone-xl-pipeline"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pelosi questions Keystone pipeline value&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Mike Lillis, The Hill, Mar 14, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Rejection of Keystone XL would hurt Canada-U.S. ties&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alberta&amp;rsquo;s premier says a U.S. rejection of the Keystone XL pipeline proposal would undermine the Canada-U.S. relationship.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://business.financialpost.com/2013/03/18/redford-calls-mulcairs-keystone-xl-comments-in-u-s-ridiculous/?__lsa=003a-3973"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rejection of Keystone XL would hurt Canada-U.S. ties: Redford&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Stepaniew Levitz, Canadian Press, Fianancial Post, Mar 13, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;US Senators push for Keystone XL approval&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;These Senators are clearly looking at oil industry bottom lines in order to protect their campaign contributions, when they should be looking at what&amp;rsquo;s in the best interests of the public.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.alternet.org/environment/senators-cashing-oil-money-push-keystone-xl-approval-new-bill"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Senators Cashing in on Oil Money Push for Keystone XL Approval With New Bill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by David Turnbull, Alternet, Mar 19, 2013&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1919</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1919</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 14:47:24 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>Watts Interview  Denial and Reality Mix like Oil and Water</title>
<description>&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;A website called &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://oilprice.com/Interviews/Climate-Change-without-Catastrophe-Interview-with-Anthony-Watts.html"&gt;Oil Price&lt;/a&gt; recently conducted an interview with climate contrarian Anthony Watts.&amp;nbsp; In the interview, Watts tries to portray himself as the reasonable skeptic in the middle of the climate 'debate'.&amp;nbsp; Watts claims that he's a "lukewarmer" (a term which frankly just refers to &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/lukewarmerism-aka-ignoring-inconvenient-evidence.html"&gt;people who ignore inconvenient evidence&lt;/a&gt;), trying to position himself between the denialists and the climate scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;However, &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/agu-2012-solving-climate-problem.html"&gt;as Richard Alley has explained&lt;/a&gt;, in reality climate scientists are the reasonable skeptics in the middle, with denialists at one extreme and doomsayers at the other.&amp;nbsp; The sheer number of myths Watts manages to jam in his Oil Price interview confirms Alley's view.&amp;nbsp; In fact, the interview offers us a case study in the tactics climate denialists use to misinform the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Denial Strategy #1: Self-Contradictory Arguments are Welcome&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The first two interview answers reveal one of the&amp;nbsp;most common flaws&amp;nbsp;in climate contrarian arguments: &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/contradictions.php"&gt;self-contradictions&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; First Watts (wrongly) suggests that global warming 'proponents' expect the warming to happen in a steady, linear fashion, but then a few moments later admits that the climate is much more complex than that (which, believe it or not, climate scientists realize).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com//pics/wattsvwatts_global_warming.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.skepticalscience.com//pics/wattsvwatts_global_warming.jpg" alt="watts vs. watts" width="500" height="165" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Image created by John Cook&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In reality, climate scientists are well aware that a number of different factors influence short-term global surface temperatures.&amp;nbsp; The climate system is noisy, and this is reflected in climate model temperature projections, as illustrated in this simple &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/hawkins-hiatus-gif.html"&gt;animation made by Ed Hawkins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.met.reading.ac.uk/%7Eed/bloguploads/hiatus.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.met.reading.ac.uk/%7Eed/bloguploads/hiatus.gif" alt="hawkins gif" width="500" height="414" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Denial Strategy #2:&amp;nbsp;Rewriting History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In the same quote, Watts has asserted that 'proponents' switched from using the term "global warming" to "climate change" because it "&lt;em&gt;can be liberally applied to just about anything observable in the atmosphere&lt;/em&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/climate-change-global-warming.htm"&gt;In reality&lt;/a&gt;, the term "climate change" has been used for decades, including in Gilbert Plass' seminal 1956 study &lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.2153-3490.1956.tb01206.x/abstract" target="_self"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;'The &lt;span id="skstip15" class="skstip beginner disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;Carbon Dioxide&lt;/span&gt; Theory of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;Climatic Change&lt;/strong&gt;'&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; A&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/climate-change-global-warming.htm"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;Google Scholar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/climate-change-global-warming.htm"&gt; search reveals&lt;/a&gt; that the term '&lt;span id="skstip21" class="skstip beginner disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;climate change&lt;/span&gt;' was in use before the term 'global warming', and has always been the more commonly-used term in scientific literature.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;There is also an organization you may have heard of called the Intergovernmental Panel on &lt;strong&gt;Climate Change&lt;/strong&gt;, formed in 1988.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="articleTitle" style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;In fact, perhaps the only individual to actually advocate changing the term from 'global warming' to '&lt;span id="skstip23" class="skstip beginner disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;climate change&lt;/span&gt;' was&amp;nbsp;Republican political strategist Frank Luntz in a &lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.ewg.org/files/LuntzResearch_environment.pdf" target="_self"&gt;controversial memo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;advising conservative politicians on communicating about the environment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time for us to start talking about &amp;ldquo;&lt;span id="skstip24" class="skstip beginner disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;climate change&lt;/span&gt;&amp;rdquo; instead of global warming and &amp;ldquo;conservation&amp;rdquo; instead of preservation. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;strong style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;span id="skstip25" class="skstip beginner disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;Climate change&lt;/span&gt;&amp;rdquo; is less frightening than &amp;ldquo;global warming&amp;rdquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;. As one focus group participant noted, &lt;span id="skstip26" class="skstip beginner disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;climate change&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt; &amp;ldquo;sounds like you&amp;rsquo;re going from Pittsburgh to Fort Lauderdale.&amp;rdquo; While global warming has catastrophic connotations attached to it, &lt;span id="skstip27" class="skstip beginner disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;climate change&lt;/span&gt; suggests a more controllable and less emotional challenge.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;As usual, Watts has got the facts completely backwards and is trying to rewrite history.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Denial Strategy #3: Damage Control by Misrepresenting Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;A new study published in &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/339/6124/1198.abstract"&gt;Marcott et al. (2013)&lt;/a&gt; has effectively extended the so-called &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/broken-hockey-stick.htm"&gt;'hockey stick' graph&lt;/a&gt; and found that current temperatures are higher than they've been for 75% of the past 11,500 years, and the current rate of warming is faster than at any point during that timeframe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/marcott-B-1000.jpg"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/marcott-B-1000.jpg" alt="marcott" width="500" height="343" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;This is a very inconvenient result for climate contrarians, who have made attacking the 'hockey stick' one of their prime objectives.&amp;nbsp; This is evident from the six separate posts on Watts' blog (to date)&amp;nbsp;desperately trying (&lt;a href="http://blog.hotwhopper.com/2013/03/watts-is-whopping-crazy-after-marcott.html"&gt;and failing&lt;/a&gt;) to find a fundamental flaw in the results of Marcott et al.&amp;nbsp; Watts rehashes one of those attempts in his interview:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;"the climate of the past has been warmer than today as well as colder as indicated by &lt;a href="http://wattsupwiththat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gisp2-ice-core-temperatures.jpg"&gt;ice core isotope records&lt;/a&gt;."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;The link goes to a plot of temperatures not for the whole planet or northern hemisphere, but in one isolated location &amp;ndash; central Greenland &amp;ndash; &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/10000-years-warmer.htm"&gt;which conveniently ends over 150 years ago&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Watts' x-axis is incorrectly labeled 'Years Before Present (2000 AD)'; in reality, "Present" in this Greenland ice core data is 1950, and the last data point is 95 years before that, in 1855.&amp;nbsp; Thus Watts' graph leaves&amp;nbsp;out about 1.5&amp;deg;C of Greenland warming over the past 158 years.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watts' Graph:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://hot-topic.co.nz/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/easterbrook_fig5.png" border="0" alt="easterbrook_fig5.png" width="480" height="360" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Same data including the past 150 years (Click the image for a larger version):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://hot-topic.co.nz/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/GISP210klarge.png"&gt;&lt;img src="http://hot-topic.co.nz/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/GISP210k480.png" alt="GISP210k480.png" width="480" height="303" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Watts was also aware of &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/10000-years-warmer.htm"&gt;this error&lt;/a&gt;, because I notified him of it in a comment on his blog post.&amp;nbsp; However, either he or his moderators deleted the comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;Denial Strategy #4: Exaggerate Uncertainty&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;Inflating uncertainty is &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/certainty-monster-vs-uncertainty-ewok.html"&gt;a common tactic&lt;/a&gt; amongst climate contrarians, and Watts tries this strategy in his interview.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;"Predicting an outcome of a chaotic system over the long term is a very, very big task, one that we&amp;rsquo;ve really only scratched the surface of."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;In reality, making long-term climate projections is easier than short-term projections, which are complicated by the noise in the system.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/climate-models-intermediate.htm"&gt;Climate model projections have also been pretty darn accurate&lt;/a&gt; so far.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;It's also important to note that&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/climate-of-doubt-strategy-2-exaggerate-uncertainty.html"&gt;uncertainty is not our friend&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; More uncertainty means that the consequences of climate change may not be as bad as we expect, and it also means &lt;strong&gt;they may be worse&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The only way to argue for climate inaction is if we have &lt;strong&gt;certainty&lt;/strong&gt; that the consequences of climate change will be small.&amp;nbsp; As Watts has admitted, we do not have that certainty, and in fact &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/global-warming-positives-negatives-advanced.htm"&gt;the body of scientific evidence strongly indicates the consequences of climate change will be bad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;Denial Strategy #5: Peddling Blog "Science"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;Watts also peddles &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/surface-temperature-measurements-advanced.htm"&gt;the myth that the surface temperature record is unreliable&lt;/a&gt;, thus arguing that human-caused global warming is smaller than climate scientists believe.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;"&lt;a href="http://wattsupwiththat.com/2012/07/29/press-release-2/"&gt;my recent study&lt;/a&gt; (preliminary) shows that not only is the deployment of weather stations faulty in siting them, but that the adjustments designed to solve those issues actually make the problem worse ... the trend from the compliant weather stations that don&amp;rsquo;t have heat sink effects--can be attributed to CO2. That value appears to be half of what NOAA claims."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;The "preliminary" paper in question has not even been submitted to a journal, let alone been subjected to the peer-review process, and contains &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/watts_new_paper_critique.html"&gt;several fundamental flaws which completely undermine the conclusions&lt;/a&gt; that Watts asserts in this quote.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/watts-pbs-newshour.html"&gt;In a previous interview&lt;/a&gt;, Watts criticized Richard Muller of the Berkeley Earth Surface Temperature team for discussing his project results before they had passed peer-review:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;"Unfortunately he has not succeeded in terms of how science views, you know, a successful inquiry. His papers have not passed peer review."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;Perhaps that Anthony Watts should have a talk with this Anthony Watts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;Denial Strategy #6: Downplay Climate Impacts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;Watts somehow manages to downplay the intensity of &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/hurricane-sandy-global-warming.htm"&gt;Hurricane Sandy&lt;/a&gt;, which was the &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/capital-weather-gang/post/sandy-packed-more-total-energy-than-katrina-at-landfall/2012/11/02/baa4e3c4-24f4-11e2-ac85-e669876c6a24_blog.html"&gt;second-most energetic&lt;/a&gt; hurricane on record, with the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Sandy#United_States_2"&gt;second-largest property damage cost&lt;/a&gt; among Atlantic hurricanes at about $75 billion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;"The idea that Hurricane Sandy, a minor class 1 storm, was somehow connected to CO2 driven &amp;ldquo;climate change&amp;rdquo; is ludicrous"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;If he ever visits New Jersey or New York, we would advise Watts not to refer to Hurricane Sandy as "a minor storm."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Human-caused global warming also &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/hurricane-sandy-global-warming.htm"&gt;indisputably amplified the damage caused by Hurricane Sandy&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Higher sea levels mean larger storm surges, warmer oceans mean stronger hurricanes, and more moisture in the atmosphere means more rainfall and thus more flooding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;To deny that CO2 amplified the impacts of Hurricane Sandy is ludicrous.&amp;nbsp; And &lt;a href="http://www.the-scientist.com/?articles.view/articleNo/33084/title/Opinion--Super-Storm-Sandy/"&gt;as Kevin Trenberth has discussed&lt;/a&gt;, all weather now occurs in a climate that humans have altered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span id="yui_3_7_2_1_1363141105854_2212"&gt;"it is important to recognize that we have a &amp;ldquo;new normal,&amp;rdquo; whereby the environment in which all storms form is simply different than it was just a few decades ago.&amp;nbsp; Global climate change has contributed to the higher sea surface and sub-surface ocean temperatures, a warmer and moister atmosphere above the ocean, higher water levels around the globe, and perhaps more precipitation in storms."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Denial Strategy #7: Misrepresent Successful Climate Predictions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Climate contrarians love to claim that climate predictions have failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"catastrophic predictions of the future just haven&amp;rsquo;t held up when you look at the observed data compared to the early predictions."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;This particular quote is rather bizarre, because climate scientists and models have not predicted catastrophic effects would occur by 2013.&amp;nbsp; They have predicted that the planet would warm, ice would melt, sea levels would rise, the atmosphere would hold more moisture, and a whole slew of other changes which have indeed occurred.&amp;nbsp; In fact, &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/climate-scientists-esld.html"&gt;climate scientists have under-predicted many key climate changes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;If you want to see some bad predictions, &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/lessons-from-past-climate-predictions-arctic-sea-ice-extent-2012.html"&gt;just look at some made by Watts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/comparing-global-temperature-predictions.html"&gt;other climate contrarians&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; They have been &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/contary-to-contrarians-ipcc-temp-projections-accurate.html"&gt;far less accurate than those made by climate scientists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/pics/IPCCvsContrarians.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.skepticalscience.com/pics/Predictions_500.gif" alt="Predictions Comparison" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Denial Strategy #8: Misrepresent Basic Economics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Ultimately Watts admits his contrarian motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"many of the &amp;ldquo;solutions&amp;rdquo; that have been proposed are to increase taxes on energy"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In reality, the proposed solutions in question put a price on &lt;strong&gt;carbon&lt;/strong&gt;, not energy.&amp;nbsp; There are plenty of low-carbon energy sources which would not be impacted by a carbon price.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The fact that the cost of the damage caused by carbon emissions via climate change is not reflected in their price is a failure of the free market.&amp;nbsp; There is &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/co2-limits-economy-advanced.htm"&gt;a high cost&lt;/a&gt; associated with this damage, but if that cost is not reflected in the prices of the products causing those greenhouse gas emissions, consumers can't factor the cost into their purchasing decisions.&amp;nbsp; This is &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/11/magazine/11Economy-t.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;_r=0"&gt;economics 101&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Failing to put a price on carbon emissions is effectively &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/carbon-the-huge-overlooked-fossil-fuel-subsidy.html"&gt;a massive subsidy&lt;/a&gt;; anybody who supports a free market should support pricing those emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Denial Strategy #9: Misrepresent Climate Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Of course Watts includes the obligatory disparaging of renewable energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"Wind and solar require fossil fuel backups to manage their inconsistent energy production, which changes with the whims of weather, so they really aren&amp;rsquo;t making much of a dent."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;When &lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2012/05/26/us-climate-germany-solar-idUSBRE84P0FI20120526"&gt;solar energy is meeting up to 50% of Germany's electricity demand&lt;/a&gt;, does that count as 'not making much of a dent'?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In reality there are &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/renewable-energy-baseload-power.htm"&gt;several ways renewable energy can supply consistent energy production&lt;/a&gt; without necessarily needing fossil fuel backup.&amp;nbsp; And whenever the wind is blowing and/or the sun is shining,&amp;nbsp;renewables are significantly reducing our fossil fuel consumption and greenhouse gas emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Denial Strategy #10: Cherrypick the Noise&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Finally, Watts completes the interview by once again cherrypicking the noise in the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"Given that CO2 has a logarithmic, not linear effect in returning a portion of outbound LWIR energy to Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface, slowing the transfer to the top of the atmosphere, this suggests that a crisis of temperature from a doubling of CO2 is not likely. This low sensitivity near saturation is supported by the lack of observed warming at the surface for more than a decade."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;This argument is just very, very wrong.&amp;nbsp; There was a rapid warming of surface air temperatures in the 1990s, and a slower surface warming in the 2000s.&amp;nbsp; Does Watts really think that the greenhouse effect suddenly became &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/carbon-the-huge-overlooked-fossil-fuel-subsidy.html"&gt;saturated&lt;/a&gt; overnight?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In reality there was &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/was-2012-hottest-la-nina-on-record.html"&gt;a preponderance of El Ni&amp;ntilde;o events in the 1990s and a preponderance of La Ni&amp;ntilde;a events since 2000&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The former cause short-term surface warming, the latter cooling.&amp;nbsp; If we just look at the surface warming trend for El Ni&amp;ntilde;o years, for La Ni&amp;ntilde;a years, and for neutral years, in each case the trend is very consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/graphics.php?g=67"&gt;&lt;img src="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/ENSO_Temps_677.gif" alt="ENSO temps" width="500" height="340" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;More importantly, only about 2% of global warming goes into heating the atmosphere.&amp;nbsp; About 90% of global warming goes into heating the oceans, and when we account for all of the data, it's clear that &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/nuccitelli-et-al-2012.html"&gt;global warming continues unabated&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Only considering the convenient bit of data is &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/cherrypicking-deny-continued-ocean-global-warming.html"&gt;just another cherrypick&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/graphics.php?g=65"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.skepticalscience.com/graphics/Nuccitelli_OHC_Data.jpg" alt="Fig 1" width="500" height="313" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;True Skeptics Consider all the Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The lone constructive result of this Oil Price interview is that it has provided us with an excellent case study in the difference between skeptic climate scientists and extreme climate denialists.&amp;nbsp; Real skeptics consider all the data, while denialists cherrypick and misrepresent data, rewrite history, and give more weight to blog 'science' than peer-reviewed science, all because they oppose the solutions to human-caused global warming.&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1914</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1914</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 03:15:14 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>2013 SkS Weekly News Roundup #11 </title>
<description>&lt;div class="greenbox" style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canada losing its seasons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can the world fight climate change and energy poverty at the same time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chief of US Pacific forces calls climate biggest worry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Five companies vie to build wind farms off North Carolina&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global warming brings on more pollen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green Climate Fund planning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;India and Bangladesh very short of water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;President Obama should abandon the all of the above energy strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Somalia famine partially blamed on climate change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="entry-title"&gt;US EPA likely to delay climate rules for new power plants&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warming drives worrying surge in Arctic fishing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why saving the planet means saving the economy, too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Canada losing its seasons&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Canada is not a country, it&amp;rsquo;s winter,&amp;rdquo; Canadians say with pride. But the nation&amp;rsquo;s long, fearsome winters will live only in memory and song for Canadian children born this decade.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ipsnews.net/2013/03/canada-losing-its-seasons/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canada Losing Its Seasons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Stephen Leahy, Inter Press Service (IPS), Mar 11, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Can the world fight climate change and energy poverty at the same time?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The United Nations has set two huge energy-related goals for the coming century. The first is to bring electricity to the 1.3 billion people who still don&amp;rsquo;t have it. The second is to curtail fossil fuel use and keep global warming below 2&amp;deg;C.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/wp/2013/03/10/can-we-tackle-climate-change-and-energy-poverty-at-the-same-time/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can the world fight climate change and energy poverty at the same time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Brad Pulmer, Washington Post, Mar 10, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Chief of US Pacific forces calls climate biggest worry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;America&amp;rsquo;s top military officer in charge of monitoring hostile actions by North Korea, escalating tensions between China and Japan, and a spike in computer attacks traced to China provides an unexpected answer when asked what is the biggest long-term security threat in the Pacific region: climate change.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/nation/2013/03/09/admiral-samuel-locklear-commander-pacific-forces-warns-that-climate-change-top-threat/BHdPVCLrWEMxRe9IXJZcHL/story.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chief of US Pacific forces calls climate biggest worry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Bryan Bender, Boston Globe, Mar 9, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Five companies vie to build wind farms off North Carolina coastline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Five companies are interested in developing wind farms in the ocean off North Carolina, hoping to take advantage of what could be the East Coast&amp;rsquo;s most promising chance to create energy through giant turbines anchored to the sea floor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mcclatchydc.com/2013/03/12/185639/five-companies-vie-to-build-wind.html#emlnl=Daily_News_Update"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Five companies vie to build wind farms off North Carolina coastline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Sean Cockerham McClatchy News, Mar 12, 2013&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Global warming brings on more pollen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;With global warming, temperature extremes are becoming a norm -- and that's bad news for allergy sufferers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="cnn_storypgraphtxt cnn_storypgraph2" style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a single century, our planet went from one of the coldest decades since the last ice age to one of the hottest. That hasn't happened in the last 11,300 years, according to a recent study on global temperatures published in the journal Science.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="cnn_storypgraphtxt cnn_storypgraph3" style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;By 2100, temperatures will rise "well above anything we've ever seen in the last 11,000 years," said study co-author Shaun Marcott.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="cnn_storypgraphtxt cnn_storypgraph3" style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/03/12/health/allergies-global-warming/index.html?hpt=hp_bn13"&gt;Global warming brings on more pollen&lt;/a&gt; by Elizabeth Landau , CNN, Mar 12, 2013&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 class="cnn_storypgraphtxt cnn_storypgraph3" style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Green Climate Fund Planning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;As the new board of the United Nations Green Climate Fund meets in Berlin this week, activist and watchdog groups here and around the world are expressing frustration over proposed rules they say are already significantly limiting civil society participation in the new initiative.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ipsnews.net/2013/03/civil-society-wants-bigger-role-in-green-climate-fund-planning/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Civil Society Wants Bigger Role in Green Climate Fund Planning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Carey&amp;nbsp;L. Biron, Inter PressService (IPS), Mar 12, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;India and Bangladesh very short of water&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Three out of four countries in Asia and the Pacific are facing a serious lack of water, and some are in danger of a crisis unless steps are taken to improve water management, a report by the Asian Development Bank and the Asia-Pacific Water Forum has said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.trust.org/alertnet/news/india-bangladesh-very-short-of-water-among-asias-worst-report"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;India, Bangladesh very short of water, among Asia's worst - report&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Nita Bhalla, Alertnet, Mar 13, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;President Obama should abandon the all of the above energy strategy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;If the Environmental Protection Agency works hard to regulate greenhouse gasses and pushes energy development away from fossil fuels and the Department of Energy works to develop the science and engineering of solar energy, we might be able to move from the non-strategy of "all of the above", to something that makes &lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;choices and makes sense.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/steven-cohen/president-obama-should-ab_b_2852047.html?utm_hp_ref=green"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;President Obama Should Abandon the All of the Above Energy Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Steven Cohen, The Huffinton Post,&amp;nbsp;Mar 11, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Somalia famine partially blamed on climate change&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Global warming may have contributed to low rain levels in Somalia in 2011 where tens of thousands died in a famine, research by British climate scientists suggests.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/15/somalia-famine-climate-change_n_2883088.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Somalia Famine Partially Blamed On Climate Change in New Study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Straziuso, The Huffington Post,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="entry-title" style="color: #003300;"&gt;US EPA likely to delay climate rules for new power plants&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Obama administration is leaning toward revising its landmark proposal to regulate greenhouse gas emissions from new power plants, according to several individuals briefed on the matter, a move that would delay tougher restrictions and could anger many environmentalists.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/epa-may-delay-climate-rules-for-new-power-plants/2013/03/15/28e9d37e-8cda-11e2-b63f-f53fb9f2fcb4_story.html"&gt;EPA likely to delay climate rules for new power plants by&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="author vcard"&gt;&lt;span class="fn"&gt;Juliet Eilperin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Washington Post, Mar 15, 2013&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Warming drives worrying surge in Arctic fishing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Climate change may be good news for the Arctic fishing industry over the next few years, but it could spell long-term disaster for one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most promising yet fragile fisheries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.trust.org/alertnet/news/warming-drives-worrying-surge-in-arctic-fishing"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warming drives worrying surge in Arctic fishing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Ali Morrow, Alertnet, March 14, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Why saving the planet means saving the economy, too&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s be clear: the deficit is not our biggest problem right now. Climate change is. It isn&amp;rsquo;t even our biggest economic problem. A stagnating economy is. And&amp;mdash;as the majority of economists have pointed out, and as the European experience clearly shows&amp;mdash;austerity will only make our economy worse.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.commondreams.org/view/2013/03/12-2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Saving the Planet Means Saving the Economy, Too&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by John Atchenson, Common Dreams, Mar 12, 2013&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1913</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1913</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 01:20:37 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>2013 SkS Weekly Digest #10</title>
<description>&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;SkS Highlights&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Dana's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/cherrypicking-deny-continued-ocean-global-warming.html"&gt;Cherrypicking to Deny Continued Ocean and Global Warming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and Rob Painting's &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Carbon-Dioxide-the-Dominant-Control-on-Global-Temperature-and-Sea-Level-Over-the-Last-40-Million-Years.html"&gt;Carbon Dioxide the Dominant Control on Global Temperature and Sea Level Over the Last 40 Million Years &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;caused commentors juices to flow. The ensuing discussions covered a lot of territory and are instructive in their own right.&amp;nbsp;Contrary perspectives serve a useful purpose by challenging SkS authors to&amp;nbsp;better explain the science of climate change.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;Toon of the Week&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;&lt;img title="the downsides of the proposed Keystone XL pipeline" src="http://www.skepticalscience.com//pics/1_2013Toon10.jpg" alt="2013 Toon 10" width="500" height="205" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Reposted with permission of Neil Wagner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;Quote of the Week&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;I HOPE the president turns down the Keystone XL oil pipeline. (Who wants the U.S. to facilitate the dirtiest extraction of the dirtiest crude from tar sands in Canada&amp;rsquo;s far north?) But I don&amp;rsquo;t think he will. So I hope that Bill McKibben and his 350.org coalition go crazy. I&amp;rsquo;m talking chain-themselves-to-the-White-House-fence-stop-traffic-at-the-Capitol kind of crazy, because I think if we all make enough noise about this, we might be able to trade a lousy Keystone pipeline for some really good systemic responses to climate change. We don&amp;rsquo;t get such an opportunity often &amp;mdash; namely, a second-term Democratic president who is under heavy pressure to approve a pipeline to create some jobs but who also has a green base that he can&amp;rsquo;t ignore. So cue up the protests, and pay no attention to people counseling rational and mature behavior. We need the president to be able to say to the G.O.P. oil lobby, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to approve this, but it will kill me with my base. Sasha and Malia won&amp;rsquo;t even be talking to me, so I&amp;rsquo;ve got to get something really big in return.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/10/opinion/sunday/friedman-no-to-keystone-yes-to-crazy.html?_r=1&amp;amp;"&gt;No to Keystone. Yes to Crazy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;Op-ed by Thomas Friedman, New York Times, Mar 9, 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;The Week in Review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/greedy-lying-bastards.html"&gt;Greedy Lying Bastards - Now In Theaters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Dana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/2013-SkS-Weekly-News-Roundup_10.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 SkS Weekly News Roundup #10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by John Harz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/educational-opportunities-addressing-misinformation-classroom.html"&gt;The educational opportunities in addressing misinformation in the classroom&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;by John Cook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/unaffected_by_climate.html"&gt;What doesn&amp;rsquo;t change with climate?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;by Ari Jokim&amp;auml;ki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/cherrypicking-deny-continued-ocean-global-warming.html"&gt;Cherrypicking to Deny Continued Ocean and Global Warming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Dana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Carbon-Dioxide-the-Dominant-Control-on-Global-Temperature-and-Sea-Level-Over-the-Last-40-Million-Years.html"&gt;Carbon Dioxide the Dominant Control on Global Temperature and Sea Level Over the Last 40 Million Years&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;by Rob Painting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/china-leading-role-solutions.html"&gt;China Takes a Leading Role in Solving Climate Change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Dana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/frozen-dirt-and-methane.html"&gt;&amp;lsquo;&lt;strong&gt;Frozen Dirt&amp;rsquo; and Methane &amp;hellip; &amp;lsquo;We Cannot Go There&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Greenman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;Coming Soon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skeptical Science launches PDF "Autonomous Information Vehicles"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (doug_bostrom)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drost, Karoly, and Braganza Find Human Fingerprints in Global Warming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Dana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does Norway lack political commitment to renewables?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;(gws)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State Department Downplays the Climate Impact of Keystone XL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Dana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Death in Jurassic Park: global warming and ocean anoxia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (John Mason)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ^ New! Abridged Skeptical Science Quick Reference Guide&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;(Daniel Bailey)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 SkS News Roundup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (John Hartz)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;In the Works&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Study, Same Result - Greenhouse Gases Dominate Global Warming&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;(Dana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;A tale told in maps and charts: Texas in the National Climate Assessment&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(Dana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Residence Time and Prof Essenhigh&lt;/span&gt; (Glenton&lt;/strong&gt; Jelbert)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;New satellite confirms dramatic thinning of Arctic ice&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(MarkR)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Lomborg's Irresponsible Conclusions&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(Agnostic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Tung and Zhou circularly blame ~40% of global warming on regional warming&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Dumb Scientist)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s getting hotter &amp;ndash; despite cooling from cosmic rays&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (John Cook)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;SkS in the News&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.abc.net.au/environment/articles/2013/03/08/3710490.htm"&gt;ABC News interviewed John Cook &lt;/a&gt;about the role of SkS in the Reality Drop project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Dana's &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/cherrypicking-deny-continued-ocean-global-warming.html"&gt;Cherrypicking to Deny Continued Ocean and Global Warming&lt;/a&gt; was re-posted &lt;a href="http://thinkprogress.org/climate/2013/03/06/1684211/cherrypicking-to-deny-continued-ocean-and-global-warming/"&gt;on Climate Progress&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://mediamatters.org/blog/2013/03/07/the-new-science-of-climate-denial/192951"&gt;Shauna Theel at Media Matters&lt;/a&gt; referenced the SkS 1970s ice age predictions myth rebuttal while debunking the myth that climate science is 'new science'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://stephenleahy.net/2013/03/07/climate-change-b-s-detector-sorting-fact-from-fiction/"&gt;Stephen Leahy endorsed Skeptical Science&lt;/a&gt; as one of the best sources to separate climate fact from fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://mediamatters.org/blog/2013/03/07/scientist-rebukes-latest-factually-wrong-attemp/192955"&gt;Max Greenberg at Media Matters&lt;/a&gt; used The Escalator and 'where is global warming going' graphics in debunking a Heartland/Forbes blog post wrongly claiming that global warming has magically stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://ourchangingclimate.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/response-to-john-christys-blog-post-regarding-klotzbach-revisited/"&gt;Jos Hagelaars in a guest post on Bart Berheggen's Our Changing Climate&lt;/a&gt; referenced the SkS hot spot rebuttal and 'human fingerprint of global warming' page in responding to claims from John Christy about the Klotzbach et al. paper on tropospheric warming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In investigating how climate science denial blogs win online awards, &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/03/05/1191805/-How-climate-skeptics-win-science-blog-awards"&gt;Daily Kos discussed the SkS withdrawal from the Bloggies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://takvera.blogspot.com/2013/03/repost-china-takes-leading-role-in.html?spref=tw"&gt;Takver Takvera at Climate Citizen&lt;/a&gt; re-posted Dana's &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/china-leading-role-solutions.html"&gt;China Takes a Leading Role in Solving Climate Change&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;SkS Spotlights&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The &lt;a href="http://oregonstate.edu/research/oregon-climate-change-research-institute-occri-0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oregon Climate Change Research Institute (OCCRI&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;, based at Oregon State University (OSU), is a network of over 100 researchers at OSU, the University of Oregon, Portland State University, Southern Oregon University, and affiliated federal and state labs. In 2007, the Oregon state legislature created OCCRI and tasked it with: fostering climate change research among faculty of the Oregon University System (OUS); serving as a clearinghouse for climate information; and providing climate change information to the public in an easily understandable form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;OCCRI is the anchor institution for two federally funded regional climate science centers. The Department of the Interior&amp;rsquo;s (DOI) Pacific Northwest Climate Science Center (CSC) is one of eight planned CSC&amp;rsquo;s. The CSC will serve as a resource for DOI agencies in providing necessary science in advising policy decisions. The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration&amp;rsquo;s (NOAA) Pacific Northwest Climate Impacts Research Consortium is one of 11 Regional Integrated Sciences and Assessments (RISA) projects. The NOAA RISA will engage and support a broad number of stakeholders, including municipalities, utilities, emergency management organizations, and state and federal agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration&amp;rsquo;s (NOAA) Pacific Northwest Climate Impacts Research Consortium (CIRC) is one of 11 Regional Integrated Sciences and Assessments (RISA) projects. The CIRC is engaging a broad number of stakeholders, including municipalities, utilities, emergency management organizations, irrigators, agricultural and Sea Grant extension, and state and federal agencies. In support of these stakeholders, CIRC is working on developing regional downscaled climate scenarios using integrated climate, hydrological, and vegetation models; PNW region and basin scale climate impacts assessments; social science and network analysis; coastal climate hazard, risk and vulnerability assessments; decision scenario visualization and planning tools; climate extension; public health risk management guidance; and community level adaptation approaches (see &lt;a href="http://pnwclimate.org/"&gt;http://pnwclimate.org&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1911</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1911</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 01:53:31 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>2013 SkS News Bulletin #3: Alberta Tar Sands and Keystone XL Pipeline</title>
<description>&lt;div class="greenbox" style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;25 Keystone XL protesters arrested at TransCanada office&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Canadian oil, the Keystone pipeline and the Chinese&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Critical part of Keystone report done by firms with deep oil industry ties&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone pipeline decision may influence oil-sands development&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone rejection wouldn&amp;rsquo;t harm US-Canada relationship&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone XL pipeline path marks new battle line in Oklahoma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;No, Minister Oliver, the oil sands have not become 'green'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;The climate scientist and the pipeline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;When to say no&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Will Canada&amp;rsquo;s proposed tar sands oil pipeline muck up its Pacific Coast?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Will our political leaders land on the right side of history?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;25 Keystone XL protesters arrested at TransCanada office&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The protests at a TransCanada office in Westborough, Mass. continued today and more than 25 protesters have been arrested, the Stop the Keystone XL Pipeline group said this morning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://insideclimatenews.org/breaking-news/20130311/25-keystone-xl-pipeline-protesters-arrested-transcanada-office-oil-sands-tar-sands-dilbit-obama-state-dep?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+solveclimate%2Fblog+%28InsideClimate+"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25 Keystone XL Protesters Arrested at TransCanada Office&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Inside Climate News, Mar 11, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Canadian oil, the Keystone pipeline and the Chinese&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Americans have a love-hate relationship with Canadian oil, as thousands of anti-Keystone demonstrators in Washington recently reaffirmed. The Chinese are clearly not so conflicted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newsobserver.com/2013/03/09/2735671/canadian-oil-the-keystone-pipeline.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canadian oil, the Keystone pipeline and the Chinese&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Stephen R. Kelly, Raleigh News Observer, Mar 9, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Critical part of Keystone report done by firms with deep oil industry ties&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two consulting firms provided State Department with key analysis of whether the pipeline would speed development of Canada's oil sands.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://insideclimatenews.org/news/20130306/keystone-xl-eis-state-department-transcanada-oil-tar-sands-industry-ensys-energy-koch-brothers-exxonmobil-bp-obama?page=3&amp;amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A%20solveclimate%2Fblog%20%28InsideClimate%20News%29"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critical part of Keystone report done by firms with deep oil industry ties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Lisa Song, Inside Climate News, Mar 6, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone pipeline decision may influence oil-sands development&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A U.S. decision on whether to approve TransCanada Corp. (TRP)&amp;rsquo;s Keystone XL pipeline has the potential to accelerate -- or slow --investments in Canada&amp;rsquo;s oil sands.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-07/keystone-pipeline-decision-may-influence-oil-sands-development.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keystone pipeline decision may influence oil-sands development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;span&gt;Brad Olson&lt;/span&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;span class="last"&gt;Jeremy van Loon,&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="datestamp" style="display: inline;"&gt;Mar 7, 2013 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone rejection wouldn&amp;rsquo;t harm US-Canada relationship&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Canadian Minister of Natural Resources Joe Oliver predicted Wednesday that the&amp;nbsp; U.S. will approve the proposed Keystone XL oil sands pipeline, but added that&amp;nbsp; rejection would not harm the relationship between the two allies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thehill.com/blogs/e2-wire/e2-wire/286637-canadian-official-keystone-rejection-wouldnt-harm-us-canada-relationship#ixzz2Mp1PJYxs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canadian official:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Keystone rejection wouldn&amp;rsquo;t harm US-Canada relationship&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;by Ben Geman, The Hill, Mar 6, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone XL pipeline path marks new battle line in Oklahoma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pipeline opponents garnered national attention last month, when some 40,000 protesters (according to &lt;a href="http://350.org/en/about/blogs/story-forwardonclimate"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;organizers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) assembled in Washington, D.C., to urge the White House to take a stand against fossil fuel emissions by vetoing the project. The event was billed as the largest rally ever held in the United States on climate change. Less noticed have been the bitter personal battles being waged in the trenches&amp;mdash;literally, those being dug by TransCanada.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/energy/2013/03/130308-keystone-xl-pipeline-battle/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keystone XL Pipeline Path Marks New Battle Line in Oklahoma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Bret Schulte, National Geographic, Mar 8, 2013&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;No, Minister Oliver, the oil sands have not become 'green'&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="column-2 gridcol"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many Canadians must have wondered if George Orwell was alive and well this week as they read that the Alberta oil sands were being pitched to U.S. officials as &amp;ldquo;green&amp;rdquo; by Natural Resources Minister Joe Oliver.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/commentary/no-minister-oliver-the-oil-sands-have-not-become-green/article9503879/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No, Minister Oliver, the oil sands have not become 'green'&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Tzeporah Berman, The Globe &amp;amp; Mail, Mar 8, 2013&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;The climate scientist and the pipeline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A set of Letters to the Editor in repsonse to a prior article appearing in the New York Times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/09/opinion/the-climate-scientist-and-the-pipeline.html?emc=tnt&amp;amp;tntemail1=y&amp;amp;_r=0"&gt;The climate scientist and the pipeline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, New York Times, Mar 8, 2012&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;When to say no&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;In itself, the Keystone pipeline will not push the world into a climate apocalypse. &lt;span data-num="2"&gt;But it will continue to fuel our appetite for oil and add to the carbon load in the atmosphere.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span data-num="3"&gt;There is no need to accept it&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/11/opinion/when-to-say-no-to-the-keystone-xl.html?nl=todaysheadlines&amp;amp;emc=edit_th_20130311&amp;amp;_r=0#h[]"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to say no&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Editorial Board, New York Times, Mar 10, 203&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Will Canada&amp;rsquo;s&amp;nbsp;proposed tar sands oil pipeline muck up its Pacific Coast?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As controversy continues around the Keystone XL Pipeline that would snake through the U.S., a similar drama plays out north of the border. Canadian officials are deciding whether to green-light a pipeline that would carry a semiliquid hydrocarbon mix for 1,172 kilometers from Alberta's tar sands over the Canadian Rockies to the Pacific coast of British Columbia. Near its proposed terminus, the proposal has met with public outcry and fierce opposition from the Coastal First Nations, a coalition of indigenous tribes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=gateway-pipeline-poses-unknown-environmental-threat"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will Canada&amp;rsquo;s Proposed Tar Sands Oil Pipeline Muck Up Its Pacific Coast?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Anne Casselman, Scientific American, Mar 5, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Will our political leaders land on the right side of history?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A few days ago, I noticed something pretty striking when reading the US State Department&amp;rsquo;s report about the proposed Keystone XL tar sands pipeline. It made me wonder if the State Department is really paying attention to what&amp;rsquo;s happening up here in British Columbia. The report claimed the pipeline is &amp;ldquo;not likely&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;result in significant environmental effects&amp;rdquo; and that it would make &amp;ldquo;no substantive change in global greenhouse gas emissions.&amp;rdquo; The underlying assumption was that even if Keystone XL wasn&amp;rsquo;t built that Enbridge and/or Kinder Morgan&amp;rsquo;s pipelines would be built and the tar sands would continue to grow.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://forestethics.org/blog/pipeline-decisions-will-our-political-leaders-land-right-side-history"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pipeline Decisions: Will Our Political Leaders Land on the Right Side of History?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;by Ben West, Forest Ethics, Mar 7, 2013&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1908</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1908</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 13:30:48 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>State Department Downplays the Climate Impact of Keystone XL</title>
<description>&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The US State Department has released a draft &lt;a href="http://keystonepipeline-xl.state.gov/draftseis/index.htm"&gt;Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement&lt;/a&gt; (SEIS) on the proposed &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/updated-keystone-climate.html"&gt;Keystone XL pipeline project&lt;/a&gt; which was immediately subjected to &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/2013-SkS-News-Bulletin-2.html"&gt;harsh criticism from scientists and environmental groups&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The primary objection to the SEIS has been to this statement in &lt;a href="http://keystonepipeline-xl.state.gov/documents/organization/205719.pdf"&gt;Section ES.6.2&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"Approval or denial of any one crude oil transport project, including the proposed Project, &lt;span class="highlight begin selected"&gt;remains&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="highlight end selected"&gt; unlikely to si&lt;/span&gt;gnificantly impact the rate of extraction in the oil sands, or the continued demand for heavy crude oil at refineries in the U.S."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The conclusion that the tar sands will be developed with or without Keystone XL is based on the assumption that rail transportation can be ramped up to handle as much as 6 to 9 million barrels of tar sands oil per day by 2030 &amp;ndash; a claim which on its face seems implausible, and which the draft SEIS report did not support very well.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://s3.amazonaws.com/s3.350.org/images/kxl-own-words-v2.pdf"&gt;Many Canadian government and oil industry officials also seem to think Keystone XL is critical&lt;/a&gt; to maximize tar sands extraction, especially given &lt;a href="http://www.thestarphoenix.com/business/Canada+intensifies+lobbying+campaign/8055126/story.html"&gt;how intensely they're lobbying for it&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Anthony Swift at NRDC has also made &lt;a href="http://switchboard.nrdc.org/blogs/aswift/on_the_wrong_track_rail_is_not.html"&gt;a compelling argument&lt;/a&gt; that this conclusion is fundamentally flawed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The SEIS also concludes that denying the Keystone XL permit will reduce overall emissions by up to&amp;nbsp;5.3 million tonnes of CO2-equivalent emissions per year if other proposed tar sands pipeline projects are also denied (a very plausible scenario given &lt;a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/commentary/you-heard-it-here-northern-gateways-dead/article4589760/"&gt;public opposition in Canada&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;nbsp; This CO2 reduction would be equivalent to removing about 1 million cars from the road.&amp;nbsp; That number will be even larger if the State Department is wrong and rail transport is unable to handle 6 to 9 million barrels of tar sands oil every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;To date, only about one-third of the 9 million barrels per day tar sands&amp;nbsp;potential is currently under construction (&lt;a href="http://www.pembina.org/pub/2407"&gt;Figure 1&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;nbsp; In addition to directly reducing greenhouse gas emissions, rejecting Keystone XL would also send a powerful and negative message to prospective investors in planned, future capital-intensive projects to extract oil from the tar sands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/TarSandsPotential.png"&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/TarSandsPotential.png" alt="tar sands growth potential" width="500" height="254" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;State Department Keystone XL SEIS Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The State Department has jurisdiction over the Keystone XL project because the pipeline would cross the border between Canada and the USA.&amp;nbsp; According to the &lt;a title="National Environmental Policy Act" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Environmental_Policy_Act"&gt;National Environmental Policy Act&lt;/a&gt; (NEPA), US government agencies must develop an &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Environmental_impact_statement"&gt;EIS&lt;/a&gt; for any project which could significantly affect the quality of the human environment.&amp;nbsp; An EIS describes the positive and negative environmental effects of the proposed action.&amp;nbsp; A public comment period is then allowed so that interested parties can provide their opinions about the draft EIS and the proposed project.&amp;nbsp; The State Department will respond to the public comments and issue a final SEIS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;There have been several EIS report iterations for the Keystone XL project, as the proposed pipeline construction path has been changed to avoid the potential for spills to contaminate the critical &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ogallala_Aquifer"&gt;&lt;span class="st"&gt;Ogallala aquifer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/keystone_route.jpg" alt="new route" width="480" height="416" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="caption"&gt;The original route (dotted line) and the revised route (in red) of the proposed Keystone XL pipeline in Nebraska.&amp;nbsp; Source: &lt;a href="http://green.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/01/22/nebraska-governor-approves-keystone-xl-route/"&gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The US Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) also has the authority to comment on the Keystone XL EIS, and &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/viewer?a=v&amp;amp;q=cache:QidR8G1UEU8J:insideclimatenews.org/sites/default/files/EPAAnalysisStateDeptDraftEISJune2011INSIDECLIMATENEWS.pdf+&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;gl=us&amp;amp;pid=bl&amp;amp;srcid=ADGEESgRkg9ZtcehxzaogxSNjk_x7QdwDUkMgAaFKji0VrfSrw7wy0YfDpAHObdplkJjf8F-hSkTgjT6Wzg7RN9Dd_DiMFXhm2IfDPjz4lC0zbRsXpgXcWNtyEZRbHFCCb3e8y4n0N2l&amp;amp;sig=AHIEtbRg1AneQMaXdMdMT2GYuPE7dhxVjQ"&gt;noted that the draft SEIS produced in 2011&lt;/a&gt; did not contain sufficient information to address potential environmental objections, for example regarding the project's greenhouse gas emissions and potential for spills to impact groundwater resources.&amp;nbsp; The EPA will also undoubtedly comment on this latest State Department Keystone XL draft SEIS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;It's also important to bear in mind that as the &lt;a href="http://keystonepipeline-xl.state.gov/documents/organization/205558.pdf"&gt;SEIS cover letter&lt;/a&gt; notes, it is just one factor which will be considered in the ultimate decision as to whether the State Department will approve or reject the Keystone XL permit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"Ultimately, a determination will be made on whether this project serves the national interest.&amp;nbsp; The national interest determination will involve consideration of many factors, including: energy security; environmental, cultural, and economic impacts; foreign policy; and compliance with relevant federal regulations. As directed by Executive Order 13337, before making such a decision, the Department will also request the views of several agencies and officials, including: the Departments of Defense, Justice, Interior, Commerce, Transportation, Energy, Homeland Security, and the Environmental Protection Agency."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The ultimate decision will be made by Secretary of State John Kerry and President Obama.&amp;nbsp; Even if they accept the draft SEIS conclusion that Keystone XL does not pose an unacceptable threat to public or environmental health, the project may still be deemed to not be in the national interest.&amp;nbsp; For example, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/05/22/report-keystone-xl-gas-prices_n_1536227.html"&gt;it would raise gasoline prices in the USA&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mediamatters.org/blog/2013/03/04/nbc-overstates-state-departments-keystone-xl-jo/192888"&gt;would provide very few temporary construction or&amp;nbsp;long-term jobs&lt;/a&gt;, while posing the threat of contamination due to pipeline spills, as well as increasing greenhouse gas emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Trains vs. Pipelines &amp;ndash; the Importance of Keystone XL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://keystonepipeline-xl.state.gov/documents/organization/205654.pdf"&gt;Section 1.4 of the SEIS&lt;/a&gt; argues the case that the tar sands will inevitably be developed with or without Keystone XL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"If the proposed Project were denied but other proposed new and expanded pipelines go forward, the incremental decrease in production could be approximately 20,000 to 30,000 bpd (from 0.4 to &lt;span class="highlight begin selected"&gt;0.&lt;/span&gt;6&lt;span class="highlight end selected"&gt; percent&lt;/span&gt; of total WCSB production) by 2030"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;"If all such pipeline capacity were restricted in the medium-to-long-term, the incremental increase in cost of the non-pipeline transport options could result in a decrease in production from the oil sands, perhaps 90,000 to 210,000 barrels per day (bpd) (approximately 2 to 4 percent) by 2030"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The main alternative to pipeline transport of tar sands oil is via rail (train).&amp;nbsp; This is a somewhat more expensive option, approximately $5 per barrel according to the SEIS, but substantially more &lt;a href="http://switchboard.nrdc.org/blogs/aswift/on_the_wrong_track_rail_is_not.html"&gt;according to NRDC&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; The SEIS argues that it will nevertheless be financially viable, based on projected crude oil prices, but that may not be true if the SEIS has underestimated the cost of rail transport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Additionally, there are already &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/rail-emerges-as-alternative-to-keystone-xl-pipeline/2013/03/02/dae5d0fe-82ae-11e2-b99e-6baf4ebe42df_story.html"&gt;48,000 rail cars on backorder in North America&lt;/a&gt;, and there is an 18- to 24-month waiting period for new tank cars in Canada.&amp;nbsp; It's not entirely clear that rail transport will be able to pick up the slack if the proposed pipeline projects are rejected &amp;ndash; in fact, &lt;a href="https://s3.amazonaws.com/s3.350.org/images/kxl-own-words-v2.pdf"&gt;many Canadian government and oil industry officials seem to think Keystone XL is key&lt;/a&gt; to maximizing tar sands extraction.&amp;nbsp; The SEIS justifies its conclusion that rail could nearly match pipeline transportation capabilities by drawing a comparison to a rapid increase in coal rail transportation from the Powder River Basin and oil from the Bakken oil field in North Dakota.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;On its face it does not seem plausible that trains could transport 6 to 9 million barrels of tar sands oil per day in 2030.&amp;nbsp; Using 600-barrel tank cars and 100-car trains with a 9 day transit time to the Gulf Coast, this would require 2,000&amp;ndash;3,000 locomotives and 200,000&amp;ndash;300,000 tanker cars making constant trips, with 200&amp;ndash;300 trains coming and going from the tar sands each day.&amp;nbsp; The logistics would be mind-boggling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;It's also worth noting that, as InsideClimate News reports,&amp;nbsp;this section of the SEIS was based on analysis provided by &lt;a href="http://insideclimatenews.org/news/20130306/keystone-xl-eis-state-department-transcanada-oil-tar-sands-industry-ensys-energy-koch-brothers-exxonmobil-bp-obama"&gt;two consulting firms with ties to oil and pipeline companies&lt;/a&gt; that could benefit from the proposed project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The problem is that&amp;nbsp;the State Department draft EIS has not considered the scenario in which alternative transportation options are unable to pick up the slack, thus slowing the extraction and transportation of tar sands oil.&amp;nbsp; In that scenario, rejection of the Keystone XL permit could reduce the tar sands' overall climate impact even further.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The EPA comments on the 2011 draft SEIS estimated that Keystone XL could lead to as much as an extra 23 million tonnes of CO2-equivalent emissions per year, which is a factor of 4 higher than in&amp;nbsp;the estimated maximum in the 2013 draft EIS.&amp;nbsp; Thus it is entirely possible that the EPA will once again comment on this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Climate Impact in the State Department Scenario&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Whether it's 5.3 million tonnes of CO2-equivalent emissions per year (State Department estimate maximum) or 23 million tonnes per year (EPA estimate maximum) it's a significant amount of greenhouse gas emissions.&amp;nbsp; These emissions must be considered in the decision to approve or reject the pipeline permit.&amp;nbsp; It would be the equivalent of adding approximately&amp;nbsp;1 to&amp;nbsp;4 million passenger vehicles to the road.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The EPA also requested that the State Department consider the &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/co2-limits-economy-advanced.htm"&gt;social cost of carbon&lt;/a&gt; (SCC &amp;ndash; an estimate of the economic damage caused by carbon emissions via climate change) from these emissions, which it appears to have bypassed in the new draft SEIS by arguing that the increased emissions would be negligible compared to overall tar sands production.&amp;nbsp; However, the SCC (&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/johnson-hope-2012.html"&gt;generally between $20 and $100 per tonne of CO2 emissions&lt;/a&gt;) for&amp;nbsp;5.3 to&amp;nbsp;23 million tonnes of CO2 per year ranges from approximately $100 million to $2.3 billion per year &amp;ndash; clearly a very high cost to overlook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Keystone XL SEIS Shortcomings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The draft SEIS has certain key shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: justify;"&gt;It fails to consider a scenario in which rail and other transportation alternatives are insufficient to pick up the slack if Keystone XL and other pipeline projects are rejected, and assumes &amp;ndash; perhaps unrealistically &amp;ndash; that rail infrastructure can ultimately transport 6 to 9 million barrels of tar sands oil daily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: justify;"&gt;It treats up to 5.3 million tonnes of CO2-equivalent greenhouse gas emissions per year in 2030 &amp;ndash; equivalent to adding&amp;nbsp;1 million cars to the road &amp;ndash; as insignificant.&amp;nbsp; And this estimate is lower than the EPA's estimated maximum 23 million tonnes (4 million cars) of added annual emissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="text-align: justify;"&gt;It does not consider the social cost of those greenhouse gas emissions &amp;ndash; potentially exceeding $2.3 billion per year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The draft SEIS is now undergoing a 45-day public review period.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Comments can be submitted via email to keystonecomments@state.gov.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The central argument of the SEIS is that a rejection of the Keystone XL pipeline will slow but not stop the tar sands expansion.&amp;nbsp; Significant volumes of&amp;nbsp;tar sands oil&amp;nbsp;can be shipped by rail, and by making adjustments and upgrades to existing pipelines. However, &lt;a href="http://switchboard.nrdc.org/blogs/aswift/on_the_wrong_track_rail_is_not.html"&gt;NRDC has made a compelling case&lt;/a&gt; that the SEIS may have significantly overestimated rail transportation capabilities and economic viability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;If the Keystone XL permit were to be rejected, it would send a powerful and negative message to prospective investors in planned, future capital-intensive projects.&amp;nbsp; There are many uncertainties considered in evaluating the economics of long-term projects like these, and the message that the US is not interested in aiding the development of the tar sands would be a very powerful one.&amp;nbsp; In this sense, the Keystone XL pipeline is indeed key to tar sands development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;That said, reducing global demand for all fossil fuels is the only long-term solution to mitigating climate change. Putting a price on carbon emissions in the USA, Canada, and other countries would go a long way to addressing this problem, particularly for the costly and high-carbon oil from the tar sands, as this &lt;a href="http://globalchange.mit.edu/files/document/MITJPSPGC_Rpt183.pdf"&gt;2010 study from MIT&lt;/a&gt; demonstrates.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Secretary Kerry and President Obama must not only decide whether permitting Keystone XL is worth potentially&amp;nbsp;adding the equivalent emissions&amp;nbsp;of millions of cars on the road, the inevitable pipeline leaks/spills and associated impacts on environmental and public health, and the resulting higher gasoline prices in the USA.&amp;nbsp; They must also consider that approval of Keystone XL will set the energy course of the US more firmly in the direction of fossil fuels, thus antagonizing the groups working to preserve a safe &lt;span id="skstip27" class="skstip beginner"&gt;climate&lt;/span&gt; for future generations.&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/11/opinion/when-to-say-no-to-the-keystone-xl.html?nl=todaysheadlines&amp;amp;emc=edit_th_20130311&amp;amp;_r=1&amp;amp;"&gt;As the &lt;span&gt;New York Times Editorial Board&lt;/span&gt; put it&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;"A president who has repeatedly identified climate change as one of humanity&amp;rsquo;s most pressing dangers cannot in good conscience approve a project that &amp;mdash; even by the State Department&amp;rsquo;s most cautious calculations &amp;mdash; can only add to the problem." &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;While Keystone XL&amp;nbsp; is an important battle, we also have to remember that it's just one front in the overall war to reduce global greenhouse gas emissions.&amp;nbsp; Our ultimate goal must be to reduce global fossil fuel demand so that the tar sands and other fossil fuel projects like it fail simply because in the full context of their environmental and climate implications, they are understood to be uneconomical.&amp;nbsp; The war will be won when there is no demand for tar sands oil.&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1906</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1906</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 05:31:31 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>2013 SkS Weekly News Roundup #10 </title>
<description>&lt;div class="greenbox" style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Australia links 'angry summer' to climate change&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Climate change as history's deal-breaker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Climate change dates back to dawn of first farmers,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Climate change poses threat to Scotland's future oil revenues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Colombia's glaciers could disappear in 30 years &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Hicks nix climate fix&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Insurers unready for climate change-related disasters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Obama&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;all of the above&amp;rsquo; energy and environment nominees&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Pakistan launches first national climate change policy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Shareholders file first-ever 'Carbon Bubble' resolutions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Three&amp;nbsp;things to know about Obama&amp;rsquo;s pick for EPA chief&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;US scientists report big jump in heat-trapping CO2&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Australia links 'angry summer' to climate change&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The hottest summer on record. The hottest January on record. The hottest day on record for Australia as a whole. Bushfires in every state and territory. Daily rainfall records and major flooding. Over a period of 90 days, these were some of the 123 extreme weather records broken during Australia's "angry summer".&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/blog/2013/mar/07/australia-angry-summer-climate-change"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Australia links 'angry summer' to climate change &amp;ndash; at last&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Jessica Aldred. The Guardian, Mar 7, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Climate change as history's deal-breaker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can there be any doubt that, to steal a phrase from that era, the personal is indeed political?&amp;nbsp; On the other hand, the apocalypse, particularly an apocalypse that features Science and Nature in its starring roles, seems anything but personal or stoppable -- unless you&amp;rsquo;re a farmer and a pipeline filled with a particularly nasty version of oil runs right through your nearest aquifer.&amp;nbsp; The real issue here is how to make climate change personal in a way that doesn&amp;rsquo;t simply cause us to shut down.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tomdispatch.com/post/175656/tomgram%3A_engelhardt%2C_climate_change_as_history%27s_deal-breaker/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climate Change as History's Deal-Breaker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Eglehardt, TomDisptach, Mar 3, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Climate change dates back to dawn of first farmers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deforestation by early farmers likely kicked off an era of man-made climate change long before our present era, suggests a climate scientist taking a hard look at agriculture's early effects.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/columnist/vergano/2013/03/02/anthropocene-climate-farming/1955041/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climate change dates back to dawn of first farmers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;span style="line-height: 14px; text-transform: none; background-color: #ffffff; font-variant: normal; font-style: normal; text-indent: 0px; letter-spacing: normal; display: inline !important; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; white-space: normal; float: none; color: #222222; font-size: 12px; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;"&gt;Dan Vergano, USA Today, Mar 3, 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Climate change poses threat to Scotland's future oil revenues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scotland's fate as a rich independent nation is again being fought over with a battle raging over the risks of relying on North Sea oil. But in future, climate change will pose a far more serious challenge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/scottish-independence-blog/2013/mar/07/scotland-independence-oil-climate"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climate change poses a far greater threat to Scotland's future oil revenues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Steven Carrell, Mar 7, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Colombia's glaciers could disappear in 30 years&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Colombia&amp;rsquo;s glaciers are melting so fast that the country has lost more than half of its glacier mass over the past three decades due to rising temperatures linked to climate change, according to a report by the Colombian Institute of Hydrology, Meteorology and Environmental Studies (IDEAM).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.trust.org/alertnet/news/colombias-glaciers-could-disappear-in-30-years-report"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colombia's glaciers could disappear in 30 years&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Anastasia Moloney, Alertnet, Mar 5, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hicks nix climate fix&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;But with the announcement this week of the usual suspects of city-bred, East Coast, well-credentialed types to the cabinet-level team that Obama is assembling to fight climate change, it&amp;rsquo;s time to consider a farmer as a leader of that cause.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://opinionator.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/03/07/hicks-nix-climate-fix/?nl=opinion&amp;amp;emc=edit_ty_20130308"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hicks Nix Climate Fix&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Timothy Egan, New York Times, Mar 7, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Insurers unready for climate change-related disasters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;The insurance industry is ill-prepared to handle climate change-related disasters, regulators and industry watchers warned Thursday, saying the business hasn&amp;rsquo;t evolved enough in the face of rising sea levels and extreme weather fueled by climate change.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mcclatchydc.com/2013/03/07/185159/report-finds-insurers-unready.html#emlnl=Daily_News_Update"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report finds insurers unready for climate change-related disasters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Erika Bolstad, &amp;nbsp;McClatchy Newspapers, Mar 7, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Obama&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;all of the above&amp;rsquo; energy and environment nominees&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;President Obama&amp;rsquo;s choices for his next energy secretary and Environmental Protection Agency administrator are, like so many of his actions, unsurprising and practical.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://dotearth.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/03/04/obamas-all-of-the-above-energy-and-environment-nominees/?ref=science"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obama&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;All of the Above&amp;rsquo; Energy and Environment Nominees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Andrew Revkin, New York Times, Mar 4, 2013&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Pakistan launches first national climate change policy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disaster-prone Pakistan has launched its&lt;a href="http://undp.org.pk/images/documents/National%20Climate%20Change%20Policy%20of%20Pakistan.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt; first ever national policy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on climate change, detailing how it plans to tackle the challenges posed by global warming, mitigate its risks and adapt key sectors of the country's economy to cope with its consequences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.trust.org/alertnet/news/pakistan-launches-first-national-climate-change-policy/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pakistan launches first national climate change policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Nita Bhalla, Alertnet, Mar 1, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Shareholders file first-ever 'Carbon Bubble' resolutions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shareholder activists are concerned that fossil fuels could become unburnable because of climate laws&amp;mdash;and they want firms to divulge the financial risks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://insideclimatenews.org/news/20130307/investor-shareholders-activism-as-you-sow-carbon-bubble-climate-change-global-warming-fossil-fuels-consol-alpha?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+solveclimate%2Fblog+%28InsideClimate+News%29"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shareholders File First-Ever 'Carbon Bubble' Resolutions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Maria Gallucci, InsideClimate News, Mar 7, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Three things To know about Obama&amp;rsquo;s pick for EPA chief&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since Lisa&amp;nbsp; Jackson announced that she would resign her post as administrator of the&amp;nbsp; U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, environmental advocates have anxiously&amp;nbsp; awaited news of who would take her place. On Monday, the suspense came to an end&amp;nbsp; as President Barack Obama announced his official nomination: Gina McCarthy, the&amp;nbsp; assistant administrator for EPA&amp;rsquo;s Office of Air and Radiation and a known&amp;nbsp; champion for public health.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.care2.com/causes/3-things-to-know-about-obamas-pick-for-epa-chief.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 Things To Know About Obama&amp;rsquo;s Pick for EPA Chief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Beth Buczynski, Care2, Mar 4, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;US scientists report big jump in heat-trapping CO2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The amount of heat-trapping carbon dioxide in the air jumped dramatically in 2012, making it very unlikely that global warming can be limited to another 2 degrees as many global leaders have hoped, new federal figures show.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wunderground.com/news/carbon-dioxide-spike-20130306"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Scientists Report Big Jump in Heat-Trapping CO2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Seth Borenstein, Associated Press, Mar 5, 3013&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1905</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1905</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 9 Mar 2013 11:37:57 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>2013 SkS Weekly Digest #9</title>
<description>&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;SkS Highlights&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;SkS founder and major domo, John Cook, posted three articles this week:&amp;nbsp;(1)&amp;nbsp; &lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/recursive-fury-huffpo.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conspiracy Theorists Respond to Evidence They're Conspiracy Theorists With More Conspiracy Theories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, (2)&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Reality-Drop-using-social-media-rapidly-respond-climate-misinformation.html"&gt;Reality Drop - using social media to rapidly respond to climate misinformation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and (3)&amp;nbsp;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Why-SkS-withdrew-from-the-Bloggies.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why SkS withdrew from the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Bloggies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The&amp;nbsp;article about the &lt;em&gt;Bloggies&lt;/em&gt; award garnered the most comments which&amp;nbsp;provides Cook with a new set of behavioral data to analyze and report on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;Toon of the Week&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;img title="Conspiracy theory du jour" src="http://www.skepticalscience.com//pics/2013Toon9.jpg" alt="2013 Toon #9" width="445" height="342" /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;Quote of the Week&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;"We can bail out banks, we can bail out member states, but you cannot bail out climate," she* said. "If we just say we must extract all the fossil fuels that we can find in the world, then it's clear that it will not be possible to stay below the 2 degrees."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;"Nobody is doing enough," added Hedegaard. "Europe is not doing enough, the U.S. is not doing enough, China is not doing enough -- all of us will have to do more."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;*Connie Hedegaard, European Union Climate Commissioner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/01/connie-hedegaard-eu-climate_n_2788754.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connie Hedegaard, EU Climate Commissioner: Obama Must Act On Global Warming Rhetoric&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Lynne Peeples, The Huffington Post, Mar, 2013&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;The Week in Review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/2013-SkS-News-Bulletin-2.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 SkS News Bulletin #2: Alberta Tar Sands and Keystone XL Pipeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by John Hartz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Why-SkS-withdrew-from-the-Bloggies.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why SkS withdrew from the Bloggies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by John Cook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/denialcanada.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Living in Denial in Canada&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Andy Skuce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Reality-Drop-using-social-media-rapidly-respond-climate-misinformation.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reality Drop - using social media to rapidly respond to climate misinformation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by John Cook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/denialnorway.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Living in Denial in Norway&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;S&amp;nbsp;by Andy Skuce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/george-will-recycling-classic-climate-change-myths.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Will - Still Recycling Classic Climate Change Myths for &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;By Dana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/recursive-fury-huffpo.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conspiracy Theorists Respond to Evidence They're Conspiracy Theorists With More Conspiracy Theories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by John Cook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/carbon-fertilization-effect.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How big is the &amp;ldquo;carbon fertilization effect&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/australian-pachauri-global-warming.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did Murdoch's &lt;em&gt;The Australian&lt;/em&gt; Misrepresent IPCC Chair Pachauri on Global Warming?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Dana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;Coming Soon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;China Takes a Leading Role in Solving Climate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Change (Dana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carbon Dioxide the Dominant Control on Global Temperature and Sea Level Over the Last 40 Million Years&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Rob Painting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drost, Karoly, and Braganza Find Human Fingerprints in Global Warming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Dana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What doesn&amp;rsquo;t change with climate?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;(Ari Jokim&amp;auml;ki)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The educational opportunities in addressing misinformation in the classroom&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (John Cook)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 SkS News Roundup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (John Hartz)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;In the Works&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does Norway lack political commitment to renewables?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (gws)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Death in Jurassic Park: global warming and ocean anoxia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (John Mason)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cherrypicking to Deny Continued Ocean and Global Warming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Dana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Study, Same Result - Greenhouse Gases Dominate Global Warming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Dana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A tale told in maps and charts: Texas in the National Climate Assessment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Dana)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Residence Time and Prof Essenhigh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Glenton Jelbert)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New satellite confirms dramatic thinning of Arctic ice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (MarkR)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lomborg's Irresponsible Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (Agnostic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style="margin-bottom: 5px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offline-friendly content added to Skeptical Science emporium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (doug_bostrom)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;SkS in the News&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wiley.com/WileyCDA/WileyTitle/productCd-EHEP002419.html"&gt;A new climate change textbook by Charles Fletcher&lt;/a&gt; uses several SkS graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;John Cook's &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Reality-Drop-using-social-media-rapidly-respond-climate-misinformation.html"&gt;Reality Drop - using social media to rapidly respond to climate misinformation&lt;/a&gt; was re-posted on &lt;a href="http://climatecrocks.com/2013/03/02/reality-drop-the-game-where-you-reality-and-the-climate-win/"&gt;Climate Crocks&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Skeptical Science's contribution to the project was also discussed on &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/02/28/reality-drop/"&gt;Mashable&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://desmogblog.com/2013/03/03/drop-some-climate-reality-web-denial-myths"&gt;DeSmogBlog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Dana's &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/kansas-renewables-guardian.html"&gt;Low emissions are no justification for Kansas scaling back renewables&lt;/a&gt; was re-posted on &lt;a href="http://thinkprogress.org/climate/2013/02/25/1634591/keystone-xl-decision-will-define-barack-obamas-climate-legacy/?mobile=nc"&gt;Climate Progress&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Why-SkS-withdrew-from-the-Bloggies.html"&gt;Skeptical Science's withdrawal from the Bloggie Awards&lt;/a&gt; was &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/blog/2013/mar/01/climate-sceptics-capture-bloggies-science"&gt;discussed by Leo Hickman at The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/nuccitelli-et-al-2012.html"&gt;Nuccitelli et al. (2012)&lt;/a&gt; was referenced in an article by Andrew Glikson in &lt;a href="http://theconversation.edu.au/fact-check-has-global-warming-paused-12439"&gt;The Conversation&lt;/a&gt; which was re-posted by &lt;a href="http://newanthropocene.wordpress.com/2013/02/26/fact-check-has-global-warming-paused/?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter"&gt;New Anthropocene&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://reneweconomy.com.au/2013/time-to-stop-hiding-behind-warming-trends-31257"&gt;Renew Economy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://theconversation.edu.au/the-hottest-summer-on-record-experts-react-12559"&gt;John Cook was interviewed by The Conversation&lt;/a&gt; about the hottest summer on record in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://scienceblogs.com/denialism/2013/02/26/what-happens-when-you-study-conspiracy-theories-the-conspiracy-theorists-make-up-conspiracy-theories-about-you/"&gt;Denialism Blog&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/john-cook/conspiracy-theorists-respond_b_2676621.html"&gt;Huffington Post&lt;/a&gt; did nice posts about &lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com/recursive-fury.html"&gt;Recursive Fury&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;John Cook's &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/no-such-thing-as-climate-change-denial.html"&gt;There is no such thing as climate change denial&lt;/a&gt; was discussed by &lt;a href="http://www.acfonline.org.au/news-media/blog/no-such-thing-climate-change-denial"&gt;the Australian Conservation Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.startleddisbelief.com/2013/02/luee-episode-50-climate-change-part-1.html"&gt;Life, the Universe &amp;amp; Everything Else&lt;/a&gt; referenced the &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Bob_Carter_arg.htm"&gt;SkS database for Bob Carter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The US Bureau of Land Management used &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/graphics.php?g=47"&gt;The Escalator&lt;/a&gt; in a presentation at the annual &lt;a href="http://www.smenet.org/public/Core/Events/eventdetails.aspx?iKey=AME2013&amp;amp;TemplateType=A"&gt;National Western Mining Conference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080;"&gt;SkS Spotlight&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.pembina.org/about/about-pembina"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pembina Institute&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a Canadian non-profit think tank that advances clean energy solutions through research, education, consulting and advocacy. We promote environmental, social and economic sustainability in the public interest by developing practical solutions for communities, individuals, governments and businesses. The Pembina Institute provides policy research leadership and education on climate change, energy issues, green economics, energy efficiency and conservation, renewable energy, and environmental governance.&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1904</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1904</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 3 Mar 2013 08:16:48 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>Why SkS withdrew from the Bloggies</title>
<description>&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The &lt;a href="http://2013.bloggi.es/"&gt;Weblog Awards&lt;/a&gt;, aka the Bloggies, is an annual competition honoring blogs in various categories. Finalists are chosen by online nomination and winners are chosen by online voting. This year, Skeptical Science made the finalists of the Science and Technology category. Yesterday, I requested that SkS be withdrawn from the competition, as reported in &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/blog/2013/mar/01/climate-sceptics-capture-bloggies-science"&gt;the Guardian&lt;/a&gt;. Why? Because the Bloggies have become inextricably associated with anti-science blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In an inversion of reality, the Science and Technology category is dominated by anti-science blogs that post conspiracy theories about the scientific community, deny the &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/empirical-evidence-for-global-warming.htm"&gt;full body of evidence&lt;/a&gt; and reject the &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/global-warming-scientific-consensus-intermediate.htm"&gt;scientific consensus&lt;/a&gt;. The fact that 4 out of 5 science finalists are anti-science demonstrates that the integrity of the Bloggies Award has been compromised. I, like any pro-science blogger, am not comfortable with the notion of competing for an award that has previously been won by anti-science blogs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It's worth considering why there is such an asymmetry with the award swarmed by readers of anti-climate science blogs but ignored by legitimate science and technology blogs. Quite simply, this is all they've got. Anti-science blogs reject the &lt;a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/306/5702/1686.full"&gt;consensus of evidence in the peer-reviewed literature&lt;/a&gt;. They reject the &lt;a href="http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2010/06/04/1003187107.abstract"&gt;overwhelming consensus in the scientific community&lt;/a&gt;. They value the opinion of anonymous internet users over &lt;a href="http://tigger.uic.edu/~pdoran/012009_Doran_final.pdf"&gt;climate scientists actively publishing climate research in the peer-reviewed literature&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; They clutch at any life preserver to ward off the rising tide of evidence for dangerous man-made global warming, as demonstrated by the zeal that led to 9 anti-science blogs appearing in the finalists of various categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Can the Bloggies free themselves from the association with anti-science and attract back the interest of the science blogging community? It's a tough ask but I see only one way to achieve this. Anti-science blogs should not be allocated to a science category. An expert panel could take an active role in filtering the nominees, to ascertain that they properly qualify in the category for which they have been nominated. Perhaps instituting such a policy may attract science and technology blogs back to the Bloggies Awards in the future, although it may take time for the association with anti-science to wear off.&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1902</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1902</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 1 Mar 2013 22:44:33 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>Cherrypicking to Deny Continued Ocean and Global Warming</title>
<description>&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/australian-pachauri-global-warming.html"&gt;Cherrypicking global surface air temperatures&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most common errors associated with global warming.&amp;nbsp; In reality, a very small percentage of overall global warming goes into heating surface air temperatures, while approxiately 90% is absorbed by the world's oceans (in totality, at all depths).&amp;nbsp; Because many other factors influence surface air temperatures on short timescales, the data are noisy, and as a result it's easy to cherrypick temporary flat periods to wrongly claim that global warming has stopped (Figure 1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/graphics.php?g=47"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;img style="nofocusline: true;" src="http://www.skepticalscience.com/graphics/Escalator_2012_500.gif" alt="Escalator" width="500" height="340" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;em style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000080; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000; nofocusline: true;"&gt;Figure 1: Average of &lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://data.giss.nasa.gov/gistemp/tabledata_v3/GLB.Ts+dSST.txt"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span id="skstip6" class="skstip advanced disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;NASA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt; &lt;span id="skstip7" class="skstip advanced disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;GISS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/cmb-faq/anomalies.php"&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;span id="skstip8" class="skstip advanced disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;NOAA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt; &lt;span id="skstip9" class="skstip advanced disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;NCDC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.metoffice.gov.uk/hadobs/hadcrut4/data/current/download.html"&gt;HadCRUT4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt; monthly &lt;span id="skstip10" class="skstip advanced disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;global surface temperature&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="nofocusline: true;"&gt; anomalies from January 1970 through November 2012 (green) with linear &lt;span id="skstip11" class="skstip advanced disabled" style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;trend&lt;/span&gt;s applied to the timeframes Jan '70 - Oct '77, Apr '77 - Dec '86, Sep '87 - Nov '96, Jun '97 - Dec '02, and Nov '02 - Nov '12.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;However, climate contrarians are now more frequently shifting their cherrypicks to the relatively shallow layer of the oceans (the upper 700 meters).&amp;nbsp; The average depth of the world's ocean is nearly 4,000 meters, but the deeper the ocean layer, the more difficult it is to measure its temperature and heat accumulation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Fortunately most ocean heat accumulation occurs close to the surface, but accounting for less of the deep ocean layers also means missing more global warming.&amp;nbsp; The best ocean heat measurements are for the 0&amp;ndash;700 meter layer, which&amp;nbsp;accounts for over 60% of overall global warming.&amp;nbsp; However, only considering ocean heat accumulation to 700 meters also means neglecting 30&amp;ndash;40% of overall global warming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Similar to surface air temperatures, the warming of the 0&amp;ndash;700 meter oceans has slowed in recent years (since about 2003), which has made them a ripe candidate for cherrypicking.&amp;nbsp; This was one of the key findings of &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/nuccitelli-et-al-2012.html"&gt;Nuccitelli et al. (2012)&lt;/a&gt;, in which we noted that while heat accumulation in the 0&amp;ndash;700 meter oceans has slowed in recent years, at the same time it has accelerated in the 700&amp;ndash;2,000 meter oceans.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Overall, there is no sign that the warming of the 0&amp;ndash;2,000 meter oceans has slowed; in fact, they have accumulated more heat in the past 15 years than during the previous 15 years (Figure 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://skepticalscience.com/pics/2_heat_content700m2000myr.png"&gt;&lt;img style="nofocusline: true;" src="http://skepticalscience.com/pics/2_heat_content700m2000myr.png" alt="OHC" width="500" height="336" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;em style="nofocusline: true;"&gt;Figure 2: Comparison of&amp;nbsp;Ocean Heat Content 0&amp;ndash;700 meter layer vs. 0&amp;ndash;2,000 meters layer, &lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://www.nodc.noaa.gov/OC5/3M_HEAT_CONTENT/"&gt;from the National Oceanographic Data Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;It should be no surprise that climate contrarians constantly ignore the accelerated warming of the 700&amp;ndash;2,000 meter oceans, pretending that they simply don't exist.&amp;nbsp; In one recent example, &lt;a href="http://wattsupwiththat.com/2013/02/25/fact-check-for-andrew-glickson-ocean-heat-has-paused-too/"&gt;a denialist blog&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;disputed the results of Nuccitelli et al. (2012) by showing&amp;nbsp;Figure 3 below (also discussed in &lt;a href="http://tamino.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/fact-checking-the-cherry-pickers-anthony-watts-edition/"&gt;this post by Tamino&lt;/a&gt; at the Open Mind blog).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/Watts_OHC_denial.png"&gt;&lt;img src="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/Watts_OHC_denial.png" alt="Watts OHC denial cherries" width="500" height="405" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 3: 0&amp;ndash;700 meter ocean heat accumulation &lt;a href="http://oceans.pmel.noaa.gov/data-page.html"&gt;from&amp;nbsp;NOAA PMEL&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;using the methodology described in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="ftp://ftp.soest.hawaii.edu/coastal/Climate%20Articles/Ocean%20warming%202010.pdf"&gt;Lyman et al.&amp;nbsp;(2010)&lt;/a&gt;, with an arbitrary yellow line drawn in an effort to indicate slowed ocean warming.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;The ocean heat content &lt;a href="http://www.nodc.noaa.gov/OC5/3M_HEAT_CONTENT/"&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; used in Nuccitelli et al. (2012) and Figure 2 above are from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) National Oceanographic Data Center (NODC) using the methodology described by &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/levitus-2012-global-warming-heating-oceans.html"&gt;Levitus et al. (2012)&lt;/a&gt;, whereas the &lt;a href="http://oceans.pmel.noaa.gov/data-page.html"&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; in Figure 3 are from the&amp;nbsp;NOAA Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory (PMEL)&amp;nbsp;using the methodology described in &lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="ftp://ftp.soest.hawaii.edu/coastal/Climate%20Articles/Ocean%20warming%202010.pdf"&gt;Lyman et al.&amp;nbsp;(2010)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;The Levitus methodology&amp;nbsp;fills data gaps with the averaged value of the available data, which&amp;nbsp;has the tendency to underestimate any anomalies.&amp;nbsp; The Lyman&amp;nbsp;methodology infills&amp;nbsp;the data gaps with anomalies from nearby grids.&amp;nbsp; The end result is that Levitus is likely to underestimate any warming &lt;span id="skstip64" class="skstip advanced disabled" style="nofocusline: true;" onmouseover="sksTip(this.id,'Trend');" onmouseout="sksTipCancel(this.id,'Trend');"&gt;trend&lt;/span&gt;, as discussed in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a style="nofocusline: true;" href="http://oceans.pmel.noaa.gov/Pdf/heat_trend.pdf"&gt;Lyman (2008)&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; As a result, the data plotted on the denialist blog actually shows &lt;span style="color: #ff0000;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; 0&amp;ndash;700 meter ocean warming than the data plotted in Nuccitelli et al. (2012).&amp;nbsp; This is illustrated in Figure 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/OHC_Denial.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="http://skepticalscience.com//pics/OHC_Denial.gif" alt="OHC cherries" width="500" height="340" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 4: 0&amp;ndash;700 meter ocean heat content data from &lt;a href="http://www.nodc.noaa.gov/OC5/3M_HEAT_CONTENT/"&gt;NOAA NODC&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Levitus) and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://oceans.pmel.noaa.gov/data-page.html"&gt;NOAA PMEL&lt;/a&gt; (Lyman)&amp;nbsp;using the same&amp;nbsp;baseline.&amp;nbsp; The yellow arbitrary denialist line is shown, followed by the linear trends for 2003&amp;ndash;2012 and 1993&amp;ndash;2012 in red.&amp;nbsp; Standard error bars are also shown.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;Despite showing a larger ocean warming trend than Levitus, climate contrarians likely prefer the Lyman data because it does not include the ocean layers below 700 meters.&amp;nbsp; However, even if we cherrypick this shallow ocean data and cherrypick 2003 as the starting point, the 0&amp;ndash;700 meter ocean heat accumulation for 2003&amp;ndash;2012 in the Lyman PMEL data is equivalent to 1.2 Hiroshima atomic bomb detonations per second over the past decade.&amp;nbsp; For 1993&amp;ndash;2012, this rate increases to the equivalent of 3.7 detonations per second, and when including global heat accumulation in Nuccitelli et al. (2012) including the&amp;nbsp;0&amp;ndash;2,000 meter oceans, the Earth has accumulated the equivalent of 4 Hiroshima atomic bomb detonations per second over the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify; nofocusline: true;"&gt;When we consider all the available data, it becomes quite clear that ocean and global warming continue unabated at a rapid rate.&amp;nbsp; Cherrypicking cannot change that reality.&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1901</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1901</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 6 Mar 2013 06:42:38 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>The educational opportunities in addressing misinformation in the classroom</title>
<description>&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;An interesting discussion arose in &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Why_Choose_One_Textbook_for_Introductory_Climate_Change_Science_Courses.html"&gt;Tom Farmer&amp;rsquo;s latest&amp;nbsp;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about our textbook &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/9400757565/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=9400757565&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=skeptscien-20"&gt;Climate Change Science: A Modern Synthesis&lt;/a&gt;. One of the commenters &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Why_Choose_One_Textbook_for_Introductory_Climate_Change_Science_Courses.html#91139"&gt;questioned whether certain sections should have been included in the textbook&lt;/a&gt;. The two chapters he referred to were &lt;a href="http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-007-5757-8_23"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chapter 23: Understanding &lt;span id="skstip12" class="skstip beginner"&gt;Climate Change&lt;/span&gt; Denial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-007-5757-8_24"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chapter 24: Rebuttals to &lt;span id="skstip14" class="skstip beginner"&gt;Climate&lt;/span&gt; Myths&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I would argue that not only are such chapters appropriate, they are essential to a comprehensive climate education. In fact, I would go further. Addressing misinformation in the classroom is not just a necessary evil &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s actually an opportunity that educators should be embracing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Firstly, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand that education isn&amp;rsquo;t just a matter of downloading new information into student&amp;rsquo;s heads. An important aspect is correcting misperceptions. &lt;a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5977/463.short"&gt;Jonathan Osborne sums it up nicely&lt;/a&gt; when he says &lt;em&gt;"Comprehending why ideas are wrong matters as much as understanding why some ideas may be right." &lt;/em&gt;Another famous educator provides &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z4jeREy7Pbc"&gt;an even pithier quote on the importance of correcting misperceptions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;What is the best way for teachers to dispel misconceptions? Is it enough to simply teach students the facts?&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;It turns out no. A &lt;a href="http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00986280902959986"&gt;study conducted with 1st year psychology students&lt;/a&gt; found that lectures explicitly refuting misconceptions were twice as effective as the standard lecture format in reducing misconceptions. Teachers need to directly challenge false ideas to provoke students into examining their preconceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.skepticalscience.com//pics/Kowalski_Refutations.png" alt="" width="500" height="295" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Similarly, a &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1365-2729.2007.00248.x/full"&gt;study of physics students&lt;/a&gt; found that directly debunking physics misconceptions was considerably more effective than exposition style lectures that merely explained the correct physics. What's interesting about this particular research was students were more confident about their physics knowledge after exposition lectures but scored worse. After a refutational lecture, they were less confident about their knowledge but scored better. This shows that misconceptions have two negative influences. They interfere with correct information and they also instill a false sense of knowing. Debunking teaches science but it also teaches a little humility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.skepticalscience.com//pics/Muller_2007_misconceptions.png" alt="" width="500" height="399" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;So addressing misinformation head-on is the most effective way of reducing students&amp;rsquo; misperceptions. But there is also an exciting educational opportunity in debunking myths. When you debunk a myth, you &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Debunking-Handbook-Part-5-Filling-gap-with-alternative-explanation.html"&gt;create a gap in people&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the world&lt;/a&gt;. If you don't fill that gap, the myth will come back to fill the hole. You fill the gap by creating an alternative explanation. The structure of an effective debunking is to create a gap, then fill the gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.skepticalscience.com/pics/dbh_gap2.gif" alt="" width="500" height="206" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;There is a highly recommended book on communication by the Heath brothers, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1400064287/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1400064287&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=skeptscien-20"&gt;Made to Stick&lt;/a&gt;. The authors identify one of the traits of &amp;ldquo;sticky&amp;rdquo; ideas that are compelling and memorable. A compelling message arouses people's curiosity then satisfies their curiosity. The way to do this is by creating gaps in people's knowledge then filling those gaps. Sound familiar? The very nature of debunking myths lends itself to creating engaging, "sticky" material that raises questions in people's minds then answers the questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/9400757565/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=9400757565&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=skeptscien-20"&gt;&lt;img style="float: right; margin-left: 20px;" src="http://www.skepticalscience.com/pics/modern_synthesis_cover_180.jpg" alt="" width="120" height="199" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This is why college professors such as &lt;a href="http://departments.weber.edu/geography/faculty/DBedford/DBedford.htm"&gt;Daniel Bedford&lt;/a&gt; from Weber State University, Utah, are &lt;a href="http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00221341.2010.498121"&gt;addressing misinformation in their classrooms as a way of teaching critical thought and the nature of science&lt;/a&gt;. Given that more lecturers and educators are recognising the importance of addressing misinformation, Tom and I decided to include the most detailed treatment of climate misinformation and the phenomenon of climate change denial in a climate textbook (to our knowledge). &lt;a href="http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-007-5757-8_23"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chapter 23: Understanding &lt;span id="skstip12" class="skstip beginner"&gt;Climate Change&lt;/span&gt; Denial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; goes into detail on the characteristics of denial, what is driving climate denial (essential to understanding the controversy) and how to respond to misinformation. &lt;a href="http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-007-5757-8_24"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chapter 24: Rebuttals to &lt;span id="skstip14" class="skstip beginner"&gt;Climate&lt;/span&gt; Myths&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; features concise rebuttals to the most popular climate myths, with each rebuttal adhering to the structure recommended in the &lt;a href="http://sks.to/debunk"&gt;Debunking Handbook&lt;/a&gt;. If any lecturers, professors or educators are interested in receiving a sample copy of the chapter &lt;a href="http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-007-5757-8_23"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Understanding &lt;span id="skstip12" class="skstip beginner"&gt;Climate Change&lt;/span&gt; Denial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, feel free to &lt;a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/contact.php"&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1899</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1899</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 8 Mar 2013 09:34:44 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>Conspiracy Theorists Respond to Evidence They're Conspiracy Theorists With More Conspiracy Theories </title>
<description>&lt;p class="greenbox" style="text-align: justify;"&gt;This is a partial re-post from The Huffington Post.&amp;nbsp; For the full article, click the link below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In 2012, cognitive scientist Stephan Lewandowsky and his colleagues surveyed more than 1,000 climate blog readers and observed a link between science denial and conspiracy theorizing. People who denied scientific propositions such as the link between AIDS and HIV or climate change and human activity were more likely to subscribe to conspiracy theories like Princess Diana was murdered or AIDS was created by the government. How did climate deniers respond to &lt;a href="http://websites.psychology.uwa.edu.au/labs/cogscience/documents/LskyetalPsychScienceinPressClimateConspiracy.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;evidence associating science denial with conspiracy theorizing&lt;/a&gt;? With more conspiracy theories, of course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The conspiracy theories directed toward the "moon landing paper" began small-scale, but grew in scope and intricacy. Now to social scientists, such a public response can mean only one thing. Data! I collaborated with Lewandowsky in documenting the various conspiracy theories and tracking their evolution over time. The analysis has now been published in the paper "&lt;a href="http://www.frontiersin.org/Personality_Science_and_Individual_Differences/10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00073/abstract" target="_hplink"&gt;Recursive fury: Conspiracist ideation in the blogosphere in response to research on conspiracist ideation&lt;/a&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Conspiracy theorists exhibit a number of tell-tale characteristics. Almost ubiquitous is the accusation of nefarious intent. After all, people never conspire with benevolent intent (unless planning a surprise party). One theory promoted by climate deniers focused on the experiment design used for the "moon landing paper." The scientists emailed survey invitations to a range of climate blogs -- some endorsing the scientific consensus that humans are causing global warming and others denying the consensus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Climate deniers accused the scientists of lying about contacting denial blogs. A flood of bloggers came forward to say they hadn't received the invitation. Amusingly, five of those bloggers were the five who had actually been contacted. Irony overload was reached when one of those contacted went so far as to provide the email address of the lead author's university, encouraging readers to send allegations of misconduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Another trait of conspiracy theorists is the mentality that "something must be wrong." If a theory is shown to be demonstrably false, the conspiracy theorist can smoothly shift to another theory while maintaining an unshaken belief that "the official account must be wrong." After the names of the five contacted bloggers were released, conspiracy theorists transitioned to a spin-off theory: "obviously they never intended for the skeptic blogs to respond." New theory, same accusation of nefarious intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/john-cook/conspiracy-theorists-respond_b_2676621.html?utm_source=Alert-blogger&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Email%2BNotifications"&gt;Click here for the rest of the story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1898</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1898</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 09:13:22 EST</pubDate>
</item>  <item> 
<title>2013 SkS News Bulletin #2: Alberta Tar Sands and Keystone XL Pipeline</title>
<description>&lt;div class="greenbox" style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Draft assessment of Tar Sands pipeline &amp;ldquo;devastatingly cynical&amp;rdquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m with the Tree Huggers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone XL won't boost oilsands growth, U.S. State Dept. says&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="entry-title" style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone XL pipeline would have little impact on climate change, State Department analysis says&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;The key to big oil's sky-high pricep play: Keystone Export XL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Redford will be Washington-bound again&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;State Dept: Build the Keystone pipeline or not, the oil sands crude will flow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;State Dept's Keystone XL analysis upsets environmentalists&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;State Dept Keystone XL Pipeline Analysis Disspirits Climate Change Opponents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;U.S. Senator: Link Keystone pipeline to efficiency boost&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Draft assessment of Tar Sands pipeline &amp;ldquo;devastatingly cynical&amp;rdquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The U.S. State Department late Friday released a draft environmental impact assessment of a contentious pipeline project that simultaneously acknowledged the dangers posed by climate change while also noting the project would &amp;ldquo;not likely result in significant adverse environmental effects&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scientists and advocates have reacted with significant alarm, warning that the new report, officially a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://keystonepipeline-xl.state.gov/draftseis/index.htm"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(SEIS)&lt;/strong&gt;, is merely recycling deeply flawed conclusions offered in previous such assessments. Since the project was first proposed by a Canadian company, TransCanada, in 2008, it has been beset by local and national opposition in both countries, including drawing some 40,000 protesters to Washington last month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ipsnews.net/2013/03/draft-assessment-of-tar-sands-pipeline-devastatingly-cynical/#sthash.6JCFHAlo.dpuf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draft assessment of Tar Sands pipeline &amp;ldquo;devastatingly cynical&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Carey L. Biron, Inter Press Serive (IPS), Mar 1, 2013&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m with the Tree Huggers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m with the tree huggers. The pipeline isn&amp;rsquo;t the worst threat to the climate, but it&amp;rsquo;s a threat. Keystone isn&amp;rsquo;t the best fight to have over fossil fuels, but it&amp;rsquo;s the fight we&amp;rsquo;re having. Now is the time to choose sides. It&amp;rsquo;s always easy to quibble with the politics of radical protest: Did ACT UP need to be so obnoxious? Didn&amp;rsquo;t the tax evasion optics of the Boston Tea Party muddle the anti-imperial message? But if we&amp;rsquo;re in a war to stop global warming &amp;mdash; a war TIME declared on a&amp;nbsp;green-bordered cover&amp;nbsp;five years ago &amp;mdash; then we need to fight it on the beaches, the landing zones and the carbon-spewing tar sands of Alberta. If we&amp;rsquo;re serious about reducing atmospheric carbon below 350 parts per million, we need to start leaving some carbon in the ground.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://swampland.time.com/2013/02/28/im-with-the-tree-huggers/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m with the Tree Huggers &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;by Michael Grunwald, Time, Feb 28, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone XL won't boost oilsands growth, U.S. State Dept. says&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Building the northern leg of TransCanada's controversial Keystone XL pipeline won't have a major impact on Alberta's oilsands development, the U.S. State Department says &amp;mdash; a finding that might make it easier for the White House to approve the controversial project.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A State Department official said the pipeline "remains unlikely to significantly impact the rate of development of the oilsands or the demand for heavy crude oil in the United States."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kerri-Ann Jones, an assistant secretary with the department, said the pipeline doesn't pose any greater risks to the environment than any other modes of transportation.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cbc.ca/news/business/story/2013/03/01/keystone-review.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keystone XL won't boost oilsands growth, U.S. State Dept. says&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, CBC, Mar 1, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span class="entry-title" style="color: #003300;"&gt;Keystone XL pipeline would have little impact on climate change, State Department analysis says&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The State Department released a draft environmental impact assessment of the controversial Keystone XL pipelineFriday, suggesting the project would have little impact on climate change.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Canada&amp;rsquo;s oil sands will be developed even if President Obama denies a permit to the pipeline connecting the region to Gulf Coast refineries, the analysis said. Such a move would also not alter U.S. oil consumption, the report added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/national/health-science/keystone-xl-pipeline-will-not-have-huge-impact-on-climate-draft-analysis-says/2013/03/01/715491b0-82a5-11e2-b99e-6baf4ebe42df_story.html?hpid=z2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keystone XL pipeline would have little impact on climate change, State Department analysis says/strong&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Juliet Eilperin and Steven Mufson, Washington Post, Mar 1, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;The Key to Big Oil's Sky-high Price Play: Keystone Export XL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Keystone XL Export Pipeline is the next move in a &lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/11/16/us-transcanada-idUSTRE7AF16J20111116" target="_hplink"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;complicated&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; chess game by the oil and gas industry to assure sky-high future prices for its products -- and unaffordable fuel for the rest of us. (In their minds the devastating environmental legacy is collateral damage -- but the economic hit is a key ingredient in their model. They want us to pay too much.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/carl-pope/oil-keystone-export-xl_b_2791064.html?utm_hp_ref=green"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Key to Big Oil's Sky-high Price Play: Keystone Export XL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Carl Pope, The Huffington Post, Mar 1, 2013&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;Redford will be Washington-bound again&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fresh off a visit to Washington, Alberta Premier Alison Redford is pledging a swift return to the American capital to woo &amp;ldquo;decision makers&amp;rdquo; to approve the Keystone XL pipeline.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ms. Redford spent the weekend at a gathering of American state governors, meeting with 22 of them. Along with Environment Minister Diana McQueen, Ms. Redford said she spent the meetings reiterating the pipeline&amp;rsquo;s economic benefits while laying out the province&amp;rsquo;s environmental track record. The Alberta Premier called it a &amp;ldquo;very good weekend,&amp;rdquo; saying she found a willing audience among her counterparts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/news/politics/redford-will-be-washington-bound-again-to-hasten-keystones-approval/article9041289/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redford will be Washington-bound again to hasten Keystone&amp;rsquo;s approval&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Josh Windgrove, The Globe and Mail, Feb 25, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;State Dept: Build the Keystone pipeline or not, the oil sands crude will flow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The State Department issued its long-awaited supplementary environmental impact assessment&amp;nbsp; (SEIS) this afternoon on the Keystone XL pipeline, which would ship up to&amp;nbsp; 830,000 barrels a day of Canadian oil&amp;nbsp; sands crude to the U.S. The full report is some 2,000 pages long&amp;mdash;and was&amp;nbsp; released at the very end of the week, thanks very much, State Department&amp;mdash;but you&amp;nbsp; can boil it down to one sentence:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://science.time.com/2013/03/01/state-dept-build-the-keystone-pipeline-or-not-the-oil-sands-crude-will-flow/#ixzz2MLUcJIPc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State Dept: Build the Keystone Pipeline or Not, the Oil Sands Crude Will Flow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Brian Walsh, Time, Mar 1, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;State Dept's Keystone XL analysis upsets environmentalists&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The State Department released their Draft Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement (SEIS) for TransCanada's Keystone XL pipeline proposal on Friday, concluding in large part that the proposal is environmentally acceptable.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/01/state-department-keystone-xl_n_2792295.html?ir=green&amp;amp;utm_campaign=030113&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=Alert-green&amp;amp;utm_content=Title"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State Department's Keystone XL Analysis Upsets Environmentalists&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, The Huffington Post, Mar 1, 2013&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;State Dept Keystone XL pipeline analysis disspirits climate change opponents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Environmentalists are fuming over the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/01/state-department-keystone-xl_n_2792295.html?utm_hp_ref=green" target="_hplink"&gt;conclusion from the State Department&lt;/a&gt; that the Keystone XL pipeline -- a fiercely-debated proposal to transport heavy crude from Alberta's oil sands deposits 1,700 miles to the U.S. Gulf Coast -- would be "environmentally sound."&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/01/state-department-keystone-xl-_n_2793160.html?utm_hp_ref=green"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State Department Keystone XL Pipeline Analysis Disspirits Climate Change Opponents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Lynne Peeples, The Huffington Post, Mar 1, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;U.S. Senator: Link Keystone pipeline to efficiency boost&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sen. Mark Warner (D-Va.) wants President Obama to approve the Keystone XL&amp;nbsp; pipeline, but hopes the project&amp;rsquo;s construction can somehow be tethered to more&amp;nbsp; aggressive energy efficiency policies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #003300;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I still think it would be better&amp;nbsp; if it could be dealt with in a compromise fashion,&amp;rdquo; Warner told The Hill in the&amp;nbsp; Capitol on Tuesday, later noting, &amp;ldquo;How we get that linkage is what I am working&amp;nbsp; on.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://thehill.com/blogs/e2-wire/e2-wire/284983-centrist-dem-link-keystone-pipeline-to-efficiency-boost"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centrist Dem: Link Keystone pipeline to efficiency boost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Geman, The Hill, Feb 26, 2013&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description> 
<link>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1897</link>
<guid>http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1897</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 2 Mar 2013 07:19:57 EST</pubDate>
</item> </channel> </rss>