<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 08:57:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Bitter Cold Grips Europe: &#8216;March Could Be Coldest In 100 Years&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/bitter-cold-grips-europe-march-coldest-100-years/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/bitter-cold-grips-europe-march-coldest-100-years/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 08:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Observatory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11342</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ “This March could be the coldest of the last 100 years,” says meteorologist Dominik Jung Europe’s bitter cold winter refuses to let up! For some areas we are now hearing that it is being called the “100-year winter“! Temperature forecast anomaly for the next 7 days. Source:http://wxmaps.org/html. For example, Berlin’s online daily Tagesspiegel writes today: Berlin [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong> “This March could be the coldest of the last 100 years,” <a href="http://www.bild.de/news/inland/wetter/arsch-kalter-tritt-29612296.bild.html">says meteorologist Dominik Jung</a></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Eiskalte Luftmassen aus Osten: Russen-Stiefel lässt Europa bibbern" src="http://bilder.bild.de/fotos-skaliert/wetter-stiefel-31470919-qf-29615142/2,w=650,c=0,view=.bild.jpeg" width="455" height="256" /></p>
<p>Europe’s bitter cold winter refuses to let up!</p>
<p>For some areas we are now hearing that it is being called the “<em>100-year winter</em>“!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://notrickszone.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Europe-end-of-March-2013.png"><img alt="Europe end of March 2013" src="http://notrickszone.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Europe-end-of-March-2013.png" width="343" height="285" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Temperature forecast anomaly for the next 7 days. Source:<a href="http://wxmaps.org/pix/temp4.html">http://wxmaps.org/html</a>.</em></p>
<p>For example, Berlin’s online daily <a href="http://www.tagesspiegel.de/berlin/wetter-kaelte-und-schnee-ende-maerz-berlin-friert-im-jahrhundertwinter/7967414.html">Tagesspiegel writes today</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Berlin freezes in 100-year winter.<br />
Lots of snow and bitter cold until the end of March – Berlin hasn’t seen this in more than 100 years.”</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Forget the <a href="http://notrickszone.com/2013/03/19/prof-mojib-latif-has-easter-egg-in-his-face-tells-us-a-1960s-climate-fib/">tall tales spread by Mojib Latif</a>. We haven’t forgotten what real winters are. We just haven’t seen anything like this since measurements began in 1895!</p>
<p>The Tagsspeigel writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>‘There has never been anything like this in Berlin in the last third of March since snow measurements began in 1895,’ says weather expert Friedemann Schenk of the Meteorological Institute for the <em>Freien Universität </em>(FU).”</p></blockquote>
<p>The English-language <a href="http://www.thelocal.de/national/20130321-48667.html">The Local here</a> reports that Germans should not expect spring to arrive anytime soon, as the German Weather Service (DWD) warns that “<em>the record-breaking wintry weather will continue until Easter</em>“.</p>
<p>This weekend will be especially cold. <a href="http://www.t-online.de/wetter/id_62682964/-noch-kaelter-geht-nicht-.html">T-online news site writes</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>In the east, temperature readings will drop dramatically – many readings will be -10°C, as low as -13°C in some spots. ‘Some cold records for end of March will fall,” prophesies Ruhnau.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Germany’s <a href="http://www.rbb-online.de/abendschau/archiv/archiv.media.!etc!medialib!rbb!rbb!abendschau!abendschau_20130321_wetter.html">RBB</a> forecasts temperatures down to -15°C! The extreme cold overall will make this March in Central Europe the coldest and snowiest in over 40 years – at least.</p>
<p><a href="http://notrickszone.com/2013/03/22/berlin-freezes-in-100-year-winter-record-snow-blankets-germany-bitter-cold-grips-europe/">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/bitter-cold-grips-europe-march-coldest-100-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Sunday Telegraph Calls For Repeal Of Climate Change Act</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/man-made-energy-crisis-sunday-telegraph-calls-repeal-climate-change-act/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/man-made-energy-crisis-sunday-telegraph-calls-repeal-climate-change-act/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 08:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11338</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is time for the Coalition to tear up its energy policy before the lights go out. The first priority must be to repeal the Climate Change Act of 2008. With the worst snow conditions in the country since 1981, it’s worrying, to say the least, that gas supplies are running low. A month ago, The [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>It is time for the Coalition to tear up its energy policy before the lights go out. The first priority must be to repeal the Climate Change Act of 2008.</strong></p>
<p>With the worst snow conditions in the country since 1981, it’s worrying, to say the least, that gas supplies are running low. A month ago, The Sunday Telegraph warned in this column of the problems of an energy policy that puts expensive, inefficient green power before coal-fired and nuclear power. There have been a few signs that the Coalition is at last turning its attentions to the issue but, still, not nearly enough has been done. Now we are reaping the consequences. Because of a misguided faith in green energy, we have left ourselves far too dependent on foreign gas supplies, largely provided by Russian and Middle Eastern producers. Only 45 per cent of our gas consumption comes from domestic sources. All it takes is a spell of bad weather, and the closure of a gas pipeline from Belgium, to leave us dangerously exposed, and to send gas prices soaring. Talk of rationing may be exaggerated, but our energy policy is failing to deal with Britain’s fundamental incapacity to produce our own power.</p>
<p>Ed Davey, the Energy Secretary, may have granted planning permission this week to a new nuclear power station, Hinkley Point in Somerset. But one nuclear power station, with two new reactors, isn’t nearly enough. Moreover, it will take a decade to build and, even then, will only provide seven per cent of the country’s energy needs.</p>
<p>It is time for the Coalition to tear up its energy policy before the lights really do go out. The first priority must be to repeal the Climate Change Act of 2008, with its brutal, punishing targets: reducing carbon emissions by 80 per cent by 2050, and 26 per cent by 2020. These targets have already had a disastrous effect, forcing the closure of coal-fired power stations, and increasing tax-funded subsidies on wind power. Next month, electricity bills will soar even higher, thanks to a new tax on carbon dioxide produced by coal-fired and gas-fired power stations.</p>
<p>There are good intentions behind a green energy policy, and no one would wilfully want to damage the environment. But green technology – in its current incarnation, anyway – is just too inefficient and expensive to meet our energy needs. In some of the worst weather for more than 30 years, green power still only provides a tiny fraction of our energy needs. Solar power is of limited use in our cold, dark, northern climate. And wind power isn’t much better – cold weather doesn’t necessarily mean windy weather.</p>
<p>At last, the Coalition – or the Conservative part of it, anyway – is beginning to recognise these painfully obvious truths. In this week’s Budget, the Chancellor backed the policy of domestic fracking – the extraction of shale gas – with the promise of tax breaks for companies involved in the industry. He will know that American gas prices have plummeted, thanks to the US embracing the shale gas revolution. Britain must do the same. George Osborne also announced in the Budget that ceramics businesses would be exempt from the Climate Change Levy on energy costs. By making that exemption, he is acknowledging that green taxes are a significant drag on industry. He should make the exemption universal.</p>
<p>Our energy problems have been deepened by the greener-than-green Liberal Democrats, with their seeming stranglehold on the Cabinet post of Energy Secretary. When Chris Huhne took on the job in 2010, he swore Britain would become more independent of energy imports. Yet the country remains just as dependent, and Huhne’s Liberal Democrat colleague, Ed Davey, is still wedded to green power. Last year, he publicly slapped down his junior Tory energy minister, John Hayes, for calling for an end to more wind farms.</p>
<p>There is some good news, however. As we report today, government sources have said that wind power subsidies are to be cut again. This is a move in the right direction and we very much welcome it. It is to be hoped that there will be more such announcements, and concrete actions, from a government that has neglected a fundamental duty – to keep the lights on, energy affordable and our houses warm.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/comment/telegraph-view/9949595/Too-much-green-energy-is-bad-for-Britain.html">The Sunday Telegraph, 24 March 2013</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/man-made-energy-crisis-sunday-telegraph-calls-repeal-climate-change-act/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Britain&#8217;s Coldest Spring Since 1963 Claims 5,000 Lives</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/britains-coldest-spring-1963-claims-5000-lives/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/britains-coldest-spring-1963-claims-5000-lives/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 08:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11335</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Freezing Britain&#8217;s unusually harsh winter could have cost thousands of pensioners their lives. This month is on track to be the coldest March for 50 years – and as the bitter Arctic conditions caused blackouts and traffic chaos yesterday, experts warned of an &#8216;horrendous&#8217; death toll among the elderly. About 2,000 extra deaths were registered in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><span data-mce-mark="1">Freezing Britain&#8217;s unusually harsh winter could have cost thousands of pensioners their lives. </span>This month is on track to be the coldest March for 50 years – and as the bitter Arctic conditions caused blackouts and traffic chaos yesterday, experts warned of an &#8216;horrendous&#8217; death toll among the elderly.</strong></p>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">About 2,000 extra deaths were registered in just the first two weeks of March compared with the average for the same period over the past five years. </span></p>
<div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Whiteout: Blizzards caused huge snow drifts leaving these cars nearly completely covered in Hadfield, Derbyshire" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/pix/2013/03/23/article-2297946-18E02043000005DC-748_634x420.jpg" width="444" height="294" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;">Whiteout: Blizzards caused huge snow drifts leaving these cars nearly completely covered in Hadfield, Derbyshire</span></p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Blizzards: The Peak District was one of the worst affected areas as blizzards swept the UK overnight " src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/pix/2013/03/23/article-2297946-18E02015000005DC-85_634x417.jpg" width="444" height="292" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;">Blizzards: The Peak District was one of the worst affected areas as blizzards swept the UK overnight</span></p>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">And for February, 3,057 extra deaths were registered in England and Wales compared with the five-year average for the month.</span></p>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">Campaigners at Age UK, which says 26,000 people die needlessly in winter every year, said the current weather could prove deadly for thousands more.</span></p>
<p>Director general Michelle Mitchell said: &#8216;Colder, harsher winters tend to lead to an increase in life-threatening conditions such as heart attacks and strokes which in turn leads to a high rate of excess winter deaths.</p>
<p>&#8216;For every one degree drop in average temperature, there are around 8,000 extra deaths.&#8217;</p>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">The Office for National Statistics said the extra death rate &#8216;could be to do with the prolonged period of cold weather we&#8217;ve been experiencing.&#8217; But it cautioned that it was too early to make an absolute link. The March figures are still provisional.</span></p>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">Malcolm Booth, chief executive of the National Federation of Occupational Pensioners, said that last month almost 700 of his members had died, compared with 250 last year.</span></p>
<p><span>&#8216;If our membership is a representative sample that was replicated across the general population, then we could be looking at a horrendous number when all the figures are in,&#8217; he said.</span></p>
<div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Snow the Welsh town of Llangollen which was cut off by road except for four wheel drive vehicles" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/pix/2013/03/24/article-2298246-18E22279000005DC-719_634x900.jpg" width="444" height="630" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;">Snow the Welsh town of Llangollen which was cut off by road except for four wheel drive vehicles</span></p>
</div>
<p><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2298246/UKs-coldest-spring-1963-claims-5-000-lives-Pensioners-worst-affected--experts-say-final-toll-horrendous.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/britains-coldest-spring-1963-claims-5000-lives/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What’s Strange About This Weather? Nothing At All</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/whats-strange-weather/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/whats-strange-weather/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 07:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11332</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[How can we stop weather hyperbole? I am so staggeringly bored of waking up each morning to headlines which insist we’re all going to be killed – on the roads, or through freezing to death, or in a flood. There have been four weather hyperboles already so far this year; warmest January, or warmest day [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How can we stop weather hyperbole? I am so staggeringly bored of waking up each morning to headlines which insist we’re all going to be killed – on the roads, or through freezing to death, or in a flood. There have been four weather hyperboles already so far this year; warmest January, or warmest day in January ever, wettest February, coldest March. There are so many criteria for awarding a hyperbole sticker that almost every day of the year could qualify. So, snow in March? An unheard of experience? Nope, it happens every other year, more or less – and that’s in the south of the country. Last year at this time we were just entering a very mild and rather pleasant phase – warmest April on record! Global warming! We’re all going to die!</p>
<p>There’s been nothing remotely strange about the weather this week or for that matter any week I can remember. I do recall one year – I think it was 1971 – when, up in Middlesbrough, we had a snowfall in every month from October to June. But that was interesting, or odd, only in a statistical sense. I suppose weather hyperbole enables journos to write long articles entitled: why are we experiencing such extreme weather phenomena? We’re not, though. You’re just writing about it more. And I suppose, as a consequence, I am too.</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/rod-liddle/2013/03/whats-strange-about-this-weather-nothing-at-all/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=whats-strange-about-this-weather-nothing-at-all">The Spectator, 23 March 2013</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/whats-strange-weather/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Little Ice Age Triggered Social And Political Crisis</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/ice-age-triggered-social-political-crisis/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/ice-age-triggered-social-political-crisis/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 06:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Climate Record]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11329</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“God Almighty has a quarrel lately with all Mankind,” lamented the Welsh historian James Howell in 1647, “for within these 12 years there have been the strangest Revolutions and horridest things happened, not only in Europe but all the world over.” The world, he thought, was “off the hinges”. He was not alone. As civil [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“God Almighty has a quarrel lately with all Mankind,” lamented the Welsh historian James Howell in 1647, “for within these 12 years there have been the strangest Revolutions and horridest things happened, not only in Europe but all the world over.” The world, he thought, was “off the hinges”. He was not alone. As civil strife raged in the British Isles, rebellion tore holes in the empires of the Ming and the Ottomans, and central Europe bled in the Thirty Years’ War, other commentators sank into despair. Every day, recorded the Oxford scholar Robert ­Burton in 1638, brought news of “war, plagues, fires, inundations, thefts, murders, massacres, meteors, comets, spectrums, prodigies, apparitions; of towns taken, cities besieged in France, ­Germany, Turky [sic], Persia, Poland etc”. Four years later, a Spanish tract suggested a terrifying but increasingly popular explanation: “This seems to be one of the epochs in which every nation is turned upside down, leading some great minds to suspect that we are now approaching the end of the world.”</p>
<p>For decades, historians havebeen gripped by the extraordinary ­agonies of the 17th century, from the civil wars in Britain and Ireland and the ­terrible ­suffering of war-torn Germany to the ­collapse of China’s Ming dynastyand the dismemberment of the hugePolish-­Lithuanian commonwealth. Eric ­Hobsbawm, probably the first historian to argue that there had been a worldwide “general crisis”, insisted that the causes were economic. By contrast, Hugh ­Trevor-Roper diagnosed a wider social breakdown, based on the conflict between court and country and driven by radical intellectual energy.</p>
<p>Now a third brilliant historian, the American-based British scholar Geoffrey Parker, has thrown a new element into the mix. In this vast, superbly researched and utterly engrossing book, Parker shows how climate change pushed the world towards chaos. This was, after all, the Little Ice Age, in which temperatures dipped across the world. The data, he insists, are “clear and consistent”, and he thinks the crisis began in the last years of the 1610s, at around the time of the outbreak of Europe’s Thirty Years’ War. Snow fell in subtropical Japan; sub-Saharan Africa suffered a five-year drought; the rivers of modern Mexico and Virginia dried up; and across Europe, harvests failed and thousands starved.</p>
<p>But this was merely a taste of what was to come. The first months of 1621 were so cold that people walked across the frozen Bosphorus from ­Constantinople to Asia. In the early 1640s, violent winds and rain destroyed harvests across northern Europe, and in Germany soldiers reported seeing people frozen to death on the roads. England lost its king and the Peace of Westphalia brought the Thirty Years’ War to an end, but still the winds blew cold. Winters between 1654 and 1667 were, on average, more than 1C cooler than they are today. Indeed, throughout the second half of the century, the world was literally a colder place, as well as an emptier one. In China, Poland, Russia and the Ottoman Empire, the population fell by about a third, while in some parts of Germany the population fell by half. In 1651, Thomas Hobbes warned that without a strong state, life would be “solitary, poor, nasty, brutish and short”. For many people, it was like that already.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thesundaytimes.co.uk/sto/culture/books/non_fiction/article1232099.ece">Full story (subscription required)</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/ice-age-triggered-social-political-crisis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christopher Booker: It’s Payback Time For Britain&#8217;s Insane Energy Policy</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/christopher-booker-its-payback-time-britains-insane-energy-policy/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/christopher-booker-its-payback-time-britains-insane-energy-policy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 20:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11324</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An obsession with CO2 has left us dangerously short of power as coal-powered stations are forced to close As the snow of the coldest March since 1963 continues to fall, we learn that we have barely 48 hours’ worth of stored gas left to keep us warm, and that the head of our second-largest electricity [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>An obsession with CO2 has left us dangerously short of power as coal-powered stations are forced to close</h2>
<div>
<div id="mainBodyArea">
<div>
<p>As the snow of the coldest March since 1963 continues to fall, we learn that we have barely 48 hours’ worth of stored gas left to keep us warm, and that the head of our second-largest electricity company, SSE, has warned that our generating capacity has fallen so low that we can expect power cuts to begin at any time. It seems the perfect storm is upon us.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>The grotesque mishandling of Britain’s energy policy by the politicians of all parties, as they chase their childish chimeras of CO2-induced global warming and windmills, has been arguably the greatest act of political irresponsibility in our history.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Three more events last week brought home again just what a mad bubble of make-believe these people are living in. Under the EU’s Large Combustion Plants Directive, we lost two more major coal-fired power stations, Didcot A and Cockenzie, capable of contributing no less than a tenth to our average electricity demands. We saw a French state-owned company, EDF, being given planning permission to spend £14 billion on two new nuclear reactors in Somerset, but which it says it will only build, for completion in 10 years’ time, if it is guaranteed a subsidy that will double the price of its electricity. Then, hidden in the small print of the Budget, were new figures for the fast-escalating tax the Government introduces next week on every ton of CO2 emitted by fossil-fuel-powered stations, which will soon be adding billions of pounds more to our electricity bills every year.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Within seven years this new tax will rise to £30 a ton, and by 2030 to £70 a ton, making it wholly uneconomical to generate any more electricity from the coal and gas-fired power stations that last week were still supplying two thirds of our electricity. Put all this together and we see more starkly than ever the game the Government is playing. It knows that no company would build wind farms unless it is given subsidies that, in effect, nearly double or treble the price of its electricity.</p>
<p>The Government will only get CO2-free nuclear power if it promises it an equal subsidy. And now the Coalition is also hell-bent on driving our much cheaper and more reliable coal and gas-fired plants out of business, by imposing a carbon tax that will not only eventually double the cost of their electricity, but also make it impossible for them to survive. So mad is this policy of “double-up all round” that it is driving even the largest and most efficient power station in the country, Drax, capable of supplying seven per cent of all the power we use, to switch from burning coal to wood chips, imported 3,000 miles across the Atlantic from the US. And how has the Government forced Drax to do this? By giving it a subsidy on wood chips that doubles the value of its electricity, while putting an increasingly prohibitive tax on coal.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>This is all insane in so many ways that one scarcely knows where to begin, except to point out that, even if our rulers somehow managed to subsidise firms into spending £100 billion on all those wind farms they dream of, they will still need enough new gas-fired power stations to provide back-up for all the times when the wind isn’t blowing, at the very time when the carbon tax will soon make it uneconomical for anyone to build them.</p>
<p>So we are doomed to see Britain’s lights going out, all because the feather-headed lunatics in charge of our energy policy still believe that they’ve got to do something to save the planet from that CO2-induced global warming which this weekend has been covering much of the country up to a foot deep in snow. Meanwhile, the Indians are planning to build 455 new coal-fired power stations which will add more CO2 to the atmosphere of the planet every week than Britain emits in a year.</p>
</div>
<p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/earth/energy/windpower/9949571/Its-payback-time-for-our-insane-energy-policy.html"></p>
<div>
<p><span style="color: #0000ff;">Full comment</span></p>
</div>
<p></a>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/christopher-booker-its-payback-time-britains-insane-energy-policy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bad News For Pessimists: Malthus Was Wrong</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/bad-news-pessimists-malthus-wrong/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/bad-news-pessimists-malthus-wrong/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 09:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11320</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is a tempting intuition to the idea that the real prices of non-renewable goods like coal, iron ore, or oil should rise, more or less, forever. It’s an easy argument to make, and it sounds right: The world’s population is getting bigger and bigger, so more and more goods like metals and hydrocarbons are [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>There is a tempting intuition to the idea that the real prices of non-renewable goods like coal, iron ore, or oil should rise, more or less, forever. It’s an easy argument to make, and it sounds right: The world’s population is getting bigger and bigger, so more and more goods like metals and hydrocarbons are being consumed. Every year, the sum total of what we’ve taken out of the ground mounts, never to be replaced. Supply of the stuff is limited—once it’s gone, it’s gone.</strong></p>
<p>So, this argument goes, as we exhaust our resources, we’ll have to mine, drill, or otherwise get our hands on it somehow but it will get more and more expensive to do so, because we’ll have exhausted the best stuff. Left to exploit ever-greater quantities of ever-more-marginal deposits, prices will rise indefinitely into the future.</p>
<p>Thus, in this line of reasoning, unless we start consume less of a given non-renewable material, it will forever and ever get more expensive.</p>
<p>The logic appears unimpeachable at first glance. But it’s wrong. The prices of raw materials have not traveled the path this story would predict for any traded commodity once inflation is factored in, over long stretches of time. One of the most powerfully counter-intuitive and empirically conclusive findings in economic history is that the real prices of nearly all major resources have actually trended lower over very long periods of time, even if they’re produced at higher and higher rates.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="http://blogs.cfr.org/levi/files/2013/03/BC-chart-3-22-131.png" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Figure 1. <em>Economist</em> Industrial-Commodity Price Index in Real and Nominal Terms (1871-2010)</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.cfr.org/levi/2013/03/22/bad-news-for-pessimists-everywhere-malthus-was-wrong/">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/bad-news-pessimists-malthus-wrong/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green Coal? Another Phony &#8216;Green Jobs&#8217; Report</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-coal-phony-green-jobs-report/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-coal-phony-green-jobs-report/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 09:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11316</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As yet another Solyndra looms, a new government report shows that by the government&#8217;s own broad definition of a green job, more can be found in a coal mine than near a solar panel. The second annual Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) report on &#8220;Employment in Green Goods and Services,&#8221; released Tuesday, will be the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>As yet another Solyndra looms, a new government report shows that by the government&#8217;s own broad definition of a green job, more can be found in a coal mine than near a solar panel.</strong></p>
<p>The second annual Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) report on &#8220;Employment in Green Goods and Services,&#8221; released Tuesday, will be the last, allegedly a casualty of the same sequestration that claimed the White House tours and may doom the Easter egg hunt on the White House lawn.</p>
<p>That is probably a good thing, for if it were published as a book, it would deserve a place at the top of the New York Times best-seller fiction list.</p>
<p>It is chock full of charts claiming millions of new &#8220;green&#8221; jobs being produced by President Obama&#8217;s efforts to heal the planet and lower the rising seas. But if you have the eyes and the patience to actually examine it, it is full of lies, damned lies and government statistics.</p>
<p>The BLS defines green jobs as those that produce goods or services &#8220;that benefit the environment or conserve natural resources,&#8221; or jobs &#8220;in which workers&#8217; duties involve making their establishment&#8217;s production processes more environmentally friendly or use fewer natural resources.&#8221;</p>
<p>Its report claims that such jobs account for 2.6% of all jobs in the economy, for a total just north of 3.4 million jobs.</p>
<p>But buried in Table 3, &#8220;Green Goods And Services,&#8221; we find under &#8220;Utilities&#8221; and &#8220;Electric power generation&#8221; a total of just 522 jobs for &#8220;solar electric power generation&#8221; and 2,724 jobs for &#8220;wind electric power generation&#8221; for a total of 3,246 jobs.</p>
<p>Under the heading &#8220;coal and petroleum products mfg.&#8221; we find 3,278 jobs. So even in the BLS list of &#8220;green&#8221; jobs, coal and oil wins.</p>
<p>So what about the &#8220;millions&#8221; of other &#8220;green&#8221; jobs claimed? The problem is in that definition.</p>
<p>The bureau includes clothing stores, television and radio broadcasters, and office furniture manufacturers among the country&#8217;s green industries.</p>
<p>Heritage Foundation energy expert Nick Loris said of the report that &#8220;you don&#8217;t have to scratch the surface too deeply to realize that these numbers are bogus.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Many of these jobs being counted as &#8216;green&#8217; are not green and not new,&#8221; says Rep. Mike Pompeo, R-Kan., a member of the Energy and Commerce Committee who sponsored legislation to repeal energy tax credits. &#8220;BLS is counting green jobs to include bus drivers, trash collectors, radio broadcasters and movie producers.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://news.investors.com/ibd-editorials/032113-648963-bls-releases-another-phony-green-jobs-report.htm">Full comment</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-coal-phony-green-jobs-report/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>America&#8217;s &#8216;Green&#8217; Jobs Revelation</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/americas-green-jobs-revelation/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/americas-green-jobs-revelation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11312</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[America can boast only 500 green jobs in solar electric power generation, but 886,000 green jobs in government — many for passage of environmental laws, enforcement of environmental regulations, and administration of environmental programs, according to the new count of green jobs for 2011 released by the Bureau of Labor Statistics this week. The new report [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>America can boast only 500 green jobs in solar electric power generation, but 886,000 green jobs in government — many for passage of environmental laws, enforcement of environmental regulations, and administration of environmental programs, <a href="http://www.bls.gov/news.release/ggqcew.nr0.htm">according to the new count of green jobs for 2011 released by the Bureau of Labor Statistics this week.</a></strong></p>
<p id="">The new report shows that the number of green jobs in the economy grew from 3.2 million in 2010, the first year of data collected, to 3.4 million in 2011. That’s an increase of one-tenth of a percent of the nation’s jobs, from 2.5% to 2.6%.</p>
<div>
<div>BLS is responsible for the federal definition of green jobs under the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007, signed into law by President George W. Bush. The Act incorporated the Green Jobs Act as Title X, sponsored by then-Rep. Hilda Solis, a California Democrat. Solis became secretary of Labor in 2009, and was charged with implementing her legislation.</div>
</div>
<p id="">Now that Solis has resigned, and the budget sequester is in place, BLS is discontinuing the survey, saving $8 million.</p>
<p id="">President Barack Obama called for the creation of 5 million green jobs over the next decade in his 2008 campaign. Most recently, in his State of the Union Address, the president reiterated his support, saying “Four years ago, other countries dominated the clean-energy market and the jobs that came with it. We’ve begun to change that.”</p>
<p id="">The Obama administration then proceeded to give out grants and guaranteed loans for green-energy projects to try to make his dream into reality. Alternative energy grants, loans, and tax breaks cost the economy about $12 billion in 2012.</p>
<p id="">When people hear of green jobs, they think workers are making wind and solar power, and electric cars and batteries. But few Americans are employed in these sectors.</p>
<p id="">In addition to the 500 jobs in solar electric power generation, biomass and geothermal electric generation each accounted for 1,000 jobs, and wind electric power generation employed 3,000 Americans. These are all dwarfed by nuclear power, at 44,000, even though nuclear power is no favorite of environmentalists.</p>
<p id="">In contrast, the number of jobs in oil and gas extraction increased from 159,000 in 2010 to 172,000 in 2011.</p>
<p id="">The largest increase in green jobs came from the construction industry, which added 102,000 jobs, mostly through relabeling. As more construction materials are categorized as energy efficient, the jobs of those who install them turn green.</p>
<p id="">For instance, BLS counts construction workers who install energy efficient windows as having green jobs, but not those who put in regular windows. Plumbers who install “Lo-Flo” toilets have green jobs, but not plumbers who put in regular fixtures.</p>
<p id="">The largest number of green jobs, 886,000, or 26% of total, are in the federal, state, and local governments. This is a decline of 15,000 from 2010, when government was responsible for 28% of green jobs. It takes a quarter of the green jobs work force to pass green jobs laws, write the regulations, and enforce them.</p>
<p id="">For instance, Gregory Friedman, inspector general of the Energy Department, has a green job and a staff of green employees. <a href="http://energy.gov/sites/prod/files/OAS-RA-13-10.pdf">Last month he wrote a report</a> describing the misuse of a $150 million grant awarded to LG Chem, a South Korean-owned battery manufacturer in Holland, Mich. LG Chem was supposed to create 440 green jobs and make enough batteries to run 60,000 electric cars by December 2013.</p>
<p id="">But LG Chem’s employees weren’t green. According to Friedman, “we confirmed that employees spent time volunteering at local non-profit organizations, playing games and watching movies during regular working hours.” LG Chem, meanwhile, sold to U.S. firms batteries made in South Korea. That’s money from Uncle Sam for green jobs in Asia.</p>
<p id="">
<p style="display: inline !important;">Full story</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/americas-green-jobs-revelation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green Jobs Up In  Smoke As Bosch Abandons Solar Energy</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-jobs-smoke-bosch-abandons-solar-energy/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-jobs-smoke-bosch-abandons-solar-energy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 09:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11309</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Bosch said it will sell or shut down its heavily loss-making solar energy operations, the latest blow to the industry as Germany curbs green energy subsidies and cheap Chinese imports flood the market. In a rare reversal of strategy from the manufacturing conglomerate, Bosch said on Friday it would end its photovoltaics, or solar panel [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bosch said it will sell or shut down its heavily loss-making solar energy operations, the latest blow to the industry as Germany curbs green energy subsidies and cheap Chinese imports flood the market.</strong></p>
<p>In a rare reversal of strategy from the manufacturing conglomerate, Bosch said on Friday it would end its photovoltaics, or solar panel production early next year and put parts of the business up for sale.</p>
<p>Unlisted Bosch, one of the world&#8217;s largest maker of car parts, has lost 2.4 billion euros (2 billion pounds) since it created the solar energy unit in 2008 after it bought Aleo Solar and Ersol. It made a 1 billion euro loss last year.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is possibly the most painful experience that I have had to endure in my professional career,&#8221; said Chairman Franz Fehrenbach in a statement unveiling the plans for the unit that employs 3,000 staff.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ibtimes.co.uk/articles/449399/20130322/bosch-abandons-solar-energy.htm">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-jobs-smoke-bosch-abandons-solar-energy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
