<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 12:26:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>2012 In Review: America’s Amazing Energy Revolution</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/2012-review-americas-amazing-energy-revolution/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/2012-review-americas-amazing-energy-revolution/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 12:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11487</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[America is in the early stages of an amazing energy revolution that represents a seismic shift in the energy landscape that has very rarely happened with such great magnitude in such a short period of time. The Department of Energy released its Monthly Energy Review today for March, with all energy statistics now updated through the end of 2012. Based on today’s updates, here are [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>America is in the early stages of an amazing energy revolution that represents a seismic shift in the energy landscape that has very rarely happened with such great magnitude in such a short period of time.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="uscrudenetimports" src="http://www.aei-ideas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/uscrudenetimports-600x393.jpg" width="480" height="314" /></p>
<p>The Department of Energy released its <a href="http://www.eia.gov/totalenergy/data/monthly/index.cfm?src=email" target="_blank">Monthly Energy Review</a> today for March, with all energy statistics now updated through the end of 2012. Based on today’s updates, here are some highlights of America’s amazing energy statistics for 2012:</p>
<p>1. The US produced an average of 6.574 million barrels of oil per day in 2012, which was the highest average annual crude oil output since 1995 (see blue line in top chart above). US oil output has been accelerating, and during the first two months of 2013 crude oil production averaged 7.046 million barrels of oil per day, which is the highest production level since 1992, twenty years ago.</p>
<p>2. In 2012, several states set new production records for crude oil output including North Dakota, New Mexico and Colorado. Other states set mult-decade production highs for crude oil output including Oklahoma (highest since 1994), Texas (highest since 1989), Utah (highest since 1988), Wyoming (highest since 1999) and Kansas (highest since 1995).</p>
<p>3. As a result of the boom in shale oil production in the US, America  produced domestically more than 60% of the oil consumed last year, and net oil imports fell below 40% in 2012 for the first time since 1991, more than twenty years ago (see red line in top chart above). Just seven years ago, it was exactly the opposite – American relied on foreign sources of oil for 60% of the oil consumed and produced only 40% before the oceans of unconventional oil were accessed using the breakthrough technologies of fracking and horizontal drilling.</p>
<p>4. Natural gas production in the US last year reached a new record high of almost 30 trillion cubic feet, an increase of 5% over 2011, following increases of 7.4% in 2011 and 3.4% in 2010.</p>
<p>5. Largely as a result of the surging production of domestic natural gas being substituted for coal to generate America’s electricity, carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions fell in 2012 to the lowest level since 1994, eighteen years ago (see middle chart above). Since the 2007 peak, greenhouse gas emissions in the US have fallen by more than 12%, which is one of the largest reductions in CO2 recorded over that period by any country in the world.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="co2" src="http://www.aei-ideas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/co2-600x427.jpg" width="480" height="342" /></p>
<p>6. As a result of natural gas production reaching an all-time high and oil production hitting a 17-year high last year, America was more energy self-sufficient in 2012 than in any year since 1991, more than 20 years ago (see bottom chart above).  Last year, the US produced domestically 83.2% of the total energy consumed, which was the highest level of energy self-sufficiency since 1991, when the US produced a slightly higher 83.3% of the energy consumed.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="energyprod" src="http://www.aei-ideas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/energyprod-600x416.jpg" width="480" height="333" /></p>
<p><strong>MP</strong>: America is in the early stages of an amazing energy revolution that represents a seismic shift in the energy landscape that has very rarely happened with such great magnitude in such a short period of time. The new Department of Energy data released today confirms that America is experiencing an amazing, game-changing energy bonanza that is truly revolutionary – natural gas production is at record levels, crude oil output is the highest in 20 years, C02 emissions have fallen precipitously to 20-year lows, and America is more energy self-sufficient than at any time since 1991 when George H.W. Bush was president. In terms of America’s energy, we’ve come a long way in short period of time, and the energy revolution is just getting started.  America’s economic future looks much, much brighter because of the shale revolution, which will continue to support and energize the US economy for decades to come.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.aei-ideas.org/2013/03/year-in-review-americas-amazing-energy-revolution/">AEIdeas, 27 March 2013</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/2012-review-americas-amazing-energy-revolution/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rupert Darwall: The Age Of Global Warming</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/rupert-darwall-age-global-warming/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/rupert-darwall-age-global-warming/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 10:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11458</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Speech given by Rupert Darwall at the GWPF Book Event on 27 March 2013: Thank you, Nigel. It is a particular honour for me to speak to the GWPF and to repay an intellectual debt to you as one of the very first to shine light into the darkness of what is climate change. I [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Speech given by Rupert Darwall at the GWPF Book Event on 27 March 2013:</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/rupert-darwall-age-global-warming/1-book-cover/" rel="attachment wp-att-11466"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-11466" alt="1 Book cover" src="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/03/1-Book-cover-224x300.png" width="224" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Thank you, Nigel.</p>
<p>It is a particular honour for me to speak to the GWPF and to repay an intellectual debt to you as one of the very first to shine light into the darkness of what is climate change.</p>
<p>I vividly recall listening to your CPS talk some 6 years ago. Global warming was a problem identified – I’m tempted to say invented &#8211; by scientists.</p>
<p>But you argued, global warming policies are a matter for economists and, pre-eminently, for democratically elected politicians.</p>
<p>Second, using the IPCC’s own numbers, the case for drastic action rested on people in the developing world being 9.5 times better off than they are today rather than 8.5 times better off if climate change was left to its natural course &#8211; a patently absurd proposition to impoverish the present for the benefit of the future.</p>
<p>And third, the superiority of adaptation over trying to cut emissions, because with adaptation you can pocket the benefits of warmer temperatures while reducing the costs of coping with them.</p>
<p>I would like to suggest a slight modification to the case for adaptation which I’ll come back to at the end of my talk.</p>
<p>It was Georges Pompidou, the most neglected of president of the 5th Republic and perhaps the most interesting, who said:</p>
<p>‘There are 3 roads to ruin. Women, gambling and technicians. The most pleasant is with women. The quickest is with gambling. But the surest is with technicians.’</p>
<p>I wonder what he would have said if he had met a climate scientist.</p>
<p>For what distinguishes the age of global warming is that scientists &#8212; particularly climate scientists &#8212; had more impact on public policy and on the destiny of nations than in any other era. Karl Marx wrote that great world historic events happen twice – the first time as tragedy, the second time as farce. With global warming and the role of scientists in directing the future of society, Marx’s formulation can be reversed: First the farce, then the tragedy.</p>
<p>It was in the 1960s and the early 1970s that scientists first staked their claim to political power, when the West experienced its first Environmental Wave. Scientists were among the most prominent riding it. Economic growth was in conflict with nature and the environment, they argued.</p>
<p>In 1972, 37 eminent experts, including 5 Fellows of the Royal Society and 16 holders of science chairs at British universities predicted the termination of industrial civilization within the lifetime of people then living. A choice had to be made, the scientists said, between famine, epidemics and war on the one hand, or a succession of what the scientists called</p>
<p>‘thoughtful, humane and measured changes.’</p>
<p>Few groups have collectively a worse predictive record than scientists when it comes to the future of society.</p>
<p>‘Nothing discredits modern bourgeois development so much as the fact that it has not yet succeeded in getting beyond the economic forms of the animal world.’- Friedrich Engels wrote in the 1860s.</p>
<p>Engels had a point, because it is not too much of a generalisation to say that the economic forms of the animal world represent the level of understanding of natural scientists when they opine on economic processes.</p>
<p>Fortunately, first time around, scientists’ advice was ignored. Although in many ways the rhetoric of alarm was more extreme then than it is now, the First Environmental Wave peaked too quickly and broke even more rapidly. In October 1973, Egyptian tanks crossed the Suez Canal. OPEC’s oil price shocks did what the scientists advocated: The economies of the West stopped growing. When growth disappeared, so too did the limits to growth debates of the early 1970s.</p>
<p>Unfortunately for us, the long tail of the Second Environmental Wave, propelled by global warming, carries the active debris of militant green policies to decarbonise our economies, in effect, trying to repeal the industrial revolution with the colossal costs involved in trying to do so.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Because every discussion on global warming at some point comes back to the science, that is where I would like to start – specifically, with scientists. I have already made one observation about scientists and their reliance on what Engels called the economic forms of the animal world.</p>
<p>The second relates to the philosophy of science and the crucial question as to what constitutes scientific knowledge. More surprising than scientists’ lack of understanding of established economic concepts is their unfamiliarity with the epistemological bounds of their field of knowledge. In his 1962 classic, ‘The Structure of Scientific Revolutions’, Thomas Kuhn observed:</p>
<p>‘Though many scientists talk easily and well about the particular individual hypotheses that underlie a concrete piece of current research, they are little better than laymen at characterising the established bases of their field, its legitimate problems and methods.’</p>
<p>Nearly half a century later, in one of his last lectures, the climate scientist Stephen Schneider made the same point somewhat differently:</p>
<p>‘Very few people learn about the basic philosophy of science and how it works,’ Schneider said.</p>
<p>As he put it:</p>
<p>‘Universities were handing out PhDs in science with no Ph. in them.’</p>
<p>A couple of years ago, the climate scientist Mike Hulme wrote an interesting book &#8216;Why we disagree about climate change.&#8217; I emailed Mike to say it missed out the most fundamental disagreement – its epistemological basis.</p>
<p>According to Karl Popper, the 20<sup>th</sup> century’s leading philosopher of science, the essence of the scientific method is critical argument and genuine attempts to refute theories with empirical tests yielding reproducible results. Because we cannot be certain of the truth, but can know what is false, in science, the truth is approached by discarding what has been proved to be false. From this, Popper derived the criterion of falsifiability – the quality of a scientific theory is its capacity to give rise to experiments that in principle could yield empirical evidence that refutes it. Thus the more a theory precludes, the stronger a theory is.</p>
<p>On that basis, what hardened into the scientific orthodoxy underpinning global warming does not meet the threshold of being a scientific theory. It would be more accurate to describe it as a conjecture or speculation. Instead, global warming must depend on the preponderance of scientific opinion.</p>
<p>In turn, maintaining the scientific consensus had profound consequences, for it brought global warming into conflict with what Popper called the essence of the scientific method – critical argument and attempts to overthrow it &#8212; a conflict between the advocacy requirements of ‘state science’ and the epistemological demands of the real thing.</p>
<p>I would like to re-frame the issue of the science in a different way than usual:</p>
<p>How was it that what was little more than a scientific curiosity for much of the 20<sup>th</sup> century, come to define an age?</p>
<p>As climate scientists like to remind us, the basic physics were established in the 19<sup>th</sup> century. A few months before Charles Darwin published ‘The Origin of the Species’, John Tyndall demonstrated the radiative properties of carbon dioxide in his basement laboratory at the Royal Institution not far from here. In 1896, the Swedish chemist, Svante Arrhenius, wrote his famous paper estimating the effect of industrialisation on atmospheric temperature.</p>
<p>And the climate seemed to respond.</p>
<p>The Central England Temperature series shows temperatures rising from the middle of the 1890s, followed by a partial decline in the first decade of the twentieth, followed by a significant rise. In the 1920s, the Arctic appeared to be warming up.</p>
<p>‘So little ice had never before been noted,’ a newspaper reported in 1922.</p>
<p>The dustbowl of the 1930s was the most extreme climatic event in American history. And in 1938, Guy Stewart Callendar quantified the effect of a 10% increase in atmospheric carbon dioxide on global temperatures.</p>
<p>All the scientific and geophysical pre-conditions were there for global warming. But the elements which turned out to be decisive were not. Science alone cannot explain how global warming became a political phenomenon. The explanation must be found elsewhere.</p>
<p>Without wishing in any way to discourage you from buying my book, I would like to share with you its conclusion in its most condensed form. Just eight words, in fact:</p>
<p>The science is weak. The idea is strong.</p>
<p>When we are talking about science, we are not talking about what John Tyndall found in a test tube, but predicting what happens to temperatures in response to small changes in the composition of the Earth’s atmosphere.</p>
<p>The science is inherently weak because it is not capable of being falsified in the here and now. It is weak because it doesn’t appear to preclude several years of standstill in average global temperature, or even, for all I know, declines in average global temperature. Neither does it preclude it snowing in March – contrary to one of the most famous prophecies made by any climate scientist.</p>
<p>‘Children just aren’t going to know what snow is,’ predicted David Viner of the University of East Anglia in March 2000.</p>
<p>Voluminous evidence is itself testament to global warming’s weakness as science. As Karl Popper argued in the 1920s, it is almost always possible to find evidence to support a proposition. Come rain or shine, drought or storm, global warming came to acquire the characteristics of phlogiston in the 18<sup>th</sup> century theory of combustion.</p>
<p>‘Chemists have made phlogiston a vague principle, which is not strictly defined and which consequently fits all the explanations demanded of it,’</p>
<p>the great French scientist Lavoisier wrote.</p>
<p>‘Sometimes it has weight, sometimes it has not … Sometimes it passes through the pores of vessels, sometimes they are impenetrable to it …</p>
<p>‘It explains at once causticity and non-causticity, transparency and opacity, colour and the absence of colours.’</p>
<p>It must be conceded that proponents of phlogiston explained their ideas with rather greater elegance than 21<sup>st</sup> century believers in global weirding. So the science is inherently weak.</p>
<p>Now to the idea.</p>
<p>Or rather the ideas, because global warming is a confluence of ideas into one Big Idea. Scratch the surface of global warming, and you’ll invariably find concern about there being too many people in the world. Indeed, earlier this week, the government Chief Scientific Adviser, Sir John Beddington, took to the air waves to talk about global warming and population growth.</p>
<p>Alarm about population growth was popularised by Thomas Malthus at the beginning of the 19<sup>th</sup> century – a century in which Britain’s population nearly quadrupled; cash wages for factory workers rose 50%; the purchasing power of money doubled; and life expectancy began its long-term increase.</p>
<p>Despite the failure of Malthus’s prediction that population growth would be repeatedly checked by famine, disease and war, for true believers, the idea that there are or will be too many humans is an article of faith.</p>
<p>In 1865, the brilliant economist William Stanley Jevons modified the Malthusian construct. Resource depletion in the form of exhaustion of cheap coal meant the prosperity of Victorian Britain could not last.</p>
<p>Jevons made the mistake that every one of his depletionist successors makes. He had not factored in the impact of new technologies and new discoveries. Jevons convinced himself that the steam engine was the farthest mankind could progress. Electrical power was a delusion and petroleum was merely the liquid essence of coal &#8211; and an expensive one at that.</p>
<p>Keynes wrote that Jevons’s conclusions were influenced by a psychological trait which many shared but was unusually strong in him, of a certain hoarding instinct and readiness to be alarmed by the idea of exhaustion of resources.</p>
<p>By contrast, Marx and Engels utterly rejected the notion of capitalist economies being constrained by a fixed resource endowment and static technology.</p>
<p>‘We start from the premise that the same forces which have created modern bourgeois society … will also suffice … to raise the productive powers of each individual so much he can produce enough for the consumption of two, three, four, five or six individuals’,</p>
<p>Engels wrote, to contrast with his criticism of those subscribing to the economic forms of the animal world.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Then there is the entry of nature into politics. In Britain, its entrance occurred between the two world wars. And what a strange entrance it was. There were the distributists, prominent among them GK Chesterton and Hilaire Belloc, who believed every family should have three acres and a cow. Then there were these folk…</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/rupert-darwall-age-global-warming/kibbo-kift/" rel="attachment wp-att-11481"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-11481" alt="Kibbo Kift" src="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/03/Kibbo-Kift-300x229.jpeg" width="300" height="229" /></a></p>
<p>the Kindred of the Kibbo Kift.</p>
<p>Those of you familiar with the ancient Kentish language will know what Kibbo Kift means. For the rest, it means – allegedly – proof of great strength. Note the North American Indian totem poles, the authentic Anglo-Saxon hoody and the interesting footwear &#8230;</p>
<p>… they had not progressed to wearing sandals.</p>
<p>In the 1930s, the Kibbo Kift started championing economic salvation in the form of Major Douglas’s cranky A+B theorem&#8230;.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/rupert-darwall-age-global-warming/green-shirts/" rel="attachment wp-att-11484"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-11484" alt="Green Shirts" src="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/03/Green-Shirts-300x205.jpeg" width="300" height="205" /></a></p>
<p>and morphed into the Green Shirt movement. They went on marches through London calling for the stringing up of bankers and the payment of the national dividend.</p>
<p>It is amazing how little has changed since the 1930s.</p>
<p>The Green Shirts were opposed by Oswald Moseley’s Black Shirts. There were clashes and scuffles between them, leading Parliament to pass the Public Order Act of 1937 which banned uniformed marches. Proto-environmentalism also existed among the Black Shirts and the pre-war circle of Nazi sympathisers. Moseley’s agriculture adviser, who penned this pamphlet for the British Union of Fascists …</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/rupert-darwall-age-global-warming/4-the-land-and-the-people/" rel="attachment wp-att-11469"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-11469" alt="4 The Land and the People" src="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/03/4-The-Land-and-the-People-198x300.jpg" width="198" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>… after the Second World War edited the Soil Association’s journal ‘Mother Earth.’</p>
<p>The sudden emergence of environmentalism as a political movement in the post-war world can be dated with precision – to 1962 and publication of Rachel Carson’s ‘Silent Spring’. In reality, ‘Silent Spring’ is a work of fiction – and all the more powerful for that. The political impact of environmentalism following ‘Silent Spring’ was immense. I would go so far as to say that ‘Silent Spring’ is the most consequential book of the post-war era. Just ten years separate ‘Silent Spring’ from the first major UN conference on the environment at Stockholm in 1972.</p>
<p>So here is the moment to introduce perhaps the most influential person you have never heard of.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/rupert-darwall-age-global-warming/5-barbara-ward/" rel="attachment wp-att-11470"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-11470" alt="5 Barbara Ward" src="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/03/5-Barbara-Ward-198x300.jpg" width="198" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>I had not heard of Barbara Ward until I started researching the book. Other than the Queen, Barbara Ward must have been the best connected woman of the 20<sup>th</sup> century. Friends with Hebert Morrison and Ernest Bevin, she escorted a young American Naval officer – John F. Kennedy during the 1945 general election. Lyndon Johnson said hers were the only books he ever read.  Harold Wilson and Ted Heath were both fervent admirers. She was friends with the first generation of African leaders and with Indira Gandhi. And she helped write Papal encyclicals. Ward believed in planning and she believed in world government. If you are in to all that sort of thing, you would love her.</p>
<p>If you are not, you might be surprised at just how much she has shaped the world in which we live.</p>
<p>To avert a threatened Third World boycott of the Stockholm conference, Barbara Ward &#8211; sipping Dom Perignon with the conference organiser Maurice Strong -</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/rupert-darwall-age-global-warming/first-phase-digital/" rel="attachment wp-att-11471"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-11471" alt="First Phase Digital" src="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/03/6-Strong-at-Stockholm-211x300.jpg" width="211" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>devised a political formula to insulate the Third World’s development aspirations from First World environmentalism. The essence of what they came up with is that economic growth is double-edged.</p>
<p>In the case of rich countries, growth harms the environment.</p>
<p>In the case of developing nations, growth improves the environment.</p>
<p>After Stockholm, Barbara Ward fleshed out an alliance of convenience between environmentalism and the Third World, which today the world knows as sustainable development. In return for participating in, but not being bound by, international environmental initiatives, the Third World would receive copious flows of development aid. Whilst professing a wish – it was not put more strongly than that – to avoid the developed world’s pattern of industrialisation, each country retained its sovereign right to determine for itself the trade-off between development and the environment. In the 1970s and 1980s, this agenda was crystallised in the New International Economic Order.</p>
<p>It was further developed in the Brandt Report of 1981 and the Brundtland Report of 1987. An early and persistent critic of Ward’s approach down to the present day was and, I am glad to say, is David Henderson. Writing on the Brandt report, Henderson criticised the report’s view that poor countries couldn’t grow without massive flows of aid from North to South. Evidence to the contrary was treated as an ‘unfact’ by the Brandt commission. The belief that economic problems had determinate solutions embodied a definite magical element in which, Henderson wrote,</p>
<p>‘Events are treated as though they could be made predictable and manipulable by formulae or spells.’</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The final idea is the pre-eminent role of science – that science should be mobilized to save the planet – science as global therapeutics. It was pithily expressed by the first political leader of undoubted world stature to embrace global warming,</p>
<p>‘The problems science has created, science can in fact solve.’</p>
<p>That was in a 1989 BBC television interview entitled ‘The Greening of Mrs Thatcher.’</p>
<p>During the age of global warming, this had a number of undesirable consequences. Despite their abysmal predictive record and their predisposition to unwarranted pessimism about the future of humanity, it gave scientists an enormously enhanced political role. Because climate science became the leading branch of global therapeutics, it made climate science too big to fail. And in becoming a tool of political advocacy, the nature of climate science became antithetical to science itself.</p>
<p>‘What is called objectivity consists solely in the critical approach,’ Popper wrote.</p>
<p>Because criticism risked undermining the consensus needed to save the planet, evidence was withheld and criticism delegitimized as serving the interests of malign fossil fuel corporations. It also blinded scientists and governments alike to the inescapable logic of global warming. A tonne of carbon dioxide added to the atmosphere has the same physical impact irrespective of who put it there. Absent a global agreement covering the world’s largest economies, even if the scientists are right, decarbonising the British economy is entirely pointless. Given all the history, the biggest surprise about the 2009 Copenhagen climate conference is that anyone was remotely surprised at the outcome.</p>
<p>When global warming first entered international politics in 1988, it was into a pre-existing set of Third World demands and conditions, the most important being that their economic development should not be constrained by environmental obligations. Belief that the Third World would agree to limit their use of fossil fuels ignores the history of the developing world’s strictly conditional involvement with First World environmentalism going back to the 1972 Stockholm conference. There was never a chance.</p>
<p>The leaders of the developing world understood better than Western politicians what the French economist Frederic Bastiat found in the 19<sup>th</sup> century. Bastiat asked: Why is it famine in Europe had become a thing of the past?</p>
<p>The answer: The means of existence rise far above the means of subsistence. When years of scarcity come, we can give up some enjoyments before encroaching up the necessities of life.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So to my final thought:</p>
<p>The best defence against capricious nature and the best global warming policy is: Economic growth – and do not do anything that stops us and the developing world from growing.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/rupert-darwall-age-global-warming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Climate Sceptics Promoted To Key Government Positions</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/climate-sceptics-promoted-key-government-positions/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/climate-sceptics-promoted-key-government-positions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 09:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11459</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The appointment of Michael Fallon to the energy brief will delight everyone. He shares the climate change scepticism of his predecessor, but will keep his focus on how to keep costs down for consumers, and how to secure long-term cheap energy. Michael Fallon MP, the new energy minister: economically hard-nosed Two significant announcements from No [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The appointment of Michael Fallon to the energy brief will delight everyone. He shares the climate change scepticism of his predecessor, but will keep his focus on how to keep costs down for consumers, and how to secure long-term cheap energy.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://blogs.telegraph.co.uk/news/files/2013/03/Michael-Fallon-MP__2346067b1.jpg"><img title="Michael Fallon MP" alt="Michael Fallon MP" src="http://blogs.telegraph.co.uk/news/files/2013/03/Michael-Fallon-MP__2346067b1-460x288.jpg" width="460" height="288" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;">Michael Fallon MP, the new energy minister: economically hard-nosed</span></p>
<p>Two significant announcements from No 10 this morning that should give the carpers (yes, I include myself) something to cheer quietly about. John Hayes is leaving the energy brief to become the Prime Minister&#8217;s senior parliamentary adviser. He remains a minister, but is assigned to the Cabinet Office (where as an IDS loyalist he can renew links with Francis Maude – that should be fun). Sam Gimyah stays on as PPS – No10 is clear that despite mutterings from backbenchers Mr Cameron values his work. This should be seen as a reinforcement of the team, but also an acknowledgment that work needs to be done to rebuild relations between the PM and his troops. Mr Hayes is of the traditionalist right, a leading light in Cornerstone. No10 hopes that by deploying his energies on reconnecting Mr Cameron with his core supporters, he will help develop a re-energised Toryism after two years of Coalition centrism. There&#8217;s a big push going on, with No10 advisers being deployed to the Commons (specifically the PCH coffee shop) to hold talks with MPs to garner their views about the operation, Dave, and what can be improved. Mr Cameron has been inviting in small groups of MPs, and rather than warm wine and cold vol-au-vents, the meetings have been given structure and more formality to denote seriousness.</p>
<p>The appointment of Michael Fallon to the energy brief will delight everyone. He is one of the proper grown-ups in the Government, economically dry as a bone, ambitious in policy, open to radical ideas, and as a Scot and a former Northern MP who has made a great success in business, he is miles away from the metropolitan gilded smugness that some find too apparent in government these days. His job will be to bring some hard-nosed economics to DECC, while managing the politics of a Lib Dem controlled department, which Mr Hayes signally failed to do. Mr Fallon is happy to advertise his contempt for the yellow peril, but he is also politically smart and has been able to forge a working relationship with Vince Cable that has been surprisingly productive. His brief in particular will be to help secure private investment for an energy revolution that&#8217;s needed in nuclear, gas and especially shale. He shares the climate change scepticism of his predecessor, but will keep his focus on the point George Osborne keeps making: how to keep costs down for consumers, and how to secure long-term cheap energy.</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.telegraph.co.uk/news/benedictbrogan/100209478/at-last-mr-cameron-calls-in-the-grown-ups/">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/climate-sceptics-promoted-key-government-positions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>James Hansen Admits Global Warming Slowing, Falling Below IPCC Projections</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/james-hansen-admits-global-warming-slowing-falling-ipcc-projections/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/james-hansen-admits-global-warming-slowing-falling-ipcc-projections/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 09:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Climate Record]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11452</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Is James Hansen becoming a skeptic of the IPCC? A paper published today by James Hansen has some startling admissions, including * the effect [forcing] of man-made greenhouse gas emissions has fallen below IPCC projections, despite an increase in man-made CO2 emissions exceeding IPCC projections * the growth rate of the greenhouse gas forcing has [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Is James Hansen becoming a skeptic of the IPCC?</strong></p>
<p>A paper published today by James Hansen has some startling admissions, including</p>
<p>* the effect [forcing] of man-made greenhouse gas emissions has fallen below IPCC projections, despite an increase in man-made CO2 emissions exceeding IPCC projections</p>
<p>* the growth rate of the greenhouse gas forcing has &#8220;remained below the peak values reached in the 1970s and early 1980s, has been relatively stable for about 20 years, and is falling below IPCC (2001) scenarios (figure 5).&#8221;</p>
<p>* the airborne fraction of CO2 [the ratio of observed atmospheric CO2 increase to fossil fuel CO2 emissions] has decreased over the past 50 years [figure 3], especially after the year 2000</p>
<p>* Hansen believes the explanation for this conundrum is CO2 fertilization of the biosphere from &#8220;the surge of fossil fuel use, mainly coal.&#8221;</p>
<p>* &#8220;the surge of fossil fuel emissions, especially from coal burning, along with the increasing atmospheric CO2 level is &#8216;fertilizing&#8217; the biosphere, and thus limiting the growth of atmospheric CO2.&#8221;</p>
<p>* &#8220;the rate of global warming seems to be less this decade than it has been during the prior quarter century&#8221;</p>
<p>According to &#8220;coal death train&#8221; Hansen,</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;<b>However, it is the dependence of the airborne fraction on fossil fuel emission rate that makes the post-2000 downturn of the airborne fraction particularly striking.</b> The change of emission rate in 2000 from 1.5% yr-1 to 3.1% yr-1 (figure 1), other things being equal, would have caused a sharp<b> increase of the airborne fraction </b>(the simple reason being that a rapid source increase provides less time for carbon to be moved downward out of the ocean&#8217;s upper layers).</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>We suggest that the <b>huge post-2000 increase of uptake by the carbon sinks</b> implied by figure 3 <b>is related to the simultaneous sharp increase in coal use </b>(figure 1).</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p><b>We suggest that the surge of fossil fuel use, mainly coal, since 2000 is a basic cause of the large increase of carbon uptake by the combined terrestrial and ocean carbon sinks. </b>One mechanism by which fossil fuel emissions increase carbon uptake is by fertilizing the biosphere via provision of nutrients essential for tissue building, especially nitrogen, which plays a critical role in controlling net primary productivity and is limited in many ecosystems.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p><b>So is the new data we present here good news or bad news, and how does it alter the &#8216;Faustian bargain&#8217;? At first glance there seems to be some good news. First, if our interpretation of the data is correct, the surge of fossil fuel emissions, especially from coal burning, along with the increasing atmospheric CO<sub>2</sub> level is &#8216;fertilizing&#8217; the biosphere, and thus limiting the growth of atmospheric CO<sub>2</sub>. </b>Also, despite the absence of accurate global aerosol measurements, it seems that the aerosol cooling effect is probably increasing based on evidence of aerosol increases in the Far East and increasing &#8216;background&#8217; stratospheric aerosols.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Both effects work to limit global warming and thus help explain why <b>the rate of global warming seems to be less this decade than it has been during the prior quarter century.&#8221;</b></p></blockquote>
<h2><a href="http://iopscience.iop.org/1748-9326/8/1/011006"></p>
<h4>CLIMATE FORCING GROWTH RATES: DOUBLING DOWN ON OUR FAUSTIAN BARGAIN</h4>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p></a></h2>
<h4> OPEN ACCESS</h4>
<div>
<div>James Hansen, Pushker Kharecha and Makiko Sato</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div><span style="font-size: 1em;" data-mce-mark="1">Perspective</span></div>
<div>
<div id="articleTabId">
<div>
<div></div>
<div>This is a Perspective for the article <a href="http://iopscience.iop.org/1748-9326/7/4/044035">2012 <em>Environ. Res. Lett.</em> <b>7</b> 044035</a></div>
</div>
<div>
<div id="articleAbsctract">
<div></div>
<div>Rahmstorf <i>et al</i> &#8217;s (2012) conclusion that observed climate change is comparable to projections, and in some cases exceeds projections, allows further inferences if we can quantify changing climate forcings and compare those with projections. The largest climate forcing is caused by well-mixed long-lived greenhouse gases. Here we illustrate trends of these gases and their climate forcings, and we discuss implications. We focus on quantities that are accurately measured, and we include comparison with fixed scenarios, which helps reduce common misimpressions about how climate forcings are changing.</div>
<div>Annual fossil fuel CO<sub>2</sub> emissions have shot up in the past decade at about 3% yr<sup>-1</sup>, double the rate of the prior three decades (figure 1). The growth rate falls above the range of the IPCC (2001) &#8216;Marker&#8217; scenarios, although emissions are still within the entire range considered by the IPCC SRES (2000). The surge in emissions is due to increased coal use (blue curve in figure 1), which now accounts for more than 40% of fossil fuel CO<sub>2</sub> emissions.</div>
<div></div>
<div><img alt="Figure 1." src="http://ej.iop.org/images/1748-9326/8/1/011006/erl459410f1_online.jpg" /></div>
<div><b>Figure 1.</b> CO<sub>2</sub> annual emissions from fossil fuel use and cement manufacture, an update of figure 16 of Hansen (2003) using data of British Petroleum (BP 2012) concatenated with data of Boden <i>et al</i> (2012).</div>
<div>The resulting annual increase of atmospheric CO<sub>2</sub> (12-month running mean) has grown from less than 1 ppm yr<sup>-1</sup> in the early 1960s to an average ~2 ppm yr<sup>-1</sup> in the past decade (figure 2). Although CO<sub>2</sub> measurements were not made at sufficient locations prior to the early 1980s to calculate the global mean change, the close match of global and Mauna Loa data for later years suggests that Mauna Loa data provide a good approximation of global change (figure 2), thus allowing a useful estimate of annual global change beginning with the initiation of Mauna Loa measurements in 1958 by Keeling <i>et al</i>(1973).</div>
<div></div>
<div><img alt="Figure 2." src="http://ej.iop.org/images/1748-9326/8/1/011006/erl459410f2_online.jpg" /></div>
<div><b>Figure 2.</b> Annual increase of CO<sub>2</sub> based on data from the NOAA Earth System Research Laboratory (ESRL 2012). CO<sub>2</sub>change and global temperature change are 12-month running means of differences for the same month of consecutive years. Nino index (Nino3.4 area) is 12-month running mean. Both temperature indices use data from Hansen <i>et al</i> (2010). Annual mean CO<sub>2</sub> amount in 1958 was 315 ppm (Mauna Loa) and in 2012 was 394 ppm (Mauna Loa) and 393 ppm (Global).</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><a href="http://hockeyschtick.blogspot.co.uk/2013/03/hansens-mea-culpa-says-man-made-global.html">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/james-hansen-admits-global-warming-slowing-falling-ipcc-projections/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sir John Beddington Is Wrong About UK Temperature Record</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/sir-john-beddington-wrong-uk-temperature-record/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/sir-john-beddington-wrong-uk-temperature-record/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 09:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11449</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In both winter and summer, year on year variations in recent years are pretty normal, or even low, when compared with the historical record. UK Chief Scientist, Sir John Beddington, has claimed in a recent interview that:- “The variation in the temperature or rainfall, which Britain has been experiencing lately, is double the average rate”. I have already [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>In both winter and summer, year on year variations in recent years are pretty normal, or even low, when compared with the historical record.<br />
</strong></p>
<p>UK Chief Scientist, Sir John Beddington, has claimed in a <a href="http://www.newstank.co.uk/headline-news/john-beddington-frequent-britain-cold-snaps/05990/">recent interview</a> that:-</p>
<p><em>“The variation in the temperature or rainfall, which Britain has been experiencing lately, is double the average rate”.</em></p>
<p>I have <a href="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.wordpress.com/2013/03/26/beddington-is-wronguk-rainfall-is-not-becoming-more-variable/">already shown</a> that Met Office data does not bear out his claims regarding rainfall, but what about temperatures? Using the Central England Temperature Series, I have used the same methodology as I did with rainfall to check Beddington’s claims.</p>
<p>Just to recap, I have calculated the year on year changes for mean temperatures, then converted any negative values to positive . (This stops negative changes from cancelling out positive ones). Finally I have added a 10 year running average. Figure 1 shows the results.</p>
<p><a href="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image55.png"><img title="image" alt="image" src="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image_thumb55.png?w=504&amp;h=302" width="504" height="302" border="0" /></a></p>
<p align="center">Figure 1</p>
<p align="left">There has only been one year on year change of note in recent years, when temperatures bounced back in 2011 from the cold year before. But this change is dwarfed by some of the changes in earlier decades and centuries.. More importantly, the 10 year average is low by comparison with much of the earlier record. This suggests that temperatures in the last decade or so have been much less volatile.</p>
<p align="left">Of course, annual numbers may cover up large fluctuations during the year. For instance, a cold winter and hot summer would cancel out, leaving an annual average temperature that looked “normal”. So, let’s extend the exercise to winter and summer seasonal temperatures, as shown in Figures 2 and 3.</p>
<p align="left"><a href="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image56.png"><img title="image" alt="image" src="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image_thumb56.png?w=504&amp;h=296" width="504" height="296" border="0" /></a></p>
<p align="center">Figure 2</p>
<p align="left"><a href="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image57.png"><img title="image" alt="image" src="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image_thumb57.png?w=504&amp;h=289" width="504" height="289" border="0" /></a></p>
<p align="center">Figure 3</p>
<p align="left">In both winter and summer, year on year variations in recent years are pretty normal, or even low, when compared with the historical record.</p>
<p><a href="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/beddington-is-wrong-about-temperatures-too/">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/sir-john-beddington-wrong-uk-temperature-record/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Economist: Climate May Be Warming Up Less Than Once Thought</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/economist-climate-warming-thought/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/economist-climate-warming-thought/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 18:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11446</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The mismatch between rising greenhouse-gas emissions and not-rising temperatures is among the biggest puzzles in climate science just now. OVER the past 15 years air temperatures at the Earth’s surface have been flat while greenhouse-gas emissions have continued to soar. The world added roughly 100 billion tonnes of carbon to the atmosphere between 2000 and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The mismatch between rising greenhouse-gas emissions and not-rising temperatures is among the biggest puzzles in climate science just now.</strong></p>
<p>OVER the past 15 years air temperatures at the Earth’s surface have been flat while greenhouse-gas emissions have continued to soar. The world added roughly 100 billion tonnes of carbon to the atmosphere between 2000 and 2010. That is about a quarter of all the CO₂ put there by humanity since 1750. And yet, as James Hansen, the head of NASA’s Goddard Institute for Space Studies, observes, “the five-year mean global temperature has been flat for a decade.”</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img title="" alt="" src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130330_STC334_1.png" width="290" height="281" /></div>
<p>Temperatures fluctuate over short periods, but this lack of new warming is a surprise. Ed Hawkins, of the University of Reading, in Britain, points out that surface temperatures since 2005 are already at the low end of the range of projections derived from 20 climate models (see chart 1). If they remain flat, they will fall outside the models’ range within a few years.</p>
<p>The mismatch between rising greenhouse-gas emissions and not-rising temperatures is among the biggest puzzles in climate science just now. It does not mean global warming is a delusion. Flat though they are, temperatures in the first decade of the 21st century remain almost 1°C above their level in the first decade of the 20th. But the puzzle does need explaining.</p>
<p>The mismatch might mean that—for some unexplained reason—there has been a temporary lag between more carbon dioxide and higher temperatures in 2000-10. Or it might be that the 1990s, when temperatures were rising fast, was the anomalous period. Or, as an increasing body of research is suggesting, it may be that the climate is responding to higher concentrations of carbon dioxide in ways that had not been properly understood before. This possibility, if true, could have profound significance both for climate science and for environmental and social policy.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.economist.com/news/science-and-technology/21574461-climate-may-be-heating-up-less-response-greenhouse-gas-emissions">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/economist-climate-warming-thought/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Confidence In Green Investment Crumbles</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/confidence-green-investment-crumbles/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/confidence-green-investment-crumbles/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 17:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11442</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Given all the interest in protecting the environment from mankind&#8217;s rapid advance, you&#8217;d think this might be the best time ever to invest in renewable energy and the Next Big Green Thing. Large parts of green-tech investment look like the torched and salted fields left behind by Roman conquerors: barren, lifeless—and bereft of a return on [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Given all the interest in protecting the environment from mankind&#8217;s rapid advance, you&#8217;d think this might be the best time ever to invest in renewable energy and the Next Big Green Thing. Large parts of green-tech investment look like the torched and salted fields left behind by Roman conquerors: barren, lifeless—and bereft of a return on capital. Put another way: In some areas, if you aren&#8217;t already investor road kill, you&#8217;re likely the hedgehog in the headlights about to join your maker.</strong></p>
<p>Investing in clean energy has to be more than just &#8220;a noble way to lose money,&#8221; says Joseph Dear, investment chief for the California Public Employees&#8217; Retirement System. He told The Wall Street Journal&#8217;s ECO:nomics conference last week that Calpers&#8217; returns from the sector have sputtered.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="image" src="http://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/EV-AA506_EVCOVE_D_20130325120652.jpg" /></p>
<p>Which is not to say there isn&#8217;t plenty of innovation fueling renewable energy. ECO:nomics annually gathers top entrepreneurs, thinkers, companies, investors and environmentalists who define the intersection of business and the environment. This year they heard plenty of reason for optimism, in such areas as energy conservation, sustainable cities, agribusiness and battery research.</p>
<p>And then there&#8217;s cheap shale gas, a dominant theme. More production of natural gas, which emits less carbon than fuels like coal, is spurring new manufacturing and job growth. Michael Brune, head of the Sierra Club, said the negative impact of shale fracking is underestimated. Marvin E. Odum, president of Shell Oil, argued that new drilling technology and industry standard-setting would allay these concerns.</p>
<p>But it was undeniable that waning investment in the green side of the energy spectrum was the other dominant theme.</p>
<p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887324103504578378653907957178.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/confidence-green-investment-crumbles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Job Offer: Students Wanted To Be IPCC Climate Change Reviewers</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/ipcc-recruting-students-review-climate-change-report/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/ipcc-recruting-students-review-climate-change-report/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 15:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11438</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Salary: None Experience: None necessary The Risk-Monger was astonished to receive an advertisement from one of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) members (the government of the Netherlands) to recruit students “who have an affinity with climate change” to review the 30 chapters of the IPCC’s Fifth Assessment Report – Working Group II (WG II).  For [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Salary: None</strong></p>
<p><strong>Experience: None necessary</strong></p>
<p>The Risk-Monger was astonished to receive an <a href="http://www.pbl.nl/en/news/newsitems/2013/seeking-phd-students-to-review-the-next-ipcc-report" target="_blank">advertisement </a>from one of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) members (the government of the Netherlands) to recruit students “who have an affinity with climate change” to review the 30 chapters of the IPCC’s Fifth Assessment Report – Working Group II (WG II).  For students, this surely is exciting and the Dutch government offers: “the opportunity to be part of an important, ambitious and unique project and develop your analytical and review skills”.</p>
<p>Maybe I am jumping to conclusions, but with all of the mess of the last IPCC Assessment Report (including a non-scientific WWF campaign document predicting the disappearance of Himalayan glaciers getting through the review process and becoming one of the IPCC’s main conclusions), shouldn’t they try to do a more rigorous review process this time around? Students, working for free, are not perhaps the ideal choice of reviewers needed to challenge the experts. WG II concerns Impacts, Adaptation and Vulnerability related to climate change, so we can assume that the students will not dare to critically challenge the experts on whether there is any bias on the actual effects of climate change. Talk about a tough review process.</p>
<p>What troubles the Risk-Monger more here is that many environmental activists are working on their PhDs and would jump at the opportunity of shaping the IPCC’s subjective conclusions to match their personal political biases. I suppose Greenpeace or WWF will pay their time-sheets to help shape the IPCC’s most socially important chapters.</p>
<p>In a <a href="http://www.pbl.nl/sites/default/files/cms/pbl-2013-letter-to-phd-students-on-ipcc-review_0.pdf" target="_blank">letter </a>to students wishing to volunteer (and asking them to let the Dutch Environmental Assessment Agency know which chapters they would like to review according to their interests), the thoroughness of the IPCC review process is revealed:</p>
<blockquote><p>As a member of the review team you will contribute to the quality of the IPCC report. Through this review you will help IPCC in their aim to produce policy-relevant and policy-neutral information on climate change. Additionally, you are part of the unique and ambitious undertaking to do a thorough review of over 2,000 pages within one month.</p></blockquote>
<p>Strangely, in that month when the entire review process will be done, students will also be taught about what the IPCC is, and how to review a document (I really wish I was making this up).</p>
<p><a href="http://risk-monger.blogactiv.eu/2013/03/25/job-offer-students-wanted-to-be-ipcc-climate-change-reviewers/#.UVMUHxw701J">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/ipcc-recruting-students-review-climate-change-report/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Committee On Climate Change VS Mail On Sunday</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/committee-climate-change-mail-sunday/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/committee-climate-change-mail-sunday/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 13:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DavidWhitehouse</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Observatory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11425</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Committee on Climate Change has given its view on the much-discussed recent article on global warming predictions in the Mail on Sunday, written by David Rose. The article points out the disparity between model simulations of global warming and real data, suggesting that using models to formulate policy in such a situation might be unwise. The [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.theccc.org.uk/ccc-blog/">Committee on Climate Change </a>has given its view on the much-discussed <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2294560/the-great-green-1-the-hard-proof-finally-shows-global-warming-forecasts-costing-billions-wrong-along.html">recent article</a> on global warming predictions in the Mail on Sunday, written by David Rose. The article points out the disparity between model simulations of global warming and real data, suggesting that using models to formulate policy in such a situation might be unwise.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/committee-climate-change-mail-sunday/rose1/" rel="attachment wp-att-11427"><img alt="Rose1" src="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/03/Rose1-300x202.jpg" width="300" height="202" /></a></p>
<p>The Committee on Climate Change is an independent, statutory body established under the Climate Change Act 2008. Its role is to advise the UK Government and Devolved Administrations on emissions targets, and report to Parliament on progress made in reducing greenhouse gas emissions and preparing for climate change. It says it conducts independent analysis into climate change science, economics and policy.</p>
<p>In their criticism of the Mail’s article Professor Sir Brian Hoskins on behalf of the committee, with assistance from Dr Steve Smith, science advisor to the committee, state that “like all scientists we take a skeptical stance, testing each assertion against the evidence.” If only they did. Throughout their riposte they emphasise models over real world data, and only select supporting research.</p>
<p>Hoskins and Smith say that three climate scientists have already taken issue with their quotes used in the Mail on Sunday article. Each was given just a single quote. Piers Forster was quoted as saying that high estimates of climate sensitivity are unlikely, something he repeated on the <a href="http://www.bishop-hill.net/blog/2013/3/18/reacting-to-rose.html">Bishop Hill blog.</a> Myles Allen was quoted as saying that future warming is likely to be significantly lower than once thought, something he repeated in <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2013/mar/20/response-mail-on-sunday-great-green-con-climate-change">the Guardian</a> a few days later, and James Annan claimed he did not say that climate sensitivity is likely to be half what is considered by many, although he did say to the <a href="http://dotearth.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/02/04/a-closer-look-at-moderating-views-of-climate-sensitivity/">New York Times</a> that values of climate sensitivity under 2 degrees are looking a lot more plausible than above 4.5 degrees.</p>
<p>Hoskins and Smith say that the last 15 years of global annual average temperature (land and ocean), which shows no warming, is unimportant. They claim the temperature trend is rising when short-term factors such as El Nino, aerosols and solar effects are filtered out. They quote <a href="http://iopscience.iop.org/1748-9326/6/4/044022">one paper </a>as evidence. In <a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/03/Whitehouse-GT_Standstill.pdf">my recent report </a>I also quote the paper as evidence but I do not ignore many more that take a very different view. What is more, their claim on the effect of aerosols on recent temperature is out of date with recent research that suggests aerosols provide less cooling than some originally thought.</p>
<p>Hoskins and Smith refer to the <a href="http://www.climatewatch.noaa.gov/article/2012/state-of-the-climate-in-2011-highlights/3  ">climatewatch</a> website in an attempt to prove that some that some climate indicators, e.g. ocean heat, sea level, sea ice cover and mountain glaciers, indicate that the Earth is continuing to warm. Some of this data does not support their case. For instance looking at the ocean heat graph on this website shows it has not increased for a decade, and that sea level has not changed its rate of rise for a century, and even has some recent indications of slowing down.</p>
<p>Hoskins and Smith misuse statistics. Regarding the graph used in the Mail on Sunday, they say that in a 60-year period one would expect six data points to be outside the 90% probability band. As they suggest this would often be that three data points are above the 90% band and three below, though such small numbers mean it often wouldn’t be. But that is not what the statistics mean in this case.</p>
<p>There is a statistical uncertainty amongst individual datapoints, but also between model runs, and they are not the same thing. Looking at the real data in the graph shows seven consecutive datapoints outside the 50% probability zone. Even allowing for the fact that the datapoints are not independent but are autocorrelated the probability of this being due to chance is tiny. What the graph does show is that the real word data is only reproduced in less than five percent of the computer model simulations. What is more, where the real data take a certain course it is irrelevant what course is taken by model forecasts. That is the essence of the Mail on Sunday story, that model simulations are wrong at least 95% of the time. Given their spread, and the fact that individual model runs with tweaked input parameters are not statistically independent entities, it is even quite possible that the model runs that fit the real world data do so only by chance. This is quite enough to cast doubt on the validity of the use of the climate models, and to question their ability to forecast the climate.</p>
<p>If this kind of data were from a drugs trial it would have been stopped long ago, even allowing for the little understood stopping bias effect which occurs when looking for the first signs of effectiveness or harm in such trials.</p>
<p>The Mail on Sunday graph was based on comparing 25 climate model simulations with real world data. Personally, I find it more illuminating not to use probability bands on such graphs but instead plot the trajectory of individual simulations. This is what is done in this graph for three sets of real world data and 38 climate simulations. Only two out of the 38 models come anywhere near the real world data, and then not particularly well.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/committee-climate-change-mail-sunday/modelcomp/" rel="attachment wp-att-11428"><img alt="ModelComp" src="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/03/ModelComp-300x231.jpg" width="300" height="231" /></a></p>
<p>I am disappointed in the Committee on Climate Change’s analysis of the Mail on Sunday article. One expects a more objective and sober assessment of empirical facts and research.</p>
<p>Feedback: david.whitehouse@thegwpf.org</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/committee-climate-change-mail-sunday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Matt Ridley: Weird Weather? That’s The Pub Bore Forecast</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/matt-ridley-weird-weather-thats-pub-bore-forecast/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/matt-ridley-weird-weather-thats-pub-bore-forecast/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 13:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Climate Record]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11422</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Forget the anecdotes and face the facts: weather always fluctuates. Arctic springs and angry summers are not oddities. The east wind could cut tungsten, the daffodils are weeks behind and the first chiffchaffs are late. It’s a cold spring and the two things everybody seems to agree upon are that there’s something weird about the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Forget the anecdotes and face the facts: weather always fluctuates. Arctic springs and angry summers are not oddities.</strong></p>
<p>The east wind could cut tungsten, the daffodils are weeks behind and the first chiffchaffs are late. It’s a cold spring and the two things everybody seems to agree upon are that there’s something weird about the weather and it’s our fault. Both are almost certainly wrong.</p>
<p>On weird weather it is true that the contrast with last year’s warm March is striking, as is the difference between the incessant rain of the past 12 months and the long drought that preceded it in most of England. In the past year America has had a heatwave, a superstorm and now a bitterly cold spring. Australia has just had an “angry summer”. And so on.</p>
<p>Sir John Beddington, the Government’s retiring chief scientist, claimed this week that we are seeing more variability. Is he right? On the whole, no. Forget the anecdotes and examine the data.</p>
<p>Start with America. Professor Roger Pielke of the University of Colorado has documented that floods, hurricanes, tornados and East Coast winter storms have shown no increase since the 1950s, while droughts have shown a slight decrease. The only thing that has changed is the financial damage done by storms, but as he drily remarks, “The actual reason for the increasing number of damaging tropical storms has to do with the reporting of damages.”</p>
<p>What about elsewhere? There has been no trend in tropical cyclone intensity or frequency worldwide. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) stated in a recent special report on climate extremes that over the coming two to three decades “signals are relatively small compared to natural climate variability” and that “even the sign of projected changes in some climate extremes over this time frame is uncertain”. Translated: the weather is just as likely to become less extreme as more extreme.</p>
<p>So why is everybody convinced otherwise? Partly because they have been listening too much to the big insurance companies, which have a vested interest in bidding up our anxiety, as Pielke’s remark reminds us. Also, it seems even government chief scientists suffer from what psychologists call “availability heuristic”: when people judge the probability of events from how easy it is to think of examples. [...]</p>
<p>The lesson that weather matters more than climate is not just a bit of fun. Airports and our councils forgot to plan for snow a few years ago because they were more focused on the trend than the variability. In 2010 Brisbane disastrously overfilled a dam because it expected drought to return; the dam could not absorb a flood when it came.</p>
<p>Climate is what you expect; weather is what you get. Which is presumably what the first chiffchaffs will soon be saying to themselves as they search barren tree branches for frozen insects.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thetimes.co.uk/tto/opinion/columnists/article3723862.ece">Full comment (subscription required)</p>
<p></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/matt-ridley-weird-weather-thats-pub-bore-forecast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
