<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 12:20:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>UK Energy Bill Illegal Under Existing EU Rules, Lawyers Claim</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/uk-energy-bill-illegal-existing-eu-rules-lawyers-claim/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/uk-energy-bill-illegal-existing-eu-rules-lawyers-claim/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 12:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11295</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Britain&#8217;s plans to reward nuclear plant operators through fixed prices for low-carbon energy are illegal under existing EU rules and efforts to adapt them are likely to draw opposition from other member states, EU and legal sources said. Britain plans to reform its electricity market to fix a minimum price for nuclear, wind and solar-generated [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Britain&#8217;s plans to reward nuclear plant operators through fixed prices for low-carbon energy are illegal under existing EU rules and efforts to adapt them are likely to draw opposition from other member states, EU and legal sources said.</strong></p>
<p>Britain plans to reform its electricity market to fix a minimum price for nuclear, wind and solar-generated power, which is carbon free.</p>
<p>The proposals are being assessed by the British parliament but the subsidy instruments, named contracts-for-difference (CfDs), will also require approval from the European Commission, the EU executive, under state aid rules.</p>
<p>&#8220;Neither under the current (&#8230;) nor under possible future frameworks could the CfD scheme for nuclear generators be declared compatible with European state aid rules,&#8221; said Doerte Fouquet, a lawyer specialised in EU law at Becker Buettner Held in Brussels.</p>
<p>The British government is already in talks with France&#8217;s EDF about a CfD for the company&#8217;s Hinkley point C nuclear project in south-west England, Britain&#8217;s first nuclear plant since 1995, which is expected to start operating around the turn of the decade.</p>
<p>The European Commission said it had not yet received a formal notification from Britain, but added that, in general, state aid is only authorised when the benefits of aid outweigh the distortion of competition brought about.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Britain&#8217;s Department of Energy and Climate Change said Britain was talking to the EU executive.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are working with the European Commission to ensure mechanisms and institutional arrangements within Electricity Market Reform are consistent with EU state aid rules,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/03/21/uk-eu-uk-nuclear-idUKBRE92K0WL20130321?irpc=401">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/uk-energy-bill-illegal-existing-eu-rules-lawyers-claim/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can Natural Gas Save Cyprus?</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/natural-gas-save-cyprus/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/natural-gas-save-cyprus/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11291</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After Cyprus was left scrambling to salvage a bailout package left nearly dead after a titanic misstep last week, the country’s new-found energy potential finally entered the conversation despite assurances from on high that it would not. Cyprus is one of a handful of countries in the Eastern Mediterranean with a firm claim on one [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>After Cyprus was left scrambling to salvage a bailout package left nearly dead after a titanic misstep last week, the country’s new-found energy potential finally entered the conversation despite assurances from on high that it would not.</strong></p>
<p>Cyprus is one of a handful of countries in the Eastern Mediterranean with a firm claim on one of the largest natural gas finds in the region, offering access to an estimated 50 to 60 tcf of gas and 1.7 billion barrels of crude in waters off its southeastern coast. If exploited with care, the reserves could bring in as much as $400 billion over the coming years, providing a boon to a deeply damaged economy as well as meet domestic demand.</p>
<p>Despite such promise, many local leaders have insisted that no pressure be put on the reserves until they actually start producing revenue, which they expect as early as 2018 or 2019. To do otherwise – and start securing loans on the back of future earnings – would be irresponsible and run the risk of selling off the country’s future at low rates; a sentiment held by Nicos Anastasiades, the center-right candidate who won national elections earlier this month. However, a new and potentially crippling development with the country’s banking system has cast doubt on the country’s immediate future, forcing the issue to the forefront of the country’s political and economic future.</p>
<p>First, for some background.</p>
<p>For those who missed it, Cyprus has been in search of a way to secure a bailout that some have put as high as the country’s annual GDP – $18.3 billion. After months of negotiations, the center-right’s Nicos Anastasiades won national elections behind the pledge to finally bring negotiations to an end and secure a support package from the European Union and the IMF. However, after four such bailouts of beleaguered EU economies, Anastasiades encountered some stiff resistance on the other side of the table. Instead of $18 billion, Cyprus was offered around $12.9. More importantly was how the EU and IMF expected the remainder to be met – with a one-time levy taken from accounts in Cyprus, with increasing rates applied to different balances. With hopes that the action would bring in about $7.5 billion, the plan was introduced to the public last week and was met with an almost immediate backlash from far and wide.</p>
<p>International observers called it misguided and critics called it bullying. Worse still, locals panicked and moved to withdraw their funds, only to be met with closed doors at the order of the government. Notably, Russia’s Vladimir Putin offered a sharp rebuke to the plan, calling it “unjust, unprofessional and dangerous” and it’s not difficult to imagine why. According to the AP, Russian companies have long appreciated the country’s “investor-friendly jurisdiction with lax banking regulations and low taxes” to the tune of $19 billion in current deposits.</p>
<p>Anastasiades and the parliament reacted with further delays on the vote to approve the plan, making its passage less and less likely with each passing hour. Finally, the government announced what they called Plan B, which “would require state pension funds to hand over about ($5.17) billion of their reserves.” The additional amount could come from Russia in exchange for an agreement freeing Russian companies with money in Cypriot banks from the one-time penalty.</p>
<p>Uneasy with the lack of local contributions, the EU and the IMF turned down the Plan B, issued a deadline for a final response (Monday March 25) and sent a firm message to Nicosia – to figure it out and fast.</p>
<p>So, with Cyprus short a few billion, their banks still shut and creditors increasingly nervous about what comes next, the question has become, where can they possibly find the money and for some, will the country’s natural gas claims play a part in where it comes from?</p>
<p>From where things stand now, it looks like Cyprus will be looking to expand on its relationship with Russia with an extension of an existing loan, an appeal for a lower interest rate and most importantly, introducing the role of untapped gas reserves to the conversation. According to a Reuters report, support could be backed up with investment efforts and direct shares of Cypriot gas reserves. Locally, the idea emerged that those depositors that kept their money in Cypriot banks for the next two years would receive bonds “linked to revenues from natural gas”. These options mark a stark difference to campaign rhetoric from Anastasiades, who insisted energy earnings be left alone until real revenues started flowing.</p>
<p>However, even with this change of pace from the country’s new leadership, Cyprus’ energy options may be limited. Put simply, the country’s gas claims are not yet proven, making deals made on the back of uncertain earnings all the more risky.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/christophercoats/2013/03/21/can-natural-gas-save-cyprus/?ss=business%3Aenergy">Full comment</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/natural-gas-save-cyprus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Big Oil And Big Greens Join Forces On Shale Fracking</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/big-oil-big-green-join-forces-shale-fracking/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/big-oil-big-green-join-forces-shale-fracking/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11287</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In an unlikely partnership between longtime adversaries, some of the nation&#8217;s biggest energy companies and environmental groups have agreed on a voluntary set of standards for gas and oil fracking in the Northeast that appear to go further than existing state and federal pollution regulations. The program announced Wednesday will work a lot like Underwriters [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>In an unlikely partnership between longtime adversaries, some of the nation&#8217;s biggest energy companies and environmental groups have agreed on a voluntary set of standards for gas and oil fracking in the Northeast that appear to go further than existing state and federal pollution regulations.</strong></p>
<p>The program announced Wednesday will work a lot like Underwriters Laboratories, which puts its UL seal of approval on electrical appliances that meet its standards. In this case, drilling and pipeline companies will be encouraged to submit to an independent review of their operations, and if they are found to be taking certain steps to protect the air and water, they will receive the blessing of the brand-new Pittsburgh-based Center for Sustainable Shale Development.</p>
<p>If the project succeeds, it could have far-reaching implications for both the industry and environmental groups. A nationwide boom in hydraulic fracturing, or fracking, has unleashed huge new energy reserves but also led to fears of pollution and climate change.</p>
<p>Shell Oil Vice President Paul Goodfellow said this is the first time the company and environmental groups have reached agreement to create an entire system for reducing the effects of shale drilling.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is something new,&#8221; said Bruce Niemeyer, president of Chevron Appalachia. &#8220;This is a bit of a unique coming-together of a variety of different interests.&#8221;</p>
<p>In addition to Shell and Chevron, the participants include the Environmental Defense Fund, the Clean Air Task Force, the Heinz Endowments, EQT Corp., Consol Energy and the Pennsylvania Environmental Council, and the organizers hope to recruit others.</p>
<p>It may be part of a trend. Earlier this month a coalition of industry and environmental groups in Illinois announced that they worked together on drilling legislation now pending there. But the Pittsburgh project, which has been in the works for nearly two years, would be voluntary.</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe it does send a signal to the federal government and other states,&#8221; said Armand Cohen, the director of the Boston-based Clean Air Task Force. &#8220;There&#8217;s no reason why anyone should be operating at standards less than these.&#8221;</p>
<p>The new standards include limits on emissions of methane, a potent greenhouse gas, and the flaring, or burning off, of unwanted gas; reductions in engine emissions; groundwater monitoring and protection; improved well designs; stricter wastewater disposal; the use of less toxic fracking fluids; and seismic monitoring before drilling begins.</p>
<p>The project will cover Pennsylvania, West Virginia and Ohio — where a frenzy of drilling is under way in the huge, gas-rich Marcellus and Utica Shale formations — as well as New York and other states in the East that have put a hold on new drilling.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/business/energy-firms-environmental-groups-agree-tough-new-fracking-standards-1C8975363">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/big-oil-big-green-join-forces-shale-fracking/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>GWPF Book Event: Rupert Darwall &#8211; The Age Of Global Warming</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/gwpf-book-event-rupert-darwall-age-global-warming/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/gwpf-book-event-rupert-darwall-age-global-warming/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=10766</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Global warming defines our age. Understanding it in the context of the history of ideas offers a mirror to our times… ‘This is a brilliant piece of work that every climate change negotiator should have in his front pocket’ &#8211;Jon Snow Rupert Darwall presents his brand new book The Age of Global Warming When: 27 March [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><span style="color: #800000;">Global warming defines our age. Understanding it in the context of the history of ideas offers a mirror to our times…</span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>‘This is a brilliant piece of work that every climate change negotiator should have in his front pocket’</em> &#8211;Jon Snow</strong></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Rupert Darwall presents his brand new book</h2>
<h1 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #000080;"><em>The Age of Global Warming</em></span></h1>
<p><strong>When</strong>: 27 March 2013, 7 pm</p>
<p><strong>Where:</strong> IOM3, 1 Carlton House Terrace, London SW1 5DB</p>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Nigel Lawson</p>
<p><strong>Registration:</strong> To register, please contact <a href="philipp.mueller@thegwpf.org">philipp.mueller@thegwpf.org</a></p>
<p><img alt="The Age of Global Warming: A History" src="http://cache1.bdcdn.net/assets/images/book/large/9780/7043/9780704372993.jpg" /></p>
<p><strong style="font-size: 13px;">About the book:</strong></p>
<p>Global warming defines our age. Understanding it in the context of the history of ideas offers a mirror to our times&#8230;</p>
<p>Rachel Carson’s epoch-creating Silent Spring marked the beginnings of the environmental movement in the 1960s, its ‘First Wave’ peaking at the 1972 Stockholm Conference. The invention of sustainable development by Barbara Ward, along with Rachel Carson the founder of the environmental movement, created an alliance of convenience between First World environmentalism and a Third World set on rapid industrialisation.</p>
<p>The First Wave crashed in 1973 with the Yom Kippur War and decade-long energy crisis. Revived by a warming economy of the 1980s, environmentalism found a new, political champion in 1988: Margaret Thatcher. Four years later at the Rio Earth Summit, politics settled the science. One hundred and ninety-two nations agreed that mankind was causing global warming and carbon dioxide emissions should be cut.</p>
<p>Rio launched rounds of climate change meetings and summits, with developing nations refusing to countenance any agreement restraining their greenhouse gas emissions – their blanket exemption from the 1997 Kyoto Protocol leading to its rejection by the United States that year, and again twelve years later in Copenhagen. This therefore marked not just the collapse of the climate change negotiations, but something larger – an unprecedented humiliation for the West at the hands of the rising powers of the East.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/gwpf-book-event-rupert-darwall-age-global-warming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Renewable Energy Losing Its Shine In Europe</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/renewable-energy-losing-shine-europe/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/renewable-energy-losing-shine-europe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11281</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[European governments have realized that the growth in green energy subsidies – with consumers footing the bill for investors&#8217; soaring profit margins – is out of control: The UK and Czech Republic have already cut their subsidies in half, while Italy imposed a cap on new renewable energy providers. Germany cut subsidies by up to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>European governments have realized that the growth in green energy subsidies – with consumers footing the bill for investors&#8217; soaring profit margins – is out of control: The UK and Czech Republic have already cut their subsidies in half, while Italy imposed a cap on new renewable energy providers. Germany cut subsidies by up to 30%.</strong></p>
<p>For British entrepreneur Timothy Porter and millions of other Europeans who get generous financial incentives for solar panels, the sun has been very lucrative.</p>
<p>Not only does the government pay Porter for producing solar energy he produces, at far higher than the market rate for electricity, but he can also use what he generates for himself.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s fantastic,&#8221; he said, admiring the solar panel he installed on the roof of his home in the English West Midlands two years ago.</p>
<p>Such subsidies are widespread in Europe, where policymakers say that energy from wind and the sun will stave global temperature increases they blame on the use of fossil fuels like oil and coal. But Europe&#8217;s debt crisis has many countries worrying more about their bottom line than climate.</p>
<p>Governments around the world have watched Europe as it has moved to implement generous subsidy schemes like Porter&#8217;s to meet ambitious green energy goals and race towards a future free of fossil fuels.</p>
<p>But with skyrocketing costs, major infrastructure challenges and biting austerity measures brought on by the debt crisis, some wonder why Europe has gone through the trouble of promising so much green so soon.</p>
<p>​Across the English Channel, Germans consumers are waking up to the costs of going green: As of Jan. 1, they are paying 11% more for electricity than they did last year thanks to government plans to replace nuclear plants with wind and solar power that requires significant and constant public money to be made cost effective.</p>
<p>There were a few reasons the subsidies were put in place years ago.</p>
<p>There was a general desire for energy independence from Russia, where natural gas had sometimes been used as a weapon to pressure nations on political matters and the cost was unpredictable. Renewable energy was also seen as a source for jobs and income.</p>
<p>There was also concern for the climate, say analysts: a 2011 Eurobarometer poll showed that Europeans believe climate change to be a graver problem than the financial crisis plaguing Europe.</p>
<p>Nowhere is this concern more acute than in Germany. The country has long had an ambitious clean energy plan that aims to have the entire country running on 80% renewable energies by the year 2050.</p>
<p>That plan was fast-tracked following the accident at Japan&#8217;s Fukushima reactor in March 2011, and by Germans&#8217; overwhelming opposition to nuclear power stemming from the lingering memories of the nuclear disaster at Chernobyl in the former Soviet Union more than two decades ago. For years after, forest-loving Germans worried about picking wild mushrooms.</p>
<p>Chancellor Angela Merkel – once a champion of nukes – did an about-face on her nuclear policy. She announced that all of Germany&#8217;s 17 nuclear plants would be shut down by the year 2022, 14 years ahead of schedule and closed eight immediately.</p>
<p>But her decision had little to do with the safety of Germany&#8217;s nuclear reactors, say analysts. Merkel&#8217;s conservative Christian Democratic Union were worried over regional elections, and federal elections in September: If she wants to remain chancellor she needed to siphon votes from the Greens and Social Democrats, both anti-nuke.</p>
<p>Dubbed the &#8220;energy transition,&#8221; the move has become a logistical and financial headache for Berlin. Nuclear power had represented one-fifth of the country&#8217;s energy supply, and Environment Minister Peter Altmaier recently estimated the shift to renewables could total up to $1.3 trillion by 2030.</p>
<p>The move left some of Germany&#8217;s neighbors grumbling.</p>
<p>&#8220;Outside of Germany, we&#8217;ve noticed that there are two perspectives,&#8221; said Gerd Rosenkranz, a spokesman for the non-profit German Environmental Aid. &#8220;One is, &#8216;there go those crazy Germans again&#8217; and the other is &#8216;there go those crazy Germans again&#8217; – but it&#8217;s possible that they&#8217;ll succeed.&#8217;&#8221;</p>
<p>But at what price?</p>
<p><a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/money/business/2013/03/21/europe-renewable-energy/2006245/">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/renewable-energy-losing-shine-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Trend In Global Drought Over The Past Six Decades</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/trend-global-drought-decades/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/trend-global-drought-decades/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 07:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11275</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In setting the stage for their intriguing paper on one of the most devastating extreme types of weather, Sheffield et al. (2012) note that drought is expected by many &#8220;to increase in frequency and severity in the future as a result of climate change, mainly as a consequence of decreases in regional precipitation but also because of increasing [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In setting the stage for their intriguing paper on one of the most devastating extreme types of weather, Sheffield <em>et al</em>. (2012) note that <em>drought</em> is expected by many &#8220;to increase in frequency and severity in the future as a result of climate change, mainly as a consequence of decreases in regional precipitation but also because of increasing evaporation driven by global warming,&#8221; citing Sheffield and Wood (2008), Dai (2010) and Seneviratne <em>et al</em>. (2012), while noting that some people feel &#8220;this may already be happening globally.&#8221;</p>
<p>So <em>is</em> it happening? &#8230; and is it happening <em>globally</em>?</p>
<p>The three researchers state that previous assessments of historic changes in drought over the late twentieth and early twenty-first centuries indicate that what some have suggested in this regard may <em>indeed</em> &#8221;be happening globally,&#8221; based on calculations of the Palmer Drought Severity Index (PDSI) performed by Dai <em>et al</em>. (2004) and Briffa <em>et al</em>. (2009). However, they appear to have a problem with this suggestion.</p>
<p>Sheffield <em>et al</em>. explain themselves by first noting that &#8220;the simplicity of the PDSI, which is calculated from a simple water-balance model forced by monthly precipitation and temperature data, makes it an attractive tool in large-scale drought assessments,&#8221; but they say that it &#8220;may give biased results in the context of climate change,&#8221; citing the work of Roderick <em>et al</em>. (2009) and going on to show that &#8220;the previously reported increase in global drought is overestimated because the PDSI uses a simplified model of potential evaporation that responds only to changes in temperature and thus responds incorrectly to global warming in recent decades.&#8221;</p>
<p>Performing what they describe as &#8220;more realistic calculations, based on the underlying physical principles that take into account changes in available energy, humidity and wind speed,&#8221; they thus derive results that suggest &#8220;there has been little change in drought over the past 60 years,&#8221; which may help, in their words, &#8220;to explain why palaeoclimate drought reconstructions based on tree-ring data diverge from the PDSI-based drought record in recent years,&#8221; as revealed by the work of Fang <em>et al</em>. (2009) and de Grandpre <em>et al</em>. (2011).</p>
<p>Therefore, even in a situation where it had been thought to have been <em>demonstrated</em> that global warming promotes global drought, such is now known <strong><em>not to be correct</em></strong>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.co2science.org/articles/V16/N12/EDIT.php">Full story &amp; references</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/trend-global-drought-decades/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Norwegian Glacier Retreating To Levels That Were Normal During Roman Times</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/norwegian-glaciers-retreating-levels-normal-roman-times/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/norwegian-glaciers-retreating-levels-normal-roman-times/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 07:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Climate Record]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11271</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A pre-Viking woolen tunic found beside a thawing glacier in south Norway shows how global warming is proving something of a boon for archaeology, scientists said on Thursday. Norway&#8217;s Lendbreen glacier, where it was found, has not been so small since 300 AD. The greenish-brown, loose-fitting outer clothing &#8211; suitable for a person up to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>A pre-Viking woolen tunic found beside a thawing glacier in south Norway shows how global warming is proving something of a boon for archaeology, scientists said on Thursday. Norway&#8217;s Lendbreen glacier, where it was found, has not been so small since 300 AD.</strong></p>
<p>The greenish-brown, loose-fitting outer clothing &#8211; suitable for a person up to about 176 cms (5 ft 9 inches) tall &#8211; was found 2,000 meters (6,560 ft) above sea level on what may have been a Roman-era trade route in south Norway.</p>
<p>Carbon dating showed it was made around 300 AD.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s worrying that glaciers are melting but it&#8217;s exciting for us archaeologists,&#8221; Lars Piloe, a Danish archaeologist who works on Norway&#8217;s glaciers, said at the first public showing of the tunic, which has been studied since it was found in 2011.</p>
<p>A Viking mitten dating from 800 AD and an ornate walking stick, a Bronze age leather shoe, ancient bows, and arrow heads used to hunt reindeer are also among 1,600 finds in Norway&#8217;s southern mountains since thaws accelerated in 2006.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is only the start,&#8221; Piloe said, predicting many more finds.</p>
<p>One ancient wooden arrow had a tiny shard from a seashell as a sharp tip in an intricate bit of craftsmanship.</p>
<p><strong>RECEDING GLACIERS</strong></p>
<p>The 1991 discovery of Otzi, a prehistoric man who roamed the Alps 5,300 years ago between Austria and Italy, is the best known glacier find. In recent years, other finds have been made from Alaska to the Andes, many because glaciers are receding.</p>
<p>The shrinkage is blamed on climate change, stoked by man-made emissions of greenhouse gases from burning fossil fuels.</p>
<p>The archaeologists said the tunic showed that Norway&#8217;s Lendbreen glacier, where it was found, had not been so small since 300 AD.</p>
<p><a href="http://planetark.org/wen/68226">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/norwegian-glaciers-retreating-levels-normal-roman-times/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>WWF Slaps Down Polar Bear Protection Bill</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/wwf-slaps-polar-bear-protection-bill/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/wwf-slaps-polar-bear-protection-bill/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 06:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11268</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Spiked Online has an excellent article which looks at the curious case of the polar bear, whose status as an endangered animal has increased at the same time that it’s population is rising. The author, Rob Lyons, looks at how the polar bear has become worth more as a symbol or mascot of global warming and allegedly melting [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Spiked Online has an excellent <a href="http://www.spiked-online.com/site/article/13462/" target="_blank">article </a>which looks at the curious case of the polar bear, whose status as an endangered animal has increased at the same time that it’s population is rising.</strong></p>
<p>The author, Rob Lyons, looks at how the polar bear has become worth more as a symbol or mascot of global warming and allegedly melting polar ice caps than as an animal in its own right.</p>
<p>Most shockingly of all, though, is the cynical maneuvering of the World Wildlife Fund (WWF). Faced with the possibility of increased protection under the CITES rules on trading animal furs and parts, the WWF said they would OPPOSE any such increased protection. Asked why on earth a charity supposedly devoted to protecting animals would be against a law which gave them greater protection, WWF “wildlife trade policy analyst” Dr Colman O’Criodain mumbled the following “justification” -</p>
<blockquote><p>“If we were tempted to support it on the basis of trade being a major threat, it is not,” says Dr Colman O’Criodain, WWF’s wildlife trade policy analyst.</p>
<p>“We have to focus on what is the major threat and not distract ourselves with a relatively minor one. We can’t be arguing for the science when it suits us and then ignore it when it doesn’t suit our case,” he added.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-20798136" target="_blank">BBC: Polar Bear Trade Ban Divides Campaigners</a></p></blockquote>
<p>What on earth is he on about? Why would one of the best known and wealthiest environmental organisations be risking their reputation by failing to support a law giving greater protection for animals? Beneath all the verbiage from the WWF, Rob Lyons thinks he knows why: cold, hard cash. The money raised from the polar bear as mascot is simply too great to allow anything to distract from that -</p>
<blockquote><p>Nonetheless, asking people to ‘adopt a polar bear’ seems to be a great vehicle for fundraising, even though WWF <a href="https://support.wwf.org.uk/adopt-a-polar-bear/?pc=ALD004001&amp;gclid=CKXbl-vNiLYCFaHHtAod-FkADw#" target="_blank">says</a> that the money given will be used for ‘raising awareness of the threats of climate change that we all face’ and ‘will also help fund other essential WWF conservation work around the world’. In other words, those monthly donations may only tangentially benefit polar bears.</p>
<p>The claim that polar bears are under threat is a cynical attempt at emotional blackmail, designed to short-circuit debate about climate change while adding cash to the overflowing coffers of multinational green mega-NGOs. WWF alone reported a worldwide income of over €500million in 2011. Given the apparent health of most polar-bear populations, it’s time the whole fairytale about polar-bear extinction was put on ice.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.spiked-online.com/site/article/13462/" target="_blank">Spiked Online. Adopt a Polar Bear?</a></p></blockquote>
<p>The Orwellian construction of the phrase “raising awareness of the threats of climate change” points to the real use the money will be put to. Donate to save a marine animal, and your money will go straight to funding the propaganda efforts of this multinational organisation with it’s multimillion dollar income.</p>
<p>Thus, as the Examiner noted, at the CITES meeting to decide whether to ban the trade in polar bear furs and parts, there was the bizarre spectacle of the WWF siding with Canada, a country it supposedly has major differences of opinion with over the tar sands -</p>
<blockquote><p>The ban was opposed by Canada, home to two-thirds of the world’s polar bear population and the only country to allow exports, as well as Norway and Greenland. In a move that baffled many conservationists, the <a href="http://www.examiner.com/topic/world-wildlife-fund/articles" target="_blank">World Wildlife Fund</a> (WWF) joined in opposing the ban.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.examiner.com/article/bid-to-save-polar-bears-shot-down-by-canada-world-wildlife-fund" target="_blank">Examiner: Bid to Save Polar Bears Shot down by Canada, World Wildlife Fund.</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Even the Center for Biological Diversity was disgusted with the cynicism shown by the WWF, putting the money-making potential of the bear as mascot over the chance to protect them against hunting for fur:</p>
<blockquote><p>But Brendan Cummings of the Center for Biological Diversity, disagreed. “It’s an unfortunate result after an ugly process,” he said. “Countries and organizations that wanted to keep the international trade in polar bear skins going for political reasons had to distort or downplay the science</p>
<p><a href="http://www.examiner.com/article/bid-to-save-polar-bears-shot-down-by-canada-world-wildlife-fund" target="_blank">Examiner: Bid to Save Polar Bears Shot down by Canada, World Wildlife Fund.</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Given that the WWF Network’s income increased to 593 Million Euros last year (approx. 756 Million dollars, US) you can understand the amounts at stake here.</p>
<p><a href="http://hauntingthelibrary.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/wwf-slaps-down-polar-bear-protection-bill-so-it-can-keep-using-them-as-global-warming-mascot/">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/wwf-slaps-polar-bear-protection-bill/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wholesale Energy Prices Drop, Energy Bills Rise</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/wholesale-energy-prices-drop-energy-bills-rise/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/wholesale-energy-prices-drop-energy-bills-rise/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 06:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11265</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The average household bill has already risen eight per cent compared with the same time last year, while the cost of energy on the wholesale market has dropped. Families should brace for a further £100 rise in their energy bills within the next year, official figures suggest. The Office for Budget Responsibility predicts a seven [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The average household bill has already risen eight per cent compared with the same time last year, while the cost of energy on the wholesale market has dropped. Families should brace for a further £100 rise in their energy bills within the next year, official figures suggest.</strong></p>
<p>The Office for Budget Responsibility predicts a seven per cent rise in energy costs for families in winter this year and a three per cent rise the year after.</p>
<p>Average bills are currently £1,420 per family for gas and electricity, signalling an increase of £99 is on the way this year followed by a £46 rise in 2014.</p>
<p>The estimates were released along with George Osborne&#8217;s Budget as part of calculations about inflation.</p>
<p>The independent economic watchdog said higher energy costs would contribute to the rising cost of living, mostly driven by rising wholesale electricity and gas prices.</p>
<p>It said green taxes and other environmental policies would probably add two per cent to electricity bills and 0.5 per cent to gas bills annually until the year 2020.</p>
<p>The OBR predicted the costs of upgrading Britain&#8217;s electricity networks will also add around two per cent over several years. This is because companies need to connect new power stations and wind farms to the national grid as traditional fossil fuel plants are closed down.</p>
<p>The average household bill has already risen eight per cent compared with the same time last year, while the cost of energy on the wholesale market has dropped.</p>
<p>At the same time, energy companies are expected to make record profits from British homes over the coming year.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/politics/9946562/Energy-bills-to-rise-100-next-winter-official-forecasts-suggest.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/wholesale-energy-prices-drop-energy-bills-rise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Britain Faces Gas Supply Crisis As Storage Runs Dry</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/britain-faces-gas-supply-crisis-storage-runs-dry/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/britain-faces-gas-supply-crisis-storage-runs-dry/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 06:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11263</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Britain is grappling with a potential gas supply crisis as a late blast of winter depletes stored reserves, coal power plants close and pending maintenance in Norway threatens to further squeeze supply. The country risks running out of stored gas by April 8 based on the fall in its reserves seen since the cold hit [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain is grappling with a potential gas supply crisis as a late blast of winter depletes stored reserves, coal power plants close and pending maintenance in Norway threatens to further squeeze supply.</p>
<p>The country risks running out of stored gas by April 8 based on the fall in its reserves seen since the cold hit at the beginning of March, Reuters calculations show.</p>
<p>Gas storage sites have been depleted by 90 percent, with the equivalent of less than two days&#8217; consumption remaining, data from Gas Infrastructure Europe shows.</p>
<p>If the cold persists, as is forecast, the UK may need to cut gas supplies to some big industrial customers, as it did in 2010 at a time of severe gas shortages.</p>
<p>The Department of Energy and Climate Change (DECC) said it was monitoring the situation closely.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our market has spare import capacity built in. However, we take gas security and the risk of harmful price spikes seriously and monitor price and supply developments working closely with National Grid,&#8221; said Emily Towers, DECC&#8217;s spokeswoman responsible for energy supply and emergency planning.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are working with (the regulator) Ofgem to review our market arrangements &#8230;At the same time, we are diversifying our energy mix to reduce our dependence on imported fossil fuels and putting in place policies to cut energy demand.&#8221;</p>
<p>The rapid depletion of gas storage sites has prompted operator Centrica, Britain&#8217;s biggest power and gas provider, to restrict withdrawals owing to falling reservoir pressure, in a sign of the growing strain on the system.</p>
<p>Full story</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/britain-faces-gas-supply-crisis-storage-runs-dry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
