<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 11:11:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>EU Climate Policy: Below Junk Status</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/eu-climate-policy-junk-status/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/eu-climate-policy-junk-status/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 11:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11967</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The real question now is whether the scuppering of the ETS will lead to the dismantling of the EU’s climate policies more generally. EUROPE’S flagship environmental policy has just been holed below the water line. On April 16th the European Parliament voted by 334 to 315 to reject proposals which (its supporters claimed) were needed [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The real question now is whether the scuppering of the ETS will lead to the dismantling of the EU’s climate policies more generally.</p>
<p>EUROPE’S flagship environmental policy has just been holed below the water line. On April 16th the European Parliament voted by 334 to 315 to reject proposals which (its supporters claimed) were needed to save the emissions-trading system (ETS) from collapse. Carbon prices promptly fell 40% (see chart). Some environmentalists fear that the whole edifice of European climate policy could start to crumble.</p>
<div><img class="aligncenter" title="" alt="" src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/2013/04/blogs/schumpeter/20130420_woc453.png" width="290" height="299" /></div>
<p>The ETS has long been troubled. The scheme is the world’s biggest carbon market, trading allowances to produce carbon which cover about half the European Union’s total carbon emissions. Partly because of weak industrial demand and partly because the EU gave away too many allowances to pollute in the first place, there is massive oversupply in the carbon-emissions market. Prices fell from €20 a tonne in 2011 to just €5 a tonne in February 2013. The European Commission, the EU’s executive arm, therefore hatched a plan to take about 900m tonnes of carbon allowances off the market now and reintroduce them in about five years time when, it was hoped, demand would be stronger (“backloading” in the jargon). This was the proposal the European Parliament turned down.</p>
<p>The rejection was a surprise. The parliament’s environment committee had looked at the plan in February and approved it by a surprisingly wide margin of 38 votes to 25.</p>
<p>As expected, most members of the largest political alliance, the centre-right European People’s Party, voted against the proposal. This was needed, they argued, to protect consumers from higher energy bills. What came as a surprise is the fact  that all but four British conservative members of the European Parliament also voted against the plan. In doing so they defied their own government, which has introduced a carbon floor price in Britain that could soon be higher than the European carbon price. And the European Socialists, which had been expected mostly to back the proposals, instead split, with 44 in favour of the plan and 31 against.</p>
<p>In theory the proposal is not quite dead. In a fit of back-pedalling after the vote, the MEPs decided to send the issue back to the environment committee. From there it could come back to the full parliament again. Or the European Commission could come up with a bunch of new proposals. The EU sometimes works by creating a crisis and then stumbling through it—witness the euro crisis, <em>passim</em>. The trouble is that neither the parliamentary committee nor the commission can do anything much unless significant numbers of MEPs change their minds. The parliamentary vote was exceptionally well attended—a measure of its importance—and there were few wavering MEPs.</p>
<p>The real question now is whether the scuppering of the ETS will lead to the dismantling of the EU’s climate policies more generally.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/schumpeter/2013/04/carbon-trading">Full comment</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/eu-climate-policy-junk-status/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Carbon Crash: Vote Leaves EU Emissions Trading In Tatters</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/carbon-crash-vote-leaves-eu-emissions-trading-tatters/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/carbon-crash-vote-leaves-eu-emissions-trading-tatters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 10:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11963</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The European Union’s flagship program to fight global warming suffered a major blow Tuesday when lawmakers rejected a proposal aimed at shoring up the region’s carbon-emissions trading system, putting its survival in doubt. Germany’s Minister of Economic and Technology Philipp Rösler welcomed the rejection of the backloading plans as an “excellent signal” for an continuing economic [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The European Union’s flagship program to fight global warming suffered a major blow Tuesday when lawmakers rejected a proposal aimed at shoring up the region’s carbon-emissions trading system, putting its survival in doubt. Germany’s Minister of Economic and Technology Philipp Rösler welcomed the rejection of the backloading plans as an “excellent signal” for an continuing economic recovery.</strong></p>
<p>After the European Parliament’s surprise afternoon vote, spooked investors drove the price of emissions permits down by nearly half. Benchmark electricity prices also fell.</p>
<p>The legislature derailed—at least temporarily—a plan to push up permit prices by postponing issuance of new permits for between five and seven years. Electricity generators and others must buy the permits in order to emit carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>Europe’s so-called Emissions Trading System, first launched in 2008, was designed to raise the cost of polluting and discourage the production of greenhouse gases to protect the environment.</p>
<p>But lately, politicians’ focus on generating jobs and sparking growth in a region struggling to recover from recession is relegating green concerns to second place behind economics.</p>
<p>“It was a vote of reason,” said Poland’s environment minister, Marcin Korolec. Poland, one of the EU’s less-affluent members, has been outspoken in its opposition to the measure, which it said could hamper development.</p>
<p>The parliament’s Environment Committee after the vote said that some lawmakers felt that “a rise in the carbon price would erode the competitiveness of European industry and be passed on in household energy bills.”</p>
<p>Germany’s Minister of Economic and Technology Philipp Rösler welcomed the rejection of the backloading plans as an “excellent signal” for an continuing economic recovery. “Reducing supply CO2 allowances would equate to an intervention into a functioning market system,” and further burden industry, he said.</p>
<p>The EU’s executive arm, the European Commission, which devised the so-called backloading plan, said it regretted parliament’s move. And the EU’s Council of Environment Ministers said it would try to draw up an alternate plan.</p>
<p>“Today’s vote is a historic failure,” said Joris den Blanken, EU climate policy director at environmental advocacy group Greenpeace. Without action to deal with an oversupply of permits, the trading system won’t “dissuade polluters and promote investments in cleaner production.”</p>
<p>Slack demand for electricity and an abundance of permits in the market helped push the price of emitting a ton of carbon below 5 euros earlier this year, down from nearly €30 in 2008. After the vote, the price dropped to €2.55 before recovering partially to €3.2.</p>
<p>Without the backloading plan to increase scarcity on the emissions permit market, “the ETS will almost certainly collapse,” said Kash Burchett, a London-based analyst at consulting company IHS Energy.</p>
<p>“Prices will likely sink below €1 per ton as participants recognize that there is no political will at present to restore the market mechanism to functioning order,” he said.</p>
<p><a href="http://stream.wsj.com/story/latest-headlines/SS-2-63399/SS-2-212666/">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/carbon-crash-vote-leaves-eu-emissions-trading-tatters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Global Warming Slowdown Is Baffling Scientists Across The Globe</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/global-warming-slowdown-baffling-scientists-globe/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/global-warming-slowdown-baffling-scientists-globe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 10:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Climate Record]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11960</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Scientists are struggling to explain a slowdown in climate change that has exposed gaps in their understanding and defies a rise in global greenhouse gas emissions. Often focused on century-long trends, most climate models failed to predict that the temperature rise would slow, starting around 2000. Scientists are now intent on figuring out the causes and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Scientists are struggling to explain a slowdown in climate change that has exposed gaps in their understanding and defies a rise in global greenhouse gas emissions. Often focused on century-long trends, most climate models failed to predict that the temperature rise would slow, starting around 2000.</strong></p>
<p>Scientists are now intent on figuring out the causes and determining whether the respite will be brief or a more lasting phenomenon.</p>
<p>Getting this right is essential for the short and long-term planning of governments and businesses ranging from energy to construction, from agriculture to insurance.</p>
<p>Many scientists say they expect a revival of warming in coming years.</p>
<p>Theories for the pause include that deep oceans have taken up more heat with the result that the surface is cooler than expected, that industrial pollution in Asia or clouds are blocking the sun, or that greenhouse gases trap less heat than previously believed.</p>
<p>The change may be a result of an observed decline in heat-trapping water vapor in the high atmosphere, for unknown reasons.</p>
<p>It could be a combination of factors or some as yet unknown natural variations, scientists say.</p>
<p>Weak economic growth and the pause in warming is undermining governments&#8217; willingness to make a rapid billion-dollar shift from fossil fuels.</p>
<p>Almost 200 governments have agreed to work out a plan by the end of 2015 to combat global warming.</p>
<p>&#8216;The climate system is not quite so simple as people thought,&#8217; said Bjorn Lomborg, a Danish statistician and author of &#8216;The Skeptical Environmentalist&#8217; who estimates that moderate warming will be beneficial for crop growth and human health.</p>
<p>Some experts say their trust in climate science has declined because of the many uncertainties.</p>
<p>The UN&#8217;s Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) had to correct a 2007 report that exaggerated the pace of melt of the Himalayan glaciers and wrongly said they could all vanish by 2035.</p>
<p>&#8216;My own confidence in the data has gone down in the past five years,&#8217; said Richard Tol, an expert in climate change and professor of economics at the University of Sussex in England.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-2309917/The-climate-change-slowdown-baffling-scientists.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/global-warming-slowdown-baffling-scientists-globe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU Carbon Collapse Deals Blow To Australia</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/eu-carbon-collapse-deals-blow-australia/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/eu-carbon-collapse-deals-blow-australia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 10:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11958</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[Australia's Labor Government] will revise down its carbon tax revenue estimates following a crash in the European carbon market, at a likely multi-billion dollar cost to the federal budget. The EU&#8217;s carbon price sank to 2.55 euros ($A3.24) in trading overnight, as legislators rejected a proposal to save the market from collapse. The federal budget [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>[Australia's Labor Government] will revise down its carbon tax revenue estimates following a crash in the European carbon market, at a likely multi-billion dollar cost to the federal budget.</strong></p>
<p>The EU&#8217;s carbon price sank to 2.55 euros ($A3.24) in trading overnight, as legislators rejected a proposal to save the market from collapse.</p>
<p>The federal budget currently assumes a $29 carbon price in 2015, when Australia&#8217;s carbon trading scheme is linked to the EU carbon market.</p>
<p>Climate Change Minister Greg Combet told the ABC: “We will continue with our plans to link with the European emissions trading scheme from 1 July 2015, which is still over two years away.</p>
<p>“But this year&#8217;s budget, as is usual practice by Treasury, will include a revised forecast for a carbon price in 2015-16 in Australia.”</p>
<p>He said the carbon revenue slump “is another way the global financial crisis has hit the budget”.</p>
<p>Much of the revenue from the carbon tax is pumped out into the economy in the form of household compensation.</p>
<p>The EU carbon price peaked at nearly 30 euros in 2008, but an abundance of permits and weak demand for electricity as a result of the European recession has pushed down the price down.</p>
<p>Yesterday, the price dropped below 3 euros before recovering partially to 3.20 euros.</p>
<p>Opposition climate action spokesman Greg Hunt said the fluctuating carbon price in Europe showed Australia would be linking its scheme to a “deeply unstable” system.</p>
<p>Australia&#8217;s carbon tax was five and a half times higher than the European tax, and completely out of step with the rest of the world, he said.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/climate/eu-carbon-collapse-deals-blow-to-australia/story-e6frg6xf-1226622388327">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/eu-carbon-collapse-deals-blow-australia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU Refuses To Resuscitate Its Dying Carbon Market</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/eu-refuses-resuscitate-dying-carbon-market/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/eu-refuses-resuscitate-dying-carbon-market/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 09:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11955</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The EU has been the global laboratory testing the green agenda to see how it works. Yesterday’s story means that the guinea pig died; the most important piece of green intervention in world history has become an expensive and embarrassing flop.  It’s hard to exaggerate the importance of this for environmentalists everywhere; if the EU [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The EU has been the global laboratory testing the green agenda to see how it works. Yesterday’s story means that the guinea pig died; the most important piece of green intervention in world history has become an expensive and embarrassing flop.  It’s hard to exaggerate the importance of this for environmentalists everywhere; if the EU can’t make the green agenda work, it’s unlikely that anybody else will give it a try.</strong></p>
<p>The European Parliament just voted down a measure that would have attempted to revive its carbon market, likely dooming it to a slow and undignified death. This was a last-ditch effort to drive the EU’s carbon price back to a level that would incentivize green reforms. And it failed.</p>
<p>The EU’s carbon market was the flagship program of its recent green efforts. Ideally, it would have given companies a reason to emit less carbon. Companies that emitted less than allowed could have sold off remaining carbon credits to firms that emitted more. But the authorities gave out too many credits, and as Europe’s economy faltered the price for those credits plummeted. The vote today was meant to save the program by addressing this over-allocation, creating an artificial shortage that would drive permit prices back up, but in a time of financial crisis, the European Parliament chose industry over green ideology. The <em>WSJ </em><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887324030704578426280702003120.html?mod=wsj_nview_latest">reports</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>“It was a vote of reason,” said Poland’s environment minister, Marcin Korolec. Poland, one of the EU’s less-affluent members, has been outspoken in its opposition to the measure, which it said could hamper development. [...]</p>
<p>After the vote, the price [of carbon credits] dropped to €2.55 before recovering partially to €3.2…down from nearly €30 in 2008.</p>
<p>Without the backloading plan to increase scarcity on the emissions permit market, “the ETS will almost certainly collapse,” said Kash Burchett, a London-based analyst at consulting company IHS Energy.</p></blockquote>
<p>The EU has been the global laboratory testing the green agenda to see how it works. Today’s story means that the guinea pig died; the most important piece of green intervention in world history has become an expensive and embarrassing flop.  It’s hard to exaggerate the importance of this for environmentalists everywhere; if the EU can’t make the green agenda work, it’s unlikely that anybody else will give it a try.</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.the-american-interest.com/wrm/2013/04/16/eu-refuses-to-resuscitate-its-dying-carbon-market/">Via Meadia, 16 April 2013</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/eu-refuses-resuscitate-dying-carbon-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU Climate Change Policy In Crisis After MEPs Vote Against High CO2 Prices</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/eu-climate-change-policy-crisis-meps-vote-high-co2-prices/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/eu-climate-change-policy-crisis-meps-vote-high-co2-prices/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 13:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11952</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The European Union&#8217;s climate change policy is on the brink of collapse today after MEPs torpedoed Europe&#8217;s flagship CO2 emissions trading scheme by voting against a measure to support the price of carbon permits. The price of carbon crashed up to 45 per cent to a record-low €2.63 a metric ton, after the European Parliament [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The European Union&#8217;s climate change policy is on the brink of collapse today after MEPs torpedoed Europe&#8217;s flagship CO2 emissions trading scheme by voting against a measure to support the price of carbon permits.</strong></p>
<div>
<p>The price of carbon crashed up to 45 per cent to a record-low €2.63 a metric ton, after the European Parliament rejected a proposal to change the EU emissions-trading laws to delay the sale of 900m CO2 permits on the world&#8217;s biggest carbon markets.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>The European Commission measure, known as &#8220;backloading&#8221; was aimed at artificially raising the price of EU carbon permits by restricting supply after they fell to a record low in January due the economic slowdown and contraction in manufacturing across Europe.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>The rejection of the measure is expected to trigger further falls in the price of carbon, to as low as €1 and could herald the end of an EU system which was aimed encouraging investment in &#8220;clean&#8221; technologies by pricing high CO2 emissions from smokestack industry or coal-fired power plants out of the market.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>MEPs were deeply divided over the proposal, with 334 voting against and 315 in favour, in a debate that pitted support of economic growth during a recession against defenders of climate change policies that punish manufacturing industry for producing CO2.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/newsbysector/energy/9997868/EU-climate-change-policy-in-crisis-after-MEPs-vote-against-high-CO2-prices.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/eu-climate-change-policy-crisis-meps-vote-high-co2-prices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conn Carroll: Fracking Revolution Vs Green Energy Failure</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/conn-carroll-fracking-revolution-green-energy-failure/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/conn-carroll-fracking-revolution-green-energy-failure/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11944</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[U.S. liberals often make light of conservative claims that the free market is perfectly capable of solving problems and creating wealth without government planning. But that is exactly what fracking has done for the U.S. economy. For years, liberal efforts to unite around a green energy agenda had run into strong opposition from the labor [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>U.S. liberals often make light of conservative claims that the free market is perfectly capable of solving problems and creating wealth without government planning. But that is exactly what fracking has done for the U.S. economy.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;" data-mce-mark="1">For years, liberal efforts to unite around a green energy agenda had run into strong opposition from the labor wing of the progressive movement, which still included significant numbers of manufacturing, mining and transportation workers who depended on affordable fossil fuels for their livelihoods.</span></p>
<p>But by 2008, these traditional blue-collar unions were no longer the driving force of organized labor. Right-to-work laws and international competition had driven many unionized companies out of business, while the numbers of government and service-sector union members (think DMV clerks and Vegas maids) had exploded.</p>
<div id="newsletter-signup-opinion"></div>
<p>Suddenly cheap energy was no longer a union priority. Enter the Apollo Alliance, which is a project of the George Soros-funded Tides Foundation. Apollo forged a new labor/environmentalist that would both limit fossil fuel use and spend billions promoting green energy.</p>
<p>Since renamed the BlueGreen Alliance, the group launched with a report calling for $500 billion in spending to create a &#8220;New Apollo Program&#8221; for the U.S. economy. It included federal subsidies for green car companies and solar firms, cash to make existing buildings energy-efficient, new power line construction and billions for new mass transit systems.</p>
<p>The New Apollo Program called for a cap-and-trade plan designed to drive energy producers away from fossil fuels and toward renewable energy like solar, wind and biomass. Apollo promised these new initiatives would create 5 million new jobs.</p>
<p>The Obama campaign fully embraced the Apollo vision, producing its own New Energy for America document that largely mirrored the Apollo report. The only real difference was that Obama&#8217;s plan created 5 million new green economy jobs for just $150 billion.</p>
<p>Of course, Obama ended up spending far more than that after he was elected. And he has come nowhere close to meeting his 5 million job promise.</p>
<p>Many of the car and solar companies Obama invested in (like Fister and Solyndra) are either bankrupt or on their way there. His energy-efficiency programs have been so ineffective that even the liberal host of &#8220;The Daily Show,&#8221; Jon Stewart, has made them the butt of jokes.</p>
<p>And Obama&#8217;s signature transportation project, high-speed rail, was not only rejected by Florida, Ohio and Wisconsin, but in the one state where it has been pursued, California, not a single mile of track has yet been laid.</p>
<p>Four years into the Obama presidency, it is safe to say that the progressive plan to remake the U.S. economy has failed.</p>
<p>Not that today&#8217;s energy sector looks at all like it did when Obama was first sworn into office. There has been a transformation of American energy production under Obama, but it has happened despite his policies, not because of them.</p>
<p>No union/environmentalist central planner set out to create hundreds of thousands of new jobs by perfecting new methods of extracting shale oil and gas from rocks thousands of feet beneath the surface. But that is exactly what the private sector has done. A recent IHS Global Insight report found the fracking industry supported 1.7 million jobs in 2012 alone. [...]</p>
<p><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://washingtonexaminer.com/conn-carroll-fracking-revolutionized-american-energy-as-green-energy-failed/article/2527040">Full comment</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/conn-carroll-fracking-revolution-green-energy-failure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biofuels: &#8216;Irrational&#8217; And &#8216;Worse Than Fossil Fuels&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/biofuels-irrational-worse-fossil-fuels/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/biofuels-irrational-worse-fossil-fuels/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11941</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The UK&#8217;s &#8220;irrational&#8221; use of biofuels will cost motorists around £460 million over the next 12 months, a think tank says. A report by Chatham House says the growing reliance on sustainable liquid fuels will also increase food prices. The author says that biodiesel made from vegetable oil was worse for the climate than fossil fuels. Under [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="story_continues_1"><strong>The UK&#8217;s &#8220;irrational&#8221; use of biofuels will cost motorists around £460 million over the next 12 months, a think tank says.</strong></p>
<p>A <a href="http://www.chathamhouse.org/sites/default/files/public/Research/Energy,%20Environment%20and%20Development/0413pp_biofuels.pdf">report by Chatham House</a> says the growing reliance on sustainable liquid fuels will also increase food prices.</p>
<p>The author says that biodiesel made from vegetable oil was worse for the climate than fossil fuels.</p>
<p>Under EU <a href="http://ec.europa.eu/energy/renewables/biofuels/biofuels_en.htm">law</a>, biofuels are set to make up 5% of the UK&#8217;s transport fuel from today.</p>
<div><span style="font-size: 13px;">Since 2008, the UK has required fuel suppliers to add a growing proportion of sustainable materials into the petrol and diesel they supply. These biofuels are mainly ethanol distilled from corn and biodiesel made from rapeseed, used cooking oil and tallow.</span></div>
<p><strong>Deep fried fuel</strong></p>
<p>But research carried out for Chatham House says that reaching the 5% level means that UK motorists will have to pay an extra £460m a year because of the higher cost of fuel at the pump and from filling up more often as biofuels have a lower energy content.</p>
<p>The report say that if the UK is to meet its obligations to EU energy targets the cost to motorists is likely to rise to £1.3bn per annum by 2020.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is hard to find any good news,&#8221; Rob Bailey, senior research fellow at Chatham House, told BBC News.</p>
<p>&#8220;Biofuels increase costs and they are a very expensive way to reduce carbon emissions,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The EU biofuel mandates are also having hugely distorting effects in the marketplace. Because used cooking oil is regarded as one of the most sustainable types of biodiesel, the price for it has risen rapidly. Rob Bailey says that towards the end of 2012 it was more expensive than refined palm oil.</p>
<p>&#8220;It creates a financial incentive to buy refined palm oil, cook a chip in it to turn it into used cooking oil and then sell it at profit,&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It is crazy but the incentives are there.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-22127123">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/biofuels-irrational-worse-fossil-fuels/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Last Year’s U.S. Drought Wasn’t Caused By Climate Change</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/years-u-s-drought-wasnt-caused-climate-change/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/years-u-s-drought-wasnt-caused-climate-change/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 10:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11934</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Those advocating limits on greenhouse gases can’t count on the weather to make their argument. Last summer, in response to an intense and prolonged drought in the U.S.—the worst, indeed, since 1895—we ran an interview with a climate scientist, Thomas Karl, director of the National Climatic Data Center in Asheville, North Carolina. He said that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<header><strong>Those advocating limits on greenhouse gases can’t count on the weather to make their argument.</strong></header>
<header></header>
<header>Last summer, in response to an intense and prolonged drought in the U.S.—the worst, indeed, since 1895—we ran an interview with a climate scientist, Thomas Karl, director of the National Climatic Data Center in Asheville, North Carolina. He said that droughts in general will be exacerbated by climate change, while noting that it’s difficult to link any particular drought to greenhouse gases. “I suspect it will be really difficult to show how much these changing patterns contributed to the drought in the Midwest this year,” he said (see “Is Climate Change to Blame for the Current U.S. Drought?”).Karl was right about the difficulty of linking a particular event to climate change.</header>
<header></header>
<header>A new study from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration provides an assessment of last year’s drought, and concludes that “human-induced climate change” did not play a significant role. It attributes the drought to natural variations, including fewer than normal thunderstorms and a change in the movement of air that redirected moist air from the Gulf of Mexico away from the Midwest, things that can happen without global warming. The report also says that climate models did not predict the drought.The report concluded that, specifically regarding the impact of global warming on precipitation in the Midwest, “the signal of climate change may be very small compared to the noise of the intrinsic year-to-year variability. Detectability of a global warming signal in the statistics of summertime Great Plains rainfall may thus be very difficult at this time.”Until the earth warms a lot more than it has already, it’s going to continue to be difficult to read the effects of climate change in the weather. Weather is too variable. There will continue to be very cold weather that will boost the popularity of climate skeptics and very hot or volatile weather—like Hurricane Sandy—that will serve to make global warming seem more plausible. The decision about what to do, or not do, about climate change will ultimately depend on how much people believe climate models’ predictions of a markedly different world in the future that we’ll see only limited—and often ambiguous—evidence of in the present.</p>
</header>
<header></header>
<section><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.technologyreview.com/view/513646/last-years-us-drought-wasnt-caused-by-climate-change"><span style="color: #0000ff;">MIT Technology Review, 12 April 2013</span></a></span></section>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/years-u-s-drought-wasnt-caused-climate-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Natural Gas Battle In The Mediterranean</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/natural-gas-battle-mediterranean/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/natural-gas-battle-mediterranean/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 10:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11929</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Europe is to a large extent dependent on Russian gas supplied by Gazprom. A quarter of Europe&#8217;s entire gas consumption is provided by Gazprom. As a new player in the market of gas exporters, Cyprus could reduce the European dependency on Russian gas. Golda Meir once quipped that Moses could have done the Jewish people [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Europe is to a large extent dependent on Russian gas supplied by Gazprom. A quarter of Europe&#8217;s entire gas consumption is provided by Gazprom. As a new player in the market of gas exporters, Cyprus could reduce the European dependency on Russian gas.</strong></p>
<p>Golda Meir once quipped that Moses could have done the Jewish people a better service. “He took us 40 years through the desert,” she said, “to bring us to the one spot in the Middle East that has no oil.”</p>
<p>Today, Golda Meir’s quip has lost its punch. Last week, natural gas began flowing out of the Tamar gas field, discovered off the coast of Israel in January 2009. Tamar and Leviathan, its neighboring gas field, discovered in June 2010, are among the world’s largest recent offshore natural gas discoveries. The Israeli companies controlling the fields are even considering exporting gas to neighboring countries.</p>
<p>Geologists assume that commercial oil reserves may lie beneath the gas find. Some analysts say that the Tamar and Leviathan fields might change Israel’s position in the geopolitical and energy world. But not just Israel’s.</p>
<p>The Israeli fields are adjacent to the Aphrodite gas field, discovered in December 2011, which lies in Cypriot territorial waters, less than 25 miles west of Leviathan. The government in Nicosia expects that the result of offshore drillings will confirm later this year that the island is sitting on vast amounts of natural gas worth billions of dollars. The recent banking crisis in Cyprus –the latest episode in the saga of the collapsing euro – came too early for the country to benefit from its future natural gas wealth. It is, however, indicative that Cyprus turned down the European Union’s demands that the gas reserves be used as collateral for the loans which the E.U. has just extended to Cyprus.</p>
<p>Brussels had demanded that a fund be created in which it was given a direct say over the revenues from Cypriot gas reserves, but Nicosia refused to do so. The Cypriots feel betrayed by the E.U. Hence, they are not inclined to let Europe share in the future wealth which they hope to derive from gas. Nicos Anastasiades, the president of Cyprus, said that Cyprus had no other choice than give in to the harsh demand of Brussels that it dismantle its banking sector. He, however, promised that savers who lost money in the Cypriotic banks would be compensated by being given shares in banks guaranteed by the future natural gas revenues.</p>
<p>Today, Cyprus is paying a very heavy price for its membership of the E.U.’s common currency, the euro. When by 2019 the gas proceeds are expected to start flowing, the tables will be turned. Then Cyprus will be in a position to leave the euro without facing the prospect of national bankruptcy.</p>
<p>To begin extracting the gas from the Aphrodite field by 2019, however, the virtually bankrupt Cypriot government will in the coming years need to make enormous investments. The Russian state-owned gas company Gazprom, the largest extractor of natural gas in the world, seems <a href="http://greece.greekreporter.com/2013/03/18/gazprom-offers-cyprus-restructuring-deal-to-avoid-eu-bailout/">keen to get involved</a>. So far, however, the Cypriots have kept the Russians at bay.</p>
<p>Europe is already to a large extent <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2009/jan/02/russia-ukraine-gazprom">dependent</a> on Russian gas, supplied by Gazprom, a company controlled by the Russian oligarchy around President Putin. A quarter of Europe’s of Europe’s entire gas consumption comes from Gazprom. As a new player in the market of gas exporters, Cyprus could reduce the European dependency on Russian gas.</p>
<p>What applies to Cyprus, obviously, applies to Israel as well. It, too, could use its gas exports to a political end. Bat Ye’or has argued that the pro-Palestinian positions of the European governments since the 1970s were to a large extent the result of Europe’s dependency on Arab oil. Israel has a unique chance of also using the Cypriot gas to its own geostrategic benefit. The Cypriot gas fields are located halfway between the Cypriot and Israeli coast. Israel, Cyprus and Greece are already collaborating in the EuroAsia Interconnector project, which is an undersea power cable linking Israel with Cyprus and Cyprus with Greece. A gas pipeline following the same route would balance the current pipeline on the Baltic seabed linking Russia with Germany.</p>
<p>Another opportunity for Israel might be the fact that some international gas companies are reluctant to get involved in the exploitation of Cypriot gas fields because they also operate in Turkey and do not want to upset the Turkish authorities who oppose the Cypriot gas extraction. Though the Aphrodite gas field lies in waters across Southern Cyprus, Turkey is demanding that all gas revenues be shared with Turkish occupied Northern Cyprus.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.gatestoneinstitute.org/3660/israel-natural-gas">Full comment</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/natural-gas-battle-mediterranean/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
