<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 11:16:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Europe Could Miss Out On Shale Gas Revolution</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-shale-gas-revolution/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-shale-gas-revolution/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 11:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11387</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[European industries and some European governments have recently begun to recognise that the unconventional gas revolution is no longer confined to North America, but is spreading globally. The rapidly expanding production of shale gas has transformed the United States from being the world’s largest import market of liquefied natural gas (LNG) to a self-sustaining gas [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>European industries and some European governments have recently begun to recognise that the unconventional gas revolution is no longer confined to North America, but is spreading globally.</strong></p>
<p>The rapidly expanding production of shale gas has transformed the United States from being the world’s largest import market of liquefied natural gas (LNG) to a self-sustaining gas producer and a net gas exporter.</p>
<p>In 2009 the US overtook Russia as the world’s largest gas producer. In 2010 it overtook Qatari gas production as the world’s largest LNG exporter by about 60 per cent.</p>
<p>The sudden gas glut since 2009, from an overcapacity of LNG, stems from a combination of three factors: a drop in demand linked to the global economic recession; an unexpected dramatic increase in American shale gas production; and new global LNG delivery capacity.</p>
<p>LNG is now less expensive in Europe than pipeline gas for long-term contracts.</p>
<p>The development of unconventional gas in the US since 2006 has not only triggered a revolution in US energy markets, it has also become the tipping point for fundamental change in global gas markets.</p>
<p>It has laid the groundwork for an expanded role of natural gas in the world economy.</p>
<p>The International Energy Agency (IEA) has said that the world is set to experience a ‘Golden Age of Gas’ in which unconventional gas has already become a ‘game changer’.</p>
<p>Some countries in Europe &#8211; including Poland, the United Kingdom, Lithuania and Ukraine &#8211; and China and Australia, have shown interest in exploiting their own unconventional gas resources.</p>
<p>But potential environmental risks have swayed other countries into adopting moratoria or outright bans on the production of shale gas, and particularly on fracking, the process of hydraulic fracturing to get gas out of the ground.</p>
<p>The IEA predicts that nearly half the increase in global gas production up to 2035 will come from unconventional gas, if the industry receives a ‘social licence to operate’ within stringent regulatory regimes to satisfy public environmental and social concerns.</p>
<p>The US is debating whether to export shale gas to Europe and Asia from 2015.</p>
<p>But there are some new strategic developments on the European gas market which could also affect energy security.</p>
<p>One is the predicted stagnation of gas demand up to 2020, rather than a significant rise previously forecast.</p>
<p>Other factors include: the expansion of new LNG terminals in Poland, the Baltic States, Croatia and other countries; new gas interconnectors with reverse flow capacities in central and southeastern Europe; and the impact of the liberalisation and unbundling (the separation of prices for goods and services) processes within the EU-27.</p>
<p>The decline in US domestic coal consumption as a result of the coal-to-gas switch also opens the prospect of it becoming a leading coal exporter, reaching 500 mt (million tonnes) per year by 2030, to Europe, Asia and other regions.</p>
<p>The rising volume of relatively cheap coal imports from the US to Europe in 2012 has reduced Europe’s consumption of gas. It has also led to higher greenhouse gas emissions and put Europe at odds with EU climate and energy policies.</p>
<p>But the energy revolution is also having a big impact on the overall economic competitiveness of the US economy and industries towards rivals in Asia and Europe.</p>
<p>Development of unconventional gas reserves in the US has increased foreign direct investment (FDI), created hundreds of thousands of new jobs, dramatically reduced energy prices for industry and helped to strengthen energy diversification.</p>
<p>Europe’s energy-intensive industries, such as the chemical industry, have become increasingly concerned that the gas glut in the US has reduced natural gas prices there by more than two-thirds since 2008.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.naturalgaseurope.com/pdfs/GIS%2040%20-%20Shale%20Gas%20Europe%20Update%20I%20190313.pdf">Full story</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-shale-gas-revolution/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inexhaustible Energy: Uranium From Seawater Is Over 3000 Times The Energy Of Methane Hydrates In Oceans</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/inexaustible-energy-uranium-seawater-3000-times-energy-methane-hydrates-oceans/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/inexaustible-energy-uranium-seawater-3000-times-energy-methane-hydrates-oceans/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 11:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11383</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Japan has extracted gas from offshore deposits of methane hydrate — sometimes called “flammable ice” — a breakthrough that officials and experts said could be a step toward tapping a promising but still little-understood energy source. Japan hopes to make methane hydrate commercially viable in 5 years. With specialized equipment, the team drilled into and then lowered the pressure in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/13/business/global/japan-says-it-is-first-to-tap-methane-hydrate-deposit.html?pagewanted=1&amp;_r=4&amp;" target="blank">Japan has extracted gas from offshore deposits of methane hydrate — sometimes</a> called “flammable ice” — a breakthrough that officials and experts said could be a step toward tapping a promising but still little-understood energy source. Japan hopes to make methane hydrate commercially viable in 5 years.<br />
With specialized equipment, the team drilled into and then lowered the pressure in the undersea methane hydrate reserve, causing the methane and ice to separate. It then piped the natural gas to the surface. The surrounding area in the Nankai submarine trough holds at least 1.1 trillion cubic meters, or 39 trillion cubic feet, of methane hydrate, enough to meet 11 years’ worth of gas imports to Japan.</p>
<p>A separate rough estimate by the National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology has put the total amount of methane hydrate in the water surrounding Japan at more than 7 trillion cubic meters, or what researchers have long said is closer to 100 years’ worth of Japan’s natural gas needs.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.cfm?id=8690" target="blank">The EIA estimates the naturally occurring gas hydrate resource vary from 10,000 trillion cubic feet to more than 100,000 trillion cubic feet of natural gas. </a>The 100,000 trillion cf would be an energy resource of 105,000 EJ. Tapping such resources would require significant additional research and technological improvements</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mcgill.ca/files/gec3/NuclearFissionFuelisInexhaustibleIEEE.pdf" target="blank">There is about 4.4 billion tons of uranium in seawater.</a> Deep burn nuclear fission (where reactors that can burn all of the uranium for energy) would enable 217 million EJ of <a href="http://nextbigfuture.com/2012/09/path-to-affordable-uranium-from-seawater.html">energy to be produced.</a></p>
<p><a href="http://nextbigfuture.com/2013/03/uranium-from-seawater-is-over-200-times.html">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/inexaustible-energy-uranium-seawater-3000-times-energy-methane-hydrates-oceans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Andrew Orlowski: The UK Energy Crisis In 3 Simple Pictures</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/andrew-orlowski-uk-energy-crisis-3-simple-pictures/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/andrew-orlowski-uk-energy-crisis-3-simple-pictures/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 10:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11378</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s no shortage of blame to go round in the UK Energy Crisis. But it should be noted that our finest climate experts consistently forecast warmer and milder winters than we have experienced. &#8220;Children just aren&#8217;t going to know what snow is,&#8221; one expert predicted in 2000. The politicians have prioritised accordingly They say a picture is worth [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>There&#8217;s no shortage of blame to go round in the UK Energy Crisis. But it should be noted that our finest climate experts consistently forecast warmer and milder winters than we have experienced. &#8220;Children just aren&#8217;t going to know what snow is,&#8221; one expert predicted in 2000. The politicians have prioritised accordingly</strong></p>
<p>They say a picture is worth a thousand words. If that’s true, we’re about to save you reading 3,000. The UK is running out of gas. Very rapidly indeed. So much so, that shortly after Easter cuts and rationing may be introduced, with industrial users and hospitals getting preferential treatment.</p>
<p>This month is the coldest March in years, and thus the UK’s gas fuel stores have run down to 10 per cent of the nation&#8217;s capacity. A year ago it was 49 per cent. While other countries have hundreds of days of supply, the UK has tens. According to <a href="http://uk.reuters.com/article/2013/03/21/uk-britain-gas-supply-crisis-idUKBRE92K0T120130321" target="_blank">Reuters</a>, stores of gas will run out by 8 April at this rate.</p>
<p>The following graphics come from the National Grid, which <a href="http://www.nationalgrid.com/uk/Gas/Data/MNReport/" target="_blank">disseminates its operational data</a> online on a daily basis. Since 2005, the National Grid has been obliged to publish supply-level monitors, called safety monitors, and &#8220;take action to ensure that storage stocks do not fall below the defined levels&#8221;. Here’s the first picture, illustrating our dwindling gas stocks.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://regmedia.co.uk/2013/03/22/ng_safety_monitor_requirement.png"><img alt="Gas stores" src="http://regmedia.co.uk/2013/03/22/ng_safety_monitor_requirement.png" width="520" height="229" /></a></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;">The amount of gas in storage over time since last October</span></div>
<p>And another below, showing our usage and the delivery of gas. All the graphs <a href="http://www.nationalgrid.com/NR/rdonlyres/0D0D463E-059D-4704-8A76-73C26A26ADB3/57056/StorageMonitorsSeptember2012.pdf" target="_blank">are explained here</a>[PDF].</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://regmedia.co.uk/2013/03/22/delivery_safety_monitor.png" target="_blank"><img alt="Delivery Safety Monitor chart" src="http://regmedia.co.uk/2013/03/22/delivery_safety_monitor.png" width="520" height="226" /></a></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;">How much gas the country needs and is delivered</span></div>
<p>And more information on the accessibility of various gas stocks and the gradual downward trend in storage: in this chart, SRS is short-term reserve storage, MRS is medium-term, and LRS long-term.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://regmedia.co.uk/2013/03/22/supply_history.png" target="_blank"><img alt="UK gas supply history" src="http://regmedia.co.uk/2013/03/22/supply_history.png" width="520" height="225" /></a></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;">The UK&#8217;s gas supply history over time [...]</span></div>
<p>The timing is exquisite. On Saturday, &#8220;Earth Hour&#8221; was held globally at 8.30pm local time. It&#8217;s an annual stunt dreamed up by a PR agency for the eco pressure group <a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2012/05/16/wwf_living_planet_report/">WWF</a>. During Earth Hour people are encouraged to voluntarily turn out their lights – &#8220;to <a href="http://www.burson-marsteller.com/Innovation_and_insights/Case_Studies/Lists/CaseStudies/DispForm.aspx?ID=91&amp;nodeName=Case%20Studies" target="_blank">raise climate change raise awareness</a>&#8221; and think of Gaia. [...]</p>
<p>There&#8217;s no shortage of blame to go round in the UK Energy Crisis. But it should be noted that our finest climate experts consistently forecast warmer and milder winters than we have experienced. &#8220;Children just aren&#8217;t going to know what snow is,&#8221; one expert <a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/environment/snowfalls-are-now-just-a-thing-of-the-past-724017.html" target="_blank">predicted</a> in 2000.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2013/03/25/uk_energy_crisis_illustrated/">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/andrew-orlowski-uk-energy-crisis-3-simple-pictures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Die Welt: &#8220;Scientists Warn Of Ice Age&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/die-welt-scientists-warn-ice-age/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/die-welt-scientists-warn-ice-age/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 08:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11375</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The lethal “100-year, record-smashing” spring cold and snow spreading across Europe over the past month has for the most part been avoided like the plague by Germany’s mainstream media. The silence over the record cold and frost, which has killed thousands and cost billions, has been ear-ringing. Yet some leading dailies are breaking ranks, and have begun [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The lethal “100-year, record-smashing” spring cold and snow spreading across Europe over the past month has for the most part been avoided like the plague by Germany’s mainstream media. The silence over the record cold and frost, which has killed thousands and cost billions, has been ear-ringing.</strong></p>
<p>Yet some leading dailies are breaking ranks, and have begun to examine the phenomenon critically and openly.</p>
<p>For example veteran journalist at German flagship daily <strong>Die Welt</strong> today has stunned the rest of the German mainstream media with a piece titled <a href="http://www.welt.de/print/die_welt/vermischtes/article114733276/Wissenschaftler-warnen-vor-Eiszeit.html">Scientists warn of ice age</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img title="Logo_die_Welt_svg" alt="" src="http://kaltesonne.de/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Logo_die_Welt_svg.png" width="248" height="38" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>German flagship daily reports that “scientists warning of ice age.” Logo: DIE WELT.</em></p>
<p>Kulke writes that recently a growing number of scientific publications have been appearing in leading journals, and that they have been challenging the simplistic “<em>one dimensional CO2 explanation</em>” for climate change and showing that even the unlikely “<em>doubling of atmospheric CO2 concentration by 2050 would not have dramatic effects</em>.”</p>
<p>Kulke writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>Yet, papers with such content, even though they have passed the peer-review process, do not make any headlines. But they have been becoming much more frequent recently.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Increasingly it seems more and more scientists are now seeing huge opportunity in overturning one of the most ballyhooed scientific hypotheses of modern time, funding be damned.</p>
<p>In the <em>Die Welt </em>piece, Kulke asks if the record cold and snow over much of the northern hemisphere “<em>is just a coincidence</em>“. The odds are increasing that it is not, and that it’s not for nothing that a growing number of scientists are becoming friendly to other explanations and that the body of evidence supporting a combination of explanations is taking shape quickly. Kulke writes that it is therefore no surprise that 2 Russian scientists have recently joined the ever more thunderous chorus of alternative explanations on what drives climate. He writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>It’s probably no coincidence that ever louder scientific opinions warning of an imminent ice period are coming also from Russia. Vladimir Baschkin and Rauf Galiulin have recently recognized the ice age possibility in a study. Both biogeochemists – a discipline that also includes the study of the Earth’s atmosphere – have written a study for the Research Institute Vniigaz of the Gazprom concern, an address of course that cannot be said is free of lobbyists. However, their arguments are underpinned by findings that are gaining more and more acceptance from independent science: solar activity is weakening considerably - to an extent that was last seen several hundred years ago, the Little Ice Age, according to scientists.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Kulke writes that not only is the CO2 science for explaining climate change one-dimensional, but that also only looking at changes in solar irradiance is completely inadequate.</p>
<p><a href="http://notrickszone.com/2013/03/25/flagship-daily-die-welt-stuns-germany-scientists-warn-of-ice-age-cites-new-peer-reviewed-russian-study/">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/die-welt-scientists-warn-ice-age/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coldest Easter Ever: Temperatures Drop To -15C</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/coldest-easter-ever-temperatures-drop-15c/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/coldest-easter-ever-temperatures-drop-15c/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 18:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11371</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[BRITAIN is braced for the coldest Easter on record with the bitter Arctic blast showing no signs of easing. Conditions in Lanchashire caused widespread drifting Another week of freezing temperatures, gales and snow is forecast as the UK shivers in the chilliest spring for 50 years. Heavy snow showers and strong winds have swept through [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>BRITAIN is braced for the coldest Easter on record with the bitter Arctic blast showing no signs of easing.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Conditions-in-Lanchashire-caused-widespread-drifting" src="http://images.dailyexpress.co.uk/img/dynamic/1/590x/386751_1.jpg" width="472" height="280" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;">Conditions in Lanchashire caused widespread drifting</span></p>
<p>Another week of freezing temperatures, gales and snow is forecast as the UK shivers in the chilliest spring for 50 years.</p>
<p>Heavy snow showers and strong winds have swept through the country causing mayhem on the roads, closing schools and downing power lines.</p>
<p>The extreme cold is thought to have caused the deaths of at least four people including two men, aged 25 and 33, at the weekend. Forecasters said the mercury was likely to fall below -10C (14F) this week but windchill could make it feel like -15C or colder across swathes of the country.</p>
<p>Central and northern regions have been worst hit with several inches of snow in many places and drifts several feet deep.</p>
<p>Thousands of homes in Scotland, Northern Ireland and Cumbria were yesterday without electricity for a third day as emergency crews struggled to restore supplies. Roads which became blocked on Friday were still impassible.</p>
<p>The Met Office issued severe weather warnings for ice today across much of the country.</p>
<p>With daytime temperatures likely to struggle above freezing, they last night extended a level-three cold weather health alert to Thursday, warning of a risk to the elderly and vulnerable.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.express.co.uk/news/uk/386751/Coldest-Easter-EVER-Arctic-misery-set-to-last-a-week-as-temperatures-drop-to-15C">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/coldest-easter-ever-temperatures-drop-15c/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Benny Peiser Sceptical Of John Beddington&#8217;s Climate Alarm</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/benny-peiser-sceptical-john-beddingtons-climate-alarm/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/benny-peiser-sceptical-john-beddingtons-climate-alarm/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 18:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11360</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The UK Government’s chief scientist has warned time delays in the climate system means that greenhouse gas emissions in the atmosphere now will determine the weather the world experiences for the next 25 years. The head of the Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF), however, said he is sceptical about anyone being able to predict what [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK Government’s chief scientist has warned time delays in the climate system means that greenhouse gas emissions in the atmosphere now will determine the weather the world experiences for the next 25 years. The head of the Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF), however, said he is sceptical about anyone being able to predict what the weather would be like in the future.</p>
<p><a title="Chief scientist warns climate change will bring extremes in weather" href="http://www.energylivenews.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Sir-Beddington350.jpg" rel="lightbox"><img alt="Chief scientist warns climate change will bring extremes in weather" src="http://www.energylivenews.com/wp-content/themes/premiumnews/thumb.php?src=wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Sir-Beddington350.jpg&amp;w=350&amp;h=250&amp;zc=1&amp;q=90" width="350" height="250" /></a></p>
<div>
<p>Sir John Beddington (pictured) said climate change is one of the things he has been trying to bring to the Government’s attention but believes it is not talked about enough. He also noted the climate and weather we’re experiencing now comes from greenhouse gases that were in the atmosphere 25 years ago.</p>
<p>He said the international community’s failure to agree binding targets for cutting carbon emissions meant problems were being stored up for the future. He told BBC Radio 4: “They may reach agreement and they may start to reduce greenhouse gases in the next five years, or it may be a little longer. But they are still climbing and when that increase is reversed, we will be left with the weather and the climate for the next 25 years from whenever that happens.”</p>
<p>Sir Beddington added: “You can think about mechanisms… carbon dioxide, carbon capture and storage, those things are very withdoing. But I kind of emphasise more on the time delays. I think the key here is this is sort of a simplistic way of thinking about it, that’s a nice indicator. But there are other things going on. For example, one of the results of the climate analyses is saying we do except more variability and we are seeing more variability… The Arctic is likely to be warming more than other parts of the planet. So I think that the issue in a sense needs to be taken out of a very simple, simplistic thing.”</p>
<p>He said the world faces huge problems of food, water and energy security as global population increases, which will be inevitable in the near future.</p>
<p>The head of the Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF), however, said he is sceptical about anyone being able predict what the climate would be like in the future.</p>
<p>Director Benny Peiser said: “No one knows whether next winter will be warm or cold or average, no one knows whether next summer will be hot or wet or dry. It’s very, very difficult to make long-term predictions and therefore, I remain rather sceptical about the reliability and accuracy of these kind of speculation. They are pure speculation, they are not based on any hard facts, it’s an assumption.”</p>
<p>Dr Peiser added setting an international target would be the only way to limit emissions. However, he said that would not happen as it would mean countries like China and India would have to stop exploiting fossil fuels.</p>
<p>“It would mean to stop their economic growth and development. They can’t afford that. The negotiations have been going on for 20 years and they have been against it. So just because John Beddington says Government should take action doesn’t mean anything for them. It’s business as usual… They are using cheap energy because it’s the only way to develop”, he said.</p>
<p>He suggested Governments need to spend more money on preparing for extreme weather conditions and be more resilient.</p>
<p>“The only realistic and pragmatic approach to the issue of climate change and extreme weather events like droughts or flooding is to make countries throughout the world more resilient so that they can cope better. If you can heat your home in the cold winter, then that’s not a big problem. If you can cool your home in a hot summer, then that’s not a problem. If you have houses that can withstand storms, then we don’t have a problem.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.energylivenews.com/2013/03/25/chief-scientist-warns-climate-change-will-bring-extremes-in-weather/"></p>
<p style="display: inline !important;"><span style="color: #0000ff;">Full story</span></p>
<p></a>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/benny-peiser-sceptical-john-beddingtons-climate-alarm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>US Shale Gas To Heat UK Homes</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/shale-gas-heat-uk-homes/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/shale-gas-heat-uk-homes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 12:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11357</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Centrica has struck a £10bn gas supply deal that could see US shale gas heating British homes by 2018. Centrica said the 20-year deal with Cheniere Energy Partners would allow it to export enough liquefied natural gas from the US to supply 1.8m British homes each year. &#8220;This landmark agreement represents a significant step forward [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Centrica has struck a £10bn gas supply deal that could see US shale gas heating British homes by 2018.</strong></p>
<p>Centrica said the 20-year deal with Cheniere Energy Partners would allow it to export enough liquefied natural gas from the US to supply 1.8m British homes each year.</p>
<p>&#8220;This landmark agreement represents a significant step forward in our strategy, enabling Centrica to strengthen its position along the gas value chain and helping to ensure the UK&#8217;s future energy security,&#8221; said Sam Laidlaw, Centrica&#8217;s chief executive.</p>
<p>Prime Minister David Cameron welcomed the deal, claiming: &#8220;Future gas supplies from the US will help diversify our energy mix and provide British consumers with a new long-term, secure and affordable source of fuel.&#8221;</p>
<p>However, Centrica is under no obligation to sell the gas to the UK and analysts said that at current market prices it would be more likely to deliver the gas to Asian markets, where prices are higher.</p>
<p>With the first shipments not due from the Louisiana-based plant until 2018, the deal will do nothing to relieve the current strained gas supplies caused by a colder than expected winter.</p>
<p>A faulty pump at the Interconnector, one of Britain&#8217;s main gas pipelines, caused an eight hour shutdown last Friday. The closure led to a 50pc spike in gas prices, and analysts warned that higher energy bills for consumers or even gas rationing for big businesses were possibilities if the cold weather continued.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/newsbysector/energy/oilandgas/9951840/Centrica-strikes-10bn-deal-that-could-see-US-shale-gas-supply-UK-homes.html">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/shale-gas-heat-uk-homes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Global Warming Policy Foundation Accepts Royal Society Offer For Meeting</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/global-warming-policy-foundation-accepts-royal-society-offer-meeting/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/global-warming-policy-foundation-accepts-royal-society-offer-meeting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 11:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Climate Record]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11354</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[London, 25 March: On behalf of the Global Warming Policy Foundation, Lord Lawson has accepted an offer by Sir Paul Nurse, the President of the Royal Society, who has offered to arrange a meeting between the GWPF and climate scientists. In a recent letter to Lord Lawson, the GWPF chairman, Sir Paul suggested that the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>London, 25 March:</strong> On behalf of the Global Warming Policy Foundation, Lord Lawson has accepted an offer by Sir Paul Nurse, the President of the Royal Society, who has offered to arrange a meeting between the GWPF and climate scientists.</p>
<p>In a recent letter to Lord Lawson, the GWPF chairman, Sir Paul suggested that the Foundation needed more mainstream and expert climate science advice and offered that the Royal Society &#8220;would be happy to put the GWPF in touch with people who can offer the Foundation informed scientific advice.&#8221;</p>
<p>In his response, Lord Lawson writes that he is &#8220;happy to accept your offer to arrange a meeting and look forward to hearing from you about this.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I hope this marks the start of a more productive dialogue with the Royal Society,&#8221; said Dr Benny Peiser, the Director of the GWPF.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/03/Nurse.pdf"><strong>Letter By Sir Paul Nurse to Lord Lawson</strong></a></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/03/Lawson-Nurse.pdf">Letter By Lord Lawson to Sir Paul Nurse</a></strong></p>
<p><strong>see also:</strong> <strong><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/lord-lawsons-letter-sir-paul-nurse/">Lord Lawson&#8217;s initial letter to Sir Paul Nurse</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/global-warming-policy-foundation-accepts-royal-society-offer-meeting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Japan Breaks China&#8217;s Stranglehold On Rare Metals</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/japan-breaks-chinas-stranglehold-rare-metals/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/japan-breaks-chinas-stranglehold-rare-metals/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 21:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11350</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Japanese scientists have found vast reserves of rare earth metals on the Pacific seabed that can be mined cheaply, a discovery that may break the Chinese monopoly on a crucial raw material needed in hi-tech industries and advanced weapons systems. &#8220;We have found deposits that are just two to four meters from the seabed surface [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Japanese scientists have found vast reserves of rare earth metals on the Pacific seabed that can be mined cheaply, a discovery that may break the Chinese monopoly on a crucial raw material needed in hi-tech industries and advanced weapons systems.</h2>
<div>
<div id="mainBodyArea">
<div>
<p>&#8220;We have found deposits that are just two to four meters from the seabed surface at higher concentrations than anybody ever thought existed, and it won&#8217;t cost much at all to extract,&#8221; said professor Yasuhiro Kato from Tokyo University, the leader of the team.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>While America, Australia, and other countries have begun to crank up production of the seventeen rare earth elements, they have yet to find viable amounts of the heavier metals such as dysprosium, terbium, europium, and ytterbium that are most important.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>China has a near total monopoly in the heavier end of the spectrum, though it is also the dominant supplier of the whole rare earth complex after driving rivals out of business in the 1990s. It still accounts for 97pc of global supply.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Beijing shocked the world when it suddenly began to restrict exports in 2009, prompting furious protests and legal complaints by both the US and the EU at the World Trade Organisation. China claimed that it was clamping down on smuggling and environmental abuse.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>&#8220;Their real intention is to force foreign companies to locate plant in China. They&#8217;re saying `if you want our rare earth metals, you must build your factory here, and we can then steal your technology,&#8221; said professor Kato.</p>
</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/asia/japan/8236899/Japan-creates-synthetic-version-of-rare-earth-metal-palladium.html"><img alt="" src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/02518/japan_2518670a.jpg" width="322" height="194" name="japan" /></a></div>
<div id="tmg-related-links" style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;"><sup style="color: #333333; text-decoration: underline;">Yasuhiro Kato, an associate professor of earth science at the University of Tokyo, displays a mud sample extracted from the depths of about 4,000 metres (13,123 ft) below the Pacific ocean surface where rare earth elements were found. – Reuters</sup></span></div>
<div>
<p>The team of scientists from Japan&#8217;s Agency for Marine-Earth Science and the University of Tokyo first discovered huge reserves in the mid-Pacific two years ago. These are now thought to be 1000 times all land-based deposits, some of it in French waters around Tahiti.</p>
<p>The latest discovery is in Japan&#8217;s Exclusive Economic Zone in deep-sea mud around the island of Minami-Torishima at 5,700 meters below sea level. Although it is very deep, the deposits are in highly-concentrated nodules that can be extracted using pressurised air with minimal disturbance off the seafloor and no need for the leaching.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/02518/japan-rare-earth_2518676e.jpg" width="300" height="320" name="japan-rare-earth" align="right" /></p>
<p>Professor Kato said exploration will continue for another two years before scaling up towards production. Over 50pc of the metal in the deposit is the heavier end of the spectrum, twice the level of China&#8217;s key mines and without the radioactive by-product thorium that makes the metals so hard to mine.</p>
<p>Japan consumes half the world&#8217;s rare earth metals in its cars, electronics, and environmental industries, and has accused China of withholding supplies as a pressure tool. The country has been scrambling to find other sources under its &#8220;Strategy for Ensuring Stable Supplies of Rare Metals&#8221;, but a joint venture in Vietnam that once looked promising has so far yielded only lighter rare earths.</p>
<p>Professor Kato said a single ship drilling in the target zone at Minami-Torishima could supply Japan&#8217;s needs for a year, breaking strategic dependence at minimal cost. &#8220;We don&#8217;t need to mine it intensively. All we need is enough to force China to lower its prices.&#8221;</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/comment/ambroseevans_pritchard/9951299/Japan-breaks-Chinas-stranglehold-on-rare-metals-with-sea-mud-bonanza.html">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/japan-breaks-chinas-stranglehold-rare-metals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Met Office Forecast: March Above-Average UK-Mean Temperatures More Likely</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/met-office-forecast-march-above-average-uk-mean-temperatures/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/met-office-forecast-march-above-average-uk-mean-temperatures/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 17:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Climate Record]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11346</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Met Office 3-Month Outlook 20 December 2012: For January as a whole below-average UK-mean temperatures are somewhat more likely than above-average, although there is considerable uncertainty. Similarly, snow and ice may occur more often than they do in an average January. For February and March the range of possible outcomes is also very broad, although above-average [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Met Office 3-Month Outlook 20 December 2012:</strong> For January as a whole below-average UK-mean temperatures are somewhat more likely than above-average, although there is considerable uncertainty. Similarly, snow and ice may occur more often than they do in an average January.</p>
<p>For February and March the range of possible outcomes is also very broad, although above-average UK-mean temperatures become more likely.</p>
<p>Overall, the probability that the UK-mean temperature for January-February-March will fall into the coldest of our five categories is around 15% whilst the probability that it will fall into the warmest of our five categories is around 20% (the 1981-2010 probability for each of these categories is 20%).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.metoffice.gov.uk/media/pdf/c/2/A3-plots-temp-JFM.pdf">Met Office, 20 December 2012</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/met-office-forecast-march-above-average-uk-mean-temperatures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
