<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Conn Carroll: Fracking Revolution Vs Green Energy Failure</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/conn-carroll-fracking-revolution-green-energy-failure/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/conn-carroll-fracking-revolution-green-energy-failure/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11944</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[U.S. liberals often make light of conservative claims that the free market is perfectly capable of solving problems and creating wealth without government planning. But that is exactly what fracking has done for the U.S. economy. For years, liberal efforts to unite around a green energy agenda had run into strong opposition from the labor [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>U.S. liberals often make light of conservative claims that the free market is perfectly capable of solving problems and creating wealth without government planning. But that is exactly what fracking has done for the U.S. economy.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;" data-mce-mark="1">For years, liberal efforts to unite around a green energy agenda had run into strong opposition from the labor wing of the progressive movement, which still included significant numbers of manufacturing, mining and transportation workers who depended on affordable fossil fuels for their livelihoods.</span></p>
<p>But by 2008, these traditional blue-collar unions were no longer the driving force of organized labor. Right-to-work laws and international competition had driven many unionized companies out of business, while the numbers of government and service-sector union members (think DMV clerks and Vegas maids) had exploded.</p>
<div id="newsletter-signup-opinion"></div>
<p>Suddenly cheap energy was no longer a union priority. Enter the Apollo Alliance, which is a project of the George Soros-funded Tides Foundation. Apollo forged a new labor/environmentalist that would both limit fossil fuel use and spend billions promoting green energy.</p>
<p>Since renamed the BlueGreen Alliance, the group launched with a report calling for $500 billion in spending to create a &#8220;New Apollo Program&#8221; for the U.S. economy. It included federal subsidies for green car companies and solar firms, cash to make existing buildings energy-efficient, new power line construction and billions for new mass transit systems.</p>
<p>The New Apollo Program called for a cap-and-trade plan designed to drive energy producers away from fossil fuels and toward renewable energy like solar, wind and biomass. Apollo promised these new initiatives would create 5 million new jobs.</p>
<p>The Obama campaign fully embraced the Apollo vision, producing its own New Energy for America document that largely mirrored the Apollo report. The only real difference was that Obama&#8217;s plan created 5 million new green economy jobs for just $150 billion.</p>
<p>Of course, Obama ended up spending far more than that after he was elected. And he has come nowhere close to meeting his 5 million job promise.</p>
<p>Many of the car and solar companies Obama invested in (like Fister and Solyndra) are either bankrupt or on their way there. His energy-efficiency programs have been so ineffective that even the liberal host of &#8220;The Daily Show,&#8221; Jon Stewart, has made them the butt of jokes.</p>
<p>And Obama&#8217;s signature transportation project, high-speed rail, was not only rejected by Florida, Ohio and Wisconsin, but in the one state where it has been pursued, California, not a single mile of track has yet been laid.</p>
<p>Four years into the Obama presidency, it is safe to say that the progressive plan to remake the U.S. economy has failed.</p>
<p>Not that today&#8217;s energy sector looks at all like it did when Obama was first sworn into office. There has been a transformation of American energy production under Obama, but it has happened despite his policies, not because of them.</p>
<p>No union/environmentalist central planner set out to create hundreds of thousands of new jobs by perfecting new methods of extracting shale oil and gas from rocks thousands of feet beneath the surface. But that is exactly what the private sector has done. A recent IHS Global Insight report found the fracking industry supported 1.7 million jobs in 2012 alone. [...]</p>
<p><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://washingtonexaminer.com/conn-carroll-fracking-revolutionized-american-energy-as-green-energy-failed/article/2527040">Full comment</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/conn-carroll-fracking-revolution-green-energy-failure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biofuels: &#8216;Irrational&#8217; And &#8216;Worse Than Fossil Fuels&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/biofuels-irrational-worse-fossil-fuels/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/biofuels-irrational-worse-fossil-fuels/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11941</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The UK&#8217;s &#8220;irrational&#8221; use of biofuels will cost motorists around £460 million over the next 12 months, a think tank says. A report by Chatham House says the growing reliance on sustainable liquid fuels will also increase food prices. The author says that biodiesel made from vegetable oil was worse for the climate than fossil fuels. Under [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="story_continues_1"><strong>The UK&#8217;s &#8220;irrational&#8221; use of biofuels will cost motorists around £460 million over the next 12 months, a think tank says.</strong></p>
<p>A <a href="http://www.chathamhouse.org/sites/default/files/public/Research/Energy,%20Environment%20and%20Development/0413pp_biofuels.pdf">report by Chatham House</a> says the growing reliance on sustainable liquid fuels will also increase food prices.</p>
<p>The author says that biodiesel made from vegetable oil was worse for the climate than fossil fuels.</p>
<p>Under EU <a href="http://ec.europa.eu/energy/renewables/biofuels/biofuels_en.htm">law</a>, biofuels are set to make up 5% of the UK&#8217;s transport fuel from today.</p>
<div><span style="font-size: 13px;">Since 2008, the UK has required fuel suppliers to add a growing proportion of sustainable materials into the petrol and diesel they supply. These biofuels are mainly ethanol distilled from corn and biodiesel made from rapeseed, used cooking oil and tallow.</span></div>
<p><strong>Deep fried fuel</strong></p>
<p>But research carried out for Chatham House says that reaching the 5% level means that UK motorists will have to pay an extra £460m a year because of the higher cost of fuel at the pump and from filling up more often as biofuels have a lower energy content.</p>
<p>The report say that if the UK is to meet its obligations to EU energy targets the cost to motorists is likely to rise to £1.3bn per annum by 2020.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is hard to find any good news,&#8221; Rob Bailey, senior research fellow at Chatham House, told BBC News.</p>
<p>&#8220;Biofuels increase costs and they are a very expensive way to reduce carbon emissions,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The EU biofuel mandates are also having hugely distorting effects in the marketplace. Because used cooking oil is regarded as one of the most sustainable types of biodiesel, the price for it has risen rapidly. Rob Bailey says that towards the end of 2012 it was more expensive than refined palm oil.</p>
<p>&#8220;It creates a financial incentive to buy refined palm oil, cook a chip in it to turn it into used cooking oil and then sell it at profit,&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It is crazy but the incentives are there.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-22127123">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/biofuels-irrational-worse-fossil-fuels/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Last Year’s U.S. Drought Wasn’t Caused By Climate Change</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/years-u-s-drought-wasnt-caused-climate-change/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/years-u-s-drought-wasnt-caused-climate-change/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 10:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11934</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Those advocating limits on greenhouse gases can’t count on the weather to make their argument. Last summer, in response to an intense and prolonged drought in the U.S.—the worst, indeed, since 1895—we ran an interview with a climate scientist, Thomas Karl, director of the National Climatic Data Center in Asheville, North Carolina. He said that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<header><strong>Those advocating limits on greenhouse gases can’t count on the weather to make their argument.</strong></header>
<header></header>
<header>Last summer, in response to an intense and prolonged drought in the U.S.—the worst, indeed, since 1895—we ran an interview with a climate scientist, Thomas Karl, director of the National Climatic Data Center in Asheville, North Carolina. He said that droughts in general will be exacerbated by climate change, while noting that it’s difficult to link any particular drought to greenhouse gases. “I suspect it will be really difficult to show how much these changing patterns contributed to the drought in the Midwest this year,” he said (see “Is Climate Change to Blame for the Current U.S. Drought?”).Karl was right about the difficulty of linking a particular event to climate change.</header>
<header></header>
<header>A new study from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration provides an assessment of last year’s drought, and concludes that “human-induced climate change” did not play a significant role. It attributes the drought to natural variations, including fewer than normal thunderstorms and a change in the movement of air that redirected moist air from the Gulf of Mexico away from the Midwest, things that can happen without global warming. The report also says that climate models did not predict the drought.The report concluded that, specifically regarding the impact of global warming on precipitation in the Midwest, “the signal of climate change may be very small compared to the noise of the intrinsic year-to-year variability. Detectability of a global warming signal in the statistics of summertime Great Plains rainfall may thus be very difficult at this time.”Until the earth warms a lot more than it has already, it’s going to continue to be difficult to read the effects of climate change in the weather. Weather is too variable. There will continue to be very cold weather that will boost the popularity of climate skeptics and very hot or volatile weather—like Hurricane Sandy—that will serve to make global warming seem more plausible. The decision about what to do, or not do, about climate change will ultimately depend on how much people believe climate models’ predictions of a markedly different world in the future that we’ll see only limited—and often ambiguous—evidence of in the present.</p>
</header>
<header></header>
<section><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.technologyreview.com/view/513646/last-years-us-drought-wasnt-caused-by-climate-change"><span style="color: #0000ff;">MIT Technology Review, 12 April 2013</span></a></span></section>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/years-u-s-drought-wasnt-caused-climate-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Natural Gas Battle In The Mediterranean</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/natural-gas-battle-mediterranean/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/natural-gas-battle-mediterranean/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 10:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11929</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Europe is to a large extent dependent on Russian gas supplied by Gazprom. A quarter of Europe&#8217;s entire gas consumption is provided by Gazprom. As a new player in the market of gas exporters, Cyprus could reduce the European dependency on Russian gas. Golda Meir once quipped that Moses could have done the Jewish people [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Europe is to a large extent dependent on Russian gas supplied by Gazprom. A quarter of Europe&#8217;s entire gas consumption is provided by Gazprom. As a new player in the market of gas exporters, Cyprus could reduce the European dependency on Russian gas.</strong></p>
<p>Golda Meir once quipped that Moses could have done the Jewish people a better service. “He took us 40 years through the desert,” she said, “to bring us to the one spot in the Middle East that has no oil.”</p>
<p>Today, Golda Meir’s quip has lost its punch. Last week, natural gas began flowing out of the Tamar gas field, discovered off the coast of Israel in January 2009. Tamar and Leviathan, its neighboring gas field, discovered in June 2010, are among the world’s largest recent offshore natural gas discoveries. The Israeli companies controlling the fields are even considering exporting gas to neighboring countries.</p>
<p>Geologists assume that commercial oil reserves may lie beneath the gas find. Some analysts say that the Tamar and Leviathan fields might change Israel’s position in the geopolitical and energy world. But not just Israel’s.</p>
<p>The Israeli fields are adjacent to the Aphrodite gas field, discovered in December 2011, which lies in Cypriot territorial waters, less than 25 miles west of Leviathan. The government in Nicosia expects that the result of offshore drillings will confirm later this year that the island is sitting on vast amounts of natural gas worth billions of dollars. The recent banking crisis in Cyprus –the latest episode in the saga of the collapsing euro – came too early for the country to benefit from its future natural gas wealth. It is, however, indicative that Cyprus turned down the European Union’s demands that the gas reserves be used as collateral for the loans which the E.U. has just extended to Cyprus.</p>
<p>Brussels had demanded that a fund be created in which it was given a direct say over the revenues from Cypriot gas reserves, but Nicosia refused to do so. The Cypriots feel betrayed by the E.U. Hence, they are not inclined to let Europe share in the future wealth which they hope to derive from gas. Nicos Anastasiades, the president of Cyprus, said that Cyprus had no other choice than give in to the harsh demand of Brussels that it dismantle its banking sector. He, however, promised that savers who lost money in the Cypriotic banks would be compensated by being given shares in banks guaranteed by the future natural gas revenues.</p>
<p>Today, Cyprus is paying a very heavy price for its membership of the E.U.’s common currency, the euro. When by 2019 the gas proceeds are expected to start flowing, the tables will be turned. Then Cyprus will be in a position to leave the euro without facing the prospect of national bankruptcy.</p>
<p>To begin extracting the gas from the Aphrodite field by 2019, however, the virtually bankrupt Cypriot government will in the coming years need to make enormous investments. The Russian state-owned gas company Gazprom, the largest extractor of natural gas in the world, seems <a href="http://greece.greekreporter.com/2013/03/18/gazprom-offers-cyprus-restructuring-deal-to-avoid-eu-bailout/">keen to get involved</a>. So far, however, the Cypriots have kept the Russians at bay.</p>
<p>Europe is already to a large extent <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2009/jan/02/russia-ukraine-gazprom">dependent</a> on Russian gas, supplied by Gazprom, a company controlled by the Russian oligarchy around President Putin. A quarter of Europe’s of Europe’s entire gas consumption comes from Gazprom. As a new player in the market of gas exporters, Cyprus could reduce the European dependency on Russian gas.</p>
<p>What applies to Cyprus, obviously, applies to Israel as well. It, too, could use its gas exports to a political end. Bat Ye’or has argued that the pro-Palestinian positions of the European governments since the 1970s were to a large extent the result of Europe’s dependency on Arab oil. Israel has a unique chance of also using the Cypriot gas to its own geostrategic benefit. The Cypriot gas fields are located halfway between the Cypriot and Israeli coast. Israel, Cyprus and Greece are already collaborating in the EuroAsia Interconnector project, which is an undersea power cable linking Israel with Cyprus and Cyprus with Greece. A gas pipeline following the same route would balance the current pipeline on the Baltic seabed linking Russia with Germany.</p>
<p>Another opportunity for Israel might be the fact that some international gas companies are reluctant to get involved in the exploitation of Cypriot gas fields because they also operate in Turkey and do not want to upset the Turkish authorities who oppose the Cypriot gas extraction. Though the Aphrodite gas field lies in waters across Southern Cyprus, Turkey is demanding that all gas revenues be shared with Turkish occupied Northern Cyprus.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.gatestoneinstitute.org/3660/israel-natural-gas">Full comment</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/natural-gas-battle-mediterranean/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will Europe Kill Its Cap-And-Trade System Tomorrow?</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-kill-cap-and-trade-system-tomorrow/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-kill-cap-and-trade-system-tomorrow/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 09:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11926</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The European Union’s 54 billion euro ($71 billion) cap-and-trade system may be undermined if the bloc’s Parliament votes against Climate Commissioner Connie Hedegaard’s temporary rescue plan tomorrow. The strategy, known as backloading, would delay the issuing of some new permits under the EU emissions trading system, or ETS, which imposes pollution limits on about 12,000 [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The European Union’s 54 billion euro ($71 billion) cap-and-trade system may be undermined if the bloc’s Parliament votes against Climate Commissioner Connie Hedegaard’s temporary rescue plan tomorrow.</strong></p>
<p>The strategy, known as backloading, would delay the issuing of some new permits under the EU emissions trading system, or ETS, which imposes pollution limits on about 12,000 power plants and factories across the region. The euro area’s recession has cut demand, exacerbating a glut that drove prices in the world’s biggest greenhouse-gas market to a record low in January.</p>
<p>Hedegaard says the low cost of the allowances erodes the incentive for polluters to invest in climate protection technology. Opponents including the government of Poland, which is Europe’s third-biggest carbon emitter, and BASF SE (BAS), the world’s largest chemicals maker, say the plan will raise energy costs, manipulate prices and undermine investors’ confidence.</p>
<p>“It’s possible to be serious about climate and the environment and not harm your economy,” Hedegaard said in a March 27 interview in Brussels. “I would have told you half a year ago backloading is a no-brainer, everybody will understand that you can’t continue to overflood a market that is already overflooded. Now this has become extremely political.”</p>
<p>Hedegaard, 52, a former Danish TV journalist and the Scandinavian country’s first climate minister, says her role is to “think beyond the crisis.” She says backloading would be an exceptional measure before Europe agrees on a longer-term overhaul of its eight-year-old carbon market.</p>
<p><strong>Parliament Divided</strong></p>
<p>“If we only think for the short term, we’re not doing our job,” said Hedegaard, who became one of the EU’s 27 commissioners in 2010. “Despite the economic crisis, there has been the willingness to move forward and to take the climate change challenge seriously.”</p>
<p>The European Commission’s emergency plan consists of a change to emissions-trading law that the Parliament will vote on tomorrow, and a separate measure detailing the backloading process that will be decided later. Without approval from member states and the assembly, which is split on the proposal, the commission can’t tackle the glut of permits that swelled to about 1 billion metric tons last year, or a half the average annual pollution limit in the ETS.</p>
<p><strong>Market Fate</strong></p>
<p>The ETS is the bloc’s main tool in meeting greenhouse gas- reduction targets, which it does by issuing companies with tradable permits that they must surrender to cover their emissions or pay a fine. While cap-and-trade programs are gaining favor in countries including Australia andSouth Korea, U.S. legislation for a market stalled in 2009 even with support from PresidentBarack Obama.</p>
<p>The commission’s draft fix involves delaying the sale of permits covering 900 million tons of emissions over the next three years and reintroducing, or backloading, them to the market in 2019 and 2020.</p>
<p>The outcome of the April 16 vote may determine the fate of the ETS for the next several years, according to Bloomberg New Energy Finance. [...]</p>
<p><strong>Buying Time</strong></p>
<p>Investors need a sign of political confidence in the ETS, or the market may be “completely undermined,” according to the International Emissions Trading Association. Backloading is needed to buy time before a deeper overhaul, which is unlikely to happen within the next four to five years, said Sarah Deblock, a Brussels-based EU policy director at the lobby group.</p>
<p>A majority of the EPP party, the biggest political group in the European Parliament, disagree with IETA. The EU is on course to meet its emissions-reduction goal and market intervention will hamper the economic recovery, EPP members Lena Kolarska- Bobinska, Alejo Vidal-Quadras, Amalia Sartori and Herbert Reul said in a letter to Hedegaard on April 10.</p>
<p>“Backloading undermines the trust in the market when we need investment certainty,” Wolfgang Weber, who oversees BASF’s EU government relations in Brussels, said on April 9.</p>
<p><strong>Serious Threat</strong></p>
<p>Poland’s Environment Minister Marcin Korolec disagrees with his counterparts in countries including Germany and the U.K. who say eight years of climate action will be lost without backloading.</p>
<p>“What creates a serious threat for the existence of our most cost-efficient climate-policy instrument is precisely undermining its market character by political intervention through backloading,” Korolec said by e-mail.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-14/europe-braces-for-verdict-on-climate-chief-s-carbon-plan.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-kill-cap-and-trade-system-tomorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green Energy Investment Falls 22% As Subsidy Cuts Stall Projects</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-energy-investment-falls-22-subsidy-cuts-stall-projects/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-energy-investment-falls-22-subsidy-cuts-stall-projects/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 09:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11923</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Clean energy investment slid 22 percent to its lowest level in four years as nations pared subsidies for technologies from wind turbines to solar power and financing in China and Brazil stalled. The $40.6 billion invested in the industry in the first three months of this year was lower than any quarter since 2009 and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Clean energy investment slid 22 percent to its lowest level in four years as nations pared subsidies for technologies from wind turbines to solar power and financing in China and Brazil stalled.</strong></p>
<p>The $40.6 billion invested in the industry in the first three months of this year was lower than any quarter since 2009 and compares with $52 billion in the same period last year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg New Energy Finance.</p>
<p>“The last 18 months have seen a number of significant support programs launched in the aftermath of the financial crisis come to an end,” said Michael Liebreich, chief executive officer of the London-based research company.</p>
<p>The decline indicates the pressure on wind and solar power manufacturers from Yingli Green Energy Holding (<a href="http://investing.businessweek.com/research/stocks/snapshot/snapshot.asp?ticker=YGE:US" data-symbol="YGE:US">YGE</a>) Co. Ltd. to Vestas Wind Systems A/S (VWS), which are suffering from a plunge in prices due to increased competition and excess production capacity. Photovoltaic modules in March were 81 percent below the 2008 levels.</p>
<p>Investment in renewables, energy efficiency and energy- smart technologies fell 54 percent in the U.S. to $4.5 billion and by 15 percent in China to $8.8 billion in China. Europe saw a 25 percent drop to $13.4 billion with investment in Spain alone falling 96 percent compared to last year.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.businessweek.com/news/2013-04-14/clean-energy-investment-falls-22-percent-as-subsidy-cuts-stall-projects">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-energy-investment-falls-22-subsidy-cuts-stall-projects/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wind Farm Developers Face New Wave Of Opposition</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/wind-farm-developers-face-wave-opposition/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/wind-farm-developers-face-wave-opposition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 08:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11918</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The opposition against the inefficient, bird killing and landscape destroying monstrous wind turbines is getting serious in Britain: Wind farm developers are facing a dramatic escalation of opposition from dozens of MPs who say they will fight every application in their constituencies. The MPs, many of whom have until now only opposed particular proposals, believe their intervention will [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The opposition against the inefficient, bird killing and landscape destroying monstrous wind turbines is<a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/earth/energy/windpower/9991898/Wind-farm-developers-face-new-wave-of-opposition-from-MPs.html"> getting serious</a> in Britain:</strong></p>
<p><em>Wind farm developers are facing a dramatic escalation of opposition from dozens of MPs who say they will fight every application in their constituencies.</em></p>
<p><em>The MPs, many of whom have until now only opposed particular proposals, believe their intervention will make it more difficult for planning permission to be given.</em></p>
<p><em>In a fresh protest against the Government’s support for onshore wind turbines, backbenchers said their constituencies had reached “tipping point” and would be ruined by further development.</em></p>
<p><em>They are sharing advice on running local campaigns against wind farms after the Tory head of a larger cross party group of MPs opposed to the spread of onshore wind distributed a manual on how to fight proposals by developers.</em></p>
<p><em>The move comes after the group of 106 MPs &#8211; 101 of them Tories &#8211; called on the Government to cut generous subsidies, which they say are driving the expansion of wind farms. In a letter to the Prime Minister in February last year they warned it was “unwise” to make consumers subsidise “inefficient and intermittent energy production”.</em></p>
<p><em>Geoffrey Cox, the MP for Torridge and West Devon, one of the signatories to the letter said: “There are now so many turbine applications that the whole of our district is affected. I believe we have now reached a tipping point.</em></p>
<p><em>Mr Cox said the proposals for six turbines on privately owned farmland in Torridge followed the construction of “dozens” of turbines in the last three years.</em></p>
<p><em>He said: “Torridge is now facing over 60 applications. They are going to make a fundamental change to the character of this exquisite landscape, trashing an ancient and beautiful countryside for the sake of filling the pockets of developers with consumer subsidies.</em></p>
<p><em>“These are some of the most romantic and attractive destinations in our country and yet we are erecting giant machines which litter the countryside. The time has come to stop feeding this extraordinary cash cow.”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://newnostradamusofthenorth.blogspot.co.uk/2013/04/uk-mps-getting-serious-about-stopping.html">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/wind-farm-developers-face-wave-opposition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hans von Storch On Cold Winters And Global Warming</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/hans-von-storch-cold-winters-global-warming/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/hans-von-storch-cold-winters-global-warming/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 15:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11915</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;The fact that the explanation [of cold winters] came afterwards, and was not searched and found before the occurrence of the phenomenon, is just more reason for doubt.” At his klimazwiebel.blog here, Professor Hans von Storch posted an interview conducted with German Weather Service (DWD) press spokesman Gerhard Lux that had appeared earlier in the Offenbacher Post. Arctic, public domain photo [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>&#8220;The fact that the explanation [of cold winters] came afterwards, and was not searched and found before the occurrence of the phenomenon, is just more reason for doubt.”</strong></p>
<p>At his <a href="http://klimazwiebel.blogspot.de/2013/04/deutscher-wetterdienst-zum-kalten.html">klimazwiebel.blog here</a>, Professor Hans von Storch posted an interview conducted with <strong>German Weather Service</strong> (DWD) press spokesman <strong>Gerhard Lux</strong> that had appeared earlier in the Offenbacher Post.</p>
<p><a href="http://notrickszone.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Arctic.gif"><img alt="Arctic" src="http://notrickszone.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Arctic.gif" width="537" height="174" /></a></p>
<p><em>Arctic, public domain photo – NASA.</em></p>
<p>The interview focused on the new hypothesis put out by some scientists now claiming that the cold winters are caused by global warming, i.e. a warm Arctic is disrupting northern hemispheric weather patterns and thus causing cold winters in Europe and elsewhere.</p>
<p>Here’s what <a href="http://klimazwiebel.blogspot.de/2013/04/deutscher-wetterdienst-zum-kalten.html?showComment=1365258164770">von Storch had to say about that hypothesis</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>An interesting aspect that demonstrates the difficulty in which climate science now finds itself is that here a hypothesis was formulated (Arctic ice deficit, subsequent winter anomaly) that ends up being a possible explanation in a model experiment. But here it cannot be concluded that this is the only or even the dominant explanation. What’s next is falsification of the suggestion using forthcoming observations to see whether the explanation is robust, or whether maybe indeed other explanations are more effective (e.g.: stochastic climate fluctuations). This is actually a normal process in science, and the fact that the explanation came afterwards, and was not searched and found before the occurrence of the phenomenon, is just more reason for doubt.”</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Other experts also doubt (or outright dismiss) the hypothesis</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://notrickszone.com/2013/04/12/hans-von-storch-fact-that-the-explanation-came-afterwards-is-just-more-reason-for-doubt/">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/hans-von-storch-cold-winters-global-warming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>English Winters Back To Normal – Met Office Blames Global Warming</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/english-winters-normal-met-office-blames-global-warming/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/english-winters-normal-met-office-blames-global-warming/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 11:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Observatory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11912</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[According to the Sun, Britain’s winters are getting colder because of melting Arctic ice, the Government’s forecaster said yesterday. Met Office chief scientist Julia Slingo said climate change was “loading the dice” towards freezing, drier weather — and called publicly for the first time for an urgent investigation. Prof Slingo said: “If you look at the way [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>According to the <a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/news/4881369/Is-the-UK-set-for-Arctic-weather.html">Sun,</a> <em>Britain’s winters are getting colder because of melting Arctic ice, the Government’s forecaster said yesterday.</em></p>
<p><em>Met Office chief scientist Julia Slingo said climate change was “loading the dice” towards freezing, drier weather — and called publicly for the first time for an urgent investigation.</em></p>
<p><em>Prof Slingo said: “If you look at the way our weather patterns have behaved over the past four or five years, we’re beginning to think that there is something happening.</em></p>
<p><em>“Our climate is being disrupted by the warming of the Arctic that we have observed very dramatically since 2007.</em></p>
<p><em>“We should pull together the best scientists to see how we can detect the influence of the Arctic on the jet stream, and on weather around the world.”</em></p>
<p>So just how cold have Britain’s winters become? Well, according to the Central England Temperature series, not very! The winter just gone ranks an unremarkable 187th coldest in the 354 years since the index started in 1660. Figure 1 shows just how unremarkable it has been. The 2012/13 winter finished at 3.83C, a fraction above the mean over the whole record of 3.72C.</p>
<p><a href="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image17.png"><img title="image" alt="image" src="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image_thumb17.png?w=504&amp;h=312" width="504" height="312" border="0" /></a></p>
<p align="center">Figure 1</p>
<p align="left">Slingo also talks about the 5 year trend, so let’s look at that as well.</p>
<p align="left"><a href="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image18.png"><img title="image" alt="image" src="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image_thumb18.png?w=504&amp;h=304" width="504" height="304" border="0" /></a></p>
<p align="center">Figure 2</p>
<p align="center">
<p align="left">There has certainly been a sharp drop away from the abnormally mild winters between 1998 and 2008, but this only takes us back to the sort of winters that were prevalent during most of the last century, and still much warmer than the 19thC. The current 5-year average is 3.6C, exactly the same as the average temperature from 1980-89. And from 1960-69, the average was, you’ve guessed it, also exactly 3.6C.</p>
<p align="left"><strong>Previous Predictions For Milder Winters</strong></p>
<p align="left">So why is Slingo so concerned? To understand this, we need to look back at all of the predictions, made in recent years by the Met Office and others, of warmer, wetter winters.</p>
<p align="left">These, of course, were based on the handful of milder winters around the turn of the century. There are too many to list, but here’s a few examples:-</p>
<p><a href="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.wordpress.com/2013/04/12/english-winters-back-to-normaljulia-blames-global-warming/">full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/english-winters-normal-met-office-blames-global-warming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shale Gas Growth Is Fracking Impressive</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/shale-gas-growth-fracking-impressive/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/shale-gas-growth-fracking-impressive/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:15:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11908</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[According to Energy Information Administration (EIA) data released 4/11/2013, dry shale natural gas production in the U.S. is 27 times higher today than it was in January of 2000. Most of that dramatic increase came after 2006. To understand how remarkable that is, it is instructive to compare it with the much vaunted renewable energy industry. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>According to Energy Information Administration (EIA) data released 4/11/2013, dry shale natural gas production in the U.S. is 27 times higher today than it was in January of 2000. Most of that dramatic increase came after 2006. To understand how remarkable that is, it is instructive to compare it with the much vaunted renewable energy industry.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="http://www.pbase.com/azleader/image/149634933.png" width="397" height="370" /></p>
<p>Dry shale production has doubled every year for each of the last 6 strait years.</p>
<p>To understand how remarkable that is, it is instructive to compare it with the much vaunted renewable energy industry.</p>
<p><strong>The Rise of Shale Gas</strong></p>
<p>In the year 2000 renewables supplied 6.1 Qbtu/year out of a total energy production of 71.3 Qbtu/yr in the United States. At that time renewables were 8.6% of all energy produced in the USA.</p>
<p>Some people may be surprised by such a large percentage so long ago. It is large because the biggest renewable energy sources are hydroelectric and biomass and they have been around for a long time.</p>
<p>On the other hand, in the year 2000, dry shale natural gas was barely 0.41 Qbtu/yr and a fractional 0.57% of total U.S. energy production.</p>
<p>By the end of 2011 renewables had increased their share to 11.8% of total U.S. energy. But by then dry shale natural gas had risen to match them at 11.6% of total U.S. energy production. Shale passed renewables last year, but final figures showing how much are not yet available.</p>
<p><strong>Renewables Sputtering</strong></p>
<p>In the year 2000, all renewable energy sources combined provided almost 20 times more energy than dry shale did.</p>
<p>In its 2013 early release overview, the EIA predicts that by 2040 all renewables combined will only increase from 13% to 16% of total U.S. electricity production. Natural gas will supply almost twice that by then.</p>
<p>Wind and solar, the glamor sources favored by Obama energy policy, were given 10s of billions in taxpayer money over the last 4 years. Taxpayer subsidized windmills are everywhere you look, but wind and solar are barely blips in the U.S. energy picture at 1.6% of total U.S. energy production.</p>
<p>Shale gas, on the other hand, has got no government support and natural gas production on federal lands has been slashed 33% under President Obama.</p>
<p>While tax supported renewables languish, shale gas’s remarkable growth was made possible through private-sector investment in fracking on non-federal lands.</p>
<p>In the last year shale gas produced 10.1 quadrillion BTUs total production. That is 40 times more energy than wind and solar combined.</p>
<p><strong>Conclusions</strong></p>
<p>The rise of fracking has driven dry shale natural gas production skyward from just 1.2 billion cubic feet/day in January of 2000 up to 27.2 billion by February, 2013.</p>
<p>Natural gas is the cleanest of the fossil fuels. It is fast replacing dirty coal as the preferred method for producing electricity. Since it releases half the CO2 of coal, overall U.S. CO2 emissions have dropped to 1994 levels and are going down.</p>
<p><a href="http://informthepundits.wordpress.com/2013/04/13/shale-natural-gas-is-fracking-impressive/">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/shale-gas-growth-fracking-impressive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
