<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 09:58:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Bad News For Pessimists: Malthus Was Wrong</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/bad-news-pessimists-malthus-wrong/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/bad-news-pessimists-malthus-wrong/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 09:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11320</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is a tempting intuition to the idea that the real prices of non-renewable goods like coal, iron ore, or oil should rise, more or less, forever. It’s an easy argument to make, and it sounds right: The world’s population is getting bigger and bigger, so more and more goods like metals and hydrocarbons are [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>There is a tempting intuition to the idea that the real prices of non-renewable goods like coal, iron ore, or oil should rise, more or less, forever. It’s an easy argument to make, and it sounds right: The world’s population is getting bigger and bigger, so more and more goods like metals and hydrocarbons are being consumed. Every year, the sum total of what we’ve taken out of the ground mounts, never to be replaced. Supply of the stuff is limited—once it’s gone, it’s gone.</strong></p>
<p>So, this argument goes, as we exhaust our resources, we’ll have to mine, drill, or otherwise get our hands on it somehow but it will get more and more expensive to do so, because we’ll have exhausted the best stuff. Left to exploit ever-greater quantities of ever-more-marginal deposits, prices will rise indefinitely into the future.</p>
<p>Thus, in this line of reasoning, unless we start consume less of a given non-renewable material, it will forever and ever get more expensive.</p>
<p>The logic appears unimpeachable at first glance. But it’s wrong. The prices of raw materials have not traveled the path this story would predict for any traded commodity once inflation is factored in, over long stretches of time. One of the most powerfully counter-intuitive and empirically conclusive findings in economic history is that the real prices of nearly all major resources have actually trended lower over very long periods of time, even if they’re produced at higher and higher rates.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="http://blogs.cfr.org/levi/files/2013/03/BC-chart-3-22-131.png" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Figure 1. <em>Economist</em> Industrial-Commodity Price Index in Real and Nominal Terms (1871-2010)</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.cfr.org/levi/2013/03/22/bad-news-for-pessimists-everywhere-malthus-was-wrong/">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/bad-news-pessimists-malthus-wrong/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green Coal? Another Phony &#8216;Green Jobs&#8217; Report</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-coal-phony-green-jobs-report/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-coal-phony-green-jobs-report/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 09:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11316</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As yet another Solyndra looms, a new government report shows that by the government&#8217;s own broad definition of a green job, more can be found in a coal mine than near a solar panel. The second annual Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) report on &#8220;Employment in Green Goods and Services,&#8221; released Tuesday, will be the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>As yet another Solyndra looms, a new government report shows that by the government&#8217;s own broad definition of a green job, more can be found in a coal mine than near a solar panel.</strong></p>
<p>The second annual Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) report on &#8220;Employment in Green Goods and Services,&#8221; released Tuesday, will be the last, allegedly a casualty of the same sequestration that claimed the White House tours and may doom the Easter egg hunt on the White House lawn.</p>
<p>That is probably a good thing, for if it were published as a book, it would deserve a place at the top of the New York Times best-seller fiction list.</p>
<p>It is chock full of charts claiming millions of new &#8220;green&#8221; jobs being produced by President Obama&#8217;s efforts to heal the planet and lower the rising seas. But if you have the eyes and the patience to actually examine it, it is full of lies, damned lies and government statistics.</p>
<p>The BLS defines green jobs as those that produce goods or services &#8220;that benefit the environment or conserve natural resources,&#8221; or jobs &#8220;in which workers&#8217; duties involve making their establishment&#8217;s production processes more environmentally friendly or use fewer natural resources.&#8221;</p>
<p>Its report claims that such jobs account for 2.6% of all jobs in the economy, for a total just north of 3.4 million jobs.</p>
<p>But buried in Table 3, &#8220;Green Goods And Services,&#8221; we find under &#8220;Utilities&#8221; and &#8220;Electric power generation&#8221; a total of just 522 jobs for &#8220;solar electric power generation&#8221; and 2,724 jobs for &#8220;wind electric power generation&#8221; for a total of 3,246 jobs.</p>
<p>Under the heading &#8220;coal and petroleum products mfg.&#8221; we find 3,278 jobs. So even in the BLS list of &#8220;green&#8221; jobs, coal and oil wins.</p>
<p>So what about the &#8220;millions&#8221; of other &#8220;green&#8221; jobs claimed? The problem is in that definition.</p>
<p>The bureau includes clothing stores, television and radio broadcasters, and office furniture manufacturers among the country&#8217;s green industries.</p>
<p>Heritage Foundation energy expert Nick Loris said of the report that &#8220;you don&#8217;t have to scratch the surface too deeply to realize that these numbers are bogus.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Many of these jobs being counted as &#8216;green&#8217; are not green and not new,&#8221; says Rep. Mike Pompeo, R-Kan., a member of the Energy and Commerce Committee who sponsored legislation to repeal energy tax credits. &#8220;BLS is counting green jobs to include bus drivers, trash collectors, radio broadcasters and movie producers.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://news.investors.com/ibd-editorials/032113-648963-bls-releases-another-phony-green-jobs-report.htm">Full comment</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-coal-phony-green-jobs-report/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>America&#8217;s &#8216;Green&#8217; Jobs Revelation</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/americas-green-jobs-revelation/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/americas-green-jobs-revelation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11312</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[America can boast only 500 green jobs in solar electric power generation, but 886,000 green jobs in government — many for passage of environmental laws, enforcement of environmental regulations, and administration of environmental programs, according to the new count of green jobs for 2011 released by the Bureau of Labor Statistics this week. The new report [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>America can boast only 500 green jobs in solar electric power generation, but 886,000 green jobs in government — many for passage of environmental laws, enforcement of environmental regulations, and administration of environmental programs, <a href="http://www.bls.gov/news.release/ggqcew.nr0.htm">according to the new count of green jobs for 2011 released by the Bureau of Labor Statistics this week.</a></strong></p>
<p id="">The new report shows that the number of green jobs in the economy grew from 3.2 million in 2010, the first year of data collected, to 3.4 million in 2011. That’s an increase of one-tenth of a percent of the nation’s jobs, from 2.5% to 2.6%.</p>
<div>
<div>BLS is responsible for the federal definition of green jobs under the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007, signed into law by President George W. Bush. The Act incorporated the Green Jobs Act as Title X, sponsored by then-Rep. Hilda Solis, a California Democrat. Solis became secretary of Labor in 2009, and was charged with implementing her legislation.</div>
</div>
<p id="">Now that Solis has resigned, and the budget sequester is in place, BLS is discontinuing the survey, saving $8 million.</p>
<p id="">President Barack Obama called for the creation of 5 million green jobs over the next decade in his 2008 campaign. Most recently, in his State of the Union Address, the president reiterated his support, saying “Four years ago, other countries dominated the clean-energy market and the jobs that came with it. We’ve begun to change that.”</p>
<p id="">The Obama administration then proceeded to give out grants and guaranteed loans for green-energy projects to try to make his dream into reality. Alternative energy grants, loans, and tax breaks cost the economy about $12 billion in 2012.</p>
<p id="">When people hear of green jobs, they think workers are making wind and solar power, and electric cars and batteries. But few Americans are employed in these sectors.</p>
<p id="">In addition to the 500 jobs in solar electric power generation, biomass and geothermal electric generation each accounted for 1,000 jobs, and wind electric power generation employed 3,000 Americans. These are all dwarfed by nuclear power, at 44,000, even though nuclear power is no favorite of environmentalists.</p>
<p id="">In contrast, the number of jobs in oil and gas extraction increased from 159,000 in 2010 to 172,000 in 2011.</p>
<p id="">The largest increase in green jobs came from the construction industry, which added 102,000 jobs, mostly through relabeling. As more construction materials are categorized as energy efficient, the jobs of those who install them turn green.</p>
<p id="">For instance, BLS counts construction workers who install energy efficient windows as having green jobs, but not those who put in regular windows. Plumbers who install “Lo-Flo” toilets have green jobs, but not plumbers who put in regular fixtures.</p>
<p id="">The largest number of green jobs, 886,000, or 26% of total, are in the federal, state, and local governments. This is a decline of 15,000 from 2010, when government was responsible for 28% of green jobs. It takes a quarter of the green jobs work force to pass green jobs laws, write the regulations, and enforce them.</p>
<p id="">For instance, Gregory Friedman, inspector general of the Energy Department, has a green job and a staff of green employees. <a href="http://energy.gov/sites/prod/files/OAS-RA-13-10.pdf">Last month he wrote a report</a> describing the misuse of a $150 million grant awarded to LG Chem, a South Korean-owned battery manufacturer in Holland, Mich. LG Chem was supposed to create 440 green jobs and make enough batteries to run 60,000 electric cars by December 2013.</p>
<p id="">But LG Chem’s employees weren’t green. According to Friedman, “we confirmed that employees spent time volunteering at local non-profit organizations, playing games and watching movies during regular working hours.” LG Chem, meanwhile, sold to U.S. firms batteries made in South Korea. That’s money from Uncle Sam for green jobs in Asia.</p>
<p id="">
<p style="display: inline !important;">Full story</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/americas-green-jobs-revelation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green Jobs Up In  Smoke As Bosch Abandons Solar Energy</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-jobs-smoke-bosch-abandons-solar-energy/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-jobs-smoke-bosch-abandons-solar-energy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 09:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11309</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Bosch said it will sell or shut down its heavily loss-making solar energy operations, the latest blow to the industry as Germany curbs green energy subsidies and cheap Chinese imports flood the market. In a rare reversal of strategy from the manufacturing conglomerate, Bosch said on Friday it would end its photovoltaics, or solar panel [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bosch said it will sell or shut down its heavily loss-making solar energy operations, the latest blow to the industry as Germany curbs green energy subsidies and cheap Chinese imports flood the market.</strong></p>
<p>In a rare reversal of strategy from the manufacturing conglomerate, Bosch said on Friday it would end its photovoltaics, or solar panel production early next year and put parts of the business up for sale.</p>
<p>Unlisted Bosch, one of the world&#8217;s largest maker of car parts, has lost 2.4 billion euros (2 billion pounds) since it created the solar energy unit in 2008 after it bought Aleo Solar and Ersol. It made a 1 billion euro loss last year.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is possibly the most painful experience that I have had to endure in my professional career,&#8221; said Chairman Franz Fehrenbach in a statement unveiling the plans for the unit that employs 3,000 staff.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ibtimes.co.uk/articles/449399/20130322/bosch-abandons-solar-energy.htm">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-jobs-smoke-bosch-abandons-solar-energy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Best Thing About Shale Gas: We Know Where It Is</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/shale-gas/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/shale-gas/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 09:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11307</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The shale-gas revolution has been, like all revolutions, a mixed blessing. It has unleashed a flood of cheap energy on the nation, but it’s also created a treadmill for drillers who must keep pouring capital into wells in a potentially hopeless attempt to show growing earnings from producing cheap gas. Retired BHP Billiton Chief Charles [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The shale-gas revolution has been, like all revolutions, a mixed blessing. It has unleashed a flood of cheap energy on the nation, but it’s also created a treadmill for drillers who must keep pouring capital into wells in a potentially hopeless attempt to show growing earnings from producing cheap gas.</strong></p>
<p>Retired BHP Billiton Chief Charles “Chip” Goodyear sketched out this bleak scenario this afternoon at the Yale Alumni in Energy Conference, an annual gathering of alumni active in all sides of the energy industry. Far from becoming a vast new source of baseload electricity fuel or even exports as liquified natural gas, a lot of the shale gas will essentially serve as a reserve in times of shortage, he said.</p>
<p>“We have a huge luxury we didn’t have before,” he said. “We know where the hydrocarbon is, and we know how much it costs to get out of the ground.”</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="English: Map of major shale gas basis all over..." src="http://b-i.forbesimg.com/danielfisher/files/2013/03/300px-EIA_World_Shale_Gas_Map1.png" /></p>
<p>Goodyear has plenty of experience with the economics of oil and gas extraction. A Yale and Wharton grad, he worked his way up at BHP Billiton from 1999 to 2007 as the Australian mining and energy company expanded from a market cap of $12 billion to $220 billion. He now runs a private investment firm and sits on the board of Anadarko Petroleum.</p>
<p>The combination of shale reserves and fracking technology has created vast new reserves that are fundamentally different than gas and oil pockets in the past, he said. Instead of hunting for them with expensive exploratory wells, drillers know exactly where the gas and oil are now, trapped in huge sandstone formations that extend across entire states.</p>
<p>The wells tend to generate 20% annual returns on capital invested, he said, but they also tend to decline at rates up to 80% in the first 18 months, meaning companies that want to show an increase in production must roll the cash flow into an expanding number of wells to stay ahead of the decline. That treadmill caught up with Chesapeake Energy, which spent billions on leases and drilling but ousted its colorful chief, Aubrey McClendon, earlier this year as it racked up a big losses and was forced to retrench.</p>
<p>“Chesapeake was a shell game, or maybe I should say a shale game,” Goodyear said. “I’m not sure it created any economic value at all.”</p>
<p>As gas production increases some are talking about — and fretting over — the possibility of exporting it as LNG to countries like Japan. But Goodyear said that assumes prices hold where they are on the international market, which is unlikely given huge new discoveries closer to Asia. Anadarko discovered a massive gas field off the coast of Mozambique in 2006 that extends across 100 miles and may contain 200 trillion cubic feet of gas (US yearly gas consumption: 30 tcf).</p>
<p>“I’ve never seen anything like it before,” Goodyear said of the field, currently estimated at 70 trillion feet. “It looks essentially like somebody laid down a layer of snow that is 500-1000 feet deep.”</p>
<p>That supply will likely drive the price in Japan from $17 to $8 per million cubic feet even as that country ramps up imports to replace retiring nuclear electric plants. Bad news for the more than 20 U.S. LNG terminal projects on the drawing board that assume cheap shale gas can be exported into more lucrative markets. The transport cost across the Pacific is $5 per mcf, he said.</p>
<p>“You can see that new gas is not going baseload” generation, he said.</p>
<p>Unconventional oil reserves like the Bakken shale are similarly on the edge, with production costs for some requiring $110 per barrel Brent to make sense. In both cases the higher cost reserves will come into play only when prices rise sharply.</p>
<p>“They will be in the market time to time, but they won’t be in the market all the time,” he said.</p>
<p>Bad news for high-cost, highly leveraged drillers but good news for the U.S. economy overall. The certainty of new supply when prices rise will give confidence to manufacturers and consumers as they plan for the future, he said.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/danielfisher/2013/03/22/the-best-thing-about-shale-gas-we-know-where-it-is/">Forbes, 22 March 2013</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/shale-gas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Frezza: Scientists Outraged That Elected Reps Control Their Handouts</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/bill-frezza-scientists-outraged-elected-reps-control-handouts/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/bill-frezza-scientists-outraged-elected-reps-control-handouts/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 16:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11304</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you believe in democracy, then spending priorities must be set by the people. Removing entire fields of endeavor from accountability by placing them in the hands of unelected bureaucrats makes a mockery of democratic principles. Concerned scientists on the dole reacted with fury when an amendment to the Continuing Appropriations Act of 2013, offered by [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>If you believe in democracy, then spending priorities must be set by the people. Removing entire fields of endeavor from accountability by placing them in the hands of unelected bureaucrats makes a mockery of democratic principles.</strong></p>
<p>Concerned scientists on the dole reacted with fury when an amendment to the <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/20/senate-passes-six-month-s_n_2917853.html?" target="_hplink">Continuing Appropriations Act of 2013</a>, offered by spending scold Sen. Tom Coburn (R-Okla), passed the Senate. It will limit the National Science Foundation&#8217;s ability to award political science grants to only those projects directly related to national security or the economic interests of the United States. &#8220;The amendment makes all scientific research vulnerable to the whims of political pressure,&#8221; shrieked the American Political Science Association in a <a href="http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/senate-delivers-a-devastating-blow-to-the-integrity-of-the-scientific-process-at-the-national-science-foundation-199221111.html" target="_hplink">press release</a>.</p>
<p>The horror! Imagine what would happen if entrenched technocrats and the tenured professors they support were actually held accountable by the elected representatives of the taxpayers who pay their bills? Where would the money come from to build <a href="http://news.ucdavis.edu/search/news_detail.lasso?id=10187" target="_hplink">RoboSquirrels</a> to entertain rattlesnakes? Or investigate why <a href="http://cnsnews.com/news/article/feds-spend-15-million-study-why-lesbians-are-fat" target="_hplink">lesbians are fat</a> and <a href="http://nation.foxnews.com/government-waste/2013/03/19/feds-spend-27m-study-drunk-lesbians" target="_hplink">drink too much</a>? Or study whether playing <a href="http://tc.msu.edu/role-social-network-sites-facilitating-collaborative-processes" target="_hplink">Farmville </a>helps people make friends? And, no, there is no need to revisit the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cMO8Pyi3UpY" target="_hplink">shrimp on the treadmill</a> brouhaha. (NPR has already rushed to the <a href="http://www.npr.org/2011/08/23/139852035/shrimp-on-a-treadmill-the-politics-of-silly-studies" target="_hplink">defense of that scientist</a>, who claims his research benefits the seafood industry. If it&#8217;s such a boon, let fishermen pay for it.)</p>
<p>Senator Coburn, a former physician and one of the few members of Congress who was not a lawyer before he joined the non-productive class, has made a career out of attacking government waste, fraud, duplication, and questionable spending. His 2011 report &#8220;<a href="http://www.coburn.senate.gov/public/index.cfm?a=Files.Serve&amp;File_id=2dccf06d-65fe-4087-b58d-b43ff68987fa" target="_hplink">The NSF Under The Microscope</a>&#8221; offered a rare glimpse into this motherhood-and-apple-pie agency that politicians question at their peril. Not many are brave enough to do so. After all, anyone who comes out against science funding risks being dragged through the mud as a climate denying creationist Neanderthal.</p>
<p>All I can say to those who take the ad hominem path is, do your worst. I was trained as a scientist. My whole career has been built around the fruits of scientific inquiry. I invest in scientists working to create products and services that improve our lives. Some of my best friends are scientists, including my son. It is entirely possible to be pro-science yet oppose wasteful spending, duplication, misplaced priorities, and the lack of accountability among those who consume taxpayer money. In fact, it is the duty of our elected representatives to do exactly that.</p>
<p>If you believe in democracy, then spending priorities must be set by the people. Removing entire fields of endeavor from accountability by placing them in the hands of unelected bureaucrats makes a mockery of democratic principles. Which makes sense if you prefer to be ruled by a benevolent dictator and his appointed minions. But at least be honest about it.</p>
<p>The real tragedy, aside from watching our federal government careen toward bankruptcy, is that big science has become a threat to innovative science.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/bill-frezza/scientists-outraged-that-_b_2926352.html">Full comment</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/bill-frezza-scientists-outraged-elected-reps-control-handouts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>US Senate Outlaws Government Funding For Political Science</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/senate-outlaws-government-funding-political-science/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/senate-outlaws-government-funding-political-science/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 16:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11301</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A measure limiting National Science Foundation funding for political science research projects passed the U.S. Senate on Wednesday, quietly dealing a blow to the government agency. Sen. Tom Coburn (R-Okla.) submitted a series of amendments to the Continuing Appropriations Act of 2013, the Senate bill to keep the government running past March 27. One of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>A measure limiting National Science Foundation funding for political science research projects passed the U.S. Senate on Wednesday, quietly dealing a blow to the government agency.</strong></p>
<p>Sen. Tom Coburn (R-Okla.) submitted a series of amendments to the Continuing Appropriations Act of 2013, the Senate bill to keep the government running past March 27. One of those amendments would prohibit the NSF from funding political science research unless a project is certified as &#8220;promoting national security or the economic interests of the United States.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Studies of presidential executive power and Americans&#8217; attitudes toward the Senate filibuster hold little promise to save an American&#8217;s life from a threatening condition or to advance America&#8217;s competitiveness in the world,&#8221; Coburn wrote in a letter to NSF director Subra Suresh last week explaining his proposal.</p>
<p>Coburn&#8217;s NSF amendment was approved by the Senate during a voice vote on Wednesday afternoon.</p>
<p>&#8220;I’m pleased the Senate accepted an amendment that restricts funding to low-priority political science grants,&#8221; Coburn said in a statement following the vote. &#8220;There is no reason to spend $251,000 studying Americans&#8217; attitudes toward the U.S. Senate when citizens can figure that out for free.&#8221;</p>
<p>NSF funding for such research has long been a target of Coburn&#8217;s. The Republican offered a similar amendment in 2009, and in 2011 released an oversight report on the NSF&#8217;s &#8220;mismanagement and misplaced priorities.&#8221;</p>
<p>The passage of Coburn&#8217;s amendment was met with backlash from members of the academic community, including the American Political Science Association.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/tom-coburn-national-science-foundation_n_2921081.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/senate-outlaws-government-funding-political-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK Energy Bill Illegal Under Existing EU Rules, Lawyers Claim</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/uk-energy-bill-illegal-existing-eu-rules-lawyers-claim/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/uk-energy-bill-illegal-existing-eu-rules-lawyers-claim/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 12:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11295</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Britain&#8217;s plans to reward nuclear plant operators through fixed prices for low-carbon energy are illegal under existing EU rules and efforts to adapt them are likely to draw opposition from other member states, EU and legal sources said. Britain plans to reform its electricity market to fix a minimum price for nuclear, wind and solar-generated [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Britain&#8217;s plans to reward nuclear plant operators through fixed prices for low-carbon energy are illegal under existing EU rules and efforts to adapt them are likely to draw opposition from other member states, EU and legal sources said.</strong></p>
<p>Britain plans to reform its electricity market to fix a minimum price for nuclear, wind and solar-generated power, which is carbon free.</p>
<p>The proposals are being assessed by the British parliament but the subsidy instruments, named contracts-for-difference (CfDs), will also require approval from the European Commission, the EU executive, under state aid rules.</p>
<p>&#8220;Neither under the current (&#8230;) nor under possible future frameworks could the CfD scheme for nuclear generators be declared compatible with European state aid rules,&#8221; said Doerte Fouquet, a lawyer specialised in EU law at Becker Buettner Held in Brussels.</p>
<p>The British government is already in talks with France&#8217;s EDF about a CfD for the company&#8217;s Hinkley point C nuclear project in south-west England, Britain&#8217;s first nuclear plant since 1995, which is expected to start operating around the turn of the decade.</p>
<p>The European Commission said it had not yet received a formal notification from Britain, but added that, in general, state aid is only authorised when the benefits of aid outweigh the distortion of competition brought about.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Britain&#8217;s Department of Energy and Climate Change said Britain was talking to the EU executive.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are working with the European Commission to ensure mechanisms and institutional arrangements within Electricity Market Reform are consistent with EU state aid rules,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/03/21/uk-eu-uk-nuclear-idUKBRE92K0WL20130321?irpc=401">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/uk-energy-bill-illegal-existing-eu-rules-lawyers-claim/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can Natural Gas Save Cyprus?</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/natural-gas-save-cyprus/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/natural-gas-save-cyprus/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11291</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After Cyprus was left scrambling to salvage a bailout package left nearly dead after a titanic misstep last week, the country’s new-found energy potential finally entered the conversation despite assurances from on high that it would not. Cyprus is one of a handful of countries in the Eastern Mediterranean with a firm claim on one [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>After Cyprus was left scrambling to salvage a bailout package left nearly dead after a titanic misstep last week, the country’s new-found energy potential finally entered the conversation despite assurances from on high that it would not.</strong></p>
<p>Cyprus is one of a handful of countries in the Eastern Mediterranean with a firm claim on one of the largest natural gas finds in the region, offering access to an estimated 50 to 60 tcf of gas and 1.7 billion barrels of crude in waters off its southeastern coast. If exploited with care, the reserves could bring in as much as $400 billion over the coming years, providing a boon to a deeply damaged economy as well as meet domestic demand.</p>
<p>Despite such promise, many local leaders have insisted that no pressure be put on the reserves until they actually start producing revenue, which they expect as early as 2018 or 2019. To do otherwise – and start securing loans on the back of future earnings – would be irresponsible and run the risk of selling off the country’s future at low rates; a sentiment held by Nicos Anastasiades, the center-right candidate who won national elections earlier this month. However, a new and potentially crippling development with the country’s banking system has cast doubt on the country’s immediate future, forcing the issue to the forefront of the country’s political and economic future.</p>
<p>First, for some background.</p>
<p>For those who missed it, Cyprus has been in search of a way to secure a bailout that some have put as high as the country’s annual GDP – $18.3 billion. After months of negotiations, the center-right’s Nicos Anastasiades won national elections behind the pledge to finally bring negotiations to an end and secure a support package from the European Union and the IMF. However, after four such bailouts of beleaguered EU economies, Anastasiades encountered some stiff resistance on the other side of the table. Instead of $18 billion, Cyprus was offered around $12.9. More importantly was how the EU and IMF expected the remainder to be met – with a one-time levy taken from accounts in Cyprus, with increasing rates applied to different balances. With hopes that the action would bring in about $7.5 billion, the plan was introduced to the public last week and was met with an almost immediate backlash from far and wide.</p>
<p>International observers called it misguided and critics called it bullying. Worse still, locals panicked and moved to withdraw their funds, only to be met with closed doors at the order of the government. Notably, Russia’s Vladimir Putin offered a sharp rebuke to the plan, calling it “unjust, unprofessional and dangerous” and it’s not difficult to imagine why. According to the AP, Russian companies have long appreciated the country’s “investor-friendly jurisdiction with lax banking regulations and low taxes” to the tune of $19 billion in current deposits.</p>
<p>Anastasiades and the parliament reacted with further delays on the vote to approve the plan, making its passage less and less likely with each passing hour. Finally, the government announced what they called Plan B, which “would require state pension funds to hand over about ($5.17) billion of their reserves.” The additional amount could come from Russia in exchange for an agreement freeing Russian companies with money in Cypriot banks from the one-time penalty.</p>
<p>Uneasy with the lack of local contributions, the EU and the IMF turned down the Plan B, issued a deadline for a final response (Monday March 25) and sent a firm message to Nicosia – to figure it out and fast.</p>
<p>So, with Cyprus short a few billion, their banks still shut and creditors increasingly nervous about what comes next, the question has become, where can they possibly find the money and for some, will the country’s natural gas claims play a part in where it comes from?</p>
<p>From where things stand now, it looks like Cyprus will be looking to expand on its relationship with Russia with an extension of an existing loan, an appeal for a lower interest rate and most importantly, introducing the role of untapped gas reserves to the conversation. According to a Reuters report, support could be backed up with investment efforts and direct shares of Cypriot gas reserves. Locally, the idea emerged that those depositors that kept their money in Cypriot banks for the next two years would receive bonds “linked to revenues from natural gas”. These options mark a stark difference to campaign rhetoric from Anastasiades, who insisted energy earnings be left alone until real revenues started flowing.</p>
<p>However, even with this change of pace from the country’s new leadership, Cyprus’ energy options may be limited. Put simply, the country’s gas claims are not yet proven, making deals made on the back of uncertain earnings all the more risky.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/christophercoats/2013/03/21/can-natural-gas-save-cyprus/?ss=business%3Aenergy">Full comment</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/natural-gas-save-cyprus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Big Oil And Big Greens Join Forces On Shale Fracking</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/big-oil-big-green-join-forces-shale-fracking/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/big-oil-big-green-join-forces-shale-fracking/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11287</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In an unlikely partnership between longtime adversaries, some of the nation&#8217;s biggest energy companies and environmental groups have agreed on a voluntary set of standards for gas and oil fracking in the Northeast that appear to go further than existing state and federal pollution regulations. The program announced Wednesday will work a lot like Underwriters [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>In an unlikely partnership between longtime adversaries, some of the nation&#8217;s biggest energy companies and environmental groups have agreed on a voluntary set of standards for gas and oil fracking in the Northeast that appear to go further than existing state and federal pollution regulations.</strong></p>
<p>The program announced Wednesday will work a lot like Underwriters Laboratories, which puts its UL seal of approval on electrical appliances that meet its standards. In this case, drilling and pipeline companies will be encouraged to submit to an independent review of their operations, and if they are found to be taking certain steps to protect the air and water, they will receive the blessing of the brand-new Pittsburgh-based Center for Sustainable Shale Development.</p>
<p>If the project succeeds, it could have far-reaching implications for both the industry and environmental groups. A nationwide boom in hydraulic fracturing, or fracking, has unleashed huge new energy reserves but also led to fears of pollution and climate change.</p>
<p>Shell Oil Vice President Paul Goodfellow said this is the first time the company and environmental groups have reached agreement to create an entire system for reducing the effects of shale drilling.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is something new,&#8221; said Bruce Niemeyer, president of Chevron Appalachia. &#8220;This is a bit of a unique coming-together of a variety of different interests.&#8221;</p>
<p>In addition to Shell and Chevron, the participants include the Environmental Defense Fund, the Clean Air Task Force, the Heinz Endowments, EQT Corp., Consol Energy and the Pennsylvania Environmental Council, and the organizers hope to recruit others.</p>
<p>It may be part of a trend. Earlier this month a coalition of industry and environmental groups in Illinois announced that they worked together on drilling legislation now pending there. But the Pittsburgh project, which has been in the works for nearly two years, would be voluntary.</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe it does send a signal to the federal government and other states,&#8221; said Armand Cohen, the director of the Boston-based Clean Air Task Force. &#8220;There&#8217;s no reason why anyone should be operating at standards less than these.&#8221;</p>
<p>The new standards include limits on emissions of methane, a potent greenhouse gas, and the flaring, or burning off, of unwanted gas; reductions in engine emissions; groundwater monitoring and protection; improved well designs; stricter wastewater disposal; the use of less toxic fracking fluids; and seismic monitoring before drilling begins.</p>
<p>The project will cover Pennsylvania, West Virginia and Ohio — where a frenzy of drilling is under way in the huge, gas-rich Marcellus and Utica Shale formations — as well as New York and other states in the East that have put a hold on new drilling.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/business/energy-firms-environmental-groups-agree-tough-new-fracking-standards-1C8975363">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/big-oil-big-green-join-forces-shale-fracking/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
