<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 10:14:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Hiding The Slaughter</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/hiding-slaughter/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/hiding-slaughter/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 10:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11254</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Big Wind hides the evidence of turbine bird kills &#8211; and gets rewarded. Here is how they do it.  In 1984 the California Energy Commission said “many institutional, engineering, environmental and economic issues must be resolved before the industry is secure and its growth can be assured.”  Though it was not clearly stated, the primary [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Big Wind hides the evidence of turbine bird kills &#8211; and gets rewarded. Here is how they do it. </strong></p>
<p>In 1984 the California Energy Commission said “many institutional, engineering, environmental and economic issues must be resolved before the industry is secure and its growth can be assured.”  Though it was not clearly stated, the primary environmental issue alluded to was the extreme hazard that wind turbines posed to raptors.</p>
<p>To hide this awful truth, strict wind farm operating guidelines were established – including high security, gag orders in leases and other agreements, and the prevention of accurate, meaningful mortality studies.</p>
<p>Since the early 1980s, the industry has known there is no way its propeller-style turbines could ever be safe for raptors. With exposed blade tips spinning in open space at speeds up to 200 mph, it was impossible. Wind developers also knew they would have a public relations nightmare if people ever learned how many eagles are actually being cut in half – or left with a smashed wing, to stumble around for days before dying.</p>
<p>For the industry this business plan has succeeded quite well in keeping a lid on the mortality problem.  While the public has some understanding that birds are killed bywind turbines, it doesn’t have a clue about the real mortality numbers. And the industry gets rewarded with subsidies, and immunity from endangered species and other wildlife laws.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Early studies identified the extent of the problem</strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">To fully grasp the wind turbine mortality problem, one needs to examine the </span><a style="font-size: 1.17em;" href="http://altamontsrc.org/alt_doc/cec_final_report_08_11_04.pdf"><span style="color: #000000;">2004 report </span></a><span style="color: #000000;">from the Altamont Pass Wind Resource Area (APWRA). The study lasted five years (1998-2003), and researchers did not have full access to all the Altamont turbines.</span></p>
<p>This careful, honest effort analyzed turbine characteristics in relation to mortality and estimated mortality from body counts compiled in careful searches. Researchers then adjusted mortality numbers by examining statistical data based on searcher efficiency and other factors, such as carcass removal by predators and scavengers. The report even suggested that the mortality estimates probably erred on the low side, due to missed carcasses and other human errors.</p>
<p>This study stands in marked contrast to studies being conducted today, especially the Wildlife Reporting Response System that is currently the only analysis happening or permitted at most wind farms. The WRRS is the power companies’ own fatality reporting system, and allows paid personnel to collect and count carcasses. It explains why mortality numbers are always on the low side and why many high-profile species are disappearing near turbine installations.</p>
<p>Incredibly, the APWRA report actually admitted: “We found one raptor carcass buried under rocks and another stuffed in a ground squirrel burrow. One operator neglected to inform us when a golden eagle was removed as part of the WRRS. Based on these experiences, it is possible that we missed other carcasses that were removed.” (Chap. 3, pg. 52) It’s easy to see how human “errors” keep bird mortality low.</p>
<p>The APWRA study also documented that raptor food sources, turbine sizes and turbine placement all directly affect raptor mortality. It was thus able to identify many of the most dangerous turbines or groups of turbines – those with a history of killing golden eagles, kestrels, burrowing owls and red-tailed hawks.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Studies worsen as turbines proliferate and increase in size</strong></p>
<p>The study also discussed how higher raptor mortality occurred when smaller towers were “upgraded” with larger turbines and proportionally longer blades. These wind turbines offered what raptors perceived as intermediate to very big windows of opportunity to fly through what looked like open spaces between towers, but were actually within the space occupied by much longer, rapidly moving rotor blades.</p>
<p>The result was significantly more fatalities of golden eagles, red-tailed hawks, American kestrels, burrowing owls, mallards, horned larks and western meadowlarks. Turbines with slower rotations per minute actually made it appear that there was more space and “greater windows of time.” This fooled birds, by giving them the illusion that they had open flight space between the rotating blades.</p>
<p>In fact, the illusion fools people, too. The newest turbines move their blades at 10-20 rotations per minute, which appears to be slow – but for their blade tips this translates into 100-200 mph!</p>
<p>All this was very important, because the industry was moving away from smaller turbines and installing much larger turbines, with much longer blades. However, the industry not only ignored the APWRA findings and rapidly installed thousands of these much larger turbines across America, despite their far greater dangers for birds and raptors. It also kept the APWRA out of the public’s awareness, and focused attention on new study results that reflected far less accurate (and honest) searches andsurveys.</p>
<p><a href="http://canadafreepress.com/index.php/article/53864">Full story </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/hiding-slaughter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Paper Finds CO2 Spiked To Levels Higher Than The Present During Termination Of Last Ice Age</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/paper-finds-co2-spiked-levels-higher-present-termination-ice-age/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/paper-finds-co2-spiked-levels-higher-present-termination-ice-age/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 10:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Climate Record]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11252</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A new paper published in Quaternary Science Reviews reconstructs CO2 levels during the termination of the last ice age and finds CO2 spiked to levels near or even exceeding those of the present, obviously without any human influence. According to the authors, &#8220;The record clearly demonstrates that [CO2 levels were] significantly higher than usually reported for the Last [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new paper published in <i>Quaternary Science Reviews</i> reconstructs CO2 levels during the termination of the last ice age and finds CO2 spiked to levels near or even exceeding those of the present, obviously without any human influence. According to the authors, &#8220;The record clearly demonstrates that [CO2 levels were] significantly higher than usually reported for the Last [Glacial] Termination,&#8221; with levels of up to ~425 ppm about 12,750 years ago, which exceeds the present CO2 concentration of 395 ppm.</p>
<table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" align="center">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0277379113000553-gr8.jpg"><img alt="" src="http://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0277379113000553-gr8.jpg" width="400" height="343" border="0" /></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Left graph shows CO2 concentrations varied dynamically between ~220-425 ppm from 14,000-11,500 years ago. Ice core comparison is shown at right.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<div></div>
<table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" align="center">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://i.imgur.com/rqIfm.jpg"><img alt="" src="http://i.imgur.com/rqIfm.jpg" width="400" height="225" border="0" /></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Related: From the paper by <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=5&amp;cad=rja&amp;ved=0CFAQFjAE&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Ficecap.us%2Fimages%2Fuploads%2F08_Beck-2.pdf&amp;ei=KvVIUcb4M-7FiwKpooGQBQ&amp;usg=AFQjCNFzbaTt4ETw-w39tBg7geCt3huJpA&amp;sig2=eny_ND0SZXKSn7LDuOa1tw">EG Beck </a>showing chemical measurements of CO2 levels of up to ~480 ppm during the 1800&#8242;s</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Related: <a href="http://hockeyschtick.blogspot.com/2012/08/new-blockbuster-paper-finds-man-made.html">New blockbuster paper finds man-made CO2 is not the driver of global warming</a></p>
<p><a href="http://hockeyschtick.blogspot.co.uk/2013/03/new-paper-finds-co2-levels-were-higher.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/paper-finds-co2-spiked-levels-higher-present-termination-ice-age/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adopt A Polar Bear? Have You Seen What They Do?</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/adopt-polar-bear-do/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/adopt-polar-bear-do/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 09:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11246</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Save the whale? That’s so 1970s. Now it’s the mighty polar bear that has become the poster child of the environmental movement. But are polar bears really facing extinction, or are they just a photogenic vehicle for promoting alarm about global warming? ‘Adopt a polar bear’, suggests the green NGO, WWF. WWF will even give [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Save the whale? That’s so 1970s. Now it’s the mighty polar bear that has become the poster child of the environmental movement. But are polar bears really facing extinction, or are they just a photogenic vehicle for promoting alarm about global warming?</b></p>
<div>
<p><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.wwf.org.uk/adoption/polarbear/">‘Adopt a polar bear’</a>, suggests the green NGO, WWF. WWF will even give you a cuddly toy polar bear for signing up. ‘Many scientists believe polar bears could be gone from most of their current range within 100 years’, says the WWF website, citing climate change as the major threat to the bears. Earlier this month, the US tried &#8211; and <a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-21703090">failed</a> - to persuade the <a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.cites.org/">Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species</a> (CITES), to ban cross-border trade in polar bears and their parts. The US lists the polar bear as a ‘threatened’ species, while the International Union for the Conservation of Nature lists it as a ‘vulnerable’ species.</p>
</div>
<p>The major claim is that climate change is causing the sea ice in the Arctic to melt earlier and refreeze later. As the <a href="http://www.alphagalileo.org/ViewItem.aspx?ItemId=129432&amp;CultureCode=en">press release</a> for a new paper in the <i>Journal of Animal Ecology</i>, released today, suggests, this makes life harder for polar bears. The paper’s researchers tracked female polar bears in the western Hudson Bay area of Canada from 1991 to 1997, and again from 2004 to 2009. According to the lead researcher, Dr Seth Cherry: ‘The data suggest that in recent years, polar bears are arriving on shore earlier in the summer and leaving later in the autumn. These are precisely the kind of changes one would expect to see as a result of a warming climate and may help explain some other studies that are showing declines in body condition and cub production.’</p>
<p>But before we start getting into a lather about the future of nature’s greatest land-based killing machines (sorry, I mean big furry canaries in the climate-change coalmine), it is worth noting that there are more optimistic voices around. Susan Crockford, an adjunct professor at the University of Victoria in Canada, has just produced a <a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/03/Crockford-Polar-Bears-3.pdf">short paper</a> for the Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF) called <i>Ten Good Reasons Not To Worry About Polar Bears</i>.</p>
<p>Crockford’s first point is that polar bears represent a ‘conservation success story’. The biggest threat to the bears in the past was hunting. Since 1973, when restrictions on hunting were introduced, it is commonly agreed that polar-bear numbers have bounced back from a low of around 10,000 to between 20,000 and 25,000. In addition, four sub-populations of polar bears are currently listed as ‘zero’, says Crockford, because they haven’t been surveyed. Add in those animals, and she argues that the true population figure could easily be between 27,000 and 32,000.</p>
<p>The only population <i>shown</i> to have declined in recent years &#8211; a fall in numbers described by Crockford as ‘modest’ &#8211; is the one in the western Hudson Bay area. Even here, claims that polar-bear numbers continue to decline are based on data that is ‘unpublished, woefully out of date, or both’, says Crockford. Polar bears have actually shown a remarkable ability to survive and thrive after months without food.</p>
<p>There’s also an assumption that the decline of Arctic ice in recent years must be due to manmade global warming, and that this change in ice conditions must be bad for polar bears. But global temperatures have barely changed since 1997, while the minimum level of Arctic sea ice has halved. That suggests other, more localised factors rather than global warming are responsible. Moreover, as Matt Ridley notes in an <a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/matt-ridley-listening-susan-crockford/">introduction</a> to Crockford’s paper, the ‘ideal habit for polar bears is first-year ice that lasts well into the summer, when they feed on fat young seals… The recent trend in most of the Arctic &#8211; no change in winter ice extent but a decline in late-summer ice extent &#8211; has been towards exactly this ideal combination.’</p>
<p><a href="http://www.spiked-online.com/site/article/13462/">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/adopt-polar-bear-do/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Even Scientists Are Cooling On Climate Change</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/scientists-cooling-climate-change/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/scientists-cooling-climate-change/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 09:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11242</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[WHAT do Peter Lilley, Andrew Tyrie, Philip Davies, Christopher Chope and I have in common? &#160; We were the only MPs to vote against the 2008 Climate Change Bill, which is to say we had by then considered all the evidence and found it wanting. For years we have endured insults. Behind the scenes Fiona [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>WHAT do Peter Lilley, Andrew Tyrie, Philip Davies, Christopher Chope and I have in common?</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We were the only MPs to vote against the 2008 Climate Change Bill, which is to say we had by then considered all the evidence and found it wanting.</p>
<p>For years we have endured insults.</p>
<p>Behind the scenes Fiona Bruce, normally the most courteous of broadcasters, called me a “flat-earther” to my face.</p>
<p>Others branded us “deniers” as if we were disputing the holocaust. The Al Gore film was accorded the status of Holy Writ. David Bellamy lost his job. Doubting scientists were scorned.</p>
<p>Nigel Lawson found it difficult to get his book An Appeal To Reason published.</p>
<p>In short there was an orthodoxy which was enforced with all the rigour of communism or fascism or, for that matter, the Spanish Inquisition. Dissenters must not be heard and global warming became a religion.</p>
<p>Well the dissenters have now been proved right.</p>
<p>Heaven knows how many billions of pounds later the world is now being told that actually the warming is so far off predictions that all bets are off and indeed the world’s temperature is static or falling.</p>
<p>So all those wind farms were in vain, as were all those expensive carbon-saving measures inflicted on industry and passed on in costs to you and me.</p>
<p>If I could tell that from the published Hadley Centre figures, the scientists must have known for years yet only now do they admit it. Why?</p>
<p>Heaven forbid that it should be because of all that money tied up in their research.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.express.co.uk/comment/columnists/ann-widdecombe/385446/Even-scientists-are-cooling-on-climate-change">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/scientists-cooling-climate-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK Promises Shale Gas Tax Breaks, Public Benefits</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/uk-promises-shale-gas-tax-breaks-public-benefits/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/uk-promises-shale-gas-tax-breaks-public-benefits/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 09:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11240</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Britain said on Wednesday it will introduce generous tax breaks for shale gas and tackle the nascent industry&#8217;s public perception problem by making sure local communities benefit from resources found in their areas. Chancellor George Osborne said in his annual budget announcement he will introduce a new gas field tax allowance for shale gas, an [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Britain said on Wednesday it will introduce generous tax breaks for shale gas and tackle the nascent industry&#8217;s public perception problem by making sure local communities benefit from resources found in their areas.</strong></p>
<p>Chancellor George Osborne said in his annual budget announcement he will introduce a new gas field tax allowance for shale gas, an industry that he expects can help kick-start Britain&#8217;s stagnant <a href="http://uk.reuters.com/finance/economy?lc=int_mb_1001">economy</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Shale gas is part of the future and we will make it happen,&#8221; he said while delivering his 2013 budget in parliament.</p>
<p>Britain, Europe&#8217;s largest gas consuming nation, lifted a ban on shale gas fracking in December and is counting on huge shale gas reserves to help cut its dependence on expensive gas imports and to contribute to state coffers.</p>
<p>In the United States, the discovery of abundant shale gas reserves has caused a plunge in gas prices and put the nation on the path towards energy independence.</p>
<p>However, environmental concerns regarding fracking, the technology which involves injecting water and chemicals to break rock formations and extract shale gas, and its potential to trigger earthquakes has led to growing public opposition.</p>
<p>Britain will now try to stem public concerns about shale gas by announcing proposals by this summer on how local communities will benefit from shale gas projects in their areas.</p>
<p>&#8220;While the <a id="itxthook0" href="http://uk.reuters.com/article/2013/03/20/uk-britain-budget-shale-idUKBRE92J0V520130320#" rel="nofollow">finance directors</a> of the developers might be quite keen on getting tax breaks, the PR and the local communities issues are probably the bigger hurdles for them to jump over and the government seems to be doing something to help that pressure,&#8221; said Ben Stansfield, senior associate at law firm Clifford Chance.</p>
<p><a href="http://uk.reuters.com/article/2013/03/20/uk-britain-budget-shale-idUKBRE92J0V520130320">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/uk-promises-shale-gas-tax-breaks-public-benefits/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Winter Snow Melt in Greenland Grossly Over-Estimated</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/winter-snow-melt-greenland-grossly-over-estimated/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/winter-snow-melt-greenland-grossly-over-estimated/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 09:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11237</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; The cumulative melt extent in Greenland is shown before the correction at left, and after at right. (Source: National Snow and Ice Data Center) Back in February, satellite observations indicated that snow was melting — in the dead of winter — across large portions of Greenland’s eastern coast. (I wrote about it here.) But [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/imageo/files/2013/03/Corrected-Melt.png"><img title="Corrected Melt" alt="" src="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/imageo/files/2013/03/Corrected-Melt.png" width="468" height="351" /></a></div>
<div>
<div id="post-main-1050">
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The cumulative melt extent in Greenland is shown before the correction at left, and after at right. (Source: National Snow and Ice Data Center)</p>
<p>Back in February, satellite observations indicated that snow was melting — in the dead of winter — across large portions of Greenland’s eastern coast. (I wrote about it <a href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/imageo/?p=291#.UUhq8dHwIsY" target="_blank">here</a>.) But now, it looks like the algorithm used to process data coming from the satellite was grossly over-estimating the melt.</p>
<p>The National Snow and Ice Data Center has revised the algorithm to better estimate conditions on the ground, and the result, posted to the <a href="http://nsidc.org/greenland-today/" target="_blank">Greenland Ice Sheet Today</a> web site last night, is seen above. Whereas the original estimate seemed to show upwards of 50 days of melting in some places from the first of the year until now, the revised algorithm reveals very little surface melt at all.</p>
<p><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/imageo/files/2013/03/Greenland-temp-anomaly.png"><img title="Greenland temp anomaly" alt="" src="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/imageo/files/2013/03/Greenland-temp-anomaly-300x244.png" width="180" height="146" /></a></p>
<p>What happened? “Despite the fact that it has been a warm winter, it has not exceeded the freezing point nearly as often as the algorithm indicated,” Ted Scambos, a research scientist with the NSIDC, told me in an email message yesterday. (Click on the thumbnail map above to see how temperatures in Greenland have departed from the norm.)</p>
<p>He continued:</p>
<blockquote><p>Your article was exactly what we were thinking at that point. But later work and data showed that we had a very unusual snowpack, much warmer (and warm at depth) than previously seen. This tripped our model for melt detection. We have now re-run the model with data from 2013, and we see far less melt than before.</p></blockquote>
<p>Something strange <em>was</em> happening, just not melting at the surface, Scambos says. It turns out that the <a href="http://nsidc.org/greenland-today/2013/02/greenland-melting-2012-in-review/" target="_blank">intense surface melt</a> that occurred last summer — which affected upwards of 97 percent of the Greenland Ice Sheet — left behind unusually warm snow. Heavy snowfall this winter then buried the warmer layers, according to the NSIDC. In addition, there’s some indication that meltwater from the summer remains unfrozen at about 5 meters beneath the surface. All of this contributed to the spurious readings indicating extensive melting.</p>
<p>“Fundamentally, this is still a story: very warm <a href="http://vulcan.wr.usgs.gov/Glossary/Glaciers/glacier_terminology.html" target="_blank">firn</a> is a result of the extreme melting season from last year,” Scambos says. “However, we are still awaiting the true start of the 2013 melt season (at least, for 99.9% of the island).”</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/imageo/?p=1050#.UUrS-hxSg7r">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/winter-snow-melt-greenland-grossly-over-estimated/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia, Saudi Arabia Hope To Emulate U.S. Shale Boom</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/russia-saudi-arabia-hope-emulate-u-s-shale-boom/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/russia-saudi-arabia-hope-emulate-u-s-shale-boom/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 09:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11234</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fracking isn’t just for shale. In Russia, producers are importing techniques from the U.S. to squeeze billions of dollars of extra oil from Soviet-era fields. TNK-BP, Russia’s third-largest producer, will use hydraulic fracturing combined with horizontal drilling in almost half the wells it sinks this year, a sixfold increase in just two years, the company [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fracking isn’t just for shale. In Russia, producers are importing techniques from the U.S. to squeeze billions of dollars of extra oil from Soviet-era fields.</strong></p>
<p>TNK-BP, Russia’s third-largest producer, will use hydraulic fracturing combined with horizontal drilling in almost half the wells it sinks this year, a sixfold increase in just two years, the company said. OAO Rosneft, OAO Lukoil and OAO Gazprom Neft have similar plans.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Saudi Arabia, the world’s biggest oil exporter, will drill about seven test wells for shale gas this year, according to Oil Minister Ali Al-Naimi.</p>
<p>“We know where the areas are,” Al-Naimi said at a conference in Hong Kong Monday, referring to the country’s shale gas deposits. “We have rough estimates of over 600 trillion cubic feet of unconventional and shale gas so the potential is very huge and we plan to exploit it.”</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia is seeking to develop its natural gas resources to meet rising domestic energy demand. Saudi Arabian Oil Co., or Saudi Aramco, is searching for shale gas in the northwest of the country as it explores for unconventional resources such as sour gas in the oil-rich eastern region and in the Empty Quarter deserts, Senior Vice President of Upstream Amin Nasser told a conference March 10 in Manama.</p>
<p>The nation may hold as much as 645 trillion cubic feet of technically recoverable shale gas, the world’s fifth-largest deposits, behind China, the U.S., Argentina and Mexico, according to estimates by Baker Hughes Inc. The kingdom also has about 282.6 trillion cubic feet of proven conventional gas reserves, according to Aramco’s 2011 annual report.</p>
<p><strong>Russian Winter</strong></p>
<p>So-called fracking, the process of blasting oil from rock by injecting a mixture of water, sand and chemicals into wells, has been used for years in Russia’s Siberian oil heartland to stimulate production. What’s new is allying it with horizontal drilling, turning the drill-bit 90 degrees to bore horizontally to reach more oil-bearing rock. The pairing was perfected in the U.S. to get economically viable flows out of shale deposits. Used in Russia, producers are recovering 15 percent more crude from aging deposits.</p>
<p>“This is a very big change in the way the company approaches production that has literally happened in the last year and a half,” said Gazprom Neft’s deputy chief executive officer. “We have made breakthroughs.”</p>
<p>Enhancing production from decades-old fields is needed to maintain Russia’s crude production above 10 million barrels a day for a fourth year, a figure that surpasses Saudi Arabia and the U.S., said Cliff Kupchan, an analyst at Eurasia Group. Apart from the Russian state, which gets half its revenue from oil and gas, the other winners are suppliers of people and equipment to frack wells including Schlumberger Ltd., Weatherford International Ltd. and C.A.T. Oil AG.</p>
<p><strong>Enhanced Production</strong></p>
<p>“Rosneft is becoming a more technologically advanced company,” Igor Sechin, chief executive officer of Russia’s largest producer, said in a speech in Houston this month.</p>
<p>State-controlled Rosneft will employ the technique at 50 wells this year at its largest production unit, up from just three in 2012, according to a company presentation. Gazprom Neft, the oil unit of Russia’s natural gas monopoly, will double the number of wells where fracks are used this year.</p>
<p>Lukoil, Russia’s second-largest producer, plans to use fracking in 55 horizontal wells over nine years to raise projected production 15 percent at Urevskoye, a 60,000 barrel-a day Siberian field that first started pumping in the 1970s, a company presentation showed. The company expects to get an extra 35 million barrels from the field, valued at about $3.7 billion based on today’s price for Russia’s benchmark grade.</p>
<p><a href="http://business.financialpost.com/2013/03/18/russia-saudi-arabia-hope-to-emulate-u-s-shale-boom/?__lsa=d6d3-7896">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/russia-saudi-arabia-hope-emulate-u-s-shale-boom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Playing Hockey – Blowing The Whistle</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/playing-hockey-blowing-whistle/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/playing-hockey-blowing-whistle/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 09:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Climate Record]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11225</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This instantly ‘famous’ 2013 Science hockey stick paper derived from Marcott’s 2011 Ph.D thesis at Oregon State University, available here. His thesis doesn’t show a hockey stick ‘blade’ projecting above its anomaly baseline NCDC 1961-1990. H/T to Jean S, posted at Climate Audit. Something changed after the thesis was published to produce the new ‘blade’ in Science. That something was [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This instantly ‘famous’ 2013 Science hockey stick paper derived from Marcott’s 2011 Ph.D thesis at Oregon State University, available <a href="http://ir.library.oregonstate.edu/xmlui/handle/1957/89/browse?value=Marcott%2C+Shaun+Andrew&amp;type=author">here</a>. His thesis doesn’t show a hockey stick ‘blade’ projecting above its anomaly baseline NCDC 1961-1990. H/T to Jean S, posted at <i>Climate Audit</i>. Something changed after the thesis was published to produce the new ‘blade’ in Science. That something was significant, since the Science paper’s Supplementary Information discussion said it <i>did not </i>enable<i> </i>discriminating such a temperature variation (i.e. a<i> </i>‘blade’) on such a short a time scale.</p>
<p>See my previous post here, <a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://judithcurry.com/2013/03/11/lets-play-hockey-again/">Lets Play Hockey Again</a>, which was right about the Medieval Warm Period (MWP) but wrong about the ‘blade origins. Mea Culpa. Here we deduce whence the ‘blade’ came using ‘crowd-sourced’ science.</p>
<p>First, SI table S1 and thesis figure C1 confirm both use exactly the same 73 proxy records. The only difference is that thesis series MD98-2181 was renamed KY07-04-01 in the SI.</p>
<p>Second, thesis figure C7 graphed each proxy series individually using the mean and 2 sigma error band from its Monte Carlo statistical error estimation technique. A visual check confirms that there is no near T0 (1950) ‘blade’ visible in any of 73 dithered proxies, although five have distinct upticks near ‘present’ (the past 100-200 years or so visually). These include Dome C (Antarctic ice core δD with ±30% uncertainty), MD98-2165 (equatorial Mg/Ca), TN057.17 (temperate diatom mat with ±0.75°C uncertainty), Agassiz Renland (Arctic borehole δ<sup>18</sup>O with ±30% uncertainty), and GeoB3910, an equatorial alkenone. The thesis itself shows (below) that these are insufficient to uptick the ensemble.</p>
<p>Importantly for what follows, figure C7 also shows start and end dates for each proxy series as given by their references, along with their proxy age/date [radioisotope] controls. 20 unequivocally carried through about 1850, and 9 extended beyond T0 (1950). All the other proxies ended earlier in time. For example, proxy MD95-2043 (Cacho 2001, alkenone, Western Mediterranean) ended about 942 AD per its reference, with a notable ending uptick from the Medieval Warm Period. Remember this proxy for a couple of pages more.</p>
<p>Third, the outstanding Ph.D thesis on which this Science paper was based does not contain a hockey stick ‘blade’ anywhere. We can compare five important correlated pieces of information from its chapter 4 and supplemental data to deduce where and how the Science ‘blade’ originated. To start, both 2000-year reconstructions were compared to <a href="http://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/paleo/pubs/mann2008/mann2008.html">Mann 2008</a>. The purple lines are the ‘standard’ simple area weighted mean 5×5 grid reconstructions.</p>
<p><a href="http://curryja.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/marcott-images-for-curry-1.jpg"><img alt="Marcott images for Curry 1" src="http://curryja.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/marcott-images-for-curry-1.jpg?w=1000&amp;h=750" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p>The Science ‘blade’ is obvious. It does not exist in the thesis.<b> </b>Something changed.<b>          </b><b>  </b></p>
<p><em id="__mceDel"><b><a href="http://curryja.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/marcott-images-for-curry-2.jpg"><img alt="Marcott images for Curry 2" src="http://curryja.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/marcott-images-for-curry-2.jpg?w=1000&amp;h=750" width="500" height="375" /></a></b></em></p>
<p>The ‘blade’ (above anomaly baseline) is visibly present in all Sciencereconstruction methods, yet in none in the thesis. It is therefore not an artifact of the various reconstruction methodologies. Something changed in either the data or in the data processing algorithms to produce the blade in Science.</p>
<p><a href="http://curryja.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/marcott-images-for-curry-3.jpg"><img alt="Marcott images for Curry 3" src="http://curryja.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/marcott-images-for-curry-3.jpg?w=1000&amp;h=750" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p>The blade is obvious in the mean of all 1000 dithered Monte Carlo proxy simulations in Science, yet is non-existent in the equivalent 10000-simulation thesis mean. The thesis error band widens symmetrically and significantly as T0 is approached. It must, given that Science reported the mean proxy resolution is 180 years, and the median is 120 years. This validates the thesis’ basic statistical algorithm as directionally correct and obviously useful.</p>
<p><a href="http://curryja.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/marcott-images-for-curry-4.jpg"><img alt="Marcott images for Curry 4" src="http://curryja.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/marcott-images-for-curry-4.jpg?w=1000&amp;h=750" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p>The schematic algorithms used to generate the above error information are identical. Without comparing the underlying code, it is impossible to ascertain with complete certainty that there was no algorithm change in Science. But beyond any reasonable doubt, the ‘blade’ arose from some data change rather than from some algorithm change</p>
<p><a href="http://curryja.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/marcott-images-for-curry-5.jpg"><img alt="Marcott images for Curry 5" src="http://curryja.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/marcott-images-for-curry-5.jpg?w=1000&amp;h=750" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p>The ‘blade’ is only present in data for figure S12a’s 20-year sampled reconstruction after 1900.  It is not present in the 100-year version that goes to 1900, and which closely tracks the 20-year version to that time. Although lower frequency sampling will mask any earlier changes, significant data changes obviously occurred in the years after 1900 where the blade arose.</p>
<p><a href="http://curryja.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/marcott-images-for-curry-6.jpg"><img alt="Marcott images for Curry 6" src="http://curryja.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/marcott-images-for-curry-6.jpg?w=1000&amp;h=750" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p>The latitude coverage in Science and the thesis is identical (horizontal grey bars). It has to be, since using the same proxies. The number of Mann2008 proxy records increases identically as the present is approached (vertical tan bars). They have to, since the same study. In both Science and the thesis, the number of Holocene proxies available at ‘2000’ is identically about 70. It should be. (And actually is <i>exactly</i> 70 based on scrutiny of thesis figure C7). These figures appear to be accurate visual representations of the underlying analytical facts.</p>
<p><i>But the number of Holocene proxies is <b>not </b>the same after about 1550</i> (500 before T0). Oddly, Science includes <i>more</i> proxies until after 1900. Even more oddly, in the thesis 9 ‘survived’ 1950, yet in Science <i>none</i> did.</p>
<p><b><i>Zero</i></b>. <i>And that is the proverbial smoking gun.</i> The data were changed by re-dating, and Science figure 1G proves it without digging into proxy details buried deep within the SI proxy data spreadsheets.</p>
<p><a href="http://judithcurry.com/2013/03/19/playing-hockey-blowing-the-whistle/">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/playing-hockey-blowing-whistle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Avoid Like The Plague</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/avoid-plague/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/avoid-plague/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 09:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11222</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sir John Beddington&#8217;s speech to the AVOID symposium is quite interesting. He takes a pop at GWPF&#8217;s Lord Turnbull, in particular with what he says is a claim that temperatures haven&#8217;t gone up for a decade. Beddington seeks to refute this claim with a graph of decadal averages temperatures. How one would know what has [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sir John Beddington&#8217;s speech to the AVOID symposium is quite interesting. He takes a pop at GWPF&#8217;s Lord Turnbull, in particular with what he says is a claim that temperatures haven&#8217;t gone up for a decade. Beddington seeks to refute this claim with a graph of decadal averages temperatures.</p>
<p>How one would know what has happened to temperatures in the last decade from a figure for the average temperature over 2001-2010 is anybody&#8217;s guess. This is probably a form of mathematics to which only the Government Chief Scientific Adviser is privy.</p>
<p>The arguments over sea ice are more interesting. I see the decline in Arctic sea ice and, like Lord Turnbull, am surprised that the extent seems to return to normal over the winter. One would have thought that since the poles are warming as rapidly as we are told, the winter ice recovery would be less each year. I should also mention that I always view discussion of the Arctic without mention of the Antarctic as fairly naked cherry-picking. As we know, the IPCC says Antarctic ice should be in decline too.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bishop-hill.net/blog/2013/3/19/avoid-like-the-plague.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/avoid-plague/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>New paper shows Greenland was warmer during the 1930&#8242;s and 1400&#8242;s than the present</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/paper-shows-greenland-warmer-1930s-1400s-present/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/paper-shows-greenland-warmer-1930s-1400s-present/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 09:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11215</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A new paper published in Climate of the Past reconstructs Greenland temperatures over the past 800 years and shows that reconstructed temperatures were higher in the 1930&#8242;s and 1400&#8242;s than at the end of the record in the year 2000. The paper also finds Greenland temperatures correlated to &#8220;solar-induced changes in atmospheric circulation patterns such as those [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new paper published in <i>Climate of the Past </i>reconstructs Greenland temperatures over the past 800 years and shows that reconstructed temperatures were higher in the 1930&#8242;s and 1400&#8242;s than at the end of the record in the year 2000. The paper also finds Greenland temperatures correlated to &#8220;solar-induced changes in atmospheric circulation patterns such as those produced by the North Atlantic Oscillation/Arctic Oscillation (NAO/AO).&#8221; The Medieval Warming Period 1000 years ago is not included in this 800 year reconstruction, but <a href="http://seeker401.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/gisp2-ice-core-temperatures.jpg?w=497&amp;h=372">Greenland ice cores demonstrate</a> that the Medieval, Roman, Minoan, Egyptian, and other unnamed warming periods were all warmer than modern Greenland temperatures.</p>
<div>
<table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" align="center">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZJi1ONNuDBs/UUjmpFpcCZI/AAAAAAAAFFc/bAkTkVW8qB4/s1600/Fullscreen%2Bcapture%2B3192013%2B32732%2BPM.jpg"><img alt="" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZJi1ONNuDBs/UUjmpFpcCZI/AAAAAAAAFFc/bAkTkVW8qB4/s400/Fullscreen%2Bcapture%2B3192013%2B32732%2BPM.jpg" border="0" /></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Reconstructed Greenland temperatures shown in blue bottom graph were higher in the 1930&#8242;s and 1400&#8242;s than at the end of the record in the year 2000. Michael Mann&#8217;s bogus hockey stick is shown for comparison in green in top graph.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://hockeyschtick.blogspot.co.uk/2013/03/new-paper-shows-greenland-was-warmer.html">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/paper-shows-greenland-warmer-1930s-1400s-present/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
