<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 17:01:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Upside-Down World: Shale Revolution Sparks &#8216;Peak Oil Demand&#8217; Theory</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/upside-down-world-shale-revolution-sparks-peak-oil-demand-theory/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/upside-down-world-shale-revolution-sparks-peak-oil-demand-theory/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 17:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11705</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s a new &#8216;peak oil&#8217; theory doing the rounds, this time with a twist: instead of an imminent peak (and subsequent decline) in global oil supplies that causes oil prices to soar, oil demand growth is expected to slow down more quickly than expected and this will result in lower oil prices going forward. In [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>There&#8217;s a new &#8216;peak oil&#8217; theory doing the rounds, this time with a twist: instead of an imminent peak (and subsequent decline) in global oil supplies that causes oil prices to soar, oil demand growth is expected to slow down more quickly than expected and this will result in lower oil prices going forward.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Energy revolution sparks 'peak oil demand' theory" src="http://im.investorschronicle.co.uk/rw/FT%20Publications/IC/Images/Generic%20Photos/M-R/Oil_Dollar_452x339_040413.jpg" width="362" height="271" /></p>
<p>In a report titled, &#8216;Global Oil Demand Growth &#8211; The End is Nigh&#8217;, commodities analysts at Citigroup predict that oil demand growth is likely to be hindered by cheaper substitutes and improvements in fuel efficiency.</p>
<p>A boom in US shale gas production has caused natural gas prices there to plummet, and that in turn is enticing industrial energy users to switch to gas-fired power generation rather than oil- or diesel-based power generation. Continued improvements in automobile fuel economy will also limit demand growth from emerging economies, with Citigroup predicting fuel usage will drop by an average of 2.5 per cent per new vehicle each year.</p>
<p>Citi&#8217;s long-term view is that the structural bull market of the previous 10 years or so will not be repeated this decade; instead, &#8220;by the end of the decade Brent [oil] prices are likely to hover within a range of $80 (£53) to $90 per barrel&#8221;. That&#8217;s down from about $111 a barrel today. However, that theory rests on certain technologies being widely adopted &#8211; such as large-scale gas-fired trucks, trains and ships &#8211; as well as continued anti-carbon policy adoption by governments.</p>
<p>Even economists at perennially bullish BP admit rising unconventional energy supplies are playing their part to limit further big price gains. In its BP Energy Outlook 2030, the company forecasts global shale gas production will more than treble and tight oil supplies will rise more than six-fold over the next two decades.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.investorschronicle.co.uk/2013/04/04/shares/news-and-analysis/energy-revolution-sparks-peak-oil-demand-theory-YChxLiPcEzBBbt0w2QvRcI/article.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/upside-down-world-shale-revolution-sparks-peak-oil-demand-theory/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robert Tracinski: The End Of An Illusion</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/robert-tracinski-illusion/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/robert-tracinski-illusion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 16:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11702</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re reaching the point where climate predictions have been around long enough to allow for significant comparison against the actual data, and we are now able to say definitively that the predictions were horribly exaggerated. Many years ago, I remember thinking that it would take many years to refute the panicked claims about global warming. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>We&#8217;re reaching the point where climate predictions have been around long enough to allow for significant comparison against the actual data, and we are now able to say definitively that the predictions were horribly exaggerated.</strong></p>
<p>Many years ago, I remember thinking that it would take many years to refute the panicked claims about global warming. Unlike most political movements, which content themselves with making promises about, say, what the unemployment rate will be in two years if we pass a giant stimulus bill—claims that are proven wrong (and how!) relatively quickly—the environmentalists had successfully managed to put their claims so far off into the future that it would take decades to test them against reality.</p>
<p>But guess what? The decades are finally here.</p>
<div>
<div id="article-box-ad">
<div id="google_ads_div_RC_300_by_250_middle_ad_wrapper">
<div id="google_ads_div_RC_300_by_250_middle_ad_container">At Forbes, Harry Binswanger dates the beginning of the campaign to 1979 and <a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/harrybinswanger/2013/04/03/global-warming-was-it-just-a-beautiful-dream-after-all/">puts it</a> in an amusing perspective.</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><em>&#8220;Remember 1979? That was the year of &#8216;We Are Family&#8217; by Sister Sledge, of &#8216;The Dukes of Hazard&#8217; on TV, and of Kramer vs. Kramer on the silver screen. It was the year the Shah was forced out of Iran. It was before the web, before the personal computer, before the cell phone, before voicemail and answering machines. But not before the global warming campaign.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;In January of 1979, a New York Times article was headlined: &#8216;Experts Tell How Antarctic Ice Could Cause Widespread Floods.&#8217;&#8230;</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;So where&#8217;s the warming? Where are the gondolas pulling up to the Capitol? Where are the encroaching seas in Florida? Or anywhere? Where is the climate change which, for 33 years, has been just around the corner?&#8221;</em></p>
<p>He concludes that &#8220;I&#8217;ve grown old waiting for the promised global warming.&#8221; Literally: &#8220;I was 35 when predictions of a looming ice age were supplanted by warmmongering. Now I&#8217;m 68, and there&#8217;s still no sign of warmer weather.&#8221;</p>
<p>He puts the issue in terms of common-sense observation. But it can also be measured in terms of hard data. We&#8217;re reaching the point where the predictions have been around long enough to allow for significant comparison against the actual data, and we are now able to say definitively that the predictions were horribly exaggerated.</p>
<p>Steven Hayward <a href="http://www.powerlineblog.com/archives/2013/03/climate-change-endgame-in-sight.php">points</a> to signs that even advocates of the global warming hysteria are starting to backtrack.</p>
<p><em>&#8220;The new issue of The Economist has a long feature on the declining confidence in the high estimates of climate sensitivity. That this appears in The Economist is significant, because this august British news organ has been fully on board with climate alarmism for years now. A Washington-based Economist correspondent admitted to me privately several years ago that the senior editors in London had mandated consistent and regular alarmist climate coverage in its pages.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;The problem for the climateers is increasingly dire. As The Economist shows in its first chart (Figure 1 here), the recent temperature record is now falling distinctly to the very low end of its predicted range and may soon fall out of it, which means the models are wrong, or, at the very least, that there&#8217;s something going on that supposedly &#8216;settled&#8217; science hasn&#8217;t been able to settle.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>See a better version of that graph <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2294560/The-great-green-1-The-hard-proof-finally-shows-global-warming-forecasts-costing-billions-WRONG-along.html">here</a>, which makes it clear that the actual predictions in the graph date only to about 2006—and they are already being proven wrong.</p>
<p>You know, you can really manipulate a graph to spin the data, for example, by manipulating the scale to &#8220;zoom in&#8221; and make something look bigger or &#8220;zoom out&#8221; to make it look smaller. We&#8217;re used to seeing the zoomed-in version of global temperature measurements, so it&#8217;s nice to see this zoomed-out version:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="http://www.realclearpolitics.com/images/wysiwyg_images/globaltemp.gif" width="258" height="286" border="0" /></p>
<p>Rather than narrowing in to measure minor variations from the long-term average, which makes annual variations of a few tenths of a degree look enormous, this one zooms out to show us the data in terms of absolute temperature measurements, in which the annual variations over the past 15 years look as insignificant as they really are.</p>
<p>So basically, all that the global warming advocates really have, as the evidentiary basis for their theory, is that global temperatures were a little higher than usual in the late 1990s. That&#8217;s it. Which proves nothing. The climate varies, just as weather varies, and as far as we can tell, this is all well within the normal range.</p>
<p>That has been one of my complaints about the global warming scare since the very beginning. We only have systematic global temperature measurements going back about 150 years, which on the relevant timescale—a geological time-scale—is a blink of an eye. Moreover, the measurement methods for these global temperatures have been not been entirely consistent, making them susceptible to changes due to everything from a different paint used on the outside of the weather station to the &#8220;urban heat island&#8221; effect that happens when a weather station in the middle of a field is surrounded over the years by parking lots. And somehow, among all the billions spent on global warming research, not much money seems to have made its way to the enormous international effort that would be required to ensure the accurate and consistent measurement of global temperatures.</p>
<p>So we have not been able to establish what ought to be the starting point for any theory about global temperatures: a baseline for what is a normal global temperature and what is a natural variation in temperature.</p>
<p>In an effort to fill in this gap—without ever admitting what a fundamental problem it is—the alarmists have made several attempts to patch together a much longer record of global temperatures, going back thousands of years. Michael Mann set the tone for this with his infamous &#8220;hockey stick&#8221; graph purporting to show temperatures going back 1,000 years, with recent temperatures spiking up ominously like the blade on a hockey stick.</p>
<p>But Mann&#8217;s hockey stick came under withering fire for its dodgy statistical methods and selective use of data and has since been pretty much <a href="http://wattsupwiththat.com/2012/10/28/manns-hockey-stick-disappears-and-crus-briffa-helps-make-the-mwp-live-again-by-pointing-out-bias-in-ther-data/">abandoned</a>. But that hasn&#8217;t kept the warmists from trying again, this time with a new graph, named after lead study author Shaun Marcott, purporting to show global temperatures over the past 11,300 years, this time with a new, even bigger &#8220;blade&#8221; to the hockey stick showing the supposed upward thrust of temperatures in the past 100 years.</p>
<p>Except that the whole thing is dissolving in another fiasco.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.realclearpolitics.com/articles/2013/04/04/the_end_of_an_illusion_117795.html"><span style="font-size: 13px;">Full comment</span></p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/robert-tracinski-illusion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Lacking &#8220;Hot Spot&#8221; Above The Tropics</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/lacking-hot-spot-tropics/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/lacking-hot-spot-tropics/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 14:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11692</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[High above the tropics, the air should warm particularly strongly according to climate models. But the observed temperature has risen much less than predicted. More and more researchers acknowledge the problem. One of the most persistent debates in climate research is about the air temperatures in the tropics. It has all the ingredients, which are [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><b>High above the tropics, the air should warm particularly strongly according to climate models. But the observed temperature has risen much less than predicted. More and more researchers acknowledge the problem.</b></h2>
<p>One of the most persistent debates in climate research is about the air temperatures in the tropics. It has all the ingredients, which are so characteristic for the geosciences: disputes about the accuracy of data and the realism of computer models &#8211; and the excited elevation as &#8220;strife&#8221; in the public sphere. Gradually, though, the view that the climate models have a real problem in the region near the equator appears to become accepted.</p>
<p><strong style="font-size: 1em;">Troposphere &#8220;too cold&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>At its core, the debate revolves around the extent to which the temperature in the tropics rises through the increase of greenhouse gases. According to climate models, the heating should be particularly pronounced there at a height of eight to twelve kilometers, i.e. in the &#8220;mid-troposphere&#8221;.</p>
<p>Each model shows a slightly different behaviour. So every few years, climate scientists put their heads together and compare their computer models. ‘Coupled Model Intercomparison Project Phase 5’ (CMIP5) was the title of the latest of these meetings. According to the examined models, the temperature of the tropical mid-troposphere should have increased on average by 0.3 degrees Celsius per decade since 1979 &#8211; more than anywhere else in the atmosphere (except for the surface air in the Arctic). One therefore also speaks of a &#8220;hotspot&#8221; in the tropics. The temperature there should also climb twice as fast as on the ground below.</p>
<p>The measurements, however, show a very different picture. Satellites show a warming of about 0.1 to 0.2 degrees per decade for the hotspot from 1979 to 2012 &#8211; only about half of what most models came up with, and the rate of warming is similar to the one on the ground.</p>
<p>1979 was chosen as the base year, because at that time the temperature measurements started with American weather satellites, which have specialized measuring instruments on board: The &#8220;Microwave Sounding Units» absorb microwave radiation, which is emitted by the element oxygen. From this signal, the temperature of various layers of air can be determined with a complex algorithm. The fact that the emission band of oxygen varies widely depending on the temperature is exploited. The measurement process has been refined over the years.</p>
<p><strong>Weather data for the climate</strong></p>
<p>From the perspective of climate scientists, however, the method suffers because the data are collected primarily for the weather forecast. For forecasters the long-term stability of the measuring instruments is not as important. Satellites, however, change their course, instruments age, and, when a satellite is replaced by newer one, connection errors can occur. For climate scientists, suppressing erroneous trends in the measurements is central &#8211; they want to measure the true trend.</p>
<p>If there was not enough to debate about satellites and models, there are also other measurements. Since the 1950s, meteorologists have ascended weather balloons in the tropics to collect vertical profiles. These data also serve actually for weather forecasts. With the data from the balloons, a warming of 0.1-0.2 degrees Celsius per decade has been <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2012GL053850/abstract;jsessionid=766E9EC14201CA67399EA802279D13B8.d02t02" target="_blank">determined</a> since 1979. Again, these observations are below the results of most computer models.</p>
<p>But the accuracy of the balloon measurements is also controversial. For example, if the sun shines on a weather balloon, then the tank with the measurement instruments heats up. This effect and other falsifying influences must be subtracted from the data later.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="http://images.nzz.ch/app.php/eos/v2/image/view/643/-/text/9bae29f2/1.18057023.1364912947.jpg" width="514" height="317" /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong style="font-size: 13px;">Combined data sources</strong></p>
<p>In addition to the measurements from satellites and balloons, there is a third data set, which is used more and more frequently. These are the so-called ‘re-analysis’ of meteorological services. In this method, the weather of past decades with its meteorological characteristic values is determined as precisely as possible, using forecast models &#8211; in retrospect (thus ‘re-analysis’). The re-analysis data of the European Centre for Weather show for the tropical middle troposphere a trend of about 0.1 degrees warming per decade since 1979.</p>
<p>Taking the data from the satellites, weather balloons and the re-analysis together, it seems to be clear <em>prima facie</em>  that the models are wrong given that they have been suggesting strong warming in the tropical mid-troposphere. The &#8220;missing hotspot&#8221; argument is often used by climate sceptics who doubt that mankind is drastically changing the climate by adding greenhouse gases.</p>
<p>However, scientists see things different: In recent years, they have discussed intensely whether the large uncertainties in the measured data and the model simulations even allow a clear statement of the probable trend difference &#8211; whether the difference is ‘significant’ in a statistical sense. Only when this significance is determined can it be said with conviction that something with the models is wrong. Peter Thorne of the University of East Anglia says that this proof could probably only be established in twenty years when more reliable measurement systems would have been operating long enough.</p>
<p>Significance or not &#8211; in recent months, several studies have been published whose authors have acknowledged the problem with the hotspot. On average, the CMIP5 models would underestimate the warming of the troposphere, wrote a team around the Californian researcher Benjamin Santer recently in the <a href="http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2012/11/28/1210514109.abstract" target="_blank">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences Journal</a>. Even in one of the drafts for the first part of the 5<sup>th</sup> Assessment Report by the IPCC, which will be published later this year, the authors acknowledged that most models show a discrepancy.</p>
<p><strong>Unclear impact</strong></p>
<p>The cause of the problem with the hot spot is probably shower and thunderstorm clouds that grow up to 16 kilometres into the sky in the tropics. A lot of water vapour is transported very up into the troposphere. For global climate models, simplistic assumptions (so-called parameterisations) have to be made in this context as the clouds themselves cannot be spatially resolved in the models because of their relatively small size.</p>
<p>If the hotspot of the models turns out false, this means first of all that in the tropical mid-troposphere, the moisture increase is lower than expected. Since water vapour is the main greenhouse gas on the planet, one could thus naively assume that global warming is weaker if there is no hotspot. But things are not so simple. In the climate system, there are so many feedback mechanisms going on that today no scientist can tell what the result would be of the corrected model simulations – because for this one would have to know first what the correction actually is.</p>
<p><strong>Hoping for more accurate models</strong></p>
<p>But what the observed discrepancy shows is the fact that climate change in the tropics is not yet fully understood and cannot yet be realistically re-constructed with climate models. This is also suggested by the fact that in a higher layer of air, the tropical lower stratosphere, the simulated and observed values ​​also diverge. There, the models have <a href="http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2012/11/28/1210514109.abstract" target="_blank">simulated</a> excessive cooling of the air. Both the water vapour and the gas ozone play a decisive role for the temperature changes.</p>
<p>The problems with the climate models are likely to be solved eventually. Year after year, the spatial and temporal resolution is increasing, so that more processes can be explicitly considered in the atmosphere. One day this will also apply to the tropical thunderstorm clouds.</p>
<p>And something is also happening with the measurements: Currently, a global reference network for climate measurements in higher air layers (&#8216;GRUAN&#8217;) is being built. In the future, particularly well calibrated weather balloons will rise at 30 to 40 stations around the globe to collect climatic temperature trends accurately. Many national meteorological services are involved in the project, including Meteo Switzerland. The involved researchers hope that with GRUAN they can finally achieve the desired accuracy of climate trends in the tropical troposphere. For now, however, the climate scientists have with the missing hotspot a stumbling block in front of them, which is too hard for them.</p>
<p><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.nzz.ch/wissen/wissenschaft/der-fehlende-hotspot-in-der-hoehe-1.18056931">Full story (in German)</a></p>
<p><em style="font-size: 13px;">Translation by Philipp Mueller</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/lacking-hot-spot-tropics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Warmer Winters? How Climate Science Failed The Test</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/warmer-winters-climate-science-failed-test/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/warmer-winters-climate-science-failed-test/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 13:57:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11688</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What follows are dozens of predictions for warmer winters made not long ago during the 2000s, many by leading scientists. What started as a simple Google search, turned into a list of false winter predictions for Central Europe, particularly Germany. “The Earth has a fever,” we were told. “The science is settled and the debate is [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>What follows are dozens of predictions for warmer winters made not long ago during the 2000s, many by leading scientists. What started as a simple Google search, turned into a list of false winter predictions for Central Europe, particularly Germany.</strong></p>
<p>“The Earth has a fever,” we were told. “The science is settled and the debate is over. Scientists are unanimous - 97% of them agree: climate change is real, and is happening now, and we’ve got to act quickly.”</p>
<p>Over more than two decades we were told again and again that everywhere was warming faster than everywhere else – <strong style="font-size: 13px;">especially winters were warming up quickly</strong>.</p>
<p>Snow was becoming a thing of the past and children soon weren’t going to know what it is.  “The warm winters that we are seeing are just a harbinger of what’s to come,” the media declared just a couple of years ago. The scientists were cock-sure.</p>
<p>Today we are finding that precisely the exact opposite is happening. Winters in Europe have turned colder and more severe. Central Europe has seen its 5th consecutive colder than normal winter in a row – a record since measurements began in the 19th century.</p>
<p>Climate scientists first reacted by claiming, “<em>One winter does not make a trend</em>“. Then they said that the cold winters were a local phenomenon. Finally they were forced to recently claim, “Cold winters now fit the picture of global warming!”</p>
<p><strong>List of failed predictions</strong></p>
<p>What follows are dozens of predictions for warmer winters made not long ago during the 2000s, many by leading scientists. What started as a simple Google search, turned into a list of false winter predictions for Central Europe, particularly Germany. By sheer coincidence reader <strong>Jimbo</strong> sent over his own list of false wintertime predictions made by “experts” in the US and Great Britain. I’ve combined the two lists and present one long list to you. Of course we still have to wait (90 years in some cases) to see how some of the predictions inevitably turn out, but current trends do not bode well for them.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, many of these predictions were passed on as reliable predictions to various sectors of industry, so that they could prepare for the new future that awaited. Many of these industries, like tourism, skiing, agriculture, highway maintenance, etc. based their investment decisions in part on these forecasts. As we now know, they turned out to be false – completely false – and the costs will be billions. Readers are welcome to suggest other false wintertime predictions, which we will gladly add to the list.</p>
<h2>Failed winter climate predictions</h2>
<p>(The first 33 concern mostly Germany and Central Europe)</p>
<p align="center"><em>1. “Due to global warming, the coming winters in the local regions will become milder.”</em><a href="http://www.pnn.de/potsdam/113720/"><br />
Stefan Rahmstorf, Potsdam Institute of Climate Impact Research, University of Potsdam</a>, 8 Feb 2006</p>
<p align="center">***</p>
<p align="center"><i>2. “Milder winters, drier summers: Climate study shows a need to adapt in Saxony Anhalt.”</i><br />
<a href="http://www.pik-potsdam.de/aktuelles/pressemitteilungen/archiv/2010/mildere-winter-trockenere-sommer-klimastudie-zeigt-anpassungsbedarf-in-sachsen-anhalt-auf">Potsdam Institute for Climate Impact Research, Press Release</a>, 10 Jan 2010.</p>
<p align="center">****</p>
<p align="center"><i>3. “More heat waves, no snow in the winter“ … “Climate models… over 20 times more precise than the UN IPCC global models. In no other country do we have more precise calculations of climate consequences. They should form the basis for political planning. … Temperatures in the wintertime will rise the most … there will be less cold air coming to Central Europe from the east. …In the Alps winters will be 2°C warmer already between 2021 and 2050.”</i><br />
<a href="http://www.spiegel.de/wissenschaft/natur/vorhersage-bis-2100-regierungsprognose-enthuellt-folgen-des-klimawandels-fuer-deutschland-a-575794.html">Max Planck Institute for Meteorology, Hamburg</a>, 2 Sept 2008.</p>
<p><a href="http://notrickszone.com/2013/04/04/climate-science-humiliated-earlier-model-prognoses-of-warmer-winters-now-todays-laughingstocks/">Full list</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/warmer-winters-climate-science-failed-test/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coal Makes A Comeback In Europe As Conventional Gas Dries Up</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/coal-comeback-europe-conventional-gas-dries/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/coal-comeback-europe-conventional-gas-dries/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 09:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11684</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Europe is in a quandary. For years, it has claimed to be a global leader in fighting climate change and slashing carbon emissions. Now it finds itself running out of conventional gas and turning back to dirty coal. Europe’s declining competitiveness with U.S. industry has its leaders worried, but they admit having no hope of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Europe is in a quandary. For years, it has claimed to be a global leader in fighting climate change and slashing carbon emissions. Now it finds itself running out of conventional gas and turning back to dirty coal.</strong></p>
<p>Europe’s declining competitiveness with U.S. industry has its leaders worried, but they admit having no hope of matching the shale revolution that is powering a revival of manufacturing across the Atlantic.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Open pit coal mining in Germany. (Photo by Rene Schwietzke via Creative Commons)" src="http://www.midwestenergynews.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/coal-mining-germany-456x304.jpg" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Open pit coal mining in Germany. (Photo by Rene Schwietzke via Creative Commons)</p>
<p>For Europe to remain in the game, energy taxes must be held in check and no new taxes levied, said the European Union’s energy commissioner, Gunther Oettinger.</p>
<p>Instead, Europe must use its energy more efficiently and the European Union’s 27 member countries should open their energy markets to cross-border competition, Oettinger said at a news conference last week in Brussels.</p>
<p>With its conventional gas fields nearly depleted and gas prices four times higher than in the United States, Europe would like to develop a thriving shale gas industry, but that seems unlikely in the near term.</p>
<p>“We do not have that many North Dakotas in Europe. We do not have those deserted areas where you can drill and no one is being asked or complaining,” said Connie Hedegaard, the European Union’s commissioner for climate action.</p>
<p>European drillers also face greater geological challenges, more stringent environmental regulations and stronger public skepticism of hydraulic fracturing.</p>
<p>“We will not see prices in Europe for shale gas come down to the level in the U.S.,” she said.</p>
<p>There is no E.U. regulation against unconventional drilling, although the environment commission is drawing up guidelines of best practices. Each country is free to chose whether to drill. So far, fracking has been conducted on a test basis, and two countries, France and Bulgaria, have banned the technique for now.</p>
<p>Oettinger and Hedegaard jointly were releasing a policy paper setting the framework for climate and energy targets for the decade after 2020. Documents released alongside the Green Paper made it clear the trends are not running in the climate’s favor.</p>
<p>Europe is in a quandary. For years, it has claimed to be a global leader in fighting climate change and slashing carbon emissions. Now it finds itself running out of conventional gas and turning back to dirty coal. Oettinger said onshore and North Sea gas deposits will be depleted by 2035 or 2040.</p>
<p>The price of imported gas from long-term contracts remains stubbornly high because Europe’s suppliers — Russia, Norway, Algeria and Qatar — link them to oil prices. Producing some shale gas would help Europe decouple the gas-to-oil index, the energy commissioner said.</p>
<p>In the meantime, coal is increasingly the option of choice.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.midwestenergynews.com/2013/04/03/coal-makes-a-comeback-in-europe-as-conventional-gas-dries-up/">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/coal-comeback-europe-conventional-gas-dries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rob Lyons: Lies, Damned Lies And Hockey Sticks</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/rob-lyons-lies-damned-lies-hockey-sticks/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/rob-lyons-lies-damned-lies-hockey-sticks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 09:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11681</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The exposure of yet another dodgy piece of climate-change alarmism shows the need for serious scepticism. ‘Global temperatures are warmer than at any time in at least 4,000 years… and over the coming decades are likely to surpass levels not seen on the planet since before the last ice age.’ That was the pithy message [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The exposure of yet another dodgy piece of climate-change alarmism shows the need for serious scepticism.</strong></p>
<p>‘Global temperatures are warmer than at any time in at least 4,000 years… and over the coming decades are likely to surpass levels not seen on the planet since before the last ice age.’ That was the pithy message offered by <i>New York Times</i> eco-columnist Justin Gillis, reporting on a new reconstruction of past global temperatures published in <i>Science</i> last month. The <i>Atlantic</i> was blunter: ‘We’re Screwed: 11,000 Years’ Worth of Climate Data Prove It.’</p>
<div>The <i style="font-size: 13px;">Science</i> <a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/339/6124/1198.abstract">paper</a> is an attempt to chart changes in global temperatures for the past 11,000 years. In the absence of actual thermometer records any earlier than the late seventeenth century, paleoclimatologists use ‘proxy’ data &#8211; things like tree rings &#8211; to estimate changing temperatures. The researchers, led by Shaun Marcott of Oregon State University, found ‘Early Holocene (10,000 to 5,000 years ago) warmth is followed by ~0.7 degree Celsius cooling through the middle to late Holocene (less than 5,000 years ago), culminating in the coolest temperatures of the Holocene during the Little Ice Age, about 200 years ago’.</div>
<p>However, then things changed dramatically: ‘Current global temperatures of the past decade have not yet exceeded peak interglacial values but are warmer than during ~75 per cent of the Holocene temperature history.’ The accompanying graph of temperature changes, as <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2013/03/were-screwed-11-000-years-worth-of-climate-data-prove-it/273870/">shown in</a> the <i>Atlantic</i> article, is startling. Temperatures are more or less stable until just over 1,000 years ago, when a marked cooling started. Then, after a recovery since the Little Ice Age, the line takes off like a rocket in the twentieth century. What clearer evidence could there be for manmade global warming?</p>
<p>The shape of the graph is very much like a hockey stick on its side &#8211; long and straight with a sharp bend at the end &#8211; and there has been plenty of past trouble caused by ‘hockey stick’ graphs. In 1999, a paper published in <i>Nature</i> by Michael Mann and colleagues suggested that the current period was the warmest in at least 1,000 years. Mann’s graph also showed no Medieval Warm Period, previously assumed to have been a spell of warmer weather in the years roughly from 900 to 1300. Such was the impact of this paper that it become the centrepiece of the IPCC’s Third Assessment Report in 2001 and got a major plug in Al Gore’s film, <i>An Inconvenient Truth</i>. As Andrew Montford <a href="http://www.spiked-online.com/debates/copenhagen_article/9056/">has noted</a> previously on <i>spiked</i>, the Canadian government even sent out a leaflet to every household featuring the ‘hockey stick’ graph.</p>
<p>The real inconvenient truth &#8211; for Mann, Gore and the IPCC &#8211; is that the ‘hockey stick’ was a mirage. A Canadian geologist, Stephen McIntyre, received one of those government leaflets. Sceptical, he decided to investigate the methods and data behind the paper. He found that the data used relied heavily on tree-ring measurements from one particular kind of tree &#8211; American bristlecone pines &#8211; which showed a spurt in growth in the twentieth century that had nothing to do with climate change. Furthermore, there were errors in Mann’s methods such that even random data processed in this way could produce hockey-stick graphs. This was hardly the damning evidence of manmade influence on the climate it had been made out to be.</p>
<p>So no wonder alarm bells rang out when last month’s new hockey-stick graph emerged. Not only did it seem to confirm Mann’s original, but it was used in exactly the same way &#8211; as a STFU to climate sceptics who suggest that current, comparatively mild temperatures could be partly or wholly explained by natural trends that have nothing to do with human greenhouse gas emissions.</p>
<p>A press release from the National Science Foundation, which funded the research, claims the paper finds that ‘during the last 5,000 years, the Earth on average cooled about 1.3 degrees Fahrenheit [0.7 degrees Celsius] &#8211; until the last 100 years, when it warmed about 1.3 degrees Fahrenheit’. That’s an astonishing ‘bounceback’ in temperatures. In an article for the environmentalist website <i>Grist</i>, Marcott is quoted as saying: ‘What we found is that temperatures increased in the last 100 years as much as they had cooled in the last 6,000 or 7,000. In other words, the rate of change is much greater than anything we’ve seen in the whole Holocene.’</p>
<p>The <i>Science</i> paper was soon getting torn apart. One academic at the University of Nottingham, Paul Matthews, noted in a <a href="http://bishophill.squarespace.com/blog/2013/3/15/marcott-in-freefall.html?currentPage=2#comment19838456">comment</a> on Montford’s blog that the data relied upon ‘show no dramatic increase in the twentieth century’. Oddly, he pointed out, Marcott’s own PhD thesis on the same subject ‘uses the same data sets and plots similar graphs, but with no trace of any sharp increase’. Of course, the change in Marcott’s results could easily be the product of further work, but this disparity seems strange nonetheless.</p>
<p>Another critic, Willis Eschenbach, argued that 10 per cent of the proxies used by Marcott <i>et al</i> did not qualify for inclusion even according to their own criteria: ‘A fine example of their choice of proxies can be seen in the fact that they’ve included a proxy which claims a cooling of about nine degrees in the last 10,000 years … although to be fair, they’ve also included some proxies that show seven degrees of warming over the same period.’ Could any sensible results be obtained from data that is clearly all over the place?</p>
<p>On Easter Sunday, Marcott and his colleagues published <a href="http://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2013/03/response-by-marcott-et-al/">a response</a> on the Real Climate blog. Most notable was this comment: ‘Our global paleotemperature reconstruction includes a so-called “uptick” in temperatures during the twentieth century. However, in the paper we make the point that this particular feature is of shorter duration than the inherent smoothing in our statistical averaging procedure, and that it is based on only a few available paleo-reconstructions of the type we used. Thus, the twentieth-century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions.’</p>
<p>Wow.</p>
<p>In other words, all that stuff about having the highest temperatures for millennia and about eye-popping warming over the past 100 years appears to have no basis in the paper’s actual temperature reconstruction. As climate policy expert Roger Pielke Jr <a href="http://rogerpielkejr.blogspot.co.uk/2013/03/fixing-marcott-mess-in-climate-science.html">points out</a>, that correction/clarification needs to be trumpeted as loudly as the original claims were. Remove the twentieth-century portion of the reconstruction and it merely shows that temperatures have been <i>falling</i> overall for the past few thousand years. That doesn’t exactly support the case for urgent action on climate change, does it?</p>
<p>The lesson from this particular episode is the need for scepticism about any claim being made right now about the world’s climate. The issue is highly politicised, with each side in the argument leaping on every new study in an attempt to prove, once and for all, whether humans are influencing the climate and to what extent. The best antidote to such partisan thinking is the fullest and most open debate possible. Current temperatures, for example, might be unusual by historical standards, but that is something that needs to be demonstrated, not merely asserted.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.spiked-online.com/site/article/13498">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/rob-lyons-lies-damned-lies-hockey-sticks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>MPs Call For Police Inquiry Into SSE Mis-Selling Scandal</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/mps-call-police-inquiry-sse-mis-selling-scandal/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/mps-call-police-inquiry-sse-mis-selling-scandal/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 09:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11675</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ MPs and consumer groups say SEE mis-seeling scandal is ‘fraud’ and requires a police investigation The man in charge of one of Britain&#8217;s biggest energy firms will receive an annual pension pot of £400,000 despite the company being found guilty of ripping off one million customers. Ian Marchant will get the payout worth up to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong> MPs and consumer groups say SEE mis-seeling scandal is ‘fraud’ and requires a police investigation</strong></p>
<p>The man in charge of one of Britain&#8217;s biggest energy firms will receive an annual pension pot of £400,000 despite the company being found guilty of ripping off one million customers.</p>
<p>Ian Marchant will get the payout worth up to £9million after 10 years of working at the helm of SSE which has been hit with a £10.5million fine following an investigation by energy regulator Ofgem.</p>
<p>Marchant, chief executive of the company, was paid just over £1million last year with a £158,000 &#8216;cash incentive&#8217; on top of his basic salary of £840,000.</p>
<p>There have also been calls for the rest of the company’s management team to be sacked.</p>
<p>On a day of shame for the power industry, SSE was attacked for ‘failing its customers’ through ruthless ‘mis-selling’, either on people’s doorsteps, over the telephone or on the high street.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of new customers were attracted to switch from other suppliers at the height of the racket – which lasted for three years – and many ended up paying higher tariffs.</p>
<p>While the fine is the largest-ever handed out by Ofgem, it is a tiny fraction of the company’s profits. Last year, it made annual pre-tax profits of £1.3billion.</p>
<p>As MPs and consumer groups said the scandal was ‘fraud’ and required a police investigation, it emerged that:</p>
<p>* Not a single executive at the firm has been sacked or forced out of SSE,</p>
<p>* The man in charge of SSE for the last decade will leave this summer with a pension pot of nearly £400,000 a year</p>
<p>* Up to 2,000 of the victims were shoppers duped by SSE salesmen into signing up to the company under the M&amp;S Energy brand</p>
<p>* SSE is not compensating victims – merely paying them the difference between their previous deal and the new rip-off rate</p>
<p>* Tories said the scandal was an ‘embarrassment’ for Labour leader Ed Miliband who publicly praised SSE in the past</p>
<p>* SSE was accused of ‘obstructing’ the investigation by contesting every allegation against it</p>
<p>* Other energy giants could also be in the spotlight with Ofgem investigating its rivals Scottish Power, Npower and E.ON</p>
<p><span>Barry Gardiner, a Labour MP who also sits on the energy select committee, said: ‘The activities that SSE have engaged in appear to be nothing short of fraud. It would be appropriate for the regulator to refer this matter for further investigation by the police.’<br />
</span></p>
<p>Michael Fallon, the Energy Minister, said he had ‘rarely seen a worse case of consumers being misled so badly’.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2303257/SSE-mis-selling-Fury-energy-giant-ripped-1million-customers-MPs-fraud-investigation-watchdog-fines-SSE-10-5m.html"><span style="color: #0000ff;">Full story</span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/mps-call-police-inquiry-sse-mis-selling-scandal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Industry Warning: &#8216;Rising Cost Of Energy May Force Jobs Overseas&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/industry-warning-rising-cost-energy-force-jobs-overseas/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/industry-warning-rising-cost-energy-force-jobs-overseas/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 09:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11671</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[INDUSTRY leaders have warned that the Government is &#8216;badly underestimating&#8217; the effect of energy and climate change policies on the ceramics sector. &#8221;Uncompetitive energy prices and poor energy security will drive energy intensive manufacturing off shore.&#8221; The British Ceramic Confederation (BCC) said that while new Government analysis recognises that businesses are bearing the financial brunt of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>INDUSTRY leaders have warned that the Government is &#8216;badly underestimating&#8217; the effect of energy and climate change policies on the ceramics sector. &#8221;Uncompetitive energy prices and poor energy security will drive energy intensive manufacturing off shore.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>The British Ceramic Confederation (BCC) said that while new Government analysis recognises that businesses are bearing the financial brunt of policy decisions, there are some &#8216;serious exclusions&#8217; in costs in its assessments.</p>
<p>The research for the Department of Energy and Climate Change (DECC) reveals that large energy-intensive business users face bills that are up to 14 per cent higher as a result of Government policies.</p>
<p>By 2020, the impact is expected to be between six per cent and 36 per cent.</p>
<p>But the BCC, based in Stoke, says this is despite the DECC not including the direct cost to companies of the EU Emissions Trading System, which many ceramics companies are subject to.</p>
<p>The system helps to set emission levels by allowing firms to buy allowances.</p>
<p>The BCC also says the DECC has not included future extra transmission, distribution and balancing costs required to strengthen the grid for intermittent renewables.</p>
<p>It warned: &#8220;Businesses are making dispassionate decisions on where to invest.</p>
<p>&#8220;They look at the combined effect of all energy bills and climate related taxes and charges for different countries in their business models – inside and outside Europe – and the UK is not faring well.</p>
<p>&#8220;All ceramic businesses compete internationally, they can&#8217;t just pass on unilateral UK only price increases to customers without losing sales.</p>
<p>&#8220;Uncompetitive energy prices and poor energy security will drive energy intensive manufacturing off shore.&#8221;</p>
<p>Energy intensive industries exist in sectors from ceramics and textiles to refineries, chemicals and plastics.</p>
<p><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.thisisstaffordshire.co.uk/Cost-power-force-jobs-overseas/story-18595632-detail/story.html#axzz2PU7lTC2b"><span style="font-size: 13px;">Full story</span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/industry-warning-rising-cost-energy-force-jobs-overseas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Europe&#8217;s Cap-and-Trade System &#8211; A &#8216;Big Flop&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/europes-cap-and-trade-system-big-flop/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/europes-cap-and-trade-system-big-flop/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 09:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11668</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Europe&#8217;s cap-and-trade system for reducing the release of greenhouse gases is broken, but not everybody wants to fix it. Industry has profited immensely from the plummeting prices of CO2 emissions certificates, and from lax checks on questionable environmental projects undertaken overseas. Saving the climate? It doesn&#8217;t seem all that difficult at first glance. All you [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Europe&#8217;s cap-and-trade system for reducing the release of greenhouse gases is broken, but not everybody wants to fix it. Industry has profited immensely from the plummeting prices of CO2 emissions certificates, and from lax checks on questionable environmental projects undertaken overseas.</strong></p>
<p>Saving the climate? It doesn&#8217;t seem all that difficult at first glance. All you have to do is fly from Germany to Zambia once in a while, as the German energy giant RWE&#8217;s environment protection team does. It has made frequent trips to the capital Lusaka in recent years to distribute a total of 30,000 small stoves &#8212; RWE&#8217;s contribution to a good cause.</p>
<p>The stoves were intended to help poor families cook in a more environmentally friendly way. Biomass was to replace charcoal as cooking fuel. In an advertising brochure for RWE, the company that &#8220;travels around the world to help our climate&#8221; touts the campaign with the slogan &#8220;New Cooking Pots &#8212; Less CO2.&#8221; But RWE doesn&#8217;t seem to have included such factors as air travel and the production of the stoves in its calculations.</p>
<p>Besides, the project wasn&#8217;t entirely altruistic, because RWE will receive credits for its effort. The stoves in Lusaka are expected to save 1.5 million tons of CO2 by 2020, and in return, RWE&#8217;s coal-fired power plants would be allowed to emit 1.5 million tons elsewhere. This sale of indulgences is called a &#8220;Clean Development Mechanism&#8221; (CDM). With such questionable projects in emerging and developing countries, which even include the renovation of coalmines in China, European companies can simply calculate away about 20 percent of their emissions.</p>
<p>In the end, the flood of such projects undermines the entire emissions trading system. &#8220;The most important tool of climate protection no longer works,&#8221; says Eva Filzmoser of Carbon Market Watch in Brussels. Four years ago, the Austrian national began a solo effort to take a closer look at the emissions trading market. She still believed in the idea at the time. But Filzmoser found herself confronted with an industry that had grown to a volume of $90 billion almost overnight, an industry complete with certifiers, forecasters, dealers and hackers, who trafficked in certificates and created more and more absurd projects.</p>
<p><strong>&#8216;A Big Flop&#8217;</strong></p>
<p>They included the supposed cleanup of African garbage dumps, as well as the retrofitting of old coolant factories in China, which only seemed to be in operation because they yielded climate certificates.</p>
<p>It is because of Filzmoser and her staff of five employees that, starting in May, at least the most questionable of these projects will no longer be approved by the United Nations Climate Change secretariat. &#8220;The trade has turned into a big flop,&#8221; she says, &#8220;a system of fraud.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.spiegel.de/international/europe/european-co2-emissions-reduction-system-is-broken-a-892134.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/europes-cap-and-trade-system-big-flop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lewandowsky Paper On Climate Conspiracists “Provisionally Removed” Due To Complaints</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/lewandowsky-al-paper-climate-conspiracists-provisionally-removed-due-complaints/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/lewandowsky-al-paper-climate-conspiracists-provisionally-removed-due-complaints/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 13:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11664</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week, we covered the complicated story of a paper by Stephan Lewandowsky and colleagues that had been removed — or at least all but the abstract — from its publisher’s site. Our angle on the story was how Frontiers, which publishes Frontiers in Personality Science and Individual Differences, where the study appeared, had handled the withdrawal. It happened [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week, we covered the <a href="http://retractionwatch.wordpress.com/2013/03/28/why-publishers-should-explain-why-papers-disappear-the-complicated-lewandowsky-study-saga/">complicated story of a paper by Stephan Lewandowsky and colleagues</a> that had been removed — or at least all but the abstract — from its publisher’s site. Our angle on the story was how Frontiers, which publishes <em>Frontiers in Personality Science and Individual Differences</em>, where the study appeared, had handled the withdrawal. It happened without any notice, and no text appeared to let the reader know why the paper had vanished.</p>
<p>Today, Frontiers posted a <a href="http://www.frontiersin.org/Personality_Science_and_Individual_Differences/10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00073/abstract">note to readers</a> on top of the paper’s abstract:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>This article, first published by Frontiers on 18 March 2013, has been the subject of complaints. Given the nature of some of these complaints, Frontiers has provisionally removed the link to the article while these issues are investigated, which is being done as swiftly as possible and which Frontiers management considers the most responsible course of action. The article has not been retracted or withdrawn. Further information will be provided as soon as possible. Thank you for your patience.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Fair enough, given the history of the study, although we wonder why this note didn’t appear when the paper was first “delinked” last week. We also wonder why Frontiers said the article was first published on March 18, given that it appeared online on February 5. Perhaps they meant the most current version of the paper, since that first version was also temporarily removed in response to complaints. But that’s a strange distinction to make.</p>
<p><a href="http://retractionwatch.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/update-lewandowsky-et-al-paper-on-conspiracist-ideation-provisionally-removed-due-to-complaints/">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/lewandowsky-al-paper-climate-conspiracists-provisionally-removed-due-complaints/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
