<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 12:56:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Labour Accuses Government Of &#8216;Cooking The Books&#8217; On Energy Policy</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/labour-accuses-government-cooking-books-energy-policy/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/labour-accuses-government-cooking-books-energy-policy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 07:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11417</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Caroline Flint, the shadow Energy and Climate Change Secretary, said the figures were a “shameful” and “underhand attempt” to mask the real impact of the Government’s policies on energy bills.  Households will have to spend thousands of pounds buying new green appliances to benefit from the Government’s claims its policies are bringing down energy bills, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Caroline Flint, the shadow Energy and Climate Change Secretary, said the figures were a “shameful” and “underhand attempt” to mask the real impact of the Government’s policies on energy bills. </strong></p>
<p>Households will have to spend thousands of pounds buying new green appliances to benefit from the Government’s claims its policies are bringing down energy bills, it emerged last night.</p>
<div>
<div id="mainBodyArea">
<div>
<p>The Government was accused of an “underhand” attempt to mask the cost of green energy and rising gas prices, after it claimed the net effect of all its policies will be a £166 reduction in bills by 2020.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Official estimates said replacing household appliances like washing machines and televisions could take £158 off the average bill, while new boilers could on average save £81 in energy costs.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Ministers claimed this would more than “offset” green taxes and subsidies, which are likely to contribute around £199 to the average bill by 2020.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Ed Davey, the Energy Secretary, said the Government has &#8220;a duty to help keep bills down – and that’s what we’ve been doing&#8221;.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>However, millions of households, especially older people, will not necessarily be replacing their appliances within the next seven years.</p>
<p>Many people choose to repair their old white goods when they go wrong or buy second hand ones that do not comply with the latest green standards.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Last night, Labour accused Mr Davey, of “cooking the books” as his claims to bring down bills will only be true if people splash out on new greener televisions, fridge-freezers, washing machines, dishwashers and gas-combi boilers.</p>
<p>Caroline Flint, the shadow Energy and Climate Change Secretary, said the figures were a “shameful” and “underhand attempt” to mask the real impact of the Government’s policies on energy bills</p>
<p>“At a time when hard-pressed families and pensioners are seeing their incomes squeezed, only this out-of-touch Government could expect people to fork out thousands of pounds on new TVs, fridge freezers and washing machines,” she said.</p>
<p>“Instead of cooking the books to trick people into thinking their energy bills will be lower, Ministers should get behind Labour’s plans to overhaul the energy market and deliver fair prices for the public.”</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/earth/energy/9955852/Households-will-have-to-buy-green-appliances-to-benefit-from-Government-energy-bill-boasts.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/labour-accuses-government-cooking-books-energy-policy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beddington Is Wrong: UK Rainfall Is Not Becoming More Variable</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/beddington-wrong-uk-rainfall-variable/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/beddington-wrong-uk-rainfall-variable/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 07:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Observatory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11413</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Professor John Beddington, the outgoing UK Chief Scientist, has been ramping up the alarmism with his prediction of drastic weather extremes in the coming 25 years in an interview with the BBC. Amongst his claims was this:- “The variation in the temperature or rainfall, which Britain has been experiencing lately, is double the average rate.” Let’s [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Professor John Beddington, the outgoing UK Chief Scientist, has been ramping up the alarmism with his prediction of drastic weather extremes in the coming 25 years in an <a href="http://www.newstank.co.uk/headline-news/john-beddington-frequent-britain-cold-snaps/05990/">interview with the BBC</a>.</p>
<p>Amongst his claims was this:-</p>
<p><em>“The variation in the temperature or rainfall, which Britain has been experiencing lately, is double the average rate</em>.”</p>
<p>Let’s check the facts.</p>
<p>The Met Office have produced an <a href="http://www.metoffice.gov.uk/hadobs/hadukp/data/download.html">England &amp; Wales Precipitation Series</a>, dating back to 1766. The annual totals are plotted in Figure 1.</p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image52.png"><img title="image" alt="image" src="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image_thumb52.png?w=504&amp;h=302" width="504" height="302" border="0" /></a></p>
<p align="center">Figure 1</p>
<p align="left">There are ups and downs, as you would expect with English weather. Wet though last year was, it was not as wet as 1768 or 1872. And dry though 2011 was, it was only the 33rd driest in the series.</p>
<p align="left">Still, this is not what Beddington was referring to. He was specifically talking about the variation in rainfall, large swings from dry to wet, or vice versa. So Figure 2 shows the variation from year to year.</p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image53.png"><img title="image" alt="image" src="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image_thumb53.png?w=504&amp;h=310" width="504" height="310" border="0" /></a></p>
<p align="center">Figure 2</p>
<p align="left">Now let’s change all the negative values to positive, so that increases and decreases are both shown on the same scale, and add a 10 year running average.</p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image54.png"><img title="image" alt="image" src="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image_thumb54.png?w=504&amp;h=308" width="504" height="308" border="0" /></a></p>
<p align="center">Figure 3</p>
<p align="left">The large increase in rainfall between 2011 and 2012 is apparent, but was less than the increase in 1789, and of a similar level to four other years. But, more importantly, what about the trend?</p>
<p align="left">There has certainly been more variability in the last few years compared to the 1980’s and early 90’s. But the current level of variability is similar to that which has existed throughout the larger part of the series. There is also no sign, despite the events of last year, that variability is on the increase.</p>
<p>Could it be that the Professor is overreacting to the events of just one year, or is he not aware of the historical facts? It is difficult to understand how a top scientist could make such basic errors, but it is hard to come to any other conclusion.</p>
<p><a href="http://notalotofpeopleknowthat.wordpress.com/2013/03/26/beddington-is-wronguk-rainfall-is-not-becoming-more-variable/">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/beddington-wrong-uk-rainfall-variable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>DECC&#8217;s Agenda</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/deccs-agenda/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/deccs-agenda/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 07:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11410</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The FT&#8217;s energy blogger, Nick Butler, notes some worrying behaviour. The UK’s Department of Energy and Climate Change is about to publish forecasts suggesting that gas prices could rise by up to 70 per cent over the next five years. This is scaremongering nonsense, and shows just how out of touch the Department is with the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The FT&#8217;s energy blogger, Nick Butler, <a href="http://blogs.ft.com/nick-butler/2013/03/26/gas-prices-time-to-return-to-reality/">notes some worrying behaviour</a>.</p>
<blockquote><p>The UK’s Department of Energy and Climate Change is about to publish forecasts suggesting that gas prices could rise by up to 70 per cent over the next five years. This is scaremongering nonsense, and shows just how out of touch the Department is with the realities of the international energy market. Officials appear not to have consulted the industry or the traders. In reality the odds are that prices are just as likely to fall as to rise&#8230;</p></blockquote>
<p>When civil servants are spreading misleading information to benefit a political agenda you know that there&#8217;s a problem.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bishop-hill.net/blog/2013/3/26/deccs-agenda.html">Bishop Hill, 26 March 2013</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/deccs-agenda/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christopher Booker: What Planet Are Ministers Living On?</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/christopher-booker-planet-ministers-living-on/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/christopher-booker-planet-ministers-living-on/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 07:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11407</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Just when we need heat and light for our homes and workplaces more than ever, we are rapidly heading for by far the most serious energy crisis this country has ever faced. With much of Britain still freezing under a layer of snow, the timing of the action plan set out yesterday by Ed Davey, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Just when we need heat and light for our homes and workplaces more than ever, we are rapidly heading for by far the most serious energy crisis this country has ever faced.</strong></p>
<p><span>With much of Britain still freezing under a layer of snow, the timing of the action plan set out yesterday by Ed Davey, Secretary of State for Energy and Climate Change, could not have been more immaculate.</span></p>
<p><span>He wanted to tell us just how committed his government is to cutting emissions of carbon dioxide from the &#8216;costly, carbon-intense fossil fuels&#8217; we use for more than &#8217;80 per cent of the heating used in UK homes, businesses and industry&#8217;.</span></p>
<p><span>And how does he propose to do this? He wants to spend £9 million to &#8216;help local authorities get heat network schemes [designed to pipe heat to homes from a central source] up and running in towns and cities across the country&#8217;.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span>He wants to hire yet more civil servants to set up a &#8216;Heat Network Unit&#8217; to provide &#8216;expert advice&#8217;. </span></p>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">And he wants us to pay for &#8217;100 green apprenticeships&#8217; for &#8216;young people to work in smallscale renewable technologies&#8217;.</span></p>
<p><span>What planet is this man living on? He has only to step outside his centrally heated Whitehall office to see that the rest of us are having to struggle through the coldest March for 50 years.</span></p>
<p><span>Yet, just when we need heat and light for our homes and workplaces more than ever, we are rapidly heading for by far the most serious energy crisis this country has ever faced.</span></p>
<p><span>We learned at the weekend that Britain&#8217;s gas supplies have run so perilously low that we could be depending on just two giant tankers imported from the Middle East to heat our homes at a time when world gas prices are soaring.</span></p>
<p>Last week, we also lost two more of our major coal-fired power stations, forced to close down by an EU pollution directive &#8211; leading the head of our second-largest power company, SSE, to warn our generating capacity is being cut back so far that major blackouts may soon be inevitable.</p>
<p><span>Mr Davey babbles away about &#8216;heat networks&#8217;, but if he had his mind on the job he is paid for, he might realise that in the real world we have a perfect storm on our hands. As every squeezed family in the country will tell you, our energy bills are rocketing upwards, having already doubled in seven years.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span>As ministers admitted yesterday, families will be forced to pay almost £300 in green taxes on their energy bills by the end of the decade (though Ed Davey did try to make a case that even greater savings will be achieved due to reduced consumption).</span></p>
<p>What is also clear is that our gas and electricity supplies are fast running out.</p>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">And if, on top of all this, you learned that next week the Government is imposing a swingeing new tax on all the coal and gas-fired power stations &#8211; which provide more than two-thirds of our electricity &#8211; would you not throw up your hands in stunned disbelief?</span></p>
<p><span>But that is what is about to happen with George Osborne&#8217;s new &#8216;carbon tax&#8217;, deliberately designed not only to double the price of electricity from our remaining fossil fuel power plants within a few years, but to make it hard for them to survive at all.</span></p>
<p><span>All this adds up to as great an act of political mismanagement as any in our history.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span>So, how did we come to such a terrifying pass?</span></p>
<p><span>There is one reason above all why our energy policy has gone so disastrously off the rails &#8211; and it lies in the conviction shared by politicians of all major parties that we must do all we can to save the planet by reducing CO² emissions.</span></p>
<p>At the time when this belief began to take shape, back in the Nineties, for 40 years Britain had had an electricity industry as efficient as any, based on the coal of which we had huge reserves and the nuclear power with which we once led the world.</p>
<p><span>Then we decided to close down most of our coal industry in favour of a &#8216;dash for gas&#8217;, because it gives off only half as much carbon dioxide as coal &#8211; this at a time when we still had enough cheap gas from the North Sea not to worry about becoming dependent on costly gas imports.</span></p>
<p><span>The next move came in 2003 with Tony Blair&#8217;s energy white paper, which ruled out building any more coal or nuclear power stations in favour of going flat out for &#8216;renewables&#8217;. This was centred on pouring huge subsidies into building thousands of wind turbines.</span></p>
<p><span>By 2008, so obsessed had our politicians become with the supposed threat from CO² that Parliament voted almost unanimously for Ed Miliband&#8217;s Climate Change Act, committing Britain uniquely in the world to reducing its emissions by 80 per cent in just 40 years.</span></p>
<p><span>Gordon Brown boasted about spending £100 billion on making Britain &#8216;the wind farm capital of the world&#8217;.</span></p>
<p>But what the politicians failed to realise was that wind and solar are not only by far the most expensive means of producing electricity &#8211; hence those green subsidies we all have to fund through our electricity bills &#8211; they are also the most unreliable, because the wind doesn&#8217;t always blow and the sun doesn&#8217;t always shine.</p>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">When David Cameron took over in 2010, his &#8216;greenest government ever&#8217; continued the headlong rush to disaster, not just by pouring ever more subsidies into those inefficient wind farms, but by deliberately driving up the price of electricity from coal and gas, to make wind energy seem competitive.</span></p>
<p><span>Hence George Osborne&#8217;s decision to impose a &#8216;carbon tax&#8217;, which comes into force on April Fool&#8217;s Day &#8211; designed to rise every year at such a rate it will make Britain&#8217;s electricity the most expensive in Europe.</span></p>
<p><span>Yet the terrifying fact is that we really do need those reliable power stations Osborne is trying to price out of business &#8211; not least to provide constantly available back-up for the 32,000 wind turbines our ministers eulogise, for all those times when the wind is not blowing.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span>Nothing better illustrates the insanity of the shambles our politicians have led us into than the fact that, just when we are closing down our coal-fired power stations in the hope of saving the planet, the Chinese are building 363 more of them, the Indians a further 455 and even the Germans another 20 &#8211; adding far more CO² to the world&#8217;s atmosphere every week than Britain puts out in a year.</span></p>
<p><span>The disaster we face is only made harder to bear by the realisation that experts were predicting it a decade ago, yet so lost were our politicians in their bubble of green make-believe that they were unable to listen.</span></p>
<p><span>So how are we to get out of this mess? If we had a grown-up government, capable of looking at the evidence, the first thing it would do would be to admit we have a quite unprecedented crisis on our hands &#8211; one that can only be met by junking all that childish wishful thinking which has shaped our national energy policy for 20 years.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-2299607/What-planet-living-As-freezing-Britain-faces-grave-energy-crisis-ministers-unveil-green-gimmicks-eco-taxes-What-folly-says-CHRISTOPHER-BOOKER.html">Full comment</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/christopher-booker-planet-ministers-living-on/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Families Face £286 Green Tax On Energy Bills</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/families-face-286-green-tax-energy-bills/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/families-face-286-green-tax-energy-bills/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 07:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11404</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Families will be paying almost £300 a year in green energy taxes by 2020. The levy will more than double until a quarter of each power bill goes on wind, solar, nuclear or home insulation schemes. * Energy Secretary insisted households will be better off due to initiatives * But families will only benefit if they [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Families will be paying almost £300 a year in green energy taxes by 2020. The levy will more than double until a quarter of each power bill goes on wind, solar, nuclear or home insulation schemes.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #0000ff;"><strong>* Energy Secretary insisted households will be better off due to initiatives</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #0000ff;"><strong>* But families will only benefit if they buy more efficient domestic appliances</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #0000ff;"><strong>* Average bill is now £1,267 with £112 of that amount going on green taxes</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #0000ff;"><strong>* By 2020 green taxes will have risen by over 150 per cent &#8211; £286 per family</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #0000ff;"><strong>* DECC reckons households will be saving £452 a year then due to schemes</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #0000ff;"><strong>* Charity said government &#8216;embarrassed by terrifying cost of green policies&#8217;</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>* Claimed it is &#8216;covering up&#8217; with a &#8216;whitewash of wildly optimistic assumptions&#8217;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Daily Mail (UK)" src="http://www.frontpagestoday.co.uk/frontpages/Daily_Mail_newspaper_front_page.jpg" /></p>
<p>Energy Secretary Ed Davey insisted last night that households will be better off thanks to the benefits of electricity-saving initiatives.</p>
<p>But families will be able to claw the money back only if they buy more efficient domestic appliances and boilers.</p>
<p>The average power bill is now £1,267 – with £112 of that going on green taxes, including an £18 wind farm subsidy.</p>
<p>By 2020, green taxes will have risen by more than 150 per cent, ensuring each family contributes £286, according to the Department for Energy and Climate Change.</p>
<div></div>
<div><img alt="green graphic " src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/pix/2013/03/26/article-0-18F1103F000005DC-726_634x485.jpg" width="634" height="485" /></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It reckons that by then households will be saving £452 a year by taking up schemes to lower energy use and by switching to more efficient kettles, fridges and TVs.</p>
<p><span>The ministry also hopes smart meters, which track energy consumption, will alter consumer behaviour and lower consumption.</span></p>
<p>But John Constable, of the charity Renewable Energy Foundation, said: ‘DECC is clearly embarrassed by the terrifying costs of its ever-growing range of green policies, and is covering up with a whitewash of wildly optimistic assumptions about energy efficiency.</p>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">‘If electricity prices increase by a third, as DECC admits they will, it is vanishingly unlikely that better dishwashers, kettles, and fridges, even assuming households can afford them, can cancel out the increases and deliver lower bills.’</span></p>
<p><span>Mr Davey said his projected savings would mean that households would end up paying £166 less than if the green policies had not been introduced in the first place.</span></p>
<p><span>‘Global gas price hikes are squeezing households,’ he added. ‘We are doing all we can to offset these global energy price rises and, while we have more to do, this new study shows that our policies are putting a cushion between global prices and the bills we all pay.</span></p>
<div>‘The analysis shows our strategy of shifting to alternatives like renewables, and of being smarter with how we use energy, is helping those that need it most save money on their bills.</div>
<p><span>‘The poorest who take advantage of the help that is available through the initiatives we have on offer stand to make the highest savings, from the warm home discount to our new regulation on energy firms to force them to improve the energy efficiency of fuel poor households.’<br />
</span></p>
<p><span>DECC claims ‘the large majority of households’ will benefit and even those that do not add insulation or take advantage of energy rebates will be £15 better off.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span>Caroline Flint, Labour’s energy spokesman, said last night: ‘The Government’s underhand attempt to mask the real impact of its policies on families’ energy bills is shameful.</span></p>
<p>‘At a time when hard-pressed families and pensioners are seeing their incomes squeezed, only this out-of-touch Government could expect people to fork out thousands of pounds on new TVs, fridge freezers and washing machines just to save a few pounds every few months on their energy bill.’</p>
<p><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2299652/286-green-tax-energy-bills-But-ministers-insist-efficient-appliances-SAVE-money.html">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/families-face-286-green-tax-energy-bills/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Obama&#8217;s Achilles&#8217; Heel On Climate Policy: Senate Democrats</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/obamas-achilles-heel-climate-policy-senate-democrats/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/obamas-achilles-heel-climate-policy-senate-democrats/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 18:58:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11401</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[More than a dozen Senate Democrats have a message for President Barack Obama: If he wants to take dramatic action on climate change, he&#8217;s on his own. The latest evidence came from this weekend&#8217;s marathon series of budget votes, in which moderate and conservative Democrats sided with the GOP on the Keystone XL oil pipeline [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>More than a dozen Senate Democrats have a message for President Barack Obama: If he wants to take dramatic action on climate change, he&#8217;s on his own.</strong></p>
<p>The latest evidence came from this weekend&#8217;s marathon series of budget votes, in which moderate and conservative Democrats sided with the GOP on the Keystone XL oil pipeline and against any prospects for a tax on carbon.</p>
<p>In the two Keystone votes, the Democrats helped the Republicans prevail by filibuster-proof majorities — a clear sign that Obama will have little political cover from his party&#8217;s middle if he chooses to reject the Canada-to-Texas pipeline, as climate advocates are urging him to.</p>
<p>The nonbinding budget votes were the first action on climate change in the new Congress, and they underscore a status quo that has held in the upper chamber since Obama’s first term, when Majority Leader Harry Reid pulled the plug on cap and trade shortly before the midterm elections.</p>
<p>Since then, the caucus of climate-weary Democrats has grown after the 2012 election, which ushered in a new class of moderates — like North Dakota&#8217;s Heidi Heitkamp — who often side with Republicans on energy policy. Several more red-state Democrats are facing tough reelection battles next year, giving Reid ample reason to protect them from casting votes that could hurt them at the ballot box.</p>
<p>“Sen. Reid will go out of his way to protect vulnerable members if he can from such votes,” said former Clinton White House climate aide Paul Bledsoe, a senior energy fellow at the German Marshall Fund.</p>
<p>Some other late Friday/early Saturday votes yielded victories for the climate cause — for example, a push by Sen. Jim Inhofe (R-Okla.) to block EPA carbon regulations received even less support than it had in the last Congress. But even then, the signal was that senators will let the Obama administration take the lead in tackling what many scientists are calling a global crisis.</p>
<p>In fact, Obama is widely expected to make executive branch actions — such as EPA rules on power plants — the centerpiece of his climate agenda, although there have been some indications that those could be delayed.</p>
<p>Former Reid senior communications adviser Jim Manley said the Nevada Democrat knows that any vote on major climate change legislation would be merely symbolic, given the likelihood of a GOP filibuster. “You probably can’t rule out a failed cloture vote,” he said.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2013/03/obamas-achilles-heel-on-climate-senate-democrats-89295.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/obamas-achilles-heel-climate-policy-senate-democrats/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>One Year Ago: &#8216;Experts&#8217; Blamed Warm March Weather On Global Warming</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/year-ago-experts-blamed-warm-march-weather-global-warming/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/year-ago-experts-blamed-warm-march-weather-global-warming/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 16:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11398</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[March 29, 2012 ‘March summer’ linked to global warming An early “March summer” in Canada and the United States with record high temperatures may be a symptom of global warming, researchers said. “We’ve never seen these kinds of temperatures before,” Dave Phillips, a senior climatologist at Environment Canada, said. “It’s quite remarkable.” “The duration, areal [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>March 29, 2012</p>
<p><strong>‘March summer’ linked to global warming</strong></p>
<p>An early “March summer” in Canada and the United States with record high temperatures may be a symptom of global warming, researchers said.</p>
<p>“We’ve never seen these kinds of temperatures before,” Dave Phillips, a senior climatologist at Environment Canada, said. “It’s quite remarkable.”</p>
<p>“The duration, areal size, and intensity of the ‘summer in March’ heat wave are simply off-scale,” Jeff Masters of the Weather Underground Web site in San Francisco said. “The event ranks as one of North America’s most extraordinary weather events in recorded history.”</p>
<p><a href="http://www.disasternews.net/news/article.php?articleid=4536">‘March summer’ linked to global warming – Disaster News Network</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Complete nonsense – March 2012 was not as warm as March 1910, and these same geniuses are blaming the cold during March 2013 on global warming.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevengoddard.wordpress.com/2013/03/26/one-year-ago-experts-blamed-warm-march-weather-on-global-warming/">full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/year-ago-experts-blamed-warm-march-weather-global-warming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Key Cameron Adviser Blocks Climate Change From G8 Agenda</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/key-cameron-adviser-blocks-climate-change-g8-agenda/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/key-cameron-adviser-blocks-climate-change-g8-agenda/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 16:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11393</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[RTCC understands that the UK Prime Minister&#8217;s Adviser for Europe and Global Issues Ivan Rogers has rejected moves from Germany and France to make the issue one of the meeting&#8217;s key talking points. Officials from the two countries are said to be disappointed their suggestions were rebuffed. Instead, Rogers is insisting that trade, transparency and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>RTCC understands that the UK Prime Minister&#8217;s Adviser for Europe and Global Issues Ivan Rogers has rejected moves from Germany and France to make the issue one of the meeting&#8217;s key talking points.</p>
<p>Officials from the two countries are said to be disappointed their suggestions were rebuffed.</p>
<p>Instead, Rogers is insisting that trade, transparency and tax form the core of discussions scheduled to take place at Lough Erne, in Northern Ireland between June 17-18.</p>
<p style="display: inline !important;"><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2013/mar/26/cameron-adviser-blocks-climate-change-g8">Full story</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/key-cameron-adviser-blocks-climate-change-g8-agenda/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scientists Warn Of Ice Age</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/scientists-warn-ice-age/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/scientists-warn-ice-age/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 15:28:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Observatory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11390</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Perhaps it is no coincidence that Russian scientists warn of an impending ice age. In Germany, a month is drawing to a close which people will not forget that quickly. At least in the north and east of the country, it could be the coldest and especially the snowiest March since the beginning of the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Perhaps it is no coincidence that Russian scientists warn of an impending ice age.</strong></p>
<p>In Germany, a month is drawing to a close which people will not forget that quickly. At least in the north and east of the country, it could be the coldest and especially the snowiest March since the beginning of the detailed records began about 100 years ago. In the Brandenburg village Coschen, the thermometer dropped to minus 19 degrees in the night to Sunday &#8211; it was the coldest place in Germany. Even though it was milder in the south, the first three weeks of March were still about three and a half degrees colder than the long-term average of this month, and the few days until its end will not change anything essential, especially since the meteorologists do not expect much higher temperatures until Easter.</p>
<p>In calculating the total meteorological winter (December to February), the measurements from March are not even taken into account, but the three winter months taken together were about half a degree colder than &#8220;normal.&#8221; And dark anyway.</p>
<p>Ornithologists have reported that migratory birds coming from the south have turned back. Others, equipped with sharper senses, remained longer than usual in the Mediterranean. The flowering of plants is delayed, and the crocus, which formed in the parks during the few mild days earlier this month, disappeared for weeks under 20 cm thick snow cover. The construction industry and other industries fear delays, losses and other cost burdens. The tenant association Hamburg expects that after the winter an increase of 100 Euros will be payable for renters of a 70 square meter apartment in the next heating bill; for public buildings, the taxpayers will be charged accordingly. Several times dozens of flights, such as to and from Frankfurt, had to be cancelled due to heavy snow, highly unusual for March.</p>
<p>Globally, temperature extremes balance each other most of the times, but in recent weeks one has to look very closely in order to identify particularly warm climes in our latitudes. Japan, for example, reports a relatively early onset of spring. On the other hand, the north-eastern United States suffered from snow chaos, in New York, many flights had to be cancelled too in mid-March because of almost half a meter of fresh snow. In the European part of northern Russia is has been particularly cold; rarely has the weather map been as deep dark blue over such large areas.</p>
<p>The blue colour projects far into our regions. Perhaps it is no coincidence, therefore, that Russian scientists warn of an impending ice age. Vladimir Bashkin and Rauf Galiulin have only recently discovered this risk in a study. The two biogeochemists &#8211; a discipline which includes the exploration of the Earth&#8217;s atmosphere &#8211; have drawn up the paper for the Research Institute VNIIGAZ of the Gazprom Group, an address that is surely not entirely free of lobbying interests. Their reasoning, however, is based on findings that the gain more and more ground in the independent science: The activity of the sun has weakened significantly, according to some experts to a degree as during the &#8220;Little Ice Age&#8221;, several hundred years ago.</p>
<p>However, it is not a variation of the warming sunshine, which would not be sufficient to explain climate changes during past centuries. However, the changes in solar ionizing radiation emissions, the so-called solar wind, could be very influential with regards the long-term development of Earth’s temperatures. These fluctuations are associated with the ups and downs of the number of sunspots. The sunspots can be observed from Earth, they are recorded since at least since their discovery by the German-British astronomer William Herschel in the 18th century. Herschel found a relationship between the number of sunspots and climate impacts, namely the good and bad years in agriculture. His theory of the &#8220;hog cycle&#8221; was long derided because an explanation was missing &#8211; until it was found a few years ago.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, there are other methods to track the variations of the solar wind than by sunspots; by isotopes in drilling cores, sediments, or millennia old ice. And lo and behold: there are clear parallel curves between the changes in solar activity and, a few years or decades later, global temperature &#8211; at least insofar as it is possible to retrospectively ascertain temperatures. Taking account of these delays, the ups and downs of temperatures during the 20th century and until the beginning of the 21st century can be explained from sun, whose activity in the second half of the last century was at its highest rate since the medieval climate optimum, which was about one degree warmer than today.</p>
<p>Several institutions, among others the nuclear research center CERN in Geneva and at the state-run National Space Institute of Denmark, are trying to find a physical explanation for this significant relationship. Through a series of tests, researchers were able, to some extent, to form a picture of how the ionizing solar wind affects cloud formation and thus the temperature of the Earth. The delay could be well explained by the buffering effect of the water masses in the oceans. One can only wonder how the work of the scientists, who study these connections, will be taken into account by the fifth &#8220;Assessment Report&#8221; of the IPCC, which will be published September. So far, it looks as if they will not play any role since the scientists who view man-made carbon dioxide emissions as almost the sole driver of the climate will set the tone.</p>
<p>However, the one-dimensional explanation of CO2 has lately been questioned by other studies, too. For example by a scientifically approved work by two climate researchers at the University of Washington in Seattle (USA), published in the February issue of the &#8220;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&#8221; &#8211; one of the world&#8217;s most prestigious scientific magazines.  The two researchers came to the following conclusion: &#8220;The anthropogenic contribution to global warming in the second half of the 20th century has been probably been overestimated by a factor of two”, i.e. only half as large as expected. According to their study, the currents and pressure conditions in the oceans have been fundamentally underestimated.</p>
<p>A study by researchers at the University of Oslo comes to a similar conclusion and will be published in the next few weeks. According to the study, even a doubling of CO2 by 2050, which hardly anyone expects, will not have the dramatic effects which the IPCC predicts. According to the study, the influence of natural factors, such as clouds and volcanic eruptions, is much stronger than previously thought.</p>
<p>So far studies with similar conclusions, though published in peer reviewed scientific journals, are mostly ignored by the media. But they are published more frequently in science journals lately. The current extreme weather does only support them to a limited degree; weather is fickle. However, this is also correct for any contrary weather conditions. In any case, from the perspective of this winter it can be said with certainty: summer is approaching. Also predictable is the next very, very hot one. The only question remaining is this: Just when will it happen?</p>
<p><em>Translation Phillip Mueller</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.welt.de/print/die_welt/vermischtes/article114733276/Wissenschaftler-warnen-vor-Eiszeit.html">Die Welt, 25 March 2013</p>
<p></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/scientists-warn-ice-age/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Europe Could Miss Out On Shale Gas Revolution</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-shale-gas-revolution/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-shale-gas-revolution/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 11:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11387</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[European industries and some European governments have recently begun to recognise that the unconventional gas revolution is no longer confined to North America, but is spreading globally. The rapidly expanding production of shale gas has transformed the United States from being the world’s largest import market of liquefied natural gas (LNG) to a self-sustaining gas [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>European industries and some European governments have recently begun to recognise that the unconventional gas revolution is no longer confined to North America, but is spreading globally.</strong></p>
<p>The rapidly expanding production of shale gas has transformed the United States from being the world’s largest import market of liquefied natural gas (LNG) to a self-sustaining gas producer and a net gas exporter.</p>
<p>In 2009 the US overtook Russia as the world’s largest gas producer. In 2010 it overtook Qatari gas production as the world’s largest LNG exporter by about 60 per cent.</p>
<p>The sudden gas glut since 2009, from an overcapacity of LNG, stems from a combination of three factors: a drop in demand linked to the global economic recession; an unexpected dramatic increase in American shale gas production; and new global LNG delivery capacity.</p>
<p>LNG is now less expensive in Europe than pipeline gas for long-term contracts.</p>
<p>The development of unconventional gas in the US since 2006 has not only triggered a revolution in US energy markets, it has also become the tipping point for fundamental change in global gas markets.</p>
<p>It has laid the groundwork for an expanded role of natural gas in the world economy.</p>
<p>The International Energy Agency (IEA) has said that the world is set to experience a ‘Golden Age of Gas’ in which unconventional gas has already become a ‘game changer’.</p>
<p>Some countries in Europe &#8211; including Poland, the United Kingdom, Lithuania and Ukraine &#8211; and China and Australia, have shown interest in exploiting their own unconventional gas resources.</p>
<p>But potential environmental risks have swayed other countries into adopting moratoria or outright bans on the production of shale gas, and particularly on fracking, the process of hydraulic fracturing to get gas out of the ground.</p>
<p>The IEA predicts that nearly half the increase in global gas production up to 2035 will come from unconventional gas, if the industry receives a ‘social licence to operate’ within stringent regulatory regimes to satisfy public environmental and social concerns.</p>
<p>The US is debating whether to export shale gas to Europe and Asia from 2015.</p>
<p>But there are some new strategic developments on the European gas market which could also affect energy security.</p>
<p>One is the predicted stagnation of gas demand up to 2020, rather than a significant rise previously forecast.</p>
<p>Other factors include: the expansion of new LNG terminals in Poland, the Baltic States, Croatia and other countries; new gas interconnectors with reverse flow capacities in central and southeastern Europe; and the impact of the liberalisation and unbundling (the separation of prices for goods and services) processes within the EU-27.</p>
<p>The decline in US domestic coal consumption as a result of the coal-to-gas switch also opens the prospect of it becoming a leading coal exporter, reaching 500 mt (million tonnes) per year by 2030, to Europe, Asia and other regions.</p>
<p>The rising volume of relatively cheap coal imports from the US to Europe in 2012 has reduced Europe’s consumption of gas. It has also led to higher greenhouse gas emissions and put Europe at odds with EU climate and energy policies.</p>
<p>But the energy revolution is also having a big impact on the overall economic competitiveness of the US economy and industries towards rivals in Asia and Europe.</p>
<p>Development of unconventional gas reserves in the US has increased foreign direct investment (FDI), created hundreds of thousands of new jobs, dramatically reduced energy prices for industry and helped to strengthen energy diversification.</p>
<p>Europe’s energy-intensive industries, such as the chemical industry, have become increasingly concerned that the gas glut in the US has reduced natural gas prices there by more than two-thirds since 2008.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.naturalgaseurope.com/pdfs/GIS%2040%20-%20Shale%20Gas%20Europe%20Update%20I%20190313.pdf">Full story</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-shale-gas-revolution/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
