<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 09:08:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Steven McIntyre: The Marcott Filibuster</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/steven-mcintyre-marcott-filibuster/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/steven-mcintyre-marcott-filibuster/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 08:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11595</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Marcott et al have posted their long-promised FAQ at realclimate here. Without providing any links to or citation of Climate Audit, they now concede: 20th century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions. Otherwise, their [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Marcott et al have posted their long-promised FAQ at realclimate <a href="http://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2013/03/response-by-marcott-et-al/">here</a>. Without providing any links to or citation of Climate Audit, they now concede:</strong></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>20th century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Otherwise, their response is pretty much a filibuster, running the clock on questions that have not actually been asked and certainly not at issue by critics. For questions and issues that I’ve actually raised, for the most part, they merely re-iterate what they already said. Nothing worth waiting for.</p>
<p>They did not discuss or explain why they deleted modern values from the Md01-2421 splice at CA <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/17/hiding-the-decline-the-md01-2421-splice/">here</a> and <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/">here</a>. Or the deletion of modern values from OCE326-GGC300 as asked <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/">here</a>.</p>
<p>Nor do they discuss the difference between the results that had (presumably) been in the submission to Nature (preserved as a chapter in Marcott’s thesis).</p>
<p>Nor did they discuss the implausibility of their coretop redating of MD95-2043 and MD95-2011 as discussed <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/">here.</a></p>
<p>Instead of dealing with actual questions, for the most part, their “FAQ” filibusters about questions that no one was asking in connection with this study.</p>
<p>Eventually, they get to a question about their redating:</p>
<blockquote><p>Q. Why did you revise the age models of many of the published records that were used in your study?</p></blockquote>
<p>But here too they filibuster. They spend 3.5 paragraphs pontificating about radiocarbon recalibration – a topic that was not an issue. Indeed, on several occasions, including a comment on a similar filibuster by William Connolley, I clearly distinguished between radiocarbon recalibration and coretop redating, taking issue only with coretop redating. Nonetheless, Marcott et al adopted the same filibuster that Connolley had used.</p>
<p>When they eventually get to coretop redating, they say only:</p>
<blockquote><p>In geologic studies it is quite common that the youngest surface of a sediment core is not dated by radiocarbon, either because the top is disturbed by living organisms or during the coring process. Moreover, within the past hundred years before 1950 CE, radiocarbon dates are not very precise chronometers, because changes in radiocarbon production rate have by coincidence roughly compensated for fixed decay rates. For these reasons, and unless otherwise indicated, we followed the common practice of assuming an age of 0 BP for the marine core tops.</p></blockquote>
<p>This is nothing more than a re-iteration of the statement in their SI that I had quoted in my <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/">Core Tops post</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Core tops are assumed to be 1950 AD unless otherwise indicated in original publication.</p></blockquote>
<p>This is not an answer or justification of what they did. I urge interested readers to re-read the <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/">Core Tops post</a> and more generally the <a href="http://www.climateaudit.org/tag/marcott">Marcott sequence.<br />
</a></p>
<p>Nor did they directly answer questions about the questionable uptick. They pose the question for themselves as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>Q: What do paleotemperature reconstructions show about the temperature of the last 100 years?</p></blockquote>
<p>They give a “short” and “technical” answer. First they stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>A: Our global paleotemperature reconstruction includes a so-called “uptick” in temperatures during the 20th-century. However, in the paper we make the point that this particular feature is of shorter duration than the inherent smoothing in our statistical averaging procedure, and that it is based on only a few available paleo-reconstructions of the type we used. Thus, the 20th century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions. Our primary conclusions are based on a comparison of the longer term paleotemperature changes from our reconstruction with the well-documented temperature changes that have occurred over the last century, as documented by the instrumental record. Although not part of our study, high-resolution paleoclimate data from the past ~130 years have been compiled from various geological archives, and confirm the general features of warming trend over this time interval (Anderson, D.M. et al., 2013, Geophysical Research Letters, v. 40, p. 189-193;<a href="http://www.agu.org/journals/pip/gl/2012GL054271-pip.pdf" rel="nofollow">http://www.agu.org/journals/pip/gl/2012GL054271-pip.pdf</a>).</p></blockquote>
<p>Although they now apparently concede that “the 20th century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions”, this was definitely not the impression left by the authors when the article was published, when it was hailed as supposed confirmation of the Hockey Stick.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/31/the-marcott-filibuster/">Full story</a></p>
<h2>see also: <a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/climate-science-scandal-brewing/">Another Climate Scandal Brewing?</a></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/steven-mcintyre-marcott-filibuster/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Climate Scandal Exposed</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/climate-scandal-exposed/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/climate-scandal-exposed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 08:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11588</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Roger Pielke Jr documents the gross misrepresentation of the findings of a recent scientific paper via press release which appears to skirt awfully close to crossing the line into research misconduct. Spot the difference In 1991 the National Research Council proposed what has come to be a widely accepted definition of misconduct in science: Misconduct in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Roger Pielke Jr documents the gross misrepresentation of the findings of a recent scientific paper via press release which appears to skirt awfully close to crossing the line into research misconduct.</strong></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-0UtrItVc9RA/UVjnUMFb6XI/AAAAAAAACks/GEbpGKABqUc/s1600/marcott1.jpg"><img alt="" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-0UtrItVc9RA/UVjnUMFb6XI/AAAAAAAACks/GEbpGKABqUc/s640/marcott1.jpg" width="320" height="256" border="0" /></a></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Spot the difference</strong></h2>
<div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-USBwfGhd5oM/UVjxNw-cO0I/AAAAAAAACk4/xUGDLM2V5Aw/s1600/marcott2.jpg"><img alt="" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-USBwfGhd5oM/UVjxNw-cO0I/AAAAAAAACk4/xUGDLM2V5Aw/s320/marcott2.jpg" width="320" height="201" border="0" /></a></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="http://www.nap.edu/openbook.php?record_id=1864&amp;page=27"><span style="color: #0000ff;">In 1991 the National Research Council proposed</span></a> </span>what has come to be a widely accepted definition of misconduct in science:</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<blockquote><p><em>Misconduct in science is defined as fabrication, falsification, or plagiarism, in proposing, performing, or reporting research. Misconduct in science does not include errors of judgment; errors in the recording, selection, or analysis of data; differences in opinions involving the interpretation of data; or misconduct unrelated to the research process.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Arguments over data and methods are the lifeblood of science, and are not instances of misconduct.</p>
<p>However, here I document the gross misrepresentation of the findings of a recent scientific paper via press release which appears to skirt awfully close to crossing the line into research misconduct, as defined by the NRC. I recommend steps to fix this mess, saving face for all involved, and a chance for this small part of the climate community to take a step back toward unambiguous scientific integrity.</p>
<p>The paper I refer to is by <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/339/6124/1198.abstract?sid=a53ce5ae-7d84-4a54-bdf1-bdee207e8d7f">Marcott et al. 2013</a>, published recently in <i>Science</i>. A<a href="http://www.nsf.gov/news/news_summ.jsp?cntn_id=127133"> press release issued by the National Science Foundation</a>, which funded the research, explains the core methodology and key conclusion of the paper as follows (emphasis added):</p>
<blockquote><p>Peter Clark, an OSU paleoclimatologist and co-author of the Science paper, says that many previous temperature reconstructions were regional and not placed in a global context.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you just look at one part of the world, temperature history can be affected by regional climate processes like El Niño or monsoon variations,&#8221; says Clark.</p>
<p>&#8220;But <b>when you combine data from sites around the world, you can average out those regional anomalies and get a clear sense of the Earth&#8217;s global temperature history.&#8221;</b></p>
<p>What that history shows, the researchers say, is that during the last 5,000 years, the Earth on average cooled about 1.3 degrees Fahrenheit&#8211;until the last 100 years, when it warmed about 1.3 degrees F.</p></blockquote>
<p>The press release clearly explains that the paper (a) combines data from many sites around the world to create a &#8220;temperature reconstruction&#8221; which gives a &#8220;sense of the Earth&#8217;s temperature history,&#8221; and (b) &#8220;that history shows&#8221; a cooling over the past 5000 years, until the last 100 years when all of that cooling was reversed.</p>
<p>The conclusions of the press release were faithfully reported by a wide range of media outlets, and below I survey several of them to illustrate that the content of the press release was accurately reflected in media coverage and, at times, amplified by scientists both involved and not involved with the study.</p>
<p><b>Examples of Media Coverage</b></p>
<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/08/science/earth/global-temperatures-highest-in-4000-years-study-says.html">Here is Justin Gillis at the <i>New York Times</i></a>, with emphasis added to this excerpt and also those further below:</p>
<blockquote><p><b>The modern rise</b> that has recreated the temperatures of 5,000 years ago is occurring at an exceedingly rapid clip on a geological time scale, <b>appearing in graphs in the new paper as a sharp vertical spike</b>.</p></blockquote>
<p>Similarly, at the NY Times Andy Revkin reported much the same in a post titled, &#8220;<a href="http://dotearth.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/03/07/scientists-find-an-abrupt-warm-jog-after-a-very-long-cooling/">Scientists Find an Abrupt Warm Jog After a Very Long Cooling</a>.&#8221; Revkin included the following graph from the paper along with a caption explaining what the graph shows:</p>
<blockquote>
<div><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-0UtrItVc9RA/UVjnUMFb6XI/AAAAAAAACks/GEbpGKABqUc/s1600/marcott1.jpg"><img alt="" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-0UtrItVc9RA/UVjnUMFb6XI/AAAAAAAACks/GEbpGKABqUc/s640/marcott1.jpg" width="400" height="320" border="0" /></a></div>
<p>Revkin&#8217;s caption:  A new Science paper includes this graph of data providing clues to past global temperature. It shows the warming as the last ice age ended (left), a period when temperatures were warmer than today, a cooling starting 5,000 years ago and<b> an abrupt warming in the last 100 years</b>.</p></blockquote>
<p>Revkin concluded: &#8220;the work reveals a fresh, and very long, climate “hockey stick.”&#8221; For those unfamiliar, a hockey stick has a shaft and a blade.</p>
<div><a href="http://www.bombayharbor.com/productImage/Ice_Hockey_Stick/Ice_Hockey_Stick.jpg"><img alt="" src="http://www.bombayharbor.com/productImage/Ice_Hockey_Stick/Ice_Hockey_Stick.jpg" width="320" height="50" border="0" /></a></div>
<p>Any association with the so-called &#8220;hockey stick&#8221; is sure to capture interest in the highly politicized context of the climate debate, in which the iconic figure is like catnip to partisans on both sides. Here is <a href="http://www.climatecentral.org/news/climate-to-warm-beyond-levels-seen-for-at-least-11300-years-15701">Michael Lemonick at <i>Climate Central</i></a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>The study&#8230; confirms the now famous <a href="http://www.climatecentral.org/news/scientist-steps-off-the-battlefield-discusses-climate-wars/">“hockey stick”</a> graph that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_E._Mann">Michael Mann</a> published more than a decade ago. <b>That study showed a sharp upward temperature trend over the past century</b> after more than a thousand years of relatively flat temperatures. . .</p>
<p>“What’s striking,” said lead author Shaun Marcott of Oregon State University in an interview, “is that <b>the records we use are completely independent, and produce the same result</b>.”</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://grist.org/climate-energy/a-bigger-badder-climate-hockey-stick/">Here is Grist.org</a>, which refers in the passage below to the same figure shown above:</p>
<blockquote><p>A study published in <i>Science</i> reconstructs global temperatures further back than ever before — a full 11,300 years. The new analysis finds that the only problem with Mann’s hockey stick was that its handle was about 9,000 years too short. <b>The rate of warming over the last 100 years hasn’t been seen for as far back as the advent of agriculture</b>.</p>
<p>To be clear, the study finds that temperatures in about a fifth of this historical period were higher than they are today. But the key, said lead author Shaun Marcott of Oregon State University, is that temperatures are shooting through the roof faster than we’ve ever seen.</p>
<p><b>“What we found is that temperatures increased in the last 100 years as much as they had cooled in the last 6,000 or 7,000,”</b> he said. “In other words, the rate of change is much greater than anything we’ve seen in the whole Holocene,” referring to the current geologic time period, which began around 11,500 years ago.</p></blockquote>
<p>Back to more mainstream outlets, <a href="http://www.nature.com/news/global-temperatures-are-close-to-11-000-year-peak-1.12564">here is how <i>Nature</i> characterized the study</a>, offering a substantially similar but somewhat more technical description of the curve shown in the figure above:</p>
<blockquote><p>Marcott and his colleagues set about reconstructing global climate trends all the way back to 11,300 years ago, when the Northern Hemisphere was emerging from the most recent ice age. To do so, they collected and analysed data gathered by other teams. The 73 overlapping climate records that they considered included sediment cores drilled from lake bottoms and sea floors around the world, along with a handful of ice cores collected in Antarctica and Greenland.</p>
<p>Each of these chronicles spanned at least 6,500 years, and each included a millennium-long baseline period beginning in the middle of the post-ice-age period at 3550 bc.</p>
<p>For some records, the researchers inferred past temperatures from the ratio of magnesium and calcium ions in the shells of microscopic creatures that had died and dropped to the ocean floor; for others, they measured the lengths of long-chain organic molecules called alkenones that were trapped in the sediments.</p>
<p>After the ice age, they found, global average temperatures rose until they reached a plateau between 7550 and 3550 bc. Then a long-term cooling trend set in, reaching its lowest temperature extreme between ad 1450 and 1850. <b>Since then, temperatures have been increasing at a dramatic clip: from the first decade of the twentieth century to now</b>, global average temperatures rose from near their coldest point since the ice age to nearly their warmest, Marcott and his team report today in <i>Science</i>.</p></blockquote>
<p>And here is <a href="http://www.newscientist.com/article/dn23247-true-face-of-climates-hockey-stick-graph-revealed.html">New Scientist</a>, making reference to the exact same graph:</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="http://proglacial.com/Proglacial/Home.html">Shaun Marcott</a> of Oregon State University in Corvallis and colleagues have compiled 73 such proxies from around the world, all of which reach back to the end of the <a href="http://www.newscientist.com/article/dn18949-the-history-of-ice-on-earth.html">last glacial period</a>, 11,300 years ago. During this period, known as the Holocene, the climate has been relatively warm – and civilisation has flourished.</p>
<p>&#8220;Most global temperature reconstructions have only spanned the past 2000 years,&#8221; says Marcott.</p>
<p><b>Marcott&#8217;s graph shows temperatures rising slowly after the ice age, until they peaked 9500 years ago. The total rise over that period was about 0.6 °C. They then held steady until around 5500 years ago, when they began slowly falling again until around 1850. The drop was 0.7 °C, roughly reversing the previous rise. </b><br />
<b><br />
</b><b>Then, in the late 19th century, the graph shows temperatures shooting up, driven by humanity&#8217;s greenhouse gas emissions.</b></p>
<p>The rate of warming in the last 150 years is unlike anything that happened in at least 11,000 years, says <a href="http://www.meteo.psu.edu/holocene/public_html/Mann/">Michael Mann</a> of the Pennsylvania State University in University Park, who was not involved in Marcott&#8217;s study. It was Mann who created the original <a href="http://www.newscientist.com/article/mg18925431.400-climate-the-great-hockey-stick-debate.html">hockey stick graph</a> (<a href="http://www.newscientist.com/data/images/ns/cms/mg18925431.400/mg18925431.400-2_752.jpg">see upper graph here</a>), which showed the change in global temperatures over <a href="http://www.newscientist.com/blogs/culturelab/2012/03/the-man-behind-the-hockey-stick-graph.html">the last 1000 years</a>.</p>
<p>Over the Holocene, temperatures rose and fell less than 1 °C, and they did so over thousands of years, says Marcott. &#8220;It took 8000 years to go from warm to cold.&#8221; Agriculture, communal life and forms of government all arose during this relatively stable period, he adds. <b>Then in 100 years, global temperatures suddenly shot up again to very close to the previous maximum</b>.</p></blockquote>
<p>It seems clear that even as various media took different angles on the story and covered it in varying degrees of technical detail, the articles listed above accurately reflected the conclusions reflected in the NSF press release, and specifically the &#8220;hockey stick&#8221;-like character of the new temperature reconstruction. Unfortunately, all of this is just wrong, as I explain below. (If you&#8217;d like to explore media coverage further <a href="https://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;gl=us&amp;tbm=nws&amp;q=marcott+hockey+stick&amp;oq=marcott+hockey+stick&amp;gs_l=news-cc.3..43j43i53.1831.6537.0.9316.20.6.0.14.0.0.118.469.4j2.6.0...0.0...1ac.1.Vn1u5xHHxRM">here is a link</a> to more stories. My colleague <a href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/imageo/2013/03/13/art-of-the-anthropocene-the-scythe/">Tom Yulsman got punked too</a>.)</p>
<p><b>The Problem with the NSF Press Release and the Subsequent Reporting</b></p>
<p>There is a big problem with the media reporting of the new paper. It contains a fundamental error which (apparently) originates in the NSF press release and which was furthered by public comments by scientists.</p>
<p>In a belatedly-posted FAQ to the paper, which appeared on Real Climate earlier today,<a href="http://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2013/03/response-by-marcott-et-al/comment-page-1">Marcott et al. make this startling admission</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><i>Q: What do paleotemperature reconstructions show about the temperature of the last 100 years?</i></p>
<p>A: Our global paleotemperature reconstruction includes a so-called “uptick” in temperatures during the 20<sup>th</sup>-century. However, in the paper we make the point that this particular feature is of shorter duration than the inherent smoothing in our statistical averaging procedure, and that it is based on only a few available paleo-reconstructions of the type we used. Thus, the 20<sup>th</sup> century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions.</p></blockquote>
<p>Got that?</p>
<p>In case you missed it, I repeat:</p>
<blockquote><p><b>. . . the 20<sup>th</sup> century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes . . .</b></p></blockquote>
<p>What that means is that this paper actually has nothing to do with a &#8220;hockey stick&#8221; as it does not have the ability to reproduce 20th century temperatures in a manner that is &#8220;statistically robust.&#8221; The new &#8220;hockey stick&#8221; is no such thing as Marcott et al. has no blade. (To be absolutely clear, I am not making a point about temperatures of the 20th century, but what can be concluded from the paper about temperatures of the 20th century.)</p>
<p>Yet, you might recall that the NSF press release said something quite different:</p>
<blockquote><p>What that [temperature reconstruction] history shows, the researchers say, is that during the last 5,000 years, the Earth on average cooled about 1.3 degrees Fahrenheit&#8211;until the last 100 years, when it warmed about 1.3 degrees F.</p></blockquote>
<p>So what the paper actually shows is the following, after I have removed from the graph the 20th century period that is &#8220;not statistically robust&#8221; (this is also the figure that appears at the top of this post):</p>
<div><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-USBwfGhd5oM/UVjxNw-cO0I/AAAAAAAACk4/xUGDLM2V5Aw/s1600/marcott2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-USBwfGhd5oM/UVjxNw-cO0I/AAAAAAAACk4/xUGDLM2V5Aw/s640/marcott2.jpg" width="400" height="320" border="0" /></a></div>
<p>Surely there is great value in such an analysis of pre-20th century temperatures. And there can be no doubt <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/31/the-marcott-filibuster">there will be continuing debates and discussions</a> about the paper&#8217;s methods and conclusions. But one point that any observer should be able to clearly conclude is that the public representation of the paper was grossly in error. The temperature reconstruction does not allow any conclusions to be made about the period after 1900.</p>
<p>Does the public misrepresentation amount to scientific misconduct? I&#8217;m not sure, but it is far to close to that line for comfort. Saying so typically leads to a torrent of angry ad hominem and defensive attacks, and evokes little in the way of actual concern for the integrity of this highly politicized area of science. Looking past the predictable responses, this mess can be fixed in a relatively straightforward manner with everyone&#8217;s reputation intact.</p>
<p><b>How to Fix This </b></p>
<p>Here are the steps that I recommend should be taken:</p>
<p>1) <i>Science</i> should issue a correction to the paper, and specially do the following:</p>
<p>(a) retract and replot all figures in the paper and SI eliminating from the graphs all data/results that fail to meet the paper&#8217;s criteria for &#8220;statistical robustness.&#8221;<br />
(b) include in the correction the explicit and unambiguous statement offered in the FAQ released today that the analysis is not &#8220;statistically robust&#8221; post-1900.</p>
<p>2) NSF should issue a correction to its press release, clarifying and correcting the statements of Peter Clark (a co-author, found above) and Candace Major, NSF program manager, <a href="http://www.nsf.gov/news/news_summ.jsp?cntn_id=127133">who says in the release</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;<b>The last century stands out as the anomaly in this record of global temperature since the end of the last ice age</b>,&#8221; says Candace Major, program director in the National Science Foundation&#8217;s (NSF) Division of Ocean Sciences.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://rogerpielkejr.blogspot.co.uk/2013/03/fixing-marcott-mess-in-climate-science.html">Full story</a></p>
<h2> see also &#8211; <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/31/the-marcott-filibuster/">Steve McIntyre: The Marcott Filibuster</a></h2>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/climate-scandal-exposed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Cost Of Green Energy Topples The Government In Bulgaria</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/cost-green-energy-topples-government-bulgaria/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/cost-green-energy-topples-government-bulgaria/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 15:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11585</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is a lesson to learned from events last month in Europe’s poorest country, Bulgaria, well actually there are 2 lessons to be learned, both unfortunately need to be learned by politicians in the rest of Europe, or the world when it comes to it. The citizens of Europe’s poorest country, Bulgaria, take to the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>There is a lesson to learned from events last month in Europe’s poorest country, Bulgaria, well actually there are 2 lessons to be learned, both unfortunately need to be learned by politicians in the rest of Europe, or the world when it comes to it.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://toryardvaark.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bulgaria_green_energy_costs_protest.jpg"><img alt="The citizens of Europe's poorest country, Bulgaia, take to the streets to protest the cost of Green Energy and Poverty" src="http://toryardvaark.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bulgaria_green_energy_costs_protest.jpg?w=604&amp;h=339" width="483" height="271" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;">The citizens of Europe’s poorest country, Bulgaria, take to the streets to protest the cost of Green Energy and Poverty</span></p>
<p>The first lesson is that people will not put up with ever increasing electricity bills in the name of saving the planet while a few fat cats and crony capitalists cream off huge profits from Green subsidies on ordinary people’s and businesses energy bills, the second lesson is that Green intermittent renewable energy wreaks havoc on electrical grids, ultimately leading to brown outs and black outs as the grid cannot cope with the sudden Green energy spikes.</p>
<p>History shows that even a short period of rolling black outs will bring down a Government, even in a country like Britain, when in 1974 then Prime Minister Edward Heath took on the miners, with the resulting <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three-Day_Week"><strong>Three Day Week</strong></a> of rolling power cuts. Heath called an election in February 1974 when the Three Day Week was at its height, and effectively lost the election as he could not form a working majority for Government.</p>
<p>On February 20th this year protests at the cost of Green energy and the resulting increased poverty toppled the government of Boyko Borissov:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Protests against high electricity bills and poverty toppled the government of Boyko Borissov on Feb. 20. Now Bulgaria may suspend as much as 40 percent of wind and solar power capacity as part of its effort to stem oversupply and stabilize electricity generation.</em></p>
<p><em>About 40 percent of wind and solar power producers aren’t providing real-time information to the country’s central electricity dispatcher, jeopardizing the safety of Bulgaria’s transmission network, Energy Minister Asen Vasilev said in a document posted on the ministry’s website. They will be temporarily disconnected, he said.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>That is a massive reduction in Green energy generation, attempts by the Bulgarian state energy regulator to curb Green energy costs by substantially increasing grid access fees has been ruled against by the courts who found in favor of 3 solar energy companies on March 15th, with more court cases by Green renewable energy suppliers to follow there will be no easy escape from Green induced poverty for the people of Bulgaria.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Bulgaria’s grid is suffering from power overloads caused by a rapid increase in wind and solar capacity coupled with decreasing domestic consumption in the <a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/bulgaria-suspend-40-green-energy-projects/">face of a weak economy</a></em></p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://toryaardvark.com/2013/03/29/the-cost-of-green-energy-topples-the-government-in-bulgaria/"></p>
<p style="display: inline !important;">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/cost-green-energy-topples-government-bulgaria/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forget Economic Recovery: Energy Bills To Soar Due To ‘Stealth Tax’</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/forget-economic-recovery-energy-bills-soar-due-stealth-tax/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/forget-economic-recovery-energy-bills-soar-due-stealth-tax/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 14:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11581</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Energy-intensive industries are bracing themselves for a renewed surge in utility bills tomorrow when the UK government’s highly controversial Carbon Price Floor starts feeding through into energy costs. The net effect will be to take money out of a fragile economy, with firms committing more of their cash to meet rising operating costs. Lambasted by business [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Energy-intensive industries are bracing themselves for a renewed surge in utility bills tomorrow when the UK government’s highly controversial Carbon Price Floor starts feeding through into energy costs. The net effect will be to take money out of a fragile economy, with firms committing more of their cash to meet rising operating costs.</strong></p>
<div>
<p>Lambasted by business and environmental groups as a “stealth tax”, the price floor is expected to raise up to £3.2 billion over the next three years.</p>
<p>Although critics say the funds should be ploughed back into the green energy technologies that the price floor is intended to support, the money will instead be absorbed for general use by the cash-strapped Exchequer.</p>
<p>Michael Murphy, energy partner with MacRoberts Solicitors in Glasgow, said all business and residential consumers would be affected, with heavy industries, hospitals, councils and other large-volume users bearing the brunt of the increases.</p>
<p>“What we have said to our clients is that we are telling you this not because there is a clever way to avoid it – we are telling you this because your utility bills are going to rocket,” he said.</p>
<p>The net effect will be to take money out of a fragile economy, with firms committing more of their cash to meet rising operating costs.</p>
<p>“That is the first call, and will come before investment in growth and new jobs,” Murphy added.</p>
<p>In an apparent effort to pre-empt any negative backlash against tomorrow’s price increases, the Department of Energy &amp; Climate Change (Decc) released a report last week, which claimed that although utility bills will continue to rise, they will be 11 per cent lower by 2020 than they would have been without the government’s energy policies.</p>
<p>However, the Decc report also conceded that many businesses are bearing a bigger share of the burden brought by government policy.</p>
</div>
<p><a href="http://www.scotsman.com/business/energy-and-utilities/energy-bills-to-soar-due-to-stealth-tax-1-2868287">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/forget-economic-recovery-energy-bills-soar-due-stealth-tax/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bjorn Lomborg: The Joy Of Global Warming</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/bjorn-lomborg-joy-global-warming/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/bjorn-lomborg-joy-global-warming/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 09:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11575</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As I fly into a snow-bound Britain, I realise that you might be asking where global warming has gone as you shiver in the coldest March for 50 years and wonder what you will do if gas has to be rationed. I have been involved in the climate debate for more than a decade, but [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>As I fly into a snow-bound Britain, I realise that you might be asking where global warming has gone as you shiver in the coldest March for 50 years and wonder what you will do if gas has to be rationed. I have been involved in the climate debate for more than a decade, but I am still amazed at how wrong we get it. Let us try to restart our thinking on global warming.</strong></p>
<p>Yes, global warming is real and mostly man-made, but our policies have failed predictably and spectacularly.</p>
<p>I was one of the strongest critics of the Kyoto climate change treaty, back when it was considered gospel.</p>
<p>People were aghast when you criticised it then. Now Kyoto has no friends, and everyone remembers how they really did not believe in it.</p>
<p>If we want to avoid our current ambitions failing in the same way, if we want to get past Britain’s unworkable and inefficient Climate Change Act and the EU’s climate policies, we need to face up to some hard truths.</p>
<p>I am going to explain the things everyone ought to know about climate change. Then I will set out the ways in which our policies do not work and show you an approach that has a much better chance of fixing the climate.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="http://www.thesundaytimes.co.uk/sto/multimedia/archive/00334/31_NWS_GLOBAL_OVERL_334567a.jpg" width="800" height="350" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thesundaytimes.co.uk/sto/newsreview/features/article1237909.ece">Full story (subscription required)</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/bjorn-lomborg-joy-global-warming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Committee On Climate Change Launches Attack On Mail On Sunday</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/committee-climate-change-launches-attack-mail-sunday/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/committee-climate-change-launches-attack-mail-sunday/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 09:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Climate Record]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11570</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The official watchdog that advises the Government on greenhouse gas emissions targets has launched an astonishing attack on The Mail on Sunday – for accurately reporting that alarming predictions of global warming are wrong. We disclosed that although highly influential computer models are still estimating huge rises in world temperatures, there has been no statistically [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The official watchdog that advises the Government on greenhouse gas emissions targets has launched an astonishing attack on The Mail on Sunday – for accurately reporting that alarming predictions of global warming are wrong.</strong></p>
<p><span>We disclosed that although highly influential computer models are still estimating huge rises in world temperatures, there has been no statistically significant increase for more than 16 years.</span></p>
<p>Despite our revelation earlier this month, backed up by a scientifically researched graph, the Committee on Climate Change still clings to flawed predictions.</p>
<div>Leading the attack is committee member Sir Brian Hoskins, who is also director of the Grantham Institute for Climate Change at Imperial College, London. In a blog on the Committee on Climate Change’s website, Sir Brian insisted: ‘The scientific basis for significant long-term climate risks remains robust, despite the points raised .  .  . Early and deep cuts in emissions are still required.’</div>
<p><span>He also claimed our report ‘misunderstood’ the value of computer models. Yet in an interview three years ago, Sir Brian conceded that when he started out as a climate scientist, the models were ‘pretty lousy, and they’re still pretty lousy, really’.</span></p>
<p>Our graph earlier this month was reproduced from a version first drawn by Dr Ed Hawkins, of the National Centre for Atmospheric Science. Last week it was reprinted as part of a four-page report in The Economist.</p>
<p>The accuracy of computer forecasts is vital because they influence politicians and their key environmental advisers on how urgently to act on climate change – and how many billions of pounds they take from the taxpayer in ‘green’ levies.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img alt="How the MoS reported the faulty forecast" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/pix/2013/03/30/article-2301757-1903167F000005DC-59_634x480.jpg" width="444" height="336" /></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;">How the MoS reported the faulty forecast</span></div>
<p><span>The Committee on Climate Change claims such forecasts must be right because world temperatures have previously matched computer models’ ‘outputs’ for most of the past 60 years. Yet as this newspaper pointed out, for almost all of that 60-year period the models were not making predictions – because they did not yet exist.</span></p>
<p><span>Instead, the models had recently been making ‘hindcasts’ – backward projections based on climate simulations and tailored to actual temperatures. The evidence shows the models collapse when they try to forecast the future.</span></p>
<p>Author Andrew Montford, who runs the widely read Bishop Hill climate blog, leapt to The Mail on Sunday’s defence and said Sir Brian’s reliance on ‘hindcasts’ was <a href="http://www.bishop-hill.net/blog/2013/3/26/the-ccc-abandons-science.html">‘crazy, crazy stuff’.</a></p>
<p>David Whitehouse, of the Global Warming Policy Foundation, said the graph showed models were so unreliable that <a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/committee-climate-change-mail-sunday/">‘if this kind of data were from a drugs trial it would have been stopped long ago’</a>.</p>
<p>And last week, <a href="http://www.economist.com/news/science-and-technology/21574461-climate-may-be-heating-up-less-response-greenhouse-gas-emissions">The Economist repeated our claims</a> that many scientists now believe that previous estimates of ‘climate sensitivity’ – how much the world will warm each time the level of carbon dioxide doubles – are far too high.</p>
<p><span>In a key 2007 report, the UN Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change suggested this was most likely to be about 3C, with 4.5C considered ‘likely’. However, recent research suggests the true figure is much lower – between 1.5C and 2C – giving the world many more decades to avoid disaster through effective new technologies.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2301757/Governments-climate-watchdog-launches-astonishing-attack-Mail-Sunday--revealing-global-warming-science-wrong.html">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/committee-climate-change-launches-attack-mail-sunday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Carbon Levy Will Be A &#8216;Stealth Poll Tax&#8217; On Energy</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/carbon-levy-stealth-poll-tax-energy/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/carbon-levy-stealth-poll-tax-energy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 08:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11568</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The government&#8217;s new carbon levy is effectively a “stealth poll tax” that will only work to put up household electricity bills and hand a windfall to old nuclear plants, the head of energy giant E.ON has warned. The Treasury’s “carbon price floor” comes into effect on Monday and official estimates say it will add £5 [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The government&#8217;s new carbon levy is effectively a “stealth poll tax” that will only work to put up household electricity bills and hand a windfall to old nuclear plants, the head of energy giant E.ON has warned.</strong></p>
<p>The Treasury’s “carbon price floor” comes into effect on Monday and official estimates say it will add £5 to household bills this year, rising to about £50 by 2020.</p>
<p>The tax is intended to provide an incentive to invest in new wind farms and nuclear plants by making it more expensive to run coal and gas plants that emit carbon.</p>
<p>Tony Cocker, chief executive of E.ON UK, attacked the policy on the eve of its implementation, arguing that it simply “pushes up the price for electricity” and should be scrapped.</p>
<p>He told The Sunday Telegraph: “The carbon price floor is a tax and it’s pretty close to a stealth poll tax. It’s not based on ability to pay, it’s based on the requirement to keep warm and light your house.</p>
<p>“It was put in place with the stated objective of encouraging investment in low-carbon energy but it certainly doesn’t achieve that objective – it’s just a tax for the Exchequer.”</p>
<p>The measure is expected to raise billions of pounds for the Treasury over the next decade.</p>
<p>Mr Cocker criticised the lack of transparency over the tax. “It’s kind of hidden away,” he said. “If you called it an electricity tax or duty, like the fuel duty on cars, we could all understand that goes to the Exchequer.”</p>
<p>The carbon tax would also provide an unintended “windfall” subsidy for existing old nuclear and hydro plants, which is “completely unnecessary because it’s already been paid for”, he said.</p>
<p>European green policies already make polluting industries buy permits for each tonne of carbon they emit. However, the Government believes the prices have been too low and has introduced the carbon price floor to “top up” the cost per tonne of carbon dioxide.</p>
<p>But the tax has not proven enough to encourage new nuclear and wind power investors, with companies now being offered separate long-term subsidy schemes.</p>
<p>Because Britain is acting unilaterally in increasing carbon costs, critics say the tax will also have no effect on reducing carbon output.“If we charge more for carbon in the UK than is charged in Europe as a whole, all that means is we will burn less coal in the UK and the rest of Europe will burn more coal,” Mr Cocker said.</p>
<p>Manufacturers have called for the tax to be scrapped as they fear it will make British businesses uncompetitive compared with the rest of Europe. Ministers are planning a £150m compensation scheme to help compensate heavy industries.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/newsbysector/energy/9963116/Carbon-levy-will-be-a-stealth-poll-tax-on-energy.html">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/carbon-levy-stealth-poll-tax-energy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coldest Easter In 100 Years</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/coldest-easter-100-years/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/coldest-easter-100-years/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 08:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11565</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The icy Easter weekend has been declared the coldest in 100 years and forecasters have warned the cold snap will continue for the rest of the week.  Despite welcoming in British summer time, temperatures plummeted to -12.4C last night in Braemar in Aberdeenshire, while South Newington in Oxfordshire dropped to -5C. The Met office confirmed it [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><span data-mce-mark="1">The icy Easter weekend has been declared the coldest in 100 years and forecasters </span><span data-mce-mark="1">have warned the cold snap will continue for the rest of the week. </span></strong></p>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">Despite welcoming in British summer time, temperatures plummeted to -12.4C last night in Braemar in Aberdeenshire, while South Newington in Oxfordshire dropped to -5C.</span></p>
<p><span>The Met office confirmed it could be the coldest Easter Sunday morning in 100 years. </span></p>
<div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Water cascading down Summerhill Force, County Durham formed icicles today as the coldest March since 1963 draws to a close" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/pix/2013/03/30/article-2301473-190190D0000005DC-145_634x358.jpg" width="444" height="251" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Water cascading down Summerhill Force, County Durham formed icicles today as the coldest March since 1963 draws to a close</p>
</div>
<div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="A walker stepped under an impressive icicle covered cliffside in County Durham in freezing conditions today" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/pix/2013/03/30/article-2301473-190190E8000005DC-780_634x915.jpg" width="444" height="641" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">A walker stepped under an impressive icicle covered cliffside in County Durham in freezing conditions today</p>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="The Thames burst its banks between Barnes and Putney Pier ahead of the Easter Sunday Oxford and Cambridge Boat Race" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/pix/2013/03/30/article-0-19009372000005DC-783_634x424.jpg" width="444" height="297" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">The Thames burst its banks between Barnes and Putney Pier ahead of the Easter Sunday Oxford and Cambridge Boat Race</p>
</div>
<p><span>Greg Dewhurst, Met office spokesman, said: &#8216;It looks it.</span><span> It should be made official on Tuesday after Bank Holiday. </span></p>
<div>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">&#8216;Last time it was this cold on an Easter Sunday temperatures fell to -9.8C. But last night it was -12.4 in Scotland.&#8217; </span></p>
<p>But if you are heading out for an Easter Sunday stroll, you are in for plenty of sunshine.</p>
<div>
<p><span>&#8216;Today will see temperatures in most places between 4C and 7C across the country&#8217;, Mr Dewhurst said.</span></p>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">&#8216;It&#8217;s not too bad. But as a consequence of the sunny spells, temperatures will fall </span><span data-mce-mark="1">to close to freezing tonight. </span></p>
<p><span data-mce-mark="1">&#8216;Towards the north and Scotland it could reach -8C again.&#8217; </span></p>
</div>
</div>
<p><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2301851/Coldest-Easter-Sunday-100-YEARS-temperatures-plummet-12C-Britain-shivering-week.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/coldest-easter-100-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Future Of Energy: A Reality Check</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/future-energy-reality-check/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/future-energy-reality-check/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 18:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11559</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Two decades from now, a world with more people and higher average incomes will mean more demand for energy. That shouldn’t be a surprise. What’s more striking is to see where all this growth will happen. Want to understand the energy challenges the world might face in the future? There are few better places to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Two decades from now, a world with more people and higher average incomes will mean more demand for energy. That shouldn’t be a surprise. What’s more striking is to see where all this growth will happen.</strong></p>
<p>Want to understand the energy challenges the world might face in the future? There are few better places to turn than this year’s BP Energy Outlook to 2030, an annual publication that shows the company’s projections for energy supply and demand over the next two decades. The three graphs below highlight some of the trends likely to define the energy landscape in the years ahead, in BP’s view.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://blogs.cfr.org/levi/files/2013/03/figure-1-3-29-2013-570x427.png" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Two decades from now, a world with more people and higher average incomes will mean more demand for energy. That shouldn’t be a surprise. What’s more striking is to see where all this growth will happen. In BP’s forecast, low and medium income economies outside the OECD will account for a full 90 percent of population growth between now and 2030, and their GDP will climb much higher. These same countries will also contribute to 90 percent of all the energy demand growth over that time, roaring ahead of the developed world.</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.cfr.org/levi/2013/03/29/the-end-of-energy-as-we-know-it-in-three-graphs/figure-2_3-29-2013/" rel="attachment wp-att-4898"><img alt="" src="http://blogs.cfr.org/levi/files/2013/03/figure-2_3-29-2013-570x427.png" width="570" height="427" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.cfr.org/levi/2013/03/29/the-end-of-energy-as-we-know-it-in-three-graphs/"></p>
<p style="display: inline !important;"><span style="color: #0000ff;">Full story</span></p>
<p></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/future-energy-reality-check/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Israel Begins Tamar Gas Production In Boost To Economy</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/britain-dithers-israel-begins-tamar-gas-production-boost-economy/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/britain-dithers-israel-begins-tamar-gas-production-boost-economy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 18:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11554</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Israel started gas production at the Tamar offshore field that may save the country about 1 billion shekels ($274 million) a month in annual energy costs, the Energy Ministry said. Tamar natural gas rig. Photo: Albatross Noble Energy Inc. Chairman Charles D. Davidson congratulated Israel in an e-mailed statement. The production is “a great achievement that will [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Israel started gas production at the Tamar offshore field that may save the country about 1 billion shekels ($274 million) a month in annual energy costs, the Energy Ministry said.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Tamar natural gas rig." src="http://www.jpost.com/HttpHandlers/ShowImage.ashx?ID=215955" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;">Tamar natural gas rig. Photo: Albatross</span></p>
<p>Noble Energy Inc. Chairman Charles D. Davidson congratulated Israel in an e-mailed statement. The production is “a great achievement that will reduce the country’s dependency on energy imports and will move the country significantly closer to energy independence,” he said. Noble Energy has a 36 percent stake in Tamar.</p>
<p>The field in the eastern Mediterranean Sea, estimated to hold 9 trillion cubic feet of natural gas, is being developed by a group that includes Noble Energy, Delek Drilling-LP, Avner Oil Exploration LLP (AVNRL) and Isramco Negev 2 LP. (ISRAL) Along with Noble, Israeli energy exploration companies have discovered over the past three years enough gas under the Mediterranean to supply the country’s needs for 150 years.</p>
<p>“We are talking about billions of dollars coming to the state from tax revenues from Tamar gas over a 20-year period,” Gilad Alper, a senior analyst at Excellence Nessuah Brokerage Ltd., said in a phone interview on March 28. “It will also reduce energy costs as we will replace expensive imports with a cheap domestic supply of natural gas. The start of the flow is a big positive for the economy.”</p>
<p>The Tamar and Dalit fields could supply Israel with gas for two decades. The larger Leviathan field is estimated to hold 18 trillion cubic feet of gas, according to a Noble press release dated March 6.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">The three fields provide Israel with reserves more than 14 times larger than </span>Germany<span style="font-size: 13px;">’s total proven gas reserves, which the BP Statistical Review of World Energy published in June 2012 lists at 2.2 trillion cubic feet.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-30/israel-begins-gas-production-at-tamar-field-in-boost-to-economy.html">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/britain-dithers-israel-begins-tamar-gas-production-boost-economy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
