<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 11:17:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Germany Energy Transition Faces Cuts After European Parliament Vote</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/germany-energy-transition-faces-cuts-european-parliament-vote/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/germany-energy-transition-faces-cuts-european-parliament-vote/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 11:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=12022</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Germany says it is facing a funding gap in its transition to green energy after a European Parliament vote against reforming the EU&#8217;s emissions trading scheme. Germany says it is facing a funding gap in its transition to green energy after a European Parliament vote against reforming the European Union&#8217;s emissions trading scheme. Much of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Germany says it is facing a funding gap in its transition to green energy after a European Parliament vote against reforming the EU&#8217;s emissions trading scheme.</strong></p>
<p>Germany says it is facing a funding gap in its transition to green energy after a European Parliament vote against reforming the European Union&#8217;s emissions trading scheme.</p>
<p>Much of the financial backing for Germany&#8217;s Energy and Climate Fund &#8212; set up to facilitate the phasing out of nuclear energy and the promotion of wind and solar alternatives &#8212; comes from the emissions trading scheme, under which polluters buy the &#8220;right&#8221; to emit carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases through an open market system.</p>
<p>The European Commission had been pushing to boost faltering prices for carbon allowances by reducing an oversupply caused by the economic downturn &#8212; &#8220;backloading&#8221; them from the current 2013-15 period to 2018-20.</p>
<p>But the Parliament, meeting in a plenary session Tuesday, rejected the proposal, which was opposed by energy-intensive businesses.</p>
<p>After the vote, prices for allowances plunged to an all-time low of $2.20 per ton of carbon equivalent, bringing predictions the ETS had been dealt a possibly fatal blow.</p>
<p>Germany had assumed a carbon price of $13 per ton last year when it set the budget for its energy transition fund, predicting it would receive around $2.5 billion from the ETS. But the low carbon prices means only $1.16 billion will actually be available this year, the treasury estimated this week.</p>
<p>Another cut of $1.4 billion could be in store for 2014, it warned.</p>
<p>German Environment Minister Peter Altmaier, expressing disappointment over the European Parliament vote, said the blow would be softened somewhat with a $406 million contribution from the KfW Development Bank this year to support research and development into electric vehicles, building retrofitting and battery storage &#8212; a major focus of the government&#8217;s green energy plans.</p>
<p>Because of that one-time contribution, those areas would thus be fully funded this year, but other areas will see their funding slashed by half.</p>
<p>&#8220;The decision of the European Parliament to reject proposals to support the European emissions trading scheme and its impact on the revenue situation for the (climate fund), must be taken into account,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Despite the vote, Altmaier remained optimistic the ETS can be saved, noting that rather than killing the backloading proposal, the EP vote referred it back to committees for more discussion, the daily Die Welt reported.</p>
<p>&#8220;I personally believe that we can effectively combat climate change with emissions trading,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The issue has produced a political split in the German governing coalition. While Altmaier, a member of Chancellor Angela Merkel&#8217;s Christian Democratic Union, pushed hard to boost the ETS, Economics Minister Philipp Rosler of the pro-business Free Democratic Party resolutely opposed the idea.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.upi.com/Business_News/Energy-Resources/2013/04/19/Germany-energy-transition-faces-cuts-after-European-Parliament-vote/UPI-91441366344240/?spt=hs&amp;or=er">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/germany-energy-transition-faces-cuts-european-parliament-vote/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Europe Needs Shale Gas</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-shale-gas/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-shale-gas/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 09:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=12012</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Developing shale gas as a viable source of energy could help Europe out of the recession. Instead, it’s still another structural disadvantage. It doesn’t have to be. &#160; Europe’s struggles to get out of the recession are handicapped by Europe’s very high relative cost base, particularly in costs for labour and energy. Labour rates that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Developing shale gas as a viable source of energy could help Europe out of the recession. Instead, it’s still another structural disadvantage. It doesn’t have to be.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Europe’s struggles to get out of the recession are handicapped by Europe’s very high relative cost base, particularly in costs for labour and energy.</p>
<p>Labour rates that are more than double those in the Asian region – and about 5 to 8 times as high as in China.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-shale-gas/wages-218x300/" rel="attachment wp-att-12017"><img alt="Wages-218x300" src="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/04/Wages-218x300.png" width="218" height="300" /></a></strong></p>
<p>Figure 1: Difference in manufacturing labor costs around the world, 2010</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There may not be much that European governments can do about the structural labour cost disadvantage, although countries such as <a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.forbes.com/places/germany/">Germany</a> have made some progress. Labour costs are very much influenced by historical conditions and social security regulation. Labour costs in Europe are high and will remain relatively high in the medium to long term.</p>
<p>However, European governments can do something about the energy cost difference. And developing shale gas reserves is the most obvious.</p>
<div>
<p>In the past ten years, natural gas in the Gulf Region has been 8-10 times cheaper than in the US, Europe and Asia. <a style="font-size: 13px;" title="" href="http://www.forbes.com/Users/ALEE/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/GOUNNCWP/CH_RevisedForbesshalegas%25e2%2580%2599s%2520shale%2520gas%2520disadvantage%2520v5.docx#_ednref1">[i]</a> The shale gas development in the US was already in full force by 2008 and led to a natural gas bonanza, with gas prices that are roughly a third of those in Europe. And though China has neither a natural gas nor oil cost advantage, it is fully leveraging its labour cost advantage and dramatically increasing its productivity and innovation. Europe, however, continues to face the same high costs as before. <a style="font-size: 13px;" title="" href="http://www.forbes.com/Users/ALEE/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/GOUNNCWP/CH_RevisedForbesshalegas%25e2%2580%2599s%2520shale%2520gas%2520disadvantage%2520v5.docx#_ednref2">[ii]</a></p>
</div>
<p>Sectors such as the (petro)chemical industry that are highly dependent on the cost of oil or natural gas (naptha or ethane) are critically exposed. By 2012, the sector employed about 1.2 billion people in Europe, a loss of 200,000 jobs.<a title="" href="http://www.forbes.com/Users/ALEE/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/GOUNNCWP/CH_RevisedForbesshalegas%25e2%2580%2599s%2520shale%2520gas%2520disadvantage%2520v5.docx#_edn3">[iii]</a> From 2006-2011, it realized one tenth of the sales growth rate of petrochemicals in Asia-Pacific (0.9% vs. 9.7%) and invested less than a third as the chemical industry in that region ($600 billion vs. $200 billion). Meanwhile the global sales share of chemicals in Europe dropped from 30% to 20% in the period 2001-2011, while the share of Asia Pacific doubled from 23% to 45%. At the same time, the Gulf region is on a massive capacity expansion drive, accounting for more than 50% of ongoing global petrochemicals capacity additions, seeking to exploit its access to cheep feedstock.<a title="" href="http://www.forbes.com/Users/ALEE/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/GOUNNCWP/CH_RevisedForbesshalegas%25e2%2580%2599s%2520shale%2520gas%2520disadvantage%2520v5.docx#_edn4">[iv]</a></p>
<div><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-shale-gas/shale-jv-300x148/" rel="attachment wp-att-12016"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12016" alt="Shale-JV-300x148" src="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/04/Shale-JV-300x148.png" width="300" height="148" /></a></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Figure 2: International joint venture investment in US shale plays, 2008-2012 <a style="font-size: 13px;" title="" href="http://www.forbes.com/Users/ALEE/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/GOUNNCWP/CH_RevisedForbesshalegas%25e2%2580%2599s%2520shale%2520gas%2520disadvantage%2520v5.docx#_edn1">[v]</a></div>
<div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-size: 13px;">Other Countries are Investing Heavily</strong></p>
<div>
<p>Between 2008 and 2012, investment in shale plays in the US totaled $133.7 billion of which joint ventures of non-US firms with US firms accounted for 20%.  There were also outright acquisitions: BHP Billiton’s acquisition of Petrohawk Energy Corp. <a title="" href="http://www.forbes.com/Users/ALEE/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/GOUNNCWP/CH_RevisedForbesshalegas%25e2%2580%2599s%2520shale%2520gas%2520disadvantage%2520v5.docx#_edn1">[vi]</a> Europe, meanwhile, has only seen a modest number of explorations, primarily in Poland, though shale gas reserves on the continent are substantial.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<p><a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-shale-gas/shale-basins-300x190/" rel="attachment wp-att-12015"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12015" alt="Shale-Basins-300x190" src="http://www.thegwpf.org/content/uploads/2013/04/Shale-Basins-300x190.png" width="300" height="190" /></a></p>
<p>Figure 3: Major shale basins around the world <a style="font-size: 13px;" title="" href="http://www.forbes.com/Users/ALEE/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/Content.Outlook/GOUNNCWP/CH_RevisedForbesshalegas%25e2%2580%2599s%2520shale%2520gas%2520disadvantage%2520v5.docx#_edn1"><strong>[vii]</strong></a></p>
<div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In the US, land owners not only own the land but also the resources below the surface. This is an advantage for rapidly developing the shale gas industry. In Europe, it is the governments which own the resources below the surface, and the popular argument today opines this situation impedes fast development of shale gas production. This is a weak argument and poor excuse for inaction.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Governments Must Act</strong></p>
<div>
<p>Governments can actually move the development of shale gas forward, as they have in the past with other public works: the development of a massive railway system, the impressive nuclear industry in countries such as France. With the necessary vision and willpower, governments can advance shale gas development and spur economic growth but it will entail using its legal power to expropriate land – and adequate compensation for landowners. They could also find, with concerted effort, solutions to the environmental challenges shale gas exploration generates.</p>
</div>
<p>Without such actions, sectors such as the European chemical industry will find themselves on the same long-term path as other sectors suffering from high costs and overcapacity, such as the car and steel industry, with consequences that are all too well known.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/insead/2013/04/18/why-europe-needs-shale-gas/">Full story</a></p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/europe-shale-gas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Renewable Energy Investment In Obama’s Once Ballyhooed Spain Evaporates – Plummeting 96%!</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/renewable-energy-investment-obamas-ballyhooed-spain-evaporates-plummeting-96/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/renewable-energy-investment-obamas-ballyhooed-spain-evaporates-plummeting-96/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 08:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PhilippMueller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=12007</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Global investment in renewable energies in the first quarter of this year plummeted a whopping 22%, falling to $40 billion, according to Bloomberg New Energy Finance here. The consequences for many companies and their employees of course will be calamitous to say the least. So many employees had been given the false promise of green jobs. Now, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Global investment</strong> in renewable energies in the first quarter of this year plummeted a whopping 22%, falling to $40 billion, according to <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-14/clean-energy-investment-falls-22-as-subsidy-cuts-stall-projects.html">Bloomberg New Energy Finance here</a>.</p>
<p>The consequences for many companies and their employees of course will be calamitous to say the least. So many employees had been given the false promise of green jobs. Now, as governments are realizing that green energies are enormously expensive, and man-made climate change is over-hyped, subsidies are being slashed.</p>
<p>On their own, renewable energies are unable to compete and investors are turning their backs.</p>
<p><strong>Green investment plummets 96% in Spain</strong></p>
<p>Ironically, the hardest hit country was Spain, writes <em><a href="http://www.gstriatum.com/solarenergy/2013/04/clean-energy-investment-in-spain-falls-by-96/">gstriatum.com</a></em>. In the first quarter of 2013 Spain saw almost all of its investment in renewable energies evaporate, plummeting a mind-numbing 96%. President Obama once touted Spain as a shining example of green economy success, see <a href="http://www.cbn.com/cbnnews/finance/2011/november/spains-green-disaster-a-lesson-for-america/">here</a> and <a href="http://www.ntu.org/governmentbytes/president-obama-is-right-we.html">here</a><em>. </em>Clearly Obama’s energy advisers had no clue about the complete lack of viability of renewable energies and have left the President standing embarrassed.</p>
<div>France and Italy have also been hard hit.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Michael Liebreich, Chief of Bloomberg New Energy: “For investment in clean energy to play its role in stemming the growth in world emissions, we would need to see investment levels at least double by 2020, rather than fall.”</div>
<p>What Liebreich really means here is: <em>If countries cannot even afford the current level, then doubling the investment is completely out of the question</em>. Expect green energy to die on the vine. The boom is over.</p>
<p>Bloomberg blames the collapsing investment on the uncertain political conditions in key markets like USA and Germany. Clearly the two countries are thinking twice about following Spain’s footsteps.</p>
<p><a href="http://notrickszone.com/2013/04/16/renewable-energy-investment-in-obamas-once-ballyhooed-spain-evaporates-plummeting-96/">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/renewable-energy-investment-obamas-ballyhooed-spain-evaporates-plummeting-96/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back To Black: Green Energy On The Back Foot As Europe Returns To Coal</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/black-green-energy-foot-europe-returns-coal/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/black-green-energy-foot-europe-returns-coal/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 17:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=12004</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been a bad week for efforts to develop green energy around the world. A new report from the International Energy Agency (IEA) says that progress towards carbon-free energy production has basically stalled while Europe has seen a return to coal in the last couple of years. Coal-fired electricity generation has seen a resurgence in Europe over the past [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>It&#8217;s been a bad week for efforts to develop green energy around the world. A new <a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.iea.org/publications/TCEP_web.pdf">report</a> from the International Energy Agency (IEA) says that progress towards carbon-free energy production has basically stalled while Europe has seen a return to coal in the last couple of years.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="coal station" src="http://news.bbcimg.co.uk/media/images/67061000/jpg/_67061125_114569998.jpg" width="499" height="281" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #888888;">Coal-fired electricity generation has seen a resurgence in Europe over the past two years</span></p>
<p>&#8220;Despite much talk by world leaders,&#8221; said IEA executive director, Maria van der Hoeven, &#8220;and despite a boom in renewable energy over the last decade, the average unit of energy produced today is basically as dirty as it was 20 years ago.&#8221;</p>
<p>The IEA uses a complex calculation called the carbon intensity index to show how much CO2 is emitted to provide a given unit of energy.</p>
<p>The index stood at 2.39 tonnes of CO2 per tonne of oil in 1990. By 2010, it has shrunk fractionally to 2.37 tonnes.</p>
<p><strong>Back to black</strong></p>
<p>The major reason for such a small reduction of that period, according to the IEA, was the <a href="http://e360.yale.edu/feature/future_of_coal_will_boom_go_bust_as_climate_concerns_increase/2639/">resurgence</a> of coal. And it continues to grow. Globally, coal-fired electricity generation rose by an estimated 6% from 2010 to 2012 , faster than non-fossil energy.</p>
<p>The major growth in coal came from developing economies, with China accounting for 46% of global coal demand in 2011.</p>
<p>But it&#8217;s not just them.</p>
<p>Europe, the region that likes to think of itself as perhaps the greenest in the world, has also seen a return to coal in the last couple of years. While the US has <a href="http://www.economist.com/news/special-report/21573279-shale-gas-and-oil-bonanza-transforming-americas-energy-outlook-and-boosting-its">turned</a> to shale gas, Europeans have once again embraced the black stuff, as the <a href="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d41c2e8a-6c8d-11e2-953f-00144feab49a.html#axzz2QijIntgg">cost</a> of coal has plummeted.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-22183232">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/black-green-energy-foot-europe-returns-coal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>West Antarctic Change Indistinguishable From Natural Variability</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/west-antarctic-change-indistinguishable-natural-variability/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/west-antarctic-change-indistinguishable-natural-variability/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 15:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=12001</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The truth is that science has only been studying climate change in the Antarctic for a short period of time. All conscientious scientists know that we do not posses enough good data spanning a long enough time period to establish significant long-term trends. For some reason a lot of people have become fixated on Antarctic [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify"><strong>The truth is that science has only been studying climate change in the Antarctic for a short period of time. All conscientious scientists know that we do not posses enough good data spanning a long enough time period to establish significant long-term trends.</strong></p>
<p align="justify">For some reason a lot of people have become fixated on Antarctic ice—is it waxing or waning, accumulating or melting. Climate alarmists have striven mightily to show that ice at the poles in on the decline, melting in the face of rising global temperatures. Antarctica, with the largest store of glacial ice on the planet, is the primary focus of attention. If Antarctica’s ice sheets were to melt it would be a calamity for mankind. Unfortunately, Earth&#8217;s climate system contains many cyclic trends, operating on decadal and longer periods of time. In the past, what some claim are clear trends have turned out to be only short term in nature. A new report, just published online, concludes that it is unclear if changes in atmospheric circulation over West Antarctica during the past few decades are part of a longer-term trend. In fact, ice cores reveal a significant increase in the oxygen isotopes from precipitation over the past 50 years, but the anomaly cannot be distinguished from natural climate variability.</p>
<p align="justify">The argument about melting polar ice rages on the pages of scientific journals and the evening TV news. People are fascinated by glaciers, those huge masses of frozen H<small><sub>2</sub></small>O that only 20,000 years ago covered much of the Northern Hemisphere. Scientists have recently observed melting in the West Antarctic Ice Sheet (WAIS) but a thickening of ice elsewhere on the southern most continent. The important question is not if there is melting in some areas or buildup in others, but what the net change in ice mass is overall. A paper published online in <i>Nature Geoscience</i> uses water-isotope (δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O) data to gauge precipitation over Antarctica. We start with the paper&#8217;s abstract:</p>
<blockquote>
<p align="justify">Changes in atmospheric circulation over the past five decades have enhanced the wind-driven inflow of warm ocean water onto the Antarctic continental shelf, where it melts ice shelves from below. Atmospheric circulation changes have also caused rapid warming over the West Antarctic Ice Sheet, and contributed to declining sea-ice cover in the adjacent Amundsen–Bellingshausen seas. It is unknown whether these changes are part of a longer-term trend. Here, we use water-isotope (δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O) data from an array of ice-core records to place recent West Antarctic climate changes in the context of the past two millennia. We find that the δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O of West Antarctic precipitation has increased significantly in the past 50 years, in parallel with the trend in temperature, and was probably more elevated during the 1990s than at any other time during the past 200 years. However, δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O anomalies comparable to those of recent decades occur about 1% of the time over the past 2,000 years. General circulation model simulations suggest that recent trends in δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O and climate in West Antarctica cannot be distinguished from decadal variability that originates in the tropics. We conclude that the uncertain trajectory of tropical climate variability represents a significant source of uncertainty in projections of West Antarctic climate and ice-sheet change.</p>
</blockquote>
<p align="justify">Occasionally an important scientific result is an inconclusive one. That is the case here. In “<a href="http://www.nature.com/ngeo/journal/vaop/ncurrent/full/ngeo1778.html">Recent climate and ice-sheet changes in West Antarctica compared with the past 2,000 years</a>,” a large team of investigators, led by Eric J. Steig, use records of the oxygen isotopic composition of precipitation (denoted δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O) from ice cores to assess the significance of recent West Antarctic climate trends, and attempt to place observed glaciological changes in a longer-term context. “Unlike temperature or other conventional climate variables, δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O is relatively well sampled in West Antarctica and thus provides the best available data for this purpose.” they claim.</p>
<p align="justify">When some global warming fan boy authoritatively claims that the melting of polar ice is an established long-term trend he is speaking nonsense. The truth is that science has only been studying climate change in the Antarctic for a short period of time. All conscientious scientists know that we do not posses enough good data spanning a long enough time period to establish significant long-term trends. Our ignorance was part of the motivation for Steig <i>et al.&#8217;s</i> investigation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p align="justify">It is unknown whether the climate and glaciological changes that have occurred in West Antarctica in recent decades are part of a longer-term trend associated with anthropogenic climate forcing. This question cannot be evaluated with direct observations. West Antarctic temperature and pressure observations begin only in 1957, and reliable satellite observations of Antarctic sea ice date to 1979. Comprehensive observations of glacier dynamics in the most rapidly changing areas were initiated in the 1990s. Borehole temperature data from the WAIS, although confirming the recent rapid rise in temperature, do not resolve decadal-scale variability in the past.</p>
</blockquote>
<p align="justify">In an attempt to discover what has remained hidden, these scientists made another study, with a different methodology. Using isotopes of oxygen as a proxy, from samples extracted from ice cores, they built a history for the past 2,000 years. Naturally, they have included the output from a computer climate model—no climate paper is complete without some model results. What they found is captured in the figure below.</p>
<p><center><a title="click for larger image" href="http://theresilientearth.com/files/images-2013/antarctic_18o_2000-ngeo2013.jpg" rel="lightbox[][Grey shading shows 2 s.d. about the decadal mean, based on the upper 100 years of the multi-core δ18O composite, providing an estimate of the 95% confidence range. The dashed line shows the 97.5 percentile value relative to the average linear trend. Source Steig et al./NatGeo.]"><img alt="" src="http://theresilientearth.com/files/images-2013/antarctic_18o_2000-ngeo2013-500.jpg" /></a><br />
<small><i>Decade-average δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O from the WAIS Divide ice core for the past 2,000 years.</i></small></center></p>
<p align="justify">The grey shading shows 2 s.d. about the decadal mean, based on the upper 100 years of the multi-core δ18O composite, providing an estimate of the 95% confidence range. The dashed line shows the 97.5 percentile value relative to the average linear trend. The frequent excursions above the line are easily visible. Below is a comparison of results for the years 1880–2009.</p>
<p><center><a title="click for larger image" href="http://theresilientearth.com/files/images-2013/antarctic_18o-ngeo2013.jpg" rel="lightbox[][a, Difference in mean simulated decadal-mean δ18O in Antarctic precipitation between 1991 and 2000 and the three preceding decades. b, Model range (2 s.d., grey shading) of simulated annual mean δ18O in precipitation averaged over West Antarctica compared with observed δ18O anomalies (black line). In both a and b, the model simulations are from 10-member ensembles of ECHAM simulations forced by global tropical SST with a slab ocean in the extratropics. c, SST anomalies averaged over the central tropical Pacific Niño region (thin solid line) and over the entire tropics (thick line), 1880–2009. Source Steig et al./NatGeo.]"><img alt="" src="http://theresilientearth.com/files/images-2013/antarctic_18o-ngeo2013-500.jpg" /></a><br />
<small><i>Modeled versus observed West Antarctic δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O and tropical SSTs.</i></small></center></p>
<p align="justify">In the illustration above: <b>a,</b> Difference in mean simulated decadal-mean δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O in Antarctic precipitation between 1991 and 2000 and the three preceding decades; <b>b,</b>Model range (2 s.d., grey shading) of simulated annual mean δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O in precipitation averaged over West Antarctica compared with observed δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O anomalies (black line). In both a and b, the model simulations are from 10-member ensembles of ECHAM simulations forced by global tropical SST with a slab ocean in the extratropics; <b>c,</b> Sea surface temperature (SST) anomalies averaged over the central tropical Pacific Niño region (thin solid line) and over the entire tropics (thick line).</p>
<p align="justify">The bottom line here is that Steig <i>et al.</i> found 50 year δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O trends as large as today&#8217;s appearing ~2% of the time over the past 2,000 years. “Hence, the anomalous δ<small><sup>18</sup></small>O values of recent decades in West Antarctica do not seem to be unprecedented, but are near the upper limit of the range of natural variability,” they conclude. A similar conclusion was reached for the northern Antarctic Peninsula. The speculative cause of the variation was identified as “variability originating in the tropical Pacific.”</p>
<p align="justify">What about all that ice mass loss from Antarctica we keep hearing about? “Projections of the contribution of the WAIS to future sea-level rise that are based on present rates of ice-sheet mass loss should be treated with caution,” Steig <i>et al.</i>warn. Science speak for “that ice loss stuff is not proven.” In other words, there is nothing strange or scary here. As I have stressed before, the climate has warmed in recent years but it is neither unusual nor unprecedented. Dangerous climate change is only in the minds of researchers with no proper sense of history or the system they study.</p>
<p>Be safe, enjoy the interglacial and stay skeptical.</p>
<p><a href="http://theresilientearth.com/?q=content/west-antarctic-change-indistinguishable-natural-variability">The Resilient Earth, 17 April 2013</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/west-antarctic-change-indistinguishable-natural-variability/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Margaret Thatcher: &#8216;Global Warming Provides A Marvelous Excuse For Global Socialism&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/margaret-thatcher-global-warming-marvelous-excuse-global-socialism/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/margaret-thatcher-global-warming-marvelous-excuse-global-socialism/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 13:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Climate Record]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11998</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In honor of Margaret Thatcher’s memory, favorite quotes from the Iron Lady have popped up everywhere. This one came across my Facebook newsfeed: “Global warming ‘provides a marvelous excuse for worldwide, supra-national socialism.’” The hundreds of comments the quote received covered sentiments ranging from hostility to adoration. A couple accused Thatcher of launching the entire global warming hoax to end [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In honor of <a title="Margaret Thatcher: Death of a Political Colossus" href="http://www.energytribune.com/75643/margaret-thatcher-death-of-a-political-colossus">Margaret Thatcher’s memory</a>, favorite quotes from the Iron Lady have popped up everywhere. <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10151599023825281&amp;set=a.10150141139700281.328977.140379955280&amp;type=1&amp;theater" target="_blank">This one</a> came across my Facebook newsfeed: “Global warming ‘provides a marvelous excuse for worldwide, supra-national socialism.’”</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Margaret Thatcher: Global Warming Provides a Marvelous Excuse for Global Socialism" src="http://cdn.energytribune.com/wp-content/themes/goodnews4/framework/scripts/timthumb.php?src=/wp-content/uploads/ET_041813Noon.jpg&amp;h=340&amp;w=615&amp;zc=1" width="492" height="272" /></p>
<p>The hundreds of comments the quote received covered sentiments ranging from hostility to adoration. A couple <a href="http://www.john-daly.com/history.htm" target="_blank">accused Thatcher</a> of launching the entire global warming hoax to end a coal-miners’ strike. Another cited an earlier <a href="http://thinkprogress.org/climate/2013/04/08/1835681/the-iron-ladys-strong-stance-on-climate-change/?mobile=nc" target="_blank">Thatcher quote</a>: “The danger of global warming is as yet unseen, but real enough for us to make changes and sacrifices.” <a href="http://www.cfact.org/" target="_blank">CFACT</a>, the poster of the comment, responded: “Thatcher evolved. Millions have joined her.” [...]</p>
<p><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://heartland.org/richard-courtney" target="_blank">Richard Courtney</a><span style="font-size: 13px;">, a consultant on matters concerning energy and the environment who has served as an expert peer reviewer for the UN’s Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, calls the global warming issue “political.” He </span><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.john-daly.com/history.htm" target="_blank">says</a><span style="font-size: 13px;">: “Each government has its own special interests in global warming but, in all cases, the motives relate to economic policies.”</span></p>
<p>Whatever the motive, Europe has led the way on renewable energy—especially wind and solar. <a href="http://www.economist.com/news/business/21575771-environmental-lunacy-europe-fuel-future" target="_blank">Germany</a>, has garnered a reputation as the country to follow when it comes to green energy. Having passed the renewable energy law in 1991, Germany has poured huge subsidies into wind and solar power. Twenty-two percent of Germany’s power is now generated with renewables that are “guaranteed more-than competitive rates.” Power companies are passing the costs on to consumers in the form of higher rates.</p>
<p>Germany’s record is held up as a shining example. After all, if Germany can get nearly a quarter of its electricity from renewables, why can’t the US do the same? Germany’s record does sound admirable if one doesn’t know the whole story.</p>
<p><a title="Fewer Choices Post-Fukushima?" href="http://www.energytribune.com/7190/fewer-choices-post-fukushima">Post-Fukushima</a>, <a href="http://finance.townhall.com/columnists/maritanoon/2012/04/29/crucifying_oil_and_gas_on_a_cross_made_of_you_and_me/page/full/" target="_blank">Germany announced</a> the closure of eight of its <a title="European Nuclear Industry Caught in Crossfire" href="http://www.energytribune.com/7731/european-nuclear-industry-caught-in-crossfire">17 nuclear power plants</a>, with the remaining 9 to be closed within the next decade. To replace the 17 power plants, it was announced that Germany would build or revamp <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2012/04/23/germany-energy-bdew-idUSF9E7J100V20120423" target="_blank">84 power plants</a>—more than half would be fossil-fuel-powered, including 17 coal-fueled. This winter, energy costs in Germany were so high that its residents were literally <a href="http://finance.townhall.com/columnists/maritanoon/2013/01/27/renewables-fail-the-cost-test-again-n1498697/page/full/" target="_blank">cutting down trees</a> in city parks and stripping the forests in order to heat their homes.</p>
<p>The tree thefts are just one of the bizarre consequences of the EU’s adoption of the climate change narrative. One of the newest revelations, reported by <a href="http://www.economist.com/news/business/21575771-environmental-lunacy-europe-fuel-future" target="_blank">The Economist</a>, is: “By far the largest so-called renewable fuel used in Europe is wood”—which it calls “the fuel of the future.”</p>
<p>The Economist reports that nearly half of Europe’s renewable energy comes from “biomass,” while in some countries—like Poland and Finland—“wood meets more than 80% of renewable energy demand.”</p>
<p>Apparently, wood was included as a renewable that would help cut CO2 emissions—the supposed driver of climate change—because if the wood came from “properly managed forests, then the carbon that billows out of the chimney can be offset by the carbon that is captured and stored in newly planted trees.” As a result of the decision to allow wood to qualify for the “renewable” mandate, its usage has “soared.” In fact, wood has saved <a title="Irony of Ironies: Europe Switches to Coal as US Gas Glut Reduces Emissions" href="http://www.energytribune.com/11431/irony-of-ironies-europe-switches-to-coal-as-us-gas-glut-reduces-emissions">coal-fueled power plants</a> that would have been shut down because the plants can be “adapted to burn a mixture of 90% coal and 10% wood with little new investment”—making it popular with power companies. Unlike expensive <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10200777774876884&amp;set=pb.1538163641.-2207520000.1365897509&amp;type=3&amp;theater" target="_blank">forests of wind turbines</a> that require new, expensive, transmission lines, the coal-fueled power plants are already connected to the grid.</p>
<p>Europe’s energy policy ends up helping the economies of Canada and the US—both of which didn’t jump into “renewables,” as the EU did. Europe doesn’t have enough wood to meet demand, so much of it will come from imports—which has created a booming new business in North America. Gordon Murray, executive director of the Wood Pellet Association of Canada, calls it “an industry invented from nothing.”</p>
<p><a href="http://www.energytribune.com/75990/margaret-thatcher-global-warming-provides-a-marvelous-excuse-for-global-socialism">Full comment</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>see also: <a href="http://www.eureferendum.com/blogview.aspx?blogno=83817">Christopher Booker &#8211; Verba non sap</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/margaret-thatcher-global-warming-marvelous-excuse-global-socialism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Global Warming Slowdown: The View From Space</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/global-warming-slowdown-view-space/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/global-warming-slowdown-view-space/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 10:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Observatory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11995</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Since the slowdown in surface warming over the last 15 years has been a popular topic recently, I thought I would show results for the lower tropospheric temperature (LT) compared to climate models calculated over the same atmospheric layers the satellites sense. Courtesy of John Christy, and based upon data from the KNMI Climate Explorer, below [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Since the slowdown in surface warming over the last 15 years has been a popular topic recently, I thought I would show results for the lower tropospheric temperature (LT) compared to climate models calculated over the same atmospheric layers the satellites sense.</strong></p>
<p>Courtesy of John Christy, and based upon data from the <a href="http://climexp.knmi.nl/start.cgi?id=someone@somewhere">KNMI Climate Explorer</a>, below is a comparison of 44 climate models versus the UAH and RSS satellite observations for global lower tropospheric temperature variations, for the period 1979-2012 from the satellites, and for 1975 – 2025 for the models:<br />
<a href="http://www.drroyspencer.com/wp-content/uploads/CMIP5-global-LT-vs-UAH-and-RSS.png"><img alt="CMIP5-global-LT-vs-UAH-and-RSS" src="http://www.drroyspencer.com/wp-content/uploads/CMIP5-global-LT-vs-UAH-and-RSS.png" width="576" height="432" /></a><br />
Clearly, there is increasing divergence over the years between the satellite observations (UAH, RSS) and the models. The reasons for the disagreement are not obvious, since there are at least a few possibilities:</p>
<p>1) the real climate system is not as sensitive to increasing CO2 as the models are programmed to be (my preferred explanation)</p>
<p>2) the extra surface heating from more CO2 has been diluted more than expected by increased mixing with cooler, deeper ocean waters (Trenberth’s explanation)</p>
<p>3) increased manmade aerosol pollution is causing a cooling influence, partly mitigating the manmade CO2 warming</p>
<p>If I am correct (explanation #1), then we will continue to see little warming into the future. Additional evidence for lower climate sensitivity in the above plot is the observed response to the 1991 Pinatubo eruption: the temporary temperature dip in 1992-93, and subsequent recovery, is weaker in the observations than in the models. This is exactly what would be predicted with lower climate sensitivity.</p>
<p>On the other hand, if Trenberth is correct (explanation #2), then there should be a period of rapid surface warming that resumes at some point, since the climate system must eventually try to achieve radiative energy equilibrium. Of course, exactly when that might be is unknown.</p>
<p>Explanation #3 (anthropogenic aerosol cooling), while theoretically possible, has always seemed like cheating to me since the magnitude of aerosol cooling is so uncertain it can be invoked in any amount desired to explain the observations. Besides, blaming a <em>lack</em> of warming on humans just seems a little bizarre.</p>
<p>The dark line in the above plot is the 44-model average, and it approximately represents what the IPCC uses for its official best estimate of projected warming. Obviously, there is a substantial disconnect between the models and observations for this statistic.</p>
<p>I find it disingenuous for those who claim that, because not ALL of individual the models disagree with the observations, the models are somehow vindicated. What those pundits fail to mention is that the few models which support weaker warming through 2012 are usually those with lower climate sensitivity.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.drroyspencer.com/2013/04/global-warming-slowdown-the-view-from-space/">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/global-warming-slowdown-view-space/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green Scandal: Wind Farms, Subsidies And Tax Avoidance</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-scandal-wind-farms-tax-avoidance/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-scandal-wind-farms-tax-avoidance/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 10:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11991</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It looks as if the Coalition is knowingly depriving the Treasury of enormous tax receipts in order to promote ugly and inefficient wind farms already in receipt of enormous government subsidies. The energy companies are as avaricious, selfish and remote as were the big banks before the crash. Arguably, they are even worse. Without any [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>It looks as if the Coalition is knowingly depriving the Treasury of enormous tax receipts in order to promote ugly and inefficient wind farms already in receipt of enormous government subsidies.</strong></p>
<p>The energy companies are as avaricious, selfish and remote as were the big banks before the crash. Arguably, they are even worse.</p>
<p>Without any apparent restraint from the Government — or are they encouraged? — they have continued to increase their prices during an economic downturn. According to the industry regulator Ofgem, the profits of the big six energy suppliers will reach £100 per household over the next 12 months.</p>
<p>While much of the rest of the country is mired in recession, it’s boom-time for the energy giants. They have increased their profit margins from 3.3 per cent in 2011 to 7 per cent a mere two years later.</p>
<p>During this time of falling incomes, an average dual-fuel domestic bill — for gas and electricity — has risen from £1,095 to £1,352.</p>
<p>Now an even bigger scam emerges. On Tuesday, the Commons Energy and Climate Change Committee learned that the energy giant npower has not paid any UK corporation tax for three years, despite making £766 million in profits during 2009 to 2011. These profits could have generated a tax bill of £200 million for RWE, its German parent company.</p>
<p>The other energy suppliers have generously paid some corporation tax, though in each case — except that of Centrica, which owns British Gas — at significantly below the lowest rate of 20 per cent.</p>
<p>Scottish Power stumped up £102 million in 2012 on profits of £1.2 billion. German-owned E.ON paid £532 million on profits of nearly £5 billion. French-owned EDF paid ‘more than £200 million’ last year on annual profits of £1.7 billion.</p>
<p>How is it that these companies, seemingly perfectly legally, can avoid paying corporation tax at the same levels as other companies? I say ‘other companies’, though there are several foreign-owned multi-nationals, such as Amazon, Google and Starbucks, which also appear to have an aversion to paying corporation tax here.</p>
<p>The answer in the case of the energy giants would seem to be that they have cut a deal with the Government and the Inland Revenue. That, at any rate, was the justification offered to the Commons Select Committee on Tuesday by Paul Massara, chief executive of npower.</p>
<p>He defended his company’s non-payment of corporation tax on the grounds that it had set the cost of building wind farms and other power-generating facilities against its tax liability. He claimed npower has ‘been the biggest investor by miles in the renewable off-shore business’.</p>
<p>So IF this is true, the Coalition is knowingly depriving the Treasury of enormous tax receipts — when there is a desperate need to balance the books — in order to promote ugly and inefficient wind farms already in receipt of enormous government subsidies. [...]</p>
<p>No one disputes that energy costs have risen, but the suppliers almost invariably pass on these costs to the consumer at once — and then add a bit more.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Government allows them to escape corporation tax or invites them to pay it at a much reduced rate. But the poor consumer is charged an extra 10 per cent on his monthly bill in green taxes.</p>
<p>These taxes amount to £112 a year and are projected by the Department of Energy and Climate Change to increase to £286 a year by 2020. We shouldn’t be surprised if they are a lot higher.</p>
<p>In other words, the energy companies are making hay while the extra burden falls on the poor consumer. The suppliers either don’t pay tax or pay as little of it as possible, while we are expected to contribute to their increased profits and subsidise their uneconomic investment. It is insane.</p>
<p>And I haven’t even mentioned the other insanity — of closing down perfectly serviceable coal-fired power stations as a result of absurd European Union diktats on climate change. It is possible that we may not be left with enough capacity to stop the lights going out in the next few years.</p>
<p>Nor has this Government or its predecessor shown any urgency in adopting a plan to replace our ageing nuclear power stations. It finds itself with a single remaining potential partner in French government-controlled EDF, with which it may well be unable to strike a satisfactory deal. [...]</p>
<p>A further problem has been a Department of Energy and Climate Change (led first by one Lib Dem, Chris Huhne, and now another, Ed Davey) obsessed with renewable energy, despite its high cost and very marginal usefulness, and happy to pile extra green taxes on already hard-pressed consumers.</p>
<p>I wonder whether David Cameron fully grasps the growing resentment of people who watch the energy companies lining their pockets while those consumers have to pay more and more. All of us know that our ever-growing bills reflect far more than the rising costs of energy.</p>
<p>If Labour were not itself even more blindly in love with renewable energy, and more than a little responsible for our existing predicament, it might have the gumption to mount a compelling case against the Coalition over its disastrous policies.</p>
<p>But I don’t think Mr Cameron should feel too relaxed. The energy giants are every bit as bad as the banks. And the truth is that this Government is in cahoots with them.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2310693/Its-insane-fleeced-energy-giants-AND-help-avoid-tax.html">Full comment</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/green-scandal-wind-farms-tax-avoidance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cap And Trade Collapses</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/cap-trade-collapses/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/cap-trade-collapses/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 08:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11988</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of the great policy bubbles of our times has been cap and trade for carbon emissions, and on Tuesday it may have popped for good. The European Parliament refused to save the EU&#8217;s failing program, which is the true-believer equivalent of the pope renouncing celibacy. The Parliament in Strasbourg voted 334-315 (with 63 abstentions) [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>One of the great policy bubbles of our times has been cap and trade for carbon emissions, and on Tuesday it may have popped for good. The European Parliament refused to save the EU&#8217;s failing program, which is the true-believer equivalent of the pope renouncing celibacy.</strong></p>
<p>The Parliament in Strasbourg voted 334-315 (with 63 abstentions) against propping up the price of carbon credits in the EU Emissions Trading System. The failed proposal would have delayed the scheduled sale of 900 million ETS permits over the next seven years, thereby suppressing supply. After carbon traders realized they weren&#8217;t getting more artificial scarcity, they drove the price of emissions permits down by 40% at one point on Tuesday.</p>
<p>EU carbon permit prices have collapsed as the Continent&#8217;s economic crisis curbs energy demand. Utilities and industrial firms have less need to emit CO2 above their statutory limits. Total emissions in the EU fell by nearly 10% between 2007-2011, according the most recent data. The low price of carbon allowances is good for consumers who don&#8217;t have to absorb the extra regulatory cost in what they pay for energy.</p>
<p>Anticarbon crusaders never give up, however, so they wanted the Parliament to intervene to prop up permit prices. They want higher-than-market prices for fossil fuels because they know that is only way they can force the production of renewable energy that is otherwise uncompetitive. The Parliament majority rightly judged that raising energy prices for companies and households is ludicrous when Europe is barely growing as it is.</p>
<p>This failed political intervention also gives the lie to the claim that cap and trade is a &#8220;market solution&#8221; to climate change. Proponents only like the market in permits when it keeps carbon emissions prices high. Cap and trade is an attempt to use brute political force to limit the supply of carbon energy.</p>
<p>All of which vindicates the Bush Administration and others who opposed cap and trade in the Kyoto Protocol. Aided by Al Gore, Europe tried to turn cap and trade into a global policy. The hot air started to go out of Kyoto after its early backers refused to implement job-killing legislation to meet emissions targets. It lost further support when it became clear that financial firms were gaming the system.</p>
<p>With the U.S. shale fracking revolution, it&#8217;s now clear that the fastest way to reduce greenhouse gases is to let private drillers expand natural gas production. When even Europe recognizes the folly of artificially raising energy prices, the anticarbon obsessives have lost in their own climate-change temple.</p>
<p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887324030704578426520736614486.html">The Wall Street Journal, 19 April 2013</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/cap-trade-collapses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>FT: Europe Shifting Away From Climate Agenda</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/ft-europe-shifting-climate-agenda/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/ft-europe-shifting-climate-agenda/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 23:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11985</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The EU Parliament’s vote is only the latest evidence of how a crisis-hit continent’s appetite for climate change policies appears to be fading fast. Not long after the European parliament cast doubt on the future of the EU’s key policy to confront global warming, José Manuel Barroso, the European Commission president, huddled with his climate [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The EU Parliament’s vote is only the latest evidence of how a crisis-hit continent’s appetite for climate change policies appears to be fading fast.</strong></p>
<p>Not long after the European parliament cast doubt on the future of the EU’s key policy to confront global warming, José Manuel Barroso, the European Commission president, huddled with his climate commissioner, Connie Hedegaard, in the VIP lounge at Strasbourg airport.</p>
<p>Mr Barroso, according to people present, reassured Ms Hedegaard that he remained absolutely committed to tackling climate change – in spite of MEPs’ rejection of her plan to prop up <a href="http://www.ft.com/intl/cms/s/0/782223e0-a6b3-11e2-95b1-00144feabdc0.html" target="_blank">the EU’s troubled carbon market</a>.</p>
<div>But beyond the confines of that room, Tuesday’s vote has provoked much soul searching about the bloc’s devotion to an issue that once topped its agenda and shaped its self-image.</div>
<p>Four years ago, in the run-up to the international climate conference in Copenhagen, Mr Barroso and other EU leaders pledged publicly and repeatedly to lead the world in the fight against global warming. They touted <a href="http://www.ft.com/intl/cms/s/0/135e1172-5636-11e1-8dfa-00144feabdc0.html" target="_blank">the EU emissions trading scheme </a>as the hub of what would one day be a global carbon market.</p>
<p>Their embrace of the climate issue cast a halo over the European project as a benign and collaborative force for good in the world. “It was an integral part of the brand,” said Tom Brookes, director of the European Climate Foundation.</p>
<p>These days, it is accepted – even by climate warriors like Mr Brookes – that global warming has been consigned to a seat in the waiting room while the EU tends to a <a href="http://www.ft.com/intl/indepth/euro-in-crisis" target="_blank">chronic economic crisis </a>that has threatened the single currency and increased unemployment. [...]</p>
<p>Tuesday’s vote is only the latest evidence of how a crisis-hit continent’s appetite for climate change policies appears to have faded in recent months.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/71c6aa1a-a77c-11e2-bfcd-00144feabdc0.html">Full comment</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/ft-europe-shifting-climate-agenda/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
