<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF)</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thegwpf.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thegwpf.org</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 09:13:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Britain Tops Fuel Poverty League Table</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/britain-tops-fuel-poverty-league-table/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/britain-tops-fuel-poverty-league-table/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 09:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11537</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In a shaming indictment of the failure of the Government and energy suppliers to tackle the rising tide of fuel poverty hitting the UK&#8217;s vulnerable people, Britain this week came bottom of a league table for western Europe. According to figures from the Association for the Conservation for Energy and the Energy Bill Revolution campaign, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>In a shaming indictment of the failure of the Government and energy suppliers to tackle the rising tide of fuel poverty hitting the UK&#8217;s vulnerable people, Britain this week came bottom of a league table for western Europe.</strong></p>
<p>According to figures from the Association for the Conservation for Energy and the Energy Bill Revolution campaign, British households are hit by the woeful levels of insulation in our homes.</p>
<p>Although most other European countries actually face higher energy prices than those of the UK, better-quality home insulation means our European neighbours pay less to heat their homes.</p>
<p>Some five million UK households, or 19.2 per cent of the total, are now in fuel poverty, according to the report.</p>
<p>A household is considered to be in fuel poverty if more than 10 per cent of its total income is spent on adequate heating.</p>
<p>That total puts the UK squarely at the bottom of the league table, a long way behind table-toppers the Netherlands, which has a reported 8.1 per cent in fuel poverty. Belgium also has less than 10 per cent of households in fuel poverty while Sweden and Austria both have less than 12 per cent.</p>
<p>The closest rival to the UK&#8217;s woeful record is France, with 16.2 per cent of households in fuel poverty.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/money/spend-save/britain-tops-the-fuel-poverty-league-table-8554723.html">Full story</p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/britain-tops-fuel-poverty-league-table/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Donna Laframboise: Reasons To Feel Hopeful</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/donna-laframboise-reasons-feel-hopeful/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/donna-laframboise-reasons-feel-hopeful/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 08:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11531</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This Easter weekend I see promising signs that we may be on our way to becoming more sophisticated in how we think about environmental issues. Below is a bouquet of reasons from the UK to feel hopeful. It’s springtime. Here’s hoping that our eyes are opening along with the blossoms. In the part of the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>This Easter weekend I see promising signs that we may be on our way to becoming more sophisticated in how we think about environmental issues. Below is a bouquet of reasons from the UK to feel hopeful.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="TripodGirl_tulip_dreams3_500" src="http://nofrakkingconsensus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tripodgirl_tulip_dreams3_500.jpg?w=455&amp;h=341" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>It’s springtime. Here’s hoping that our eyes are opening along with the blossoms.</em></p>
<p>In the part of the world in which I live, Easter is associated with springtime. Green shoots emerging from the ground. Bulbs, vines, and trees awakening from dormancy. This is a moment of renewal, of hope, an opportunity to set off in a new direction.</p>
<p>This Easter weekend I see promising signs that we may be on our way to becoming more sophisticated in how we think about environmental issues. Below, therefore, is a bouquet of reasons from the UK to feel hopeful:</p>
<p>Over at <em>Spiked,</em> Rob Lyons has a lengthy and <a href="http://www.spiked-online.com/site/reviewofbooks_article/13491/" target="_blank">informative review</a> of a book titled <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Age-Global-Warming-Rupert-Darwall/dp/0704372991/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1364573897&amp;sr=8-1" target="_blank"><em>The Age of Global Warming: A History</em></a>. Recently released in the UK, it isn’t yet available in North America, but its focus on the history of the ideas that inform today’s green movement suggests it will make an important contribution to our understanding.</p>
<p>Lyons’ review (<a href="http://nofrakkingconsensus.com/2013/03/29/new-beginnings/www.spiked-online.com/site/reviewofbooks_article/13491/" target="_blank">read the whole thing here</a>) emphasizes how firmly the green movement is now associated with affluent elites. In his words:</p>
<blockquote><p>Western politicians and royalty, the management of giant corporations like BP and the offspring of the rich and powerful, like Zac Goldsmith and Robert F Kennedy Jr, have declared the importance of tackling climate change again and again.</p></blockquote>
<p>That many of those people lack a fundamental awareness of – or sympathy for – the concerns of ordinary folk struggling to make ends meet is glaringly obvious if one examines how the climate policies they’ve promoted are playing out in the real world.</p>
<p>Fraser Nelson does a brilliant job of illustrating this in a column titled <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/health/elderhealth/9959856/Its-the-cold-not-global-warming-that-we-should-be-worried-about.html" target="_blank"><em>It’s the cold, not global warming, that we should be worried about</em></a>.</p>
<p>All that precious time and money being blown on preparing for a speculative hot future entirely ignores the fact that tens of thousands of people are dying prematurely from the cold in the UK here and now. How can it possibly be the case that today’s tragedies are of less concern than hypothetical deaths sometime in the future? As Nelson says:</p>
<blockquote><p>The reaction to the 2003 heatwave was extraordinary. It was blamed for 2,000 deaths, and taken as a warning that Britain was horribly unprepared for the coming era of snowless winters and barbecue summers. The government’s chief scientific officer, Sir David King, later declared that climate change was “more serious even than the threat of terrorism” in terms of the number of lives that could be lost. <strong>Such language is never used about the cold, which kills at least 10 times as many people every winter</strong>.</p>
<p>Since Sir David’s exhortations, some <strong>250,000 Brits have died from the cold, and 10,000 from the heat</strong>. It is horribly clear that we have been focusing on the wrong enemy. Instead of making sure energy was affordable, ministers have been trying to make it more expensive, with carbon price floors and emissions trading schemes. Fuel prices have doubled over seven years, forcing millions to choose between heat and food… [bold added, <a href="http://www.webcitation.org/6FU8UbPUJ" target="_blank">backed up here</a>]</p></blockquote>
<p>We may wonder what spell has been cast over our communities that we’ve failed to notice the obvious. But instead, let us celebrate the fact that words like this are finally being spoken:</p>
<blockquote><p>This is the supposed threat facing us: children would be less likely to have snow to play in at Christmas, but more likely to have grandparents to visit over Easter. Not a bad trade-off.</p></blockquote>
<p>Read Nelson’s entire <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/health/elderhealth/9959856/Its-the-cold-not-global-warming-that-we-should-be-worried-about.html" target="_blank"><em>tour de force</em> here</a>.</p>
<p>Andrew Orlowski over at the <em>Register</em> also has an eye-opening piece titled <a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2013/03/25/uk_energy_crisis_illustrated/" target="_blank"><em>The UK Energy Crisis in 3 simple awareness-raising pictures</em></a>. Its first paragraph includes the following:</p>
<blockquote><p>The UK is running out of gas. Very rapidly indeed. So much so, that shortly after Easter cuts and rationing may be introduced, with industrial users and hospitals getting preferential treatment.</p></blockquote>
<p>Green policies almost always sound wonderful. But they frequently result in dire, unintended consequences. That’s a hard lesson to learn – and an expensive one.</p>
<p>Perhaps our long, dark winter is coming to end and sufficient numbers of eyes are beginning to open.</p>
<p><a href="http://nofrakkingconsensus.com/2013/03/29/new-beginnings/"><span style="color: #0000ff;">No Frakking Consensus, 29 March 2013</span></p>
<p></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/donna-laframboise-reasons-feel-hopeful/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>David Henderson: Plus Ca Change&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/david-henderson-ca-change/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/david-henderson-ca-change/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion: Pros & Cons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11523</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[THEN: In 1985 I gave the BBC Reith Lectures, and the text formed the basis for a book published by Blackwell in 1986 entitled Innocence and Design: The Influence of Economic ideas on Policy’. In the book, I argued that there were ‘extensive areas of policy in which the beliefs and perceptions that influence governments and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;" align="center"><b>THEN: </b><i>In 1985 I gave <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p00gq1cr">the BBC Reith Lectures</a>, and the text formed the basis for a book published by Blackwell in 1986 entitled </i><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Innocence-Design-Influence-Economic-Policy/dp/0631147969">Innocence and Design: The Influence of Economic ideas on Policy</a>’. <i>In the book, I argued that there were ‘extensive areas of policy in which the beliefs and perceptions that influence governments and public opinion alike are unrelated to the characteristic ways of thinking of professional economists, and have changed little down the centuries. These are the ideas of </i>do-it-yourself economics’ [DIYE].</p>
<p><i>Chapter 3 of the book features energy policies in particular. It is headed ‘Needs, Centralism and Autarchy’. Here are a few short excerpts from it.</i></p>
<p>‘<i>Unreflecting centralism</i> [which I identified as one of the characteristic elements of DIYE] has two mutually supporting elements. One is the disposition to assume that outcomes have to be planned and decided by governments. Second is the tendency to think of governments and states as the principal, or even the only, actors on the economic scene, and to attribute to them roles and functions which are not necessarily theirs’ (p. 36).</p>
<p>‘A few years ago &#8230; a former senior British government official, Peter Vinter, observed that “As a nation we have not yet succeeded in setting up an effective nuclear reactor construction company”. I think his point is a fair one, and perhaps he would say the same today.  But why should it be the collective responsibility of “we as a nation” to establish a nuclear reactor construction company? Why should such a company, if indeed there is a place for it, not emerge from the impersonal competitive selection process of markets&#8230;?’ (p.38)</p>
<p>‘One reason for centralism, which applies in energy policy and a number of other fields, is the uncritical acceptance of essentialist ideas. In the case of energy, each country is perceived as having needs which must be met, and each national government as having an inescapable responsibility to anticipate and provide for those needs. In the more rustic treatments of these questions, reference is made to a possible ‘energy gap’ which the government has to ensure is bridged. Even in more sophisticated official presentations, governments usually appear as indispensable providers. Here again is David Howell, from his period as Secretary of State for Energy:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>“The Government, in my view, must ensure that we have enough energy in the future to heat our homes and power our industries. Failure to achieve this could mean lower living standards for us all and a very severe constraint on our society”.</em></p>
<p>So essentialism leads naturally to unreflecting centralism­. Also here in its place on the DIYE stage is Micawber’s dichotomy: either we-as-a-nation have enough energy, or we do not. But who is to say how much is enough?  You will search in vain in official White Papers and statistical publications for figures showing national energy needs, for the simple reason that the concept can be neither defined nor measured. If you ask someone who uses the term what are the current or prospective energy needs of the United Kingdom, the only answer you will get is a figure which relates to demand – in other words, to actual or prospective purchases of energy products. Demand is identified with needs, for no better reason than that energy, like food, is cast in the [DIYE] soap opera script as essential’. (pp. 40-41)</p>
<p><b>NOW</b></p>
<p>* Here is the Department of Energy and Climate Change, as of September 2012. The opening sentence of a covering note for an official animation entitled ‘The Energy Challenge’ reads:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">“As a nation we need to decide how the UK is going to power itself”</p>
<p>* On 27 March, 2013, in launching the government’s <i>Nuclear Industry Strategy </i>report, Vince Cable, Secretary of State for Business, Innovation and Skills, said that</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">“nuclear power has the potential to play an increasing role in meeting the UK’s future energy needs”. <i> </i></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><b>THEN</b></p>
<p>In May 1976 I gave an inaugural lecture at University College London. I offered a mid-term cost-benefit analysis of what I termed ‘two British errors’: one was the Concorde programme, and the other the UK Second Nuclear Power programme.  In a subsequent radio talk, I suggested that these might be seen as ‘two of the three worst civil investment projects in the history of mankind’. Since then I have learned of other ventures which could be viewed as equally ill-starred; and one of these is the British fast (nuclear) reactor programme. The programme was finally brought to an end after nearly half a century of fruitless public expenditure, leaving behind it only further heavy and still-continuing commitments of expenditure for reactor decommissioning and site cleaning.</p>
<p>In the <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio4/features/the-reith-lectures/transcripts/1980/#y1985">Reith Lectures, I said:</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>‘</em>The history of British nuclear power programmes over the past 30 years [from 1955] provides a depressing example of unreflecting centralism in action – stoutly reinforced, I might add, by other forms of DIYE’ (p. 39)</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">From today’s perspective, 30 years appears as too short a period to quote.</p>
<p>Over the decades, successive nuclear programmes were adopted by both Labour and Conservative governments, and secured broad cross-party support.</p>
<p><b>NOW</b></p>
<p>In view of this history of misguided official ‘strategies’ and costly failures, the following claim came as a surprise. It is made in the opening paragraph of the Ministerial Foreword, signed by Vince Cable and Ed Davey, to the just-published report, <i>Nuclear Industrial Strategy -The UK’s Nuclear Future</i>. (Italics added).</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">‘The UK was the first country successfully to develop, deliver and safely operate nuclear power stations, meeting all the scientific, technological and industrial challenges that this involved. <i>We can now look back on nearly sixty years of successful</i> and, above all, safe <i>exploitation of low-carbon nuclear power</i> which has also enhanced our energy security’.</p>
<p>It is to be feared that the officials and ministers who chose and approved this form of words actually believed it to be true.</p>
<p><b>THEN</b></p>
<p>The extent of past failure in British nuclear power programmes largely resulted from the fact that responsibility for those programmes rested with government departments and public corporations: in particular, what was then the Atomic Energy Authority has a lot to answer for. A continuing feature was the uncritical acceptance, by governments, media and public opinion, of official scientific advice.</p>
<p><b>NOW</b></p>
<p>Privatisation of the electricity supply industry, and stripping the Atomic Energy Authority of virtually all its former functions and powers, have made it impossible for the mistakes of the past to be replicated.  However, current and prospective policies to deal (supposedly) with climate change have created a whole new dimension of state involvement and direction. Old-style unreflecting centralism still holds sway; and once again, it is linked to uncritical treatment of ‘the science’. But these elements are now reflected, not in ambitious investments by public corporations, but in an array of costly interventionist measures designed to shape and direct the conduct of households and private businesses.</p>
<p>The measures in question, and what is thought to be their rationale, have been endorsed by past Conservative and Labour governments, as well as the present Coalition. They have secured continuing cross-party support.</p>
<p><b>David Henderson</b></p>
<p>30 March, 2013</p>
<p><strong>Professor David Henderson</strong><em> was formerly Head of the Economics and Statistics Department of the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) in Paris. He is the chairman of the GWPF&#8217;s Academic Advisory Council.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/david-henderson-ca-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Global Warming Hiatus Has Climate Scientists Puzzled</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/global-warming-hiatus-climate-scientists-puzzled/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/global-warming-hiatus-climate-scientists-puzzled/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Observatory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11519</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[DEBATE about the reality of a [16 year] pause in global warming and what it means has made its way from the sceptical fringe to the mainstream. In a lengthy article this week, The Economist magazine said if climate scientists were credit-rating agencies, then climate sensitivity &#8211; the way climate reacts to changes in carbon-dioxide [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>DEBATE about the reality of a [16 year] pause in global warming and what it means has made its way from the sceptical fringe to the mainstream.</strong></p>
<p>In a lengthy article this week, The Economist magazine said if climate scientists were credit-rating agencies, then climate sensitivity &#8211; the way climate reacts to changes in carbon-dioxide levels &#8211; would be on negative watch but not yet downgraded.</p>
<p>Another paper published by leading climate scientist James Hansen, the head of NASA&#8217;s Goddard Institute for Space Studies, says the lower than expected temperature rise between 2000 and the present could be explained by increased emissions from burning coal.</p>
<p>For Hansen the pause is a fact, but it&#8217;s good news that probably won&#8217;t last.</p>
<p>Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change chairman Rajendra Pachauri recently told The Weekend Australian the hiatus would have to last 30 to 40 years &#8220;at least&#8221; to break the long-term warming trend.</p>
<p>But the fact that global surface temperatures have not followed the expected global warming pattern is now widely accepted.</p>
<p>Research by Ed Hawkins of University of Reading shows surface temperatures since 2005 are already at the low end of the range projections derived from 20 climate models and if they remain flat, they will fall outside the models&#8217; range within a few years.</p>
<p>&#8220;The global temperature standstill shows that climate models are diverging from observations,&#8221; says David Whitehouse of the Global Warming Policy Foundation.</p>
<p>&#8220;If we have not passed it already, we are on the threshold of global observations becoming incompatible with the consensus theory of climate change,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>Whitehouse argues that whatever has happened to make temperatures remain constant requires an explanation because the pause in temperature rise has occurred despite a sharp increase in global carbon emissions.</p>
<p>The Economist says the world has added roughly 100 billion tonnes of carbon to the atmosphere between 2000 and 2010, about one-quarter of all the carbon dioxide put there by humans since 1750. This mismatch between rising greenhouse gas emissions and not-rising temperatures is among the biggest puzzles in climate science just now, The Economist article says.</p>
<p>&#8220;But it does not mean global warming is a delusion.&#8221;</p>
<p>The fact is temperatures between 2000 and 2010 are still almost 1C above their level in the first decade of the 20th century.</p>
<p>&#8220;The mismatch might mean that for some unexplained reason there has been a temporary lag between more carbon dioxide and higher temperatures in 2000-2010.</p>
<p>&#8220;Or it might mean that the 1990s, when temperatures were rising fast, was the anomalous period.&#8221;</p>
<p>The magazine explores a range of possible explanations including higher emissions of sulphur dioxide, the little understood impact of clouds and the circulation of heat into the deep ocean.</p>
<p>But it also points to an increasing body of research that suggests it may be that climate is responding to higher concentrations of atmospheric carbon dioxide in ways that had not been properly understood before.</p>
<p>&#8220;This possibility, if true, could have profound significance both for climate science and for environmental and social policy,&#8221; the article says.</p>
<p>There are now a number of studies that predict future temperature rises as a result of man-made carbon dioxide emissions at well below the IPCC best estimate of about 3C over the century.</p>
<p>The upcoming IPCC report is expected to lift the maximum possible temperature increase to 6C.</p>
<p>The Research Council of Norway says in a non-peer-reviewed paper that the best estimate concludes there is a 90 per cent probability that doubling CO2 emissions will increase temperatures by only 1.2C to 2.9C, the most likely figure being 1.9C.</p>
<p>Another study based on the way the climate behaved about 20,000 years ago has given a best guess of 2.3C.</p>
<p>Other forecasts, accepted for publication, have reanalysed work cited by the IPCC but taken account of more recent temperature data and given a figure of between 1C and 3C.</p>
<p>The Economist says understanding which estimate is true is vital to getting the best response.</p>
<p>&#8220;If as conventional wisdom has it, global temperatures could rise by 3C or more in response to a doubling of emissions, then the correct response would be the one to which most of the world pays lip service; rein in the warming and the greenhouse gases causing it,&#8221; the article says.</p>
<p>&#8220;If, however, temperatures are likely to rise by only 2 degrees Celsius in response to a doubling of carbon emissions (and if the likelihood of a 6 degrees Celsius is trivial) the calculation might change,&#8221; it says.</p>
<p>&#8220;Perhaps the world should seek to adjust to (rather than stop) the greenhouse-gas splurge.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is no point buying earthquake insurance if you don&#8217;t live in an earthquake zone.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to The Economist, &#8220;given the hiatus in warming and all the new evidence, a small reduction in estimates of climate sensitivity would seem to be justified.&#8221; On face value, Hansen agrees the slowdown in global temperature rises can be seen as &#8220;good news&#8221;.</p>
<p>But he is not ready to recalculate the Faustian bargain that weighs the future cost to humanity of continued carbon dioxide emissions.</p>
<p>Hansen argues that the impact of human carbon dioxide emissions has been masked by the sharp increase in coal use, primarily in China and India.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/features/twenty-year-hiatus-in-rising-temperatures-has-climate-scientists-puzzled/story-e6frg6z6-1226609140980">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/global-warming-hiatus-climate-scientists-puzzled/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Warm Bias: The Met Office&#8217;s Disastrous Track Record</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/warm-bias-met-offices-disastrous-track-record/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/warm-bias-met-offices-disastrous-track-record/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11515</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Met Office&#8217;s temperature forecasts issued in 12 out of the last 13 years have been too warm.  None of the forecasts issued ended up too cold.  That makes the errors systemic and significant. Met Office 2008 Forecast: Trend of Mild Winters Continues Met Office, 25 September 2008: The Met Office forecast for the coming winter suggests [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The Met Office&#8217;s temperature forecasts issued in <strong>12 out of the last 13 years </strong>have been too warm.  None of the forecasts issued ended up too cold.  That makes the errors systemic and significant.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="http://blogs.telegraph.co.uk/news/files/2011/01/winter_of_discontent_scr.jpg" /></p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #800000;" data-mce-mark="1">Met Office 2008 Forecast:</span> Trend of Mild Winters Continues</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.metoffice.gov.uk/corporate/pressoffice/2008/pr20080925.html">Met Office, 25 September 2008</a>: The Met Office forecast for the coming winter suggests it is, once again, likely to be milder than average. It is also likely that the coming winter will be drier than last year.</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #0000ff;" data-mce-mark="1">Reality Check:</span> Winter of 2008/09 Coldest Winter For A Decade</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.metoffice.gov.uk/climate/uk/2009/winter.html">Met Office, March 2009</a>: Mean temperatures over the UK were 1.1 °C below the 1971-2000 average during December, 0.5 °C below average during January and 0.2 °C above average during February. The UK mean temperature for the winter was 3.2 °C, which is 0.5 °C below average, making it the coldest winter since 1996/97 (also 3.2 °C).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #800000;" data-mce-mark="1">Met Office 2009 Forecast:</span> Trend To Milder Winters To Continue, Snow And Frost Becoming Less Of A Feature</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.metoffice.gov.uk/corporate/pressoffice/2009/pr20090225.html">Met Office, 25 February 2009</a>: Peter Stott, Climate Scientist at the Met Office, said: “Despite the cold winter this year, the trend to milder and wetter winters is expected to continue, with snow and frost becoming less of a feature in the future. <strong><em>“The famously cold winter of 1962/63 is now expected to occur about once every 1,000 years or more, compared with approximately every 100 to 200 years before 1850.”</em></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #0000ff;" data-mce-mark="1">Reality Check:</span> Winter Of 2009/10 Coldest Winter For Over 30 Years</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.metoffice.gov.uk/corporate/pressoffice/2010/pr20100301.html">Met Office, 1 March 2010</a>: Provisional figures from the Met Office show that the UK winter has been the coldest since 1978/79. The mean UK temperature was 1.5 °C, the lowest since 1978/79 when it was 1.2 °C.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="http://wattsupwiththat.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/met_office_forecast_computer-520.jpg?w=334&amp;h=334&amp;h=334" src="http://wattsupwiththat.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/met_office_forecast_computer-520.jpg?w=334&amp;h=334&amp;h=334" /></p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #800000;" data-mce-mark="1">Met Office July 2010:</span> Climate Change Gradually But Steadily Reducing Probability Of Severe Winters In The UK</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.express.co.uk/posts/view/215087">Ross Clark, Daily Express, 3 December 2010</a>: ONE of the first tasks for the team conducting the Department for Transport’s “urgent review” into the inability of our transport system to cope with snow and ice will be to interview the cocky public figure who assured breakfast TV viewers last month that “I am pretty confident we will be OK” at keeping Britain moving this winter. They were uttered by Transport secretary Philip Hammond himself, who just a fortnight later is already being forced to eat humble pie… If you want a laugh I recommend reading the Resilience Of England’s Transport Systems In Winter, an interim report by the DfT published last July. It is shockingly complacent. Rather than look for solutions to snow-induced gridlock the authors seem intent on avoiding the issue. <strong><em>The Met Office assured them “the effect of climate change is to gradually but steadily reduce the probability of severe winters in the UK”.</em></strong></p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #800000;" data-mce-mark="1">Met Office 2010 Forecast:</span> Winter To Be Mild Predicts Met Office</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.express.co.uk/posts/view/208012/Winter-to-be-mild-predicts-Met-Office/Winter-to-be-mild-predicts-Met-OfficeWinter-to-be-mild-predicts-Met-OfficeWinter-to-be-mild-predicts-Met-OfficeWinter-to-be-mild-predicts-Met-OfficeWinter-to-be-mild-predicts-">Daily Express, 28 October 2010</a>: IT’S a prediction that means this may be time to dig out the snow chains and thermal underwear. The Met Office, using data generated by a £33million supercomputer, claims Britain can stop worrying about a big freeze this year because we could be in for a milder winter than in past years… The new figures, which show a 60 per cent to 80 per cent chance of warmer-than-average temperatures this winter, were ridiculed last night by independent forecasters. The latest data comes in the form of a December to February temperature map on the Met Office’s website.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #0000ff;" data-mce-mark="1">Reality Check:</span> December 2010 “Almost Certain” To Be Coldest Since Records Began</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/coldest-december-on-record-puts-brakes-on-start-of-the-big-getaway-2163615.html">The Independent, 18 December 2010</a>: December 2010 is “almost certain” to be the coldest since records began in 1910, according to the Met Office.</p>
<p><strong>Met Office Predicted A Warm Winter. Cheers Guys</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/opinion/columnists/john-walsh/john-walsh-met-office-predicted-a-warm-winter-cheers-guys-1871928.html">John Walsh, The Independent, 19 January 2010</a>: Some climatologists hint that the Office’s problem is political; its computer model of future weather behaviour habitually feeds in government-backed assumptions about climate change that aren’t borne out by the facts. To the Met Office, the weather’s always warmer than it really is, because it’s expecting it to be, because it expects climate change to wreak its stealthy havoc. If it really has had its thumb on the scales for the last decade, I’m afraid it deserves to be shown the door.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>BBC Analysis: A Frozen Britain Turns The Heat Up On The Met Office</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/blogs/paulhudson/2010/01/a-frozen-britain-turns-the-hea.shtml">Paul Hudson, BBC Weather, 9 January 2010: </a>Which begs other, rather important questions. Could the model, seemingly with an inability to predict colder seasons, have developed a warm bias, after such a long period of milder than average years? Experts I have spoken to tell me that this certainly is possible with such computer models. And if this is the case, what are the implications for the Hadley centre’s predictions for future global temperatures? Could they be affected by such a warm bias? If global temperatures were to fall in years to come would the computer model be capable of forecasting this?</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-52CWsZDusEw/UA_xh84qKuI/AAAAAAAAFOo/PHPYxcvaSOw/s1600/Met+Office.png" width="379" height="272" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>A Period Of Humility And Silence Would Be Best For Met Office</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.timesonline.co.uk/tol/comment/columnists/dominic_lawson/article6982310.ece">Dominic Lawson, The Sunday Times, 10 January 2010</a>: A period of humility and even silence would be particularly welcome from the Met Office, our leading institutional advocate of the perils of man-made global warming, which had promised a “barbecue summer” in 2009 and one of the “warmest winters on record”. In fact, the Met still asserts we are in the midst of an unusually warm winter — as one of its staffers sniffily protested in an internet posting to a newspaper last week: “This will be the warmest winter in living memory, the data has already been recorded. For your information, we take the highest 15 readings between November and March and then produce an average. As November was a very seasonally warm month, then all the data will come from those readings.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #800000;" data-mce-mark="1">Met Office 2012 Forecast:</span> Drier than average conditions for April-May-June</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.metoffice.gov.uk/media/pdf/p/i/A3-layout-precip-AMJ.pdf">Met Office 3-month Outlook, 23 March 2012:</a> <em>“The forecast for average UK rainfall slightly favours drier-than-average conditions for April-May-June as a whole, and also slightly favours April being the driest of the 3 months. <strong>With this forecast, the water resources situation in southern, eastern and central England is likely to deteriorate further during the April-May-June period</strong>… This forecast is based on information from observations, several numerical models and expert judgement.”</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #0000ff;" data-mce-mark="1">Reality Check:</span> W<strong>ettest April for 100 years</strong></strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-17897982">April:</a> <strong>2012 had wettest April for 100 years, Met Office says</strong> “It has been the wettest April in the UK for over 100 years, with some areas seeing three times their usual average, figures from the Met Office show. Some 121.8mm of rain has fallen, beating the previous record of 120.3mm which was set in 2000.”</p>
<p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/topics/weather/9352334/June-on-course-to-be-wettest-in-a-century-but-rain-to-clear-for-start-of-Wimbledon.html">June:</a> <strong>June on course to be wettest in a century</strong>: Flooding, storms and persistent showers have blighted the country in recent weeks putting this June in line to become one of the soggiest in 100 years.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/news/4392350/Spring-is-wettest-in-Britain-for-250-years.html">25 June:</a> <strong>Spring is wettest in Britain for 250 years</strong> - England and Wales are on course for the wettest late spring and early summer for 250 years, experts said yesterday. June has just seen its fourth washout weekend and yet more downpours are forecast. Now it is feared combined rainfall for April, May and June will break the record of 13.2in (336mm) set in 1782 and be the highest since records began in 1766.</p>
<p><img alt="Floods force hundreds to leave homes" src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/02257/floods_2257139b.jpg" width="434" height="271" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #800000;" data-mce-mark="1">Met Office 2013 Forecast:</span> Feb-March Above-Average UK Temps More Likely</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.metoffice.gov.uk/media/pdf/c/2/A3-plots-temp-JFM.pdf">Met Office, 20 December 2012</a>: For February and March the range of possible outcomes is also very broad, although above-average UK-mean temperatures become more likely.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong><span style="color: #0000ff;" data-mce-mark="1">Reality Check:</span> Met Office confirms coldest March in more than 50 years</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.thisisbristol.co.uk/Met-Office-confirms-coldest-March-50-years/story-18546390-detail/story.html">Press Association, 29 March 2013:</a> This March is the coldest in the UK since 1962, forecasters have confirmed. After weeks of speculation about whether this miserable March would top the list, the Met Office has announced it is the coldest in 51 years according to provisional statistic.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Image Attachment" src="http://climaterealists.com/attachments/ftp/Daily%20express%20422.jpg" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Paul Hudson: Met Office global forecasts too warm in 11 out of last 12 years</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/blogs/paulhudson/2012/02/met-office-global-forecasts-to.shtml">Paul Hudson, BBC Weather, 10 February 2012: </a>Although this discrepancy is within the stated margin of error, it is the 11th year out of the last 12 when the Met Office global temperature forecast has been too warm.  In all these years, the discrepancy between observed temperatures and the forecast are within the stated margin of error. But all the errors are on the warm side, with none of the forecasts that have been issued in the last 12 years ending up too cold.  And, in my opinion, that makes the error significant.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Martin Rosenbaum: The Met Office and its seasonal problems</strong></h2>
<div><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/blogs/opensecrets/2010/12/met_office_seasonal_forecasts.html">BBC Open Secrets, 23 December 2010</a></div>
<div><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/blogs/opensecrets/2010/12/met_office_seasonal_forecasts.html"><br />
</a>As Britain remains cold and snowy, an interesting little dispute has boiled up between the Global Warming Policy Foundation (GWPF) and the Met Office over the quality of longer-range weather forecasting.</div>
<div>
<div><img alt="Vehicles on snow covered motorway" src="http://www.bbc.co.uk/blogs/opensecrets/snoemotorway304.jpg" width="304" height="171" /></div>
<p>And this is illuminated by documents obtained by the BBC under freedom of information from the Met Office. These shed new light on the problems faced by the Met Office in its public communications and the strategies it has adopted for tackling them.</p>
<p>The Met Office is <a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/uk-news/2086-gwpf-calls-for-independent-inquiry-into-met-offices-winter-advice-.html">under attack</a> from the GWPF, for its &#8220;poor advice&#8221; on the likelihood of a harsh and cold winter.</p>
<p>The GWPF is <a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/uk-news/2088-that-met-office-global-long-range-probability-map.html">drawing attention</a> to a map published on the Met Office website in October which indicated that the UK was likely to experience above-normal temperatures in the ensuing three-month period.</p>
<p>For the GPWF, which is sceptical of the Met Office and other mainstream analysis of global warming, this is evidence of a <a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/science-news/2073-warm-bias-how-the-met-office-mislead-the-british-public.html">Met Office tendency</a> to under-predict cold weather and over-predict mild winters&#8230;..</p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/warm-bias-met-offices-disastrous-track-record/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will Michael Fallon Kill &#8216;Absurd&#8217; Carbon Floor Price?</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/michael-fallon-kill-absurd-carbon-floor-price/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/michael-fallon-kill-absurd-carbon-floor-price/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[UK News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11511</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[David Cameron’s new energy minister has attacked an “absurd” new green tax brought in by the Coalition for wasting people’s money. In a meeting with business leaders, Michael Fallon laid into the Treasury’s Carbon Floor Price, which will start driving up the price of electricity for households and businesses from Monday. Official figures suggest it [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>David Cameron’s new energy minister has attacked an “absurd” new green tax brought in by the Coalition for wasting people’s money.</strong></p>
<p>In a meeting with business leaders, Michael Fallon laid into the Treasury’s Carbon Floor Price, which will start driving up the price of electricity for households and businesses from Monday.</p>
<p>Official figures suggest it will add around £5 to energy bills this year and about £50 a year by 2020.</p>
<p>On top of this, the taxpayer will have to give £150 million in compensation to factories that could be put out of business by the high costs of the levy – the equivalent of £6 per household.</p>
<p>Mr Fallon, a business minister who was yesterday given extra responsibility for energy, suggested this situation was &#8220;absurd&#8221;.</p>
<p>At the Centre for Policy Studies event last month, he said everyone “would have to pay” for the unintended consequences of the tax.</p>
<p>A recording obtained by the Telegraph shows he told businesses: “We’ve inherited this Carbon Floor and I am now to find, thanks to the Treasury, over £150 million to design a compensation scheme for energy-intensive industries precisely to compensate from this arrangement which we’ve inherited from our predecessors.</p>
<p>“This is a fairly absurd waste of your money, this situation we’re now in. Governments intervene in markets they don’t understand and there are consequences and we all have to pay for those consequences.”</p>
<p>The introduction of the Carbon Floor Price was a Conservative policy championed in the party&#8217;s election manifesto, the Coalition agreement and this year&#8217;s mid-term review .</p>
<p>The point of the tax is to persuade energy companies to produce their electricity from green sources, like wind power and nuclear plants, rather than high-carbon fossil fuels.</p>
<p>At the moment, industrial companies in Europe have to buy a permit for every tonne of carbon dioxide they produce under the EU emissions trading scheme.</p>
<p>However, the Treasury is going one step further with an extra supplementary tax per tonne of carbon dioxide emitted.</p>
<p>Energy companies will not swallow the extra costs of the Carbon Floor Price themselves, but will pass them on to households and businesses through electricity bills.</p>
<p>Because the tax only applies to British companies, there are fears that heavy industry will leave the UK and move abroad.</p>
<p>This is why ministers have announced their £150 million scheme to subsidise the energy bills of some factories that are in danger of being put out of business.</p>
<p>Asked whether Mr Fallon now backs the Carbon Floor Price, a spokesman for the Department of Energy said that he “wants Britain to lead the way to a low carbon economy whilst making sure that the UK&#8217;s energy intensive industries remain competitive”.</p>
<p>Caroline Flint, Labour&#8217;s shadow energy secretary, said it is a &#8220;huge embarrassment for David Cameron that the man he has just appointed as energy minister is criticising his own energy policy&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;Worse still, Michael Fallon does not even seem to realise that the Carbon Price Floor was a Tory manifesto pledge,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Michael Fallon needs to make clear whether he still thinks the policy he is now in charge of is an &#8216;absurd waste of your money&#8217;.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/politics/9960100/Michael-Fallon-attacked-Coalitions-new-green-tax-for-causing-absurd-waste-of-money.html">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/michael-fallon-kill-absurd-carbon-floor-price/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unconventional Energy Supply To Triple By 2030</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/unconventional-energy-supply-triple-2030/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/unconventional-energy-supply-triple-2030/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11507</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The global supply of unconventional energy sources will triple by 2030 compared with 2011levels, which will have a major impact on the international energy market and benefit China, BPPlc said in an outlook released in Beijing on Thursday. A natural gas facility in Puyang, Henan province. China is expected tobenefit from US exports of shale oil and shale gas due to their impact onglobal energy prices. Hu Qingming / For China Daily Global energy demand will rise 36 percent by 2030 compared with 2011 with almost all of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The global supply of unconventional energy sources will triple by 2030 compared with 2011levels, which will have a major impact on the international energy market and benefit China, BPPlc said in an outlook released in Beijing on Thursday.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img id="5982201" title="" alt="Unconventional energy supply to triple by 2030: BP" src="http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/cndy/attachement/jpg/site1/20130329/f04da2db112212bf20a709.jpg" align="center" border="0" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: xx-small; color: #888888;"><strong>A natural gas facility in Puyang, Henan province. China is expected tobenefit from US exports of shale oil and shale gas due to their impact onglobal energy prices. Hu Qingming / For China Daily</strong></span></p>
<p>Global energy demand will rise 36 percent by 2030 compared with 2011 with almost all of the growth coming from emerging economies, it added.</p>
<p>&#8220;Unconventional sources &#8211; shale gas and light oil together with heavy oil and biofuels &#8211; will play an increasingly important role and transform the energy balance of the United States,&#8221; said Zhang Chi, head of the Asian economics department at BP.</p>
<p>Growing production from unconventional sources is expected to contribute more than 70percent of the net growth of the global oil supply by 2030.</p>
<p>Increasing production and weaker demand will result in the US being 99 percent self-sufficient in net energy by 2030, while it was only 70 percent self-sufficient in 2005.</p>
<p>And although the US is the biggest beneficiary of the shale gas &#8220;revolution&#8221;, China will benefit from it to some extent, experts said.</p>
<p>Exports of US shale oil and shale gas will help cap international oil prices, which is good news for oil importers, said David Robinson, senior research fellow with the Oxford Institute for Energy Studies.</p>
<p>He told China Daily on Thursday that because the geological conditions of US shale gas blocks are favorable, shale gas companies there will be able to adjust their production plans according to international crude oil price fluctuations.</p>
<p>Christopher Allsopp, director of the institute, said, &#8220;The increasing shale gas supply from the US cannot promise cheap energy, but it has its impact on the natural gas pricing mechanism.&#8221;</p>
<p>Natural gas prices in Asia are now linked to international crude oil prices, but that link is set to blur as natural gas is more likely to be priced, as in other markets, on supply and demand, he said.</p>
<p>For China, the increasing output of US shale gas has given the country a bigger say during talks with Russian natural gas suppliers, said Keun-Wook Paik, another senior research fellow at the institute.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/cndy/2013-03/29/content_16355561.htm">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/unconventional-energy-supply-triple-2030/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Germany Faces Coldest March Since 1883</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/germany-faces-coldest-march-1883/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/germany-faces-coldest-march-1883/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 09:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[International News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11503</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Complaining about the weather has reached epidemic proportions in northern Germany this &#8220;spring.&#8221; And with good reason. With Easter just around the corner, meteorologists are telling us this could end up being the coldest March in Berlin and its surroundings since records began in the 1880s. Snowmen are fine. Snow Easter Bunnies, though, are a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="spArticleWideTopSection">
<p id="spIntroTeaser"><strong>Complaining about the weather has reached epidemic proportions in northern Germany this &#8220;spring.&#8221; And with good reason. With Easter just around the corner, meteorologists are telling us this could end up being the coldest March in Berlin and its surroundings since records began in the 1880s.</strong></p>
<div id="spBigaBild">
<div align="right"><a title="Photo Gallery: Dreaming of a White Easter" href="http://www.spiegel.de/fotostrecke/photo-gallery-dreaming-of-a-white-easter-fotostrecke-94950-3.html"><img title="Snowmen are fine. Snow Easter Bunnies, though, are a sign of a spring gone..." alt="Snowmen are fine. Snow Easter Bunnies, though, are a sign of a spring gone..." src="http://cdn2.spiegel.de/images/image-478315-galleryV9-rtpv.jpg" width="680" height="453" border="0" /></a></div>
<div align="right"><span style="color: #808080;">Snowmen are fine. Snow Easter Bunnies, though, are a sign of a spring gone terribly wrong. These not-entirely-lifelike sculptures were photographed in the northern German state of Mecklenburg-Western Pomerania this week.</span></div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="spArticleColumn" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">
<div id="spArticleSection">
<p>The poor Easter Bunny deserves our sympathy. Whereas in recent years he has grown used to dodging daffodils, lilies and tulips as he carries his cargo of eggs and chocolate to homes across northern Europe, this year the rabbit will find himself confronted with ice slicks, snow drifts and bundled up humans in foul moods.</p>
<p>Easter, after all, may be upon us. But spring weather most definitely is not. Biologists are warning that the Easter Bunny&#8217;s wild brethren, European hares, are having trouble keeping their broods warm and healthy in the unseasonable chill. Meteorologists are keeping close tabs on thermometers to determine whether this March will go down as the coldest ever &#8212; since records began in the 1880s. And wiseacres on the streets of Berlin have not yet tired of noting that Easter promises to be colder than last Christmas.And it&#8217;s not just the northern regions of Continental Europe where the Easter Bunny will encounter problems. Great Britain and Ireland are likewise suffering through unseasonable weather, with power outages threatening the roast lamb and snow drifts making hopping difficult. Russia and Ukraine are also suffering.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><a href="http://www.spiegel.de/international/europe/cold-german-winter-refuses-to-warm-up-for-easter-a-891468.html">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/germany-faces-coldest-march-1883/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rupert Darwall: The Age Of Global Warming</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/rupert-darwall-age-global-warming-2/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/rupert-darwall-age-global-warming-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 09:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best of Blogs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11500</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Rupert Darwall’s history of the idea of global warming shows how the belief in an impending man-made apocalypse emanated from the top of wealthy Western societies. Long before there was climate change, there was environmentalism. As Rupert Darwall explains in his new book, The Age of Global Warming: A History, environmentalism had for decades proposed that humans [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Rupert Darwall’s history of the idea of global warming shows how the belief in an impending man-made apocalypse emanated from the top of wealthy Western societies.</strong></p>
<p>Long before there was climate change, there was environmentalism. As Rupert Darwall explains in his new book, <em>The Age of Global Warming: A History,</em> environmentalism had for decades proposed that humans were a blight on the planet. ‘During the course of the twentieth century’, he writes, ‘mankind’s relationship with nature underwent a revolution. At the beginning of the last century, human intervention was regarded as beneficient and a sign of the progress of civilisation. By century’s end, such interventions were presumed harmful unless it could be demonstrated they were not.’&#8230;</p>
<p>While environmentalism is certainly an obsession of many rich people, and a natural fit for many conservatives, one of the major factors that Darwall cites in the rise of environmentalism is the collapse of the left. But interestingly, this is not the usual argument about disillusioned ex-Communists turning from red to green, although such people have indeed often been the brains behind the development of these ideas. Rather, it was the collapse of a left-wing opposition to eco-notions about lowering growth that was crucial. Darwall notes the strong tradition on the left, from Marx onwards, in support of the need to increase the material wealth of society….</p>
<p>The elitist idea of environmentalism could only become dominant because of the exit of working-class politics from the Western political stage and the shrivelling of the political voice of the mass of Western populations. The failure of socialist and social-democratic parties meant there were no longer critics of environmentalism from the left. The declining membership of all political parties deprived the bulk of the population of an important means to hold politicians to account. To criticise the science and politics of global warming now meant you were a lackey of big business or some kind of ‘flat Earther’ who denied the importance of science. What remains is weariness of the modern world among those &#8211; from the middle classes upwards, and most particularly among the elites &#8211; who can afford such self-indulgence….</p>
<p>Reining in development in the name of the planet was always a rich man’s fancy. The Age of Global Warming should certainly become a touchstone for anyone interested in examining this issue seriously.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.spiked-online.com/site/reviewofbooks_article/13491">Full book review</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/rupert-darwall-age-global-warming-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Britain&#8217;s Colder Than The Arctic: -10c Freeze Over Easter</title>
		<link>http://www.thegwpf.org/britains-colder-arctic-10c-freeze-easter/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thegwpf.org/britains-colder-arctic-10c-freeze-easter/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 09:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bennypeiser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Climate Record]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thegwpf.org/?p=11497</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[BRITAIN will be colder than parts of Greenland this Easter with temp­eratures plunging to an Arctic -10C (14F). Snowploughs battle to clear drifts as the big freeze shows no signs of relenting Though the clocks go forward tomorrow night, marking the start of British Summer Time, there is no end in sight to the bitter [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<header>
<h3>BRITAIN will be colder than parts of Greenland this Easter with temp­eratures plunging to an Arctic -10C (14F).</h3>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div style="text-align: center;" data-send="false" data-layout="button_count" data-width="50" data-show-faces="false" data-font="arial"><img title="Snowploughs battle to clear drifts as the big freeze shows no signs of relenting" alt="Snowploughs-battle-to-clear-drifts-as-the-big-freeze-shows-no-signs-of-relenting" src="http://images.dailyexpress.co.uk/img/dynamic/1/590x/387878_1.jpg" /></div>
<div style="text-align: center;" data-send="false" data-layout="button_count" data-width="50" data-show-faces="false" data-font="arial">Snowploughs battle to clear drifts as the big freeze shows no signs of relenting</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</header>
<div>
<section>Though the clocks go forward tomorrow night, marking the start of British Summer Time, there is no end in sight to the bitter weather.This has already been the coldest March since 1962, the Met Office confirmed yesterday, and the fourth coldest since records began.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Image Attachment" src="http://climaterealists.com/attachments/ftp/Daily%20express%20422.jpg" /></p>
<p>Instead of spending the four-day Bank Holiday pottering in the garden or driving to the coast, people are being advised to wrap up warm and stay indoors.</p>
<p>Millions have given up hope of spring arriving and are jetting off for some much-needed sun. And some are still digging themselves out after being marooned by 20ft snowdrifts.</p>
<p>Parts of the UK are likely to see a white Easter with wintry showers forecast for eastern areas, though these are likely to be isolated and the snow should be fairly light.</p>
<p>By Sunday and Monday much of Britain may look sunny and spring-like but will still feel unseasonably chilly. And the snowdrifts could remain well into April.</p>
<p>Leon Brown, forecaster for The Weather Channel, said: “With these sorts of temperatures those drifts aren’t going to melt much at all.</p>
<p>“Because of the easterly winds there have been drifts that have left areas up to 20ft deep in snow. This is why farmers have really struggled.</p>
<p>“They have lost many of their sheep and there’s no good news for them, other than that the winds will die down. The actual drifts will melt only very slowly, even if the temperatures do lift above normal.</p>
<p>“Sea temperatures are now well depressed so temp­eratures are going to struggle to get anywhere near normal.</p>
<p>“There’s a risk of severe frost and some places could see temperatures as low as -10C.</p>
<p>“Anyone hoping to do a bit of gardening this Easter is out of luck. There’s no possibility of putting out early plants. I should think people will need to wait until late April before they can plant anything outside.”</p>
<p>The record lowest Easter temperature of -9.8C was set at Lagganlia, Inverness, on Easter Monday 1986.</p>
<p>Temperatures hit -8.8C early yesterday in Aonach Mor, Inverness, and -6.7C at Great Dun Fell, Cumbria.</p>
<p>That is much colder than parts of Greenland in the Arctic Circle which will see Easter lows of 1C.</p>
<p>Government cold weather health warnings have been extended until Monday – the first time the system has been used in April.</p>
<p>Channel 4 forecaster Liam Dutton said: “BST starts on Saturday night but the weather hasn’t noticed. Recent cold is remarkable and even weathermen are sick of it.”</p>
<p>Statistics from the Met Office show that from March 1 to 26 the UK mean temperature was 2.5C, which is three degrees below the long-term average. This made it the joint fourth coldest March in the UK since records began in 1910.</p>
<p>Around 1,200 homes in the west of Scotland remained without power for a sixth day yesterday following a problem with mobile generators.</p>
</section>
</div>
<p><a href="http://www.express.co.uk/news/uk/387878/Britain-s-colder-than-the-Arctic-10c-freeze-over-Easter">Full story</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thegwpf.org/britains-colder-arctic-10c-freeze-easter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
