<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2enclosuresfull.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>EDUKWEST</title>
	
	<link>http://www.edukwest.com</link>
	<description>on the search for better education</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 19:07:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
<xhtml:meta xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="robots" content="noindex" />
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/edukwest" /><feedburner:info uri="edukwest" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit><itunes:subtitle>on the search for better education</itunes:subtitle><feedburner:emailServiceId>edukwest</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>babbel.com raises $10 million Series B – busuu and Livemocha to follow?</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~3/dYwj2Ov4MrU/</link>
		<comments>http://www.edukwest.com/babbel-com-raises-10-million-series-b-busuu-and-livemocha-to-follow/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 19:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kirsten Winkler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding & Deals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babbel.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[busuu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[livemocha]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.edukwest.com/?p=6369</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Just a week after announcing the acquisition of PlaySay, Berlin-based language learning startup babbel.com closed a $10 million Series B.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6371" alt="babbel.com Series B" src="http://www.edukwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/babbel-funding.jpg" width="600" height="234" /></p>
<p>Just a week after announcing the <a title="babbel.com enters US Market through Acquisition of PlaySay" href="http://www.edukwest.com/babbel-com-enters-us-market-through-acquisition-of-playsay/"><strong>acquisition of PlaySay</strong></a>, Berlin-based language learning startup babbel.com has more <a title="Babbel Closes $10 Million Series B Funding Round" href="http://www.babbel.com/home/node/2295" target="_blank"><strong>news to share</strong></a>. Today we learned that they have closed a $10 million Series B round led by Reed Elsevier Ventures with participation of Nokia Growth Partners as well as the existing investors, IBB Beteiligungsgesellschaft via its VC Fonds Technologie Berlin and Kizoo Technology Ventures.</p>
<p>The round brings the total funding raised to date to $12.2 million and therefore close to its US based competitor Livemocha which raised <a title="Livemocha secures another $8 Million in Series B Funding" href="http://www.kirstenwinkler.com/livemocha-secures-another-8-million-in-series-b-funding/" target="_blank"><strong>around $14 million</strong></a>. The third of the trio, busuu comes to a total of $4.5 million with its latest <a title="busuu finally raises Series A Round – moves to London" href="http://www.edukwest.com/busuu-finally-raises-series-a-round-moves-to-london/" target="_blank"><strong>Series A round last October</strong></a>.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-6373" alt="babbel_graph_users" src="http://www.edukwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/babbel_graph_users-300x225.png" width="300" height="225" />While the ability to raise funding not necessarily makes a statement about the quality of the product or its business model I think that in this case it actually makes sense. As I wrote in my previous article about babbel.com last week, the founding team has proven to be able to build a viable company based on a relatively small amount of outside capital and then grow based on revenue. As babbel.com noted in the press release about the PlaySay acquisition which was also “fueled from operative cash flow”.</p>
<p>According to <a title="Language Startup Babbel Closes $10M Series B Funding To Expand Globally, Build Team" href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/26/babbel-closes-10m-series-b/" target="_blank"><strong>TechCrunch</strong></a> the three founders won’t take money off the table, therefore the investment will go directly into the expansion of babbel.com into new markets and platforms. Other European countries and the Americas are now in the focus. With two major global events around the corner and a growing middle class with dispensable income, Brazil is poised to be one of the battle grounds for language learning startups. The US which Markus Witte, CEO of babbel.com sees as “most matured” will be the other main market the startup wants to grow in with help through the PlaySay acquisition.</p>
<p>Which brings us to London-based busuu. The startup has a similar story and modus operandi, having raised small amounts of outside funding and growing quickly since the introduction of their mobile applications. According to the numbers both startups officially share, busuu has about 10 million users more than babbel.com, 25 million to 15 million. On the other hand, babbel.com only offers premium content which means that all users have to pay for the service whereas busuu offers freemium content which means that a significant number of its userbase does not pay for learning languages.</p>
<p>I am pretty sure that busuu is going to raise a $10 million or similar Series B in the coming weeks, latest in two months. It should not be difficult for the founding team as their numbers are quite impressive as well and the startup is also generating positive cash flow for years now. From what I have heard the busuu team certainly have some interesting ideas on how to innovate on their product which might go beyond ‘just’ apps. Let’s see if that vision is yet mature enough to be released in a near future.</p>
<p>However, busuu and to a certain degree Livemocha will need a well-filled war chest to fight off babbel.com. All three now target the same markets and thus it is going to be about marketing and teams on the ground.</p>
<p>Which brings us to Livemocha. Up to now Livemocha has <a href="https://callisto.zendesk.com/entries/23233938-Does-Livemocha-have-a-mobile-app-" target="_blank"><strong>no mobile applications</strong></a> I know of. It seems as if they are working on a new version of the web application (which probably also includes mobile applications) but nevertheless they are late to the game. Even compared to the yellow box selling old bull, aka Rosetta Stone, which offers a variety of mobile and tablet based applications.</p>
<p>It is hard to say how much money is left from the $14 million and if it is enough to launch a compelling suite of mobile applications. Maybe Livemocha has to raise a new round as well but I am not sure if the numbers are as good as those of babbel.com and busuu as the other two have basically accomplished the same user growth with far less funding.</p>
<p>Nevertheless I won’t count out Livemocha just yet as their focus now also seems to go into premium content and teacher lead learning. There are some English for professionals courses going on which are a mix of self-paced learning with the web application, peer learning with the community and instructor lead live lessons in a virtual classroom. Again, pretty similar to Rosetta Stone TOTALe.</p>
<p>So while babbel.com and busuu seem to go for the mass market with applications for the self guided learner, Livemocha is going towards a more personalized approach with expert teachers and live interactions. All in all the battle between the three promises to remain interesting.</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/edukwest/~4/dYwj2Ov4MrU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.edukwest.com/babbel-com-raises-10-million-series-b-busuu-and-livemocha-to-follow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.edukwest.com/babbel-com-raises-10-million-series-b-busuu-and-livemocha-to-follow/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>babbel.com enters US Market through Acquisition of PlaySay</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~3/o56acErDLWg/</link>
		<comments>http://www.edukwest.com/babbel-com-enters-us-market-through-acquisition-of-playsay/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kirsten Winkler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Reports & Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[application]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babbel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babbel.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[busuu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[livemocha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mlearning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlaySay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spanish]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.edukwest.com/?p=6362</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[German based language learning startup babbel.com announced the acquisition of PlaySay, a San Francisco based competitor in the mobile space.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6366" alt="Babbel playsay" src="http://www.edukwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/babbel-playsay.jpg" width="600" height="234" /></p>
<p>Now that is indeed something that does not happen everyday. <a title="Education Startup babbel.com Acquires San Francisco based PlaySay" href="http://www.babbel.com/home/node/2289"><strong>A German startup acquires an US based startup</strong></a> for parts, in this case language learning startup babbel.com from Berlin the user base of San Francisco based PlaySay which is pretty telling as neither the PlaySay team nor the technology will be integrated into babbel.com products. Only PlaySay’s founder Ryan Meinzer, whom I interviewed in October 2011, is going to join babbel.com in the role of an advisor for the US market.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://blip.tv/play/hI85gtqZUwA.x?p=1" height="366" width="600" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe><object style="display: none;" width="320" height="240" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="src" value="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85gtqZUwA" /><embed style="display: none;" width="320" height="240" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85gtqZUwA" /></object></p>
<p>So let’s break this one down. PlaySay started at TechCrunch Disrupt as a <strong><a title="PlaySay language learning tool raises $1.3m, demos at TechCrunch Disrupt" href="http://technical.ly/philly/2011/09/13/playsay-to-demo-at-techcrunch-disrupt" target="_blank">Facebook application</a></strong> for learning Spanish, and eventually pivoted its way to a mobile application to learn Spanish. It even ranked #1 in the education category of the iTunes Store in ten different countries including the US at one point.</p>
<p>But babbel.com does not seem to be interested in the technology or applications but merely in the PlaySay users who now have 45 days to switch over to using babbel.com instead.</p>
<p>babbel.com is part of a group of three language learning startups which all emerged at about the same time and have battled to become the next Rosetta Stone. Besides babbel.com the others are Livemocha out of Seattle and busuu who just relocated their HQ from Madrid to London after <a title="busuu finally raises Series A Round – moves to London" href="http://www.edukwest.com/busuu-finally-raises-series-a-round-moves-to-london/" target="_blank"><strong>raising a Series A round</strong></a>.</p>
<p>While Livemocha and busuu chose and continue to rely on a freemium model as their business strategy, babbel.com decided to <a title="There is no free lunch – Babbel goes Premium" href="http://www.kirstenwinkler.com/there-is-no-free-lunch-babbel-goes-premium/" target="_blank"><strong>switch to a premium model</strong></a> rather early on. Whereas this might have contributed to slowing down the startup’s growth in terms of users compared to Livemocha and busuu, it has certainly helped substantially in terms of revenue generation and breaking even.</p>
<p>Similar to busuu, babbel.com did not take on tons of funding at this point which probably helped the team a lot to figure out the business model and how to sell best. A strong factor in the growth of both busuu and babbel.com have been the respective mobile applications. In fact, babbel.com&#8217;s <a title="Babbel triples Revenue – Takes over App Department of Aspirement" href="http://www.edukwest.com/babbel-triples-revenue-takes-over-app-department-of-aspirement/" target="_blank"><strong>first acquisition</strong></a> was the mobile app developing startup that had built the first babbel.com applications.</p>
<p>The only real problem babbel.com seems to have had is growing its footprint and finding success in new territories. Both Livemocha and busuu succeeded early on to grab market share in key markets like the US and South America.</p>
<p>Taking all this into consideration I suppose that babbel.com got PlaySay for a pretty reasonable price as the press release states</p>
<blockquote><p>Deal fueled from operative cash flow.</p></blockquote>
<p>PlaySay have only <strong><a title="PlaySay: Social Language Learning App Launches With $820k And A HarperCollins Deal In Its Pocket" href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/01/playsay-social-language-learning-app-launches-with-820k-and-a-harpercollins-deal-in-its-pocket/" target="_blank">raised $820k</a></strong> since 2008 which means that even if babbel.com paid a bit more, like in the range of $1.5m to $2m it was still kind of cheap. It also shows that PlaySay did not manage to get enough traction to make it worthwhile for the founder and his team to keep on working on the product or to raise another round of funding. I think the following sentence from the press release why PlaySay sold to babbel.com is pretty telling.</p>
<blockquote><p>“It&#8217;s fun, social and mobile, just like PlaySay&#8230;only better!”</p></blockquote>
<p>I don’t know how many users PlaySay actually has in its database but if we assume that 1 million people have downloaded the application or signed up for the Facebook application at one point, babbel.com may have paid about $2 per user. I am also not sure what the cost per acquisition for a language learner is these days but I guess it’s much higher, maybe in the $10 range.</p>
<p>Of course, babbel.com can’t be sure that all of the PlaySay users will happily switch to the new service and then also pay for it but in the end it might be enough to get the babbel.com Spanish app ranking in the US iTunes Store which will eventually lead to better exposure and new users.</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/edukwest/~4/o56acErDLWg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.edukwest.com/babbel-com-enters-us-market-through-acquisition-of-playsay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<media:content url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~5/fsCYK7nCUWc/api.swf" fileSize="36" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" /><itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit><itunes:subtitle>German based language learning startup babbel.com announced the acquisition of PlaySay, a San Francisco based competitor in the mobile space.</itunes:subtitle><itunes:summary>German based language learning startup babbel.com announced the acquisition of PlaySay, a San Francisco based competitor in the mobile space.</itunes:summary><itunes:keywords>Reports &amp; Analysis, application, babbel, babbel.com, busuu, livemocha, mlearning, mobile learning, PlaySay, spanish</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://www.edukwest.com/babbel-com-enters-us-market-through-acquisition-of-playsay/</feedburner:origLink><enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~5/fsCYK7nCUWc/api.swf" length="36" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" /><feedburner:origEnclosureLink>http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85gtqZUwA</feedburner:origEnclosureLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>EDUKWEST #98 with Vikas Pota of GEMS Education</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~3/T3b5oyaZ0Mg/</link>
		<comments>http://www.edukwest.com/edukwest-98-with-vikas-pota-of-gems-education/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 14:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kirsten Winkler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[EDUKWEST]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GEMS Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GEMS Schools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Varkey GEMS Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vikas Pota]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.edukwest.com/?p=6350</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My guest on the program is Vikas Pota, Global Head of Corporate Affairs of GEMS Education and Chief Executive of the Varkey GEMS Foundation.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-6354" alt="EDUKWEST 98 Vikas Pota GEMS Education" src="http://www.edukwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/edukwest-98-vikas-pota-gems-education-pic-150x1501.jpg" width="150" height="150" />For EDUKWEST episode 98 my guest on the program is Vikas Pota, Global Head of Corporate Affairs of <a title="GEMS Education" href="http://gemseducation.com" target="_blank"><strong>GEMS Education</strong></a> and Chief Executive of the <a title="Varkey GEMS Foundation" href="http://www.gemseducation.com/MENASA/investors/contents.php?pageid=33&amp;parentid=16" target="_blank"><strong>Varkey GEMS Foundation</strong></a>. Today he was awarded one of the <a title="Young Global Leaders" href="http://www.weforum.org/news/world-economic-forum-announces-young-global-leaders-class-2013?news=page" target="_blank"><strong>Young Global Leaders</strong></a> of the World Economic Forum.</p>
<p>GEMS Education is a private education company that runs GEMS K12 schools all over the world several of which in Dubai and the United Arab Emirates. Subject of our talk is the upcoming <a title="Education and Skills Forum" href="http://educationandskillsforum.org" target="_blank"><strong>Education and Skills Forum</strong></a> that will take place in Dubai from March 15-17.</p>
<p>To me, Dubai and the whole region seems to establish itself as a hotspot for educational conferences, fairs and trade shows around e-learning.</p>
<p><a href="http://vodburner.com?utm_source=edukwest" target="_blank"><img title="vodburner600x40" alt="vodburner600x40" src="http://www.edukwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/vodburner600x40.jpg" width="600" height="40" /></a></p>
<p><iframe src="http://blip.tv/play/hI85g4_gQQA.x?p=1" height="366" width="600" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe><object style="display: none;" width="320" height="240" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="src" value="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g4_gQQA" /><embed style="display: none;" width="320" height="240" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g4_gQQA" /></object></p>
<table width="600px">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="200px"><img alt="Subscribe to review:ed" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/subscribe-edukwest.png" /></td>
<td width="200px"><a title="EDUKWEST Video Podcast" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/edukwest-video"><img alt="Subscribe to EDUKWEST Video via RSS" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/subscribe-rss-video.png" /></a></td>
<td width="200px"><a title="EDUKWEST Audio Podcast" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/edukwest-edukwest-audio"><img alt="Subscribe to EDUKWEST Audio via RSS" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/subscribe-rss-audio.png" /></a><br />
<a title="EDUKWEST Audio Podcast iTunes" href="http://itunes.apple.com//podcast//id491329239?l=en"><img alt="Subscribe to EDUKWEST Audio via iTunes" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/subscribe-itunes-audio.png" /></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="200px"><img alt="Download Episode" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/download-episode.png" /></td>
<td width="200px"><a title="EDUKWEST #98 with Vikas Pota of GEMS Education [Video]" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp4/www.blip.tv/file/get/EDUKWEST-EDUKWEST98WithVikasPotaOfGEMSEducation188.mp4"><img alt="Download Episode Video" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/download-video.png" /></a></td>
<td width="200px"><a title="EDUKWEST #98 with Vikas Pota of GEMS Education [Audio]" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/www.archive.org/download/Edukwest98VikasPotaGemsEducation/edukwest%2098%20vikas%20pota%20gems%20education.mp3"><img alt="Download Episode Audio" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/download-audio.png" /></a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>The online education market in the region is thriving; it is estimated that by 2016 its revenue will be of $560 million and the private school market in the UAE makes 65% of the overall schooling today.</p>
<p>The conference features some key people of the education industry one of which is Anant Agarwal of edX whom I had the pleasure to interview just recently for Today’s Campus Innovation Interview Series. As we see lots of innovation happening in the higher education space, it should be interesting whether this allows to draw some conclusions or explore a vision for further disruption of the K12 space.</p>
<p>The Varkey GEMS Foundation, however, a not-for-profit aims at improving education of underprivileged children through an innovative low-cost teacher training program.</p>
<p>As always, it’s a great challenge when so many different situations and needs converge as they do in education at the moment.<br />
I enjoyed Vikas’ take on some of the aspects we touched on and hope the conference will be able to add one or the other interesting perspective or practical approach to solve some of the issues and challenges we’re faced with.</p>
<p>To get updates on the Education and Skills Forum use the Twitter hashtag #GESF to follow the conversation or to engage, i.e. tweet your questions. For the President Clinton live link to the conference via satellite there is a separate hashtag #askClinton</p>
<h2><strong style="font-size: 13px;">Additional Links:</strong></h2>
<table width="100%" border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Homepage:</td>
<td><a title="GEMS Education" href="http://gemseducation.com" target="_blank"><strong>http://gemseducation.com</strong></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Homepage:</td>
<td><a title="Global Education and Skills Forum" href="http://educationandskillsforum.org" target="_blank"><strong>http://educationandskillsforum.org</strong></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>GEMS Education on Twitter:</td>
<td><a title="GEMS Education Twitter" href="http://twitter.com/gemseducation" target="_blank"><strong>@gemseducation</strong></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>GESF on Facebook:</td>
<td><strong><a title="Global Education and Skills Forum" href="http://facebook.com/GESForum" target="_blank">http://facebook.com/GESForum</a><br />
</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>LinkedIn:</td>
<td><strong><a title="Vikas Pota LinkedIn" href="http://uk.linkedin.com/in/vikaspota" target="_blank">Vikas Pota</a><br />
</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/edukwest/~4/T3b5oyaZ0Mg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.edukwest.com/edukwest-98-with-vikas-pota-of-gems-education/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>

<enclosure url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/www.archive.org/download/Edukwest98VikasPotaGemsEducation/edukwest%2098%20vikas%20pota%20gems%20education.mp3" length="233" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<media:content url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~5/RUnxkutZ-bw/EDUKWEST-EDUKWEST98WithVikasPotaOfGEMSEducation188.mp4" fileSize="199" type="video/mp4" /><itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit><itunes:subtitle>My guest on the program is Vikas Pota, Global Head of Corporate Affairs of GEMS Education and Chief Executive of the Varkey GEMS Foundation.</itunes:subtitle><itunes:summary>My guest on the program is Vikas Pota, Global Head of Corporate Affairs of GEMS Education and Chief Executive of the Varkey GEMS Foundation.</itunes:summary><itunes:keywords>EDUKWEST, GEMS Education, GEMS Schools, Varkey GEMS Foundation, Vikas Pota</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://www.edukwest.com/edukwest-98-with-vikas-pota-of-gems-education/</feedburner:origLink><enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~5/RUnxkutZ-bw/EDUKWEST-EDUKWEST98WithVikasPotaOfGEMSEducation188.mp4" length="199" type="video/mp4" /><feedburner:origEnclosureLink>http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp4/www.blip.tv/file/get/EDUKWEST-EDUKWEST98WithVikasPotaOfGEMSEducation188.mp4</feedburner:origEnclosureLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Today’s Campus Innovation Interview #9 – Andrew Shakman of LeanPath</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~3/0uh87Fhv8WA/</link>
		<comments>http://www.edukwest.com/todays-campus-innovation-interview-9-andrew-shakman-of-leanpath/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 19:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kirsten Winkler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Today's Campus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrew Shakman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LeanPath]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.edukwest.com/?p=6341</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[LeanPath can help customers to reduce their food waste by up to 80% and save 2%-4% or more on their annual food purchases.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-6346" alt="Today's Campus 9 Andrew Shakman LeanPath" src="http://www.edukwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/todays-campus-9-andrew-shakman-leanpath-pic-150x1501.jpg" width="150" height="150" />We speak a lot about making college more affordable. Tuition and textbooks naturally come to mind first. But saving colleges money can also happen through food waste prevention and tracking systems.</p>
<p>For this interview my guest is Andrew Shakman, the CEO and President of <strong><a title="LeanPath" href="http://leanpath.com" target="_blank">LeanPath</a></strong>. LeanPath has been in the business for over ten years and helps its customers reduce their waste significantly and also save on their food purchases through its management tools. According to their website, LeanPath claims that their technology can help customers to reduce their food waste by up to 80% and save 2%-4% or more on their annual food purchases.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://blip.tv/play/hI85g4_AGQA.x?p=1" height="366" width="600" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe><object style="display: none;" width="320" height="240" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="src" value="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g4_AGQA" /><embed style="display: none;" width="320" height="240" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g4_AGQA" /></object></p>
<p>Andrew takes us through the process of how the technology actually works as well as the different possibilities of how colleges and universities can reduce their pre-consumer food waste and save money.</p>
<p>LeanPath university customers include among other Michigan Tech, the University of Massachusetts Amherst and the University of North Dakota. Over time the company has become what you could call green.</p>
<p>If you’re looking for solutions on how to reduce food waste and lower the cost for your university or you’re generally interested in the topic you should check out the various resources such as stats on food waste, the regular webinars and other free resources i.e. the savings calculator on the <strong><a title="LeanPath" href="http://leanpath.com" target="_blank">LeanPath</a></strong> website.</p>
<p>It was quite a fascinating and educational talk about a topic we don’t usually think and hear about that much.</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/edukwest/~4/0uh87Fhv8WA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.edukwest.com/todays-campus-innovation-interview-9-andrew-shakman-of-leanpath/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<media:content url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~5/24cZmOAqDno/api.swf" fileSize="36" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" /><itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit><itunes:subtitle>LeanPath can help customers to reduce their food waste by up to 80% and save 2%-4% or more on their annual food purchases.</itunes:subtitle><itunes:summary>LeanPath can help customers to reduce their food waste by up to 80% and save 2%-4% or more on their annual food purchases.</itunes:summary><itunes:keywords>Today's Campus, Andrew Shakman, food waste, LeanPath</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://www.edukwest.com/todays-campus-innovation-interview-9-andrew-shakman-of-leanpath/</feedburner:origLink><enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~5/24cZmOAqDno/api.swf" length="36" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" /><feedburner:origEnclosureLink>http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g4_AGQA</feedburner:origEnclosureLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Today’s Campus Innovation Interview #8 – Ulrik Juul Christensen of area9</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~3/1tM7NA594Mk/</link>
		<comments>http://www.edukwest.com/todays-campus-innovation-interview-8-ulrik-juul-christensen-of-area9/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 23:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kirsten Winkler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Today's Campus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adaptive learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[area9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LearnSmart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[McGraw-Hill Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ulrik Juul Christensen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.edukwest.com/?p=6333</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[area9 is the startup behind McGraw-Hill's LearnSmart product. In this interview I talk with Ulrik Juul Christensen, area9 co-founder &#038; CEO.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-6337" alt="Today's Campus 8 Ulrik Juul Christensen area9" src="http://www.edukwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/todays-campus-8-ulrik-juul-christensen-area9-pic-150x1501.jpg" width="150" height="150" />I have blogged about adaptive learning and interviewed startups on that matter since 2010. Most of these companies offer solutions for math and test preparation such as US startups <strong><a title="Rohit Agarwal of TenMarks" href="http://www.edukwest.com/rohit-agarwal-of-tenmarks/">TenMarks</a></strong> (K-12), <a title="Robert Gange of Perfect800" href="http://www.edukwest.com/robert-gange-of-perfect800/">Perfect800</a> (test prep) or European math startup <strong><a title="EDUKWEST #86 with Richard Fielding of PrepMyFuture" href="http://www.edukwest.com/edukwest-86-with-richard-fielding-of-prepmyfuture/">PrepMyFuture</a></strong>.</p>
<p>I also had the chance for two interviews with McGraw-Hill executives. I always find it insightful how big companies position themselves for the future and in which areas those companies see big potential. McGraw-Hill undoubtedly sees their LearnSmart product as one of their key-products to be well positioned for the future of education. McGraw-Hill Education<br />
Edukwest’s Senior Editor Christopher Dawson and I talked with <strong><a title="review:ed #27 with Vineet Madan of McGraw-Hill Education" href="http://www.edukwest.com/reviewed-27-with-vineet-madan-of-mcgraw-hill-education/">Vineet Madan</a></strong>, Senior VP of New Ventures and I also interviewed <strong><a title="EDUKWEST #90 with Jay Chakrapani of McGraw-Hill Higher Education Digital Group" href="http://www.edukwest.com/edukwest-90-with-jay-chakrapani-of-mcgraw-hill-higher-education-digital-group/">Jay Chakrapani</a></strong>, McGraw-Hill’s VP and General Manager of the higher education digital education group.</p>
<p>Therefore, when I got offered the possibility to talk to <a title="area9" href="http://area9.dk" target="_blank"><strong>area9</strong></a> co-founder Dr. Ulrik Juul Christensen, it was particularly interesting for me to seize my chance and interview the creators behind the LearnSmart and SmartBook products.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://blip.tv/play/hI85g47wHwA.x?p=1" height="366" width="600" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe><object style="display: none;" width="320" height="240" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="src" value="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g47wHwA" /><embed style="display: none;" width="320" height="240" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g47wHwA" /></object></p>
<p>McGraw-Hill also recently made a strategic investment in area9 and bought 20% of the company. With its products area9 wants to achieve three key points: create personalized solutions, on a global scale that are affordable.</p>
<p>In this interview, we talk about the state of adaptive or personalized learning in 2013 and whether we have already achieved true adaptiveness. As pointed out at the beginning of this article, I have mostly heard about adaptive solutions in the math and test prep space. I was interested in hearing whether there might be a particular explanation for this, for instance if it is simply easier to realize such a product in the math space than in language arts.</p>
<p>We also talk about the challenges, particularly for colleges and universities, to integrate Interactive Learning Online (ILO) and how long it might take until adoption at large scale (3 years+).</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/edukwest/~4/1tM7NA594Mk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.edukwest.com/todays-campus-innovation-interview-8-ulrik-juul-christensen-of-area9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<media:content url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~5/Wn6lXYm8fyU/api.swf" fileSize="36" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" /><itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit><itunes:subtitle>area9 is the startup behind McGraw-Hill's LearnSmart product. In this interview I talk with Ulrik Juul Christensen, area9 co-founder &amp;#038; CEO.</itunes:subtitle><itunes:summary>area9 is the startup behind McGraw-Hill's LearnSmart product. In this interview I talk with Ulrik Juul Christensen, area9 co-founder &amp;#038; CEO.</itunes:summary><itunes:keywords>Today's Campus, adaptive learning, area9, LearnSmart, McGraw-Hill Education, Ulrik Juul Christensen</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://www.edukwest.com/todays-campus-innovation-interview-8-ulrik-juul-christensen-of-area9/</feedburner:origLink><enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~5/Wn6lXYm8fyU/api.swf" length="36" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" /><feedburner:origEnclosureLink>http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g47wHwA</feedburner:origEnclosureLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Deliberate Tech to Create a Sustainable Campus</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~3/da_DgZyHjXs/</link>
		<comments>http://www.edukwest.com/deliberate-tech-to-create-a-sustainable-campus/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 13:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lida Hasbrouck</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Op-Ed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[campus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.edukwest.com/?p=6325</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lida shared some easy fixes for three obvious problems (paper, presentations and transportation)  to create a more sustainable campus.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="size-full wp-image-6328 aligncenter" alt="sustainable campus" src="http://www.edukwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/college2.jpg" width="600" height="234" /></p>
<p><strong>Editor’s Note:</strong> <em>This article first appeared on our partner site <a title="Deliberate Tech to Make Your Campus Sustainable" href="http://todayscampus.com/article/Deliberate_Tech_to_Make_Your_Campus_Sustainable"><strong>Today’s Campus Magazine</strong></a> – Covering the people, campuses, and companies that are making business news in higher education.</em></p>
<p>Every college on the planet has taken steps toward sound, sustainable practices, but for that matter, so has every business, household, etc. The little things, like using both sides of the copy paper or highlighting reusable utensils as an option in the cafeteria, are becoming more mainstream.</p>
<p>The problem is, these types of processes are all manual; students and faculty need to make a deliberate choice to help you help the environment each time they use the resource. The most efficient green decisions are ones you can make once and automate for the future, with a campus-wide effect.</p>
<p>Let’s focus on a few obvious problem areas which have relatively simple fixes. The first two are easily actionable, so you really have no excuse not to step-up and implement them. The last will require an investment of time and money, but should yeild the highest returns.</p>
<h2>Paper</h2>
<p>Did you know that your institution’s proprietary content (i.e. campus newsletter, magazine, newspaper, catalog) can be “published” beautifully online, privately or publicly, completely free? I didn’t know about <strong><a href="http://www.youblisher.com/">youblisher</a></strong> until a friend of mine texted me, asking about publishing in a digital magazine format. I started looking around, and couldn’t help but sign-up for every service I could find to spot the differences.</p>
<p>So far, (despite the name) youblisher is my favorite. The process is super simple: upload a PDF and they churn-out a link for you to share or embed. It gives you a virtual magazine, with beautiful page flip animations. How much would it save your school to publish next year’s course catalog exclusively online instead of in print? As I mentioned, there are quite a few services like this out there for this, so it’s possible to find the right fit for any institution.</p>
<h2>Presentations</h2>
<p>Getting someone’s meeting or lecture notes and slides can be close to impossible after the fact. If you do get them, good luck making that .key play in PowerPoint. Because of this, we’ve taken to mass printing slides (or sharing them as PDFs, which destroys the whole point of a presentation). <strong><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/">SlideShare</a></strong> makes these problems disappear. (Aside: it’s also a great source for open content!) Never worry again about trying to get your presentation reference sheet to the 4 people in the room who requested them. Tell your faculty there’s a better way to share lecture slides.</p>
<p>Before you even present, upload everything to SlideShare. It’s a quick process and allows you to set your privacy settings for each file. Set everything to public for the easiest, non-controlled method of distribution. Otherwise, share the link privately to keep it locked-down. They offer a wide range of features and benefits, with plans starting at “free,” so experimenting is risk-free.</p>
<h2>Transportation</h2>
<p>How do your faculty and students get to campus, and once they’re there, how do they get around? If your institution is in a major US city, you may already be familiar with <strong><a href="http://www.bcycle.com/">B-cycle</a></strong>, a bike rental system. How it works: you go to a kiosk, swipe your credit card, take a bike from the rack, ride to the kiosk closest to your destination, and “return” the bike at that location. Again, they have competitors, but I only have personal experience with their service.</p>
<p>If your college is located in a city that already has B-cycle stations, and the sprawl of your campus warrants an alternative to walking, this would be optimal. This would be an excellent way for faculty and students to get to and from campus, if they’re located a few miles off and public transit isn’t an easy option. And since the B-cycle bikes are outfitted with GPS and other high-tech features, they’re nearly impossible to steal or lose. Just think how cool and accessible your campus will be by incorporating a technology like this. B-cycle would even improve your connectedness to the local community, another huge plus.</p>
<div>Of course, as with anything, the largest part of these changes is the willingness to make them. You’re administration is already leading by example since they cut plastic bags from the bookstore checkout. This and any other steps you take will empower the administrators, faculty and students, to make changes in their own lives on campus. Do your decisions prove your institution is focusing on green education technology?</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="http://mrg.bz/Xcp1mX" target="_blank"><strong>Image</strong></a></div>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/edukwest/~4/da_DgZyHjXs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.edukwest.com/deliberate-tech-to-create-a-sustainable-campus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.edukwest.com/deliberate-tech-to-create-a-sustainable-campus/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>EDUKWEST #97 with Michael Trucano of The World Bank</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~3/inaHXWfROAI/</link>
		<comments>http://www.edukwest.com/edukwest-97-with-michael-trucano-of-the-world-bank/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 13:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kirsten Winkler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[EDUKWEST]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developing countries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Trucano]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The World Bank]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.edukwest.com/?p=6313</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My interview at OEB 2012 with Michael Trucano, the World Bank’s Sr. ICT &#038; Education Policy Specialist on edtech in developing countries.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-6319" alt="EDUKWEST 97 Michael Trucano The World Bank" src="http://www.edukwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/edukwest-97-michael-trucano-world-bank-pic-150x1501.jpg" width="150" height="150" />Back in December 2012 I took part in Online Educa Berlin, the largest global e-learning conference for the corporate, education and public service sectors.</p>
<p>One of the keynote speakers at the conference was the World Bank’s Sr. ICT &amp; Education Policy Specialist Michael Trucano.</p>
<p>I took the chance for a quick interview with him and asked a few question on the state of e-learning in the developing world.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://blip.tv/play/hI85g46sPwA.x?p=1" height="366" width="600" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe><object style="display: none;" width="320" height="240" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="src" value="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g46sPwA" /><embed style="display: none;" width="320" height="240" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g46sPwA" /></object></p>
<table width="600px">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="200px"><img alt="Subscribe to review:ed" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/subscribe-edukwest.png" /></td>
<td width="200px"><a title="EDUKWEST Video Podcast" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/edukwest-video"><img alt="Subscribe to EDUKWEST Video via RSS" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/subscribe-rss-video.png" /></a></td>
<td width="200px"><a title="EDUKWEST Audio Podcast" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/edukwest-edukwest-audio"><img alt="Subscribe to EDUKWEST Audio via RSS" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/subscribe-rss-audio.png" /></a><br />
<a title="EDUKWEST Audio Podcast iTunes" href="http://itunes.apple.com//podcast//id491329239?l=en"><img alt="Subscribe to EDUKWEST Audio via iTunes" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/subscribe-itunes-audio.png" /></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="200px"><img alt="Download Episode" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/download-episode.png" /></td>
<td width="200px"><a title="EDUKWEST #97 with Michael Trucano of The World Bank [Video]" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp4/www.blip.tv/file/get/EDUKWEST-EDUKWEST97WithMichaelTrucanoOfTheWorldBank360.mp4"><img alt="Download Episode Video" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/download-video.png" /></a></td>
<td width="200px"><a title="EDUKWEST #97 with Michael Trucano of The World Bank [Audio]" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/www.archive.org/download/Edukwest96WithFarboodNiviOfGrockitAndLearnist/Edukwest96FarboodNiviGrockitLearnist.mp3"><img alt="Download Episode Audio" src="http://www.edukwest.com/pics/icons/download-audio.png" /></a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I was particularly interested in learning more about Internet penetration in general, the use of mobile devices, namely tablets and phones, in education and what he sees as some of the more innovative approaches in different countries of the developing world when it comes to implementing ICT in education.</p>
<p>You can find Michael’s blog on ICT use in Education <strong><a title="EduTech" href="http://blogs.worldbank.org/edutech/" target="_blank">here</a></strong> and follow him on Twitter <strong><a title="Michael Trucano" href="http://twitter.com/trucano" target="_blank">@trucano</a></strong>.</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/edukwest/~4/inaHXWfROAI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.edukwest.com/edukwest-97-with-michael-trucano-of-the-world-bank/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>

<enclosure url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/www.archive.org/download/Edukwest96WithFarboodNiviOfGrockitAndLearnist/Edukwest96FarboodNiviGrockitLearnist.mp3" length="235" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<media:content url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~5/6YERz0_NbRk/EDUKWEST-EDUKWEST97WithMichaelTrucanoOfTheWorldBank360.mp4" fileSize="203" type="video/mp4" /><itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit><itunes:subtitle>My interview at OEB 2012 with Michael Trucano, the World Bank’s Sr. ICT &amp;#038; Education Policy Specialist on edtech in developing countries.</itunes:subtitle><itunes:summary>My interview at OEB 2012 with Michael Trucano, the World Bank’s Sr. ICT &amp;#038; Education Policy Specialist on edtech in developing countries.</itunes:summary><itunes:keywords>EDUKWEST, developing countries, ICT, Michael Trucano, The World Bank</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://www.edukwest.com/edukwest-97-with-michael-trucano-of-the-world-bank/</feedburner:origLink><enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~5/6YERz0_NbRk/EDUKWEST-EDUKWEST97WithMichaelTrucanoOfTheWorldBank360.mp4" length="203" type="video/mp4" /><feedburner:origEnclosureLink>http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp4/www.blip.tv/file/get/EDUKWEST-EDUKWEST97WithMichaelTrucanoOfTheWorldBank360.mp4</feedburner:origEnclosureLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>The Future of MOOCs is Vertical</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~3/5FXzq4QYcts/</link>
		<comments>http://www.edukwest.com/the-future-of-moocs-is-vertical/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 15:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Hank Horkoff</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Op-Ed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MOOCs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.edukwest.com/?p=6305</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While technologists have started MOOCs, teachers need to consolidate these gains by contributing their real world pedagogical experience.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="size-full wp-image-6308 aligncenter" alt="MOOCs" src="http://www.edukwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/classroom.jpg" width="600" height="234" /></p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s Note:</strong> <em>This post has first been published on <a title="The Future of MOOCs is Vertical" href="http://openlanguage.com/blog/419/the-future-moocs-vertical" target="_blank"><strong>The Hum of Language Acquisition</strong></a>.</em></p>
<p>Over the course of 2012, massively open online classrooms, or MOOCs, have started to radically disrupt the foundations of traditional education structures. These MOOCs (such as Khan Academy, Coursera, Udacity, Udemy, etc) use videos &#8211; independent of time and location &#8211; to replace lectures, blowing away the walls of the traditional classroom and potentially bringing the genius of the best teachers to any network-connected student in the world. Beyond just providing lectures or lesson input, these MOOCs are rapidly rounding out their offerings by adding exercises to test comprehension and collecting study data with the long-term vision of designing personalized, learning pathways. In contrast to this innovation, traditional institutions are clinging to their last remaining solid foothold, that of providing credentials.</p>
<p>While the technologists have started the MOOC revolution, teachers and subject matter experts need to consolidate these gains by contributing their real world pedagogical experience. While the teaching of some subjects are in the format of lecture, lecture then test, others are more complicated and require students to do more than just watch videos and take exercises. This gap is exactly where there is an opportunity for vertical MOOCs.</p>
<h2>Specialized Review</h2>
<p>Some subjects require specialized review activities to reinforce and explore the key concepts presented in the lectures, or lesson input. For instance when learning a new language, after a student is introduced to a new lesson (ideally focused around a real-life dialogue in the target language) they need to examine and start to play with the language. What did that person say? How is that sentence constructed? Can that term be used in other ways? What are other similar wards that can be used with the same sentence? How can I save these terms for future review?</p>
<p>While a video lecture can kick off the learning experience, for some subjects specialized review tools are necessary to facilitate increased student learning and engagement.</p>
<h2>Specialized Practice</h2>
<p>Some subjects require more than just an intellectual understanding of a concept, they require the student to mimic, apply or recreate the desired skill. While a medical student maybe be able to acquire a perfect intellectual understanding of anatomy, how many patients would consent to the same person performing an operation without hours and hours of practice and coaching?</p>
<p>Specialized Learning Pathways</p>
<p>The big promise of moving learning onto digital platforms is that the underlying study data can be collected and used to help optimize learning environments and pathways. With enough data, the visions contend, it should be possible to customize learning environments (much like you would A/B test a website) to increase the students chances for success. For a similar cohort of students, does the length of a lecture matter? The time of day? The ethnicity of their teacher? There are hundreds of variables that could potentially be optimized.</p>
<p>Once these optimization efforts hit learning materials things become more complicated. Some subjects, like math, rely on pre-requisites when constructing a study plan. With this linear progression, the visions contend, it should be possible to build a &#8216;funnel&#8217; and then &#8216;optimize&#8217; the pathways for various student cohorts. But what happens with a subject that doesn&#8217;t rely so much on pre-requisites (e.g. history &#8211; does it matter if a student learns about the American Revolution before the Second World War?) or where the pre-requisites are more blurry (e.g. language learning &#8211; where pre-requisites rely more on bands of difficulty rather than linear progression).</p>
<p>This is the big data problem that MOOCs are looking to solve. It will likely need highly customized algorithms for different subjects.</p>
<h2>Specialized Pedagogy</h2>
<p>One of the most exciting consequences of using videos to provide lectures to students before class is that class time can be re-purposed to focus more on coaching and helping students overcome their individual problems. This &#8216;flipped classroom&#8217; approach makes use of the best that both technology and the classroom can offer, hopefully creating a more personalized and effective learning experience for the student.</p>
<p>For many subjects, teachers and face-to-face time are still an important piece of the learning process. MOOCs should be providing integrated support for teachers with lesson plans and student activity streams to help them understand where students are succeeding and failing. Math and languages are not taught the same in a traditional classroom context, nor should they be with a flipped classroom model.</p>
<p>Teachers will have specific needs depending on their subject area and vertical MOOCs will be in the best position to serve them.</p>
<h2>Specialized Assessment</h2>
<p>Different subjects measure proficiency in different ways. While it may sufficient for some subjects simply to test students with a multiple choice exam, others require additional evaluation lenses to determine learning success. With language acquisition for instance, multiple choice exams can be used for reading and listening comprehension, but written assignments are needed to measure writing ability and oral exams to measure speaking ability.</p>
<p>The difference in how subjects are assessed is just one further example of why there is an opportunity for learning platforms specialized on vertical subjects.</p>
<h2>Just the Beginning</h2>
<p>After more than 15 years of the Internet, MOOCs are finally starting to disrupt Industrial-era education. While significant innovations have already been made, the next stage will be able about specific subject-matter verticals filling out the offering to finally define the share of new, Internet-era education structures.</p>
<p><a title="Morguefile" href="http://morguefile.com/archive/display/789316" target="_blank">Image</a></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/edukwest/~4/5FXzq4QYcts" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.edukwest.com/the-future-of-moocs-is-vertical/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.edukwest.com/the-future-of-moocs-is-vertical/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Today’s Campus Innovation Interview #7 – Sean Conway of Notehall</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~3/AII-S4y72wA/</link>
		<comments>http://www.edukwest.com/todays-campus-innovation-interview-7-sean-conway-of-notehall/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 10:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kirsten Winkler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Today's Campus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chegg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Notehall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sean Conway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[study guides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[study notes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.edukwest.com/?p=6296</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Notehall stirred up some discussion around selling study notes yet managed to attract a growing audience of students and universities alike.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-6299" alt="Sean Conway Notehall" src="http://www.edukwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/todays-campus-7-sean-conway-notehall-pic-150x1501.jpg" width="150" height="150" />In this episode of the Today&#8217;s Campus Innovation Interview Series, I talk with Sean Conway, co-founder of Notehall.</p>
<p>A few years ago Notehall stirred up some discussion around the selling of study notes and guides yet managed to attract a growing audience of students and universities alike.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://blip.tv/play/hI85g43mSgA.x?p=1" height="366" width="600" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe><object style="display: none;" width="320" height="240" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="src" value="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g43mSgA" /><embed style="display: none;" width="320" height="240" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g43mSgA" /></object></p>
<p>The startup was then acquired by textbook rental juggernaut Chegg for an undisclosed sum. In the interview Sean talks about the reasons why he and his co-founders started Notehall when they were still in college, how they managed to grow the platform and how it might get integrated in the Chegg platform this year.</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/edukwest/~4/AII-S4y72wA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.edukwest.com/todays-campus-innovation-interview-7-sean-conway-of-notehall/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<media:content url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~5/nY8XFhk3auE/api.swf" fileSize="36" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" /><itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit><itunes:subtitle>Notehall stirred up some discussion around selling study notes yet managed to attract a growing audience of students and universities alike.</itunes:subtitle><itunes:summary>Notehall stirred up some discussion around selling study notes yet managed to attract a growing audience of students and universities alike.</itunes:summary><itunes:keywords>Today's Campus, chegg, Notehall, Sean Conway, study guides, study notes</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://www.edukwest.com/todays-campus-innovation-interview-7-sean-conway-of-notehall/</feedburner:origLink><enclosure url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~5/nY8XFhk3auE/api.swf" length="36" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" /><feedburner:origEnclosureLink>http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hI85g43mSgA</feedburner:origEnclosureLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>My radical 9th grade college idea</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/edukwest/~3/2BfDh4ztCgs/</link>
		<comments>http://www.edukwest.com/my-radical-9th-grade-college-idea/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 17:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Fahad Hassan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Op-Ed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college application]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[high school]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.edukwest.com/?p=6291</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here’s a radical idea – What if we had every 9th grader in America fill out a college application before they start high school?]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6293" alt="college" src="http://www.edukwest.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/college.jpg" width="600" height="234" /></p>
<p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>This article was first published on Fahad Hassan&#8217;s personal <a title="My radical 9th grade college idea" href="http://www.fahadhassan.com/2012/02/29/my-radical-9th-grade-college-idea/" target="_blank">blog</a>.</em></p>
<p>Here’s a radical idea – What if we had every 9th grader in America fill out a college application before they start high school? These applications are exactly what they’d see as juniors and seniors with one exception – they don’t actually get sent to the schools.</p>
<p>Sometimes we get caught up in all the numbers and statistics only to forget that life has a lot of simple answers waiting for us. My proposition for having every 9th grader fill out a college application started from a simple thought I myself had about high school: “If I only knew then, what I know now.” Haven’t you had this thought in your life at some point? Well, as adults we know the value of a higher education. We know that kids have extraordinary potential; now more than ever with all the tools and technology available for them; and we also know that most 14 year olds – no matter how polished or educated until that age – have no idea what the college process is really like. So why not give it to them? The application won’t obviously go out – but will simply be a “practice run” on what they’ll actually need to do towards the end of high school. An early guide, kick in the face – whatever you want to call it for every student entering high school with one objective in mind: continue your education in college with a mastery and understanding of this application process being your “golden ticket” out.</p>
<p>I’ve spent the past four years of my life working at an education company in Washington DC selling software to college admissions offices, so I’ve picked up a few tidbits about the college application process over the years. I’ve talked to and met with schools in places I didn’t even know had schools. Did you know there are over 4,000 Colleges and Universities in America and 20,000+ programs? I don’t believe for a second that there isn’t an option for every kid out there who truly wants to get a degree of higher learning in something; Heck a lot of schools now even allow you to “create” your own major!</p>
<p>If every high school freshman filled out a “practice” college application, I believe it will do the following:</p>
<p>1) Show them first hand what schools will ask of them throughout their high school career outside of the classroom (extra-curricular activities, sports, clubs, etc). I think this alone will help boost engagement and teach kids the value of a rounded experience in high school and that simply getting good grades isn’t everything or enough.</p>
<p>2) It will give them a better idea of what kind of grades their favorite schools tend to look for. I believe this will better motivate kids to achieve in the classroom because for the first time, they’ll have an exact goal to aim for. They’ll learn that not everyone can or needs to be a valedictorian or that every school requires a 4.0 to get accepted. I think most kids have a fear their grades aren’t good enough for college when most of them consistently show extraordinary capacity for academic success.</p>
<p>3) For the first time in their lives, it will give students a direct correlation between education and money. Yes money – not just a “job”. Most of us grew up being told, “Go to College and you’ll make more money”. Okay – but like most things teenagers hear, I think that goes in one ear and out the other. What if a freshman in high school could understand that a career in anthropology, technology, music, arts, dance, advertising, media, etc – all have a better start with a foundation in higher education. I bet most kids in high school have no clue how broad college is in terms of what it can offer.</p>
<p>I haven’t been able to find any statistical data or analysis on giving freshman a “college application” experience and then tracking that against a control group to see if their:</p>
<p>a) Performance academically over four years increases.</p>
<p>b) Their desire to attend and actually apply to college increases.</p>
<p>c) Their retention rates in college are higher because of the early path they started on.</p>
<p>d) They are less likely to commit crimes or go to prison.</p>
<p>e) They are more likely to have a social impact on society.</p>
<p>I’m willing to bet – a whole heck of a lot that if we continue to push students at a younger age with more information about their future – in lectures, charts – numbers – and statistics, it will only move the needle so far.</p>
<p>We need to let students discover all of this for themselves. They need to feel the impact of their future, before the future gets to them. Our job as education advocates, teachers, and “adults” is to use information and data to create better systems for students to adopt, try, and develop. Our job is not simply to feed kids data and information about their future and expect them to “understand” how they need to live their lives for success.</p>
<p>Let’s hand them the future – literally.</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/edukwest/~4/2BfDh4ztCgs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.edukwest.com/my-radical-9th-grade-college-idea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.edukwest.com/my-radical-9th-grade-college-idea/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	<media:rating>nonadult</media:rating></channel>
</rss>
