<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://dlisted.com" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Dlisted - Be Very Afraid</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Vanilla Gorilla Is Somebody&#039;s Husband For The Fourth Time </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/vanilla-gorilla-somebodys-husband-fourth-time</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;You&#039;d think that the only thing that would agree to marry&lt;b&gt; Jesse James&lt;/b&gt; would be a popped anal wart on an alley rat&#039;s ass (no offense to popped anal warts on an alley rat&#039;s ass), but he actually found a living, breathing human being who wants to call him her husband. &lt;b&gt;Vanilla Gorilla&lt;/b&gt; married billionaire shampoo and tequila heiress &lt;b&gt;Alexis DeJoria&lt;/b&gt; in Malibu on Sunday. Either Vanilla Gorilla seriously brainwashed a ho Nazi-style or Alexis just really wants to be married to a tattooed bag of dehydrated gorilla dingles who will keep her guessing. What I mean by that is Alexis will constantly ask herself, &quot;&lt;i&gt;I wonder what kind of STD Vanilla Gorilla&#039;s nomad dick will deliver to my coochie today&lt;/i&gt;?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20685016,00.html&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt; says that Vanilla Gorilla and Alexis DeJoria, who&#039;s also a drag racer, have only been bumping tattooed crotches for about 7 months. VG jumped on Alexis just a second after he broke up with &lt;b&gt;Kat Von D&lt;/b&gt;. VG and Alexis got married at the Malibu home of her dad &lt;b&gt;John Paul DeJoria&lt;/b&gt;, the co-founder of Paul Mitchell and Patron. VG&#039;s daughter Sunny was a flower girl along with Alexis&#039; daughter Bella. The flower girls wore Hitler Youth uniforms, the bride wore &lt;a href=&quot;http://abagond.files.wordpress.com/2008/07/swastika-dress.jpg&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the bride&#039;s family all wore tears on their faces, because they realized that they&#039;ll have to look at Vanilla Gorilla&#039;s punchable face every time they go to a family party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, VG better start stock piling and hiding as many cases of Patron as he can, because it&#039;s only a matter of time before his fourth marriage ends when Alexis catches his dick doing the Hitler salute right into the pussy of some down river skank. Speaking of down river skanks, let&#039;s all take this to remember VG&#039;s skankiest side piece &lt;b&gt;Bombshit McGee&lt;/b&gt;. Here&#039;s some pictures from last year of Bombshit getting her coochie warts burned and sawed off at the free clinic. Alexis, this is your future!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/vanilla-gorilla-somebodys-husband-fourth-time#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/368">Gold Diggers</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/gross">Gross</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/-not-going-end-well">This Is Not Going To End Well</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/trash">Trash</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/567">Vanilla Gorilla</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/63">Weddings</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 11:24:49 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49322 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Blue Ivy Carter Will Tower Over All Of Us </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/blue-ivy-carter-will-tower-over-all-us</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Soon, &lt;b&gt;Blue Ivy Carter &lt;/b&gt;will look down on us regular peons both figuratively and literally. As Beyonce and Blue Ivy Carter were walking to their SUV after having brunch at Buttermilk Channel in Brooklyn yesterday, someone was able to get a picture of the 14-month-old chosen one. They were able to take this picture right before Beyonce&#039;s bodyguards ordered them to bow down to the holy queens of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But seriously, there must be some serious kinds of growth hormones in the diamonds that Beyonce and &lt;b&gt;Jay-Z &lt;/b&gt;feeds Blue Ivy Carter, because that is one tall one year old. Blue Ivy&#039;s line on the growth chart is above Kevin Hart&#039;s, Tommy Girl&#039;s and Ryan Seacrest&#039;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It must be those Timbs. Those baby Timbs are so damn heavy that they&#039;re stretching out her legs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/p/XQxW_PR2Kf/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;http://bossip.com/747642/brooklyn-babe-blue-ivy-spotted-rockin-pig-tails-and-timbs-while-out-to-lunch-with-mommy-bey-in-nyc/&quot;&gt;Bossip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/blue-ivy-carter-will-tower-over-all-us#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/112">Beyonce</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/blue-ivy-carter">Blue Ivy Carter</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/well-damn">Well Damn</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 10:08:56 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49321 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The CAPTION THIS Contest WINNER For March 22nd! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/caption-contest-march-22nd</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Jessica Simpson has taken up art during her second pregnancy.&lt;br /&gt;
First up? A portrait of Joe, made entirely of Weight Watchers&#039; leftovers. - &lt;b&gt;Sugarcoatedbitch&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Runners-up:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The doctors warned Adrienne Maloof not to go in the sun or her new face would melt off and the old one would reemerge. - &lt;b&gt;daisy100&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bruce Willis should probably have taken a look at the script before he signed on to do the film &quot;Fry Hard.&quot; - &lt;b&gt;Detective_LaToya&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in zombie death, Richard Simmons is FAAAABULOUUUUS! - &lt;b&gt;Half.Mexican.Wonder&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://cheezburger.com/7124732160&quot;&gt;Picture Is Unrelated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/caption-contest-march-22nd#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/-caption-contest">The CAPTION THIS Contest</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 09:26:41 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49300 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Hot Slut Of The Day! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/hot-slut-day</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sunkist Fun Fruits Creme Supremes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/03/24/hot-sluts-day&quot;&gt;Tickle Trees&lt;/a&gt; need to slap me down and spit in my face, because in my ode to Sunkist Fun Fruits &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/03/24/hot-sluts-day&quot;&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, I completely forgot to mention and pay homage to Creme Supremes. Sunkist Fun Fruits Creme Supremes were the best kind of Sunkist Fun Fruits. They were like extra luxurious Fun Fruits, because they were dipped in yogurt and everything is better when it&#039;s dipped in white stuff. It was so decadent to me as a kid. If Fun Fruits were cubic zirconia, then Creme Supremes were diamonds. If Fun Fruits were a beige Buick, then Creme Supremes were a burgundy (or &quot;&lt;i&gt;maroon&lt;/i&gt;&quot; as us classy hos call it) Cadillac. If Fun Fruits were Krystle Carrington, then Creme Supremes were Alexis Carrington. They were &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; fancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they&#039;re also the best, because their tagline was: &quot;&lt;i&gt;We&#039;re covered with yogurt and filled with fun!&lt;/i&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If John Travolta and Tommy Girl killed 100 body thetans every time they said that line during a Scientology bath house orgy, they&#039;d be the queens of the world. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/hot-slut-day#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/hot-slut-day">Hot Slut of the Day</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 09:08:33 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49320 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Birthday Sluts</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/birthday-sluts-0</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/v8QvBUfpUQk?feature=player_detailpage&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cathy Dennis (44)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;Aly Michalka (24)&lt;br /&gt;
Ryan Lewis (25)&lt;br /&gt;
Jason Castro (26)&lt;br /&gt;
Katharine McPhee (29)&lt;br /&gt;
Sean Faris (31)&lt;br /&gt;
Danica Patrick (31)&lt;br /&gt;
Jenny Slate (31)&lt;br /&gt;
Lee Pace (34)&lt;br /&gt;
Édgar Ramírez (36)&lt;br /&gt;
Wladimir Klitschko (37)&lt;br /&gt;
Gigi Leung (37)&lt;br /&gt;
Melanie Blatt of All Saints (38)&lt;br /&gt;
Juvenile (38)&lt;br /&gt;
Lark Voorhies (39)&lt;br /&gt;
Sarah Jessica Parker (48)&lt;br /&gt;
Lisa Gay Hamilton (49)&lt;br /&gt;
Marcia Cross (51)&lt;br /&gt;
Brenda Strong (53)&lt;br /&gt;
Daniel Boulud (58)&lt;br /&gt;
Bonnie Bedlia (65)&lt;br /&gt;
Elton John (66)&lt;br /&gt;
Paul Michael Glaser (70)&lt;br /&gt;
Aretha Franklin (71)&lt;br /&gt;
Anita Bryant (73)&lt;br /&gt;
Gloria Steinem (79)&lt;br /&gt;
Gene Shalit (87)&lt;br /&gt;
Eileen Ford (91)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/birthday-sluts-0#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/birthday-sluts">Birthday Sluts</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 08:35:55 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49317 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Open Post: Hosted By A Cat Walking A Dog </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/24/open-post-hosted-cat-walking-dog</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/RnrCki4Cmzw?feature=player_embedded&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now here&#039;s the true definition of &quot;&lt;i&gt;pussy whipped&lt;/i&gt;.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the cats take over the world and make dogs their slaves, this is what it&#039;s going to look like. I bow down to our pussy overlords. But more importantly, where can I get a dog-walking cat, because I need one of those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/24/cat-walks-dog-home-on-leash_n_2944786.html?utm_hp_ref=comedy&quot;&gt;HuffPo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/24/open-post-hosted-cat-walking-dog#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/385">Open Post</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 19:06:23 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49319 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Now THIS Is Elegance At Its Finest </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/24/now-elegance-its-finest</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/03/24/class-leann-rimes-wearing-shiny-booty-shorts-and-ankle-booties-kids-baseball-game&quot;&gt;Falkor Rimes&lt;/a&gt; could learn a thing or five hundred from the silicone dragon flower &lt;b&gt;Jenna Jameson&lt;/b&gt;, because this is how a real, bona fide style icon wears vinyl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While looking like the queen of the Meth Face Prom, Jenna Jameson posed until she split a seam at her birthday party at Crazy Horse III in Las Vegas last night. I&#039;m trying to figure out what&#039;s the best part of this look:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) Jenna&#039;s bipolar titties. Jenna&#039;s right titty must be on downers, because it looks sad and it obviously wants to be alone. Jenna&#039;s left titty must be on uppers, because it looks like it&#039;s on cloud 9 and the king of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) Jenna&#039;s catsuit, which makes her look like a slutty black and white cookie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c) Jenna&#039;s exquisite, pristine and angelic white leather camel toe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d) Jenna&#039;s algae green hair color, which hos spend hours upon hours in the pool to get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e) All of the above!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is obviously e!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s more of Jenna looking like a methed-out, sun-damaged garden lizard trapped in a pile of seaweed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/24/now-elegance-its-finest#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/432">Elegance Has A Name</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/263">Jenna Jameson</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/mess">MESS!</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/143">Meth Faces</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 18:50:07 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49318 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>What In The Hell Kind Of GD Outfit Is This? </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/24/class-leann-rimes-wearing-shiny-booty-shorts-and-ankle-booties-kids-baseball-game</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Because &lt;b&gt;LeAnn Rimes&lt;/b&gt; thinks she&#039;s the sexy hot stepmom, she went to her stepson&#039;s baseball game yesterday dressed like a down-and-out train track whore on her day off. This outfit is a bigger mess than LeAnn&#039;s sanity. It doesn&#039;t really bother me that she wore skank shorts to a children&#039;s event, it bothers me that she wore those shorts with that sweater. Tacky!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, who wears that kind of sweater with shorty shorts usually worn by a go-go boy at a goth gay club? That shit doesn&#039;t go together. Either wear that sweater with white cotton coochie cutters and high heel Chucks or wear those plastic shorts with a latex bra and a velvet choker.&amp;nbsp;Poor boy had to try to hit the ball while his stepmom was sitting on the bleachers wearing the worst walk of shame outfit ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And did LeAnn screw with her mug again, because she&#039;s starting to look like a Dark Crystal pantyhose doll that got mangled in the wash.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/24/class-leann-rimes-wearing-shiny-booty-shorts-and-ankle-booties-kids-baseball-game#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/654">Eddie Cibrian</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/653">LeAnn Rimes</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/trash">Trash</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 16:37:30 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49316 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Lindsay Lohan Will Party In Brazil Before Going To Rehab </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/24/lindsay-lohan-will-party-brazil-going-rehab</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Before &lt;b&gt;Lindsay Lohan &lt;/b&gt;checks herself into lockdown rehab for 90 days, she&#039;s going to fly to Brazil to collect a six-figure check to pose and party at several events. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/24/lindsay-lohan-brazil-rehab/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; says that right after LiLo shoots a guest appearance on her sugar daddy&#039;s show &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Anger Management,&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; she&#039;s taking her freckled ass to South America. If the California Justice System really wants LiLo to serve that 90 days, they better attach a 6,000 mile-long leash on her ass, because something tells me bitch is going to predictably &quot;&lt;i&gt;lose&lt;/i&gt;&quot; her passport or she&#039;s going to marry a South American drug lord and stay down there forever. Brazil better close their doors to all things Lohan before they&#039;re stuck with her ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LiLo still owes the IRS over $100,000 and since they refused &lt;b&gt;White Oprah&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;offer to call it even in exchange for &lt;b&gt;Cody Lohan&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; internal organs, LiLo has to somehow come up with the money. Some source tells TMZ that LiLo made a six-figure deal with a clothing line to promote their shit in Brazil. LiLo leaves on Wednesday. Since TMZ&#039;s source&#039;s name probably rhymes with Vina Hohan, she&#039;s probably exaggerating as usual and by &quot;&lt;i&gt;six-figures&lt;/i&gt;&quot; she really means two 8-balls and a half bottle of gin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other LiLo news, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/23/lindsay-lohan-drinking-rehab/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; also says that even though she accepted 90 days in rehab, she doesn&#039;t think she has a problem with booze and keeps filling her body with the sweet nectar. LiLo was guzzling down vodka sodas just hours after she was sentenced to rehab and she&#039;s been partying ever since. On Friday night, LiLo and a friend showed up to a club called FLUXX in San Diego and sat at a VIP table. LiLo apparently didn&#039;t want to be seen, because she wore a hoodie sweatshirt and a cap. Several vodkas on the rocks made their way down LiLo&#039;s throat and she demanded that the server bring her vodka in a glass carafe, because she didn&#039;t want any booze bottles on the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TMZ also reports that a bear shit in the woods on Friday night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lindsay Lohan getting as much booze in her body as she can before she checks into rehab is about as surprising as me spending my Friday night drunkenly watching &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Showgirls&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; on Cinemax and reciting every single line. I can&#039;t do a lot of things while drunk (example: pee standing up), but I can perfectly recite every line in &lt;i&gt;Showgirls&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/24/lindsay-lohan-will-party-brazil-going-rehab#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/96">Drunks</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/duh">DUH</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/lindsay-lohan">Lindsay Lohan</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 15:40:18 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49315 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Um....</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/24/um</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Who knew that Doogie Howser was a gusher? If your eyes woke up this morning with a craving for a picture of &lt;b&gt;Neil Patrick Harris &lt;/b&gt;and&lt;b&gt; Sandra Bullock &lt;/b&gt;making terrifying O faces as a geyser of slimy goo shoots into the air, here you go, you sucio perv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually when &lt;b&gt;Kristen Stewart&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;hands are covered in slime, it&#039;s because she ran them through her hair. But yesterday, KStew got covered in Slimer&#039;s butt drool after she hugged Sandra Bullock and Neil Patrick Harris while accepting her award for Favorite Movie Actress at the Nickelodeon Kids&#039; Choice Awards in L.A. Yeah, the kids chose her as their favorite movie actress. This is why kids should never get a vote. And the Earth tipped a little to the side yesterday, because KStew gave her usual bitchface the day off and actually cracked a few smiles during the show. Nickelodeon must have stuffed the bongs in her dressing room with some serious good shit. Either that or that green&#039;s slime got some THC&amp;nbsp;in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#039;s a few more pictures from yesterday&#039;s KCAs. In order: Sandra Bullock, KStew and NPH (looking like Goop&#039;s colonic machine exploded all over them), Katy Perry, Selena Gomez, a greasy and knocked up Fergie Ferg, Ke$hit channeling &lt;i&gt;Dumb and Dumber &lt;/i&gt;with her brother, a domesticated Sasquatch, Dog Chapman with Beth Chapman and the Smith kids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/24/um#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/104">Award Shows</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/fergie">Fergie</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/486">Katy Perry</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/630">Ke$ha</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/khloe-kardashian">Khloe Kardashian</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/544">Kristen Stewart</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/663">Neil Patrick Harris</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/302">Sandra Bullock</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/734">Selena Gomez</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 14:41:39 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49314 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
