<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://dlisted.com" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Dlisted - Be Very Afraid</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Brangie Did Not Get Married </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/28/brangie-did-not-get-married</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly enough, all the Supreme Court Justices didn&#039;t stop the Prop 8 hearings yesterday to announce that after much consideration, they&#039;ve decided to overturn Prop 8 and also make marriage legal for everyone everywhere, because when it came down to it they realized that they really, really just want to see &lt;b&gt;Brad Pitt &lt;/b&gt;and &lt;b&gt;Angelina Jolie&lt;/b&gt; get married. But that didn&#039;t happen, so Brad and St. Angie are still the opposite of married.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;St. Angie graced the Congo with her holy presence a few days ago and when she got there, she wasn&#039;t wearing the huge 5,000-carat diamond engagement ring that is so damn expensive she could probably buy the entire Congo with it. Instead, St. Angie wore a demure gold wedding band, which made some hos start screaming about how she must&#039;ve gotten secret married to Brad Pitt. But no, she didn&#039;t. St. Angie left her Fortress of Solitude-sized ring at home, because wearing a diamond ring that big in the Congo is wrong for many reasons and because wearing a wedding band will get her a tabloid cover or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While serving up some &quot;&lt;i&gt;2008 Michael Jackson meets business woman Morticia Addams&lt;/i&gt;&quot; realness, Angie strolled through LAX yesterday and a mere mortal from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/27/angelina-jolie-ring-not-married-video/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; dared asked the human halo of infinite light if she got married. She spat out a &quot;&lt;i&gt;no&lt;/i&gt;.&quot; Then when he turned off the camera, she turned around, wrapped her zombie witch hands around his neck and swallowed his soul until all that was left of him was a pile of bone dust. That settles that!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/28/brangie-did-not-get-married#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/799">Angelina Jolie</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/brad-pitt">Brad Pitt</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/brangelina">Brangelina</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/370">Yeah Okay</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 10:35:38 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49371 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The CAPTION THIS Contest WINNERS For March 27th! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/caption-contest-march-27th</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Raging Stallion presents its President&#039;s Day collection -- Paul ReRear&#039;s Midnight Ride; Yankee Do-Hole and the Skin Flute Player; George Washington Crossing Del&#039;s Underwear; and Abra-Him Lincoln, and his 9&quot; Log -- just don&#039;t call it a &quot;Box Set&quot;, we&#039;re allergic to boxes. - &lt;b&gt;Strepsi&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Oh, you want an American &#039;flag&#039;. Nevermind.&quot; - Betsy Ross misunderstood on her first attempt. - &lt;b&gt;Homeless J&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Runners-up:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One look at the wallpaper selection and it was clear why Marcus Bachmann&#039;s gay conversion therapy clinic was a bust. - &lt;b&gt;H321&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. of Heyyyyyyyyyyy - &lt;b&gt;Trixster&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vivid paves the way for 4th of July fetish porn with the release of &quot;Foreplay, Foreskins, and Forefathers&quot;. - &lt;b&gt;perky&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://cheezburger.com/7165885184&quot;&gt;Picture Is Unrelated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/caption-contest-march-27th#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/-caption-contest">The CAPTION THIS Contest</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 09:45:02 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49364 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Hot Slut Of The Day! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/28/hot-slut-day</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Rollie EggMaster Egg Cooking System! &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making eggs is really, really hard (no, it really, really isn&#039;t). When you crack one open, the yolk flies everywhere (no, it doesn&#039;t) and afterward your kitchen counter and cooktop look like they were the scene of a messy, gross bukkake orgy with a bunch of hens. When you cook them on a pan, they fall apart and it gets so frustrating that you just break down on the floor, punch the kitchen cabinets and yell at everyone around you before running into your bedroom to soothe your nerves with a bottle vodka and a few dozen bong hits. That&#039;s why some of us are stoner drunks. Making eggs did that to us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the genius brains behind the &lt;a href=&quot;http://laughingsquid.com/the-rollie-eggmaster-cooking-system-makes-eggs-on-a-stick/&quot;&gt;Rollie EggMaster Egg Cooking System&lt;/a&gt; don&#039;t want you to have a nervous breakdown while making eggs, so they invented a plastic thermos that cooks eggs perfectly every single time! You just crack an egg into it and minutes later out will come some nasty shit that looks like a barf Churro or like a gigantic tampon (fun fact: Jon Hamm&#039;s piece has to use a tampon that size after she has sex with him. The things the Hammaconda does to her).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/1XILbEZlS0U?feature=player_embedded&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it also doubles as a ghetto, at-home insemination machine. Just pour a cup of potent sperm into it, wait a few minutes and out will come a jizz tampon. You know what to do next. OctoMom is calling in right now to ask them if they take WIC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getrollie.com/&quot;&gt;Laughing Squid&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/28/hot-slut-day#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/hot-slut-day">Hot Slut of the Day</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 09:40:13 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49370 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Birthday Sluts</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/28/birthday-sluts-1</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Duchess of Alba (87)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;Lady Gaga (27)&lt;br /&gt;
Julia Stiles (32)&lt;br /&gt;
Kate Gosselin (38)&lt;br /&gt;
Shanna Moakler (38)&lt;br /&gt;
Richard Kelly (38)&lt;br /&gt;
Mr. Cheeks (42)&lt;br /&gt;
Vince Vaughn (43)&lt;br /&gt;
Brett Ratner (44)&lt;br /&gt;
Cheryl &quot;Salt&quot; James (47)&lt;br /&gt;
Reba McEntire (58)&lt;br /&gt;
Dianne Weist (65)&lt;br /&gt;
Conchata Ferrell (70)&lt;br /&gt;
Mike Newell (71)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/28/birthday-sluts-1#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/birthday-sluts">Birthday Sluts</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 08:39:25 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49363 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>There Will Be No Senator Ashley Judd </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/there-will-be-no-senator-ashley-judd</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;After months and months of &lt;b&gt;Ashley Judd &lt;/b&gt;teasing that she might run for Senate in her home state of Kentucky, she &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AshleyJudd&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;a today that she&#039;s not running and if you want to see her in a political role, go see her as First Lady in that &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Olympus Has Fallen&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; mess. My fourth favorite Judd (after Naomi, Wynonna and Judd Nelson) wrote this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Dear Friends,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for these months of remarkable support &amp;amp; encouragement, for your voices, exhortations, &amp;amp; prayers. I have decided. After serious and thorough contemplation, I realize that my responsibilities &amp;amp; energy at this time need to be focused on my family. Regretfully, I am currently unable to consider a campaign for the Senate.  I have spoken to so many Kentuckians over these last few months who expressed their desire for a fighter for the people &amp;amp; new leader.  While that won&#039;t be me at this time, I will continue to work as hard as I can to ensure the needs of Kentucky families are met by returning this Senate seat to whom it rightfully belongs: the people &amp;amp; their needs, dreams, and great potential.  Thanks for even considering me as that person &amp;amp; know how much I love our Commonwealth. Thank you! Thank you for the outpouring of good wishes. Thanks for having so much confidence both in me &amp;amp; that we could work together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashley Judd is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/01/30/ashley-judd-and-her-hot-piece-husband-broke&quot;&gt;separated&lt;/a&gt; from her hot piece of a husband and she doesn&#039;t have any kids, so I&#039;m guessing that by &lt;i&gt;&quot;focused on my family&lt;/i&gt;&quot; she means that she&#039;s going to tell her inner thoughts to her therapy dog and get drunk in the front row at &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dancing in the Has-Beens &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;while watching Wynonna Judd. (Actually, all that sounds better than running for Senate.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything I know about the Fifth Amendment, I learned from &lt;i style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;Double Jeopardy,&lt;/i&gt; so Ashley Judd can continue to educate the masses about important politics stuff through her movies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/there-will-be-no-senator-ashley-judd#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/804">Ashley Judd</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 23:00:26 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49369 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>But Which One&#039;s The Top And Which One&#039;s The Bottom? </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/which-ones-top-and-which-ones-bottom</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;People&#039;s Sexiest Potato Alive 2012 &lt;b&gt;Channing Tatum &lt;/b&gt;tells &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/showbiz/4861538/channing-tatum-says-hed-have-sex-on-george-clooney.html&quot;&gt;The Sun&lt;/a&gt; that his dream man is People&#039;s Sexiest Man Alive 1997/2006&lt;b&gt; George Clooney &lt;/b&gt;and that he wants to make out with George&#039;s butt all night long. Whenever Channing is in a room with George, everybody else disappears, his body turns into a giant boner and all he sees is George&#039;s perfect face. Channing would leave his knocked up wife &lt;b&gt;Jenna Dananahwatever &lt;/b&gt;and his unborn baby for George. A stream of drool trickled out of Channing&#039;s mouth when he said this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“I’ve spent time with George Clooney and he’s the most interesting man on the planet. He can do it all. I guess what I’m saying is I’d have sex with him.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#039;s it? Channing Tatum can&#039;t say that he&#039;d bone George Clooney and leave out the most important details. Would they make out or just get right to it? Would they 69 or 88 or both? Would Channing make George slap him in the face with his peen? These are the details everybody (aka just me) wants to know. But more importantly, who&#039;d be the top and who&#039;d be the bottom?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#039;ve seen Channing Tatum&#039;s body rolls in that Magic Mike shit, so I&#039;d say he&#039;s the top. Then again, he seems like the sort of dude you&#039;d meet at a bar, peg as a total top, but then when you get to his apartment and make out for a bit, he excuses himself to freshen up in the bathroom. That totally means he&#039;s going to clean his butt out with a balloon enema. BOTTOM!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&#039;s George. That one&#039;s easy. George looks like he loves it most when his ass is up in the air and his teeth are biting down on a pillow. POWER BOTTOM!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what I&#039;m saying is that they&#039;d totally use a double-sided dildo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/which-ones-top-and-which-ones-bottom#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/channing-tatum">Channing Tatum</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/114">George Clooney</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 21:01:40 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49368 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Add &quot;Alleged Homewrecker&quot; To Lindsay Lohan&#039;s Illustrious Resume </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/add-alleged-homewrecker-lindsay-lohans-illustrious-resume</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lindsay Lohan&lt;/b&gt; is currently rubbing her cokey vag all over musician type &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eonline.com/news/401810/lindsay-lohan-s-boyfriend-avi-snow-opens-up-about-new-ladylove-quot-she-s-a-lot-of-fun-quot?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-topstories&amp;amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;amp;utm_campaign=rss_topstories&quot;&gt;Avi Snow &lt;/a&gt;(she would get it on a dude with the last name &quot;&lt;i&gt;Snow&lt;/i&gt;&quot;), but a few months ago she was apparently spreading her chocha queso on a dude who had a girlfriend of five years. The girlfriend &lt;b&gt;Aesha Waks &lt;/b&gt;(the girl on the left who sort of looks like she&#039;s made with half Olsen DNA and half Arquette DNA) tells &lt;a href=&quot;http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/03/lindsay-lohan-homewrecker-says-woman-lost-fiance/&quot;&gt;Star Magazine&lt;/a&gt; that her full-time, live-in piece&lt;b&gt; Liam McMullan&lt;/b&gt; (the dude in the middle who looks like the dandiest Slytherin you&#039;ve ever seen) left her after he hooked up with Lindsay Lohan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aesha said that Liam didn&#039;t spend Christmas with her and when she asked him about it he let her know that he spent Jesus&#039; birthday tangled up in Lindsay Lohan&#039;s pussy. Now, if you&#039;re dude tells you that he put his lips on LiLo&#039;s sex parts, you change the locks, forget he existed and rinse your ears out with bleach just in Lohan diseases are catchable through a phone call (it&#039;s more than possible). But Aesha didn&#039;t do any of that. She begged him to come back to her. If only dignity came in a pill, Aesha wouldn&#039;t have said any of this shit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“Lindsay destroyed my world. I am devastated and still love him, but he says he wants to be with her and save her. I was supposed to spend Christmas day with Liam and his family, but he cancelled. A few days later, Liam finally got in touch and said that he and Lindsay had formed a ‘deep spiritual relationship.’ He admitted that he had actually been with Lindsay on Christmas, lying in bed for hours together.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liam tells Star that he and Aesha were done before he got with LiLo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep spiritual relationship? Yeah, I&#039;ve had many of those. I&#039;ve had one with my a throw pillow after taking thirty too many bong hits. Deep spiritual relationship is just a fancy way of saying LiLo&#039;s got good coke. If your piece leaves you for Lindsay Lohan, it has nothing to do with you personally. Bitch just left your ass, because LiLo has better drugs than you. That&#039;s all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/add-alleged-homewrecker-lindsay-lohans-illustrious-resume#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/lindsay-lohan">Lindsay Lohan</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/536">Well Well Well</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 18:51:29 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49367 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Blind Items: I Guess, You Guess </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/blind-items-i-guess-you-guess</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;This female A list celebrity got into a knock down drag out fight with this C list celebrity after the C lister started doing coke on a private jet flight the two were sharing. The C lister didn&#039;t seem to care that she was doing it front of a publicist and the flight attendant. The two spent over an hour screaming at each other and it got to the point where the pilot said if they didn&#039;t stop he was going to land the plane. Huh. Kind of like when a dad pulls over the family truckster. Yeah, that last part is a clue, but has nothing to do with Vacation. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crazydaysandnights.net/2013/03/blind-item-6_27.html&quot;&gt;CDAN&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I guess the last clue means that they&#039;re related so I say it&#039;s either:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Jessica&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Asshole Simpson&lt;/b&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Beyonce&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Basement Baby&lt;/b&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hilary&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Haylie Duff&lt;/b&gt;? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Audrey&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Judy Landers&lt;/b&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#039;s probably not Beyonce and Basement Baby, because Beyonce makes Basement Baby fly Southwest. It&#039;s not Hilary and Haylie Duff, because Hilary has slid down the B list and is hanging on while her toe touches the C list. It&#039;s not Audrey and Judy Landers, because they&#039;re both sitting on top of the A list and they&#039;re too elegant to scream at each other. So my final guess is Jessica and Asshole. Chestica should shut her lips, because it&#039;s hard out there for a ho who&#039;s daddy is licking the b-holes of skinny twinks who look like her with shorter hair.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This A list rapper has been telling friends that he has made a serious mistake by getting involved with his girlfriend. He says that it has been nothing but drama and that he is bombarded by her family for requests to help them out and that he should be doing it out of the goodness of his heart. He has been spending a great deal of time alone or with his &quot;assistant,&quot; and doing a ton of coke. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crazydaysandnights.net/2013/03/blind-item-1_27.html&quot;&gt;CDAN&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Kanye&lt;/b&gt;? Asshole Simpson should start hitching rides on his jet instead of Jessica&#039;s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This almost A list celebrity/reality star should probably be worried because there are three women who have all banded together and are in the process of selling a joint story about the celebrity cheating on his A- list celebrity wife. The three are just the tip (Insert Office joke here). (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crazydaysandnights.net/2013/03/blind-item-5_27.html&quot;&gt;CDAN&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Keith Urban &lt;/b&gt;and&lt;b&gt; Nicole Kidman&lt;/b&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, there was a sweet and spicy little star of a television show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the week of the Grammys, she met a big rapper who was nominated for a major award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was married and a lot older than him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But they hooked up anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there is tape out there documenting the very special time they spent together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The End. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://blindgossip.com/?p=51918&quot;&gt;Blind Gossip&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Charo&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Rick Ross&lt;/b&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which troubled actress – who is now better know for her troubles with the law than any work she has done in years – was caught climbing out of a window of a Beverly Hills mansion after the house party got interrupted by the police?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The private party was assumed to be a ‘safe place’ to engage in illegal activities until the cops arrived after complaints about the noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The house was full of some of Los Angeles’ hardest-partying kids and even they were worried about the young star that certainly knows her way around a courtroom! (&lt;a href=&quot;http://naughtybutnicerob.com/climbed-out-of-the-window-when-police-arrived-at-party-guess-who/&quot;&gt;Naughty But Nice Rob&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;http://blindgossip.com/?p=51880&quot;&gt;Blind Gossip&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This is obviously about &lt;b&gt;Lindsay Lohan,&lt;/b&gt; but I don&#039;t know why she was running from the cops. Like they&#039;d really arrest her ass. If she snorted a line off of a baby&#039;s ass in front of a cop, the cop would probably say, &quot;&lt;i&gt;Let me hold that baby down for you, it&#039;s squirming around&lt;/i&gt;.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/blind-items-i-guess-you-guess#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/blind-items">Blind Items</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 17:42:20 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49366 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Afternoon Crumbs </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/afternoon-crumbs</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/PZLqDHzWptI?feature=player_embedded&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ryan Lochte&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; reality show is going to make &lt;i&gt;Jersey Shore &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;look like a Mensa orientation video -&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jezebel.com/5992604/the-ryan-lochte-reality-show-looks-amazing-if-you-like-amphibious-sex-idiots&quot;&gt;Jezebel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tom Hardy &lt;/b&gt;and his pit bull puppy should go on a double date with&lt;b&gt; Anderson Cooper&lt;/b&gt; and&lt;b&gt; Grumpy Cat&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laineygossip.com/Tom-Hardy-and-Noomi-Rapace-continue-to-torture-us-with-puppy-cuteness/26375&quot;&gt;Lainey Gossip &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If &lt;b&gt;Glimmer&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;She-Ra &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;went to a costume party as &lt;b&gt;Ozzy Osbourne&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://theberry.com/2013/03/26/todays-celebrity-rundown-14-photos-48/&quot;&gt;The Berry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If &lt;b&gt;Bo&lt;/b&gt; from &lt;i&gt;She-Ra&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; shaved his stache, lost 30 pounds, got Tupperware titties and posed in a bikini - &lt;a href=&quot;http://drunkenstepfather.com/2013/03/27/gretchen-rossi-bikinis-of-the-day#.UVNGu795iXI&quot;&gt;Drunken Stepfather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Justin Bieber&lt;/b&gt; is a spitter - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thesuperficial.com/justin-bieber-battery-neighbor-ferrari-100-mph-03-2013&quot;&gt;The Superficial&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BREAKING: Money-hongray fame fucker trying to shake down a money-hongray fame fucker - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.celebitchy.com/288558/kourtney_kardashians_old_lover_still_claims_he_could_be_mason_disicks_father/&quot;&gt;Celebitchy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Robin Thicke&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Pharrell&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; music video is filled with lady nips - (NSFW)&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://drunkenstepfather.com/2013/03/27/robin-thicke-featuring-emily-ratakowski-dancing-nude-is-the-music-video-of-the-day#.UVNGx795iXI&quot;&gt;Drunken Stepfather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jenna Wolfe&lt;/b&gt; is a gayelle! Jenna Wolfe has a partner! Jenna Wolfe is having a baby! - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.towleroad.com/2013/03/wolfe.html&quot;&gt;Towleroad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Dr. 90210 &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;being the consummate medical professional he is -&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hollywoodtuna.com/?p=91480&quot;&gt; Hollywood Tuna&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#039;m sorry, &lt;b&gt;Vanessa Hudgens&lt;/b&gt;, you can try to dress up your UGGs with unicorn jizz, but they&#039;re still UGGly - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popoholic.com/2013/03/27/vanessa-hudgens-works-up-a-sexy-sweat/&quot;&gt;Popoholic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Words I thought I&#039;d never type with one hand while pinching my nip with the other: Why, hello there, &lt;b&gt;Adam Brody&lt;/b&gt;... - &lt;a href=&quot;http://imnotobsessed.com/2013/03/27/adam-brody-l-a/&quot;&gt;I&#039;m Not Obsessed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s &lt;b&gt;Amy Smart&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;nipples for your Wednesday afternoon - &lt;a href=&quot;http://moejackson.com/2013/03/27/breaking-a-braless-amy-smart-hits-up-cafe-med-in-weho/&quot;&gt;Moe Jackson&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kendall Jenner&lt;/b&gt; is just as annoying and dumb as the other Kartrashians - &lt;a href=&quot;http://icydk.com/2013/03/27/kendall-jenner-im-constantly-criticized-for-being-too-skinny/&quot;&gt;ICYDK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#039;s all be jealous of &lt;b&gt;Sygmond The Grey&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; fleas, because they are living in luxury - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzfeed.com/erinlarosa/sygmond-the-grey-is-the-most-majestic-cat-youll-ever-gaze-up&quot;&gt;Buzzfeed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kate Upton&lt;/b&gt; makes nerd boners go soft by turning down that kid&#039;s invitation to prom - &lt;a href=&quot;http://idontlikeyouinthatway.com/2013/03/kate-upton-isnt-going-to-your-stupid-prom-nerd.html&quot;&gt;IDLYITW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like &lt;b&gt;Courteney Cox&lt;/b&gt; got a fresh layer of stretched Silly Putty glued to her face - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.justjared.com/2013/03/27/courteney-cox-thrilled-about-cougar-town-renewel/&quot;&gt;Just Jared&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What your end product would look like if your teacher asked you to make a diorama based on the theme &quot;&lt;i&gt;douche&lt;/i&gt;&quot; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omgblog.com/2013/03/omg_franco-files_3_james_franc.php&quot;&gt;OMG Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Marisa Zanuck&lt;/b&gt; got fired from &lt;i&gt;The Real Housewives of Beverly Hills&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.realitytea.com/2013/03/27/marisa-zanuck-says-good-bye-to-real-housewives-of-beverly-hills/&quot;&gt;Reality Tea&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kim Kardashian &lt;/b&gt;with mirror nipples - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popsugar.com/Kim-Kardashian-Baby-Bump-Pictures-NYC-28896140&quot;&gt;Popsugar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Oscar de la Renta&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; swollen bitch gene is still sore from &lt;b&gt;Michelle Obama&lt;/b&gt; slapping at it by not wearing his clothes - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crunktastical.net/2013/03/27/oscar-de-la-renta-shades-michelle-obama/&quot;&gt;Crunk + Disorderly&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/afternoon-crumbs#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/afternoon-crumbs">Afternoon Crumbs</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 16:06:34 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49365 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Open Post: Hosted By Courtney Stodden Wall &quot;Art&quot; </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/open-post-hosted-courtney-stodden-wall-art</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Since you can&#039;t resurrect Michelangelo from the dead to get him to paint a fresco mural on the beige wall in the living room of your condo, you should get the next most artistic thing: a life-size &lt;b&gt;Courtney Stodden&lt;/b&gt; wall sticker! I didn&#039;t even know shit like that existed, but it does. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eonline.com/news/401799/life-size-courtney-stodden-wall-art-is-now-available-yes-really?utm_source=eonline&amp;amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;amp;utm_campaign=imdb_topstories&quot;&gt;E!&lt;/a&gt; says that some store called &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.theblownup.com/collections/128252-all-products&quot;&gt;The Blown Up&lt;/a&gt; is selling $50 self-adhesive wall stickers of the porn iguana in various states of elegance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blown Up store doesn&#039;t say if these stickers are wipeable, but I&#039;m assuming they are, because they&#039;re going to be all the rage at every frat house glory hole. But you can also use these porn iguana wall stickers for other things too. You can use one as an alarm clock. Just stick it to your bedroom ceiling and when you open your eyes in the morning and stare at it, you&#039;ll jump out of your bed while screaming for Jesus. You can also stick one on your bathroom wall. It&#039;ll inspire you to scrub your skin off with a Chore Boy until you hit the bone. If you put one on your refrigerator, you&#039;ll never eat food again. It&#039;s the perfect diet tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just make sure you coat your wall with a thick layer of liquid antibiotics before you stick one on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I&#039;ll pass, but poke at me when a wipeable Prince Hot Ginge wall-sticker comes out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/27/open-post-hosted-courtney-stodden-wall-art#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/385">Open Post</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 14:58:55 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49362 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
