<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://dlisted.com" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Dlisted - Be Very Afraid</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Morrissey Is Probably Going To Retire Soon </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/morrissey-probably-going-retire-soon</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prince William&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Duchess Kate&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/2012/08/06/breaking-morrissey-still-hates-british-royals&quot;&gt;#1 fan&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;Morrissey&lt;/b&gt; is down and out in Mexico after he was rushed to the hospital with internal bleeding and stayed there for five weeks. Morrissey has been struck down with the sicks for a while now and he says he was recently hospitalized for five weeks because of a bleeding ulcer, pneumonia and a throat condition called Barrett&#039;s esophagus. Morrissey plans to rest in Mexico and he&#039;s considering retiring so he can focus on his true passion: being the head boss of a gum-selling ring in Tijuana. Morrissey was kind of born to yell at kids to sell more chicles on the streets of Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Morrissey isn&#039;t doing so well right now, he&#039;s canceled his entire North American tour and is thinking about ending his singing career. During an interview with Mexican radio station Reactor 105.7 (via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/morrissey-retiring-smiths-health-career_n_2931658.html&quot;&gt;HuffPo&lt;/a&gt;), they asked Morrissey if all these health problems are making him consider retirement and he said, &quot;&lt;i&gt;I have been cautioned to, but it&#039;s difficult for me because it&#039;s very ingrained in me. It almost became absurd the number of things that happened to me, but everything just attacked me at once. The double pneumonia -- everything was really a result of the fact I had lost so much blood, so the immune defenses were very, very low and couldn&#039;t cope with anything, so therefore the slightest gust of wind and I would have a terrible cold.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in Buckingham Palace, &lt;b&gt;THE QUEEN&lt;/b&gt; is softly caressing her corgis while a smug smile of victory appears on her face, because after weeks upon weeks of making one of her slaves (aka Fergie) sneak into Morrissey&#039;s kitchen to sprinkle arsenic powder on his uncooked quinoa and kale chips, her mission has finally been accomplished. Morrissey&#039;s cunt genes will really explode when he finds out that THE QUEEN bought that arsenic powder with her dole money. Bleehehehehehehhehe!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/morrissey-probably-going-retire-soon#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/673">Morrissey</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:31:58 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49295 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Eva Mendes And Rachel McAdams Are About To Do A Real-Life Duet Of &quot;The Boy Is Mine&quot; </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/eva-mendes-and-rachel-mcadams-are-about-do-real-life-duet-boy-mine</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;The extremely accurate and beacon of one hundred percent potent truthiness &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nowmagazine.co.uk/celebrity-news/543331/eva-mendes-rages-at-ryan-gosling-s-ex-rachel-mcadams-stay-away-from-my-man#image2&quot;&gt;Now Magazine&lt;/a&gt; says that &lt;b&gt;Eva Mendes&lt;/b&gt; has temporarily put aside her evil plan to take down the Power Rangers and is instead pointing her Orb of Doom at that Gosling-stealing, two-bit hussy whore &lt;b&gt;Rachel McAdams&lt;/b&gt;. A source (aka a drunk intern who also runs the We Hate Evil Menses Tumblr on the side) tells Now that ever since Rachel McAdams &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/02/27/rachel-mcadams-and-michael-sheen-broke-too&quot;&gt;broke up with&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;Michael Sheen&lt;/b&gt;, she&#039;s been wiping her heartbroken tears on the shoulder of her ex-piece &lt;b&gt;Ryan Gosling&lt;/b&gt;. Eva, whose right eyebrow always looks like it&#039;s in the &lt;i&gt;&quot;bitch, step back&lt;/i&gt;&quot; position, is really raising her eyebrow in the &quot;&lt;i&gt;bitch, step back&lt;/i&gt;&quot; position, because she wants Rachel McAdams to step away from her man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, Rachel and Ryan stayed friends and talked every now and again when she was with Michael Sheen, but now that she&#039;s single they&#039;ve been talking on the phone even more. The source said, &lt;i&gt;&quot;Rachel&#039;s always kept in touch with Ryan, but now that she&#039;s split with Michael, she&#039;s been calling him and using him as a shoulder to cry on. It hasn&#039;t gone down very well with Eva, to say the least, but Ryan wants to be there as a friend for his ex.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, since the LeAnn Rimes/Eddie Cibrian/Brandi Glanville feud is the bottom shelf version of the Angelina Jolie/Brad Pitt/Jennifer Aniston feud, we needed a middle shelf version too and here it is. This is something to keep hope alive for those McGosling fans who think &lt;i&gt;The Notebook&lt;/i&gt; is real-life and Ryan and Rachel will be sucking rain water off of each other&#039;s faces in the end. Ain&#039;t no love like Canadian love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shit probably isn&#039;t true, but it still makes for the perfect triangle. Rachel McAdams is a wholesome-looking white angel with golden hair like a melted halo and Eva looks like an 80s soap opera villainess who can steal your man and half of your company in one day. I mean, she even dresses like Alexis Carrington (see: pictures of her outside of Letterman below). So that is why I will always wear a Team Eva t-shirt from Kitson (do they still sell &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.monstersandcritics.com/people/news/article_8728.php/Aniston_versus_Jolie_T-shirts&quot;&gt;that shit&lt;/a&gt;?).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/eva-mendes-and-rachel-mcadams-are-about-do-real-life-duet-boy-mine#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/296">Eva Mendes</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/211">Rachel McAdams</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/312">Ryan Gosling</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/419">Why Are You Pulling My Dick?</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 10:39:47 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49294 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The CAPTION THIS Contest WINNER For March 21st! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/caption-contest-march-21st</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Pope Francis was shocked to discover that Benedict had left behind his very favorite footwear, Gucci Special Edition Ponteef heels. - &lt;b&gt;Dawn Davenport&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Runners-up:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Ahh, the new Jimmy Chews. - &lt;b&gt;RandéSleepover &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what happens when you kick Gary Busey in the face. - &lt;b&gt;Ikcor&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, Charlie Sheen, do hereby bequeath my remaining teeth to be commissioned into a custom pair of Ho shoes to be given to Lindsay Lohan as she will no doubt require my help long after I am gone. - &lt;b&gt;Trishee&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Suri&#039;s upcoming 6th Birthday, Tom has had a special pair of high heels made with the teeth of Sea Org slaves. - &lt;b&gt;RHONYC&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://tosh.comedycentral.com/blog/2013/03/21/gonna-snag-me-a-hot-dentist&quot;&gt;Tosh.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/caption-contest-march-21st#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/-caption-contest">The CAPTION THIS Contest</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 09:47:52 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49287 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Hot Slut Of The Day! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/hot-slut-day</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mood lipstick! &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you didn&#039;t wear a mood ring in the 80s, your finger skin would shrivel up and slip right off of the bone. Everybody wore one! So since mood shit was the shit in the 80s, some genius-brained inventor came up with mood lipstick. Mood lipstick came in non-traditional lipsticky colors like green, orange, blue, etc.. etc... The green one looks like something that would come out of a gremlin&#039;s dick when he gets horny, but when you smear it on your lips, it goes on clear and dries some different color like bright pink or Xtina red. It&#039;s magic for your lips! It&#039;s supposed to change color to fit your mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully for humanity and people who care about glamour, mood lipstick survived the 80s and still exists today, because I saw some for sale at a dollar store the other day. I played around with my cousin&#039;s mood lipstick a little bit when I was a kid, but that shit didn&#039;t work on me. It was totally jank. Every time I put it on, it turned my lips the color of molten charcoal. It was like the color of the dried dead souls that&#039;s stuck under Lucifer&#039;s fingernails. It&#039;s like that mood lipstick was trying to tell me that I&#039;m dead inside. Oh, wait...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/hot-slut-day#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/hot-slut-day">Hot Slut of the Day</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 09:43:26 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49293 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Birthday Sluts</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/birthday-sluts-0</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;William Shatner (82)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;Cody Gifford (23)&lt;br /&gt;
Mims (32)&lt;br /&gt;
Shannon Bex (33)&lt;br /&gt;
Reese Witherspoon (37)&lt;br /&gt;
Cole Hauser (38)&lt;br /&gt;
Elvis Stojko (41)&lt;br /&gt;
Guillermo Díaz (38)&lt;br /&gt;
Meghan Chavalier (44)&lt;br /&gt;
Matthew Modine (54)&lt;br /&gt;
Stephanie Mills (56)&lt;br /&gt;
Lena Olin (58)&lt;br /&gt;
Bob Costas (61)&lt;br /&gt;
Fanny Ardant (64)&lt;br /&gt;
Wolf Blitzer (65)&lt;br /&gt;
Andrew Lloyd Webber (65)&lt;br /&gt;
Stephen Sondheim (83)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/birthday-sluts-0#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/birthday-sluts">Birthday Sluts</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 08:34:59 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49288 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Presented Without Comment </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/presented-without-comment</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;via&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AmandaBynes/status/314906707929214976&quot;&gt; @amandabynes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; (Thanks to Isabelle for sending this in and giving me the image of a chalk outline around Amanda Bynes&#039; cooch) &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/presented-without-comment#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/amanda-bynes">Amanda Bynes</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/739">No Words Necessary</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 22:10:20 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49292 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The Original Aunt Viv Goes After Wendy Williams, Again </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/original-aunt-viv-goes-after-wendy-williams-again</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;I will never tell Aunt Viv the First from &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Fresh Prince of Bel Air&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; to kindly step away from her laptop or to turn off her recording device of choice, because when she yanks off a bitch&#039;s wig, she yanks so hard that it leaves a carpet burn on that bitch&#039;s forehead. &lt;b&gt;Janet Hubert &lt;/b&gt;already &lt;a href=&quot;http://necolebitchie.com/2012/02/22/janet-hubert-slams-wendy-williams-you-crucified-whitney-the-whole-time-she-was-alive/&quot;&gt;went after &lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;Wendy Williams&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;for dragging Whitney Houston when she was alive but turning into a puddle of sad tears and wet wig hair when she died. This time, Janet is grabbing the step stool and climbing up it to choke Wendy out, because Wendy brought up her name while talking to&lt;b&gt; Tatyana Ali &lt;/b&gt;o&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=Q0E2XxN0iCA&quot;&gt;n her show earlier this week&lt;/a&gt;. Wendy only asked Tatyana what happened to the first Aunt Viv, and I guess Janet didn&#039;t like that her name came out of Wendy&#039;s mouth, because she had some shit to say and then some on her &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Blog Talk Radio &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;show. Here&#039;s just a piece of the verbal slap down Aunt Viv laid down on Wendy, courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ronaldmatters.com/2013/03/aunt-viv-reads-wendy-williams-from-sea-to-shining-sea-again-audio.html#more-10054&quot;&gt;Ronald Matters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://theurbandaily.com/2149898/janet-hubert-writes-letter-to-wendy-williams-and-calls-her-a-demon/&quot;&gt;The Urban Daily&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Dear Wiggy, I’m sorry, Wendy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, you found the need to put an end to the mystery surrounding my departure from a show that I did so damn long ago that I don’t even remember why I departed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wendy Williams, or whatever you are supposed to be, I’m not quite sure. I’m writing you yet again, to appeal to your sense of womanhood or manhood as some suggest. Please close your mouth about things that you know nothing of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now perhaps other black women have allowed you to berate them and continued to support you in this manner of madness and rewarding hatefulness. So I sat there and watched you like some devilish sinkhole swallow up Tatyana Ali. You reduced her to a child sitting their tempting to keep some symbolism of dignity about her as you pried and invaded her life until you got what you wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are such a demon Wendy. You are wicked, awful, conniving, sinister, spiteful, jealous of every other woman. Simply put, Wendy you are a virus. You are not nor have you ever been a true woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just would like to know who died and told you that you were reborn as Oprah. You want to be Oprah so bad that you would kill for it and you will kill anyone to achieve success. Sister, you will never be another Oprah. Oprah lifted her audience up and exuded an air of class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you know what Wendy, you are not even in my league. It is so beneath me to even bother with someone like you, but you asked for it. You will not destroy all of the hard work that I went through for the last decade to clear my good name. I simply will not allow you to do so. I’m a lady and a real one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wendy girlfriend you just messed with the wrong sista.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here is my advice to you Wendy. Wipe your giant teeth off camera. Please put some sweat pits under your arms, and darling if your sweater is pulling until there are lines across your chest, its too tight. You might want to deflate those tremendous breast. Take off the fake blonde hair. You have to stop playing the race card because you are coming off like a wannabe white girl who will never be white.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I kind of feel sorry for you. You sit there on your big-footed tacky throne everyday while millions of people are laughing at you not with you. There is a big difference. Nobody cares about what you think about their lives. But we do care about what you put out there about us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart saddens at how women, especially black women, have embraced her evil after all of our struggles in society. You and your kind have set us back a hundred years or so. How dare you chastise anyone when you are such a travesty?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now take that, chew it my dear and stick it on your lord have mercy you are disgusting fly ridden gum wall. And that’s the advice I have for you my sister. Peace.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love how Wendy didn&#039;t even talk shit about Aunt Viv. All she did was say Aunt Viv&#039;s name and Janet Hubert still put a question mark over her crotch, called out her juicy pits and said she was a demon from hell. I swear, Aunt Viv acts like Wendy broke into her backyard, stole her dog, skinned it and is now wearing it as a wig. But I still love it when Aunt Viv loses whatever is left of her mind and goes off. Can somebody please lie to Aunt Viv 1.0 and tell her the Kardashians are smearing shit all over her good name, because I want to see her rip their faces off with her words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogtalkradio.com/speak-own-it/2013/03/20/janet-hubert-to-wendy-williamsagain&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to listen to Aunt Viv the First reading her letter out loud. Why isn&#039;t she on &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The View&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;?!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/original-aunt-viv-goes-after-wendy-williams-again#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/pure-poetry">Pure Poetry</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 21:25:16 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49291 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Joe Jonas&#039; Dildo-Filled Sex Tape Is Coming Out In April, Allegedly (UPDATE: Joe Denies It)</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/joe-jonas-dildo-filled-sex-tape-coming-out-april-allegedly</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;For about a week, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blindgossip.com/?p=51632&quot;&gt;Blind Gossip &lt;/a&gt;has had several blind items about a celebrity dude&#039;s girlfriend who tricked him into doing something that will make her a bigger star than she already is. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/03/15/blind-items-i-guess-you-guess&quot;&gt;I figured &lt;/a&gt;that &lt;b&gt;Stacy Keibler&lt;/b&gt; reversed &lt;b&gt;George Clooney&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; vasectomy in his sleep and then made a baby, but apparently it&#039;s way more escandaloso than that. &lt;a href=&quot;http://blindgossip.com/?p=51632&quot;&gt;Blind Gossip&lt;/a&gt; claims that all their blind items are really about a sex tape starring&lt;b&gt; Joe Jonas&lt;/b&gt; and his model piece &lt;b&gt;Blanda Eggenschwiler.&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;The most shocking part of all of this is that Joe Jonas (allegedly) touched an actual, real-life vagina on camera. The other shocking part of all of this is that Blanda Eggenschwiler is the name of a person and not the name of an otter in a Roald Dahl book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jonas Brothers are currently on tour in South America and Blind Gossip says that earlier this month at the Park Hotel in Buenos Aires, Joe and the fittingly-named Blanda made a fuck tape where they get drunk, smoke weed and he licks her coochie juices off of a dildo. They didn&#039;t just put a video camera on a tripod, either. Apparently, this was all planned out and they got their videographer friend to film them. Professional shit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The people who were in the room while the tape was being made were Joe, Blanda, and the photographer/videographer. The p/v is a friend of the couple, and was asked to shoot the video because they both trusted him. In addition to the video, he also took some very explicit nude  photos of the couple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the video, Joe and Blanda are sitting on the bed together. They are both drinking and smoking pot, and Blanda explains to Joe what she is going to do to him in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They proceed to engage in multiple sex acts utilizing a variety of sex toys, including a large dildo, a gag ball, and a slapper paddle. Joe participates willingly, but seems less sure of how to use the sex toys, as well as how they will be used on him. He does not enjoy being paddled. At one point he has had enough and cries “Owww! Don’t do that anymore!” Blanda is the more dominant one in the video. At one point she inserts the dildo inside of herself, orders Joe to “lick my pussy juice off of it,” and he complies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The couple is very vocal and there is a lot of overly dramatic screaming and moaning. The sex is explicit, and there are multiple close-up shots of Joe’s face, penis and testicles, as well as Blanda’s face, breasts, and vagina. In between sex acts, they consume shots of alcohol. The video looks as if it was shot over the course of several hours, and some scenes were shot multiple times, so we do not know which takes will appear in the final cut. Both Joe and Blanda start out sober but appear to be inebriated by the end of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blind Gossip says that for the past year, Joe Jonas has been all sad about his career and is drowning his sadness in booze and the bad shit. When he started dating Blanda, he started drinking and drugging even more. His family is trying to get him into rehab, but he keeps pulling a Lindsay Lohan by telling them he doesn&#039;t have a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, Blanda planned this whole sex tape thing, because she wants to become the next Kim Kardashian. She got the videographer, brought in the fuck toys and directed the whole thing. She has already cut a deal with a sex tape distributor and will take 35% of the profits. She&#039;s planning to dump Joe as soon as that shit comes out. The sex tape is supposed to come out April 3rd, but Blind Gossip thinks it could come out even sooner. Also, Blanda Egegwgegwbgwhatever has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/blandablanda/status/314054553328824320&quot;&gt;tweeting&lt;/a&gt; about how April 3rd is going to be her special day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The description of that fuck tape sounds like Joe Jonas fanfiction written 50 Shades of Grey-style. This all sounds like some elaborate April Fool&#039;s joke, but if a tape comes out of Joe holding onto his purity cock ring as his insane girlfriend does him with a strap-on while slapping his nalgas with a paddle, I will pull the drapes closed, call it a day and watch the hell out of that mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE&lt;/b&gt;: Joe Jonas&#039; spokeswhore tells &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/21/joe-jonas-no-sex-tape/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; that a sex tape doesn&#039;t exist and there&#039;s no way he could&#039;ve ever made one with Blanda Egegwwgwgwhatever, because he has never seen a vagina in person before!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/joe-jonas-dildo-filled-sex-tape-coming-out-april-allegedly#comments</comments>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:53:40 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49290 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Afternoon Crumbs </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/afternoon-crumbs</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;The ghost of &lt;b&gt;Lindsay Lohan&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; future and the ghost of what could&#039;ve been &lt;b&gt;Blake Lively&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;future hung out together last night and this is why L.A. is all out of vodka and the good shit today - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laineygossip.com/Mischa-Barton-and-Tara-Reid-has-beens-at-a-movie-premiere/26327&quot;&gt;Lainey Gossip&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;b&gt;Kim Kartrashian &lt;/b&gt;said during her deposition that she really loved&lt;b&gt; Kris Humphries&lt;/b&gt;, she really meant that she loved all the MONAY and attention marrying him would bring - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.celebitchy.com/287288/kim_kardashian_secretly_deposed_claimed_she_really_did_love_kris_humphries/&quot;&gt;Celebitchy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lindsay Lohan&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;attorney&#039;s son is also her part-time pimp - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thesuperficial.com/lindsay-lohan-mark-heller-son-hamptons-parties-03-2013&quot;&gt;The Superficial&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CNN should pair &lt;b&gt;Elisabeth Hasselcrack&lt;/b&gt; with&lt;b&gt; Nancy Grace &lt;/b&gt;so they can shriek at each other until the ozone layer bursts and ends our misery - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.towleroad.com/2013/03/elisabeth-hasselbeck-to-cnn.html&quot;&gt;Towleroad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Girls Aloud&lt;/b&gt; is over forever and ever - &lt;a href=&quot;http://drunkenstepfather.com/2013/03/21/girls-aloud-final-performance-of-the-day#.UUtlS6V5iXI&quot;&gt;Drunken Stepfather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ashley Benson &lt;/b&gt;carries a book and wears glasses so she can look as smart as her Mensa president boyfriend&lt;b&gt; James Franco&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hollywoodtuna.com/?p=91148&quot;&gt;Hollywood Tuna&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Caroline Manzo&lt;/b&gt; of &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Real Housewives of New Jersey&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; thinks that all men, including her husband, have wandering peens - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.realitytea.com/2013/03/21/caroline-manzo-promotes-new-book-acknowledges-albert-may-have-cheated-says-rhonj-is-tough-but-incredible/&quot;&gt;Reality Tea&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blood-drinking crazy from &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;My Strange Addiction&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; makes me miss the piss-drinking crazy from &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;My Strange Addiction&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://gawker.com/5991696/my-strange-addiction-features-blood+drinker-in-its-most-revolting-episode-ever&quot;&gt;Gawker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jimmy Fallon&lt;/b&gt; might replace&lt;b&gt; Jay Leno&lt;/b&gt; sometime in the far future - &lt;a href=&quot;http://icydk.com/2013/03/21/jimmy-fallon-to-replace-jay-leno-in-2014-excited/&quot;&gt;ICYDK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jamie Foxx&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; daughter is all grown up and looks like this in a bikini - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popoholic.com/2013/03/21/say-hello-to-jamie-foxxs-daughter-corinne-bishop-damn/&quot;&gt;Popoholic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hot pieces of the new &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;G.I. Joe &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;movie - &lt;a href=&quot;http://theberry.com/2013/03/21/meet-the-sexy-guys-of-g-i-joe-9-photos/&quot;&gt;The Berry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift &lt;/b&gt;has already chosen her next victim - &lt;a href=&quot;http://idontlikeyouinthatway.com/2013/03/breaking-taylor-swift-is-falling-fast-for-some-new-dude.html&quot;&gt;IDLYITW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Some actor type named &lt;b&gt;Álex González h&lt;/b&gt;as a peen and here it is - (NSFW) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omgblog.com/2013/03/omg_princess_and_the_peen_alex.php&quot;&gt;OMG Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to make wall-to-wall carpet out of &lt;b&gt;Damian Lewis&#039;&lt;/b&gt; hair - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.justjared.com/2013/03/21/damian-lewis-freedom-of-the-city-of-london-award-recipient/&quot;&gt;Just Jared&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ashton Kutcher &lt;/b&gt;is really some super genius who is fooling us all, FYI - &lt;a href=&quot;http://videogum.com/691232/what-is-supergenius-ashton-kutcher-plotting-against-us/behind-the-scenes/&quot;&gt;Videogum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BREAKING: &lt;b&gt;Ben Affleck&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; daughter got a haircut - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popsugar.com/Ben-Affleck-Seraphina-Brentwood-Pictures-28763333&quot;&gt;Popsugar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to slap myself for mistaking &lt;b&gt;Vanessa Hudgens&lt;/b&gt; for &lt;b&gt;Lisa Bonet&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://moejackson.com/2013/03/21/breaking-vanessa-hudgens-forgets-to-remove-tag-from-jeans-shakes-her-booty-for-jay-leno/&quot;&gt;Moe Jackson&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is &lt;b&gt;Kanye&lt;/b&gt; styling &lt;b&gt;Rob Kartrashian &lt;/b&gt;too? - &lt;a href=&quot;http://imnotobsessed.com/2013/03/21/rob-kardashian-partying-lamar-odom/&quot;&gt;I&#039;m Not Obsessed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/afternoon-crumbs#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/afternoon-crumbs">Afternoon Crumbs</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:59:40 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49289 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Dear Miley Cyrus, Now This Is How You Twerk </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/dear-miley-cyrus-now-how-you-twerk</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/KP9GmIKefL8?feature=player_detailpage&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/miley-cyrus-did-wop-two-minutes-and-i-watched-all-it&quot;&gt;Miley Cyrus&lt;/a&gt; needs to have a seat and take notes. Because you&#039;re not really twerking unless you&#039;re twerking in all the aisles at Walmart. I love an ass that can clap for itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crunktastical.net/2013/03/21/youtubes-serial-twerker-channel-worthy-subscription/&quot;&gt;Crunk + Disorderly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/dear-miley-cyrus-now-how-you-twerk#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/739">No Words Necessary</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 15:27:03 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49286 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
