<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://dlisted.com" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Dlisted - Be Very Afraid</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Open Post: Hosted By The True Queen Of Coachella</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/14/open-post-hosted-true-queen-coachella</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;The fake flower aisle at every Michael&#039;s is completely empty this weekend and that could mean only one things: It&#039;s that time for the annual Fake Flower Headbands and Jorts Convention (aka Coochella)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The largest gathering of jorts, next to a Cyrus family reunion, happened in Indio, CA this weekend and it brought out a million celebwhores since celebwhores can&#039;t resist an occasion to look a mess. Of course, international supermodel &lt;b&gt;Phoebe Price&lt;/b&gt; doesn&#039;t fall into the &quot;&lt;i&gt;mess&lt;/i&gt;&quot; category, because not only she was the most relevant celebrity there, but she was also the most gorgeous and kept it glamorous in a skirt made of denim spaghetti.&amp;nbsp;If you asked PP which bands she was there to see, she&#039;d probably say &quot;&lt;i&gt;They play music here?!&lt;/i&gt;&quot; but that&#039;s not why she was there.&amp;nbsp;PP was there, because Coachella was in need of her legendary seat filling skills. Or should I say, in need of her legendary patch of grass filling skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#039;s all the hos that PP put to shame this weekend: &lt;b&gt;Vanessa Hudgens&lt;/b&gt; (A BLOOMING MESS!), &lt;b&gt;ASkars&lt;/b&gt;, two hitchhiking hobos, &lt;b&gt;Basement Baby, Emma Roberts&lt;/b&gt; with &lt;b&gt;Evan Peters, Tater Head, Tallulah Willis,&lt;/b&gt; &lt;strike&gt;Verdine White&lt;/strike&gt; &lt;b&gt;Kelly Rowland, Kate Bosworth &lt;/b&gt;with &lt;b&gt;Michael Polish&lt;/b&gt;, some fourth-rate desert tramp, &lt;b&gt;Connor Cruise&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Rita Whora.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/14/open-post-hosted-true-queen-coachella#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/385">Open Post</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 15:58:05 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49571 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Hugh Jackman&#039;s Stalker Arrested For Throwing Her Chocha Hair At Him </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/14/stalker-throws-pubic-hair-at-hugh-jackman</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of us have wet dreams of throwing our pubic hair at&lt;b&gt; Hugh Jackman&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;face, but usually our crotches are still attached to that pubic hair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugh Jackmeoff was working out at NYC&#039;s Gotham Gym on Saturday morning when one of his crazy stalkers ran in, screamed &quot;&lt;i&gt;I love you!&lt;/i&gt;&quot; and threw a razor covered in her pussy fur at him. It&#039;s pretty surprising that Hugh didn&#039;t scream &quot;&lt;i&gt;I love you!&quot;&lt;/i&gt; back and hire her as his new beard, because I know I instantly fall in love with every crazy trick who throws pubes at me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nypost.com/p/news/local/manhattan/hugh_pubic_enemy_NsCZo3ohNZFoRarAghXk9H&quot;&gt;The New York Post &lt;/a&gt;says that 47-year-old&lt;b&gt; Kathleen Thurston&lt;/b&gt; was hysterically sobbing when she slipped passed the gym&#039;s check-in counter and ran to the area where the object of her stalking affection was. Kathleen reached into her waistband and Hugh thought she was going to pull out a gun, but she pulled out a&amp;nbsp;coochie hair-covered razor and threw it at him. One of the trainers grabbed her, threw her out of the gym and then called the cops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cops caught up with Kathleen a few blocks away and arrested her. Hugh told the cops that Kathleen has shown up to his home before and even trolled around his daughter&#039;s school. Kathleen has no criminal history and lives at a shelter for the mentally ill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Hugh Jackman gets the essence of Kathleen&#039;s dirty pubes off of his body by marinating in a tub full of boiled Purell for a few hours, he should look into getting something called a restraining order. And poor Kathleen. Everybody knows you&#039;re not supposed to throw your dirty crotch hair at the dude you love. That scares them off. You&#039;re supposed to knit them a nice pubic hair cozy for their peen. Some crazy hos just don&#039;t know...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#039;s Hugh walking around NYC with his wife the other day. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/14/stalker-throws-pubic-hair-at-hugh-jackman#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/366">Hugh Jackman</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 15:28:10 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49570 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Be Still My Heart: The Mysterious Beauty That Is Wendy Lynn </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/14/be-still-my-heart-mysterious-beauty-wendy-lynn</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;A photo agency&#039;s database is like an out-of-season garden. There&#039;s weeds, brown patches of grass and sad stretches of dirt everywhere, but if you keep looking your eyes will eventually land on a stunning and special flower. That&#039;s what happened to me when I was scrolling through a photo agency&#039;s database and landed on pictures of a beautiful, natural and always in season blond rose named &lt;b&gt;Wendy Lynn&lt;/b&gt;. The pictures of Wendy Lynn were taken at a cancer awareness event in Santa Monica on Tuesday night. Wendy Lynn is an exquisite goddess whose delicate face peeks out of a cloud of curly blond hair. She&#039;s the beauty that Loni Anderson longs to be. She&#039;s the love child of Elly May Clampett and a swan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The photo agency didn&#039;t have any information about Wendy Lynn besides her name. I had to know everything about her. I wanted to know how many men have fought for her honor? How many women have joined a convent, because they knew they couldn&#039;t compete with her? How many rose petals does she crush and smear all over her lips to get them looking so fresh and delicate (answer: none, her lips look like that naturally)? I needed to know everything about Wendy Lynn, because I planned to write another unauthorized biography about her. I say &quot;&lt;i&gt;another&lt;/i&gt;&quot; because a woman that fascinating and gorgeous has obviously been the subject of several unauthorized biographies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick Google search, led to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hissplendor.com/AboutUs.htm&quot;&gt;this Christian website&lt;/a&gt; that had a small blurb about Wendy Lynn Adams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
David and Wendy Adams were both privileged to be raised in Christian homes where Jesus Christ was Lord.  Our homes centered on the Bible and in the church.  Wendy’s dad was a pastor so she was ministering and singing since she was a young girl.  When she was 21 the TV show “Hee Haw” was starting and Wendy was chosen to be “Nurse Good-body” on what became the top show on TV.  She has had two of her own TV shows and traveled for years with her own groups.  In 1998 she was inducted into the Celebrity Hall of Fame.  For 11 years she fed the homeless and the children in the slums, ministering the gospel and helping them to get jobs and homes.  She is in demand ministering and singing all over the nation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked for clips from &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hee Haw&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; on YouTube to see the magnificent Wendy Lynn in action, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NRcDkX6Fuv8&quot;&gt;the only clip &lt;/a&gt;of Nurse Goodbody I found didn&#039;t star Wendy Lynn. It starred &lt;b&gt;Gunilla Hutton&lt;/b&gt; as Nurse Goodbody. I figured that maybe Wendy Lynn was the original Nurse Goodbody and she left Hee Haw, because her spectacular beauty made all the cameras burst. I kept Googling, but couldn&#039;t find anything that backed my guess up. Then my eyes landed on a post at&lt;a href=&quot;http://theprincessandthemoose.blogspot.com/2011/08/elvis-hee-haw.html&quot;&gt; Creating Balance &lt;/a&gt;from Judith who met Wendy Lynn at an event at Graceland. She was immediately hypnotized by Wendy Lynn&#039;s presence (who isn&#039;t?) and Wendy Lynn told her that she was Nurse Goodbody on Hee Haw. A couple of days later, Judith did a Google search and found out the same shit I found out: Wendy Lynn was never Nurse Goodbody!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I emailed a hee-haw expert that I found while searching, to ask her. She responded that Gunilla was the only Nurse Goodbody.  Hee Haw&#039;s 1st episode was in June of 1969. Gunilla first appeared in episode 13, in December of &#039;69. I checked the IMDB website, and there is no Wendy Lynn listed in any of the first 12 episodes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ms. Adams&#039; website says she was inducted into the Celebrity Hall of Fame in 1998. There is no such thing as a Celebrity Hall of Fame. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found only one other reference to this Wendy Adams as Nurse Goodbody on this site where it says that she was inducted into the Country Music Hall of Fame in 1998. But there were only four 1998 inductees. Two of them included Tammy Wynette and Elvis Presley. And I&#039;m pretty sure we did not meet Tammy Wynette on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site also gave a quote where Wendy claimed to be Elvis&#039; &quot;prayer partner&quot;.  Um, ok.  I&#039;ll give her that one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have honestly spent hours on this.  I can compare the feelings on this to when I found out there wasn&#039;t a Santa Claus, and when I found out Delilah was not in Memphis, but a syndicated show out of California.  (I&#039;m still not over that one)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I can&#039;t get over, is that she visited my home church several times during that week, introducing herself as Nurse Goodbody.  So this wasn&#039;t a one-time introduction, or encounter with her at Graceland.  She made this statement to a lot of people.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe she was a stand-in?  Maybe she was a back-up singer?  IDK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what I do know about Wendy Lynn is that she&#039;s a minister, tells everyone that she was Nurse Goodbody on Hee-Haw and is the most fascinating and gorgeous liar ever! &lt;b&gt;Barbara Walters &lt;/b&gt;needs to stop calling herself a journalist, because she failed as a journalist when she didn&#039;t make Wendy Lynn the Most Fascinating Person of Every Year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/14/be-still-my-heart-mysterious-beauty-wendy-lynn#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/and-we-pray">And We Pray</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/505">International Treasure</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 14:32:32 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49563 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Justin Bieber Hopes Anne Frank Would&#039;ve Been A Belieber </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/14/justin-bieber-hopes-anne-frank-wouldve-been-belieber</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;In &quot;&lt;i&gt;fuckery you just can&#039;t make up&lt;/i&gt;&quot; news, &lt;b&gt;Justin Bieber &lt;/b&gt;and some of his friends visited the Anne Frank House in Amsterdam last night and not only did the shit-brained fetus keep his sunglasses on in the museum (picture above), but he also vomited up pieces of his ego all over the museum&#039;s guestbook. After learning that Anne Frank hid in the attic for two years and was eventually captured by the Nazis and died in a concentration camp, the only question the Biebs asked was, &quot;&lt;i&gt;I wonder if she would&#039;ve been a Belieber&lt;/i&gt;?&quot;&amp;nbsp;Out of everything, that&#039;s what he got out of the Anne Frank Museum.&amp;nbsp;I just.... I don&#039;t.... I mean... I CAN&#039;T!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/annefrankhouse?fref=ts&amp;amp;rf=220532757961219&quot;&gt;The Anne Frank Museum Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; posted a transcription of what Justin Bieber wrote and it&#039;s the reason why humanity cries today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yesterday night Justin Bieber visited the Anne Frank House, together with his friends and guards. Fans were waiting outside to see a glimpse of him. He stayed more than an hour in the museum. In our guestbook he wrote: &quot;Truly inspiring to be able to come here. Anne was a great girl. Hopefully she would have been a belieber.&quot; Tonight Bieber will give a concert in Arnhem in the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, everybody knows that Anne Frank would&#039;ve been a One Direction fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another sad part of this is that the Beliebers probably don&#039;t even know who Anne Frank is and they&#039;re going to start sending her death threats on Twitter, because he gave her a shout out instead of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Justin Bieber accomplished the impossible by managing to out-Bieber himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/2013/04/14/showbiz/bieber-anne-frank/index.html?hpt=hp_t2&quot;&gt;CNN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/14/justin-bieber-hopes-anne-frank-wouldve-been-belieber#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/253">Dumb Bitch of the Day</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/571">Justin Bieber</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/310">Shut Your Hole</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 13:59:39 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49569 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Hot Slut Of The Day! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/14/hot-slut-day</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Ghost Of Witch McCoy from Scooby Doo! &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/04/12/rip-jonathan-winters&quot;&gt;The death of Jonathan Winters &lt;/a&gt;made me think about Scooby Doo, which made me think of all the Scooby Doo villains, because next to that hot bitch Daphne, the Scooby Doo villains were the hottest part of that mess of a cartoon. The one Scooby Doo villain I remember the most is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scoobydoo.wikia.com/wiki/Ghost_of_Witch_McCoy&quot;&gt;Ghost of Witch McCoy &lt;/a&gt;who the villagers believed held dark magic powers and could turns hos into frogs and could turn herself into a black cat. The Ghost of Witch McCoy turned out to be Aggie Wilkins and she wanted to scare the Hatfields away from their cabin, because her ex-man hid a treasure map in their cabin and she wanted to get to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many reasons for why the Ghost of Witch McCoy was everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ghost of Witch McCoy wore a sack dress that St. Angie Jolie wishes she owned. The Ghost of Witch McCoy wore a white wig that was almost as glorious as Emmylou Harris&#039; natural mane. The Ghost of Witch McCoy&#039;s claws were creeper than Madge&#039;s, her eyebrow game ruled the Ozarks and she was the original owner of the Voldemort nose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And during her episode, she crawled into bed with Scooby Doo. Kinky bitch!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/14/hot-slut-day#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/hot-slut-day">Hot Slut of the Day</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 12:58:13 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49568 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Birthday Sluts</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/13/birthday-sluts</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Adrien Brody (40)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;Abigail Breslin (17)&lt;br /&gt;
Nick Krause (21)&lt;br /&gt;
Win Butler (33)&lt;br /&gt;
Sarah Michelle Gellar (36)&lt;br /&gt;
Georgina Chapman (37)&lt;br /&gt;
Da Brat (39)&lt;br /&gt;
Anthony Michael Hall (45)&lt;br /&gt;
Robert Carlyle (52)&lt;br /&gt;
Brad Garrett (53)&lt;br /&gt;
Lothaire Bluteau (56)&lt;br /&gt;
Julie Christie (72)&lt;br /&gt;
Loretta Lynn (78)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/13/birthday-sluts#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/birthday-sluts">Birthday Sluts</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 11:37:01 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49567 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Lindsay Lohan And Adderall Shall Never Be Parted</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/13/lindsay-lohan-and-adderall-shall-never-be-parted</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lindsay Lohan&lt;/b&gt; is currently living out the best decision of her life (served in a bong made of sarcasm)&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2308569/Lindsay-Lohan-hits-Coachella-underage-brother-Cody.html?ito=feeds-newsxml&quot;&gt;by trolling around &lt;/a&gt;the current Ecstasy capital of the world Coachella and in a few weeks she&#039;ll have to shuffle her ass into &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/04/10/lindsay-lohan-will-spend-summer-hamptons&quot;&gt;court-ordered rehab in the Hamptons&lt;/a&gt;. Because LiLo can never make anything easy and can&#039;t breathe unless she&#039;s sticking a thorn into somebody&#039;s ass lips, she&#039;s going to give the rehab staff a hard time as soon as she walks through the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/13/lindsay-lohan-adderall-rehab-seafield-center-new-york/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; says that LiLo was under the impression that she can keep downing Adderall while in rehab, but that isn&#039;t the case. LiLo claims she has ADHD (in LiLo&#039;s case that stands for attention-loving delusional ho disorder) and has to take Adderall at all times. But TMZ is hearing that Seafield Center isn&#039;t going to allow it and will make her turn in all of her Adderall when she checks in. Some source says that the Seafield Center allows their patients to take meds prescribed by a doctor, but they&#039;re forever side-eyeing Adderall. They&#039;re apparently going to try to wean LiLo off of Adderall by giving her a substitute that&#039;s less addictive. LiLo is telling her friends that if they try to rip her Adderall from her cold, freckled, demon claws, she&#039;ll quit that bitch in a second. And if she quits that bitch in a second, off to jail she goes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, please, they&#039;re not going to take away her Adderall. This is LiLo we&#039;re talking about. Bitch rules the world. When she checks in, the staff will softly ask her, &quot;&lt;i&gt;Um, your HIGHness, do you think that we can take your, um, Add-&lt;/i&gt;&quot; She&#039;ll spit out &quot;&lt;i&gt;NO&lt;/i&gt;!&quot; they&#039;ll say &quot;&lt;i&gt;OK&lt;/i&gt;!&quot; and they&#039;ll give her all the Adderall she wants. They&#039;ll put an Adderall on her pillow during turn down service every night and they&#039;ll constantly fill the mint bowl in her room with Adderall. LiLo will start selling Adderall to the other patients and staff, and by the time she&#039;s out of there, everyone in there will be hooked on that shit! The makers of Adderall should really make that bitch a majority shareholder, because ho is keeping them in business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/13/lindsay-lohan-and-adderall-shall-never-be-parted#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/lindsay-lohan">Lindsay Lohan</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/mess">MESS!</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 13:58:31 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49566 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Hot Slut Of The Day! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/13/hot-slut-day</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/EmKLqfH_vsc?feature=player_embedded&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The half ginger-faced mama pussy who adopted a baby bunny rabbit. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my childhood cats was this wild ho who we found wandering in the hills. She was a true pussy of the wild and hated being inside. She was always outside and was always bringing us &quot;&lt;i&gt;presents&lt;/i&gt;.&quot; One time she dropped a rabbit head on our welcome mat and the first thing I looked for when I saw it was the gift receipt, because that was not a gift I wanted. So that was my introduction to pussy and bunny relations and it left a scare on my childhood. But now I can wipe away that scar thanks to this video of a half ginger-faced mama pussy giving some love to a baby bunny rabbit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope a follow-up video comes out in a few months, because I really want to see this baby bunny rabbit purr, meow, use the litter box, get high on cat nip and silently judge humans from afar. I fully embrace this pussy trapped in a bunny&#039;s body. It&#039;s a bussy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzfeed.com/nelly06/cat-adopts-baby-bunny-9dpe&quot;&gt;Buzzfeed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/13/hot-slut-day#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/hot-slut-day">Hot Slut of the Day</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 13:22:57 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49565 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Birthday Sluts</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/13/birthday-sluts-1</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rick Schroder (43)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;Nellie McKay (31)&lt;br /&gt;
Courtney Peldon (32)&lt;br /&gt;
Kyle Howard (35)&lt;br /&gt;
Lou Bega (38)&lt;br /&gt;
Caroline Rhea (49)&lt;br /&gt;
Max Weinberg (62)&lt;br /&gt;
Peabo Bryson (62)&lt;br /&gt;
Ron Perlman (63)&lt;br /&gt;
William Sadler (63)&lt;br /&gt;
Al Green (67)&lt;br /&gt;
Tony Dow (68)&lt;br /&gt;
Paul Sorvino (74)&lt;br /&gt;
Stanley Donen (89)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/13/birthday-sluts-1#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/birthday-sluts">Birthday Sluts</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 12:44:50 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49564 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Kim Kartrashian Wore This To Court Today </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/12/kim-kartrashian-wore-court-today</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Sadly for us, &lt;b&gt;Kim Kartrashian&lt;/b&gt; wasn&#039;t in kourt today to answer to her krimes against humanity. Kim was in court for a hearing in her never-ending divorce battle against Encino Man&#039;s slower&amp;nbsp;younger&amp;nbsp;brother&lt;b&gt; Kris Humphries&lt;/b&gt;. Kim and Kris were supposed to meet plastic face-to-caveman face today, but he got a severe case of the Lindsay Lohans and didn&#039;t show up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/12/kim-kardashian-kris-humphries-divorce-trial-court-no-show/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; says that Kris was stuck in New York for some reason (SPOILER ALERT: He forgot how to operate a door knob and just stayed in his apartment and stared at the door until someone came for him), so he never got on a plane to L.A. The judge wasn&#039;t happy about it and TMZ says he ripped Kris a new asshole (&quot;&lt;i&gt;Been there and Ray J&#039;s boomerang dick is to blame&lt;/i&gt;.&quot; - Kim). The judge set a new pre-trial hearing date for April 19th and he might throw a few fines at Kris for being late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/04/kim-kardashian-divorce-headed-trial-settlement-talks-fail/&quot;&gt;Radar&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;has a totally different story. They say that Kris wasn&#039;t in court today, because his team the Brooklyn Nets are playing the Indiana Pacers in Indianapolis and he was already excused. Radar also says that the trial will begin on May 6th and the court hasn&#039;t decided if cameras are allowed or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope there&#039;s going to be a sea of cameras in the court room. I really need to see smoke rise from Kris Humphries&#039; head when he&#039;s asked a question that has more than three words in it. And I really need to see a crack form in Kim&#039;s concrete forehead when she spits out a lie after she&#039;s asked if she faked her marriage for publicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And somewhere there&#039;s a sad, tacky, new money toddler who has to get a new first communion outfit, because this is what she was planning to wear. &lt;b&gt;Kim Kartrashian&lt;/b&gt; really does ruin everything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/12/kim-kartrashian-wore-court-today#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/fug">Fug</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/194">Kim Kardashian</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/kris-humphries">Kris Humphries</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 18:31:13 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49562 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
