<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://dlisted.com" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Dlisted - Be Very Afraid</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Easter Open Post: Hosted By Courtney Cottontail </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/easter-open-post-hosted-courtney-cottontail</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/2_3SPl071JY?feature=player_embedded&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s the porn iguana inhaling meth-laced baby carrots and wishing all of us a Hoppy Easter. Yes, Jesus came back to life for this. Hoppy Easter, I guess. But I really don&#039;t want to know where her crusty oatmeal-faced husband hid his eggs this year. No.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/easter-open-post-hosted-courtney-cottontail#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/385">Open Post</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 19:12:30 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49407 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Kirstie Alley Hates Abilify </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/kirstie-alley-hates-abilify</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/tGymr78FtbU?feature=player_detailpage&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientologists don&#039;t believe in anti-depressants, because when they want to get happy, they fuck themselves in the butt with an e-meter can while humming the theme to &lt;i&gt;Close Encounters of a Third Kind.&lt;/i&gt; So it&#039;s not exactly surprising that &lt;b&gt;Kirstie Alley&lt;/b&gt; is throwing ten balls of hate at the anti-depressant Abilify for using cartoons in their commercials. The Jabba the Hutt of Scientology spent yesterday and today ranting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kirstiealley&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; about how Abilify is targeting children by using cartoons. Kirstie may not have a PhD in pharmacology, but she has a PhD in batshit lunacy, so she definitely knows what she&#039;s talking about. Here&#039;s the truth according to Dr. Kirstie:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/files/images/kalleyabilify.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Kirstie is hating on a pill that claims to help with depression and yet she&#039;s the member of a &quot;&lt;i&gt;religion&lt;/i&gt;&quot; that claims to cure gayness? Oh, Kirstie, never stop being you. This bitch needs some Abilify. And you know, I think I&#039;d rather suffer from dizziness and have trouble swallowing (I can&#039;t believe I just typed that, my social life is ruined) than be a Scientologist. So Kirstie, you stay worshipping an alien god and we&#039;ll stay pilled up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/03/scientologist-kirstie-alley-slams-antidepressant-drug-advertising//&quot;&gt;Radar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/kirstie-alley-hates-abilify#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/251">Alien Voodoo</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/crazy">Crazy</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/564">Kirstie Alley</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 18:46:06 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49406 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The Time Freddie Mercury Dressed Princess Diana Up As A Man And Smuggled Her Into A Gay Club </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/time-freddie-mercury-dressed-princess-diana-man-and-smuggled-her-gay-club</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;I just want to hump that headline and cuddle with it afterward and I never want to cuddle after. I usually just want to drink tap water out of the bathroom faucet and then go and watch &lt;i&gt;Dateline&lt;/i&gt; re-runs in the other room, but not with this headline. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/31/freddie-mercury-princess-diana-gay-bar_n_2989139.html&quot;&gt;HuffPo&lt;/a&gt; says that in her new book&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt; The Power of Positive Drinking&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, comedian &lt;b&gt;Cleo Rocos&lt;/b&gt; writes about the time in the magical 80s when she, &lt;b&gt;Freddie Mercury a&lt;/b&gt;nd TV star&lt;b&gt; Kenny Everett &lt;/b&gt;dragged &lt;b&gt;Princess Diana&lt;/b&gt; up as a hot dude to sneak her into a gay club in London. They put her in an army jacket, sunglasses and a black cap, and snuck her into the Vauxhall Tavern in South London. Cleo writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;When we walked in ... we felt she was obviously Princess Diana and would be discovered at any minute. But people just seemed to blank her. She sort of disappeared. But she loved it. She did look like a beautiful young man. She was always a very fit girl, so they might have thought, &#039;There&#039;s a nice young man with pert buttocks.&#039;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That should be Disney&#039;s next cartoon movie. I really need to see a cartoon movie about a princess who escapes her life by dressing up like a twink bottom to go to gay clubs. Greenlight that shit now, Disney. But seriously, I will never forgive my parents. They should&#039;ve had me decades earlier and moved to London, so that I could&#039;ve gone to Vauxhall Tavern and hit on a dragged up Princess Diana. Because the next best thing to hitting on &lt;b&gt;Prince Hot Ginge&lt;/b&gt; at a gay club is hitting on a twinkified Princess Diana at a gay club.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/time-freddie-mercury-dressed-princess-diana-man-and-smuggled-her-gay-club#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/finally-some-good-news">Finally Some Good News</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/469">This Belongs In A Museum</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 17:53:33 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49404 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The End Of A Chav Era </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/end-chav-era</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Back when &lt;b&gt;Posh Beckham &lt;/b&gt;was the empress of the chavs with a complexion like a basketball and tits that looked like they were filled with more plastic than the ball pit at Chuck E. Cheese, she and &lt;b&gt;David Beckham&lt;/b&gt; bought a 1930s estate outside of London and called it Beckingham Palace. They&#039;ve had their fill of English country life and want to live in London now. They bought it in 1999 for £2.5 million and they put in a snooker room (Side note: No, a snooker room isn&#039;t an altar room dedicated to Snooki and it&#039;s not a room where you plan your schemes, it&#039;s a billiard room) and a recording studio. It was the headquarters of chavism and now Posh and Becks are selling it. Pour out a bottle of self-tanner on a bedazzled pink Razr phone, because it really is the end of an era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2301669/Beckingham-Palace-goes-sale-David-Victoria-eye-London-life--wont-allow-developers-buy-it.html&quot;&gt;The Daily Mail &lt;/a&gt;says that Posh and Becks are privately selling it for  £10 million. The DM&#039;s source says that not just any bitch can buy Beckingham Palace. Posh and Becks will only sell it to a family, because they don&#039;t want an investor turning their precious mansion into a condo building. The source said this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;They know there aren’t lots of individuals looking for houses of this size, and developers would jump at the chance to turn it into smaller flats, which would have added value because of the Beckham connection. But both David and Victoria spent years improving Rowneybury (aka Beckingham palace) and they’re prepared to wait for the right buyer who will continue their work, rather than someone looking to cash in on their name.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you have £10 million and really want to keep your batteries in the same freezer where Posh kept her soul frozen while she slept and you really want to cook bacon on the same cooktop where Posh didn&#039;t cook anything on, this is the country estate for you! Posh doesn&#039;t shit or piss since she gets rid of all the waste in her body by having it lipoed out while she sleeps in a steel coffin, so most of the toilets are barely used. That&#039;s a selling point! But you know what would really be a selling point? If that huge ass house came with Becks and a pair of chonies. The chonies aren&#039;t for him to wear. The chonies are for you to stuff into his mouth, because his voice ruins everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s Becks handling balls in Paris today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/end-chav-era#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/posh-becks">Posh &amp;amp; Becks</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 16:56:24 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49403 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>People Of Walmart: Our Lady Of Cheetos Edition </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/people-walmart-our-lady-cheetos-edition</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;While some of us were spending our Saturday afternoon trying to perfect the Easter Cadbury Creme Egg mojito (aka &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2299298/Creme-Egg-mojito-specially-prepared-Easter-containing-1-000-calories.html&quot;&gt;a tall drink of delicious barf&lt;/a&gt;) recipe we got from the gourmet journal The Daily Mail, &lt;b&gt;Brit Brit Spears &lt;/b&gt;was in Kentwood, LA steering her blue plastic and metal chariot through the aisles of the hillbilly Shangri-La that is Walmart. The People of Walmart disappoint me, because in every single one of these pictures, they should be bowing down and showering her with the coupons they cut out from the PennySaver, because this is their queen. Brit Brit dressed up for them and everything and they failed to pay tribute to her. For shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, that bruised and battered weave looks like it has more grease in it than the back of Matthew McConaughey&#039;s panties, but the worst part of this look is at the opposite end of her body. Brit Brit is always killing me softly with her UGGs. I am way too hungover and not daytime drunk enough to deal with that shit. I think those tin man UGGs gave me mercury poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/people-walmart-our-lady-cheetos-edition#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/272">Beautifulest</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/britney-spears">Britney Spears</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/432">Elegance Has A Name</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 15:55:19 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49402 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Hot Slut Of The Day! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/hot-slut-day</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sammy&lt;/b&gt; (as played by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0640413/?ref_=tt_cl_t10&quot;&gt;Kevin J. O&#039;Connor&lt;/a&gt;), Annelle&#039;s bunny suit-wearing piece from &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Steel Magnolias&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steel Magnolias has been on all weekend (actually, I&#039;m pretty sure Steel Magnolias is ALWAYS on, which is the way that it should be) and I&#039;ve been watching the Easter scenes over and over again. They should&#039;ve made a sequel out of the Easter scenes, because so much happens. Those dumb asses break all the Easter eggs in the car trunk, Clairee tells Shelby&#039;s kid &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WWrAvLJncWY&quot;&gt;a beautiful Easter story&lt;/a&gt;, Ouiser gets bitch slapped by a blond moppet, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V_2L3qbr5Hw&quot;&gt;Annelle&#039;s baby starts its long journey down her birthin&#039; canal &lt;/a&gt;and Sammy gets a ride to the hospital on the back of a motorcycle while wearing a bunny suit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next to Donnie Darko and the bunny in Fatal Attraction, Sammy is my favorite movie bunny rabbit. Usually, Easter Bunnies are nightmares covered in white fur, but there was nothing terrifying about Sammy&#039;s Easter Bunny. I mean, what&#039;s so horrifying about a broken down Easter Bunny who stumbled around like a zombie and had human hands instead of bunny hands? And are those leg warmers he&#039;s wearing? The most fashion-forward Easter Bunny ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Easter (or Zombie Jesus Day), everyone! Now, it&#039;s almost time for the Easter Buh-knee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/L4CcAo2yPWs?feature=player_detailpage&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/hot-slut-day#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/hot-slut-day">Hot Slut of the Day</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 13:54:13 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49401 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Birthday Sluts </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/birthday-sluts</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christopher Walken (70)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;Jessica Szohr (28)&lt;br /&gt;
Josh Saviano (37)&lt;br /&gt;
Ewan McGregor (42)&lt;br /&gt;
Samantha Brown (43)&lt;br /&gt;
Deborah Kara Unger (49)&lt;br /&gt;
Tony Cox (55)&lt;br /&gt;
Angus Young (58)&lt;br /&gt;
Al Gore (65)&lt;br /&gt;
Rhea Perlman (65)&lt;br /&gt;
Valerie Curtin (68)&lt;br /&gt;
Gabe Kaplan (68)&lt;br /&gt;
Richard Chamberlain (79)&lt;br /&gt;
Shirley Jones (79)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/31/birthday-sluts#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/birthday-sluts">Birthday Sluts</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 11:05:56 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49400 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Open Post: Hosted By Macaulay Culkin And Friend </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/30/open-post-hosted-macaulay-culkin-and-friend</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, &lt;b&gt;Macaulay Culkin&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/showbiz/4484302/Macaulay-looks-like-he-is-dying-of-some-disease-or-on-drugs.html&quot;&gt;was looking like&lt;/a&gt; a 75-year-old zombie version of Rickety Cricket from &lt;i&gt;It&#039;s Always Sunny &lt;/i&gt;and now here he is looking healthier in Paris last night. Macaulay and a hot, stached man friend hugged and kissed on each other while making cakes at the opening night of the 50th Foire du Trone. These pictures are several layers of what? I don&#039;t really know what&#039;s going on in these pictures, I don&#039;t know why Macaulay&#039;s man friend looks like he just inhaled a whole lot of dirty ass and I don&#039;t know how I feel about Macaulay looking like a skinny Tyler Durden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh whatever, I&#039;d still hit it. Hell, I&#039;d hit every single dude in every single one of these pictures, especially the dude in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/node/49399/images/spl516146_031.jpg&quot;&gt;this picture&lt;/a&gt; who looks like a wonk-eyed komodo dragon that&#039;s about to attack.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/30/open-post-hosted-macaulay-culkin-and-friend#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/385">Open Post</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 17:41:20 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49399 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>And Here&#039;s Your Weekend Dose Of Ass And Class </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/30/and-heres-your-weekend-dose-ass-and-class</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Your eyeballs are probably covered with a thick layer of crusty pieces of self-tanner, &lt;b&gt;Diddy&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; dried drool and Fashion Fair bronzer, and that could mean only one thing: it&#039;s &lt;b&gt;Aubrey O&#039;Day&lt;/b&gt;! When Aubrey &amp;nbsp;Ho&#039;DayandNight was fired from Diddy&#039;s harem of yodeling concubines, he probably thought that in 5 years she&#039;d be giving $2 daytime lap dances in the 40oz room of an illegal strip club on the outskirts of Tampa, FL. But Diddy was more than wrong, because here&#039;s Aubrey giving a nighttime lap dance at a casino burlesque show in Coconut Creek, FL. Diddy can smear it on Aubrey&#039;s ass and eat it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#039;s more of Aubrey popping her ass out in The Knockouts Burlesque Show at the Seminole Casino. I love how Aubrey usually has chichis all the way out when she&#039;s strolling down the streets, but she covers them up with a turtleneck when she&#039;s performing in a damn burlesque show. Aubrey&#039;s fresh petals are always full of surprises.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/30/and-heres-your-weekend-dose-ass-and-class#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/294">Aubrey O&amp;#039;Day</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/puts-assy-classy">Puts The Assy In Classy</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/slow-news-day">Slow News Day</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 17:13:39 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49398 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Madge&#039;s Homeless Brother Says That She Doesn&#039;t Give A Shit About Him </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/30/madges-homeless-brother-says-she-doesnt-give-shit-about-him</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Anthony Ciccone&lt;/b&gt; is back and he&#039;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/2011/10/23/madges-older-brother-homeless-and-living-under-bridge&quot;&gt;once again crying &lt;/a&gt;to the media about how his younger sister Madonna would rather gargle her coochie out with dirty hydrangea water than spend one second with him. Anthony is pretty much estranged from the entire Ciccone family and he says that they&#039;ve all turned their backs on him when he needed them most. Anthony has been living on the streets of Traverse City, Michigan for three years and he spends his day guzzling from a bottle of booze wrapped in a paper bag. Anthony did have a job at the Ciccone family vineyard, but he was fired for drinking the sweet nectar straight out of the vat and now he gets money by begging on the streets (and spilling the shit about his sister to tabloids).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2301196/As-Madonna-joins-billionaire-club-tragic-homeless-brother-says-She-doesnt-care-Im-dead-alive.html&quot;&gt;The Daily Mail &lt;/a&gt;caught up with Anthony Ciccone and they found out that his ass spent a month in jail after he was arrested for drunkenly yelling at kids in a church (that&#039;s my future). Anthony couldn&#039;t pay the fine, so they locked him up. Anthony tells the DM that even though his dad sometimes brings him leftovers, he thinks his father would be happy if he froze to death on the streets and he also said that his trillionaire sister can&#039;t be bothered with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;Madonna doesn’t give a shit if I’m dead or alive. She lives in her own world. I never loved her in the first place, she never loved me. We never loved each other. My father would be very happy if I died of hypothermia and then he would not have to worry about it anymore. He’s old school, he grew up in the depression. He doesn’t want to be bothered, he’s lived his life you see. He doesn’t like me. He doesn’t want me to be me, he wants me to be somebody else. He thinks the way I live is intentional. He simply doesn’t know me.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthony blamed the state of his life on his family. Anthony says that they aren&#039;t helping him and all he wants is a job. Apparently, Madge has paid for him to go to rehab several times. When the DM asked if he thinks he needs rehab, he farted out a Lohan-approved line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;I’m a human being, you can call me what you want. [Alcoholic] is a label, I don’t like it. I don’t need brain surgery, I merely need love and care of family and friends.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A worker at the Ciccone family vineyard told the DM that the family is afraid Anthony will really drink himself to death if they give him his job back. They&#039;ll only take him back if he quits the bottle for good. And Anthony ended the interview by saying that he doesn&#039;t think Madge owes him anything:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;Evidently various people have been pestering [Madonna] about matters of neglect regarding family and such. I think she&#039;s probably a little bit pissed off with me for even troubling her. But I&#039;ve never asked my sister for anything. She don&#039;t owe me nothing. That&#039;s her shit, man, she made her money, she worked for it, I&#039;ve got no beef. If she wants to live that way, that&#039;s her thing.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that ends our yearly visit with Anthony Ciccone. Till next year. You know, if Anthony Ciccone really wants to make some money, he should write a tell-all where he can spill all of Madge&#039;s childhood secrets and talk about what a bitch-hearted bitch-faced bitch she is. That shameless whore &lt;b&gt;Christopher Ciccone&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Life-Sister-Madonna-Christopher-Ciccone/dp/B002YX0G0K&quot;&gt; knows what I&#039;m talking about&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/30/madges-homeless-brother-says-she-doesnt-give-shit-about-him#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/madonna">Madonna</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/370">Yeah Okay</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 16:10:51 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49397 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
