<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://dlisted.com" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Dlisted - Be Very Afraid</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Birthday Sluts</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/17/birthday-sluts-0</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Posh Beckham (39)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;Rooney Mara (28)&lt;br /&gt;
Monet Mazur (37)&lt;br /&gt;
Jennifer Garner (41)&lt;br /&gt;
Claire Sweeney (42)&lt;br /&gt;
Redman (43)&lt;br /&gt;
Kimberly Elise (46)&lt;br /&gt;
Henry Ian Cusick (46)&lt;br /&gt;
Liz Phair (46)&lt;br /&gt;
William Mapother (48)&lt;br /&gt;
Maynard James Keenan (49)&lt;br /&gt;
Lela Rochon (49)&lt;br /&gt;
Sean Bean (54)&lt;br /&gt;
Nick Hornby (56)&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Rowdy&quot; Roddy Piper (59)&lt;br /&gt;
Olivia Hussey (62)&lt;br /&gt;
L. Scott Caldwell (63)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/17/birthday-sluts-0#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/birthday-sluts">Birthday Sluts</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 08:34:12 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49594 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Amanda Bynes Has A Friend.... That She Paid....To Be Her Friend</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/amanda-bynes-has-friend-she-paidto-be-her-friend</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;The time has possibly come for me to slide over to the side of the room that thinks &lt;b&gt;Amanda Bynes&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;has been trolling us all and the fuckery she&#039;s been bringing is all part of an elaborate performance art piece co-produced by MoMA or some shit. Amanda followed up &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/amanda-bynes-face-motion&quot;&gt;her nightmare-inducing primp video&lt;/a&gt; with a Tuesday afternoon stroll through NYC with her rent-a-friend. Even if I got high on whatever Amanda Bynes is getting high on, I couldn&#039;t make this mess up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paparazzi say that the blonde girl in the green jacket waited for Amanda in front of her apartment building and then the two fake laughed, fake talked and fake bonded the way all fake friends do. The two did this for a while before they walked to an ATM and Amanda took out some cash which she then gave to her rent-a-friend. The rent-a-friend then went on her way to her next rent-a-friend gig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#039;t even fucking know....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I thought blondie was Amanda&#039;s dealer, but what kind of dealer walks around with you in front of the paps? But then again, what kind of rent-a-friend doesn&#039;t ask for the money upfront, especially a professional friend who is dealing with Amanda Bynes? Amanda really needs to get her money back and leave a bad Yelp review, because that rent-a-friend did not do her job. Rent-a-friends don&#039;t let client friends do themselves up like a white trash Nicki Minaj. Rent-a-friends don&#039;t let client friends hire rent-a-friends to put on a show in front of the paps. Rent-a-friends don&#039;t let client friends paint a pair of lazy, busted down chola brows onto their face. And finally, rent-a-friends don&#039;t let client friends do crazy shit like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to hire a rent-a-friend to tell me what to think of this shit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/amanda-bynes-has-friend-she-paidto-be-her-friend#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/amanda-bynes">Amanda Bynes</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/693">Stunt Queens</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 23:35:50 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49598 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The Photoshop Awards: Tamara Ecclestone On Playboy </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/photoshop-awards-tamara-ecclestone-playboy</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Every line of code in every one of &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Playboy&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;copies of Photoshop is overworked and temporarily broken, because they slaved away on this cover starring Formula One heiress and&lt;b&gt; Bernie Ecclestone&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;daughter &lt;b&gt;Tamara Ecclestone&lt;/b&gt;. The cracked rhinestone that thinks she&#039;s a priceless diamond posed as a precious jewel on the cover of Playboy and she tells &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eonline.com/news/408338/tamara-ecclestone-poses-nude-for-playboy&quot;&gt;E!&lt;/a&gt; that she&#039;s so proud and honored to be one of the world&#039;s most beautiful women:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;I am so proud of this beautiful shoot. As a woman, I believe you have to embrace your body, and feel beautiful both inside and out!  Playboy is so iconic, and for nearly 60 years, the magazine has featured some of the world&#039;s most beautiful women in its pages. I am extremely honored to be part of this legacy as the magazine&#039;s May cover girl!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But are you &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; on the cover of a magazine if they Photoshop your face so much that it doesn&#039;t even look like you? It&#039;s like they erased all of Tamara&#039;s facial features and started again. On another note, I&#039;m mad at Playboy for not using a pun for their cover line. That cover line should&#039;ve been, &quot;&lt;i&gt;Yesterday, Today and Tamara!&quot;&lt;/i&gt; or &quot;&lt;i&gt;Tamara Never Comes!&lt;/i&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, I kind of like this 14k twat, because she&#039;s so damn bold. Tamara&#039;s sister &lt;b&gt;Petra&lt;/b&gt; spent $85 million of her trust fund on the Spelling mansion and so Tamara is trying to outdo that bitch. Tamara recently looked at a $95 million, 35,000 square foot mansion in Holmby Hills &lt;a href=&quot;http://la.curbed.com/archives/2013/04/ecclestones.php&quot;&gt;and she told her broker that it&#039;s &quot;&lt;i&gt;too small.&lt;/i&gt;&quot;&lt;/a&gt; Hahahaha. How can she act like a $95 million estate isn&#039;t good enough for her when her $2 tit job looks like it was done in a garage by a disgraced plastic surgeon whose license was revoked? But you know, a 35,000 square foot house is too small for her, because she&#039;s going to need more space to house all of her delusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s some pictures of a non-Photoshopped Tamara with her dude in Miami last month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/photoshop-awards-tamara-ecclestone-playboy#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/photoshop-awards">Photoshop Awards</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 20:48:11 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49597 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Robert Downey Jr. Will Win An Oscar One Day, So Says Robert Downey Jr. </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/robert-downey-jr-will-win-oscar-one-day-so-says-robert-downey-jr</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;While reading&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;Robert Downey Jr.&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; interview with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gq.com/entertainment/movies-and-tv/201305/robert-downey-jr-profile-may-2013?currentPage=6&quot;&gt;GQ&lt;/a&gt;, I learned that he made $50 million for &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Avengers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, always carries around a vial of antiparasitics (for when he&#039;s about to eat sushi or breathe in the same air as a Kardashian), has four alpacas and thinks he&#039;s one of the best actors around who will have his hands around Oscar&#039;s tiny ass cheeks one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess RDJ once said that he thinks he&#039;s always the most talented ho on the set, so GQ asked him if he really thinks that. RDJ said he did, but he also said that Hollywood is full of crap actors who have the emotional range of a dried up nipple pimple, so that&#039;s not saying much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;GQ&lt;/b&gt;: But I still believe that you think you&#039;re almost always the most talented person there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDJ&lt;/b&gt;: Yeah, but you know what? I&#039;m afraid that&#039;s just a tape that&#039;s running in my head, and I&#039;m really happy that it&#039;s there, but it doesn&#039;t make it real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GQ&lt;/b&gt;: And so if you stop that tape running for a second, how talented are you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDJ&lt;/b&gt;: I&#039;m probably one of the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GQ&lt;/b&gt;: That was you speaking, and not the tape?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDJ&lt;/b&gt;: Yeah. But it&#039;s not that big a deal. It&#039;s not like this is the greatest swath or generation of actors that has ever come down the pike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GQ&lt;/b&gt;: What are you bad at as an actor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDJ&lt;/b&gt;: Tons. Everything I avoid. I don&#039;t like opening doors and looking surprised. I can do all that emo stuff, but I&#039;m so over everyone who has to have a meltdown— everybody is emotional all the time. In movies people seem to be more emotional than they would ever be if that situation was actually happening to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RDJ was nominated for &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Chaplin&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; and he lost, which he says made him frown for a second. When he was nominated again for &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tropic Thunder&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, he knew he was going to lose, because he was up against &lt;b&gt;Heath Ledger&lt;/b&gt;. RDJ says he doesn&#039;t mind going to the Oscars and watching other hos win, because he knows it&#039;ll be his turn one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;GQ&lt;/b&gt;: How much would you like to win an Oscar?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDJ&lt;/b&gt;: I couldn&#039;t care less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GQ&lt;/b&gt;: Really?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDJ&lt;/b&gt;: Well, I know it&#039;s going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GQ&lt;/b&gt;: Is that the persona or the person speaking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDJ&lt;/b&gt;: That&#039;s just a fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GQ&lt;/b&gt;: You&#039;re certain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDJ&lt;/b&gt;: I, personally, would be shocked if we went to the end of the tape now and I didn&#039;t have at least one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GQ&lt;/b&gt;: Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDJ&lt;/b&gt;: Because it just doesn&#039;t make sense. That&#039;s why I don&#039;t mind showing up and watching everybody else get them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GQ&lt;/b&gt;: Why doesn&#039;t it make sense?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDJ&lt;/b&gt;: Because I&#039;m young enough, and I&#039;m running down being occupied with these kind of genre movies, close enough. Even the next thing we&#039;re doing with the missus, I&#039;m so confident about it. It&#039;s the best script the studio has; it&#039;s the best thing I&#039;ve read in years. You know, honestly, my real answer to that is: I don&#039;t care. I used to think I cared, and I couldn&#039;t care less. Now, I&#039;m not saying I wouldn&#039;t get a little choked up, but it is amazing to see how people are literally hyperventilating when they get up there, because they have such an attachment to this outcome. I mean, it&#039;s not like we&#039;re at the fucking Olympics or something. Look, even if I don&#039;t get one directly, eventually they&#039;re just going to have to give me one when I get old. So no matter how you slice it, I&#039;m getting one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;People are literally hyperventilating when they get up there...&quot;&lt;/i&gt; RDJ, I see you throwing a little shade at &lt;b&gt;GOOPY Paltrow &lt;/b&gt;for nearly hyperventilating out of her pink princess dress when she was an Oscar for being a pretty bland girl with famous parents. RDJ isn&#039;t telling any lies, though. He will win an Oscar one day and if he doesn&#039;t, somebody will win one for playing Robert Downey Jr. in The Robert Downey Jr. Story and I&#039;m sure they&#039;ll hyperventilate out of their panties when they win.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/robert-downey-jr-will-win-oscar-one-day-so-says-robert-downey-jr#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/robert-downey-jr">Robert Downey Jr.</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/536">Well Well Well</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 18:49:46 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49596 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Afternoon Crumbs </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/afternoon-crumbs</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Amanda Seyfried&#039;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;Allure photo shoot looks like cover pictures from a YA romance series about love on a horse ranch -&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popoholic.com/2013/04/16/amanda-seyfried-is-very-alluring-and-cleavagy-and-dreamy-and/&quot;&gt;Popoholic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Justin Timberlake&lt;/b&gt; and&lt;b&gt; Jessica Biel&lt;/b&gt; look like a couple of middle-aged, Volvo-driving suburbanites who only do it under the sheets with the lights on. In other words, they have never looked hotter -&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laineygossip.com/Justin-Timberlake-Jessica-Biel-golfing-Tennessee/26544&quot;&gt; Lainey Gossip&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#039;s not that &lt;b&gt;James Deen &lt;/b&gt;has a small peen, it&#039;s that &lt;b&gt;Teen Mom Farrah&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; vagina is as big as a power bottom&#039;s gaping b-hole after a fisting party - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thesuperficial.com/teen-mom-farrah-sex-tape-james-deen-04-2013&quot;&gt;The Superficial&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me fix that for you, &lt;b&gt;LeAnn&lt;/b&gt;... &quot;I&lt;i&gt;t&#039;s nice to have a husband who lies to your Falkor face all the time&lt;/i&gt;.&quot; There, much more truthiful! - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.celebitchy.com/292259/leann_rimes_its_nice_to_have_a_husband_who_tells_you_youre_beautiful_all_the_time/&quot;&gt;Celebitchy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A gorgeous beauty with an A+++++ eyebrow situation like that should be able to use whatever bathroom she wants - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.towleroad.com/2013/04/transgender-woman-banned-from-idaho-grocery-store-for-using-womens-bathroom.html&quot;&gt;Towleroad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The soft, yodeling bird girl from &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Nashville&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; is naked - &lt;a href=&quot;http://drunkenstepfather.com/2013/04/16/naya-rivera-jennifer-morrison-clare-bowen-christa-miller-nude-for-allure-of-the-day#.UW2voL95iXI&quot;&gt;Drunken Stepfather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am actually surprised that &lt;b&gt;Beyonce&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; delicate skin didn&#039;t fall off from putting H&amp;amp;M stuff on her body - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hollywoodtuna.com/?p=92675&quot;&gt;Hollywood Tuna&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talking dog is a traitor (or he&#039;s going undercover to find out the true secrets of the pussy community) - &lt;a href=&quot;http://jezebel.com/since-we-could-all-use-a-little-levity-right-now-here-473064772&quot;&gt;Jezebel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some celebrity pays their kids to eat and believe it or not that celebrity isn&#039;t GOOP! - &lt;a href=&quot;http://icydk.com/2013/04/16/heidi-klum-admits-she-pays-her-kids-to-eat-healthy-good-idea-or-wtf/&quot;&gt;ICYDK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Alison Brie&lt;/b&gt; impersonates the internet - &lt;a href=&quot;http://theberry.com/2013/04/16/alison-brie-imitates-popular-internet-memes-video/&quot;&gt;The Berry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bradley Cooper&lt;/b&gt; is living with his mom - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.justjared.com/2013/04/16/bradley-cooper-i-want-to-be-a-father-one-day/&quot;&gt;Just Jared&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes magical things happen at Walmart - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omgblog.com/2013/04/omg_first_off_sofia_the_first.php&quot;&gt;OMG Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But was &lt;b&gt;Kimmy Gibbler &lt;/b&gt;the flower girl? - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/jodie-sweetin-married-full-house-morty-coyle_n_3093757.html?utm_hp_ref=celebrity&quot;&gt;HuffPo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another day, another sex tape from some reality show trick - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.realitytea.com/2013/04/16/buckwilds-shae-bradley-confirms-sex-tape-with-jesse-j/&quot;&gt;Reality Tea&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Friends&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; reunion is happening in 2014 but probably not - &lt;a href=&quot;http://videogum.com/704222/the-friends-rumor-weve-all-been-waiting-for/tv/&quot;&gt;Videogum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translation: &lt;b&gt;Kanye&lt;/b&gt; hates &lt;b&gt;Kim&lt;/b&gt; (hey, that would be a great title for their reality show) - &lt;a href=&quot;http://idly.craveonline.com/2013/04/kanye-west-is-a-great-dad-so-far/?slide=1&quot;&gt;IDLYITW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy + paste peen into &lt;b&gt;Leonardo DiCaprio&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; right hand - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popsugar.com/Leonardo-DiCaprio-Esquire-May-2013-29484453&quot;&gt;Popsugar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;....and then &lt;b&gt;Katie Couric &lt;/b&gt;brought out the hymen cam - &lt;a href=&quot;http://seriouslyomg.com/?p=33151&quot;&gt;SOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pussy smoked the wrong stuff -&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hollywoodrag.com/index.php?/weblog/comments2/sox_the_self_aware_cat/&quot;&gt; Hollywood Rag &amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What these pictures are telling me is that &lt;b&gt;Tom Sturridge&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Sienna Miller &lt;/b&gt;went for a bike ride, got bored with that, dropped their bikes, left them there and then hailed a cab. Rich people! &amp;nbsp;- &lt;a href=&quot;http://imnotobsessed.com/2013/04/15/sienna-miller-tom-sturridge-enjoying-spring-weather/&quot;&gt;I&#039;m Not Obsessed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/afternoon-crumbs#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/afternoon-crumbs">Afternoon Crumbs</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 17:18:50 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49595 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The CAPTION THIS Contest For April 16th! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/caption-contest-april-16th</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://cheezburger.com/7335235328&quot;&gt;PIU&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/caption-contest-april-16th#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/-caption-contest">The CAPTION THIS Contest</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 15:50:18 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49593 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Open Post: Hosted By Jon Hamm On Sesame Street </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/open-post-hosted-jon-hamm-sesame-street</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/NCE0M-icUY0?feature=player_embedded&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jon Hamm&lt;/b&gt; was on &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sesame Street &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;and did a little skit with &lt;b&gt;Elmo&lt;/b&gt;. While Elmo chiseled a sculpture of himself, he made Jon Hamm show him sculpture after sculpture after sculpture. Yes, Elmo made a sculpture of himself. It&#039;s so obvious that this is a different Elmo. Because the Elmo we all know &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/topics/elmo-you-sick-bitch&quot;&gt;is a dirty, pervy trick&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and he would&#039;ve made a life-sized sculpture of The Hammaconda and he definitely would&#039;ve made Jon Hamm pose for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And why did they only shoot Jon Hamm from the chest up?! What are the drunk stay-at-home moms and dads supposed to look at?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://videogum.com/704261/requisite-posting-of-jon-hamm-on-sesame-street/cameos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Videogum+%28Videogum%29&quot;&gt;Videogum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/open-post-hosted-jon-hamm-sesame-street#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/385">Open Post</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 15:48:16 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49592 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Kat And Mau5 Are Going To Have An Underwater-Themed Wedding </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/kat-and-mau5-are-going-get-married-underwater</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;I guess &lt;b&gt;Kat Von D &lt;/b&gt;and &lt;b&gt;Deadmau5 &lt;/b&gt;are ignoring the health department&#039;s request and not getting married in a quarantine tent while officials in Hazmat suits spray them down with liquid antibiotics. Instead of doing that, Kat and Mau5 are planning on throwing an underwater-themed wedding. This is actually a good idea, because now their guests won&#039;t look too weird when they throw bacteria-killing chlorine bleach at them before hugging them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kat Von D tells &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20691311,00.html&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt; that on August 10th, she will become Deadmau5&#039;s future ex-wife during an underwater-themed wedding in front of 200 friends and family in Los Angeles. Kat says that she and Deadmau5 are really into the short story &lt;i&gt;The Call of Cthulhu,&lt;/i&gt; about an octopus human, so their wedding will feature all the creatures of the sea. They&#039;re going to have blue and green-colored food and performers dressed as mermaids. Kat also said that her dress is going to look like something the ocean threw up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;It will have a sleek silhouette and include hints of iridescent teals, blues and deep violet ombré gradients. I didn&#039;t know the dress was supposed to be a surprise.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kat and Mau5 both look like something rotten that a fisherman threw back into the ocean after it got caught in his net, so this underwater theme is perfect for them. I can already hear their guests let out an &quot;&lt;i&gt;awwww&lt;/i&gt;&quot; when Kat&#039;s crotch crabs come shuffling out in their bridesmaids dresses. I really hope that the front of their invitation has Deadmau5&#039;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/SRXwx.jpg&quot;&gt;octopus sex tattoo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on it, because that will set the tone for a day of true romance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s Kat wearing a zippered camel toe jumpsuit and alien heels to a book signing in NYC last night.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/kat-and-mau5-are-going-get-married-underwater#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/deadmau5">Deadmau5</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/330">Free Clinic Shit</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/664">Kat Von D</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 15:21:33 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49591 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Would You Hit It? </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/would-you-hit-it</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#039;s&lt;b&gt; Jamie Foxx &lt;/b&gt;looking like a cross between an overgrown Smurf on roids and a mutantized veiny Na&#039;vi peen while shooting scenes as Electro on the NYC set of &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Amazing Spider-Man 2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp;I should be offended on behalf of blue-Americans that the producers of &lt;i&gt;Spider-Man&lt;/i&gt; put Jamie Foxx in blueface instead of casting a naturally blue person, but I&#039;m too busy wishing that I had a lit anal bead-lined hoodie during my raver days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer own headline question, I should say &quot;&lt;i&gt;yes&lt;/i&gt;&quot; since Jamie Foxx sort of looks like Powder after a bukkake party with the Blue Man Group, but no, I wouldn&#039;t hit it. But only because when I look into his freezer burned eyes all I see is Nicole Kidman right after she gets out of her ice chamber in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/would-you-hit-it#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/426">Jamie Foxx</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/94">Would You Hit It?</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 14:07:51 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49590 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Ozzy Osbourne Fell Off The Wagon, But He&#039;s Not Getting a Divorce </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/ozzy-osbourne-fell-wagon-hes-not-getting-divorce</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the mound of rotten cottage cheese in my head farted up the image of &lt;b&gt;Ozzy Osbourne &lt;/b&gt;walking aimlessly in a circle with his dick in his hand for hours, because TMZ said that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/04/15/sharon-and-ozzy-osbourne-broke&quot;&gt;he&#039;s no longer living with Sharon Osbourne &lt;/a&gt;and how can he function without her ass?! TMZ said that Sharon and Ozzy are living in different places and not spending any time together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Sharon tried to&lt;a href=&quot;http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/04/sharon-osbourne-aimee-vacation-mexico-ozzy-relapse-denies-divorce/&quot;&gt; cure herself of the sads in Mehico&lt;/a&gt;, Ozzy wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ozzyosbourne/posts/10151607133627318&quot;&gt;Facebook letter &lt;/a&gt;to his family and fans where he said that his marriage isn&#039;t completely over, but he spent all of last year guzzling down booze and the bad shit, so he needs some time to get his shit right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
For the last year and a half I have been drinking and taking drugs. I was in a very dark place and was an asshole to the people I love most, my family. However, I am happy to say that I am now 44 days sober. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to set the record straight, Sharon and I are not divorcing. I’m just trying to be a better person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to apologize to Sharon, my family, my friends and my band mates for my insane behavior during this period………and my fans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God Bless,&lt;br /&gt;
Ozzy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ozzy and Sharon have been married for a million years and they&#039;ve probably been through this a million times before. Ozzy gobbles down the bad shit, gets messed up, bites off at an animal&#039;s head, gets in a mumble fight with the air, Sharon leaves, Ozzy gets clean, Sharon comes back, etc... etc... I&#039;ll bet my entire collection of anal beads that they&#039;ll get back together. Ozzy should hope that they get back together before &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.billboard.com/articles/news/1557492/black-sabbath-announce-north-american-tour-dates-for-13&quot;&gt;Black Sabbath&#039;s tour &lt;/a&gt;starts in August, because he&#039;s going to need her ass. I don&#039;t know how Ozzy is going to walk on stage let alone perform for thousands of people. They should use a hologram.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/16/ozzy-osbourne-fell-wagon-hes-not-getting-divorce#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/729">Ozzy Osbourne</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/159">Sharon Osbourne</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 12:28:11 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49589 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
