<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://dlisted.com" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Dlisted - Be Very Afraid</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Joe Jonas&#039; Dildo-Filled Sex Tape Is Coming Out In April, Allegedly (UPDATE: Joe Denies It)</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/joe-jonas-dildo-filled-sex-tape-coming-out-april-allegedly</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;For about a week, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blindgossip.com/?p=51632&quot;&gt;Blind Gossip &lt;/a&gt;has had several blind items about a celebrity dude&#039;s girlfriend who tricked him into doing something that will make her a bigger star than she already is. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/03/15/blind-items-i-guess-you-guess&quot;&gt;I figured &lt;/a&gt;that &lt;b&gt;Stacy Keibler&lt;/b&gt; reversed &lt;b&gt;George Clooney&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; vasectomy in his sleep and then made a baby, but apparently it&#039;s way more escandaloso than that. &lt;a href=&quot;http://blindgossip.com/?p=51632&quot;&gt;Blind Gossip&lt;/a&gt; claims that all their blind items are really about a sex tape starring&lt;b&gt; Joe Jonas&lt;/b&gt; and his model piece &lt;b&gt;Blanda Eggenschwiler.&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;The most shocking part of all of this is that Joe Jonas (allegedly) touched an actual, real-life vagina on camera. The other shocking part of all of this is that Blanda Eggenschwiler is the name of a person and not the name of an otter in a Roald Dahl book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jonas Brothers are currently on tour in South America and Blind Gossip says that earlier this month at the Park Hotel in Buenos Aires, Joe and the fittingly-named Blanda made a fuck tape where they get drunk, smoke weed and he licks her coochie juices off of a dildo. They didn&#039;t just put a video camera on a tripod, either. Apparently, this was all planned out and they got their videographer friend to film them. Professional shit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The people who were in the room while the tape was being made were Joe, Blanda, and the photographer/videographer. The p/v is a friend of the couple, and was asked to shoot the video because they both trusted him. In addition to the video, he also took some very explicit nude  photos of the couple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the video, Joe and Blanda are sitting on the bed together. They are both drinking and smoking pot, and Blanda explains to Joe what she is going to do to him in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They proceed to engage in multiple sex acts utilizing a variety of sex toys, including a large dildo, a gag ball, and a slapper paddle. Joe participates willingly, but seems less sure of how to use the sex toys, as well as how they will be used on him. He does not enjoy being paddled. At one point he has had enough and cries “Owww! Don’t do that anymore!” Blanda is the more dominant one in the video. At one point she inserts the dildo inside of herself, orders Joe to “lick my pussy juice off of it,” and he complies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The couple is very vocal and there is a lot of overly dramatic screaming and moaning. The sex is explicit, and there are multiple close-up shots of Joe’s face, penis and testicles, as well as Blanda’s face, breasts, and vagina. In between sex acts, they consume shots of alcohol. The video looks as if it was shot over the course of several hours, and some scenes were shot multiple times, so we do not know which takes will appear in the final cut. Both Joe and Blanda start out sober but appear to be inebriated by the end of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blind Gossip says that for the past year, Joe Jonas has been all sad about his career and is drowning his sadness in booze and the bad shit. When he started dating Blanda, he started drinking and drugging even more. His family is trying to get him into rehab, but he keeps pulling a Lindsay Lohan by telling them he doesn&#039;t have a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, Blanda planned this whole sex tape thing, because she wants to become the next Kim Kardashian. She got the videographer, brought in the fuck toys and directed the whole thing. She has already cut a deal with a sex tape distributor and will take 35% of the profits. She&#039;s planning to dump Joe as soon as that shit comes out. The sex tape is supposed to come out April 3rd, but Blind Gossip thinks it could come out even sooner. Also, Blanda Egegwgegwbgwhatever has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/blandablanda/status/314054553328824320&quot;&gt;tweeting&lt;/a&gt; about how April 3rd is going to be her special day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The description of that fuck tape sounds like Joe Jonas fanfiction written 50 Shades of Grey-style. This all sounds like some elaborate April Fool&#039;s joke, but if a tape comes out of Joe holding onto his purity cock ring as his insane girlfriend does him with a strap-on while slapping his nalgas with a paddle, I will pull the drapes closed, call it a day and watch the hell out of that mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE&lt;/b&gt;: Joe Jonas&#039; spokeswhore tells &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/21/joe-jonas-no-sex-tape/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; that a sex tape doesn&#039;t exist and there&#039;s no way he could&#039;ve ever made one with Blanda Egegwwgwgwhatever, because he has never seen a vagina in person before!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/joe-jonas-dildo-filled-sex-tape-coming-out-april-allegedly#comments</comments>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:53:40 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49290 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Afternoon Crumbs </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/afternoon-crumbs</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;The ghost of &lt;b&gt;Lindsay Lohan&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; future and the ghost of what could&#039;ve been &lt;b&gt;Blake Lively&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;future hung out together last night and this is why L.A. is all out of vodka and the good shit today - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laineygossip.com/Mischa-Barton-and-Tara-Reid-has-beens-at-a-movie-premiere/26327&quot;&gt;Lainey Gossip&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;b&gt;Kim Kartrashian &lt;/b&gt;said during her deposition that she really loved&lt;b&gt; Kris Humphries&lt;/b&gt;, she really meant that she loved all the MONAY and attention marrying him would bring - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.celebitchy.com/287288/kim_kardashian_secretly_deposed_claimed_she_really_did_love_kris_humphries/&quot;&gt;Celebitchy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lindsay Lohan&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;attorney&#039;s son is also her part-time pimp - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thesuperficial.com/lindsay-lohan-mark-heller-son-hamptons-parties-03-2013&quot;&gt;The Superficial&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CNN should pair &lt;b&gt;Elisabeth Hasselcrack&lt;/b&gt; with&lt;b&gt; Nancy Grace &lt;/b&gt;so they can shriek at each other until the ozone layer bursts and ends our misery - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.towleroad.com/2013/03/elisabeth-hasselbeck-to-cnn.html&quot;&gt;Towleroad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Girls Aloud&lt;/b&gt; is over forever and ever - &lt;a href=&quot;http://drunkenstepfather.com/2013/03/21/girls-aloud-final-performance-of-the-day#.UUtlS6V5iXI&quot;&gt;Drunken Stepfather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ashley Benson &lt;/b&gt;carries a book and wears glasses so she can look as smart as her Mensa president boyfriend&lt;b&gt; James Franco&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hollywoodtuna.com/?p=91148&quot;&gt;Hollywood Tuna&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Caroline Manzo&lt;/b&gt; of &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Real Housewives of New Jersey&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; thinks that all men, including her husband, have wandering peens - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.realitytea.com/2013/03/21/caroline-manzo-promotes-new-book-acknowledges-albert-may-have-cheated-says-rhonj-is-tough-but-incredible/&quot;&gt;Reality Tea&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blood-drinking crazy from &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;My Strange Addiction&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; makes me miss the piss-drinking crazy from &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;My Strange Addiction&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://gawker.com/5991696/my-strange-addiction-features-blood+drinker-in-its-most-revolting-episode-ever&quot;&gt;Gawker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jimmy Fallon&lt;/b&gt; might replace&lt;b&gt; Jay Leno&lt;/b&gt; sometime in the far future - &lt;a href=&quot;http://icydk.com/2013/03/21/jimmy-fallon-to-replace-jay-leno-in-2014-excited/&quot;&gt;ICYDK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jamie Foxx&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; daughter is all grown up and looks like this in a bikini - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popoholic.com/2013/03/21/say-hello-to-jamie-foxxs-daughter-corinne-bishop-damn/&quot;&gt;Popoholic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hot pieces of the new &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;G.I. Joe &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;movie - &lt;a href=&quot;http://theberry.com/2013/03/21/meet-the-sexy-guys-of-g-i-joe-9-photos/&quot;&gt;The Berry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift &lt;/b&gt;has already chosen her next victim - &lt;a href=&quot;http://idontlikeyouinthatway.com/2013/03/breaking-taylor-swift-is-falling-fast-for-some-new-dude.html&quot;&gt;IDLYITW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Some actor type named &lt;b&gt;Álex González h&lt;/b&gt;as a peen and here it is - (NSFW) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omgblog.com/2013/03/omg_princess_and_the_peen_alex.php&quot;&gt;OMG Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to make wall-to-wall carpet out of &lt;b&gt;Damian Lewis&#039;&lt;/b&gt; hair - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.justjared.com/2013/03/21/damian-lewis-freedom-of-the-city-of-london-award-recipient/&quot;&gt;Just Jared&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ashton Kutcher &lt;/b&gt;is really some super genius who is fooling us all, FYI - &lt;a href=&quot;http://videogum.com/691232/what-is-supergenius-ashton-kutcher-plotting-against-us/behind-the-scenes/&quot;&gt;Videogum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BREAKING: &lt;b&gt;Ben Affleck&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; daughter got a haircut - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popsugar.com/Ben-Affleck-Seraphina-Brentwood-Pictures-28763333&quot;&gt;Popsugar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to slap myself for mistaking &lt;b&gt;Vanessa Hudgens&lt;/b&gt; for &lt;b&gt;Lisa Bonet&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://moejackson.com/2013/03/21/breaking-vanessa-hudgens-forgets-to-remove-tag-from-jeans-shakes-her-booty-for-jay-leno/&quot;&gt;Moe Jackson&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is &lt;b&gt;Kanye&lt;/b&gt; styling &lt;b&gt;Rob Kartrashian &lt;/b&gt;too? - &lt;a href=&quot;http://imnotobsessed.com/2013/03/21/rob-kardashian-partying-lamar-odom/&quot;&gt;I&#039;m Not Obsessed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/afternoon-crumbs#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/afternoon-crumbs">Afternoon Crumbs</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:59:40 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49289 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The CAPTION THIS Contest For March 21st! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/caption-contest-march-21st</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://tosh.comedycentral.com/blog/2013/03/21/gonna-snag-me-a-hot-dentist&quot;&gt;Tosh.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/caption-contest-march-21st#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/-caption-contest">The CAPTION THIS Contest</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 15:35:49 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49287 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Dear Miley Cyrus, Now This Is How You Twerk </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/dear-miley-cyrus-now-how-you-twerk</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/KP9GmIKefL8?feature=player_detailpage&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/miley-cyrus-did-wop-two-minutes-and-i-watched-all-it&quot;&gt;Miley Cyrus&lt;/a&gt; needs to have a seat and take notes. Because you&#039;re not really twerking unless you&#039;re twerking in all the aisles at Walmart. I love an ass that can clap for itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crunktastical.net/2013/03/21/youtubes-serial-twerker-channel-worthy-subscription/&quot;&gt;Crunk + Disorderly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/dear-miley-cyrus-now-how-you-twerk#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/739">No Words Necessary</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 15:27:03 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49286 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Open Post: Hosted By Pricasso </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/open-post-hosted-pricasso</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#039;t know if this is an auction, but I&#039;m still raising my paddle, because I will sell my entire family, all of my internal organs and my burned DVD copies of the entire season of &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Titans_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;Titans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; for just a one-minute pony rode with Dlisted&#039;s favorite artist&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/node/33572&quot;&gt;Pricasso&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pricasso is the artiste who paints masterpieces with his peen and he&#039;s also the one who&#039;s wearing the same outfit you wore to work today. If you&#039;re in Sydney, the weekend forecast is calling for a 100% of precipitation in your panties, because Pricasso is there doing what he does best at Sexpo 2013. Giddyup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And who knew that &lt;a href=&quot;http://suzicate.files.wordpress.com/2010/07/blond-my-buddy-doll.jpg&quot;&gt;My Buddy&#039;s&lt;/a&gt; grandpa was a world famous artist and legendary panty creamer?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/open-post-hosted-pricasso#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/385">Open Post</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 15:22:03 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49285 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>What Rush Limaugh Thinks Beyonce&#039;s &quot;Bow Down&quot; Is About </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/what-rush-limaugh-thinks-beyonces-bow-down-about</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#039;m sure that when you first heard&lt;b&gt; Beyonce&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/2013/03/18/beyonce-subtle-and-humble-ever&quot;&gt;new humble anthem &quot;&lt;i&gt;Bow Down/I Been On&lt;/i&gt;,&quot; &lt;/a&gt;the first thing you asked yourself was, &lt;i&gt;&quot;What does Rush Limbaugh think about this?&quot;&lt;/i&gt; Or you might&#039;ve asked yourself, &lt;i&gt;&quot;What does a shit stain on a piece of rest stop toilet paper think about this?&lt;/i&gt;&quot; Same thing, really. Well, Rush Limbaugh never disappoints and the human Whoopee cushion of lukewarm farts expressed his thoughts about Beyonce&#039;s new song on his radio show the other day. But before we get to that mess...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the lyrics in Beyonce&#039;s ear-killing song goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I took some time to live my life&lt;br /&gt;
But don’t think I’m just his little wife&lt;br /&gt;
Don’t get it twisted, get it twisted&lt;br /&gt;
This my shit, bow down bitches&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So basically, King B is telling us that she&#039;s back and we all need to get on our knees and blah blah blah blah... Well, Rush, who is always trollin&#039;, thinks that now that Beyonce has married a rich dude, she&#039;s gone against her female empowerment beliefs and is all about bowing down to her husband now. via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.billboard.com/articles/columns/the-juice/1554203/beyonces-bow-down-criticized-misinterpreted-by-rush-limbaugh&quot;&gt;Billboard&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;Beyoncé used to be the lead for a three-girl group called Destiny&#039;s Child. And their songs were attempts to inspire young women not to take any grief from men. Essentially don&#039;t take any grief. Don&#039;t let these guys walk all over you. Don&#039;t do this, don&#039;t do that, just walk away. You don&#039;t need to put up with that. She&#039;s done a 180. Beyonce, now having been married, having been impregnated and given birth to Blue Ivy, she&#039;s going out on a new tour. And they may as well call it the &#039;Bow Down B-I-ITCH Tour.&#039; She&#039;s got a new song, &#039;Bow down, bitches,&#039; a total 180. Beyoncé&#039;s now saying, &#039;go ahead and put up with it.&#039; And you know why? I&#039;ll tell you why. She married the rich guy. She&#039;s even calling herself Mrs. Carter on the tour. She has shelved Beyonce. She&#039;s gonna call herself Mrs. Carter on the Bow Down Bitches Tour. That&#039;s the title of the single that&#039;s fronting the tour. And the advice to these women is put up with it. Bow down, b-i-itches. Because why? She got married. She married the rich guy. She now understands that it&#039;s worth it to bow down.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHHAAHAHHAHAHAHAHAHAHAAA! Rush Limbaugh should give his analysis on every new song that comes out.&amp;nbsp;Oxycontin has&amp;nbsp;co-produced some batshit crazy thoughts, but this thought sits at the top of the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s Beyonce in a new ad for H&amp;amp;M, which is sponsoring her Mrs. Carter World Tour. Whatever, I&#039;m sure Solange&#039;s ads for Filene&#039;s Basement will be way hotter than this shit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/what-rush-limaugh-thinks-beyonces-bow-down-about#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/112">Beyonce</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/463">I Can&amp;#039;t With You</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/501">You Learn Something New</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 14:32:34 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49284 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The Empress Of Lucite&#039;s Teeth Shine Bright Like A Diamond </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/empress-lucites-teeth-shine-bright-diamond</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;The most gorgeous earth goddess in the world &lt;b&gt;Shauna Sand&lt;/b&gt; already leaves a strand of liquid elegance on every peen her mouth touches and now she&#039;s going to leave a scattering of cubic zirconia dust on every peen her mouth touches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Shauna Sand is America&#039;s most priceless jewel, a team of Brink&#039;s security guards and Secret Service Agents follow her around at all times, but she&#039;ll have to up her security now that she has gemstones almost as precious as her embedded into her citrine-colored teeth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/21/shauna-sand-diamond-teeth-photos/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; somehow got a hold of these extremely exclusive and private pictures of a Manhattan dentist showing off the Barbie earrings he implanted into the Empress of Lucite&#039;s teeth. Elegance IS looking like a giant diamond just came all over your teeth. Those diamond studs will go perfectly with the exquisite pearl necklace she usually wears around her neck. Before going into her mouth, those diamond studs were worth $60 each, but an appraiser says that now that they&#039;re a part of Shauna Sand, they&#039;re&amp;nbsp;worth more money than exists in this world. Disneyland should replace the&lt;a href=&quot;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/93/208709703_dd9fe57425.jpg&quot;&gt; giant mountain of gold coins&lt;/a&gt; in the Pirates of the Caribbean ride with these pictures, because nothing is more luxurious than this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#039;s everything Courtney Stodden wishes she was and more sashaying into the free clinic in Beverly Hills the other day. Wearing that sweater with a naked picture of herself on it solidifies Shauna Sand as a fashion icon for the ages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/empress-lucites-teeth-shine-bright-diamond#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/432">Elegance Has A Name</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/246">Shauna Sand</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 13:25:08 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49283 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Xtina Gives Her Red Lip Paint The Night Off </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/xtina-gives-her-red-lip-paint-night</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Typing the words &lt;i&gt;&quot;Christina Aguilera actually looks kind of natural in the face&quot;&lt;/i&gt; feels unnatural, wrong and it goes against all the laws of clown glamour, but it&#039;s what I have to type, because she kind of does. &amp;nbsp;It only took five chisels, a sandblaster and a few dozen passes through the $5 car wash at the Shell gas station, but they managed to scrape all thirty five layers of dried Bronzer off of &lt;b&gt;Xtina&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;skin for last night&#039;s screening of &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Voice 4 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;in Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xtina kept her mug on the natural side and pruned her brows so they don&#039;t look like they belong on a box of Count Chocucla, and I know I&#039;m supposed to say she looks better like this, but I can&#039;t. Xtina is just isn&#039;t the same when she doesn&#039;t look like a Hatchet Face impersonator/clown hooker who just worked five shifts in a row. Although, at least her weave still looks like it was put together using ten different kinds of man-made materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#039;s some other hos at last night&#039;s screening party. In order: Xtina, Blake Shelton with Miranda Lambert, Justin Bieber&#039;s biological mother, Delta Goodrimgjob, Seal and Benji Madden.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/xtina-gives-her-red-lip-paint-night#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/176">Christina Aguilera</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/587">Excuse My Beauty</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/536">Well Well Well</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 12:27:21 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49282 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Yeah, We&#039;re All Looking For The Same Thing Right Now </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/yeah-were-all-looking-same-thing-right-now</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;You are not among the living if you don&#039;t immediately start searching for any signs of the Hamm steak as soon as you see a picture of its owner &lt;b&gt;Jon Hamm.&lt;/b&gt; It&#039;s a natural reaction. Just like knuckling yourself in the eyeball is a natural reaction to seeing the name &quot;&lt;i&gt;Kardashian&lt;/i&gt;.&quot; You just knuckled yourself in the eyeball, right? If only you could put the Hamm steak on it to stop the swelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/03/20/free-hammaconda&quot;&gt; cock-blocking executives at AMC&lt;/a&gt; must&#039;ve told Jon Hamm to shove his crotch beast in a bowl of ice before sticking it between his ass cheeks and holding it down with metal chains, because it did not make a grand appearance at last night&#039;s season 6 premiere of&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt; Mad Men&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. Those bitches at AMC just don&#039;t appreciate what they have, because they should&#039;ve rolled out the red carpet for Jon Hamm&#039;s big dick. Hell, they should&#039;ve rolled Jon Hamm&#039;s big dick out and used &lt;i&gt;it &lt;/i&gt;as the red carpet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except for the little girl, mostly everybody looked like hell last night.&lt;b&gt; Christina Hendricks &lt;/b&gt;covered up her magnificent chichis and dressed like an 85-year-old Italian widow. January Jones looked like a sad Popsicle. And &lt;b&gt;Vincent Kartheiser&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; guinea pig comb over is just dreadful. I&#039;m assuming that they all looked like shit on purpose, because they wanted all of the attention to go to the true star of the show, the Hammaconda. And it didn&#039;t even show up. It&#039;s a sad day for us all and AMC can eat some cold ass in hell for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here&#039;s a few pictures from last night&#039;s Hammaconda-less &lt;i&gt;Mad Men&lt;/i&gt; premiere party. In order: Jon Hamm with Jennifer Westfeldt, John Slattery, Vincent Kartheiser, Kiernan Shipka, Alison Brie, Christina Hendricks, January Jones, Jessica Pare, Teyonah Parris and Ben Feldman.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/yeah-were-all-looking-same-thing-right-now#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/92">Big Ones</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/527">Christina Hendricks</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/elisabeth-moss">Elisabeth Moss</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/670">Jon Hamm</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/793">Mad Men</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 11:28:13 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49281 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Miley Cyrus Did The Wop For Two Minutes And I Watched All Of It </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/miley-cyrus-did-wop-two-minutes-and-i-watched-all-it</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/KrVxR6gAjvQ?feature=player_embedded&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is why I should mainline &lt;a href=&quot;http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/lifestyle/2013/03/caffeination-death-wish-is-two-times-stronger-than-coffee/&quot;&gt;Death Wish&lt;/a&gt; coffee before I open up my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chipmunk Slytherin spent all of her teen years working hard to put squirrel meat on the shopping cart grill, so she didn&#039;t get the whole &quot;&lt;i&gt;twerking in front of a video camera&quot;&lt;/i&gt; thing out of her system the way most of us did before we turned 16. But since bitch doesn&#039;t have shit to do now, this is how she&#039;s spending her time. Last night, &lt;b&gt;Miley Cyrus &lt;/b&gt;uploaded a 2 minute-long video of her shaking her ass in a unicorn onesie. Bitch looks more like a deranged boxing kangaroo with physical Tourettes. The most tragic part of all of this is that my caffeine-less brain spent the first few minutes of my morning trying to process all of this mess. I should really put a warning label on the front of my laptop that reads: &quot;&lt;i&gt;Do Not Operate Unless You Are Under the Influence of Caffeine Or a Mind-Altering Substance.&lt;/i&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s Miley&#039;s maybe fiance &lt;b&gt;Liam Hemsworth&lt;/b&gt; arriving back in L.A. last night. I keep refreshing the photo agency databases for pictures of Liam Hemsworth leaving L.A. this morning, because I&#039;m sure as soon as he got home and saw this video of Miley trying to twerk, he turned right back around and got the fuck out of there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/21/miley-cyrus-did-wop-two-minutes-and-i-watched-all-it#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/68">Dumbasses</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/i-cant-myself">I Can&amp;#039;t With Myself</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/318">Miley Cyrus</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 10:25:02 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49280 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
