<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://dlisted.com" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Dlisted - Be Very Afraid</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Birthday Sluts</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/24/birthday-sluts</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Louie Anderson (60)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;Keisha Castle-Hughes (23)&lt;br /&gt;
Nivea (31)&lt;br /&gt;
Lake Bell (34)&lt;br /&gt;
Jessica Chastain (36)&lt;br /&gt;
Peyton Manning (37)&lt;br /&gt;
Alyson Hannigan (39)&lt;br /&gt;
Jim Parsons (40)&lt;br /&gt;
Lara Flynn Boyle (42)&lt;br /&gt;
Sharon Corr (42)&lt;br /&gt;
Houston (44)&lt;br /&gt;
The Undertaker (48)&lt;br /&gt;
Annabella Sciorra (49)&lt;br /&gt;
Star Jones (51)&lt;br /&gt;
Kelly LeBrock (53)&lt;br /&gt;
Nena (53)&lt;br /&gt;
Robert Carradine (59)&lt;br /&gt;
Donna Pescow (59)&lt;br /&gt;
Tommy Hilfiger (62)&lt;br /&gt;
Nick Lowe (64)&lt;br /&gt;
Curtis Hanson (68)&lt;br /&gt;
Bob Mackie (73)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(GIF via &lt;a href=&quot;http://guyism.com/sports/katherine-webb-dedicated-her-splash-dive-to-brent-musburger.html&quot;&gt;Guyism&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/24/birthday-sluts#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/birthday-sluts">Birthday Sluts</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 11:13:43 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49311 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Open Post: Hosted By Zack Morris </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/open-post-hosted-zack-morris</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s a priceless picture of &lt;b&gt;Mark-Paul Gosselaar &lt;/b&gt;clenching his nalgas and giving us his O face while shooting scenes with&lt;b&gt; Breckin Meyer &lt;/b&gt;for their show &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Franklin &amp;amp; Bash&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; in Malibu yesterday. Since my brain is powered by dirty gutter water and weed smoke, to me it looks like he&#039;s trying to blow that ball. It&#039;s like a scene straight out of a &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cast Away &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;parody porn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#039;t exactly know what&#039;s going on in these pictures, but I like all of it. Zack Morris, who&#039;s the kind of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/03/13/would-you-hit-it&quot;&gt;panty creamer &lt;/a&gt;who gets hotter as the days go by, looks like he&#039;s having sweaty ass sex with a ghost. He&#039;s doing all sorts of positions on that beach. He&#039;s doing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/node/49312/images/spl514564_011.jpg&quot;&gt;side fuck&lt;/a&gt; position, he&#039;s doing the &quot;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/node/49312/images/spl514564_012.jpg&quot;&gt;wrap your legs around that waist and hold on tight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&quot; position and he&#039;s doing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/node/49312/images/spl514564_018.jpg&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; position, which I can&#039;t put into words. Get it and take it all, Zack Morris.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/open-post-hosted-zack-morris#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/385">Open Post</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 18:40:56 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49312 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>RiRi Keeps A Bunch Of School Children Waiting For Hours </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/riri-keeps-bunch-school-children-waiting-hours</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;In &quot;&lt;i&gt;RiRi is a tacky, tardy ass, but what else is new?&lt;/i&gt;&quot; news, &lt;b&gt;RiRi&lt;/b&gt; kept 2,000 school children in Chicago waiting for over three hours on Thursday afternoon. Barrington High School in Chicago won first place in the national &quot;&lt;i&gt;Shine Like A Diamond&quot;&lt;/i&gt; contest and their prize was getting a visit from RiRi. &amp;nbsp;They should&#039;ve asked if they could get cash instead, because they waited and waited and waited and waited and waited for her stupid ass to show up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://articles.chicagotribune.com/2013-03-23/news/chi-rihanna-barrington-high-school-20130322_1_rihanna-pop-star-barbadian&quot;&gt;The Chicago Tribune&lt;/a&gt; says that the students were all gathered in the gym at around noon and she was supposed to drop in at 1pm. When 1pm came and went, all the kids turned into clumps of boredom and spent their time Facebooking on their phones and braiding each other&#039;s hair. The school then announced that she would show up at 2. At around 4:30, RiRi &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rihanna/status/315211808770236416&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that she was stuck in traffic. Bitch finally strolled in after 5pm and was there for a grand total of 16 minutes. RiRi talked for a second and posed for pictures before leaving. RiRi didn&#039;t apologize for being a tardy bitch. The school principal said that she apologized to him and gave him a few extra concert tickets to pass out to the students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several students weren&#039;t amused and weren&#039;t shy about it either. One seventh grader said,  &lt;i&gt;&quot;Rihanna is pathetic. She shouldn&#039;t be making us wait for her.&lt;/i&gt;&quot; Another student co-signed that statement and added a few words of her own, &lt;i&gt;&quot;It&#039;s one thing to be fashionably late. This is just rude. Our lives don&#039;t revolve around a pop star. Our school worked hard to win this. She should be more respectful.&quot; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, the only reason for RiRi to be at a school assembly is to tell the children to learn from her mistakes and to not go back to the crusted-over piece of dick cheese who almost beat your face off. Second of all, RiRi could&#039;ve apologized by giving every student &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/02/15/riri-got-bouquet-buds-vd&quot;&gt;a weed bouquet&lt;/a&gt;. Nothing says I&#039;m truly sorry like a weed bouquet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RiRi is NO &lt;b&gt;Tina Yothers&lt;/b&gt;. Tina Yothers spoke at my school and not only did she stay for hours, but she also had lunch with us. But I&#039;m sure she only had lunch with us because it was square pizza day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Pic via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SpanishNavy&quot;&gt;@spanishnavy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/riri-keeps-bunch-school-children-waiting-hours#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/152">Rihanna</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/536">Well Well Well</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 17:30:38 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49310 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>This Is Art: Sleeping Tilda </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/art-sleeping-tilda</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;When I take a long nap in public, the police wake me up and tell me to put on my pants and go sober up at home. When the humanized form of a unicorn horn &lt;b&gt;Tilda Swinton &lt;/b&gt;does it, people wait in line to see it and they call it ART!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting today and continuing for the rest of the month, Tilda Swinton will take naps in a glass box at MoMA in NYC all day, on random days. &lt;a href=&quot;http://gothamist.com/2013/03/23/photos_tilda_swinton_is_sleeping_in.php&quot;&gt;Gothamist&lt;/a&gt; says that even the employees at MoMA don&#039;t know when she&#039;s going to show up. Tilda just glides into the museum in the morning, gets into the glass box and sleeps off her hangover. The only things in the box besides Tilda are a water jug and cushions. The piece is called &lt;i&gt;&quot;The Maybe&quot;&lt;/i&gt; and Tilda first performed it in London in 1995. The museum said this about Tilda&#039;s art piece:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
An integral part of The Maybe&#039;s incarnation at MoMA in 2013 is that there is no published schedule for its appearance, no artist&#039;s statement released, no no museum statement beyond this brief context, no public profile or image issued. Those who find it chance upon it for themselves, live and in real—shared—time: now we see it, now we don&#039;t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call this shit stupid and scream about how you do this every night, but this is the legendary Tilda doing it. It&#039;s like going to a unicorn zoo. I&#039;d rather watch Tilda sleep or take bird sips of tap water from a plastic tumbler for six hours straight than watch Lady CaCa or Beyonce or whoever do anything. This shit is a bargain too. I think it&#039;s like $25 if you&#039;re not a member.&amp;nbsp;Bitches have spent a lot more money to watch Brit Brit nap on stage during her concert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, this is hard work. Tilda has to hold in her pee (although, I don&#039;t even know if she does pee), she can&#039;t fap and if she lets out a fart, there&#039;s nowhere for her to escape from it. She should&#039;ve called this piece &lt;i&gt;&quot;Dutch Glass Oven.&lt;/i&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you landed on this post after Googling &quot;&lt;i&gt;Tilda&#039;s box&lt;/i&gt;,&quot; I&#039;m sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/files/images/tildamoma2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/art-sleeping-tilda#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/505">International Treasure</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/469">This Belongs In A Museum</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/546">Tilda Swinton</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 16:32:29 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49309 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>This Is What Kim Kartrashian Wore Yesterday</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/what-kim-kartrashian-wore-yesterday</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Another day, another set of messy pictures of&lt;b&gt; Kim Kardashian&lt;/b&gt; looking like she wants us all to forget that she&#039;s got a ticket to relevancy growing in her womb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having lunch at Fred Segal in West Hollywood with the mutant Muppet we all know as&lt;b&gt; Robin Antin&lt;/b&gt;, Kim teetered through the parking lot and you can practically hear the muffled cries from her nipple slits as they try to gasp for air. That top is stretched more than her face is and it looks like her titties are choking and trying to find the nearest exit. Those titties need an oxygen mask and a pep talk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitch looks like a rotten and deflated blueberry that has given up on its will to go on. And ho&#039;s face is telling a different color story than her body is. Either her live-in car painter forgot to spray her body down with orange paint or that extra tight shit is cutting off her circulation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/what-kim-kartrashian-wore-yesterday#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/fug">Fug</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 15:39:31 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49305 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>America&#039;s Sweethearts Finally Meet </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/americas-sweethearts-finally-meet</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;If you read that as &quot;&lt;i&gt;America&#039;s Sweetfarts&lt;/i&gt;,&quot; that works too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Anderson Cooper&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;talk show ends in just a few months, but he should take a bow early, because he will never get a more important or famous guest than the guest he had on Friday&#039;s show: &lt;b&gt;Grumpy Cat &lt;/b&gt;(born name: Tardar Sauce)! Grumpy Cat, who is looking more and more like my abuelita at every children&#039;s birthday party she went to, finally made a thousand dreams come true by meeting The Silver Fox. Anderson tried to put on his best grumpy pussy face while posing with Tardar Sauce and well, he shouldn&#039;t quit his job to become a Grumpy Cat impersonator anytime soon. He tried, but he looks more like Constipated Fox than Grumpy Cat. He kind of looks like the soft part of his sugar walls got poked hard by a peen and he&#039;s not sure if he&#039;s into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all that being said, I&#039;m still going to print out this picture, throw a veil on it and marry it in a quickie wedding at the courthouse. I don&#039;t know for sure if human-paper marriage is legal in California or not, but Kris Humphries did marry a water damaged piece of cardboard here, so I&#039;m guessing it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s Grumpy Cat not giving three fucks while hanging out with The Silver Fox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/toYQ2ery1Bg?feature=player_detailpage&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/p/XLdak7kkAM/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;(Thanks to everyone who sent this in)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/americas-sweethearts-finally-meet#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/326">Anderson Cooper</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/grumpy-cat">Grumpy Cat</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/469">This Belongs In A Museum</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 14:53:40 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49307 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Hot Slut Of The Day! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/hot-slut-day</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/8EKl-DTg4jI?feature=player_embedded&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ramona&lt;/b&gt;, a Goldendoodle who lives at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oregonhumane.org/bo/&quot;&gt;Oregon Humane Society&lt;/a&gt; in Portland and is trying to get Bo Obama to be her date to the Humane Society&#039;s Doggie Dash fundraiser in May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole annoying trend of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/03/20/kate-upton-might-go-prom-high-school-senior-who-asked-her-out-youtube-video&quot;&gt;people asking celebrities to be their dates to their prom or whatever&lt;/a&gt; has reached a fever pitch and this, hopefully, is its grand finale! The Oregon Human Society says that their in-house dog Ramona as a serious crush on Bo Obama and her heart beats for him (or since this is a dog we&#039;re talking about, her nose twitches for his b-hole). They produced a video invitation where Ramona asks Bo to come to Portland and marry her at the Doggie Dash on May 11th. Yeah, it&#039;ll be Ramona and Bo&#039;s first date AND their wedding. Ramona isn&#039;t wasting any time. Bitch moves fast. She&#039;s like the Brit Brit of dogs (but her weave has less fleas in it). Or maybe Ramona is a traditional girl and won&#039;t sniff ass until she&#039;s married.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bo hasn&#039;t accepted or denied Ramona&#039;s invitation yet, but I hope he accepts and I also hope that George W. Bush flies to Portland to &lt;a href=&quot;http://gawker.com/5991732/a-watermelon-a-golf-course-a-horse-and-monstrous-dogs-12-new-paintings-from-george-w-bush&quot;&gt;paint their wedding portrait&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.peoplepets.com/people/pets/article/0,,20684830,00.html&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/hot-slut-day#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/hot-slut-day">Hot Slut of the Day</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 13:26:43 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49306 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Birthday Sluts</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/birthday-sluts-1</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Chaka Khan (60)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;Princess Eugenie of York (23)&lt;br /&gt;
Nicholle Tom (35)&lt;br /&gt;
Keri Russell (37)&lt;br /&gt;
Michelle Monaghan (37)&lt;br /&gt;
Gail Porter (42)&lt;br /&gt;
Poe (46)&lt;br /&gt;
John Bobbitt (46)&lt;br /&gt;
Richard Grieco (48)&lt;br /&gt;
Hope Davis (49)&lt;br /&gt;
Catherine Keener (54)&lt;br /&gt;
Amanda Plummer (56)&lt;br /&gt;
Kenneth Cole (59)&lt;br /&gt;
Ric Ocasek (64)&lt;br /&gt;
Michael Haneke (71)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/23/birthday-sluts-1#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/birthday-sluts">Birthday Sluts</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 11:30:45 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49303 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Brit Brit And Normal Guy Dave Held Hands In Public, But What In 50s Diner Waitress Hell Is She Wearing? </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/brit-brit-and-normal-guy-dave-held-hands-public-what-50s-diner-waitress-hell-she-wearing</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Daddy Spears&lt;/b&gt; obviously insists on sending &lt;b&gt;Brit Brit&lt;/b&gt; out for staged hand holding photo-ops with her leased boyfriend &lt;b&gt;David Somethingoranother&lt;/b&gt;, but couldn&#039;t he fix her style beforehand? This makes the veins in my eyeballs hurt since we&#039;re so used to seeing Brit Brit looking like the fashion icon she is&amp;nbsp;in baggy, grease-stained sweats, a t-shirt that doubles as a booger rag and fug boots that are meant to be given out as a gag gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked that dress better when&lt;b&gt; Lily Tomlin&lt;/b&gt; wore it in &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Big Business&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. It looks like something a &lt;b style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Project Runway &lt;/b&gt;contestant would come up with if they had to make a flight attendant dress out of tablecloths and napkins from a Sweet 16 birthday party. And she just had to go full fug by pairing a black and pink dress with your memaw&#039;s least favorite brown church shoes. Those are dookie shoes. And he looks like the maitre d&#039; of a Cracker Barrel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swear, Daddy Spears is totally just screwing with us now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/brit-brit-and-normal-guy-dave-held-hands-public-what-50s-diner-waitress-hell-she-wearing#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/britney-spears">Britney Spears</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/fug">Fug</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/536">Well Well Well</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:28:37 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49304 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>One Of Ashley Greene&#039;s Dogs Died In A Fire That Destroyed Her Condo (UPDATE) </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/one-ashley-greenes-dogs-died-fire-destroyed-her-condo</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s some shitty and sad news for your Friday afternoon... One of &lt;b&gt;Ashley Greene&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; dog is up in heaven now after it died in a fire that broke out this morning and completely destroyed her condo in West Hollywood. Ashley had two dog friends, &lt;b&gt;Marlo&lt;/b&gt; (pictured with her above) and &lt;b&gt;Theo&lt;/b&gt;, and one of them survived. It&#039;s not known which one died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashley&#039;s rep tells &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/ashley-greenes-apartment-destroyed-in-fire-dog-dies-in-blaze-2013223&quot;&gt;UsWeekly&lt;/a&gt; that she wasn&#039;t home when the fire broke out on the couch this morning, but she drove over there as soon as one of her neighbors called to tell her what happened. But &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/22/ashley-greene-apartment-fire-west-hollywood-l-a/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; heard a different story. A firefighter at the scene told TMZ that Ashley, her boyfriend (who apparently &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laineygossip.com/Is-Ashley-Greene-dating-Ryan-Phillippe/26340&quot;&gt;isn&#039;t Ryan Phillippe&lt;/a&gt;) and her brother were out late last night so they were sleeping in. A fire started on the sofa in the living room and after they woke up and realized the whole place was in flames, they ran out of there without the dogs. They all realized that the dogs didn&#039;t run out with them, so her boyfriend and her brother tried to go back to get them, but they weren&#039;t able to. As Ashley&#039;s neighbors tried to control the fire with fire extinguishers, one dog made it out. One of Ashley&#039;s nosy neighbors tells TMZ that before the fire, her brother and her boyfriend were going in and out of the apartment all morning and they heard glass breaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a fire broke out in my apartment, the only things I&#039;d grab would be my bong and my dog. If a fire broke out in my apartment, I&#039;d like to think that my dog would grab me too, but he&#039;d probably just grab the bacon from the fridge. Speaking of bacon, I should probably put back the battery I took out of the smoke alarm in my living room because it kept going off every time I cooked bacon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rest in peace, Ashley&#039;s doggy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/22/ashley-greene-fire-unattended-candle-cause-dog-died/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; says that a candle was the cause. Somebody left a candle on and it somehow fell on the sofa and started the fire.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/one-ashley-greenes-dogs-died-fire-destroyed-her-condo#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/707">Ashley Greene</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/sadness">Sadness</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 18:37:38 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49302 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
