<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://dlisted.com" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Dlisted - Be Very Afraid</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Birthday Sluts</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/26/birthday-sluts-1</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Steven Tyler (65)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;Carly Chaikin (23)&lt;br /&gt;
Jonathan Groff (28)&lt;br /&gt;
Keira Knightley (28)&lt;br /&gt;
Sara Jean Underwood (29)&lt;br /&gt;
Amy Smart (37)&lt;br /&gt;
T. R. Knight (40)&lt;br /&gt;
Leslie Mann (41)&lt;br /&gt;
James Iha (45)&lt;br /&gt;
Kenny Chesney (45)&lt;br /&gt;
Michael Imperioli (47)&lt;br /&gt;
Jennifer Grey (53)&lt;br /&gt;
Chris Hansen (54)&lt;br /&gt;
Leeza Gibbons (56)&lt;br /&gt;
Martin Short (63)&lt;br /&gt;
Vicki Lawrence (64)&lt;br /&gt;
Diana Ross (69)&lt;br /&gt;
James Caan (73)&lt;br /&gt;
Nancy Pelosi (73)&lt;br /&gt;
Alan Arkin (79)&lt;br /&gt;
Leonard Nimoy (82)&lt;br /&gt;
Sandra Day O&#039;Connor (83)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/26/birthday-sluts-1#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/birthday-sluts">Birthday Sluts</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 08:31:24 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49329 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Eva Mendes Think The Tabloids Should Blur Out The Faces Of Celebrity Dogs</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/eva-mendes-think-tabloids-should-blur-out-faces-celebrity-dogs</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Eva Mendes &lt;/b&gt;did an interview with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vulture.com/2013/03/eva-mendes-the-place-beyond-the-pines.html&quot;&gt;New York Magazine&lt;/a&gt; (via&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eonline.com/news/400976/eva-mendes-wants-paparazzi-protection-for-her-and-ryan-gosling-s-dogs?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-topstories&amp;amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;amp;utm_campaign=rss_topstories&quot;&gt; E!&lt;/a&gt;) to promote that movie she did with &lt;b&gt;Ryan Gosling&lt;/b&gt; called&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt; Place Beyond the Pines&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; and she didn&#039;t really want to talk about anything. If I was interviewing Eva, I&#039;d ask her to show me with her hands how big Ryan&#039;s dick is and then I&#039;d ask her if he giggles when she tickles his taint. You know, basic questions. But I&#039;d be wasting my breath and mouth muscles, because she wouldn&#039;t answer any of those question. New York Magazine asked her some simple shit and she put on an &quot;&lt;i&gt;OHMYGODIMSOPRIVATE!&lt;/i&gt;&quot; act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They asked her where she met Ryan Gosling and she said, &quot;&lt;i&gt;That&#039;s where I start to shut down. Because it gets into personal territory that I don&#039;t feel comfortable talking about. So sorry&lt;/i&gt;.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They asked her about her role in the movie and she said, “&lt;i&gt;I don’t want to disclose anything because I feel like there are no more surprises anymore, whether it’s in film, about the ending of a story, or what a character looks like—by the time we see the movie, we’ve seen paparazzi shots of the actor wearing the wig. Where’s the mystery? Where’d it go? I want it back.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They asked her if she wants to make tiny Goslings with Ryan Gosling and she said, &lt;i&gt;&quot;I&#039;m so out of here. You know the cartoon where the steam comes out and it says, &#039;Boop-bee-boop. System down&#039;?&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They finally asked her why is she wasting their fucking time when they could be at home fapping while eating Thin Mints instead of rolling their eyes every time she refused to answer their question. No, they didn&#039;t ask that, but they should&#039;ve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Eva did want to talk about her dog&#039;s privacy. Eva wishes that tabloids and blogs would blur out her dog&#039;s face the way British tabloids blur out the faces of children in paparazzi pictures. Eva said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;I&#039;ll go somewhere and they&#039;ll be like, &#039;Hey, Hugo!&#039; and I&#039;m like, &#039;How do you know Hugo&#039;s name?&#039; That&#039;s so creepy!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, please. She&#039;s just mad, because they knew her dog&#039;s name and didn&#039;t know hers. Hugo is way more famous than she is (which is how it should be). Did Eva even ask Hugo what he wants? Maybe he&#039;s a fame whore and loves the attention? Just look at that picture. She&#039;s the one throwing her hands up all dramatic like she&#039;s Norma Desmond and Hugo&#039;s just chilling there. But you know, if we had to blur out the faces of canine creatures who lick their own butts, then that means we&#039;d have to blur out the faces of every Kardashian. Maybe that crazy bitch Eva Mendes is on to something after all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/eva-mendes-think-tabloids-should-blur-out-faces-celebrity-dogs#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/296">Eva Mendes</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/242">Girlfriend Please</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 21:09:55 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49341 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Does Lockdown Rehab Even Exist? </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/does-lockdown-rehab-even-exist</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lindsay Lohan&lt;/b&gt; was so close to pulling her greatest con yet and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/25/lindsay-lohan-lockdown-rehab-jail/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; and that spotlight-humping whore &lt;b&gt;Dr. Drew &lt;/b&gt;had to ruin it all! The Santa Monica City Attorney agreed to let LiLo &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/03/18/what-waste-gold-glitter&quot;&gt;serve 90 days in a lockdown rehab facility &lt;/a&gt;in New York instead of going to jail. The judge signed off on it and LiLo&#039;s itty bitty lawyer &lt;b&gt;Mark Heller&lt;/b&gt; said that there was a lockdown rehab facility in NYC. Since Googling &quot;&lt;i&gt;Does lockdown rehab exist?&quot;&lt;/i&gt; is hard, none of the prosecutors checked to see if the littlest lawyer was telling the truth. But TMZ checked and they found out that lockdown rehab is a fairytale place that only exists in the mind of Mark Heller. No such things exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They checked and couldn&#039;t find one private rehab joint in the entire country that locks the doors and forces their patients to stay there. The only lockdown rehab facility in NY they did find is connected to a prison and&amp;nbsp;you need a felony record to get. Surprisingly, LiLo doesn&#039;t have a felony record. TMZ asked Dr. Drew about the myth that is lockdown rehab and he said,&lt;i&gt; &quot;There is no rehab that will hold you against your will, unless they feel the person is a suicide risk, and in that case they can hold the individual for 72 hours.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now the prosecutors are at their desks Googling &quot;&lt;i&gt;Does lockdown rehab exist?&lt;/i&gt;&quot; Apparently, they&#039;re trying to figure out what to do now that they&#039;ve been duped and they might just throw her in jail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dammit all! LiLo was probably going to check into a spa resort that holds AA meetings/mocktail classes in their bar every other week (that practically counts as rehab) and then she was going to stuff her bed with pillows and strands of dried orange seaweed. Every time the prosecutors called to make sure she&#039;s there, the maid would peek into her room, see the strands of dried orange seaweed on her bed, mistake it for her weave and tell them that she&#039;s there and sleeping. Meanwhile, she&#039;d be partying with her johns somewhere. And now TMZ has foiled her plan! Bitch will probably be sent to jail instead and she&#039;ll sit in a cell for a total of 90 seconds before they release her due to overcrowding. Woe is her!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I don&#039;t know why the prosecutors believed Mark Heller in the first place. You should never trust a charbroiled troll with Henry Winkler hair. They&#039;re the shiftiest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/does-lockdown-rehab-even-exist#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/68">Dumbasses</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/lindsay-lohan">Lindsay Lohan</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 19:44:36 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49340 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Blind Items: I Guess, You Guess </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/blind-items-i-guess-you-guess</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the most unlikely – and shocking – celebrity pairing of the year! We’ll call them Big and Little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big supposedly has a steady girlfriend. He used to be good, but he is definitely behaving badly now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little is married. She wants everyone to think she is a very good girl, but she is definitely a very bad girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big and Little hooked up in Los Angeles earlier this year during the week of a major awards show. He just couldn’t keep it in his pants. She just couldn’t keep it out of her mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much more to come on this one. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://blindgossip.com/?p=51817&quot;&gt;Blind Gossip&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I&#039;m probably ever layer of wrong and guessing &quot;&lt;i&gt;Rhea Perlman &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;ASkars&lt;/i&gt;&quot; would probably make more sense, but I&#039;m going to say &lt;b&gt;Liam Neeson&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Reese Witherspoon&lt;/b&gt;? I don&#039;t know if Liam Neeson is still with his girlfriend, but he works as a guess, because he&#039;s big in more ways than one. Exhibit: (NSFW) &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/ZZXHF&quot;&gt;EVERYTHING&lt;/a&gt;. The Hammaconda who? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This must have been a sight to see. Kid&#039;s Choice Awards after party. Two huge tweener stars on a a show that is currently airing. Mid-teens at best and bent over with their knees on the bathroom floor and short dresses riding up while they do lines of coke off a menu from the party. Meanwhile there were five or six other people in the bathroom. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crazydaysandnights.net/2013/03/blind-item-1-kids-choice-awards.html&quot;&gt;CDAN&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Those coke whores &lt;b&gt;SpongeBob &lt;/b&gt;and&lt;b&gt; Patrick Star?&lt;/b&gt; But, big deal. Those Nickelodeon tricks are amateurs. I&#039;m sure as this was going on, two Disney hos were shooting heroin into Mickey Mouse&#039;s eyeballs as Daisy Duck smoked crack through her butt in the corner.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a survey of celebrity coke users, the consensus is that if you are ever wanting to hang out with another celebrity because of their coke stash, this former A list reality star and now C- list celebrity who thinks of herself always as A list has by far the best coke anyone has ever tried. It is one of the reasons that other actors and actresses and celebrities never really said bad things about her. They didn&#039;t want to be cut off. Yes, it is supposedly really that good. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crazydaysandnights.net/2013/03/blind-item-4_24.html&quot;&gt;CDAN&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Parasite Hilton&lt;/b&gt;? But those bags of white dust she gives them isn&#039;t coke. It&#039;s her toxic coochie dandruff. Suckers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This A+ list mostly movie actor who is an Academy Award winner/nominee who spent one weekend night talking to women in a bar. When they approached him, he asked each what they would be willing to do for $1000. Apparently one of them answered the way he wanted because he invited her to sit down and then left the bar with her a short time later. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crazydaysandnights.net/2013/03/blind-item-1_25.html&quot;&gt;CDAN&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Leonardo DiCaprio&lt;/b&gt;? My guess is that the bar chick told Leo that for $1,000, she&#039;ll dress up in a fancy gown, stand at an imaginary podium and say the words, &quot;&lt;i&gt;And the Oscar goes to Leonardo DiCaprio!&lt;/i&gt;&quot; The Oscars hate him and he&#039;s not going to win one in real life, so he might as well win one while role playing with a call girl.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/blind-items-i-guess-you-guess#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/blind-items">Blind Items</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 18:34:49 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49337 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Afternoon Crumbs </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/afternoon-crumbs</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;World War Zzz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; trailer is out and&lt;b&gt; Brad Pitt&lt;/b&gt; looks stoned as shit throughout all of it. Don&#039;t you hate it when the zombie apocalypse fucks with your high? - &lt;a href=&quot;http://videogum.com/693221/brad-pitt-seems-pretty-chill-about-the-collapse-of-human-civilization/movies/trailer/&quot;&gt;Videogum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ben Affleck&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Jennifer Garner&lt;/b&gt; kill all the marriage problem rumors with a good old-fashioned staged PDS (public displays of stuntin&#039;) session -&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laineygossip.com/Ben-Affleck-and-Jennifer-Garner-affectionate-during-family-weekend-at-the-farmers-market/26354&quot;&gt; Lainey Gossip&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#039;s tons of cocktails for your Easter weekend, or you can do what I do and wrap your lips around a bowl full of Peeps and Strawberry Hill - &lt;a href=&quot;http://theberry.com/2013/03/25/get-hopped-up-on-these-easter-cocktails-25-photos-recipes/&quot;&gt;The Berry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swimming with crocodiles is nothing for &lt;b&gt;The Silver Fox.&lt;/b&gt; I mean, he&#039;s gone tanning with &lt;b&gt;Snooki&lt;/b&gt; and that was way more dangerous and more hazardous to his health - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.towleroad.com/2013/03/anderson-cooper-dives-with-nile-crocodiles-video.html&quot;&gt;Towleroad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#039;re the crazy real-life Van Gogh bitch who cut off your ear and sent it to &lt;b&gt;Jared Leto&lt;/b&gt;, he&#039;s wearing it as a necklace, FYI - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.celebitchy.com/287742/jared_leto_received_a_human_ear_in_the_mail_wore_it_as_a_necklace_really/&quot;&gt;Celebitchy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is &lt;b&gt;RiRi&lt;/b&gt; licking on today? - &lt;a href=&quot;http://drunkenstepfather.com/2013/03/25/rihanna-is-fun-on-instagram-of-the-day-2#.UVCs8L95iXI&quot;&gt;Drunken Stepfather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Courtney Stodden&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;transformation into &lt;b&gt;Anna Nicole Smith&lt;/b&gt; is almost complete - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.realitytea.com/2013/03/25/courtney-stodden-and-bobby-trendy-filming-new-reality-tv-show/&quot;&gt;Reality Tea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hayden Panatroll &lt;/b&gt;and her jolly Ukrainian giant boyfriend went to a basketball game together - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hollywoodtuna.com/?p=91357&quot;&gt;Hollywood Tuna&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Doutzen Kroes &lt;/b&gt;gave birth a couple of months ago and she obviously hasn&#039;t lost all the baby weight yet (served on a wet bed of sarcasm) - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popoholic.com/2013/03/25/ridiculously-sexy-doutzen-kroes-candid-bikini-pictures-wow/&quot;&gt;Popoholic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Amanda Bynes&#039; &lt;/b&gt;family is going to step in to help her crazy ass as soon as they finish spending her money on booze and coke while partying with &lt;b&gt;White Oprah&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://idontlikeyouinthatway.com/2013/03/amanda-bynes-family-is-concerned.html&quot;&gt;IDLYITW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talentless fame whore vs. talentless fame whores - &lt;a href=&quot;http://icydk.com/2013/03/25/tori-spelling-twitter-bashes-kourtney-and-kim-take-miami/&quot;&gt;ICYDK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waxed Italian man ass alert! - (NSFW) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omgblog.com/2013/03/omg_giu_whizz_giulio_berruti_i.php&quot;&gt;OMG Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lily Tomlin &lt;/b&gt;almost did the &quot;&lt;i&gt;Yup, I&#039;m Gay!&lt;/i&gt;&quot; magazine cover before &lt;b&gt;Ellen DeGeneres&lt;/b&gt; did it - &lt;a href=&quot;http://greginhollywood.com/lily-tomlin-remembers-being-offered-a-yep-im-gay-time-magazine-cover-decades-before-ellen-82480&quot;&gt;Greg in Hollywood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These &lt;b&gt;Jon Hamm &lt;/b&gt;pictures need less scarf and more Hammaconda - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.justjared.com/2013/03/25/jon-hamm-i-love-justin-timberlakes-style/&quot;&gt;Just Jared&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attack of the Clones: &lt;b&gt;Madge&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Yoko Ono&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kennethinthe212.com/2013/03/separated-at-birth-madonna-and-yoko-ono.html&quot;&gt;Kenneth in the (212)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#039;s hard to take Details&#039; Most Fuckable Celebrities list seriously when neither &lt;b&gt;Angelyne&lt;/b&gt; nor &lt;b&gt;Richard Simmons &lt;/b&gt;is on it - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boyculture.com/boy_culture/2013/03/sexy-stars-ryan-gosling-zac-efron.html&quot;&gt;Boy Culture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;b&gt;Angelyne&lt;/b&gt;... - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crunktastical.net/2013/03/25/sexual-napalm-angelyne-2/&quot;&gt;Crunk + Disorderly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Spice Girls&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; will have to find another frozen mannequin to move her lips and point at the audience, because &lt;b&gt;Posh&lt;/b&gt; is out! - &lt;a href=&quot;http://imnotobsessed.com/2013/03/25/victoria-beckham-singing-days-ovah/&quot;&gt;I&#039;m Not Obsessed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Posh&lt;/b&gt; can&#039;t be bothered with the &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Spice Girls&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, because she&#039;s way too busy posing on rolls of pink bubble wrap - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hollywoodrag.com/index.php?/weblog/comments2/victoria_beckham_sitting_on_pink_bubble_wrap/&quot;&gt;Hollywood Rag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/afternoon-crumbs#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/afternoon-crumbs">Afternoon Crumbs</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 16:31:34 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49328 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The CAPTION THIS Contest For March 25th! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/caption-contest-march-25th</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/p/XN6B6OOS7r/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/caption-contest-march-25th#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/-caption-contest">The CAPTION THIS Contest</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 15:31:53 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49327 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Open Post: Hosted By Jennifer Lawrence&#039;s Hot 70s Prom Hair </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/open-post-hosted-jennifer-lawrences-hot-70s-prom-hair</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;No, these aren&#039;t pictures from the set of the &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Legally Blonde&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; prequel starring &lt;b&gt;Jennifer Lawrence &lt;/b&gt;as a young version of &lt;b&gt;Jennifer Coolidge&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; character. These are pictures of Jennifer Lawrence on the set of that &lt;b&gt;David O. Russell &lt;/b&gt;movie about the Abscam operation in Boston. Jennifer plays &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/would-you-hit-it&quot;&gt;Christian Bale&#039;s&lt;/a&gt; wife, so she&#039;s the lucky young bitch who gets to lick his stick-on beard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn&#039;t Jennifer Lawrence wear this same hairstyle at the end of &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Silver Linings Playbook&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; too? Well, we already know that David O. Russell has a serious Jennifer Lawrence fetish and now we know that he also has a serious fetish for 70s updos that are held together with at least 3 cans of Miss Breck hairspray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Jennifer Lawrence should always wear her hair like this, because the&lt;b&gt; Ellen Barkin&lt;/b&gt; in&lt;i&gt; Drop Dead Gorgeous&lt;/i&gt; look IS the look.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/open-post-hosted-jennifer-lawrences-hot-70s-prom-hair#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/385">Open Post</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 15:28:19 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49326 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>FYI: Kim Kardashian Does Not Weigh 200 Pounds </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/fyi-kim-kardashian-does-not-weigh-200-pounds</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;On this week&#039;s priceless cover of InTouch Weekly, they have &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/2013/03/20/kim-kartrashian-cant-stop-eating-and-afraid-kanye-going-cheat-her-because-it&quot;&gt;a herp derp picture of &lt;b&gt;Kim Kartrashian&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; next to the headline &quot;&lt;i&gt;I CAN&#039;T STOP EATING&lt;/i&gt;,&quot; and this week&#039;s National Enquirer also says that she&#039;s gained 65 pounds from Jessica Simpsoning her way through her pregnancy. But Kim says that those stories are about as true as her last marriage. While promoting that&lt;b&gt; Tyler Perry&lt;/b&gt; movie she&#039;s in, &lt;b&gt;Pimp Mama Kris&#039;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;number one ho told &lt;a href=&quot;http://omg.yahoo.com/video/kim-kardashian-dishes-omg-insider-133406526.html&quot;&gt;OMG Insider&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href=&quot;http://ohnotheydidnt.livejournal.com/76419735.html&quot;&gt;ONTD&lt;/a&gt;) that the number 200 doesn&#039;t look back at her when she steps on the scale and she hasn&#039;t turned her mouth into a food court trash can by filling it with tons of delicious junk. Kim also said that she&#039;s not suffocating the Kimye fetus by shoving her body into a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-style/news/kim-kardashian-wears-skin-tight-leather-skirt-fur-stole-in-latest-pregnancy-outfit-picture-2013223&quot;&gt;four-sizes-too-small leather skirt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;It says that I&#039;m like 200 pounds on there. That&#039;s like, definitely a good 60 pounds off. It&#039;s ridiculous. Obviously you don&#039;t want to be called fat, but I&#039;m pregnant. I would hope to gain some weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#039;s so funny is I love junk food and I love fast food, I love sweets, ice cream. I haven&#039;t been able to eat any of that since I&#039;ve been pregnant. I am so sad that I&#039;m not craving like In-N-Out and Taco Bell. None of it. That&#039;s what I was craving before. I&#039;m craving like carrots and celery with ranch.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I wore this like leather skirt and by the way it&#039;s a maternity skirt that I had made. Like everything is bigger. And they&#039;re like, &#039;Oh you can&#039;t wear anything tight. That is ridiculous.&#039; They have pregnancy Spanx that are tighter than the skirt I&#039;m wearing. I want to feel good about myself and still feel fashionable. That&#039;s who I am. Happy mommy, happy baby.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Kim K&#039;s mouth is a ticker tape machine of lies, just reverse everything she said there and that&#039;s the truth. So Kim weighs more than 200 pounds, eats a Double Double animal-style off of Kanye&#039;s pussy hole three times a day and that leather skirt was so tight her baby had to stick its head out of her cooch to get some air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s Kim not looking good and not looking fashionable at LAX last night.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/fyi-kim-kardashian-does-not-weigh-200-pounds#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/194">Kim Kardashian</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/419">Why Are You Pulling My Dick?</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/370">Yeah Okay</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 14:34:52 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49325 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Get Naked And Grab Your Cue Stick! Prince Hot Ginge Is Coming Back To America! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/get-naked-and-grab-your-cue-stick-prince-hot-ginge-coming-back-america</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. is finally getting another dose of its favorite &lt;strike&gt;pastime&lt;/strike&gt; faptime sport: watching &lt;b&gt;Prince Hot Ginge &lt;/b&gt;get dick-out naked for a game of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2012/08/21/dreams-do-come-true-prince-hot-ginge-gets-naked-vegas-my-head-explodes-new-york?page=2&quot;&gt;nude ass billiards!&lt;/a&gt; The streets of New Jersey, NYC, Connecticut, DC and Colorado Springs will all be covered with a river of genital juices this May, because PHG is coming for a visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;St. James Palace announced this morning that starting on May 9th, some of you lucky whores will be breathing in the air that PHG&#039;s crotch carrot exhales out. The third in line to the throne and the first in line to my b-hole will start his American tour by making an appearance at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teamusa.org/US-Paralympics/Military/Warrior-Games-presented-by-Deloitte.aspx&quot;&gt;2013 Warrior Games&lt;/a&gt; in Colorado Springs. I&#039;m going to take a Peter Pan Bus to Colorado Springs, cover my body with suction cups and stick myself to PHG. Once his royal guards pry me off, he will then make his way to New Jersey to visit the victims of Hurricane Sandy. PHG will then visit a landline clearance exhibition on Capitol Hill and he&#039;ll show up to a charity event in NYC. PHG will end his American tour at  the Sentebale Polo Cup in Greenwich, Conn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/prince-harrys-united-states-tour-itinerary-revealed-2013253&quot;&gt;UsWeekly&lt;/a&gt; says that this is strictly a business trip and don&#039;t expect him to get his nipples out while drunkenly partying with some hos. PHG&#039;s press secretary said, &lt;i&gt;&quot;Prince Harry wants to highlight once again the extraordinary commitment and sacrifice of our injured servicemen and women.&quot; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PHG is coming on May 9th, which gives us a little over a month to hypnotize his piece &lt;b&gt;Cressida Boners&lt;/b&gt; into making the biggest mistake of her life by dumping him. Then PHG will have to honor &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/03/17/presenting-headline-my-life&quot;&gt;the solemn oath he drunkenly made&lt;/a&gt; to a random stranger in front of a club on the streets of London. He&#039;ll have to go gay. I better call the Warrior Games and ask them how much it&#039;ll cost me for them to tattoo my Grindr username on the forehead of every athlete that PHG&#039;s supposed to meet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/get-naked-and-grab-your-cue-stick-prince-hot-ginge-coming-back-america#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/finally-some-good-news">Finally Some Good News</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/300">Prince Hot Ginge</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 13:43:07 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49324 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Casper Smart Has Hair Now </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/casper-smart-has-hair-now</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;This is why you should always keep your Chia Pet seeds out of the reach of children, because if you don&#039;t they will sprinkle some on their heads and grow a lawn of brown Chia hair like &lt;b&gt;Casper Smart &lt;/b&gt;did. At &lt;i&gt;Muhammad Ali&#039;s Celebrity Fight Night XIX&#039;&lt;/i&gt; at the JW Marriott in Phoenix, AZ on Saturday night, Casper the Friendly Boy Toy showed off his freshly grown locks which go perfectly with the hair pimple below is lower lip. If Casper Smart was going for the &quot;&lt;i&gt;Monchhichi disguised as KFed circa 2007&lt;/i&gt;&quot; look or the &quot;&lt;i&gt;Huey Duck in a toupee&lt;/i&gt;&quot; look, then he nailed it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bet &lt;b&gt;JLo&lt;/b&gt; is the one who made Casper Smart grow hair on his dome. JLo knows that it was easy for Casper Smart to take a Baby Wipe to the top of his bald head after one of his glory hole buddies busted a pearl necklace on it, and it&#039;s kind of hard to easily get rid of the evidence now that his head is covered with hair. JLo just have to ruin EVERYTHING!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/25/casper-smart-has-hair-now#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/casper-smart">Casper Smart</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/117">Jennifer Lopez</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/not-look">Not The Look</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 12:26:56 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49323 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
