<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://dlisted.com" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Dlisted - Be Very Afraid</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Jada Pinkett Smith On The Rumor That She And Will Smith Have An Open Marriage </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/jada-pinkett-smith-rumors-she-and-will-smith-have-open-marriage</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/2013/03/12/jada-pinkett-smith-wants-everybody-stop-bullying-young-celebrities&quot;&gt;The prophet of Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;, Jada Pinkett Smith&lt;/b&gt;, is always up for opening her mouth to talk about her marriage and she&#039;s already&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/node/32960&quot;&gt; told everyone&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;b&gt;Will&lt;/b&gt; and her are boning all the time. They bone until their fuck parts fall off, then they slap their fuck parts back on and keep on boning. So because Jada is all for talking about her marriage,&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/03/jada-pinkett-will-smith-open-relationship-rumor_n_3007718.html?utm_hp_ref=mostpopular&quot;&gt; HuffPo Live&lt;/a&gt; asked her about the rumor that she and Will are allowed to pass their genitals to who ever they want, whenever they want. Jada spit out a quick &quot;&lt;i&gt;no&lt;/i&gt;&quot; and then she explained that Will can stick his dick in anything he wants as long as he can look himself in the mirror afterward. Jada said this shit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;I think people get that idea, because Will and I are very relaxed with one another. You know, from how I&#039;ve answered questions like, &#039;&lt;i&gt;Girl, what would you do if he came home and this and that and that and being married to a big superstar like Will, how do you deal with other women&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&#039; I&#039;ve always told Will, &#039;&lt;i&gt;You can do whatever you want as long as you can look at yourself in the mirror and be okay.&lt;/i&gt;&#039; Because at the end of the day, Will is his own man. I&#039;m here as his partner, but he is his own man. He has to decide who he wants to be and that&#039;s not for me to do for him. Or vice versa.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what I&#039;m getting from this is that Will Smith doesn&#039;t own a mirror and hasn&#039;t looked at one in years and he uses his iPhone camera to check to see if his forehead needs another visit from the Botox needle. Jada didn&#039;t say anything about looking at himself in his iPhone camera. And somewhere &lt;b&gt;Tiger Woods &lt;/b&gt;is cursing at God for not making Jada Pinkett a straight white woman with blond hair. He would&#039;ve married her so hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#039;s Will and a Madame-fied Jada at the premiere of &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Free Angela and all Political Prisoners &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;in NYC last night. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/jada-pinkett-smith-rumors-she-and-will-smith-have-open-marriage#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/jada-pinkett-smith">Jada Pinkett Smith</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/355">Will Smith</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/370">Yeah Okay</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 18:40:24 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49460 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Afternoon Crumbs </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/afternoon-crumbs</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;For once, I&#039;m going to thank&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;Brit Brit&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;for decorating her feet with the official footwear of Hell, because those&amp;nbsp;UGGs&amp;nbsp;are distracting me from her possible camel toe situation -&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.justjared.com/2013/04/04/britney-spears-david-lucado-hold-hands-at-vons/&quot;&gt;Just Jared&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you want to fill your ear holes with a few bars of&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;Beyonce&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; cover of &quot;&lt;i&gt;Back to Black&lt;/i&gt;&quot; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laineygossip.com/New-Great-Gatsby-trailer-features-gorgeous-Leonardo-DiCaprio-and-great-soundtrack/26438&quot;&gt;Lainey Gossip &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;EJ Johnson&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;can protect himself by beating a trick with his pocket book, but &lt;b&gt;Magic Johnson&lt;/b&gt; has his back just in case - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.towleroad.com/2013/04/magicej.html&quot;&gt;Towleroad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s &lt;b&gt;Heidi Klum&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; uncensored life-saving nip - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thesuperficial.com/heidi-klum-bikini-beach-rescue-riptide-hawaii-04-2013&quot;&gt;The Superficial&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ryan Gosling&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; new movie just looks like &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drive&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; in Bangkok, but I&#039;d still let him drag me around by my mouth - &lt;a href=&quot;http://jezebel.com/5993597/your-boyfriend-ryan-gosling-is-so-hot-when-hes-a-stone+faced-killer&quot;&gt;Jezebel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ivanka Trump&lt;/b&gt; is working working working working working always working - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.celebitchy.com/290021/ivanka_trump_works_16_hour_days_i_think_it_makes_me_a_better_mom_when_im_home/&quot;&gt;Celebitchy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mimi&lt;/b&gt; needs to visit the Gay Mermtailor of Florida if she really wants to be a magical mermaid - &lt;a href=&quot;http://drunkenstepfather.com/2013/04/03/mariah-carey-is-a-mermaid-sent-from-heaven-of-the-day#.UV3hg795iXI&quot;&gt;Drunken Stepfather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Today&#039;s&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;Jill Martin&lt;/b&gt; is in a two piece and in his office at 30 Rock, &lt;b&gt;Matt Lauer&lt;/b&gt; just shut the door and grabbed the lotion - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hollywoodtuna.com/?p=91952&quot;&gt;Hollywood Tuna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish &lt;b&gt;Mrs. Roper&lt;/b&gt; was still alive today so she could show that trick &lt;b&gt;MiserAlba&lt;/b&gt; how to really wear that caftan - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popoholic.com/2013/04/04/jessica-alba-hits-the-beach/&quot;&gt;Popoholic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, &lt;b&gt;Matthew Lillard,&lt;/b&gt; you have to take off &lt;b&gt;John Stamos&#039;&lt;/b&gt; clothes before you try to suck off his nipple knob - &lt;a href=&quot;http://theberry.com/2013/04/04/celebs-airbrush-twitter-pics-17-photos-8/&quot;&gt;The Berry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank every God for pixelated bars - &lt;a href=&quot;http://icydk.com/2013/04/04/video-chelsea-handler-and-conan-obrien-naked-in-the-shower-together/&quot;&gt;ICYDK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another day, another &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Real Housewives of New Jersey &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;brawl - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.realitytea.com/2013/04/04/breaking-police-investigating-real-housewives-of-new-jerseys-posche-2-brawl-possible-assault-charges-to-be-filed-against-joe-gorga-chris-laurita/&quot;&gt;Reality Tea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that really is &lt;b&gt;Sisquo&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; peen, then Sisquo&#039;s peen has been through some serious shit - (NSFW) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omgblog.com/2013/04/omg_let_me_see_that_schlong_si.php&quot;&gt;OMG Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rob Kartrashian&lt;/b&gt; and Pimp Mama Kris look like fools, but what else is new? - &lt;a href=&quot;http://moejackson.com/2013/04/04/rob-kardashian-found-himself-a-hot-new-girlfriend-naza-jafarian/&quot;&gt;Moe Jackson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;RPattz&lt;/b&gt; duckfaces it in Los Feliz while holding hands with &lt;b&gt;KStew&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popsugar.com/Kristen-Stewart-Robert-Pattinson-Hold-Hands-Photos-29054264&quot;&gt;Popsugar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this &lt;b&gt;Jay Leno&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;recreation of the &lt;b&gt;Kim Kardashian&lt;/b&gt; sex tape? - &lt;a href=&quot;http://seriouslyomg.com/?p=32864&quot;&gt;SOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; goes shopping for groceries, manages not to catch herself a new boyfriend while doing so - &lt;a href=&quot;http://imnotobsessed.com/2013/04/04/taylor-swift-hitting-grocery-store/&quot;&gt;I&#039;m Not Obsessed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you expect with a name like&lt;b&gt; Daddy Yankee&lt;/b&gt;? - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.queerty.com/daddy-yankee-comes-out-of-the-closet-and-then-quickly-goes-back-in-20130403/&quot;&gt;Queerty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/afternoon-crumbs#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/afternoon-crumbs">Afternoon Crumbs</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 17:01:27 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49459 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Roger Ebert Dies At The Age Of 70 </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/roger-ebert-dies-age-70</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a couple of days after&lt;b&gt; Roger Ebert&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ebertchicago/status/319316948045422593&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that his cancer came back and he&#039;s taking a &lt;i&gt;&quot;leave of presence&lt;/i&gt;,&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.suntimes.com/news/metro/17320958-418/roger-ebert-dies-at-70-after-battle-with-cancer.html&quot;&gt;The Chicago Sun-Times &lt;/a&gt;reports that he passed away at the age of 70. Roger Ebert was diagnosed with thyroid cancer in 2007 and four years later he lost his ability to talk and eat when doctors removed part of his lower jaw, but that didn&#039;t stop him doing what he loved and he kept reviewing movies almost until the end. Here&#039;s what Roger &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.suntimes.com/ebert/2009/05/go_gently_into_that_good_night.html&quot;&gt;said a few years ago&lt;/a&gt; about death. A dust storm is coming your way, so grab your crying cloth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;I know it is coming, and I do not fear it, because I believe there is nothing on the other side of death to fear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I hope to be spared as much pain as possible on the approach path. I was perfectly content before I was born, and I think of death as the same state. What I am grateful for is the gift of intelligence, and for life, love, wonder, and laughter. You can’t say it wasn’t interesting. My lifetime’s memories are what I have brought home from the trip. I will require them for eternity no more than that little souvenir of the Eiffel Tower I brought home from Paris.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now he&#039;s in a screening room in heaven, fighting with Gene Siskel. Rest in peace, Roger Ebert.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/roger-ebert-dies-age-70#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/sadness">Sadness</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 16:00:46 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49458 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The CAPTION THIS Contest For April 4th! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/caption-contest-april-4th</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.break.com/pictures/coolest-pics-of-4413-diving-with-the-inflatable-girlfriend-2430217&quot;&gt;Break.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/caption-contest-april-4th#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/-caption-contest">The CAPTION THIS Contest</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 15:24:40 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49457 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Open Post: Hosted By Grumpy Cat&#039;s First Birthday </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/open-post-hosted-grumpy-cats-first-birthday</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Even sharing a birthday with &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/birthday-sluts-1&quot;&gt;RDJ&lt;/a&gt; and getting the chance to eat her own face can&#039;t bring a smile out of &lt;b&gt;Tardar Sauce&lt;/b&gt;. Unhappy Barfday, Grumpy Cat! Here&#039;s to another grumpy ass year! (Side note: Grumpy Cat is kind of making the same face I made on my birthday when I was drunk, gassy and wishing that there were more frosting flowers on my grocery store cake.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/open-post-hosted-grumpy-cats-first-birthday#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/385">Open Post</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 15:15:45 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49456 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>One Of Lindsay Lohan&#039;s Sugar Daddies Arrested For Drug Possession and Trafficking</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/one-lindsay-lohans-sugar-daddies-arrested-drug-possession-and-trafficking</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;41-year-old multi-millionaire hotelier &lt;b&gt;Vikram Chatwal&lt;/b&gt;, better known a&lt;b&gt;s Lindsay Lohan&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;regular, was put into handcuffs at Florida&#039;s Fort Lauderdale/Hollywood International Airport on Tuesday when his stupid ass tried to get onto an airplane with a whole lot of drugs shoved into his panties and carry-on. What an amateur. LiLo has never been more embarrassed, because she can shove half of Bolivia into her Chocha Full of Grace and easily walk by a drug-sniffing dog. The drug-sniffing dog&#039;s nose doesn&#039;t even twitch, but probably because it knows to hold its breath whenever she walks by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20688189,00.html&quot;&gt;People&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/04/lindsay-lohan-dream-hotel-owner-vikram-chatwal-arrested-drugs/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; say that TSA found 6 grams of heroin, coke, Xanax, weed, cat tranquilizers and other pills hidden in his crotch area and bag. Vikram didn&#039;t have a prescription for any of those drugs and he later admitted that he bought all of that shit illegally. The TSA handed him over to the Broward County Sherrif&#039;s Office and he was booked on one count of trafficking and seven counts of possession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LiLo couldn&#039;t be reached for comment, because she was too busy scratching out Vikram&#039;s number from her black book. How can she be associated with a first degree dum-dum who didn&#039;t use the fool-proof &lt;i&gt;&quot;THAT&#039;S NOT MY CROTCH! THAT&#039;S NOT MY BAG!&lt;/i&gt;&quot; excuse? But Michael Lohan was available for comment (duh) and he told &lt;a href=&quot;http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/04/lindsay-lohan-sugar-daddy-busted-drugs-vikram-chatwal/&quot;&gt;Radar&lt;/a&gt; that he&#039;s really happy about this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&quot;I hope all the money in the world can’t get him out of this one. After seeing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thesuperficial.com/lindsay-lohan-dream-hotel-owner-vikram-chatwal-coke-2-12-2011&quot;&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt; of him in the past partying with Lindsay in the Dream Hotel it scares me to think that he had ketamine in his possession. I can only image what might have or would have happened to Lindsay with a sick person like this. Even worse, after communicating with Dina she has the nerve to actually defend Vikram. Birds of a feather flock together!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course White Oprah&#039;s going to defend Vikram. You never bite the hand that feeds you coke. It&#039;s kind of funny, because &amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&quot;I can only image what might happen to Lindsay with a sick person like this&quot;&lt;/i&gt; is the same thing the nurse thought to herself when she handed over a baby LiLo to Michael Lohan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#039;s LiLo, Vikram and her other sugar daddy &lt;b&gt;Domingo Zapata&lt;/b&gt; at some gallery show opening last year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/one-lindsay-lohans-sugar-daddies-arrested-drug-possession-and-trafficking#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/476">Bad Shit</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/lindsay-lohan">Lindsay Lohan</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/mess">MESS!</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/536">Well Well Well</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 14:19:36 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49455 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Beyonce Dances With Beyonce In A New Commercial Promoting Beyonce (And Pepsi)</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/beyonce-dances-beyonce-new-commercial-promoting-beyonce-and-pepsi</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;445&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/_2smYVl0zrk?feature=player_embedded&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, &lt;b&gt;Beyonce&lt;/b&gt; released &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rap-up.com/2013/04/03/video-beyonce-teases-4-4-13-announcement-beyherenow/&quot;&gt;a mysterious teaser trailer&lt;/a&gt; for something big that was going to happen on April 4th. The bumblebeys of the beyhive all stung each other out of excitement, because they thought she was going to throw a new song at them, but nope. It turns out her &quot;&lt;i&gt;something big&lt;/i&gt;&quot; is a Pepsi commercial. It shouldn&#039;t be surprising that Beyonce releases a teaser trailer for a commercial since she releases a teaser trailer five minutes before she has a bowel movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess drinking Pepsi while you&#039;re under the influence of yourself and wig glue makes you hallucinate, because Beyonce starts a dance-off with Beyonces of the past. Whatever, I&#039;ll save my excitement for when &lt;b&gt;Basement Baby&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;commercial for Mountain Lighting airs on Public Access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/beyonce-dances-beyonce-new-commercial-promoting-beyonce-and-pepsi#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/112">Beyonce</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/463">I Can&amp;#039;t With You</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 13:13:15 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49454 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Well, At Least Ho Let Her Bump Breathe </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/well-least-ho-let-her-bump-breathe</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking like the Ghost of Fame Whores Present, &lt;b&gt;Kim Kartrashian &lt;/b&gt;walked into a frozen yogurt place in Sherman Oaks, CA yesterday and that tension you feel is from her bra using its last strength to hold up her two ton titty balls. Maybe it&#039;s because I&#039;m so used to seeing Kim looking like a pork sausage busting out of its leather casing, but titty trauma and face aside, this isn&#039;t completely hurting my eyeballs. I mean, the good news is that she isn&#039;t suffocating her bump with ten layers of Spanx and a leather skirt that&#039;s tighter than &lt;b&gt;Kanye&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; b-hole after he got anal rejuvenation surgery the first time. If Kim continues to let her bump breathe, then maybe her publicity stunt baby won&#039;t be born all elongated and with its eyes smushed shut, which I guess is a bad thing since then it&#039;ll be able to clearly see who its parents are. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And replacing Botox with an all-natural replacement (aka Kanye&#039;s ass syrup) is making Kim&#039;s face morph back into its original state. She looks like a Saw puppet version of OctoMom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other Kartrashian news, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/03/kim-kardashian-kris-humphries-divorice-trial-start-date/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; says that Kim won&#039;t be in court on the first day of her divorce war against&lt;b&gt; Kris Humphries&lt;/b&gt;, because she has to whore out her new bottle of stank water in NYC. Kim&#039;s lawyer tried to get the date moved from May 6th to May 3rd, but the judge denied her. Kim doesn&#039;t have to be in court on the first day anyway. Kim is expected to testify on the second or third day of the trial, so that gives &lt;b&gt;Pimp Mama Kris&lt;/b&gt; plenty of time to program a pre-written script of lies into her hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/well-least-ho-let-her-bump-breathe#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/276">Chichis</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/194">Kim Kardashian</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/382">Your Face Scares Me</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 12:30:43 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49453 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The Hottest Boy On Girls Quits Girls </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/hottest-boy-girls-quits-girls</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;I should correct that title. Personally, I think that &lt;b&gt;Adam&lt;/b&gt; is the hottest guy on &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Girls&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, because I&#039;m gross and have a thing for long-faced, Afghan Hound-looking dudes who look like they smell like snots and always have crusty sleepies in their eyes. Glad I could clear that up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/cutest_boy_leaving_girls_0IrrLAkGdxV4Nqu1N1JxMI&quot;&gt;Page Six &lt;/a&gt;says that &lt;b&gt;Christopher Abbott,&lt;/b&gt; who plays Charlie on &lt;i&gt;Girls&lt;/i&gt;, figuratively flipped&lt;b&gt; Lena Dunham&lt;/b&gt; off, pushed the emergency exit and &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/node/38378&quot;&gt;slid down the inflatable yellow slide&lt;/a&gt; to freedom. A source says that as soon as shooting for season 3 started, Charlie and Lena Dunham started fighting about the direction of his character. Season 2 ended (SPOILER ALERT) with Charlie getting back together with the oh-so-pube-pulling-annoying Marnie after he got rich from inventing some app. Christopher Abbot&#039;s rep confirmed that he&#039;s not going to be on the show next season:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
“[Chris] is grateful for the experience of collaborating with Lena, Judd [Apatow], and the entire ‘Girls’ cast and crew, but right now he’s working on numerous other projects and has decided not to return to the show.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rep for HBO said that Lena Dunham will slap a black curly wig on her right tit and it will resume the role of Charlie.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/hottest-boy-girls-quits-girls#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/girls">Girls</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/quit-bitch">Quit This Bitch</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 11:00:37 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49452 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Amanda Bynes&#039; Impostor Is Still Out There! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/amanda-bynes-impostor-still-out-there</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;On April 2nd, the paparazzi took pictures of&lt;b&gt; Amanda Byne&lt;/b&gt;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/amanda-bynes-claims-she-has-a-redheaded-impostor-picture-201334&quot;&gt;with chola burgundy hair and Nike sandals with white socks on her feet&lt;/a&gt;. The last part was the biggest cry for help, because you should only wear Adidas sandals with white socks if the year is 2005 and your name is &lt;b&gt;KFed&lt;/b&gt;. But that night, Amanda Bynes went on twitter and claimed that somebody was identity thieving her ass. Amanda claimed it wasn&#039;t her in the pictures, because her blond hair has never touched a bowl full of blackberry Kool-Aid hair dye. We all sort of quietly nodded while hiding all the pink wigs, green umbrellas and barber clippers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then last night, Amanda tried to clear her name again by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AmandaBynes&quot;&gt;tweeting&lt;/a&gt; (and deleting) the picture above along with this denial:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/files/images/amandabynestwitternotthatgirl.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That lavender MS Paint splatter says it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Amanda&#039;s sanity is slowly spiraling down the gutter drains on the streets of Times Square, then somebody needs to come and get this child. If this is all just some elaborate, never-ending performance art piece, then somebody needs to come and get this child. If Amanda is just really method and this is all research for her new role in the Lindsay Lohan biopic, then somebody needs to come and get this child. What I&#039;m saying is that whatever the reason for this is, somebody needs to help a ho out, because loved ones don&#039;t let loved ones wear Adidas sandals in the year 2013 no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, when Amanda screamed &lt;i&gt;&quot;IMPOSTOR!&lt;/i&gt;&quot; the first time, I looked at the pictures and I actually thought to myself, &lt;i&gt;&quot;Hmmm, maybe that isn&#039;t her.&quot;&lt;/i&gt; She got to me! She&#039;s making me believe. This is what she wants me to think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And somebody really needs to slap a warning label on &lt;b&gt;Kid Cudi&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; dick, because this is what happens when you take a spin on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#039;s Not Amanda Bynes hiding Not Amanda Bynes&#039; face in NYC yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/04/04/amanda-bynes-impostor-still-out-there#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/amanda-bynes">Amanda Bynes</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/good-god-girl-get-grip">Good God Girl Get A Grip</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 10:42:25 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49451 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
