<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://dlisted.com" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Dlisted - Be Very Afraid</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Brit Brit And Normal Guy Dave Held Hands In Public, But What In 50s Diner Waitress Hell Is She Wearing? </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/brit-brit-and-normal-guy-dave-held-hands-public-what-50s-diner-waitress-hell-she-wearing</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Daddy Spears&lt;/b&gt; obviously insists on sending &lt;b&gt;Brit Brit&lt;/b&gt; out for staged hand holding photo-ops with her leased boyfriend &lt;b&gt;David Somethingoranother&lt;/b&gt;, but couldn&#039;t he fix her style beforehand? This makes the veins in my eyeballs hurt since we&#039;re so used to seeing Brit Brit looking like the fashion icon she is&amp;nbsp;in baggy, grease-stained sweats, a t-shirt that doubles as a booger rag and fug boots that are meant to be given out as a gag gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked that dress better when&lt;b&gt; Lily Tomlin&lt;/b&gt; wore it in &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Big Business&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. It looks like something a &lt;b style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Project Runway &lt;/b&gt;contestant would come up with if they had to make a flight attendant dress out of tablecloths and napkins from a Sweet 16 birthday party. And she just had to go full fug by pairing a black and pink dress with your memaw&#039;s least favorite brown church shoes. Those are dookie shoes. And he looks like the maitre d&#039; of a Cracker Barrel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swear, Daddy Spears is totally just screwing with us now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/brit-brit-and-normal-guy-dave-held-hands-public-what-50s-diner-waitress-hell-she-wearing#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/britney-spears">Britney Spears</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/fug">Fug</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/536">Well Well Well</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:28:37 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49304 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>One Of Ashley Greene&#039;s Dogs Died In A Fire That Destroyed Her Condo (UPDATE) </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/one-ashley-greenes-dogs-died-fire-destroyed-her-condo</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s some shitty and sad news for your Friday afternoon... One of &lt;b&gt;Ashley Greene&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; dog is up in heaven now after it died in a fire that broke out this morning and completely destroyed her condo in West Hollywood. Ashley had two dog friends, &lt;b&gt;Marlo&lt;/b&gt; (pictured with her above) and &lt;b&gt;Theo&lt;/b&gt;, and one of them survived. It&#039;s not known which one died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashley&#039;s rep tells &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/ashley-greenes-apartment-destroyed-in-fire-dog-dies-in-blaze-2013223&quot;&gt;UsWeekly&lt;/a&gt; that she wasn&#039;t home when the fire broke out on the couch this morning, but she drove over there as soon as one of her neighbors called to tell her what happened. But &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/22/ashley-greene-apartment-fire-west-hollywood-l-a/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; heard a different story. A firefighter at the scene told TMZ that Ashley, her boyfriend (who apparently &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laineygossip.com/Is-Ashley-Greene-dating-Ryan-Phillippe/26340&quot;&gt;isn&#039;t Ryan Phillippe&lt;/a&gt;) and her brother were out late last night so they were sleeping in. A fire started on the sofa in the living room and after they woke up and realized the whole place was in flames, they ran out of there without the dogs. They all realized that the dogs didn&#039;t run out with them, so her boyfriend and her brother tried to go back to get them, but they weren&#039;t able to. As Ashley&#039;s neighbors tried to control the fire with fire extinguishers, one dog made it out. One of Ashley&#039;s nosy neighbors tells TMZ that before the fire, her brother and her boyfriend were going in and out of the apartment all morning and they heard glass breaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a fire broke out in my apartment, the only things I&#039;d grab would be my bong and my dog. If a fire broke out in my apartment, I&#039;d like to think that my dog would grab me too, but he&#039;d probably just grab the bacon from the fridge. Speaking of bacon, I should probably put back the battery I took out of the smoke alarm in my living room because it kept going off every time I cooked bacon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rest in peace, Ashley&#039;s doggy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/22/ashley-greene-fire-unattended-candle-cause-dog-died/&quot;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt; says that a candle was the cause. Somebody left a candle on and it somehow fell on the sofa and started the fire.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/one-ashley-greenes-dogs-died-fire-destroyed-her-condo#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/707">Ashley Greene</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/sadness">Sadness</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 18:37:38 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49302 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Afternoon Crumbs </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/afternoon-crumbs</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Princess Charlene of Monaco&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;wore this for Pope Francis the Fist&#039;s debut at The Vatican, but she probably wears this same outfit every day to mourn the death of her freedom - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laineygossip.com/Andrea-Casiraghi-welcomes-baby-boy-heir-of-Monaco-as-Prince-Albert-and-Charlene-at-Pope-inauguration/26344&quot;&gt;Lainey Gossip&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody put &lt;b&gt;Gucci Mane &lt;/b&gt;and &lt;b&gt;Kim Kardashian&lt;/b&gt; together or he&#039;ll slip into a coma from stage 5 boredom - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thesuperficial.com/gucci-mane-spring-breakers-sex-scene-fell-asleep-03-2013&quot;&gt;The Superficial&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 pictures that make me either want to spend the day fapping or spend the day using the ab roller that&#039;s collecting dust in the corner - &lt;a href=&quot;http://theberry.com/2013/03/22/shirtless-friday-29-photos-16/&quot;&gt;The Berry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Brangie&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; child army can only speak French to her - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.celebitchy.com/287440/the_villainess_jolie_ignores_her_children_until_they_speak_to_her_in_french/&quot;&gt;Celebitchy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tina Fey&lt;/b&gt; as &lt;b&gt;Sarah Palin&lt;/b&gt; 2016! - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.towleroad.com/2013/03/feypalin.html&quot;&gt;Towleroad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.....and then the machine broke -&lt;a href=&quot;http://drunkenstepfather.com/2013/03/22/cocos-workout-pic-of-the-day#.UUy1UqV5iXI&quot;&gt; Drunken Stepfather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IN THIS ECONOMY, it was very financially smart for &lt;b&gt;Heather Graham&lt;/b&gt; to re-wear the dress she wore to junior prom in 1986 - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hollywoodtuna.com/?p=91214&quot;&gt;Hollywood Tuna&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#039;ll finally get more servings of&lt;b&gt; La Bruja&lt;/b&gt;, because &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Real Housewives of Miami &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;has started filming again - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.realitytea.com/2013/03/21/has-filming-started-for-the-third-season-of-real-housewives-of-miami/&quot;&gt;Reality Tea&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rose McGowan &lt;/b&gt;or &lt;b&gt;Chrissy Crocker &lt;/b&gt;circa 2006 after a blowout? - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popoholic.com/2013/03/22/rose-mcgowans-hotness-is-starting-to-make-a-comeback/&quot;&gt;Popoholic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like feeling emotions, here&#039;s a story about &lt;b&gt;Dax Shepard&#039;s d&lt;/b&gt;ying father meeting his unborn baby - &lt;a href=&quot;http://icydk.com/2013/03/21/dax-shepard-opens-up-about-losing-his-father-and-shares-precious-picture-of-him-meeting-his-unborn-grandchild/&quot;&gt;ICYDK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rebel Wilson&lt;/b&gt; might be in &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Hunger Games&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.... - &lt;a href=&quot;http://imnotobsessed.com/2013/03/22/rebel-wilson-joining-cast-hunger-games/&quot;&gt;I&#039;m Not Obsessed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why you should never take &quot;&lt;i&gt;kill it with fire&lt;/i&gt;&quot; literally - &lt;a href=&quot;http://gawker.com/5991942/womans-house-burns-to-the-ground-after-she-tries-to-kill-a-snake-with-fire&quot;&gt;Gawker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#039;s &lt;b&gt;Kelly Brook&lt;/b&gt; getting out of a car - &lt;a href=&quot;http://idontlikeyouinthatway.com/2013/03/good-morning-kelly-brook.html&quot;&gt;IDLYITW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Um, being married to &lt;b&gt;Daniel Day-Lewis &lt;/b&gt;is like fucking a different man every night, because he always takes work home with him - &lt;a href=&quot;http://videogum.com/691182/what-its-like-being-married-to-daniel-day-lewis/news/&quot;&gt;Videogum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lindsay Lohan &lt;/b&gt;should&#039;ve stolen a bra during her little &quot;&lt;i&gt;shopping&lt;/i&gt;&quot; trip - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.justjared.com/2013/03/22/lindsay-lohan-shopping-after-taking-court-plea-deal/&quot;&gt;Just Jared&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are&lt;b&gt; Duchess Kate &lt;/b&gt;and the Cub Scouts making campfire churros? - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.popsugar.com/Kate-Middleton-Camping-Cub-Scouts-28770224&quot;&gt;Popsugar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/afternoon-crumbs#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/afternoon-crumbs">Afternoon Crumbs</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 16:25:10 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49301 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The CAPTION THIS Contest For March 22nd! </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/caption-contest-march-22nd</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;http://cheezburger.com/7124732160&quot;&gt;Picture Is Unrelated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/caption-contest-march-22nd#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/-caption-contest">The CAPTION THIS Contest</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:28:29 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49300 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Open Post: Hosted By Tom Hardy Kissing A Pit Bull Puppy </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/open-post-hosted-tom-hardy-kissing-pit-bull-puppy</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&#039;s all take a little time out from being bitches to awwwww all over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/03/11/oh-its-just-tom-hardy-and-puppy-sweater&quot;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/2013/03/19/open-post-hosted-tom-hardy-noomi-rapace-and-pit-bull-puppy&quot;&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt; from the Brooklyn set of &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Animal Practice&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; of 2013&#039;s couple of the year: &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tom Hardy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; and his pit bully puppy. Actually, these pictures make me want to be a bigger bitch, but I don&#039;t know who to be a bitch toward: the pit bull puppy for getting to lick on Tom Hardy&#039;s triple stuffed sausage lips or Tom Hardy for getting to hug that puppy. Let&#039;s just be bitches toward that jacket for getting to be near both of them. I hate that jacket.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/open-post-hosted-tom-hardy-kissing-pit-bull-puppy#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/385">Open Post</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:26:21 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49299 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>You Too Can Look Like A Fresh Spring One Percenter For Just $458,000</title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/you-too-can-look-fresh-spring-one-percenter-just-458000</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;Goop&#039;s Fashion Picks for Spring is so damn popular and she get so many requests for it that she has brought it back for a third year in a row. 99% of those emails are probably from people telling her to please bring it back up, because it makes them laugh so damn hard that they make a wet spot in their $2 cotton panties from KMart.&amp;nbsp;If you&#039;re Elin Nordegren, all you have to do is shake the change of your purse and you can buy everything on &lt;b&gt;Goopy Paltrow&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; fashion list for spring. If you&#039;re everybody else, all you have to do is sell your house, sell your car, sell every drop of blood in your body, empty out your checking account, rob a bank and blow Charlie Sheen a few times, and you too can buy a bunch of designer clothes you can&#039;t wear anywhere without looking a fool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this week&#039;s edition of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goop.com/journal/get/217/annual-spring-edit&quot;&gt;Goop&lt;/a&gt;, Goopy showed her readers how they can update their spring wardrobe using stuff they can buy from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.net-a-porter.com/&quot;&gt;Net-A-Porter&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eonline.com/news/400004/gwyneth-paltrow-shows-you-how-to-update-your-spring-wardrobe-with-450-000-worth-of-products&quot;&gt;E!&lt;/a&gt; totaled everything up on her list and it came to only $458,003! On the list is a $5,495 Valentino bag, $850 Alexander Wang leather shorts (which will make you look like you have a wang) and an $895 Victoria Beckham dress. The $475 fancy shorts in the picture above are perfect to wear during a lunch date with your husband. When he doesn&#039;t show up, the shininess of the shorts will make you forget that your husband hates you, because you&#039;re ridiculous and is probably in a cheap motel room shoving his face in a pile of Twinkies just to spite you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite thing on the list is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/node/49298/images/goodspring5.jpg&quot;&gt;a $1,615 skirt&lt;/a&gt;, which Goopy says is a wonderful thing to wear during a night in with your friends. Yes, a $1,600 ball gown skirt is the perfect thing to wear while hanging out with your friends at home. Oh, you&#039;ll feel so comfortable wearing a $1,600 skirt while lounging on your red panda leather sofa. When your friend Bunny accidentally spills a glass of vintage Krug (it&#039;s a casual night-in, you save the good stuff for formal events) on your $1,600 skirt after you tell a joke about how you saw Muffy carrying a COACH purse into the tennis club, you don&#039;t have to freak out. It&#039;s just a casual $1,600 skirt. You&#039;ll just tell your maid to cut it into squares to use as wee wee pads for the Burmese ponies you bought for little Pomegranate and Jeduthun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hope Goop stays so unaware and never pulls her head out of her ass, because all of this is gold. Oh wait, I don&#039;t mean gold. Gold is for the poors!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/you-too-can-look-fresh-spring-one-percenter-just-458000#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/242">Girlfriend Please</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/147">Gwyneth Paltrow</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/tales-one-percent">Tales From The One Percent</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/you-fancy">You Fancy</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:49:24 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49298 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Damn, Dat Ass </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/david-beckham-bubble-butt-bejing</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#039;t know where I&#039;ve been, because I have never noticed&lt;b&gt; David Beckham&#039;s &lt;/b&gt;beautiful bubble bottom butt before. It&#039;s glorious. Is he wearing push-up panties, because his ass is so high that it looks like it&#039;s worshiping God. No wonder Becks&#039; former stalker &lt;b&gt;Tommy Girl &lt;/b&gt;wanted to surgically attach his tongue to Becks&#039; anus lips. He wanted to wake up in dat ass for the rest of his days and I can&#039;t blame him. I want to lay my head on that ass. I want to eat Thin Mints off that ass. I want to miniaturize myself and jump on it like I&#039;m in a Sleepy&#039;s commercial. I want to stay miniaturized and twirl around on his butt cheeks while singing, &quot;&lt;i&gt;the hiiiiiiiiiills are alive&lt;/i&gt;.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screw that football shit, with nalgas like that, he should be the captain of the Twerk Team. It&#039;s a damn shame that&lt;b&gt; Posh Beckham &lt;/b&gt;won&#039;t munch on his ass, because she thinks butt has too many calories in it. When he wiggles it and convinces her to lick it, she probably pours a little Sensa on it before she eats. How dreadful and a waste of some good Honey Baked ham ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#039;s pictures of Becks&#039; nearly busting the back seams of his pants at a stadium in Bejing yesterday and also pictures of him signing autographs at an event for his H&amp;amp;M bodywear line in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/david-beckham-bubble-butt-bejing#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/david-beckham">David Beckham</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/262">Panty Pudding</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 13:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49297 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Would You Hit It? </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/would-you-hit-it</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;That scent of strawberry shampoo and unattainable dreams wafting into your right nostril is from &lt;b&gt;Amy Adams&#039;&lt;/b&gt; 80s hair commercial hair and that scent of Pierre Cardin cologne and a dried cum stain on a Little Trees wafting into your left nostril is coming from&lt;b&gt; Christian Bale&lt;/b&gt;. Amy Adams and Christian Bale are currently in Boston to shoot &lt;b&gt;David O. Russell&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; newest Oscar-bait movie about the Abscam operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I refuse to believe that Christian Bale put on a bald cap and a comb over wig to look like a sleazy stereotypical used car salesman who jacks into the glove compartment of every car he&#039;s selling and who&#039;s been kicked out of every Waffle House in the area for giving the shocker to all of their waitresses. That isn&#039;t a hairpiece on Christian&#039;s head. Christian doesn&#039;t fake shit. Christian made his scalp stop growing hair with HIS MIND, or he yelled at his follicles in the mirror until they got so scared that they stopped growing hair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, I&#039;d hit it on the vinyl seats in the back of a Chevy Caprice. There&#039;s something about a sleaze ball who keeps his shirt and tie on during fuck times and throws his tie over his shoulder when he&#039;s about to hit it from the back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/would-you-hit-it#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/topics/amy-adams">Amy Adams</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/770">Christian Bale</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/94">Would You Hit It?</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 12:30:57 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49296 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Morrissey Is Probably Going To Retire Soon </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/morrissey-probably-going-retire-soon</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prince William&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Duchess Kate&#039;s&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dlisted.com/2012/08/06/breaking-morrissey-still-hates-british-royals&quot;&gt;#1 fan&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;Morrissey&lt;/b&gt; is down and out in Mexico after he was rushed to the hospital with internal bleeding and stayed there for five weeks. Morrissey has been struck down with the sicks for a while now and he says he was recently hospitalized for five weeks because of a bleeding ulcer, pneumonia and a throat condition called Barrett&#039;s esophagus. Morrissey plans to rest in Mexico and he&#039;s considering retiring so he can focus on his true passion: being the head boss of a gum-selling ring in Tijuana. Morrissey was kind of born to yell at kids to sell more chicles on the streets of Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Morrissey isn&#039;t doing so well right now, he&#039;s canceled his entire North American tour and is thinking about ending his singing career. During an interview with Mexican radio station Reactor 105.7 (via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/morrissey-retiring-smiths-health-career_n_2931658.html&quot;&gt;HuffPo&lt;/a&gt;), they asked Morrissey if all these health problems are making him consider retirement and he said, &quot;&lt;i&gt;I have been cautioned to, but it&#039;s difficult for me because it&#039;s very ingrained in me. It almost became absurd the number of things that happened to me, but everything just attacked me at once. The double pneumonia -- everything was really a result of the fact I had lost so much blood, so the immune defenses were very, very low and couldn&#039;t cope with anything, so therefore the slightest gust of wind and I would have a terrible cold.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in Buckingham Palace, &lt;b&gt;THE QUEEN&lt;/b&gt; is softly caressing her corgis while a smug smile of victory appears on her face, because after weeks upon weeks of making one of her slaves (aka Fergie) sneak into Morrissey&#039;s kitchen to sprinkle arsenic powder on his uncooked quinoa and kale chips, her mission has finally been accomplished. Morrissey&#039;s cunt genes will really explode when he finds out that THE QUEEN bought that arsenic powder with her dole money. Bleehehehehehehhehe!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/morrissey-probably-going-retire-soon#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/673">Morrissey</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:31:58 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49295 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Eva Mendes And Rachel McAdams Are About To Do A Real-Life Duet Of &quot;The Boy Is Mine&quot; </title>
 <link>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/eva-mendes-and-rachel-mcadams-are-about-do-real-life-duet-boy-mine</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;The extremely accurate and beacon of one hundred percent potent truthiness &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nowmagazine.co.uk/celebrity-news/543331/eva-mendes-rages-at-ryan-gosling-s-ex-rachel-mcadams-stay-away-from-my-man#image2&quot;&gt;Now Magazine&lt;/a&gt; says that &lt;b&gt;Eva Mendes&lt;/b&gt; has temporarily put aside her evil plan to take down the Power Rangers and is instead pointing her Orb of Doom at that Gosling-stealing, two-bit hussy whore &lt;b&gt;Rachel McAdams&lt;/b&gt;. A source (aka a drunk intern who also runs the We Hate Evil Menses Tumblr on the side) tells Now that ever since Rachel McAdams &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlisted.com/2013/02/27/rachel-mcadams-and-michael-sheen-broke-too&quot;&gt;broke up with&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;Michael Sheen&lt;/b&gt;, she&#039;s been wiping her heartbroken tears on the shoulder of her ex-piece &lt;b&gt;Ryan Gosling&lt;/b&gt;. Eva, whose right eyebrow always looks like it&#039;s in the &lt;i&gt;&quot;bitch, step back&lt;/i&gt;&quot; position, is really raising her eyebrow in the &quot;&lt;i&gt;bitch, step back&lt;/i&gt;&quot; position, because she wants Rachel McAdams to step away from her man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, Rachel and Ryan stayed friends and talked every now and again when she was with Michael Sheen, but now that she&#039;s single they&#039;ve been talking on the phone even more. The source said, &lt;i&gt;&quot;Rachel&#039;s always kept in touch with Ryan, but now that she&#039;s split with Michael, she&#039;s been calling him and using him as a shoulder to cry on. It hasn&#039;t gone down very well with Eva, to say the least, but Ryan wants to be there as a friend for his ex.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, since the LeAnn Rimes/Eddie Cibrian/Brandi Glanville feud is the bottom shelf version of the Angelina Jolie/Brad Pitt/Jennifer Aniston feud, we needed a middle shelf version too and here it is. This is something to keep hope alive for those McGosling fans who think &lt;i&gt;The Notebook&lt;/i&gt; is real-life and Ryan and Rachel will be sucking rain water off of each other&#039;s faces in the end. Ain&#039;t no love like Canadian love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shit probably isn&#039;t true, but it still makes for the perfect triangle. Rachel McAdams is a wholesome-looking white angel with golden hair like a melted halo and Eva looks like an 80s soap opera villainess who can steal your man and half of your company in one day. I mean, she even dresses like Alexis Carrington (see: pictures of her outside of Letterman below). So that is why I will always wear a Team Eva t-shirt from Kitson (do they still sell &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.monstersandcritics.com/people/news/article_8728.php/Aniston_versus_Jolie_T-shirts&quot;&gt;that shit&lt;/a&gt;?).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://dlisted.com/2013/03/22/eva-mendes-and-rachel-mcadams-are-about-do-real-life-duet-boy-mine#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/296">Eva Mendes</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/211">Rachel McAdams</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/312">Ryan Gosling</category>
 <category domain="http://dlisted.com/taxonomy/term/419">Why Are You Pulling My Dick?</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 10:39:47 -0400</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael K</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">49294 at http://dlisted.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
