<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.boingboing.net/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0"><channel><title>Boing Boing</title><link>http://boingboing.net</link><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.boingboing.net/boingboing/iBag" /><description>Brain candy for Happy Mutants</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 08:42:16 PDT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.1</generator><sy:updatePeriod xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/">hourly</sy:updatePeriod><sy:updateFrequency xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/">1</sy:updateFrequency><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.boingboing.net/boingboing/iBag" /><feedburner:info uri="boingboing/ibag" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><image><link>http://boingboing.net</link><url>http://boingboing.net/icons/bb144.jpg</url><title>Boing Boing</title></image><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item><title>Around the World in 80 Cakes</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/9ywp6zBZg5g/around-the-world-in-80-cakes.html</link><category>Short</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 08:42:16 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220810</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[Cakewrecks has a fun photo gallery of <a href='http://www.cakewrecks.com/home/2013/3/24/sunday-sweets-around-the-world-in-80-days.html'>cakes inspired by Jules Verne's "Around the World in 80 Days</a>."<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/9ywp6zBZg5g" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Cakewrecks has a fun photo gallery of cakes inspired by Jules Verne's "Around the World in 80 Days."</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/around-the-world-in-80-cakes.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/around-the-world-in-80-cakes.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Generative music apps</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/PZsjn2vIh0U/generative-music-apps.html</link><category>Post</category><category>apps</category><category>art</category><category>music</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Pescovitz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 08:34:11 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220806</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<img style="display:block; margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;" src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NewImage73.png" alt="NewImage" title="NewImage.png" border="0" width="600" height="194" class="alignnone"/>

<p>
At our sponsor Intel's LifeScoop site, I posted about "<a href="http://mylifescoop.com/2013/03/25/music-that-writes-itself/">Music That Writes Itself</a>":

<blockquote>In ambient music pioneer Brian Eno’s 1996 book A Year with Swollen Appendices, the composer wrote, “I really think it is possible that our grandchildren will look at us in wonder and say: ‘you mean you used to listen to exactly the same thing over and over again?’” Eno was talking about generative music, a process by which a computer creates unique works from fixed parameters set by the artist. In its simplest form, you twist a few knobs (virtual or otherwise) and the computer takes it from there, creating music that can be credited to the system itself. The term generative art is most likely derived from “generative grammar,” a linguistic theory Noam Chomsky first proposed in his book Syntactic Structures (1965) to refer to deep-seated rules that describe any language. Steven Holtzman, author of Digital Mosaics (1997), traces the art form to the dawn of the information age in the 1960s, when musicians like Gottfried Michael Koenig and Iannis Xenakis pioneered computer composition. Decades later, a number of generative music apps are bringing Eno’s vision to our smartphones.
</blockquote>"<a href="http://mylifescoop.com/2013/03/25/music-that-writes-itself/">Music That Writes Itself</a>"<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/PZsjn2vIh0U" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>At our sponsor Intel's LifeScoop site, I posted about "Music That Writes Itself": In ambient music pioneer Brian Eno’s 1996 book A Year with Swollen Appendices, the composer wrote, “I really think it is possible that our grandchildren will look at us in wonder and say: ‘you mean you used to listen to exactly the [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/generative-music-apps.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/generative-music-apps.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>The case of the poison potato</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/QxqVOWPmldg/the-case-of-the-poison-potato.html</link><category>Feature</category><category>Business</category><category>potatoes</category><category>Science</category><category>snacks</category><category>toxicity</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maggie Koerth-Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 08:15:53 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220790</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>Frying a potato is a tricky proposition. Doing it right isn’t just about your skill as a cook, but also your partner, the potato itself. Waxy potatoes &mdash; high in sugar, low in starch &mdash; brown a little too easily as the sugar in them is altered by heat. By the time the interior is cooked through, the exterior is burnt to a crisp.<span id="more-220790"></span>

<p>Good potato chips come from starchy potatoes. But to get just the right chip <em>color</em> &mdash; that perfect, buttery golden brown &mdash; you have to pay attention to a lot of different factors, from the types of sugar found in the potato, to the internal chemistry that happens as the potato sits in a sack post-harvest.

<p>In the late 1960s, researchers from the US Department of Agriculture, Penn State University, and the Wise Potato Chip Company teamed up breed a very special potato, which they named the Lenape. More than 30 years later, one of their colleagues still thought fondly of that spud. “Lenape was [wonderful],” Penn State scientist Herb Cole told journalist Nancy Marie Brown in 2003. “It chipped golden.”

<p>Yes, the Lenape made a damn fine potato chip.

<p>Unfortunately, it was also kind of toxic.

<center><p><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/potato1.jpg" style="width:200px;"></center>

<p>Despite an almost boring reputation as the squishy white bread of the plant kingdom, potatoes actually come from somewhat nasty roots. Their closest relatives are innocuous enough. Potatoes have strong genetic ties to tomatoes and eggplants. But their more distant cousins include tobacco, chili peppers, deadly nightshade, and the hallucinatory drug-producing flower, datura.

<p>This is a phylogenetic family that is ready to throw down, chemically speaking. Called <em>Solanaceae, </em>its members are known for producing a wide variety of nitrogen-rich chemical compounds, called alkaloids. Nicotine is an alkaloid. So are caffeine, cocaine, and a host of other plant-derived chemicals that humans have taken a liking to over the millennia. Depending on the dose, and on the specific compound, alkaloids can have effects ranging from medicinal, to far-out crazy hallucinatory, to deadly.

<p>Potatoes produce an alkaloid called solanine. All potatoes have it, and it’s a feature, not a bug &mdash; at least as far as the potato is concerned. Like a lot of other plant-produced alkaloids, solanine is a natural defense mechanism. It protects the potato from pests. Think of potato blight, the fungus-like disease partly responsible for the Irish Famine of the 19<sup>th</sup> century. The more solanine a potato contains, the less susceptible it is to blight. When a potato is put into a compromising situation &mdash; when it’s young and vulnerable, for instance, or when tubers get uncovered and, thus, more exposed to things that might eat it &mdash; solanine production can rev up.

<p>Those triggers aren’t always the most convenient for the potato’s human predators. A sudden frost, for instance, can stunt the growth of tubers and promote the growth of vines and leaves, which mimics a younger stage of development and is accompanied by higher solanine concentrations. And if you leave potatoes exposed to the sun for too long after harvest, they start reacting as though they just got accidentally uncovered. They turn green and they produce more solanine. This is actually why you’re not supposed to eat green potatoes. Those spuds, and especially their skins, are rich in solanine. How much solanine varies; it might just be enough to make your stomach a little upset. Or, it could lead to serious illness accompanied by vomiting, diarrhea, loss of consciousness, and convulsive twitching. In very rare cases, people who ate green potatoes have even died.

<center><p><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/potato2.jpg" style="width:200px;"></center>

<p>Poor post-harvest handling was not the problem with the Lenape, however. In 1974, after Lenape potatoes had been recalled from agricultural production and relegated to the status of “breeding material”, the USDA published results of an experiment where they grew Lenape, and five other potato varieties, at 39 locations around the country. They carefully monitored growing and harvesting conditions and then compared the solanine content of all the potatoes.

<p>The conclusion: Lenape was genetically predisposed towards producing an extraordinarily high amount of solanine, no matter what happened to it during growth and harvest. The average Russet potato, for instance, contained about 8 mg of solanine for every 100 g of potato. Lenape, on the other hand, was closer to 30 mg of toxin for every 100 g of food. That made it nicely resistant to a lot of agricultural pests. But it also explained why some of the people who were the first to eat Lenapes &mdash; most of them breeders and other professionals in the agriculture industry &mdash; ended up with severe nausea, like a fast-acting stomach bug.

<p>What makes the Lenape really interesting, though, is its legacy as a cautionary tale. I first learned about it from Fred Gould, an entomologist at North Carolina State University, whom I met while I was working on a <em>New York Times Magazine</em> story about genetically modified mosquitoes.

<p>He used Lenapes as an example of risk and uncertainty. Often, people frame genetically modified plants as this huge open question &mdash; a giant uncertainty, of the sort we’ve never dealt with before. There’s this idea that GM plants are uniquely at risk of producing unexpected side effects, and that we have no way of knowing what those effects would be until average consumers start getting sick, Gould told me. But neither of those things is really true. Conventional breeding, the simple act of crossing one existing plant with another, can produce all sorts of unexpected and dangerous results. One of the reasons Lenape potatoes are so infamous, I later found out, is that they played a big role in shaping how the USDA treats and tests new varieties of conventionally bred food plants today.

<p>In fact, from Gould’s perspective, there’s actually a lot more risk and uncertainty with conventional breeding, than there is with genetic modification. That’s because, with GM, you’re mucking about with a single gene. There are a lot more genes in play with conventional breeding, and a lot more ways that surprising genetic interactions could come back to haunt you. “You try breeding potatoes for pest resistance, but you’re bringing in a whole chromosome from a wild potato,” he said. “We’ve found interactions between the wild genomes and the cultivated genomes that actually led to potentially poisonous chemicals in the potato.”

<p>In 2004, a National Academies panel on the unintended health effects of genetic engineering reported that conventional potato breeders continue to try to increase the amount of solanine produced by the leaves and vines of their potato plants in hopes of making those plants more naturally pest-resistant. Because of that, the USDA actually has a recommended limit for solanine content of new potato varieties &mdash; but that limit isn’t strictly enforced.

<p><a name="_GoBack"></a> Gould’s point isn’t that genetic modification is always better than conventional breeding. It’s not. Instead, they’re both tools &mdash; imperfect technologies that could produce unintended side effects. Which one you choose to use depends on what you’re trying to do. But, either way, you can’t say that one is scary and one is safe.

<h3>CREDITS</h3>
<small>
<p>&bull; <em>Photo: REUTERS/Hazir Reka </em>

<br />&bull; <a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=Y2zYrfEOL3cC&#038;lpg=PA172&#038;ots=2mC3voBKJb&#038;dq=Lenape%20potato&#038;pg=PA172#v=onepage&#038;q=Lenape%20potato&#038;f=false" >Mendel In The Kitchen: A Scientist's View Of Genetically Modified Food</a> [Google Books]

<br />&bull; <a href="http://www.bmj.com/content/2/6203/1458.2.pdf%2Bhtml">Towards fewer handicapped children</a> [bmj.com]

<br />&bull; <a href="http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2FBF02863068?LI=true#page-1">Lenape: A new potato variety high in solids and chipping quality</a> [springer.com]

<br />&bull; <a href="http://www.nap.edu/openbook.php?record_id=10977&#038;page=43">Safety of Genetically Engineered Foods: Approaches to Assessing Unintended Health Effects</a> [nap.edu]

<br />&bull; <a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=X6coAAAAYAAJ&#038;lpg=PA7&#038;ots=fwYVILnrlU&#038;dq=potato%20lenape&#038;pg=PA24#v=onepage&#038;q=Lenape&#038;f=false" >Effect of Environment on Glycoalkaloid Content of Six Potato Varieties</a> [Google Books]

<br />&bull; <a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=EePNniHaROoC&#038;lpg=PA169&#038;ots=bBAYGlVk42&#038;dq=potato%20lenape&#038;pg=PA169#v=onepage&#038;q=potato%20lenape&#038;f=false">The Potato in the Human Diet</a> [Google Books]

<br />&bull; <a href="http://ucce.ucdavis.edu/files/datastore/234-182.pdf">A Review of Important Facts about Potato Glycoalkaloids</a> [PDF, ucdavis.edu]

<br /><a href="http://library.umaine.edu/MaineAES/TechnicalBulletin/tb103.pdf">hFACTORS DETERMINING POTATO CHIPPING QUALITY</a> [PDF, umaine.edu]

<br /><a href="http://eap.mcgill.ca/MagRack/EFA/EF_93_A_09.htm">POTATOES' NATURAL DEFENCES</a> [McGill.ca]
</small><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/QxqVOWPmldg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>The Lenape potato, developed in the 1960s for the snack business, made a damn fine potato chip. Unfortunately, it was also kind of toxic.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/the-case-of-the-poison-potato.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/the-case-of-the-poison-potato.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Hong Kong: court denies migrant domestic workers residency</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/1NGm0mfZUgc/hong-kong-court-denies-migran.html</link><category>Short</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 07:33:23 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220788</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[The top court in Hong Kong has ruled that <a href='http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-21920811'>domestic workers may not apply for permanent residency</a>. The case has been fought for two years. The outcome affects some 300,000 domestic workers, mostly from the Philippines and Indonesia, who may spend decades of their lives working in the territory.  [BBC News/Thanks Antinous]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/1NGm0mfZUgc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>The top court in Hong Kong has ruled that domestic workers may not apply for permanent residency. The case has been fought for two years. The outcome affects some 300,000 domestic workers, mostly from the Philippines and Indonesia, who may spend decades of their lives working in the territory. [BBC News/Thanks Antinous]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/hong-kong-court-denies-migran.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/hong-kong-court-denies-migran.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Uber unfairly skimming our tips, say some drivers</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/7iDJIalMRG0/uber-unfairly-skimming-our-tip.html</link><category>Short</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 06:38:28 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220785</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<a href='http://www.motherjones.com/politics/2013/03/uber-drivers-strike-tips-wages-class-action'><em>Mother Jones</em> has an item today</a> on complaints by drivers for "hail a black car/taxi/SUV with your smartphone" company Uber: the company website claims your fare includes a 20% gratuity "for the driver,"  but one driver told <em>MoJo</em>'s Josh Harkinson that "half of that gratuity actually goes to Uber." And if that's true, "the company would be misleading consumers and breaking the law in some cities." <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/7iDJIalMRG0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Mother Jones has an item today on complaints by drivers for "hail a black car/taxi/SUV with your smartphone" company Uber: the company website claims your fare includes a 20% gratuity "for the driver," but one driver told MoJo's Josh Harkinson that "half of that gratuity actually goes to Uber." And if that's true, "the company [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/uber-unfairly-skimming-our-tip.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/uber-unfairly-skimming-our-tip.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>NY Mag feature on epic NBC "Today" Lauer/Curry cold war is backstab-o-licious</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/To0hjZWE6MI/ny-mag-feature-on-epic-nbc-t.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 06:28:04 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220780</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/todayshow130401_560.jpg" alt="" title="todayshow130401_560" width="560" height="411" class="bordered alignright size-full wp-image-220782" /><a href="http://nymag.com/news/features/today-show-hosts-2013-4/">Joe Hagan's <em>New York Magazine</em> feature on the bitter internal conflict</a> behind the smiles of NBC's long-running <em>Today</em> show is a wonderful read, whether or not you give a shit about <em>Today</em>, or network daytime television in general. <p>I don't want to spoil it for you, but that 9th graf down from the top is the ultimate "oh snap!" of media gossip writing. <p>The piece is full of interesting dirt about Ann Curry, Matt Lauer, and the suits that run NBC, including this little nugget about the network's cockblocking of a compassionate gesture for a woman with cancer at a rival network:<p> "When Robin Roberts left Good Morning America a month later to get treatment for MDS, Curry asked NBC if she could tweet a note of sympathy for the ABC co-host. NBC said no, afraid she was trying to aid the enemy." <p><em><small>(Photo: Gillian Laub/NY Magazine)</small></em><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/To0hjZWE6MI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Joe Hagan's New York Magazine feature on the bitter internal conflict behind the smiles of NBC's long-running Today show is a wonderful read, whether or not you give a shit about Today, or network daytime television in general. I don't want to spoil it for you, but that 9th graf down from the top is [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/ny-mag-feature-on-epic-nbc-t.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/ny-mag-feature-on-epic-nbc-t.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Tell Me Something I Don't Know: Katie Skelly, creator of Nurse Nurse comic book</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/vKvguNRtGdE/tell-me-something-i-dont-kno-4.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 06:00:58 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220664</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F84713343"></iframe></p>

<p><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/untitled10.jpg"  class="alignleft"><em>Thanks to <a href="https://soundcloud.com/">Soundcloud</a> for hosting Boing Boing's podcasts!</em></p>

<p>This is episode 4 of Boing Boing's newest podcast, <em>Tell Me Something I Don't Know</em>. It's an interview podcast featuring artists, writers, filmmakers, and other creative people discussing their work, ideas, and the reality/business side of how they do what they do.</p>

<p>In this episode Jim, Jasen, and Ed interview Katie Skelly, a cartoonist who lives and works in New York City. She has been making mini-comics since 2003, and has contributed to several comic anthologies including the Garo-inspired <a href="http://secretprisoncomics.blogspot.com/">Secret Prison #7</a> and <a href="http://thickness.me/">Thickness #1</a>.</p>

<p>In 2012, Sparkplug Comic Books published her <a href="http://sparkplugcomicbooks.com/shop/comic-books/nurse-nurse/">first graphic novel, the Barbarella-esque, psychedelic sci-fi <a href="http://calicocomics.com/comics.htm">Nurse Nurse</a>. 
</a></p>

<p>She is currently serializing her girl-biker gang graphic novel, <a href="http://calicocomics.tumblr.com/post/34522196746/now-taking-pre-orders-for-operation-margarine-1">Operation: Margarine</a>, as silkscreen-covered, limited-edition mini-comics. Number 2 debuts at MoCCA 2013.</p> 

<p>Learn more at her <a href="http://calicocomics.com/">website</a> and follow her on <a href="https://twitter.com/nurse_nurse">Twitter</a> and <a href="http://calicocomics.tumblr.com/">Tumbler</a>.</p>

<p>TMSIDK produced and hosted by three talented cartoonists and illustrators:</p>

<p><a href="http://jimrugg.com/">Jim Rugg</a>, a Pittsburgh-based comic book artist, graphic designer, zinemaker, and writer best known for <a href="http://amzn.to/YSvmXE">Afrodisiac</a>, <a href="http://amzn.to/XDT2Op">The Plain Janes</a>, and <a href="http://amzn.to/WfFEk2">Street Angel</a>.</p>

<p>Jasen Lex is a designer and illustrator from Pittsburgh. He is currently working on a graphic novel called Washington Unbound. All of his art and comics can be found at <a href="http://jasenlex.com/">jasenlex.com</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/02/11/the-ed-piskor-interview.html">Ed Piskor</a> is the cartoonist who drew the comic, <a href="http://amzn.to/157hKMk">Wizzywig</a>, and draws the <a href="http://boingboing.net/tag/hip-hop-family-tree">Brain Rot/ Hip Hop Family</a> Tree comic strip at this very site, soon to be collected by Fantagraphics Books.</p>

<p>Follow <a href="http://twitter.com/TMSIDKS">TMSIDK</a> on Twitter</p>

<p>Subscribe to the <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/tmsidk">Tell Me Something I Don't Know</a> podcast | <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/tell-me-something-i-dont-know/id602420258">iTunes</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/vKvguNRtGdE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Thanks to Soundcloud for hosting Boing Boing's podcasts! This is episode 4 of Boing Boing's newest podcast, Tell Me Something I Don't Know. It's an interview podcast featuring artists, writers, filmmakers, and other creative people discussing their work, ideas, and the reality/business side of how they do what they do. In this episode Jim, Jasen, [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/tell-me-something-i-dont-kno-4.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/tell-me-something-i-dont-kno-4.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>It's snowing in DC this morning.</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/ZMeyLsf30Gc/its-snowing-in-dc-this-morni.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Video</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 05:59:21 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220769</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--youtu.be--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/omQCnTLhUeE?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<a href="http://youtu.be/omQCnTLhUeE">That</a> is all.<p>

<a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/its-snowing-in-dc-this-morni.html/snow" rel="attachment wp-att-220771"><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/snow1.jpg" alt="" title="snow" width="1200" height="615" class="bordered aligncenter size-full wp-image-220775" /></a><p class="caption">Photo + video: Xeni Jardin</p> 
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/ZMeyLsf30Gc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>A snowy morning snapshot.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/its-snowing-in-dc-this-morni.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/25/its-snowing-in-dc-this-morni.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Independent midwives to march in London today to protest impending shutdown of indie midwifery</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/DBb5em_RvRU/independent-midwives-to-march.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Business</category><category>gender</category><category>health</category><category>protest</category><category>uk</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 22:59:53 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220695</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<p>
There are apparently no insurers in the UK willing to extend cover to independent midwives, and so independent midwives and their clients operate in an insurance-free zone, which is risky, but it was apparently a risk everyone was willing to take. However, a new EU regulation mandates that midwives operate with insurance, and once that regulation is implemented locally, it will end the practice of independent midwifery in the UK unless there's some drastic action to create an insurance policy to which independent midwives may subscribe.
<p>
We had our daughter at home with an NHS midwife, and it was wonderful. Not everyone is lucky enough to live in the cachement of a hospital with midwives who'll help mothers deliver at home (especially now as NHS budgets are being slashed to ribbons across the country).  If this rule comes to pass in the UK without any insurance fix, having a baby safely at home will become effectively illegal for families across the country.
<p>
A silent protest is scheduled for today at the House of Commons:

<blockquote>
<p>
This campaign continues with a Silent Protest and march in Westminster on Monday 25 March, from 11am, to lobby Government to protect women's right to choose their maternity care and find a solution to the issues raised by an EU Directive.
<p>
Independent Midwives are registered midwives who have chosen to work outside the NHS to be able to offer continuous care and support to women who choose it. This is the kind of autonomous midwifery that you see in the hugely popular programme “Call the Midwife”. Nowadays it is mostly only independent midwives who are able to provide what David Cameron once called “gold standard care”. Due to staff shortages and budgetary pressures very few NHS Trusts are able to provide this kind of care.
<p>
Sally Randle is an independent midwife in Bristol, offering local women an alternative to NHS care. Sally says, “I was lucky enough to practise this way in the NHS in London, but local maternity services did not provide this way of working. I decided to become an independent midwife so I could continue this rewarding work. I love my job; I don't even mind getting up in the night to go out to a birth because I know the family well and feel privileged to be involved in this amazing time in their lives”. 
</blockquote>
<p>
I can't figure out why insurers can't sort this out. The actuarial data set is robust and well-established. The potential liability, though high, is calculable. If you can get insurance to juggle machetes in Covent Garden (high potential liability, small data set, massive individual variation), why the hell can't indie midwives get cover?

<p>
<a href="http://www.independentmidwives.org.uk/?node=12764">Silent Protest and March</a>

(<i>Thanks, William!</i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/DBb5em_RvRU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>There are apparently no insurers in the UK willing to extend cover to independent midwives, and so independent midwives and their clients operate in an insurance-free zone, which is risky, but it was apparently a risk everyone was willing to take. However, a new EU regulation mandates that midwives operate with insurance, and once that [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/24/independent-midwives-to-march.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/24/independent-midwives-to-march.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Arijit "Poop Strong" Guha has died of colon cancer</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/klvavwbexZ4/arijit-poop-strong-guha-ha.html</link><category>Post</category><category>cancer</category><category>colon cancer</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 10:36:03 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220668</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/arijit.jpg" alt="" title="arijit" width="600" height="399" class="bordered aligncenter size-full wp-image-220669" /><p>Arijit "<a href="http://poopstrong.org/">Poop Strong</a>" Guha (<a href="https://twitter.com/Poop_Strong">Twitter</a>), a really sweet guy who <a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/07/28/poop-strong-young-cancer-pati.html#previouspost">took on a dirty rotten insurance company</a> and <a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/08/21/delta-refuses-boarding-to-poop.html#previouspost">stood up to TSA "Flying While Brown" bullying</a> (while wearing a <a href="http://shirt.woot.com/offers/threat-level-doctorow">t-shirt designed by Boing Boing's own Cory Doctorow</a>) has died. <p>
He was 31, and had metastatic colon cancer. <p>
I did not know Arijit in person, but we exchanged a number of internet messages since we met online as cancer-compadres. His wife posted this today to <a href="http://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=494776847236728&#038;id=309483725766042">their Facebook page</a>.

<span id="more-220668"></span>

<blockquote><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/with-chickens.jpg" alt="" title="with-chickens" width="640" height="640" class="bordered alignright size-full wp-image-220670" />It is with the deepest sadness I have ever known that I share the following: Arijit Guha—the bravest, kindest, most compassionate man to grace this planet—died earlier today. He went peacefully, at home, surrounded by love and free from pain. He lived his life, even up to the very end, with warmth, humor, and positivity, and his boundless capacity for hope and love gives me strength. He will be greatly missed, but I know that his beauty, goodness, and desire to make the world a better place will continue on through all of the people and lives he has touched.
<p>
My heart is aching, but the pain is eased a bit knowing that he has the support of such an amazing community of people, so many of whom have never met him. I thank you all, from the bottom of my heart, for all you have done for him. He is truly an inspiration (though he hated being told so), and I will be eternally grateful to have had him in my life, and to have been able to share him with all of you.
<p>
Love,<p>
Heather</blockquote>
<p>

Here's a Facebook memorial page for him: "<a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Celebrating-Arijit-Life-and-Hope/434159706673803">Celebrating Arijit, Life, and Hope</a>."



<blockquote>Arijit Guha—rabble rouser, do-gooder, mustache enthusiast—died on March 22, 2013, after a spirited, graceful, and inspirational bout with cancer. His life was one of love, optimism, joy, humor, and compassion, and this page is to celebrate that life.</blockquote>



<P>

 My heart goes out to you, Heather, and to all who knew and loved this kind young man. <P>
Fuck cancer. And fuck injustice. Long live love.
<p><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/67021_434162146673559_828894626_n.jpg" alt="" title="67021_434162146673559_828894626_n" width="720" height="960" class="bordered aligncenter size-full wp-image-220676" /><p>


<em>(via <a href="http://azstarnet.com/news/blogs/health/arizona-student-who-took-on-aetna-has-died-of-colon/article_a1e96822-9417-11e2-9774-001a4bcf887a.html">Arizona Daily Star</a> and @<a href="https://twitter.com/KinkyCancer/status/315874239032983552">KinkyCancer</a>)</em>
<p>
<div class="previously2">
<em>&nbsp;</em><ul><li><a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/14/a-health-update-from-arijit.html#previouspost">A health update from Arijit &quot;Poop Strong,&quot; cancer blogger and ...</a></li>
<li><a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/08/21/delta-refuses-boarding-to-poop.html#previouspost">Delta refuses boarding to Poop Strong man for flying while brown ...</a></li>
<li><a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/07/28/poop-strong-young-cancer-pati.html#previouspost">Poop Strong: Cancer patient whose costs exceeded insurance cap ...</a></li>
</ul>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/klvavwbexZ4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Arijit "Poop Strong" Guha (Twitter), a really sweet guy who took on a dirty rotten insurance company and stood up to TSA "Flying While Brown" bullying (while wearing a t-shirt designed by Boing Boing's own Cory Doctorow) has died. He was 31, and had metastatic colon cancer. I did not know Arijit in person, but [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/24/arijit-poop-strong-guha-ha.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/24/arijit-poop-strong-guha-ha.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>HOWTO bake anatomical heart-bread</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/YRgIRhP8L98/howto-bake-anatomical-heart-br.html</link><category>Post</category><category>anatomy</category><category>bakers</category><category>carbs</category><category>Food</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>makers</category><category>not food</category><category>romance</category><category>vday</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 05:52:02 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220645</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/p10208051.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
Here's a fun set of instructions for baking anatomical heart-shaped bread that you rip apart and gorge upon:

<blockquote>
<p>
Nothing says romance like ritual cannibalism. Use this anatomical heart pull apart loaf to pretend you’re vampires feasting on the heart of that asshole in HR who gave a promotion to Brad. Alternately, you could engage in a little Indiana Jones cosplay where the sexy archaeologist in your life can rescue you from having your heart ripped out by any other man. Gentlemen bakers, you could show up at your vegetarian girlfriend’s house triumphantly holding this and declaring you were successful in the hunt, so tonight you feast. There are so many ways to express your doughy love.
</blockquote>

<p>
<a href="http://kitchenoverlord.com/2013/02/13/bitchin-bread-battle-day-13-valentines-day-anatomical-heart-pull-apart-bread/">Bitchin’ Bread Battle Day 13: Valentine’s Day Anatomical Heart Pull Apart Bread</a>

(<i>via <a href="http://neatorama.com">Neatorama</a></i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/YRgIRhP8L98" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Here's a fun set of instructions for baking anatomical heart-shaped bread that you rip apart and gorge upon: Nothing says romance like ritual cannibalism. Use this anatomical heart pull apart loaf to pretend you’re vampires feasting on the heart of that asshole in HR who gave a promotion to Brad. Alternately, you could engage in [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/24/howto-bake-anatomical-heart-br.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/24/howto-bake-anatomical-heart-br.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Toothy tongue</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/U417S0hYwl8/toothy-tongue.html</link><category>Post</category><category>anatomy</category><category>art</category><category>gross</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>sculpture</category><category>Weird</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 20:06:22 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220625</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/tonya_by_jengabean-d4w5g0a1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
DeviantArt's Jengabean made Tonya, this wonderful, toothy tongue sculpture. Jengabean's whole portfolio is rather wonderful, and worth a look. There's word of an upcoming Etsy store, too.
<p>
<a href="http://jengabean.deviantart.com/art/Tonya-295866442">Tonya</a>

(<i>via <a href="http://www.jwz.org/blog/">JWZ</a></i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/U417S0hYwl8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>DeviantArt's Jengabean made Tonya, this wonderful, toothy tongue sculpture. Jengabean's whole portfolio is rather wonderful, and worth a look. There's word of an upcoming Etsy store, too. Tonya (via JWZ)</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/toothy-tongue.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/toothy-tongue.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Grandmothers who are brilliant at technology</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/xtUTMEwPxu8/grandmothers-who-are-brilliant.html</link><category>Post</category><category>age</category><category>gender</category><category>Technology</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 17:58:49 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220594</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/helen-quinn-20082.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
A wonderful site called "Grandma Got STEM" profiles grandmothers who have accomplished marvellous feats of technology, and aims to drive a stake through the heart of stupid, thoughtless phrases like "How would you explain that to your grandmother?" or "So simple my grandma could do it."
<p>
Shown above, <a href="http://ggstem.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/helen-quinn/">Helen Quinn</a>, "particle physicist, PhD from Stanford in 1967, and grandmother of three young girls."
<p>
I've never understood why geeks hold their grandmothers in such contempt.

<blockquote>
<p>

Perhaps you are tired of hearing people say 'how would you explain that to your grandmother?' when they probably mean something like 'How would you explain the idea in a clear, compelling way so that people without a technical background can understand you?'
<p>
Here's a similar saying you may have heard: 'That's so easy, my grandmother could understand it.'
<p>
Grandma got STEM counters the implication that grannies (gender + maternity + age) might not easily pick up on technical/theoretical ideas by sharing pictures and remembrances from/of Grandmothers who have made contributions in STEM-related fields.
</blockquote>



<p>
<a href="http://ggstem.wordpress.com/"> Grandma Got STEM </a>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/xtUTMEwPxu8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>A wonderful site called "Grandma Got STEM" profiles grandmothers who have accomplished marvellous feats of technology, and aims to drive a stake through the heart of stupid, thoughtless phrases like "How would you explain that to your grandmother?" or "So simple my grandma could do it." Shown above, Helen Quinn, "particle physicist, PhD from Stanford [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/grandmothers-who-are-brilliant.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/grandmothers-who-are-brilliant.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>As seen in Belgrade</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/NcHd1bf5HcI/as-seen-in-belgrade.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Weisberger</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 17:03:22 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220632</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>
<a href="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/221775_10200151640168796_1026344893_n.jpg"><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/221775_10200151640168796_1026344893_n.jpg" alt="" title="221775_10200151640168796_1026344893_n" width="720" height="960" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-220633" /></a>
<p>
via the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/boingboing">Boing Boing Facebook feed</a>.
<p>
<em>Thanks Ian Cattell!</em><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/NcHd1bf5HcI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>via the Boing Boing Facebook feed. Thanks Ian Cattell!</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/as-seen-in-belgrade.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/as-seen-in-belgrade.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Sen Chuck Schumer took $100K from private prisons, now gets to help decide whether to send undocumented immigrants to jail</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/dBvqWkarH7Q/sen-chuck-schumer-took-100k-f.html</link><category>Post</category><category>corruption</category><category>dems</category><category>immigration</category><category>petitions</category><category>politics</category><category>prison</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 14:43:34 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220577</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
Senator Chuck Schumer (D-NY) is one of the key figures in the political wrangle over whether undocumented immigrants in the USA will be legalized or deported. He's also the recipient of over $100,000 in campaign contributions from the private prison industry, whose profits would skyrocket if his push for prison for all those people is successful.

<blockquote>
<p>
Chuck Schumer is the lead Senate Democrat working on immigration reform--he gets to decide whether millions of undocumented immigrants will be imprisoned or legalized. Yet he’s also taken over $100,000 in campaign contributions from the private prison industry. Is it any surprise he’s pushing for billions more dollars spent on increased enforcement and detention of immigrants?
<p>
We can’t trust Sen. Schumer to push for fair legislation when he’s accepting money from private prison companies that have a strong interest in jailing as many immigrants as possible. How much of an interest? The two corporations from which Sen. Schumer took money, GEO Group and CCA, made $296.9 million in profits from the jailing of immigrants last year. 
<p>
Tell Sen. Schumer to return this money immediately. 
<p>
If 15,000 people sign, we'll personally deliver your petitions to Sen. Schumer and demand a response. 
</blockquote>

<p>
<a href="http://act.presente.org/sign/schumermoney">Sen. Schumer: Give back the money</a>

(<i>via <a href="http://www.nielsenhayden.com/makinglight/">Making Light</a></i>)<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/dBvqWkarH7Q" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Senator Chuck Schumer (D-NY) is one of the key figures in the political wrangle over whether undocumented immigrants in the USA will be legalized or deported. He's also the recipient of over $100,000 in campaign contributions from the private prison industry, whose profits would skyrocket if his push for prison for all those people is [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/sen-chuck-schumer-took-100k-f.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/sen-chuck-schumer-took-100k-f.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Congressman boasts on Twitter about the money he got to support CISPA, then thinks better of it</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/CSi7JHVHPn8/congressman-boasts-on-twitter.html</link><category>Post</category><category>christ what an asshole</category><category>cispa</category><category>citizens united</category><category>corruption</category><category>twitter</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 11:39:10 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220568</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Politwoops-CISPA-Mike-Rogers.png1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
CISPA is a bill before Congress that will radically increase the ease with which the government and police can spy on people without any particular suspicion. It is being rammed through by people like Rep. Mike Rogers (R-MI), who received a small fortune in funding from the companies that stand to get rich building the surveillance tech CISPA will make possible. 
<p>
What's more, Rogers admits it, and even tweets about it! Nicko Margolies from the Sunlight Foundation writes,

<blockquote>
<p>

<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/cispa1.png" align="right">
Rep. Mike Rogers (R-MI), a co-sponsor and major supporter of the controversial Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act (CISPA), deleted a retweet of an analysis of contributions to lawmakers from pro-CISPA companies. MapLight looked at the powerful House Intelligence Committee, where Rep. Rogers serves as Chairman, and followed campaign contributions to the members who are currently considering the bill that would allow companies to share more information on Internet traffic and users with the U.S. government.
<p>
Rep. Rogers, or possibly a member of his staff, retweeted the story that identified that members of the House Intelligence Committee "have received, on average, 15 times more money in campaign contributions from pro-CISPA organizations than from anti-CISPA organizations." He retweeted MapLight's tweet of this information from his iPhone and after 23 minutes thought better of it and removed it. Fortunately the Sunlight Foundation's Politwoops project caught it and archived this change of message and of heart. According to the MapLight piece, Rep. Rogers received $214,750 from interest groups that support CISPA.
</blockquote>
<p>
The EFF has <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2013/03/week-action-opposing-cispa">more info on CISPA</a>, and ways you can help kill it.


<p>
<a href="http://sunlightfoundation.com/blog/2013/03/22/pro-cispa-lawmaker-deletes-retweet-about-money-received-from-pro-cispa-groups/">Pro-CISPA Lawmaker Deletes Retweet about Money Received from Pro-CISPA Groups</a>

(<i>Thanks, <a href="http://politwoops.sunlightfoundation.com/tweet/314899025910456321">Nicko</a>!</i>)



<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/CSi7JHVHPn8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>CISPA is a bill before Congress that will radically increase the ease with which the government and police can spy on people without any particular suspicion. It is being rammed through by people like Rep. Mike Rogers (R-MI), who received a small fortune in funding from the companies that stand to get rich building the [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/congressman-boasts-on-twitter.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/congressman-boasts-on-twitter.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>IRS apologizes for $60k Star Trek parody</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/uur6Cf-m_W0/irs-apologies-for-60k-star-t.html</link><category>Video</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jason Weisberger</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 10:38:29 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220622</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--www.youtube.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/VxU6n4pAnrU?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>
Seems in 2010 this training video got a green light. The Associated Press has <a href="http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2013/mar/23/irs-apologizes-wasting-taxpayer-cash-60000-star-tr/?utm_source=RSS_Feed&#038;utm_medium=RSS&#038;google_editors_picks=true">the details</a>. <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/uur6Cf-m_W0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Seems in 2010 this training video got a green light. The Washington Times has &lt;a href="http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2013/mar/23/irs-apologizes-wasting-taxpayer-cash-60000-star-tr/?utm_source=RSS_Feed&amp;#038;utm_medium=RSS&amp;#038;google_editors_picks=true"&gt;the details&lt;/a&gt;.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/irs-apologies-for-60k-star-t.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/irs-apologies-for-60k-star-t.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>We have a choice about the world that technology will give us</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/0Qf2ryDpgHI/we-have-a-choice-about-the-wor.html</link><category>Post</category><category>first days of a better nation</category><category>floss</category><category>surveillance</category><category>ubicomp</category><category>web theory</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 08:31:26 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220565</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
Phil Windley, former CTO of Utah and now CTO of a startup called Kynetx, has an inspiring, brief piece on how technologists can help build a technological world where technology helps us live better lives over which we have more control, and how a failure to do something to build this world will give us a place where we are continuously spied upon and manipulated.


<blockquote>
<p>


<p>
We probably don’t really have a choice about whether a $0.03 wireless sensor platform will exist. Technology marches on. 
</p>

<p>
But we <em>do have a choice</em> about how it will be employed. If we follow the path we’re on now, all those devices will be controlled by some company somewhere that is providing the service behind them. All that data that all those devices are gathering about you will be streamed back to a walled garden via an encrypted channel to end up as fodder for some big data analytics platform that will be used by someone to sell you more stuff. You will be spied on by everything around you with no rational way to understand where all that data is going and how it’s being used. We’ll create government regulations that will do little to rationalize your world or help you understand it because they will only succeed in further Balkanizing it. 
</p>

<p>
There is another path: in this alternate world all the devices that are related to you will push their data into a place that you control. This will seem rational and natural because the model will follow the structure of the world you’re already used to with clear delineations between public and private spaces and easy-to-understand controls over how data is used and shared. I say “natural” in a literal way. This is the way the physical world works and we’re all used to it. In this alternate world <em>you are in control</em>. 
</p>
</blockquote>

<P>
<a href="http://www.windley.com/archives/2013/03/build_the_world_you_want_to_live_in.shtml">Build the World You Want to Live In</a>

(<i>via <a href="http://blog.felter.org/">Hack the Planet</a></i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/0Qf2ryDpgHI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Phil Windley, former CTO of Utah and now CTO of a startup called Kynetx, has an inspiring, brief piece on how technologists can help build a technological world where technology helps us live better lives over which we have more control, and how a failure to do something to build this world will give us [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/we-have-a-choice-about-the-wor.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/we-have-a-choice-about-the-wor.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Eating a wedding cake in reverse</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/WcsWW5xEwCU/eating-a-wedding-cake-in-rever.html</link><category>Video</category><category>australia</category><category>cake</category><category>Food</category><category>movies</category><category>not food</category><category>videos</category><category>Weird</category><category>youtube</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 07:25:55 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220601</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--youtu.be--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/DTkoKiyfmps?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>
Tommy sez, "I made this film clip with a great photographer friend of mine and it took two takes. That means I had to eat TWO CAKES.

I ended up eating so much confetti and glitter that I had a glittery poo the next day. But it was all worth it as backwards eating really can end up looking quite beautiful.

Thankfully the clip was not about the glittery poo."
<p>
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DTkoKiyfmps">
Spender - NEVER AGAIN - {Official}
</a>

(<i>Thanks, <a href="http://www.spender.com.au/">Tom</a>!</i>)




<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/WcsWW5xEwCU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Tommy sez, "I made this film clip with a great photographer friend of mine and it took two takes. That means I had to eat TWO CAKES."</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/eating-a-wedding-cake-in-rever.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/eating-a-wedding-cake-in-rever.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>How long should we expect Google Keep to last?</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/EBD-MugggRo/how-long-should-we-expect-goog.html</link><category>Post</category><category>google</category><category>stats</category><category>web theory</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 06:26:59 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220558</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen_Shot_2013-03-22_at_12.13.00.png1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
On the <em>Guardian</em>, Charles Arthur has totted up the lifespan of 39 products and services that Google has killed off in the past due to insufficient public interest. One interesting finding is that Google is becoming less patient with its less popular progeny, with an accelerating trend to killing off products that aren't cutting it. This was occasioned by the launch of Google Keep, a networked note-taking app which has the potential to become quite central to your workflow, and to be quite disruptive if Google kills it -- much like Google Reader, which is scheduled for impending switch-off.

<blockquote>

So if you want to know when Google Keep, opened for business on 21 March 2013, will probably shut - again, assuming Google decides it's just not working - then, the mean suggests the answer is: 18 March 2017. That's about long enough for you to cram lots of information that you might rely on into it; and also long enough for Google to discover that, well, people aren't using it to the extent that it hoped. Much the same as happened with Knol (lifespan: 1,377 days, from 23 July 2008 to 30 April 2012), or Wave (1,095 days, from May 2009 - 30 April 2012) or of course Reader (2,824 days, from 7 October 2005 to 1 July 2013).
<p>

If you want to play around further with the numbers, then if we assume that closures occur randomly as a normal distribution around the mean, and that Google is going to shut Google Keep, then there's a 68% chance that the closure will occur between April 2015 and February 2019. Even the later date wouldn't be much longer than Evernote - which is still growing - has already lasted. Is Google really that committed to Keep?
</blockquote>


<p>
<a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2013/mar/22/google-keep-services-closed">Google Keep? It'll probably be with us until March 2017 - on average</a>

(<I>via <a href="http://slashdot.org">/.</a></i>)<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/EBD-MugggRo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>On the Guardian, Charles Arthur has totted up the lifespan of 39 products and services that Google has killed off in the past due to insufficient public interest. One interesting finding is that Google is becoming less patient with its less popular progeny, with an accelerating trend to killing off products that aren't cutting it. [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/how-long-should-we-expect-goog.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/23/how-long-should-we-expect-goog.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Launching the UK edition of Rapture of the Nerds TODAY at Forbidden Planet London</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/-cfHHmkx8Ew/launching-the-uk-edition-of.html</link><category>Post</category><category>events</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>london</category><category>science fiction</category><category>singularity</category><category>uk</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 22:49:42 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220581</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/rapture_UKcover.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
Hey, Londoners! I'll be launching the UK edition of <a href="http://craphound.com/rotn">Rapture of the Nerds</a> <em>today</em> at 1PM <a href="http://forbiddenplanet.com/events/2013/03/23/cory-doctorow-signing-rapture-nerds/">at Forbidden Planet</a>. Although the book is available across the country at finer stores, this will be your only chance to stroke the marvellous <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/cory-signing-rapture-of-the-ne.html">3D printed Space Marine Stross</a> and have your picture taken with it. 

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/-cfHHmkx8Ew" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Hey, Londoners! I'll be launching the UK edition of Rapture of the Nerds today at 1PM at Forbidden Planet. Although the book is available across the country at finer stores, this will be your only chance to stroke the marvellous 3D printed Space Marine Stross and have your picture taken with it.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/launching-the-uk-edition-of.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/launching-the-uk-edition-of.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Crocheted skeleton with organs</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/YxcLYVPfT58/crocheted-skeleton-with-organs.html</link><category>Post</category><category>anatomy</category><category>art</category><category>makers</category><category>sculpture</category><category>textiles</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:39:03 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220297</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/cimg2884111.jpg" class="bordered">

<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/cimg0140111.jpg" class="bordered" align="right">
Artist Shanell Papp has a project called "Bawdy," which is about bodies and textiles. The centerpiece is "Lab," a yarn skeleton with a complete set of organs. 
<P>
<a href="http://shanellpapp.com/textiles/">Lab (skeleton)</a>

(<i>via <a href="http://www.nielsenhayden.com/makinglight/">Making Light</a></i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/YxcLYVPfT58" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Artist Shanell Papp has a project called "Bawdy," which is about bodies and textiles. The centerpiece is "Lab," a yarn skeleton with a complete set of organs. Lab (skeleton) (via Making Light)</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/crocheted-skeleton-with-organs.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/crocheted-skeleton-with-organs.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Skype's IP-leaking security bug creates denial-of-service cottage industry</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/LWZlkbYMltk/skypes-ip-leaking-security-b.html</link><category>Post</category><category>ddos</category><category>security</category><category>skype</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 18:04:14 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220291</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/anonyresolver.png1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
It's been more than a year since the <em>WSJ</eM> reported that Skype leaks its users' IP addresses and locations. Microsoft has done nothing to fix this since, and as Brian Krebs reports, the past year has seen the rise of several tools that let you figure out someone's IP address by searching for him on Skype, then automate launching denial-of-service attacks on that person's home.

<blockquote>
<p>


In the above screen shot, we can see one such service being used to display the IP address most recently used by the Skype account “mailen_support” (this particular account belongs to the tech support contact for Mailien, a Russian pharmacy spam affiliate program by the same name).

<p>
Typically, these Skype resolvers are offered in tandem with “booter” or “stresser” services, online attack tools-for-hire than can be rented to launch denial-of-service attacks (one of these services was used in an attack on this Web site, and on that of Ars Technica last week). The idea being that if you want to knock someone offline but you don’t know their Internet address, you can simply search on Skype to see if they have an account. The resolvers work regardless of any privacy settings the target user may have selected within the Skype program’s configuration panel.
<p>
Beyond exposing one’s Internet connection to annoying and disruptive attacks, this vulnerability could allow stalkers or corporate rivals to track the movement of individuals and executives as they travel between cities and states.
</blockquote>

<p>
<a href="http://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/03/privacy-101-skype-leaks-your-location/">Privacy 101: Skype Leaks Your Location</a>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/LWZlkbYMltk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>It's been more than a year since the WSJ reported that Skype leaks its users' IP addresses and locations. Microsoft has done nothing to fix this since, and as Brian Krebs reports, the past year has seen the rise of several tools that let you figure out someone's IP address by searching for him on [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/skypes-ip-leaking-security-b.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/skypes-ip-leaking-security-b.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Beautiful booze-trailer for sale</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/Y315pCboSWc/beautiful-booze-trailer-for-sa.html</link><category>Post</category><category>automotive</category><category>booze</category><category>Gadgets</category><category>gift guide</category><category>happy mutants</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:58:12 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220284</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NMO5411_mp.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
From the Neiman-Marcus gift catalog, a trailer that converts into an elaborate, beautiful bar, and comes with a year's supply of Bulleit bourbon and rye. There are two for sale at $150K each, with 10 percent going to an HIV/AIDS charity.

<blockquote>
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NMO5411_ap.jpg" align="right" class="bordered">
 A chorus of cheers rings out the minute you pull up. Tailgating will never be the same now that your Bulleit Frontier Whiskey Woody-Tailgate Trailer is on the scene. Designed by interior designer Brad Ford, it's impressive on the outside, but what's on the inside truly astounds: sleek leather furnishings and details from Moore &#038; Giles, rich wood finishings (handcrafted from reclaimed Bulleit Bourbon casks), elegant glassware, and a top-notch entertainment system, including a flat-screen TV, Blu-ray Disc™ player, and a state-of-the-art sound system, plus a one-year supply of Bulleit Bourbon and Bulleit Rye*. You park, open the hatch, and slide out the bar—cocktails anyone?
 </blockquote>
<p>
Bulleit is delicious bourbon, but I recently bought a bottle of Elmer T Lee Single Barrel and holy cats, is that stuff astounding.
<p>
<a href="http://www.neimanmarcus.com/christmasbook/fantasy.jsp?cid=CBF12_O5411&#038;cidShots=m,a,b,c,z&#038;r=cat44770736&#038;rdesc=The+Fantasy+Gifts&#038;pageName=Best+Gift,+Bar+None&#038;icid=CBF12_O5411"> BEST GIFT, BAR NONE! &#038; BULLEIT TO GO</a>

(<I>via <a href="http://neatorama.com">Neatorama</a></i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/Y315pCboSWc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>From the Neiman-Marcus gift catalog, a trailer that converts into an elaborate, beautiful bar, and comes with a year's supply of Bulleit bourbon and rye. There are two for sale at $150K each, with 10 percent going to an HIV/AIDS charity. A chorus of cheers rings out the minute you pull up. Tailgating will never [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/beautiful-booze-trailer-for-sa.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/beautiful-booze-trailer-for-sa.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Phone wars</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/7c0wudrtJmw/phone-wars.html</link><category>Short</category><category>wired</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob Beschizza</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:00:52 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220553</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[Mat Honan has a request: <a href="http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2013/03/nobody-cares-what-you-think-about-their-phone/?cid=co6585924">Please Stop Fighting About Your Smartphone</a>. "The phone wars, the platform wars, should be left to people who work for Apple and Samsung and Google and Microsoft and Nokia and BlackBerry. Do you work for Apple? Do you work for Samsung? No? Then shut up." [Wired]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/7c0wudrtJmw" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Mat Honan has a request: Please Stop Fighting About Your Smartphone. "The phone wars, the platform wars, should be left to people who work for Apple and Samsung and Google and Microsoft and Nokia and BlackBerry. Do you work for Apple? Do you work for Samsung? No? Then shut up." [Wired]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/phone-wars.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/phone-wars.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>The art and science of beer: a video feature on the "Pope of Foam"</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/1uyzrTpRrQc/the-art-and-science-of-beer-a.html</link><category>Video</category><category>alcohol</category><category>beer</category><category>homebrew</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:49:07 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220541</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--youtu.be--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/3QFQVblxzSk?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

In <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3QFQVblxzSk">this video</a>, Charlie The Pope of Foam" Bamforth, the head of Malting and Brewing Science at UC Davis, explains beer-making and reveals how to pick the freshest pint when you're at a pub. "How Beer Saved The World,"  "Why I Tease Those Wine Guys," and  "How Bird Poop Makes A More Aromatic Belgian Beer" are but a few tidbits.
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/1uyzrTpRrQc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>"How Beer Saved The World,"  "Why I Tease Those Wine Guys," and  "How Bird Poop Makes A More Aromatic Belgian Beer" are but a few tidbits.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/the-art-and-science-of-beer-a.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/the-art-and-science-of-beer-a.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>A cybersecurity lobbying boom in DC, as congress considers new laws</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/wrNw9X4zFA4/a-cybersecurity-lobbying-boom.html</link><category>Short</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:44:33 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220548</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[Recent actions by Congress and the Obama administration to "protect networks of critical U.S. industries from hackers and cyberspies" have led to an explosive growth opportunity...for lobbyists. <a href='http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-21/cybersecurity-lobby-surges-as-congress-considers-new-laws.html'>Bloomberg reports that there were</a> "513 filings by consultants and companies to press Congress on cybersecurity by the end of 2012, up 85 percent from 2011 and almost three times as many as in 2010."
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/wrNw9X4zFA4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Recent actions by Congress and the Obama administration to "protect networks of critical U.S. industries from hackers and cyberspies" have led to an explosive growth opportunity...for lobbyists. Bloomberg reports that there were "513 filings by consultants and companies to press Congress on cybersecurity by the end of 2012, up 85 percent from 2011 and almost [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/a-cybersecurity-lobbying-boom.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/a-cybersecurity-lobbying-boom.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Shepard Fairey talks about some of his favorite YouTube videos</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/tj-7rsetVSk/shepard-fairey-talks-about-som.html</link><category>Video</category><category>art</category><category>graphic design</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:42:37 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220545</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--youtu.be--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Kkq6AolKvdc?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

In a video for Los Angeles <a href="http://bit.ly/MOCATwitter">MOCA</a>, Shepard Fairey selects some of his favorite clips from YouTube, and talks about videos that have inspired him "including the great graphic designer Saul Bass, and music videos for Rapture by Blondie and Atomic Dog by George Clinton."  Video produced and edited by Stephen Pagano and Tom Salvaggio.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/tj-7rsetVSk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Shepard Fairey selects some of his favorite clips from YouTube, and talks about videos that have inspired him.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/shepard-fairey-talks-about-som.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/shepard-fairey-talks-about-som.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>A celebration of ‘Paris Is Burning’ with Peaches Christ and Latrice Royale</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/g7-qimKX3Nc/a-celebration-of-paris-is-b.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:17:32 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220524</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--youtu.be--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/78TAbjx43rk?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

According to <a href="http://dangerousminds.net/comments/a_celebration_of_paris_is_burning_with_peaches_christ_and_latrice_royale">Niall Connolly at Dangerous Minds</a>, "If you have not seen <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B007QJ89VU/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&#038;camp=1789&#038;creative=390957&#038;creativeASIN=B007QJ89VU&#038;linkCode=as2&#038;tag=boingboing06-20"><em>Paris Is Burning,</em></a> you’re just not doing it right. I’m talking Life, honey."



<blockquote>I’ve written about <em>Paris Is Burning </em>before, and referenced it in <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/06/ballroom.html">my recent ballroom piece for Boing Boing</a>, but the truth is that the impact of this film on gay culture, and by extension culture at large, cannot be overestimated. That a film about underground drag culture and voguing resonated so strongly amongst gays should not be a surprise, but what is surprising is how far its influence has spread in “straight” circles. Its language and imagery are now common parlance, and it won a recent <a href="http://www.pbs.org/pov/blog/2012/11/the-greatest-documentaries-of-all-time/#.UUyTXM2zcxp">PBS “best documentary” poll</a> by an overwhelming landslide.</p><p>Which is why I was so delighted to see Paris Is Burning get recent a Midnight Mass screening in San Francisco, hosted by the queens Peaches Christ and Latrice Royale.</p></blockquote>

<p>Read: <a href='http://dangerousminds.net/comments/a_celebration_of_paris_is_burning_with_peaches_christ_and_latrice_royale'>Legendary: A celebration of ‘Paris Is Burning’ with Peaches Christ and Latrice Royale</a> [Dangerous Minds]</p><p>
And don't miss Niall's earlier <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/06/ballroom.html">feature for Boing Boing on voguing</a>.<p>

Check out <a href="http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.582790885064245.1073741832.191247967551874&#038;type=1">Robbie Sweeny's photoset</a> from the Castro Theater event.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/g7-qimKX3Nc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>According to Niall Connolly at Dangerous Minds, "If you have not seen Paris Is Burning, you’re just not doing it right. I’m talking Life, honey." I’ve written about Paris Is Burning before, and referenced it in my recent ballroom piece for Boing Boing, but the truth is that the impact of this film on gay [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/a-celebration-of-paris-is-b.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/a-celebration-of-paris-is-b.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>National Conference for Media Reform coming to Denver, CO, April 5-17 2013</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/zI72WQelvLM/national-conference-for-media.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:02:09 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220518</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<a href="https://plus.google.com/104083764762208158473/posts">Josh Stearns</a> writes,



<blockquote>
<p>
<a href="http://conference.freepress.net/ncmr-2013"><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-22-at-1.57.jpg" alt="" title="Screen-Shot-2013-03-22-at-1.57" width="397" height="431" class="alignright size-full wp-image-220519" /></a>Denver is about to become the epicenter of awesome, when the <a href="http://conference.freepress.net/ncmr-2013">National Conference for Media Reform</a> comes to town bringing 2,500 coders, journalists, media makers, artists and <a href="http://conference.freepress.net/session/after-party-and-comedy-showcase">comedians</a> together to hack the <a href="http://conference.freepress.net/schedule?ncmr_days_only%5Bvalue%5D%5Byear%5D=2013&#038;ncmr_days_only%5Bvalue%5D%5Bmonth%5D=4&#038;ncmr_days_only%5Bvalue%5D%5Bday%5D=&#038;field_room_nid=All&#038;field_presenters_nid=All&#038;field_track_value=Internet+Freedom%2C+Technology+and+Innovation">future of tech</a>, media and democracy.<p>

&bull; What other event brings together <a href="http://conference.freepress.net/overview#tech-playground">3D printers and wearable computers</a> with policy debates about CISPA and slam poetry?
<p>
&bull; Where else can you see <a href="http://conference.freepress.net/presenters">Kimya Dawson of the Moldy Peaches and Evangeline Lilly from Lost</a> hanging out with Democracy Now's Amy Goodman and Former White House Tech Advisor Susan Crawford?
<p>
&bull; Why in the world would the heads of <a href="http://conference.freepress.net/schedule">Upworthy, NARAL, Common Cause and ColorofChange.org</a> be going to Denver?
<p>
&bull; What if you could see <a href="http://conference.freepress.net/schedule?ncmr_days_only%5Bvalue%5D%5Byear%5D=2013&#038;ncmr_days_only%5Bvalue%5D%5Bmonth%5D=4&#038;ncmr_days_only%5Bvalue%5D%5Bday%5D=&#038;field_room_nid=All&#038;field_presenters_nid=All&#038;field_track_value=Journalism+and+Public+Media">Brian Stelter of the New York Times talking with Jezebel.com</a> founder Anna Holmes about digital media?
<p>
&bull; What if you <a href="http://conference.freepress.net/session/building-future-women-code-and-inclusion">learned how to code</a> from Catherine Bracy of Code for America and Kimberly Bryant of Black Girls Code?
<p>
The fight for civil liberties, for Internet Freedom, for digital rights is coming to Denver, April 5-7 -- are you?

</blockquote>


More links: <a href="http://conference.freepress.net/blog/2013/03/22/latino-advocates-take-center-stage-national-conference-media-reform">Latino Tech and Media Activism</a> at the conference,  and the <a href="http://conference.freepress.net/blog/2013/03/21/art-meets-activism-national-conference-media-reform">Arts, Comedy and Music events</a> taking place there.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/zI72WQelvLM" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Josh Stearns writes, Denver is about to become the epicenter of awesome, when the National Conference for Media Reform comes to town bringing 2,500 coders, journalists, media makers, artists and comedians together to hack the future of tech, media and democracy. &amp;#8226; What other event brings together 3D printers and wearable computers with policy debates [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/national-conference-for-media.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/national-conference-for-media.html</feedburner:origLink></item></channel></rss>
