<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.boingboing.net/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0"><channel><title>Boing Boing</title><link>http://boingboing.net</link><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.boingboing.net/boingboing/iBag" /><description>Brain candy for Happy Mutants</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 08:28:01 PDT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.1</generator><sy:updatePeriod xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/">hourly</sy:updatePeriod><sy:updateFrequency xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/">1</sy:updateFrequency><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.boingboing.net/boingboing/iBag" /><feedburner:info uri="boingboing/ibag" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><image><link>http://boingboing.net</link><url>http://boingboing.net/icons/bb144.jpg</url><title>Boing Boing</title></image><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item><title>Just look at this human-sized banana.</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/uR3Byqys_SY/just-look-at-this-human-sized.html</link><category>Post</category><category>bananas</category><category>just look at it</category><category>madison</category><category>not food</category><category>wi</category><category>wide</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 08:00:48 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219585</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/EllasBanana1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
Just look at it.
<p>
<a href="http://www.ellasdeli.com/">Ella's Deli and Ice Cream Parlor</a>
(<i>Thanks, <a href="http://tankriot.com/">Viktor</a>!</i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/uR3Byqys_SY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Just look at it. Ella's Deli and Ice Cream Parlor (Thanks, Viktor!)</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/just-look-at-this-human-sized.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/just-look-at-this-human-sized.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Resident Alien Volume 1: Welcome to Earth!</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/iImDApQ8kyU/resident-alien-volume-1-welco.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Comic Books</category><category>giftguide</category><category>Reviews</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 07:30:17 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219549</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/ra.jpg"  class="alignnone">
<br clear ="all"><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1616550171/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il?ie=UTF8&#038;camp=1789&#038;creative=9325&#038;creativeASIN=1616550171&#038;linkCode=as2&#038;tag=boingboing"><img border="0" src="http://ws.assoc-amazon.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&#038;ASIN=1616550171&#038;Format=_SL160_&#038;ID=AsinImage&#038;MarketPlace=US&#038;ServiceVersion=20070822&#038;WS=1&#038;tag=boingboing" class="alignleft"></a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=boingboing&#038;l=as2&#038;o=1&#038;a=1616550171" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />Michael Pusateri recommended the comic book <em>Resident Alien</em> on an episode of Gweek last year. A few days ago I received a review copy of the paperback anthology that collects the first four issues and loved it.</p><p> <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1616550171/boingboing">Resident Alien Volume 1: Welcome to Earth!</a> is about an alien who crash lands his spacecraft on Earth and must interact with human beings in a small mountain town. The alien can uses his formidable mental powers to block his appearance so that the townsfolk see him as a human (with one interesting exception). But as readers, we see him as a purple skinned, bug-eyed, pointy-eared spaceman.</p>

<p>In the afterword to the anthology, writer Peter Hogan explains how he came up with the idea for the series: </p>

<p><blockquote>I blame Elvis Presley. Many years ago, I edited a book about the man, and got fascinated by Alfred Wertheimer's photos from the early days of his career. He showed Presley in everyday settings like diners and hotels, traveling on trains and hanging around in stations &#8211;- and the truly remarkable thing about them was the fact that all the other people in those photographs were completely ignoring Elvis, despite the fact that he looked nothing like anyone else in the room (or on the planet, for that matter). It was like there was a Martian in town, and they just couldn't see him.</blockquote></p>

<p>The alien is friendly. He is fascinated by human behavior, and when the town doctor is murdered, the mayor asks him to step in as a temporary replacement until they can find a permanent doctor. He agrees, somewhat reluctantly, because he is still unaccustomed to the ways of humans, but his curiosity wins out. The story develops into a good old fashioned murder mystery, with the twist that an alien disguised as a doctor is involved. Steve Parkhouse's art is excellent, and I'm looking forward to the next volume, which  will be called "The Suicide Blonde."</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1616550171/boingboing">Resident Alien Volume 1: Welcome to Earth!</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/iImDApQ8kyU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Michael Pusateri recommended the comic book Resident Alien on an episode of Gweek last year. A few days ago I received a review copy of the paperback anthology that collects the first four issues and loved it. Resident Alien Volume 1: Welcome to Earth! is about an alien who crash lands his spacecraft on Earth [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/resident-alien-volume-1-welco.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/resident-alien-volume-1-welco.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kim Newman's critically-acclaimed 1993 horror novel re-issued (excerpt)</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/BWG8mIbyDvQ/kim-newmans-critically-accla.html</link><category>Post</category><category>books</category><category>Excerpts</category><category>horror</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 06:40:07 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219096</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[Titan Books has released a brand-new edition of Kim Newsman's critically-acclaimed 1993 adult horror novel, <a href="http://amzn.to/10RmgLv">Jago</a>.

<blockquote><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1781164231/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il?ie=UTF8&#038;camp=1789&#038;creative=9325&#038;creativeASIN=1781164231&#038;linkCode=as2&#038;tag=boingboing"><img border="0" src="http://ws.assoc-amazon.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&#038;ASIN=1781164231&#038;Format=_SL110_&#038;ID=AsinImage&#038;MarketPlace=US&#038;ServiceVersion=20070822&#038;WS=1&#038;tag=boingboing" class="alignleft"></a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=boingboing&#038;l=as2&#038;o=1&#038;a=1781164231" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
Paul, a young academic composing a thesis about the end of the world, and his girlfriend Hazel, a potter, have come to the tiny English village of Alder for the summer. Their idea of a rural retreat gradually sours as the laws of nature begin to break down around them. The village, swollen by an annual rock festival of cataclysmic proportions, prepares to reap a harvest of horror. </blockquote>

<span id="more-219096"></span>

<p>When they first came to Alder, the big heat had already been on for over a month. In the daytime, the house, built to weather centuries of winters, was like a Casablanca gambling hell. Paul had tried working upstairs and almost come down with heat stroke. Luckily, there had been a wobbly rolltop desk on the verandah. Hazel helped him set it up surreally on the lawn, under the fairly constant shade of a survivor elm. He replaced the missing foot with a nonessential book &#8211; William LeQueux&rsquo;s nigh-unreadable Great War in England in 1897 &#8211; and now had a decent workspace. The extension cord of his IBM electric snaked back into the house through the kitchen window. Papers flapped under makeshift weights, which was irritating, but even the slightest breeze was better than still heat. The typewriter hummed, but he didn&rsquo;t even have a sheet of paper in the roller. This was one of his &lsquo;thinking&rsquo; sessions, which meant he was stalled, letting his mind wander until his unconscious sorted out what he should do next and passed the message upstairs.</p>

<p>The converted cow sheds had big folding doors that opened to turn the studio into a cutaway diagram. Hazel was hunched over her wheel, working a lump of clay. She pushed her longish hair out of her eyes with a dry wrist, then got her wet fingers back to the emerging pot. Clay rose and fell, a mushroom cloud, a vinegar bottle. Throwing pots was hypnotic, almost erotic, to watch. Sometimes the process appealed more than the result.</p>

<p>Paul knew nothing about ceramics but could tell Hazel relied too often on what her tutors told her. In the shop attached to the studio, her pots were distinct from the Bleaches&rsquo;, wax fruit among the real. But she was improving. Certainly, she had been the more productive of them so far this summer. She applied herself with enviable concentration, a strength he hadn&rsquo;t expected.</p>

<p>He had been going out with her since Easter, and it was now mid-July. Paul supposed he loved her, although he was always uncomfortable with the &lsquo;L&rsquo; word. She was named Hazel for hazel eyes, naturally. In fact, almost almond eyes. She had very slight epicanthic folds. Her father had been in the Navy. Maybe a seafaring ancestor once took a Chinese wife. Otherwise, he guessed she was just pretty. She was Paul&rsquo;s first major affair since Sally the Psychotic &#8211; she had liked skunk music and torn up T-shirts for a rock-merchandising company &#8211; and they had arranged to spend the summer together before deciding whether she should move into his flat back in Brighton. He&rsquo;d thought this a formality, but now the possibility of it not working out was starting to tickle the back of his mind. While the countryside was very obviously burning up, they were almost imperceptibly cooling off.</p>

<p>The crisis had been official since spring, and the harvest was set to be a disaster. The land was ailing. Around him, the grass was piss-yellow. Up in the orchard, the property was a post-holocaust wasteland. The apples had ripened early, but under shiny skins the fruit had been sour and hard. This morning, Hazel had had to get up at six to phone the Bleaches, on their lecture tour in Canada until September, and break the bad news. Their garden was suffering a slow, lingering death. Mike and Mirrie were understanding. The instructions were to do the best to limit the damage. Paul had only met the couple once, but liked them very much. Mike was external assessor for the polytechnic, and one of Hazel&rsquo;s tutors recommended her as a working caretaker for the summer. The Bleaches were right not to shut up shop while they were away; agriculture might be down, but tourism was up. The shop was so busy some mornings that Paul had to fill in for Hazel with customers so she could get a few uninterrupted hours at the wheel.</p>

<p>The bell by the showroom steps jingled. He looked across the lawn. Hazel was sliding off the seat of her wheel, brushing off her apron. The visitors weren&rsquo;t customers. They hadn&rsquo;t gone into the shop. Hazel joined them on the steps. Paul realized immediately they were a pair of Jago&rsquo;s peace-and-love zombies. In their Woodstock-era outfits and beatific living-dead expressions, they were unmistakable. He&rsquo;d seen a few of the species around the village, but had never had to speak to any of them. Until now. He&rsquo;d heard of Alder before this summer, of course. The Village Where god Lives. There&rsquo;d been a piece on cults in the Independent, and an acid profile of Anthony Jago in The New Statesman. The Agapemone was well away from the village but could be seen from the moor, a prime sample of early Victorian megalomaniac architecture halfway up its own little hill.</p>

<p>&lsquo;Hi,&rsquo; said the broad-hipped woman, &lsquo;my name&rsquo;s Wendy, and he&rsquo;s Derek. Welcome to Alder. We&rsquo;d have been round before, but it&rsquo;s been hectic.&rsquo;</p>

<p>She had brought flowers, miraculously unshrivelled, and handed them into Hazel&rsquo;s arms carefully, as if passing a baby. The Lord god evidently outranked the parish council when it came to water regulations. Paul had been yearning to violate the local authority&rsquo;s sprinkler ban and give emergency aid to the lawn, but water laws were being enforced with the zeal eighteenth-century revenue men had employed sniffing out lace smugglers.</p>

<p>&lsquo;Hello, I&rsquo;m Paul Forrestier.&rsquo; They&rsquo;d come over to his desk. Hazel had provisionally put the flowers in a vase in the showroom, and was wiping clay-grey hands on her caked apron. &lsquo;This is Hazel.&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;Chapel,&rsquo; she added, smiling. Her name was Chapelet actually, but she didn&rsquo;t like it. </p>

<p>&lsquo;Hi, thanks for the flowers.&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;We&rsquo;re from the Agapemone,&rsquo; said Wendy, &lsquo;that means&#8211;&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;Abode of Love,&rsquo; said Paul.</p>

<p>&lsquo;Right. I&rsquo;m impressed. I heard you were a brain of some sort. Are you a greek scholar?&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;No,&rsquo; he said, embarrassed. &lsquo;English Lit. I read an article...&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;Oh.&rsquo; Wendy dropped a hint of defensiveness. &lsquo;Well, never mind. Don&rsquo;t be put off. Jesus Christ didn&rsquo;t get a good press either. We&rsquo;re not really like the Manson family, honest.&rsquo;</p>

<p>Wendy&rsquo;s cheeriness was suddenly unconvincing. <i>The New Statesman</i> had compared Jago with Sun Myung Moon, L. Ron Hubbard and, tactfully, Jim Jones, but Paul let it pass. He didn&rsquo;t want to go into a discussion of the tenets of the Acid gospel. He had Wendy and Derek pegged as old hippies, but Wendy&rsquo;s conversational daintiness was almost conventional. She wore CND, Animal Rights and Legalize It patches on her embroidered waistcoat, and her grey-touched hair was frizzed and long. However, she&rsquo;d have been as happy representing the Women&rsquo;s Institute as a fringe cult which worshipped god in the flesh. Under multicoloured skirt and tie-dyed blouse, she was creeping chubbily into middle age.</p>

<p>&lsquo;Tony&rsquo;s amazing,&rsquo; said the man, Derek. He was thin and worn, his Midlands-accented hesitance suggesting he did little of the talking. &lsquo;He&rsquo;s got the whole world sussed.&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;Oh yes.&rsquo; Wendy took over again, digging leaflets out of her Rupert Bear shoulder bag. Hazel took one. &lsquo;He&rsquo;s helped us sort ourselves out. We used to be really screwed up.&rsquo;</p>

<p>Paul cringed inwardly. He was afraid Wendy was going to ramble on about their Messiah.</p>

<p>&lsquo;He&rsquo;s far out,&rsquo; said Derek, without apparent irony. If this went on much longer, Paul was going to have trouble keeping a straight face. Hazel sat in one of the garden chairs and picked through the handout. Wendy and Derek sat on the ground, cross-legged. Derek plucked a few straw-coloured blades of grass, and started braiding them. &lsquo;The earth is dying,&rsquo; he said. Or was that &lsquo;The Earth is dying&rsquo;?</p>

<p>&lsquo;Yeah,&rsquo; said Paul. &lsquo;Time for the big red sunset and the giant crabs.&rsquo; &lsquo;<i>The Time Machine, right</i>?&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;Yes.&rsquo; Paul was surprised. He would assume Derek was remembering the film, but Hollywood had left out the giant crabs. Hazel was excited, brighter than he had seen her since spring. &lsquo;Can we go?&rsquo; The tiny overlap of her front teeth, which she hated and he quite liked, showed, as it did whenever she forgot not to smile broadly. She handed him a leaflet. It was for the summer festival. He did not realize how big it was going to be. Hazel pointed out the names of several groups he had never heard of. One of the headline acts was Loud Shit, a skunk band Sally had taken him to last year. He didn&rsquo;t think they&rsquo;d get involved in anything remotely religious, and grinned at the idea of how well they would go down with the Tory-voting farmers of Alder. The nearest they came to a love song was a number called &lsquo;Fuck Off and Die&rsquo;. He&rsquo;d broken up with Sally shortly afterwards, when she&rsquo;d had one of her breasts tattooed.</p>

<p>&lsquo;We were going to ask you...&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;(Because you make pots)&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;...if you&rsquo;d like a stall to sell stuff from. We&rsquo;ve got all sorts of crafts people. Weavers, woodturners, jewellers. And some really good theatre groups. And things for kids. We&rsquo;ve been scheming for months. It&rsquo;ll be even better than last year.&rsquo;</p>

<p>Hazel went &lsquo;umm&rsquo;. She was unhappy with her recent work.</p>

<p>&lsquo;I&rsquo;ve only had one gloss firing, and there was a hiccough with the glaze. Too many things came out dingy brown. I haven&rsquo;t got much sellable stuff. A few things from last term.&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;I&rsquo;m sure it&rsquo;ll be lovely.&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;Most people will be stoned anyway,&rsquo; said Derek, nearly giggling. &lsquo;They&rsquo;ll make up their own colours.&rsquo;</p>

<p>A pause. Wendy&rsquo;s lips thinned momentarily. Derek would get a reasonable talking-to later, Paul was sure. He felt sorry for the man, intuiting that he&rsquo;d been dragged by his girlfriend into Jago&rsquo;s sect and was liable to be stuck with it. Until the Reverend gave the Beatles&rsquo; Double White one spin too many and called for a bloodbath, or, depressed by an income-tax investigation, decided it was time to try out the Kool-Aid and cyanide cocktail on his congregation.</p>

<p>&lsquo;But I&rsquo;m firing again tonight. I think I know where I went wrong. I&rsquo;m not used to this big kiln. If it turns out okay, I&rsquo;ll have some pretty things. I hope. I&rsquo;ve also got a couple of boxes of Mike and Mirrie Bleach&rsquo;s pots. They&rsquo;re supposed to replace the work that sells from the shop, but nobody will mind if they go during the festival.&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;That&rsquo;s great.&rsquo; Wendy clacked her beads. &lsquo;We&rsquo;ll put you down for a table. Come over to the Agapemone when you can, and pick a site. We don&rsquo;t lock up or anything. We try to be really open, and anyone can come to one of our meals or Tony&rsquo;s services. There&rsquo;s no real mystery. We&rsquo;d like to have you. Both.&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;Thanks, I&rsquo;m a bit busy with my thesis, but&#8211;&rsquo;</p>

<p>&lsquo;We&rsquo;d love to drop over,&rsquo; said Hazel. &lsquo;There&rsquo;s blow all else to do out here.&rsquo;</p>

<p>Hazel took Paul&rsquo;s hand. Hers was dry, and he felt slip-clay powder between their palms.</p>

<p>&lsquo;You must come. He&rsquo;ll like you. And you&rsquo;ll like Him. Tony.&rsquo;</p>

<p>Paul had known whom Wendy meant. The Reverend Anthony William Jago. In photographs, he had eyes like Robert Powell as Jesus and the three-weeks-dead expression Paul associated with William S. Burroughs.</p>

<p>Post addressed to &lsquo;The Lord god, Alder&rsquo; was apparently delivered to him.</p>

<p>&lsquo;We must be going,&rsquo; Wendy said. &lsquo;So much to do, so little time to do it in.&rsquo;</p>

<p>When Wendy and Derek had gone, Hazel got a different vase for the flowers and filled it with precious water. Then she went back to work, and Paul was left to his books.</p>

<p><a href="http://amzn.to/10RmgLv">Jago</a>, by Kim Newman</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/BWG8mIbyDvQ" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Titan Books has released a brand-new edition of Kim Newsman's critically-acclaimed 1993 adult horror novel, Jago. Paul, a young academic composing a thesis about the end of the world, and his girlfriend Hazel, a potter, have come to the tiny English village of Alder for the summer. Their idea of a rural retreat gradually sours [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/kim-newmans-critically-accla.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/kim-newmans-critically-accla.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Minimalist Parenting: Getting Things Done meets childrearing</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/8nMN6dEOSj8/minimalist-parenting.html</link><category>Post</category><category>books</category><category>gift guide</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>Kids</category><category>lifehacks</category><category>parenting</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 06:28:20 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=193931</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>
<img src="http://craphound.com/images/minimalist parenting-final.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1937134342/downandoutint-20">Minimalist Parenting: Enjoy Modern Family Life More by Doing Less</a> is a just-published book by Asha Dornfest (of <a href="http://www.parenthacks.com/">Parenthacks</a>) and Christine Koh. It's a simple, short, entirely sensible guide to escaping social expectations and personal childrearing anxiety. It's a book about figuring out the parenting choices that'll make you and your family the happiest, and to clearing your life of all the stuff that's been foisted on you as a must-do for modern parenting. 
<p>
There's a lot of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0142000280/downandoutint-20">Getting Things Done</a> in here (tailored for parenting), a lot of general life-hacking, and a lot of free-range parenting. For me, it was just the right balance of time-saving tips, techniques for figuring out your own priorities, and specific advice about schools, holidays and birthdays, vacations, chores, allowance, and all the other minutae of parenting. It's a great book for new parents and for those of us already mid-adventure.




<p>
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1937134342/downandoutint-20">Minimalist Parenting: Enjoy Modern Family Life More by Doing Less</a>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/8nMN6dEOSj8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Minimalist Parenting: Enjoy Modern Family Life More by Doing Less is a just-published book by Asha Dornfest (of Parenthacks) and Christine Koh. It's a simple, short, entirely sensible guide to escaping social expectations and personal childrearing anxiety. It's a book about figuring out the parenting choices that'll make you and your family the happiest, and [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/minimalist-parenting.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/minimalist-parenting.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Google Maps now allows you to explore Everest, Kilimanjaro and other great mountains</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/AYYzLalIK5U/google-maps-now-allows-you-to.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 06:18:23 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219608</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="240" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="https://www.google.com/maps?layer=c&amp;cbp=13,23.32,,0,-9.74&amp;panoid=H8PAjy9NvX-vXj6mqmiNxA&amp;t=m&amp;cbll=-3.068289,37.327011&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;source=embed&amp;ll=-3.112406,37.347507&amp;spn=0.082276,0.145912&amp;z=12&amp;output=svembed" width="425"></iframe><br />
</div>

<p>Google this week unveiled the ability to virtually explore, via Google Maps, some of the most famous mountains on Earth, including Aconcagua (South America), Kilimanjaro (Africa), Mount Elbrus (Europe) and Everest Base Camp (Asia). 



<blockquote>These mountains belong to the group of peaks known as the Seven Summits—the highest mountain on each of the seven continents. While there’s nothing quite like standing on the mountain, with Google Maps you can instantly transport yourself to the top of these peaks and enjoy the sights without all of the avalanches, rock slides, crevasses, and dangers from altitude and weather that mountaineers face. </p><p>Start your adventure on Tanzania’s Mount Kilimanjaro, the dormant volcano known as the Roof of Africa. See amazing views of the highest freestanding mountain in the world covered in snow just three degrees south of the equator.</p></blockquote>

<p>It's pretty amazing. I <a href="http://www.explorers.org/">attended the Explorer's Club 2013 dinner</a> over the weekend with people who have actually summited these mountains (the experience of being a fly on the wall during that dinner is a blog post all its own), and this is a great tool for the many of us who won't make it up there in our lifetimes. And, for young people whose horizons need expanding. <p>
<a href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2013/03/explore-everest-kilimanjaro-and-more.html'>Official Blog: Explore Everest, Kilimanjaro and more with Google Maps</a>.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/AYYzLalIK5U" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Google this week unveiled the ability to virtually explore, via Google Maps, some of the most famous mountains on Earth, including Aconcagua (South America), Kilimanjaro (Africa), Mount Elbrus (Europe) and Everest Base Camp (Asia). These mountains belong to the group of peaks known as the Seven Summits—the highest mountain on each of the seven continents. [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/google-maps-now-allows-you-to.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/google-maps-now-allows-you-to.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Rube Goldberg machines in YouTube Space Tokyo</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/NzqN--mmgkA/rube-goldberg-machines-in-yout.html</link><category>Video</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 06:13:03 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219603</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--youtu.be--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/bXRK4nOhaP8?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

Japan, India and Korea YouTube creators <a href="http://youtu.be/bXRK4nOhaP8">build a huge Rube Goldberg machine</a> in YouTube Space Tokyo. Boing Boing pal <a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/03/19/aibo-japans-beatboxing-prin.html">Aibo the beatbox princess</a> has by far the coolest part! <em>(Thanks, <a href="http://shey.net">Tim Shey</a>!)</em><p>
<div class="previously2">
<em>&nbsp;</em><ul><li><a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/04/26/japanese-beatbox-princess-aibo.html#previouspost">Japanese beatbox princess Aibo gives a shout-out to.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/03/19/aibo-japans-beatboxing-prin.html#previouspost">Aibo, Japan&#39;s Beatboxing Princess, with and without cats (video ...</a></li>
<li><a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/03/05/meet-japanese-human-beatboxe.html#previouspost">Meet Japanese &quot;human beatboxer&quot; Hikakin (and prepare to be ...</a></li>
<li><a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/06/27/japanese-beatboxer-hikakin-mee.html#previouspost">Japan-based beatboxer Hikakin meets US-based freestyle dancer ...</a></li>
</ul>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/NzqN--mmgkA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Japan, India and Korea YouTube creators &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/bXRK4nOhaP8"&gt;build a huge Rube Goldberg machine&lt;/a&gt; in YouTube Space Tokyo.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/rube-goldberg-machines-in-yout.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/rube-goldberg-machines-in-yout.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>CNN, Fox News, MSNBC air name of 16yo Steubenville rape victim</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/Iufbeeq1HLs/cnn-fox-news-msnbc-air-name.html</link><category>Short</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 06:05:18 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219601</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[Three cable news networks, CNN, Fox News and MSNBC, <a href='http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/18/fox-news-steubenville-rape-victim_n_2901635.html?ir=Media'>outed the underage victim in the Steubenville rape trial by name</a> during reports about the case. The identification of the 16 year old rape victim occurred in the course of a clip in which one of the convicted rapists apologized to the victim and her family. Local CBS affiliate WTRF also aired the clip without editing out the victim's name. [HuffPo]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/Iufbeeq1HLs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Three cable news networks, CNN, Fox News and MSNBC, outed the underage victim in the Steubenville rape trial by name during reports about the case. The identification of the 16 year old rape victim occurred in the course of a clip in which one of the convicted rapists apologized to the victim and her family. [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/cnn-fox-news-msnbc-air-name.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/cnn-fox-news-msnbc-air-name.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Occupy SXSW 2013</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/c6Yarb4dbug/occupy-sxsw-2013.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Jasmina Tesanovic</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 06:00:51 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219597</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/sxsw.jpg" alt="" title="sxsw" width="1105" height="623" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-219628" />

<p class="caption">Image: Creative Commons <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en">Attribution 2.0 Generic</a> image from <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/dumbledad/">Tim Regan's</a> photostream</p><p>



I must start with a tweet from my wise friend Xeni Jardin:
<p>
"Some of you have asked why I'm not at SXSW: as a person with cancer, have I not suffered enough already?"
<p>
    Well, some of us still are there at South By South West every year,  among hordes of nerds, geeks and unnoticed celebrities in a magnificent carnival of tech  in Austin, Texas.<p>

    This year, I had Stendhal’s syndrome after day two: I risked a stampede while fleeing the endless queue for Al Gore’ s keynote.   At a festival of this size, people queue like in war zones where any queue means available goods.  It's only after you get a firm place in line that you ask: what are we waiting for?<p>

   Individualism in  armies is not tolerated, and by day three the entire army itself seemed as crushed  by the challenge as I was.  The geeks walked aimlessly, tired, with  dark bags around their eyes, dirty clothes, undone laces.   Austin is a besieged town in these ten days: with thirty thousand paying attendees and an un-numbered horde of  locals and curiosity-seekers, roaming the streets of this  proudly weird city.<p><span id="more-219597"></span>

    The headless and dismembered horde of internet geeks overloaded the Internet in the Austin convention center, and  phone service also crashed because of too much downloading,  uploading, tweeting, flickring, tumblring and whatever new social media was invented this year.  Every startup longs to become a Twitter, leaping into prominence among these early adopters  and thought pioneers.  They may expect a Twitter at SXSW 2007 and find themselves with an Arab revolution of 2011!
<p>
When you are at SXSW, you have an anxious feeling of missing just about everything except the event you are actually seeing.  Seeing too much too soon  upsets the stomach, and how painful to think that your limited human mind will never comprehend the virtual nomadic language of these young natives. Even their body language changes radically year by year, as they invent new ways of poking, stroking or scratching their new devices.  You can forget the mannerly habits of looking people straight in the eye, cordially shaking their hand.   Their eyes drift when they speak, they stare at their handheld devices and send smilies to distant comrades, and instead of shaking hands they bump fists.<p>

    A new esthetics implies a new fashion. This year the crowd was much better dressed than last year: fewer fat desktop jockeys and more girls who "forgot their skirts" it's all about elastic jeggings and beautiful computer generated patterned tights.
<p>
     A panel explained how to wear  gadgets in the future; expect them to vanish into the electric seams of the clothing.  Since we are becoming tech fashion victims,  why consider it creepy to wander the streets with head-mounted Google Glass?  What could there be to fear in enhancing the human experience, by tossing one's clumsy phone aside and wearing it on your forehead?  Why hide the technology, for if you hide it too effectively you're being spied upon by surveillance you can't even see.  Put GPS inside your beautiful shoes, then draw tender hearts on the fabric of your jeans and have your trousers send that straight to the pants  of a loved one.  As your heart beats faster with emotional joy, your blouse and your earrings blush with LED color.
<p>
    Augmented Reality  activist/ artists are getting political, using their devices to "invade" the closed locales of NATO bases, or decorating the air around the tents of the Occupy movement in New York and elsewhere.
<p>
    Half the participants  at SXSW seem to be volunteers, a hardworking invisible army of young locals who supply the sweat and labor behind the fancy screens and stages of the interactive superstars.  This found a strange parallel in the film "Good Old Freda," which documented the obscure life of hardworking Beatles fan and secretary Freda Kelly.  This teenage Beatlemania devotee was the private,  invisible secretary of  The Beatles, faithfully answering their fan mail from their very first day and after the band split.  A woman who once she stopped working for the Beatles,  scarcely bothered to tell her story, even to her children or grandchildren.  Until today! and boy, Freda is the best of the Beatles, the only one who wasn't destroyed by all the hype!
<p>
At SXSW the  halls and rooms and ballrooms were set that everybody could be a star for three minutes:  you could sit on throne of the "Games of Thrones" fantasy television series, or stand in an ad for some fancy product…the horizontal structure of social media transforms the masses into Good ol' Fredas with a story to tell.  We can only hope there is somebody left to listen!
<p>
On Tuesday, with the hordes mostly gone back to the coasts or Europe, the event closed with three Austin gurus, futurists and-or hustlers,  Hugh Forrest, Jon Lebkowsky and Bruce Sterling, veterans of the event's early days, confronting a second and third generation of geeks.  <p>It was a moving sign that the show must go on… Occupy SXSW!<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/c6Yarb4dbug" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Image: Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 Generic image from Tim Regan's photostream I must start with a tweet from my wise friend Xeni Jardin: "Some of you have asked why I'm not at SXSW: as a person with cancer, have I not suffered enough already?" Well, some of us still are there at South By South [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/occupy-sxsw-2013.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/occupy-sxsw-2013.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>More on the impact of UK press regulation on blogs, websites, tweeters, and social media</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/rg2UwYcNdTI/more-on-the-impact-of-uk-press.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Business</category><category>free speech</category><category>law</category><category>uk</category><category>web theory</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 04:48:54 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219593</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<p>
Further to yesterday's <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/uk-press-regulation-defines.html">post</a> about the way that the UK's new press regulation will affect bloggers, tweeters, tumblrers, facebookers, et al., Lisa O'Carroll at the <em>Guardian</em> points out that anyone who doesn't sign up for the "voluntary" system of press regulation will be liable to punitive "exemplary" damages for libel, as well as being on the hook for their accusers' legal fees, even if no fault is found.

<blockquote>
<p>The exemplary damages clause was recommended in the Leveson report but has been opposed by newspapers, including the Guardian, which have been given legal advice that it could be contrary to the European convention on human rights, which enshrines the principle of free speech.
<p>
Lord Lester, the campaigner for libel reform, warned during the Leveson debate in the House of Lords earlier this year that publications such as Private Eye and local newspapers could face closure as a result of the imposition of exemplary damages.
<p>
On Monday night, the editor of the Guardian, Alan Rusbridger said he welcomed cross-party agreement on press regulation, but said: "We retain grave reservations about the proposed legislation on exemplary damages."
<p>
Under sustained questioning on Monday night during the Commons debate about the courts bill, which includes the Leveson regulations, the culture secretary, Maria Miller, said the "publisher would have to meet the three tests of whether the publication is publishing news-related material in the course of a business, whether their material is written by a range of authors – this would exclude a one-man band or a single blogger – and whether that material is subject to editorial control".

</blockquote>

<p>
But if you and three friends edit a joint Twitter account or blog or Facebook group, you fit the bill. To those who say that a Twitter account isn't a website, I think they're erroneously assuming consensus about what is and isn't a webpage. If www.wordpress.com/doctorow is a website, then why isn't www.twitter.com/doctorow?

<p>
<a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2013/mar/19/bloggers-libel-fines-press-regulation">Bloggers may face libel fines under press regulation deal</a>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/rg2UwYcNdTI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Further to yesterday's post about the way that the UK's new press regulation will affect bloggers, tweeters, tumblrers, facebookers, et al., Lisa O'Carroll at the Guardian points out that anyone who doesn't sign up for the "voluntary" system of press regulation will be liable to punitive "exemplary" damages for libel, as well as being on [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/more-on-the-impact-of-uk-press.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/more-on-the-impact-of-uk-press.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Cory at Forbidden Planet London with Rapture of the Nerds this Saturday!</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/TSUuOmq7v-E/cory-at-forbidden-planet-londo.html</link><category>Post</category><category>books</category><category>events</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>london</category><category>singularity</category><category>uk</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 03:31:57 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219429</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<P>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8569214688_c3f6ae213f_b1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />



Hey, Londoners! A quick reminder that <a href="http://forbiddenplanet.com/events/2013/03/23/cory-doctorow-signing-rapture-nerds/">I'll be signing the new UK edition</a> of <a href="http://craphound.com/rotn">Rapture of the Nerds</a> this Saturday at Forbidden Planet on Shaftesbury Ave at 13h. Come on down and say hi!

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/TSUuOmq7v-E" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Hey, Londoners! A quick reminder that I'll be signing the new UK edition of Rapture of the Nerds this Saturday at Forbidden Planet on Shaftesbury Ave at 13h. Come on down and say hi!</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/cory-at-forbidden-planet-londo.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/19/cory-at-forbidden-planet-londo.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Casino cheats used house CCTVs to score $32M</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/ziACE80Pknk/the-cameras-at-crown-are-state.html</link><category>Post</category><category>australia</category><category>cctv</category><category>crime</category><category>gambling</category><category>petard</category><category>security</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 20:12:24 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219357</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>
<iframe src ="http://video.heraldsun.com.au/embed/2344441648/Crown-Casino-in-high-tech-scam?player=narrow" width="330" height="365" frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
<p>
A rich, high-stakes gambler was dragged out of his opulent comp suite at the  Crown Towers casino in Melbourne, accused of participating in a $32M scam that made use of the casino's own CCTV cameras to cheat. 
<p>


<blockquote>
<p>
The Herald Sun understands remote access to the venue's security system was given to an unauthorised person.
<p>
Images relayed from cameras were then used to spy on a top-level gaming area where the high roller was playing.
<p>
Signals were given to him on how he should bet based on the advice of someone viewing the camera feeds. Sources said the total stolen was $32 million.
<p>

<p>
They are capable of transmitting the most intricate detail of goings-on inside the building.
</blockquote>
<p>
Casinos were the world leaders in CCTV use, and really represent ground zero for the panopticon theory of security. What is rarely mentioned is that "security" measures can be turned against defenders if attackers can hijack them. This is as true when a mugger uses his victim's gun against him as it is when a casino's own CCTVs are used to defeat its own anti-cheating measures. This is the high-stakes gambling version of all those IP-based CCTVs that leak sensitive footage of the inside of peoples' houses onto the public Internet.

<P>
<a href="http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/law-order/crown-casino-hi-tech-scam-nets-32-million/story-fnat79vb-1226597666337">Crown casino hi-tech scam nets $32 million</a> [Mark Buttler/Herald Sun]

<p>
(<i>via <a href="http://slashdot.org">/.</a></i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/ziACE80Pknk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>A rich, high-stakes gambler was dragged out of his opulent comp suite at the Crown Towers casino in Melbourne, accused of participating in a $32M scam that made use of the casino's own CCTV cameras to cheat. The Herald Sun understands remote access to the venue's security system was given to an unauthorised person. Images [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/the-cameras-at-crown-are-state.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/the-cameras-at-crown-are-state.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Peter Murphy busted for DUI hit-and-run injury and meth possession</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/BESSy2RS_eg/peter-murphy-busted-for-dui-hi.html</link><category>Post</category><category>crime</category><category>goth</category><category>music</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Pescovitz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 19:25:59 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219554</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>
Peter Murphy, singer for Bauhaus, was arrested this weekend in Los Angeles for an alleged DUI hit-and-run that reportedly injured the other driver. A witness followed Murphy and blocked him until cops arrived. According to police, Murphy appeared to be "very confused." From the Glendale News Press:


<blockquote><img style="display:block; margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;" src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NewImage68.png" alt="NewImage" title="NewImage.png" border="0" width="398" height="499" class="alignright"/>Murphy denied drinking alcohol that day, adding that he had only taken his regular prescription pills for depression, according to police.
<p>
Murphy — who’s from England but lives in Turkey — reportedly admitted to being involved in a traffic collision, telling officers he was jet-lagged from a recent flight, police said. 
<p>
Inside the Los Angeles police patrol car where Murphy had been detained, officers reported finding a small plastic bag, possibly of methamphetamine, police said. Murphy denied the bag belonged to him, but officers said they believed he was trying to discard it in the patrol car.</blockquote>

"<a href="http://www.glendalenewspress.com/news/tn-818-0318-british-goth-rocker-arrested-for-alleged-dui-hitandrun-in-glendale,0,7800622.story">Peter Murphy arrested for alleged DUI hit-and-run in Glendale</a>" <em>(Thanks, <a href="http://totaldickhead.blogspot.com">Dave Gill</a>!)</em><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/BESSy2RS_eg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Peter Murphy, singer for Bauhaus, was arrested this weekend in Los Angeles for an alleged DUI hit-and-run that reportedly injured the other driver. A witness followed Murphy and blocked him until cops arrived. According to police, Murphy appeared to be "very confused." From the Glendale News Press: Murphy denied drinking alcohol that day, adding that [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/peter-murphy-busted-for-dui-hi.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/peter-murphy-busted-for-dui-hi.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Down and Out in the Magic Kingdom read-aloud part 01</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/8g0PR54dHLU/down-and-out-in-the-magic-king.html</link><category>Post</category><category>audiobooks</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>podcasts</category><category>science fiction</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 17:30:19 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219509</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<iframe src="http://archive.org/embed/Cory_Doctorow_Podcast_242" width="500" height="30" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>
As I mentioned in <a href="http://www.locusmag.com/Perspectives/2013/03/cory-doctorow-ten-years-on/">my March Locus column</a>, I'm celebrating the tenth anniversary of <a href="http://craphound.com/down">Down and Out in the Magic Kingdom</a> by planning a prequel volume. As part of that planning, I'm going to read aloud the entire text of that first book into my podcast, making notes on the book as I go. Here's part one.
<p>
Mastering by John Taylor Williams: wryneckstudio@gmail.com
<p>
John Taylor Williams is a audiovisual and multimedia producer based in Washington, DC and the co-host of the Living Proof Brew Cast. Hear him wax poetic over a pint or two of beer by visiting <a href="http://livingproofbrewcast.com/">livingproofbrewcast.com</a>. In his free time he makes "Beer Jewelry" and "Odd Musical Furniture." He often "meditates while reading cookbooks."  
<p>
<a href="https://archive.org/download/Cory_Doctorow_Podcast_242/Cory_Doctorow_Podcast_242_Down_and_Out_in_the_Magic_Kingdom_01.mp3">MP3 link</a>
<p>
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/doctorow_podcast">Podcast subscription link (RSS/XML)</a><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/8g0PR54dHLU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>As I mentioned in my March Locus column, I'm celebrating the tenth anniversary of Down and Out in the Magic Kingdom by planning a prequel volume. As part of that planning, I'm going to read aloud the entire text of that first book into my podcast, making notes on the book as I go. Here's [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/down-and-out-in-the-magic-king.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/down-and-out-in-the-magic-king.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Copyright shouldn't take away real property rights</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/GUK2YlXi9NE/copyright-shouldnt-take-away.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Copyfight</category><category>dmca</category><category>drm</category><category>makers</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 16:02:02 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219480</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<p>
iFixit's Kyle Wiens has a must-read op-ed in <em>Wired</em> on the insane way that copyright is being used to take away your property rights in tools as diverse as tractors and cars and cellphones and phone switches. The manufacturers use a variety of copyright claims (especially anti-circumvention claims under the 1998 Digital Millennium Copyright Act/DMCA) to make it illegal to understand how your stuff works, to improve on it, or to repair it. Wiens makes the good point that it's nuts to use metaphorical property (copyright) to end real property rights in things that you buy and pay for.

<blockquote>
Meanwhile, progress is being made to legalize cellphone unlocking. With grassroots groups leading the charge, the Obama administration announced its support for overturning the ban last week. Since then, members of Congress have authored no fewer than four bills to legalize unlocking.
<p>
This is a step in the right direction, but it’s not enough. Let’s make one thing clear: Fixing our cars, tractors, and cellphones should have nothing to do with copyright.
<p>
As long as Congress focuses on just unlocking cellphones, they’re missing the larger point. Senators could pass a hundred unlocking bills; five years from now large companies will find some other copyright claim to limit consumer choice. To really solve the problem, Congress must enact meaningful copyright reform. The potential economic benefits are significant, as free information creates jobs. Service information is freely available online for many smartphones from iFixit (my organization) and other websites. Not coincidentally, thousands of cellphone repair businesses have sprung up in recent years, using the repair knowledge to keep broken cellphones out of landfills.
<p>
As long as we’re limited in our ability to modify and repair things, copyright — for all objects — will discourage creativity. It will cost us money. It will cost us jobs. And it’s already costing us our freedom.
</blockquote>

<P>
<A HREF="http://www.wired.com/opinion/2013/03/you-dont-own-your-cellphones-or-your-cars">Forget the Cellphone Fight — We Should Be Allowed to Unlock Everything We Own</a>

(<i>via <a href="http://slashdot.org">/.</a></i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/GUK2YlXi9NE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>iFixit's Kyle Wiens has a must-read op-ed in Wired on the insane way that copyright is being used to take away your property rights in tools as diverse as tractors and cars and cellphones and phone switches. The manufacturers use a variety of copyright claims (especially anti-circumvention claims under the 1998 Digital Millennium Copyright Act/DMCA) [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/copyright-shouldnt-take-away.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/copyright-shouldnt-take-away.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Machines that do nothing but switch themselves off</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/sgGIO8kblSc/machines-that-do-nothing-but-s.html</link><category>Short</category><category>Funny</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>hobbies</category><category>joy</category><category>machines</category><category>Science</category><category>Technology</category><category>Weird</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maggie Koerth-Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 15:41:50 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219545</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[Useless machines are home-built <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887323628804578348572687608806.html">devices that turn themselves off as soon as you turn them on</a> &mdash; and that's it. That's all the they do. The more elaborate and gimmicky the method by which they accomplish this job, the better. As a hobby, useless machines have been around since the 1950s, but Abigail Pesta of the Wall Street Journal says they're making a comeback. <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/sgGIO8kblSc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Useless machines are home-built devices that turn themselves off as soon as you turn them on &amp;#8212; and that's it. That's all the they do. The more elaborate and gimmicky the method by which they accomplish this job, the better. As a hobby, useless machines have been around since the 1950s, but Abigail Pesta of [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/machines-that-do-nothing-but-s.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/machines-that-do-nothing-but-s.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Literature's business model explained, with special reference to the age of the Internet</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/-aVTSAlmJfw/literatures-business-model-e.html</link><category>Post</category><category>books</category><category>Business</category><category>Copyfight</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>History</category><category>publishing</category><category>web theory</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 15:38:31 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219424</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/6780422391_9491b35a37_z1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
Richard Nash's essay "On the business of literature" is one of the best, most thought-provoking, most beautifully argued articles about the business of publishing through history and in the Internet age that I've ever read. It's one of those pieces from which it is nearly impossible to choose an illustrative quotation -- as I read, I kept happening on passages and thinking, "Aha, that's what I'll put in the post so people will know how interesting and important this is," only to find <em>another</em> passage a few minutes later that superseded the former one. So here's one quote to whet your appetite, and I'll stick another after the jump, but for heaven's sake, just go read the whole thing. Really.

<blockquote>
<p>
	What is particularly crucial to understand is that books were not dragged kicking and screaming into each new area of capitalism. Books not only are part and parcel of consumer capitalism, they virtually began it. They are part of the fuel that drives it. The growth of the chain model in books offered everyone the opportunity to decry the groceryfication of the bookstore, utterly belying the reality, as Striphas outlines in his excellent The Late Age of Print, that the bookstore is in fact the model for the supermarket:
<p>
   <em> In the history of shop design, it is bookstores, strangely enough, that were the precursors of supermarkets. They, alone of all types of shop, made use of shelves that were not behind counters, with the goods arranged for casual browsing, and for what was not yet called self-service. Also, when brand name goods and their accompanying packages were non-existent or rare in the sale of food, books had covers that were designed at once to protect the contents and to entice the purchaser; they were proprietary products with identifiable authors and new titles.</em>
<p>
There are other examples of significant innovation being driven by the publishers—Penguin founder Allen Lane's 1937 paperback vending machine for better commuter distribution being among the most charming—but the point is that books aren't sitting grumpily in economy class on the airplane to the future. They're in the cockpit.
</blockquote>
<p>
Nash founded the amazing Soft Skull Press, which had many triumphs, not least publishing the amazing <a href="http://boingboing.net/2009/03/16/get-your-war-on-the-1.html">Get Your War On books</a>. 
<p>
<a href="http://www.vqronline.org/articles/2013/spring/nash-business-literature/">VQR » On the business of literature</a>

<span id="more-219424"></span>



<blockquote>
<p>
The PostScript output of PageMaker (later to become the more familiar "PDF") undermined the Industrial Revolution model, initiating the digital, post-Industrial phase of abundance, even though, at the time, it appeared to be reinforcing the Industrial model by reforming it. Independent presses could make digital files and send them to offset printers. They still had to deal with the classic economies of scale of analog printing, but they didn't have to deal with the complex, inaccessible, and arcane world of traditional typesetting. The number of publishers began to increase, as did the number of titles, as the creation of a title (by publisher, of course, not by author) became significantly cheaper and began to undo ever so slightly Vonnegut's otherwise accurate analysis of the business of culture. The genius opera singer needed systems to distribute her genius as broadly as possible, and the copyright system combined with analog reproduction made that easy. And it was getting easier for the non-mainstream, too, be that the lover of the avant-garde, or the early music, or the campy, or the local, or the familial (the recording of your grandmother singing opera). The non-mainstream was abetted by the growth of the superstore model of bookstores. The traditional independent bookstore stocked 5,000–10,000 titles, and so could only handle the new and backlist output of a limited number of publishers. But a Barnes &#038; Noble or Borders superstore could have fifty, sixty, or seventy thousand titles! Indeed, it needed those non-mainstream offerings to fill its shelves. Ironically, while indie, alternative, and literary presses frequently decried the predations of the superstores, the superstores were critical to their existence.
</blockquote>


<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/-aVTSAlmJfw" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Richard Nash's essay "On the business of literature" is one of the best, most thought-provoking, most beautifully argued articles about the business of publishing through history and in the Internet age that I've ever read. It's one of those pieces from which it is nearly impossible to choose an illustrative quotation -- as I read, [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/literatures-business-model-e.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/literatures-business-model-e.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Instant gold</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/HMjD6_7DPn4/instant-gold.html</link><category>Short</category><category>geology</category><category>minerals</category><category>Science</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maggie Koerth-Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 15:36:44 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219543</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[Under the right conditions, <a href="http://www.nature.com/news/earthquakes-make-gold-veins-in-an-instant-1.12615">veins of gold can form in just a few tenths of a second</a>, writes Richard Lovett at Nature News. The key is the massive changes in below-ground pressure that can accompany an earthquake. Under the right conditions, water vaporizes, leaving behind crystallized minerals. <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/HMjD6_7DPn4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Under the right conditions, veins of gold can form in just a few tenths of a second, writes Richard Lovett at Nature News. The key is the massive changes in below-ground pressure that can accompany an earthquake. Under the right conditions, water vaporizes, leaving behind crystallized minerals.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/instant-gold.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/instant-gold.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Cancer as a contagious disease</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/z28b8OHu0WQ/cancer-as-a-contagious-disease.html</link><category>Short</category><category>animals</category><category>cancer. weird</category><category>contagion</category><category>disease</category><category>Science</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maggie Koerth-Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 15:27:40 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219541</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[In 2011, Hugo Chavez alleged that he was the victim of an assassination plot ... that unnamed US agents had infected him with a transmissible cancer. Scientifically speaking, that's highly unlikely. But what's interesting is that the idea of contagious cancer isn't totally outside the realm of reality. <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=is-cancer-contagious">Transmissible cancers do exist, just not in any primate species</a>. At Scientific American, Marissa Fessenden
interviews a geneticist about the contagious cancers that affect dogs and Tasmanian devils. 
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/z28b8OHu0WQ" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>In 2011, Hugo Chavez alleged that he was the victim of an assassination plot ... that unnamed US agents had infected him with a transmissible cancer. Scientifically speaking, that's highly unlikely. But what's interesting is that the idea of contagious cancer isn't totally outside the realm of reality. Transmissible cancers do exist, just not in [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/cancer-as-a-contagious-disease.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/cancer-as-a-contagious-disease.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Space station cake from EVE Online</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/sysUXbQpYhM/space-station-cake-from-eve-on.html</link><category>Post</category><category>cake</category><category>carbs</category><category>Food</category><category>Games</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>mmorpgs</category><category>not food</category><category>science fiction</category><category>sculpture</category><category>Space</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 14:40:11 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219341</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/cc1f96dbb335810298139e9ed77b04211.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
This amazing EVE Online Gallente Space Station cake was created by Duff Goldma of <a href="http://www.charmcitycakes.com/">Charm City Cakes</a> in Baltimore, MD. It's unquestionably the greatest MMORPG space-station cake I've ever seen.

<p>
<a href="http://whengeekswed.com/blog/2013/03/18/dock-your-fork-in-this-gallente-space-station-cake/">Dock Your Fork in This Gallente Space Station Cake</a>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/sysUXbQpYhM" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>This amazing EVE Online Gallente Space Station cake was created by Duff Goldma of Charm City Cakes in Baltimore, MD. It's unquestionably the greatest MMORPG space-station cake I've ever seen. Dock Your Fork in This Gallente Space Station Cake</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/space-station-cake-from-eve-on.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/space-station-cake-from-eve-on.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Interview with Joel, Veronica, and Greg of Gizmodo's Gadget Testers</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/OIFB3Pz-SHo/interview-with-joel-veronica.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 14:19:58 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219530</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--youtu.be--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PgBKxLgyaY8?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>Earlier today Rob <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/dont-miss-joel-johnsons-gi.html">mentioned</a> <em>Gizmodo: The Gadget Testers</em>, a TV pilot that airs tonight at 10:20/9:20c on BBC America. It stars our pals Joel Johnson and Veronica Belmont. I interviewed Veronica, Joel, and co-host Greg Foot today about some of their funny experiences making the pilot.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/OIFB3Pz-SHo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Earlier today Rob mentioned Gizmodo: The Gadget Testers, a TV pilot that airs tonight at 10:20/9:20c on BBC America. It stars our pals Joel Johnson and Veronica Belmont. I interviewed Veronica, Joel, and co-host Greg Foot today about some of their funny experiences making the pilot.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/interview-with-joel-veronica.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/interview-with-joel-veronica.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Free downloadable magic/automata books from Robert Houdin's private club</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/Gez4-ZOPOmA/free-downloadable-magicautoma.html</link><category>Post</category><category>automata</category><category>books</category><category>ebooks</category><category>Gadgets</category><category>gift guide</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>History</category><category>magic</category><category>Old school</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 14:17:31 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219457</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
Dug North sez, "The book titled 'Two Odd Volumes on Magic & Automata; has been available <a href="http://leafpdx.com/pages/online_houdin.html">in a printed version</a> for a while, but is now available as a PDF. The book is offered for free from LEAFpdx, but I am sure donations would be welcome."


<blockquote>
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/two_odd_cover_240e1.jpg" align="right">
The Sette of Odd Volumes published two fantastic books in the early 1890s. The Sette was a club of book collectors and eccentric personalities in London. It was founded by the famed book dealer Bernard Quaritch in 1878. He collected members for his club much like he did rare editons: each had an expertise in some unusual specialty.
<p>
William Manning was a club member who gave an after dinner talk on his recollections of the great magician Robert-Houdin. When Manning was a young boy he met the great magician and befriended Robert-Houdin's sons. His 'recollections' about Robert-Houdin were later published as a small book. Reading it today, over a hundred years after the speech was originally given, one is still struck by how forward thinking Robert-Houdin was and how down to earth. He developed many famous magic acts that are still performed today. Originally trained as a clockmaker, Robert-Houdin built all his own automata and magic props. He experimented with electricity and even wired his house with clocks and alarms in the 1860s which must have seemed very magical indeed. Manning captures the spirit of his admired friend. His words make the magician seem very contemporary and even more remarkable.
</blockquote>

<P>
<a href="http://www.leafpdx.com/pages/donationware1.html">Two Odd Volumes on Magic &#038; Automata</a>

(<i>Thanks, <a href="http://blog.dugnorth.com/">Dug</a>!</i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/Gez4-ZOPOmA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Dug North sez, "The book titled 'Two Odd Volumes on Magic &amp; Automata; has been available in a printed version for a while, but is now available as a PDF. The book is offered for free from LEAFpdx, but I am sure donations would be welcome." The Sette of Odd Volumes published two fantastic books [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/free-downloadable-magicautoma.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/free-downloadable-magicautoma.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Just look at this banana sculpture.</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/ToeY52PwZmk/just-look-at-this-banana-sculp.html</link><category>Post</category><category>art</category><category>bananas</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>just look at it</category><category>not food</category><category>sculpture</category><category>wide</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 13:26:50 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219418</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/PageImage-507571-3372236-mbanana21.jpg"><br />
Just look at it.

<P>
<a href="http://mattstoneart.com/banana#/id/i3372236">fruit - Matt James Stone</a>

(<i>Thanks, Marie!</i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/ToeY52PwZmk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Just look at it. fruit - Matt James Stone (Thanks, Marie!)</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/just-look-at-this-banana-sculp.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/just-look-at-this-banana-sculp.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Growing up in the future</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/DrMHXtSlYqA/growing-up-in-the-future.html</link><category>Short</category><category>essays</category><category>future</category><category>futurism</category><category>Kids</category><category>Science</category><category>Technology</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maggie Koerth-Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 13:18:52 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219501</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[When Veronique Greenwood went to college in 2004, she took a laptop with her ... and a videophone. In an engaging essay at Aeon Magazine, <a href="http://www.aeonmagazine.com/world-views/veronique-greenwood-futurist-childhood/">Greenwood writes about what it was like to grow up with a Futurist for a mom</a>, particularly a futurist who, in retrospect, seemed to be more interested in premature technologies than in the sleek, widely adopted versions that eventually succeeded in the marketplace. Greenwood's mother loved the videophone. When Skype came along, free of dedicated hardware, she lost interest. <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/DrMHXtSlYqA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>When Veronique Greenwood went to college in 2004, she took a laptop with her ... and a videophone. In an engaging essay at Aeon Magazine, Greenwood writes about what it was like to grow up with a Futurist for a mom, particularly a futurist who, in retrospect, seemed to be more interested in premature technologies [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/growing-up-in-the-future.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/growing-up-in-the-future.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Django Django video for "WOR"</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/6q3cayy8kls/django-django-video-for-wor.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Video</category><category>Django Django</category><category>music</category><category>video</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Amy Seidenwurm</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 12:15:47 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219511</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--youtu.be--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ojVsXB12zC8?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>We featured <a href="http://www.djangodjango.co.uk/">Django Django</a>'s <a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/03/08/django-django-default-m.html">first single</a> over a year ago. The record came out in the U.S. in October and is still going strong.  "WOR"  is their 7th video from their self-titled debut, and is a mesmerizing peek into the lives of daredevils drivers at a fair in Allahabad.</p>
<p>Go see the band live - they're fun, charming,extremely talented and have the biggest tambourine you've ever seen. I highly recommend it - <a href="http://www.djangodjango.co.uk/live/">tour dates here.</a></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/6q3cayy8kls" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description> "WOR"  is Django Django's 7th video from their self-titled debut, and is a mesmerizing peek into the lives of daredevils drivers at a fair in Allahabad.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/django-django-video-for-wor.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/django-django-video-for-wor.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Yogurt for manly men</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/3TPlcWKO1FQ/yogurt-for-manly-men.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Food</category><category>gender</category><category>not food</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 11:36:42 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219335</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/yogurt-005-cd7c076c4ee341bf948caa3d0d740146b1663f73-s41.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
A company called "Powerful Yogurt" has shipped a line of "brogurt" -- single-serving bacteria cultures that are meant to appeal to manly men who are put off by the femininity of traditional yogurt packaging. Comedian Jessi Klein said of the product on an episode of NPR's <em>Wait, Wait... Don't Tell Me</em>, "If male yogurt marketing is anywhere near as annoying as female yogurt marketing, you are in for a treat. Every female yogurt commercial is basically like women in a wedding dress just petting a kitten and eating yogurt."
<p>
Now NPR has a full review:


<blockquote>
<p>


Peter: I liked the fact there was no lid. You had to smash it on your forehead to get to it.
<p>
Ian: I guess this is pretty manly, but not as manly as that Dannon flavor you have to hunt and kill with your bare hands.
<p>
Mike: This is good. Like, this is "morning after a night in a Tijuana brothel and I still have both my kidneys" good.
<p>
Brogurt doesn't taste so different than regular yogurt. We were sort of hoping for manly flavors, like "Truck" or "Mixed Berry Martial Arts."
<p>
Miles: I could really go for some "Essence of Burt Reynolds."
<p>
Mike: I like that yogurt flavor titles do not appear on bill.



</blockquote>

<p>
<a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thesalt/2013/03/17/174411023/yogurt-for-men-a-review?sc=tw&#038;cc=share">Yogurt For Men: A Review</a> [Ian Chillag/NPR]

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/3TPlcWKO1FQ" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>A company called "Powerful Yogurt" has shipped a line of "brogurt" -- single-serving bacteria cultures that are meant to appeal to manly men who are put off by the femininity of traditional yogurt packaging. Comedian Jessi Klein said of the product on an episode of NPR's Wait, Wait... Don't Tell Me, "If male yogurt marketing [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/yogurt-for-manly-men.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/yogurt-for-manly-men.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>The journal of horrifying science</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/CQN08OedVtk/the-journal-of-horrifying-scie.html</link><category>Short</category><category>bad ideas</category><category>History</category><category>scary</category><category>Science</category><category>tumblr</category><category>Weird</category><category>ZOMGWEREALLGONNADIERUNHIDE</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maggie Koerth-Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 11:28:52 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219507</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<a href="http://sciencehorrors.tumblr.com/">Science Horrors</a> is a tumblr blog that compiles stories about the discomfiting, disturbing, and just plain terrifying parts of science. From 13th-century bioterrorism to the killer carbon dioxide gas bubbles of central Africa, there's plenty here to amaze you and freak you the frack out. <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/CQN08OedVtk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Science Horrors is a tumblr blog that compiles stories about the discomfiting, disturbing, and just plain terrifying parts of science. From 13th-century bioterrorism to the killer carbon dioxide gas bubbles of central Africa, there's plenty here to amaze you and freak you the frack out.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/the-journal-of-horrifying-scie.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/the-journal-of-horrifying-scie.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Electronic cotton and stretchable silicon</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/WCuMu3PQrjY/electronic-cotton-and-stretcha.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Gadgets</category><category>wearables</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Pescovitz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 11:18:44 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219503</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<img style="display:block; margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;" src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NewImage65.png" alt="NewImage" title="NewImage.png" border="0" width="600" height="332" class="alignnone"/>
<P>

Over at our sponsor Intel's <a href="http://mylifescoop.com/2013/03/18/smartly-dressed-the-future-of-wearable-computing">My Life Scoop</a> site, I wrote about the future of wearable computing:
<blockquote>
<strong>Electronic Cotton</strong><br />
Several university laboratories are developing transistors — the building blocks of all computers — that are literally woven from cotton fibers. In a recent project led by Cornell University’s Textiles Nanotechnology Laboratory, engineers coated cotton with gold nano particles and a conductive polymer layer. So far, they’ve only created simple circuits as a proof of concept. The first applications will likely be, say, clothing with chemical sensors for firefighters or shirts that measure vital signs. But according to Lab director Juan Hinestroza, “If you think about how many fibers you have in your T-shirt, and how many interconnections you have between the weft and the warp of the fabric, you could get pretty decent computing power.”
<p>

<strong>Stretchable Silicon</strong><br />
University of Illinois nano scientist John Rogers developed a method to print ultra-thin silicon circuits, like those on a computer chip, onto a highly-elastic surface that you can stick on your skin. Think of a temporary tattoo containing electronic components that are one-fifth the thickness of human hair. The possible uses of this are broad, ranging from a tiny patch that will detect when you need more sunscreen and alert you, to implantable (yes implantable) sensors that keep a constant vigil for infections inside the body. Rogers spun out a company called MC10 to commercialize the technology and has already partnered with Reebok on a forthcoming wearable device to track athletic performance.</blockquote>

"<a href="http://mylifescoop.com/2013/03/18/smartly-dressed-the-future-of-wearable-computing/">Smartly Dressed: The Future of Wearable Computing</a>"<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/WCuMu3PQrjY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Over at our sponsor Intel's My Life Scoop site, I wrote about the future of wearable computing: Electronic Cotton Several university laboratories are developing transistors — the building blocks of all computers — that are literally woven from cotton fibers. In a recent project led by Cornell University’s Textiles Nanotechnology Laboratory, engineers coated cotton with [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/electronic-cotton-and-stretcha.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/electronic-cotton-and-stretcha.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>The Exploratorium's Sound Uncovered: A science museum in your hand (for free)</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/Z_y1d6eu6ao/the-exploratoriums-sound.html</link><category>Review</category><category>apps</category><category>brain</category><category>education</category><category>Exploratorium</category><category>Games</category><category>illusions</category><category>neuroscience</category><category>Science</category><category>senses</category><category>sound</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maggie Koerth-Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 11:15:33 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219492</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/6a0162fff12125970d017ee95cf41c970d-800wi.png"><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/6a0162fff12125970d017ee95cf41c970d-800wi.png" alt="" title="6a0162fff12125970d017ee95cf41c970d-800wi" width="318" height="352" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-219498" /></a></p>

<p><em>This review also appears on <a href="http://www.downloadtheuniverse.com/">Download the Universe</a>, a group blog reviewing the best (and worst, and just "meh") in science-related ebooks and apps.</em></p>

<p>When I go to science museums, I like to press the buttons. I'm convinced this is a special joy that you just do not grow out of. Hit the button. See something cool happen. Feel the little reward centers of your brain dance the watusi. </p>

<p>But, as a curmudgeonly grown-up, I also often feel like there is something missing from this experience. There have definitely been times when I've had my button-pushing fun and gotten a few yards away from the exhibit before I've had to stop and think, "Wait, did I just learn anything?"</p>

<p>Science museums are chaotic. They're loud. They're usually full of small children. Your brain is pulled in multiple directions by sights, sounds, and the knowledge that there are about 15 people behind you, all waiting for their turn to press the button, too. <a href="http://boingboing.net/2011/09/23/science-museums-are-failing-grown-ups.html">In fact, research has shown that adults often avoid science museums (and assume those places aren't "for them") precisely because of those factors</a>. 

<em>Sound Uncovered</em> is an interactive ebook published by The Exploratorium, the granddaddy of modern science museums. Really more of an app, it's a series of 12 modules that allow you to play with auditory illusions and unfamiliar sounds as you learn about how the human brain interprets what it hears, and how those ear-brain interactions are used for everything from selling cars to making music. </p>

<span id="more-219492"></span>

<p>It's part of a series that also includes <em>Color Uncovered</em>. The app is basically a portable Exploratorium. It would be very simple to convert everything in here (from games to text) into a meatspace exhibit. And that's a good thing. There are some big benefits to having access to your own, private museum.
<br /> A) You get to press the buttons as many times as you want. 
<br /> B) You actually have the time and the headspace necessary to explore the text and learn the things the button-pressing is supposed to teach you.</br> </p>

<p>For instance, one module features a psuedo vintage tape deck that allows you to record yourself speaking, and then play the recording both normally, and in reverse. You're particularly encouraged to try recording palindromes—words and phrases that are spelled the same backwards and forwards. You might think that palindromes would also sound the same backwards and forwards, but you'd be wrong. The phrase "too bad I hid a boot", for instance, sounds more like garbled Japanese when it's played backwards. </p>

<p>Having this all to yourself on an iPad means that you can spend a lot of time being silly (examples of recordings made by this reviewer include palindromes in different accents, "Hail Satan", and multiple swear words) while easily jumping back and forth between the interactive diversion and the explanations of how it works and how it fits into modern society. I can even imagine kids playing with the toy part of this for a while before finally stumbling upon the embedded text and having their games suddenly illuminated with meaning. That's pretty cool. In a museum setting, I've watched plenty of kids muck around with the button pressing and then run off before they ever have a chance to learn that phonemes are distinct units of sound or that backward speech doesn't just reverse the order of the phonemes, but reverses the phonemes themselves. Sound doesn't have palindromes. </p>

<p>The other benefit here is that Sound Uncovered eliminates the need for the role of Boring Adult — the person charged with the futile task of reading the explanatory text out loud to a gaggle of button-pressing children who really do not care about that right now. In doing so, it frees adults to actually have fun and learn something, too. If you don't have to be the education enforcer, and can trust that your kids will discover the explanations as they play with the app over time, then you're able to actually engage in play yourself —both with your kids and without them. The portable museum is a place for kids, and it's a place for adults, too. </p>

<p>That said, I think an adult on their own would probably burn through this pretty quickly. I got most of what I'm going to get out of it on a three-hour plane flight. But it's also free, so it's not like you're out a lot of money for a small amount of information. In general, I'd say Sound Uncovered is a good example of how the digital format can be used to improve science communication in ways that aren't easily possible in the real world.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.exploratorium.edu/explore/apps/sound-uncovered">Sound Uncovered</a> and <a href="http://www.exploratorium.edu/explore/apps">Color Uncovered</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/Z_y1d6eu6ao" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>This review also appears on Download the Universe, a group blog reviewing the best (and worst, and just "meh") in science-related ebooks and apps. When I go to science museums, I like to press the buttons. I'm convinced this is a special joy that you just do not grow out of. Hit the button. See [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/the-exploratoriums-sound.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/the-exploratoriums-sound.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Brainless bots exhibit swarming</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/VM61S4Y5IW0/brainless-bots-exhibit-swarmin.html</link><category>Video</category><category>robots</category><category>swarms</category><category>systems thinking</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Pescovitz</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 11:12:54 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219493</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--www.youtube.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/0uqsRGFLM20?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>
Harvard University researchers show how simple, brainless "bristle-bots" (like those you can <a href="http://blog.makezine.com/2007/12/19/how-to-make-a-bristlebot/">make yourself</a> or purchase for $6 as a "<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002R7IK74/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&#038;camp=1789&#038;creative=390957&#038;creativeASIN=B002R7IK74&#038;linkCode=as2&#038;tag=boingboing0e-20">Hexbug Nano</a>") exhibit swarming behavior when contained in a small area. According to the scientists, when this kind of behavior is seen in the natural world, among termites for example, it's "linked with insect cognition and social interactions. Our study shows how the behavioral repertoire of these physically interacting automatons controlled by one parameter translates into the mechanical intelligence of swarms." "<a href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1302.5952v1.pdf">Swarming, swirling and stasis in sequestered bristle-bots</a>" <em>(PDF)</em><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/VM61S4Y5IW0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Harvard University researchers show how simple, brainless "bristle-bots" exhibit swarming behavior when contained in a small area.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/brainless-bots-exhibit-swarmin.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/brainless-bots-exhibit-swarmin.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>The sky was the color of a birthday cake tuned to a dead channel</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/SoI-yBlvQk8/the-sky-was-the-color-of-a-bir.html</link><category>Post</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>science fiction</category><category>short</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 11:12:36 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219415</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
Hey, yesterday was <a href="http://dangerousdays.tumblr.com/post/45619440258/happy-birthday-to-william-gibson-images-courtesy">William Gibson's birthday</a>. Happy birthday, Bill! Here's some <a href="http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=jmeMsVRO-goC&#038;pg=PT87&#038;lpg=PT87&#038;dq=You+can%27t+let+the+little+pricks+generation+gap+you+neuromancer&#038;source=bl&#038;ots=KPhhLWLPyQ&#038;sig=wB-lJuWvyelKjm68VsTldu20KUg&#038;hl=en&#038;sa=X&#038;ei=byBHUZugEeaN0AXpwoGQBA&#038;redir_esc=y">sage advice</a> I always try to keep in mind on my own birthdays.

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/SoI-yBlvQk8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Hey, yesterday was William Gibson's birthday. Happy birthday, Bill! Here's some sage advice I always try to keep in mind on my own birthdays.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/the-sky-was-the-color-of-a-bir.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/the-sky-was-the-color-of-a-bir.html</feedburner:origLink></item></channel></rss>
