<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.boingboing.net/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0"><channel><title>Boing Boing</title><link>http://boingboing.net</link><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.boingboing.net/boingboing/iBag" /><description>Brain candy for Happy Mutants</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 07:58:05 PDT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.1</generator><sy:updatePeriod xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/">hourly</sy:updatePeriod><sy:updateFrequency xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/">1</sy:updateFrequency><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.boingboing.net/boingboing/iBag" /><feedburner:info uri="boingboing/ibag" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><image><link>http://boingboing.net</link><url>http://boingboing.net/icons/bb144.jpg</url><title>Boing Boing</title></image><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item><title>UK press-regulation defines "press" so broadly as to include tweeters, Facebook users, bloggers</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/9RUnY4gYOx0/uk-press-regulation-defines.html</link><category>Post</category><category>law</category><category>newspapers</category><category>press</category><category>regulation</category><category>uk</category><category>web theory</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 07:58:05 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219398</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-18-at-09.11.02.png1.gif" class="bordered"><br />
UK regulations may soon regulate all tweeters, bloggers, and other people who post on the Internet as part of a new system of press regulation.
<p>
Today in London, Parliament is the in throes of a closed-door horse-trading exercise over "Leveson" -- that is, the Leveson Inquiry in to the bad behavior of the British press, whose tabloids got caught illegally spying on people (from MPs and Lords down to grieving parents of murdered children), bribing cops high and low, and otherwise engaging in shenanigans that were pretty awful. Strangely, although all of these things were <em>already</em> illegal (but were not vigorously investigated by cops and politicos who were beholden to the press for lucrative "columns," gifts, and favourable coverage), the English political establishment has decided that the real problem is that the press isn't regulated enough.
<p>
The Tories want the press regulated without a specific law -- they favour an obscure instrument called a Royal Charter. Labour and the LibDems want a press-regulating law. All of the coverage of this issue today is about the difference between these two options. What neither of them are talking about is Schedule 4, which establishes that the new rules will cover "a website containing news-related material (whether or not related to a newspaper or magazine)" where publication "takes place in the United Kingdom" and relates to "news or information about public affairs" or "opinion about matters relating to the news or current affairs."
<p>

In a nutshell, then: if you press a button labelled "publish" or "submit" or "tweet" while in the UK, these rules as written will treat you as a newspaper proprietor, and make you vulnerable to an arbitration procedure where the complainer pays nothing, but you have to pay to defend yourself, and that will potentially have the power to fine you, force you to censor your posts, and force you to print "corrections" and "apologies" in a manner that the regulator will get to specify.
<p>
As Alec Muffett writes, "anyone who says 'Yes, but this is all about 'smoke filled rooms' and controlling Murdoch, they’d never do it to bloggers' has no memory of any previous overreach of powers by the state, police or other regulators."
<p>

<a href="http://dropsafe.crypticide.com/article/11188">UK Bloggers &#038; Tweeters: Be aware that the Royal Charter re: #Leveson is also aimed at regulating *you*</a>

(<i>Thanks, <a href="http://www.snowmanonfire.com/">Hal</a>!</i>)<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/9RUnY4gYOx0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>UK regulations may soon regulate all tweeters, bloggers, and other people who post on the Internet as part of a new system of press regulation. Today in London, Parliament is the in throes of a closed-door horse-trading exercise over "Leveson" -- that is, the Leveson Inquiry in to the bad behavior of the British press, [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/uk-press-regulation-defines.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/uk-press-regulation-defines.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>What is good and important about steampunk</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/RhVbFciYIwo/what-is-good-and-important-abo.html</link><category>Post</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>Steampunk</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 06:46:19 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219371</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<p>
Nick Harkaway's essay "The Steampunk Movement is Good and Important" does a good job of answering charges that steampunk is cover for racism or colonialism, and does an even better job of explaining the attraction of steampunk technological visions to a modern artist:

<blockquote>
<p>
Just as it would be tragic to ignore the advantages and consolations of the cognitive - and those who denigrate it in favour of a romanticised understanding of the instinctual or the mystical slander themselves - so equally it is idle and spurious to contend that we are cognitive entities riding around in bony control centres in our skulls, peeping out through windows in the face. We are not just brains with mobile life support. The emerging understanding of embodied cognition is the last nail in the coffin of that idea. We are bodies which think, and we’re at home with Steampunk because it is an ethos of design and creativity which acknowledges the humanly physical, that which we can understand with our fingers. It values our bounded selves, whose world is the middle earth between the flea and the horizon line in which objects obey Newton and relativity is barely more than an academic interest. It is a cognitively limited and incomplete sort of place. In terms of our senses, though, it’s all there is, and Steampunk is about being able to have the wonders of technology while still valuing, acknowledging and respecting that restricted view.
<p>
From that one central aspect of its identity, Steampunk mounts a challenge to grey-black plastic industrial design, to the faux-sanitised world of consumer technology and to techno-/neo-colonialism. It insistently re-makes technology as something friendly and even quasi-biological by producing things that owe more to Rube Goldberg than to the Filippo Marinetti-style “faster, harder” culture of Sony and Microsoft or the endless iterations of Apple and Samsung. The ethos admits of failure: Steampunk devices almost are not working properly if they don’t have leaks, if they don’t require maintenance and the occasional thump. That’s where they get character and animation, identities of their own which reflect their owners, while every iPhone can be seen as Apple’s endlessly replicated identity given passage into your every waking moment, a tiny and instantly replaceable cloned shopfront: what role is conferred or imposed by such a device on the person carrying it? It’s not that Jonathan Ive’s designs are poor, it’s that they are profoundly truthful: an iPhone is a vector, not an object, valued by its creator for its purpose and interchangeability, not individuality. Steampunk, on the other hand, repurposes, scavenges, remakes and embellishes in an arena where embellishment is seen as decadence, never mind the inherent decadence of creating the sheer amount of computing power our society now possesses in order that most of it should sit idle or be used for email and occasional games of Plants vs Zombies. Steampunk appeals to the idea of uniqueness, to the one-off item, while every mainstream consumer technology of recent years is about putting human beings into ever more granular, packageable and mass-produced identities so that they can be sold or sold to, perfectly mapped and understood.
</blockquote>

<p>
<a href="http://harkaway.tumblr.com/post/45604944287/the-steampunk-movement-is-good-and-important">The Steampunk Movement is Good and Important</a>

(<i>via <a href="http://kadrey.tumblr.com/">Kadrey</a>!</i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/RhVbFciYIwo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Nick Harkaway's essay "The Steampunk Movement is Good and Important" does a good job of answering charges that steampunk is cover for racism or colonialism, and does an even better job of explaining the attraction of steampunk technological visions to a modern artist: Just as it would be tragic to ignore the advantages and consolations [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/what-is-good-and-important-abo.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/what-is-good-and-important-abo.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Hans Blix on why invading Iraq was "a terrible mistake"</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/2v5IC1DuXjA/hans-blix-on-why-invading-iraq.html</link><category>Short</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 06:35:11 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219396</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[In <a href='http://edition.cnn.com/2013/03/18/opinion/iraq-war-hans-blix/index.html?hpt=hp_c1'>an op-ed for CNN.com</a>, Hans Blix writes: "I headed the U.N. inspections in Iraq at the time of the war 10 years ago. Today, I look again at the reasons why this terrible mistake -- and violation of the U.N. charter -- took place and explore if any lessons be drawn. Here are my thoughts. [CNN.com]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/2v5IC1DuXjA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>In an op-ed for CNN.com, Hans Blix writes: "I headed the U.N. inspections in Iraq at the time of the war 10 years ago. Today, I look again at the reasons why this terrible mistake -- and violation of the U.N. charter -- took place and explore if any lessons be drawn. Here are my [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/hans-blix-on-why-invading-iraq.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/hans-blix-on-why-invading-iraq.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>"I tried to make the intel behind Iraq War less bogus"</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/FB58TC1EBVg/i-tried-to-make-the-intel-be.html</link><category>Short</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 06:33:32 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219394</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[A CIA counterterrorism analyst, <a href='http://www.wired.com/dangerroom/2013/03/iraq-intelligence/?utm_source=twitterfeed&#038;utm_medium=twitter'>in an essay for Wired's Danger Room</a>: "Ten years ago this week, the U.S. invaded Iraq, citing intelligence that turned out to be bogus. I had to work on some of it — and I also had to work on keeping the really, really terrible versions of it out of our analysis." <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/FB58TC1EBVg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>A CIA counterterrorism analyst, in an essay for Wired's Danger Room: "Ten years ago this week, the U.S. invaded Iraq, citing intelligence that turned out to be bogus. I had to work on some of it — and I also had to work on keeping the really, really terrible versions of it out of our [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/i-tried-to-make-the-intel-be.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/i-tried-to-make-the-intel-be.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Adorable baby komodo dragons born in Indonesia zoo</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/S7iGiLCexjI/adorable-baby-komodo-dragons-b.html</link><category>Short</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 06:32:04 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219392</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[Seven tiny cute little baby komodo dragons have been born in a zoo in Indonesia's East Java Province. You'll want to watch the  <a href='http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-21826763#?utm_source=twitterfeed&#038;utm_medium=twitter'>BBC News video</a>.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/S7iGiLCexjI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Seven tiny cute little baby komodo dragons have been born in a zoo in Indonesia's East Java Province. You'll want to watch the BBC News video.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/adorable-baby-komodo-dragons-b.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/adorable-baby-komodo-dragons-b.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Andrew "Weev" Auernheimer to be sentenced in ATT/iPad case</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/Q28OV1k05-M/andrew-weev-auernheimer-to.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 06:21:17 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219387</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[Tim Pool is <a href="http://new.livestream.com/timcast/AMAWithWeev">webcasting the sentencing hearing</a> this morning for Andrew "<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weev">Weev</a>" Auernheimer, whom a court <a href="http://www.businessweek.com/ap/2013-03-18/man-faces-sentencing-in-ipad-data-breach-case">has convicted</a> of illegally <a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/blog/no-more-lulz-should-weev-the-world-s-most-notorious-troll-go-to-jail-for-hacking">gaining access</a> to AT&#038;T's servers and accessing more than 100,000 email addresses of iPad users. Gawker published redacted versions of the emails. There was <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/1ahkgc/i_am_weev_i_may_be_going_to_prison_under_the/">a Reddit AMA</a> and <a href="http://venturebeat.com/2013/03/17/terrorist-hacker-freedom-fighter-andrew-auernheimer-parties-tonight-in-expectation-of-jail-tomorrow/">a party</a> in his honor last night. The self-proclaimed troll is expected to be incarcerated immediately after the sentencing hearing, despite <a href="http://gizmodo.com/5990462/exclusive-att-hackers-final-argument-against-prison">a last-minute plea to avoid prison</a>.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/Q28OV1k05-M" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Tim Pool is webcasting the sentencing hearing this morning for Andrew "Weev" Auernheimer, whom a court has convicted of illegally gaining access to AT&amp;#038;T's servers and accessing more than 100,000 email addresses of iPad users. Gawker published redacted versions of the emails. There was a Reddit AMA and a party in his honor last night. [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/andrew-weev-auernheimer-to.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/andrew-weev-auernheimer-to.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Control-Alt-Hack: delightful strategy card game about white-hat hacking</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/oPadEMAc_ho/control-alt-hack-delightful-s.html</link><category>Review</category><category>Games</category><category>gift guide</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>infosec</category><category>Reviews</category><category>security</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 06:17:48 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219304</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[


<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/boxcontents.png1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Control-Alt-Hack-White-Hacking-Profit-Card/dp/B008HIX5KO">Control-Alt-Hack</a> is a tremendously fun, hacker-themed strategy card game that uses the mechanic of the classic Steve Jackson <a href="http://www.sjgames.com/ninjaburger/">Ninja Burger</a> game. It comes out of the <a href="http://seclab.cs.washington.edu/">University of Washington Computer Security and Privacy Research Lab</a>, and features extremely entertaining and funny computer-security-themed scenarios, buffs, attacks and characters.
<p>
The gameplay is very well-thought-through  (<a href="http://www.controlalthack.com/downloadrules.php">here's a PDF of the rules</a>). Three of us sat down to play it this weekend with only a cursory glance at the rules beforehand. By following the quickstart instructions, we were able to jump straight into play, and within a few turns, we really had the rhythm and were busily sabotaging one another and cursing at the dice when they rolled against our favor.
<p>
Based on my play session, I'm really impressed. Though one player led the game early on, there were several reversals, wherein the leading and trailing players traded places -- always the mark of a great game. There was a good mix of skill, strategy and luck, and things were just complicated enough that it absorbed our full attention, without lagging or flagging.
<p>
A full game takes about an hour, and between three and six people can play at once. We played it after Sunday brunch and it was a great digestive aid. All three of us loved the geeky, info-sec-y references, the funny scenarios (everything from devising a cryptographic protocol for implanted medical devices to pranking a labmate with a gag WiFi keystroke-inserter), and the grace-notes (like a scenario that is encoded as a cryptogram). There were moments of unlikely hail-mary-heroism, crushing defeat, and lots of laughs. We'll play this one again.
<p>
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Control-Alt-Hack-White-Hacking-Profit-Card/dp/B008HIX5KO">Control-Alt-Hack: White Hat Hacking for Fun and Profit </a>
<p>
<a href="http://www.controlalthack.com/">Control-Alt-Hack</a> [Publisher's site]

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/oPadEMAc_ho" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Control-Alt-Hack is a tremendously fun, hacker-themed strategy card game that uses the mechanic of the classic Steve Jackson Ninja Burger game. It comes out of the University of Washington Computer Security and Privacy Research Lab, and features extremely entertaining and funny computer-security-themed scenarios, buffs, attacks and characters. The gameplay is very well-thought-through (here's a PDF [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/control-alt-hack-delightful-s.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/control-alt-hack-delightful-s.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Six-year-old's first plane ride in open cockpit Piper Cub</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/dK3CY-HsypE/six-year-olds-first-plane-ri.html</link><category>Video</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 06:11:16 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219384</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--youtu.be--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/w8JU-1ZrRAg?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

Lainey, who is 6, rides in a plane for the first time. "A cub in a Cub," says <a href="http://milesobrien.com">Miles</a>. <em>(Thanks, <a href="http://andreajames.com">Andrea James</a>!)</em><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/dK3CY-HsypE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>"A cub in a Cub," says &lt;a href="http://milesobrien.com"&gt;Miles&lt;/a&gt;.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/six-year-olds-first-plane-ri.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/six-year-olds-first-plane-ri.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>"Rainbow Gravity," Ugo Rondinone</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/eRuSaQ7mzgU/rainbow-gravity-ugo-rondi.html</link><category>Video</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 06:03:16 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219379</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--vimeo.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/19781996" width="392" height="700" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

An <a href="http://vimeo.com/19781996">experimental film</a> made in 2011 for LVMH, by Ugo Rondinone and Robin Kob.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/eRuSaQ7mzgU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>An &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/19781996"&gt;experimental film&lt;/a&gt; made in 2011 for LVMH, by Ugo Rondinone and Robin Kob.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/rainbow-gravity-ugo-rondi.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/rainbow-gravity-ugo-rondi.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>BMEzine founder Shannon Larratt dead in apparent suicide</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/sptRXXXDp4I/bmezine-founder-shannon-larrat.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 05:58:18 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219376</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Shannon.jpg" alt="" title="Shannon" width="600" height="420" class="alignright size-full wp-image-219377" />Shannon Larratt,  creator of body modification zine and early online community BMEzine, <a href="http://news.bme.com/2013/03/15/rip-shannon-larratt-1973-2013">has died</a>. The <a href="http://www.zentastic.com/blog/">statement he left behind</a> indicates that he committed suicide, after several years of <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0967586807006625">a rare illness</a> that left him in extreme, constant pain. <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/sptRXXXDp4I" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Shannon Larratt, creator of body modification zine and early online community BMEzine, has died. The statement he left behind indicates that he committed suicide, after several years of a rare illness that left him in extreme, constant pain.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/bmezine-founder-shannon-larrat.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/bmezine-founder-shannon-larrat.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Correcting error-ridden WSJ column praising "aiding the enemy" charge for Manning, Wikileaks</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/hQmAxsm-KRQ/correcting-error-ridden-wsj-co.html</link><category>Short</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 05:44:03 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219374</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[At <a href='https://pressfreedomfoundation.org/blog/2013/03/correcting-error-riddled-wall-street-journal-column-wikileaks-bradley-manning-and-press'>Freedom of the Press Foundation</a>, Trevor Timm factchecks an absurd column by Gordon Crovitz which praised the 'aiding the enemy' charge against Bradley Manning and insisted WikiLeaks be prosecuted under the Espionage Act.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/hQmAxsm-KRQ" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>At Freedom of the Press Foundation, Trevor Timm factchecks an absurd column by Gordon Crovitz which praised the 'aiding the enemy' charge against Bradley Manning and insisted WikiLeaks be prosecuted under the Espionage Act.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/correcting-error-ridden-wsj-co.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/18/correcting-error-ridden-wsj-co.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Muppet Danny Boy, the only St Paddy's celebration you need</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/DJLeD750c3s/muppet-danny-boy-the-only-st.html</link><category>Video</category><category>Funny</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>holidays</category><category>ireland</category><category>muppets</category><category>music</category><category>videos</category><category>youtube</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 18:30:50 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219309</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--www.youtube.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/OCbuRA_D3KU?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>
In what's becoming <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OCbuRA_D3KU">a regular St Paddy's tradition</a> around here, here's the Muppet Danny Boy you know you want to hear but were afraid to ask for.

<p>
<a href="http://boingboing.net/2008/03/17/muppet-danny-boy-per.html">Muppet Danny Boy performed by Beaker, Swedish Chef and Animal</a>





<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/DJLeD750c3s" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>In what's becoming &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OCbuRA_D3KU"&gt;a regular St Paddy's tradition&lt;/a&gt; around here, here's the Muppet Danny Boy you know you want to hear but were afraid to ask for.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/17/muppet-danny-boy-the-only-st.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/17/muppet-danny-boy-the-only-st.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Beautiful, cleverly fastened wooden sculptures from the architect for this year's Burning Man temple</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/M9LGtMbGKwk/beautiful-cleverly-fastened-w.html</link><category>Post</category><category>art</category><category>burning man</category><category>Gadgets</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>makers</category><category>sculptures</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 15:00:16 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219293</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/chairs.jpg"><br />
M. Otis Beard writes, "Gregg Fleishman, the architect whose team was awarded the honorarium grant to build the Temple for Burning Man 2013 today, makes insane sculpture, furniture, toy cars, etc. out of single pieces of flat plywood, with no metal fasteners, joints, nails, or screws. Some of his pieces even incorporate wooden hinges and springs."


<blockquote>
<P>

<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pistil.jpg" class="bordered" align="right">
The 2013 Temple design is highly geometrical, and will be built using Fleishman’s patented connectors at each joint, capitalizing on the intrinsic strength of the arch at every opportunity in an interlocking jigsaw of triangles and pyramids. No nails, screws, or other metal connectors will be used at all. The gross form of the Temple will consist of a large central trussed pyramid, sixty-four feet tall and eighty-seven feet square, with four smaller satellite pyramids measuring twenty feet tall and twenty-nine feet at the base, intricately interlocked and ornamented in Fleishman’s signature style: Archimedes, Pythagoras, and R. Buckminster Fuller holding hands and enjoying some really good acid.
</blockquote>


<p>
<a href="http://burners.me/2013/03/16/temple-builders-revealed/"> Temple Builders Revealed! </a>

(<i>Thanks, <a href="http://www.burners.me/">M. Otis</a>!</i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/M9LGtMbGKwk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>M. Otis Beard writes, "Gregg Fleishman, the architect whose team was awarded the honorarium grant to build the Temple for Burning Man 2013 today, makes insane sculpture, furniture, toy cars, etc. out of single pieces of flat plywood, with no metal fasteners, joints, nails, or screws. Some of his pieces even incorporate wooden hinges and [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/17/beautiful-cleverly-fastened-w.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/17/beautiful-cleverly-fastened-w.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Death Star was an inside job: a Loose Change parody</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/NSYi1uyAmQY/death-star-was-an-inside-job.html</link><category>Video</category><category>conspiracies</category><category>fanac</category><category>Funny</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>star wars</category><category>truthers</category><category>videos</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 11:39:16 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219283</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--www.youtube.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/2dvv-Yib1Xg?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>	`	
Spocko sez, "Brilliant, and well made parody of the 9/11 video '<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loose_Change_%28film_series%29">Loose Change</a>.' 
It points out all the 'coincidences' in the destruction of the Death Star. Was it an inside job?"

<blockquote>
<p>
An examination of some questionable events and circumstances leading up to the destruction of the Death Star, through the eyes of an amateur investigative journalist within the Star Wars galaxy. The focus is mainly on the connections between the people who created and operated the Death Star and those responsible for destroying it. 
</blockquote>

<p>
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2dvv-Yib1Xg&#038;feature=youtu.be">
Luke's Change: an Inside Job
</a>


(<I>Thanks, <a href="http://spockosbrain.com">Spocko</a>!</i>)






<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/NSYi1uyAmQY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Brilliant, and well made parody of the 9/11 video '&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loose_Change_%28film_series%29"&gt;Loose Change&lt;/a&gt;.' 
It points out all the 'coincidences' in the destruction of the Death Star. Was it an inside job?</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/17/death-star-was-an-inside-job.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/17/death-star-was-an-inside-job.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Sheet music for the Mario "coin" sound</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/pczDIUVmDjk/sheet-music-for-the-mario-co.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Copyfight</category><category>fanac</category><category>Games</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>music</category><category>wide</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 09:14:42 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219277</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<P>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Mario-Sheet-Music-Coin-Sound.png1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
From the <a href="http://www.mariopiano.com/">Mario Piano site</a>, where you'll find "authentic, high-fidelity Mario sheet music that was entirely faithful to the original Mario themes and sound effects, and which could be trusted to be 100% accurate," the sheet music for the Mario "coin" sound.

<p>
<a href="http://www.mariopiano.com/mario-sheet-music-coin-sound.html">Mario Piano Sheet Music - Coin Sound</a>
(<i>via <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/">Hacker News</a></i>)

<p>
<b>Derp</b>: <a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/10/09/sheet-music-for-super-mario-br.html">Mark blogged this one back in October</a>!<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/pczDIUVmDjk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>From the Mario Piano site, where you'll find "authentic, high-fidelity Mario sheet music that was entirely faithful to the original Mario themes and sound effects, and which could be trusted to be 100% accurate," the sheet music for the Mario "coin" sound. Mario Piano Sheet Music - Coin Sound (via Hacker News) Derp: Mark blogged [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/17/sheet-music-for-the-mario-co.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/17/sheet-music-for-the-mario-co.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>CPAC racism panel derailed by audience member who suggests slaves should have been grateful for food, shelter &amp; clothing</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/FMt1KB4RsNE/cpac-racism-panel-derailed-by.html</link><category>Video</category><category>christ what an asshole</category><category>cpac</category><category>gop</category><category>race</category><category>videos</category><category>youtube</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 06:08:50 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219272</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--www.youtube.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/EQf9_oflU9s?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>
<a href="http://www.soulhill.com/">Gregory</a> sez, "A conservative group looking to make inroads with African American Voters held a talk on Friday called 'Trump the Race Card'. It devolved into a chaos when Scott Terry of North Carolina suggested Fredrick Douglass should have been grateful for the food and shelter provided by his former slave master."

<blockquote>
<p>


When asked by ThinkProgress if he’d accept a society where African-Americans were permanently subservient to whites, he said “I’d be fine with that.” He also claimed that African-Americans “should be allowed to vote in Africa,” and that “all the Tea Parties” were concerned with the same racial problems that he was.
<p>
At one point, a woman challenged him on the Republican Party’s roots, to which Terry responded, “I didn’t know the legacy of the Republican Party included women correcting men in public.”
<p>
He claimed to be a direct descendent of Confederate President Jefferson Davis.
</blockquote>

<p>
<a href="http://thinkprogress.org/justice/2013/03/15/1729331/cpac-slavery-minority-outreach/?mobile=nc">CPAC Participant Defends Slavery At Minority Outreach Panel: It Gave ‘Food And Shelter’ To Blacks</a>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/FMt1KB4RsNE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>A conservative group looking to make inroads with African American Voters held a talk on Friday called 'Trump the Race Card'.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/17/cpac-racism-panel-derailed-by.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/17/cpac-racism-panel-derailed-by.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Poplocks and Paper Pose-Ables: papercraft joints for pose-able robots</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/cIHaOU-6IpY/poplocks-and-paper-pose-ables.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Gadgets</category><category>gift guide</category><category>Kids</category><category>makers</category><category>papercraft</category><category>parenting</category><category>robots</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 18:30:02 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219254</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/gupp-e_green1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
Poplocks are a very clever system for making movable papercraft fastenings with die-cutting and folding. The Paper Pose-Ables site has a bunch of downloadable papercraft toys you can print out and make, as well as pre-cut/scored kits you can <a href="http://paperposeables.bigcartel.com/">buy</a>, for making fabulous poseable robots and other cool figures.
<p>
The Pose-Ables people came out to one of my signings last month and gave me a couple of GUPP-E robots, which I've put together this week, with help from my five-year-old daughter Poesy. The robots were fun to put together -- just intricate enough to be challenging without being frustrating -- and the Poplocks system really makes for a great, semi-rigid joint for the toys.
<p>
The Poplocks themselves are CC licensed for use in your own models.

<blockquote>
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/poplock_rocks.jpg" class="bordered" align="right".

Using Poplocks is really fun and easy. Take two pieces of paper, each with an equal-size hole. Line up these holes. Fold a poplock in half and insert the two tips into the hole. Allow it to expand and then press down on the middle. You'll feel a "pop" as it deforms into a new shape.
<p>
The Poplock pushes the two pieces of paper tightly together, creating lots of friction! It can also stay put, and won't pop out on it's own, unless a good amount of force is used to bend it out of place.
<p>
Combine the Poplock Wedge with the special Locking Flaps hole, and you will create a nigh-invincible connection. Seriously, you won't be able to get the connection apart with torsion or pulling forces unless you rip or crumple the parts. Even then, the Poplock will probably stay put... holding two mangled pieces of paper together!

</blockquote>

<p>
<a href="http://www.paperposeables.com/p/poplocks.html"> Poplocks </a>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/cIHaOU-6IpY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Poplocks are a very clever system for making movable papercraft fastenings with die-cutting and folding. The Paper Pose-Ables site has a bunch of downloadable papercraft toys you can print out and make, as well as pre-cut/scored kits you can buy, for making fabulous poseable robots and other cool figures. The Pose-Ables people came out to [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/16/poplocks-and-paper-pose-ables.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/16/poplocks-and-paper-pose-ables.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Maria Del Camino: an art-car that's part tank, part El Camino</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/kX07bzP76RA/maria-del-camino-an-art-car-t.html</link><category>Post</category><category>art</category><category>automotive</category><category>burning man</category><category>Gadgets</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>makers</category><category>videos</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 14:48:59 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219251</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<p>
<object id="flashObj" width="480" height="270" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=9,0,47,0"><param name="movie" value="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&#038;isUI=1" /><param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /><param name="flashVars" value="videoId=2198253393001&#038;playerID=1577029897001&#038;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAAF1BIQQ~,g5cZB_aGkYZC26fBYKv5Nsnal0IamyGL&#038;domain=embed&#038;dynamicStreaming=true" /><param name="base" value="http://admin.brightcove.com" /><param name="seamlesstabbing" value="false" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="swLiveConnect" value="true" /><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /><embed src="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&#038;isUI=1" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" flashVars="videoId=2198253393001&#038;playerID=1577029897001&#038;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAAF1BIQQ~,g5cZB_aGkYZC26fBYKv5Nsnal0IamyGL&#038;domain=embed&#038;dynamicStreaming=true" base="http://admin.brightcove.com" name="flashObj" width="480" height="270" seamlesstabbing="false" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowFullScreen="true" allowScriptAccess="always" swLiveConnect="true" pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash"></embed></object>
<p>
Wired Design has a great short video documentary on my friend Bruce Tomb, who has built an amazing art-car called <a href="http://mariadelcamino.brucetomb.com/">Maria Del Camino</a> that's part tank, part 59 El Camino, part flying car. I camp with Bruce and his wife Mary and our friends at Burning Man, along with Maria, at the Liminal Labs camp every summer. Maria is such a wonderful addition to our Burn!

<blockquote>
<p>


The outcome might not be what you’d expect. With the help of some friends, Tomb created “Maria del Camino.” She’s an excavator topped with a 1959 El Camino, mounted on a hydraulic array that lifts it high off the ground. Her body is adorned with thousands of drilled-out holes, and her hood sports a portrait of the robot woman from Fritz Lang’s Metropolis, which shines when the light hits it. In simple terms, it’s nothing but sheer magnificence.
<p>
Maria is currently being worked on at the DIY space Nimby in Oakland California. We stopped by to ask Tomb how — and why — he built his “flying” car, and he took us for a beer run, stopping traffic along the way.
<p>
As for future modifications, Tomb has a big one in mind. “Been working on removing the manual controls,” he says. “I’ve heard driverless cars are all the rage!”
</blockquote>

<p>
<a href="http://www.wired.com/design/2013/03/maria-the-flying-car">This Homemade ‘Flying Car’ Can’t Exactly Fly, But It Still Turns Heads</a> [Annaliza Savage/Wired]

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/kX07bzP76RA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Wired Design has a great short video documentary on my friend Bruce Tomb, who has built an amazing art-car called Maria Del Camino that's part tank, part 59 El Camino, part flying car. I camp with Bruce and his wife Mary and our friends at Burning Man, along with Maria, at the Liminal Labs camp [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/16/maria-del-camino-an-art-car-t.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/16/maria-del-camino-an-art-car-t.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Boing Boing reader discovers internet vulnerability</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/-ZGaPucuFV4/boing-boing-reader-discovers-i.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 14:42:03 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219266</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NewImage57.jpg"  class="alignnone">Please do not reboot. Internet will be deleted. <em>(Via <a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/114726437548864340539/posts?cfem=1">Andrew Roach</a> BB G+)</em></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/-ZGaPucuFV4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Please do not reboot. Internet will be deleted. (Via Andrew Roach BB G+)</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/16/boing-boing-reader-discovers-i.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/16/boing-boing-reader-discovers-i.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>EFF explains yesterday's National Security Letter ruling</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/xoWKZu0tpco/eff-explains-yesterdays-nati.html</link><category>Post</category><category>authoritarianism</category><category>fbi</category><category>law</category><category>privacy</category><category>surveillance</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 11:42:48 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219246</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/nsl_team.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
Further to <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/national-security-letters-unco.html">Xeni's post from yesterday</a> about the landmark ruling by a San Francisco district court judge that the FBI may not issue "national security letters" (NSLs), the Electronic Frontier Foundation, who fought the case, has posted a good explanation about what NSLs are and why they were so creepy:

<blockquote>
<p>


The controversial NSL provisions EFF challenged on behalf of the unnamed client allow the FBI to issue administrative letters -- on its own authority and without court approval -- to telecommunications companies demanding information about their customers. The controversial provisions also permit the FBI to permanently gag service providers from revealing anything about the NSLs, including the fact that a demand was made, which prevents providers from notifying either their customers or the public. The limited judicial review provisions essentially write the courts out of the process.
<p>
In today's ruling, the court held that the gag order provisions of the statute violate the First Amendment and that the review procedures violate separation of powers. Because those provisions were not separable from the rest of the statute, the court declared the entire statute unconstitutional. In addressing the concerns of the service provider, the court noted: "Petitioner was adamant about its desire to speak publicly about the fact that it received the NSL at issue to further inform the ongoing public debate."
<p>
"The First Amendment prevents the government from silencing people and stopping them from criticizing its use of executive surveillance power," said EFF Legal Director Cindy Cohn. "The NSL statute has long been a concern of many Americans, and this small step should help restore balance between liberty and security."
</blockquote>
<p>
I am so proud of my friends at EFF this morning. Go team!

<P>
<a href="https://www.eff.org/press/releases/national-security-letters-are-unconstitutional-federal-judge-rules">National Security Letters Are Unconstitutional, Federal Judge Rules</a>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/xoWKZu0tpco" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Further to Xeni's post from yesterday about the landmark ruling by a San Francisco district court judge that the FBI may not issue "national security letters" (NSLs), the Electronic Frontier Foundation, who fought the case, has posted a good explanation about what NSLs are and why they were so creepy: The controversial NSL provisions EFF [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/16/eff-explains-yesterdays-nati.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/16/eff-explains-yesterdays-nati.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>How Chinese secret police talk about their jobs when they think the camera isn't rolling</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/yFoI2akKX_Q/how-chinese-secret-police-talk.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Video</category><category>authoritarianism</category><category>china</category><category>videos</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 08:38:56 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219242</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--www.youtube.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/tIRbTD5fhnw?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<P>
When a Sky News reporter broadcasting live from Tiananmen Square mentioned the 1989 protests, Chinese <s>secret</s> police swooped down on his and hustled him and his cameraman into the back of a van, and kidnapped them to a distant park where they were polite but Orwellian in their explanation for their deeds (they didn't realize he was still broadcasting, and thought it was all going to disc or tape whence it could be scrubbed):



<blockquote>
<P>


At this point, the police do something Orwellian in its brilliance. An officer who speaks English informs Stone that they have to stop filming because they don’t have official permission. Stone disagrees, saying that they sought and received permission to film in Tiananmen Square. But the officer counters that they’re not in Tiananmen anymore. They’re in a park where the police have brought Stone against his will, and he doesn’t have permission to record in that park, so regrettably the police have no choice but to insist the camera be switched off. Who could have possibly foreseen that little complication?
<p>
The officer then takes the Orwellianism to the next level by explaining that Stone and his team are neither being detained nor are they free to go. They can do whatever they like, except that they must go sit in an empty classroom and wait for some unnamed officials to show up.
</blockquote>
<p>
This reminds me of nothing so much as the <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/06/politely-refusing-to-talk-to-d.html">DHS checkpoint officials</a> who won't tell you if you're being detained, won't tell you if you're legally required to answer their questions about your citizenship, but also won't let you go.

<p>
<a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/worldviews/wp/2013/03/15/video-chinese-police-detain-british-reporter-unaware-hes-broadcasting-live-throughout/?Post+generic=%3Ftid%3Dsm_twitter_washingtonpost">Video: Chinese police detain British reporter, unaware he’s broadcasting live throughout</a> [Max Fisher/Washington Post]

<p>
(<i>via <a href="http://reddit.com">Reddit</a></i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/yFoI2akKX_Q" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>This reminds me of &lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/06/politely-refusing-to-talk-to-d.html"&gt;DHS checkpoint officials&lt;/a&gt; who won't tell you if you're being detained or if you're legally required to answer questions, but won't let you go.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/16/how-chinese-secret-police-talk.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/16/how-chinese-secret-police-talk.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Glitched out blankets and tapestries</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/levt0mumipw/glitched-out-blankets-and-tape.html</link><category>Post</category><category>art</category><category>gift guide</category><category>glitch</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>housewares</category><category>new aesthetic</category><category>wide</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 06:20:57 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219196</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<P>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/img_3337_small12.jpg" class="bordered"><br />

<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/img_9888_glitchtapestries1.jpg" class="bordered" align="right">
Phillip Stearns is an artist who commissions blankets and tapestries woven in the USA with glitch-art patterns he generates with broken digital cameras. They're for sale! $200+
<p>
<a href="http://phillipstearns.wordpress.com/jacquard-woven-glitch-tapestries/">Tapestries</a>
<p>
<a href="http://phillipstearns.wordpress.com/machine-knit-glitch-blankets/">Blankets</a>
<p>
(<i>via <a href="http://kottke.org">Kottke</a></i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/levt0mumipw" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Phillip Stearns is an artist who commissions blankets and tapestries woven in the USA with glitch-art patterns he generates with broken digital cameras. They're for sale! $200+ Tapestries Blankets (via Kottke)</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/16/glitched-out-blankets-and-tape.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/16/glitched-out-blankets-and-tape.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Tanker-truck full of inedible pig blood</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/yLomQdC0nso/tanker-truck-full-of-inedible.html</link><category>Post</category><category>gross</category><category>not food</category><category>photos</category><category>Weird</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 19:44:17 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=218984</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pork-blood-tanker-truck1.jpg" class="bordered">
Welp, there's something you don't see every day. Unless you work at an abattoir.

<p>
<a href="http://www.joeydevilla.com/2013/03/14/im-goin-to-prom/">“I’m Goin’ to Prom!”</a>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/yLomQdC0nso" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Welp, there's something you don't see every day. Unless you work at an abattoir. “I’m Goin’ to Prom!”</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/tanker-truck-full-of-inedible.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/tanker-truck-full-of-inedible.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Grotesque portraits from Christian Rex van Minnen</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/LDv8aMmKwxY/grotesque-portraits-from-chris.html</link><category>Post</category><category>art</category><category>denver</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>science fiction</category><category>Weird</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 17:43:54 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=218975</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[



<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/VAN_MINNEN_Christian_ALWAYS_2011_Oil_Panel_24_x_18in1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/VAN_MINNEN_Christian_CONTACT_2011_Oil_Canvas_20_x_16in1.jpg" class="bordered" align="right">
Christian Rex van Minnen's grotesque portraits are spectacular. IO9's Lauren Davis <a href="http://io9.com/grotesque-portraits-of-aristocrats-from-another-dimensi-453767313">called them</a> "portraits of aristocrats from another dimension." I love the crammed-together, rammed-together higgeldy piggeldy of insectoid body parts, high fashion, and toons. He's got a <a href="http://hifructose.com/2013/03/13/preview-christian-rex-van-minnens-welsh-rats-at-robischon-gallery/">show on</a> at Denver's Robischon Gallery.

<p>
<a href="http://www.christianvanminnen.com/2012-2011">2012-2011 - Christian Rex van Minnen</a>

(<i>via <a href="http://io9.com/">IO9</a></i>)


<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/LDv8aMmKwxY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Christian Rex van Minnen's grotesque portraits are spectacular. IO9's Lauren Davis called them "portraits of aristocrats from another dimension." I love the crammed-together, rammed-together higgeldy piggeldy of insectoid body parts, high fashion, and toons. He's got a show on at Denver's Robischon Gallery. 2012-2011 - Christian Rex van Minnen (via IO9)</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/grotesque-portraits-from-chris.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/grotesque-portraits-from-chris.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Ethan Zuckerman on civic engagement</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/AXndTBukmoA/ethan.html</link><category>Video</category><category>activism</category><category>civics</category><category>youth</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Elisabeth Soep</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 16:08:50 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219102</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--www.youtube.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/-EeMnqU6Kh8?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>
It’s easy to find alarming evidence that we’ve lost our way when it comes to civics in the US. But longtime global activist and MIT prof Ethan Zuckerman says there’s a lot to get excited about too, if we’re willing to think in new ways about what it even means to be civically engaged in the digital age.

<p>
Ethan’s working with a group of scholars and practitioners (I’m one of them) to track how young people are expressing voice and exerting agency in public spheres through participatory politics. Registering to vote or campaigning for a candidate are obvious and important political moves. But so is appropriating <a href="https://twitter.com/OccupySandy">Occupy for hurricane relief</a>, mobilizing Hunger Games fans to <a href="http://www.atreein504.blogspot.com">organize for real-life civil rights,</a> or producing a libertarian music video <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=psosLpDALuA">professing a crush</a> on the economist Friedrich Hayek, (thanks Liana Gamber Thompson).
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/dml-civics.022.jpg" alt="Dml civics 022" title="dml civics.022.jpg" border="0" width="300" height="168" class="alignright" />
<p>
But here’s the rub. If we’re willing to take this expansive view of civics, how do we start to make sense of what any given activity really achieves in the world? When does “voice” make a difference? That’s the question Ethan took on this week in his keynote, How Do We Teach Digital Civics? at the <a href="http://dml2013.dmlhub.net">Digital Media and Learning</a> conference in Chicago. He offered this diagram as a way to map actions into one of four quadrants. 
<p>
Want to figure out where your own civic moves fit in the mix? You can watch <a href="http://dml2013.dmlhub.net/content/videos-day-1-keynote-ignite-talks">Ethan’s whole talk here</a>. It’s an attempt to envision an approach to civics that engages young people’s imaginations and networks rather than telling them what to do. <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/AXndTBukmoA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Tracking how young people are expressing voice and exerting agency in public spheres through participatory politics.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/ethan.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/ethan.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>English town council wants to abolish apostrophes in street-names to end "confusion"</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/OjcsP7zGRIQ/english-town-council-wants-to.html</link><category>Post</category><category>language</category><category>orthography</category><category>politics</category><category>uk</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 15:24:43 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219090</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<p>
The Conservative council in Mid-Devon, England has mooted a proposal to remove apostrophes from street signs, claiming they cause "potential confusion." I live on a street in East London with an on-again/off-again apostrophe whose presence depends on which database you're using. But given that all serious UK navigation and geocoding is done by postcode, this just seems like a bit of silliness.

<blockquote>
<p>
The council communications manager Andrew Lacey said: "Our proposed policy on street naming and numbering covers a whole host of practical issues, many of which are aimed at reducing potential confusion over street names.
<p>
"Although there is no national guidance that stops apostrophes being used, for many years the convention we have followed here is for new street names not to be given apostrophes.
<p>
"In fact, there are currently only three official street names in Mid Devon which include them: Beck's Square and Blundell's Avenue, both in Tiverton, and St George's Well in Cullompton – all named many, many years ago. No final decision has yet been made and the proposed policy will be discussed at cabinet."
</blockquote>
<p>
The science fiction legend Damon Knight used to semi-seriously advocate for the abolition of the apostrophe altogether. I remember thinking he had a point at the time.

<P>
<a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/15/council-ban-apostrophes-street-signs">Council considers ban on apostrophes in street signs</a> [Press Association]

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/OjcsP7zGRIQ" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>The Conservative council in Mid-Devon, England has mooted a proposal to remove apostrophes from street signs, claiming they cause "potential confusion." I live on a street in East London with an on-again/off-again apostrophe whose presence depends on which database you're using. But given that all serious UK navigation and geocoding is done by postcode, this [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/english-town-council-wants-to.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/english-town-council-wants-to.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Loose Ends: "Hangin' on a String (Contemplating)" (1985)</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/c5OhGy-ncsY/loose-ends-hangin-on-a-st.html</link><category>Video</category><category>music</category><category>soul</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">David Pescovitz</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 14:46:23 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219224</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--www.youtube.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Adn6klYsHB0?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NewImage56.png" alt="NewImage" title="NewImage.png" border="0" width="300" height="296" class="alignright" />
From Loose Ends' 1985 LP <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000002PAF/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&#038;camp=1789&#038;creative=390957&#038;creativeASIN=B000002PAF&#038;linkCode=as2&#038;tag=boingboing0e-20">A Little Spice</a>, "Hangin' on a String (Contemplating)" was the first track by a British band to ever hit #1 on the US Billboard R&#038;B Chart. And it's the perfect quiet storm for this Friday evening.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/c5OhGy-ncsY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>From Loose Ends' 1985 LP &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000002PAF/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;#038;camp=1789&amp;#038;creative=390957&amp;#038;creativeASIN=B000002PAF&amp;#038;linkCode=as2&amp;#038;tag=boingboing0e-20"&gt;A Little Spice&lt;/a&gt;, "Hangin' on a String (Contemplating)" was the first track by a British band to ever hit #1 on the US Billboard R&amp;#038;B Chart.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/loose-ends-hangin-on-a-st.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/loose-ends-hangin-on-a-st.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>National Security Letters Unconstitutional, finds federal judge, who bans them</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/9POrpMZMSLg/national-security-letters-unco.html</link><category>Short</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 13:35:34 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219216</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA["Ultra-secret national security letters that come with a gag order on the recipient are an unconstitutional impingement on free speech, a federal judge ruled Friday."  <a href='http://www.wired.com/threatlevel/2013/03/nsl-found-unconstitutional/?cid=co6425864'>Kim Zetter at Wired News has more on the order from U.S. District Judge Susan Illston</a>, who today ordered the government to stop issuing so-called NSLs. [Wired News]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/9POrpMZMSLg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>"Ultra-secret national security letters that come with a gag order on the recipient are an unconstitutional impingement on free speech, a federal judge ruled Friday." Kim Zetter at Wired News has more on the order from U.S. District Judge Susan Illston, who today ordered the government to stop issuing so-called NSLs. [Wired News]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/national-security-letters-unco.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/national-security-letters-unco.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Drew Friedman on The Caricature Art of Robert Grossman</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/wscZndbn0HY/drew-friedman-on-the-caricatur.html</link><category>Post</category><category>art &amp; design</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 13:35:05 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=219218</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Nixon-lamp-big-1.jpg"  class="alignnone">
Artist Drew Friedman has assembled a nice gallery of airbrush illustrator extraordinaire Robert Grossman's work. I became familiar with Grossman's illustrations by reading <em>National Lampoon</em> (Thank goodness the Boulder Public Library subscribed to it so I could read it when I was 11 years old). Grossman also did work for Paul Krassner's <em>The Realist</em>, and illustrated the cover of The Firesign Theatre's LP, <em>Don't Crush That Dwarf, Hand Me The Pliers</em>.

Drew says:

<blockquote><p>Illustrator, sculptor, comics artist, animator Robert Grossman has had an astounding career covering the last 50 years. To say he's the greatest airbrush artist/caricaturist of all time isn't hyperbole, it's an understatement. Picking just a few samples from his incredible body of work is a near impossible task (he's created over 500 magazine covers alone!) but I'm presenting some of my favorites. If anyone deserves to have a career retrospective/anthology it's Bob Grossman. Check out these beautifully rendered, consistently brilliant and memorable illustrations, most chosen from the 60's-80's. As Steven Heller wrote: "his mordant wit is never duplicated".</p>

<p>Bob is still going strong, turning out wonderful new drawings and comic strips regularly for, among others, <em>Rolling Stone</em>, <em>The Atlantic</em> and the <em>NY Observer</em> where I've been proud to have alternated with him as a regular cover artist for the last 20 years.</p></blockquote>

<a href="http://drewfriedman.blogspot.com/2013/03/the-caricature-art-of-robert-grossman.html">The Caricature Art of Robert Grossman</a><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/wscZndbn0HY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Artist Drew Friedman has assembled a nice gallery of airbrush illustrator extraordinaire Robert Grossman's work. I became familiar with Grossman's illustrations by reading National Lampoon (Thank goodness the Boulder Public Library subscribed to it so I could read it when I was 11 years old). Grossman also did work for Paul Krassner's The Realist, and [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/drew-friedman-on-the-caricatur.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/drew-friedman-on-the-caricatur.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Best of Etsy Star Wars posters</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/kh1_vdf-t0A/best-of-etsy-star-wars-posters.html</link><category>Post</category><category>art</category><category>Copyfight</category><category>design</category><category>etsy</category><category>gift guide</category><category>makers</category><category>star wars</category><category>wide</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 13:33:08 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=218960</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/il_fullxfull.354687560_5v342.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/il_fullxfull.384094435_3ong2.jpg" class="bordered" align="right"><br />

On Wonderland, Alice has had a deep trawl through the world of Etsy Star Wars posters and rounded up a collection of top choices, including the <a href="http://www.etsy.com/listing/103903857/space-cowboy-star-wars-inspired-han-solo">Space Cowboy</a> by  CONCEPCIONSTUDIOS (top) and <a href="http://www.etsy.com/listing/111935634/vintage-pop-art-star-wars-trilogy-for-40">Vintage Pop Art </a> set from  Posterinspired (right).

<p>
<a href="http://www.wonderlandblog.com/wonderland/2013/03/beautiful-etsy-star-wars-posters.html?utm_source=feedburner&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Wonderland+%28Wonderland%29">Beautiful Etsy Star Wars posters</a>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/kh1_vdf-t0A" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>On Wonderland, Alice has had a deep trawl through the world of Etsy Star Wars posters and rounded up a collection of top choices, including the Space Cowboy by CONCEPCIONSTUDIOS (top) and Vintage Pop Art set from Posterinspired (right). Beautiful Etsy Star Wars posters</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/best-of-etsy-star-wars-posters.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/best-of-etsy-star-wars-posters.html</feedburner:origLink></item></channel></rss>
