<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.boingboing.net/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0"><channel><title>Boing Boing</title><link>http://boingboing.net</link><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.boingboing.net/boingboing/iBag" /><description>Brain candy for Happy Mutants</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 09:12:57 PDT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.1</generator><sy:updatePeriod xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/">hourly</sy:updatePeriod><sy:updateFrequency xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/">1</sy:updateFrequency><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.boingboing.net/boingboing/iBag" /><feedburner:info uri="boingboing/ibag" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><image><link>http://boingboing.net</link><url>http://boingboing.net/icons/bb144.jpg</url><title>Boing Boing</title></image><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item><title>Guatemala genocide trial continues; watch or listen live</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/BPGIv5R3Wlc/guatemala-genocide-trial-conti.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Xeni Jardin</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 09:01:45 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220428</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-22-at-8.16.jpg" alt="" title="Screen-Shot-2013-03-22-at-8.16" width="600" height="188" class="bordered aligncenter size-full wp-image-220431" />
<p>
Efrain Ríos Montt, the former de facto dictator of Guatemala, is in court today for the third day of his trial on charges that of genocide during the country's 36-year civil war. <a href="http://radio.cmiguate.org/">Listen here</a>, or <a href="http://paraqueseconozca.blogspot.mx/">watch here</a>. I've created a Twitter list so you can follow the accounts of people live-tweeting from the courtroom (or listening to the audio/video stream, where dialogue is in Spanish and Ixil Maya only).
<p>
As you can see for yourself on the video stream, the ex-general is sitting and listening in the courtroom while prosecution witnesses, Ixil Maya victims, recount in gruesome detail the atrocities they survived under his regime. As I type this blog post, an Ixil woman, Cecilia Sánchez Sánchez, is breaking down in tears as she retells the story of how on one day in 1982, her husband, two sons, and baby were murdered, her home burned, and "flying instruments" (helicopters) swarmed overhead, dropping bombs on the villagers. Did you see your husband again, the interrogator asks her. "No, I only went to carry away his bones."
<p>

<p>

This tribunal is the first and only genocide trial in history held in a domestic court against a former head of state, and is a huge historic moment for Guatemala. It's also an important moment for America. Our military, and our government, was intimately involved in orchestrating, funding, and propping up to power the Guatemalan generals who led the bloody civil war that killed at least 200,000, and left tens of thousands more "disappeared." <p>

<a href="http://www.theworld.org/2013/03/genocide-trial-in-guatemala-a-tribute-to-tenacity-of-indigenous-groups/">PRI's The World has a good interview</a> with Kate Boyle of the Guatemala Documentation Project for the National Security Archive, who has been monitoring the proceedings and has been working for years to help preserve the evidence that makes this process possible.<p>
But denial persists. Supporters of Montt and the military legacy he represents call the trial a form of political persecution or "political lynching," and deny that any genocide took place. <a href="http://cacif.org.gt/index.php?option=com_content&#038;view=article&#038;id=953%20888&#038;Itemid=468&#038;lang=es">Here is one such example</a>.<p>
<a href="http://nisgua.blogspot.com/">NISGUA</a> has been liveblogging the proceedings, too. <a href="http://www.nisgua.blogspot.com/2013/03/genocide-on-trial-in-guatemala-ixil.html">Day 1</a>, <a href="http://nisgua.blogspot.com/2013/03/genocide-on-trial-in-guatemala-day-2.html">Day 2</a>, <a href="http://nisgua.blogspot.com/2013/03/genocide-on-trial-in-guatemala-day-3.html">Day 3</a>.<p>

<a href="http://nisgua.blogspot.com/2013/03/genocide-on-trial-in-guatemala-day-3.html">From today's NISGUA post</a>, a powerful documentation that I encourage you to read:


<p>
<blockquote>Survivor testimony continued on the third day of former dictator Efraín Rios Montt and intelligence chief Rodriguez Sánchez's trial for genocide and crimes against humanity. Hours of intense first-person accounts of violence and endurance left impressions of profound grief: "They killed our fathers, our mothers, and everything we loved," said one witness; as well as resolute purpose: "I am one of the few survivors. Perhaps I was sent to be the messenger of the story here."
</blockquote>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/BPGIv5R3Wlc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Efrain Ríos Montt, the former de facto dictator of Guatemala, is in court today for the third day of his trial on charges that of genocide during the country's 36-year civil war. Listen here, or watch here. I've created a Twitter list so you can follow the accounts of people live-tweeting from the courtroom (or [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/guatemala-genocide-trial-conti.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/guatemala-genocide-trial-conti.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Human bodies mercilessly jiggled by gravity at 2000fps [NSFW]</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/KDmhif8VBBg/human-bodies-mercilessly-jiggl.html</link><category>Video</category><category>art</category><category>merciless gravity</category><category>movies</category><category>NSFW</category><category>video</category><category>Weird</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 07:32:34 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220269</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--www.youtube.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XZcVrd8-ibY?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>
LA video artist Michael Haussman recorded human bodies bouncing up and down at 2000 fps, synching the camera to the movement so that the people appear to be standing still while gravity mercilessly attempts to separate their meat from their bones. Add in some spooky music and it's like watching someone in the first stages of being torn to shreds by angry, invisible poltergeists.
<blockquote>
<p>
This slow motion study reveals the shocking effects of gravity upon our body. What is normally missed in the blink of an eye, is poetically recorded in extreme slow motion, as gravity takes hold and pulls the body down to earth, causing the skin, cellulite, muscles and facial expression to sag down, with a weariness, as if the subject has suddenly aged thirty years. It appears like a special effect, the force ripples from the legs up, turning the body wrinkled and saggy, with a worn, older face that is defeated and depressed. Then the exact opposite effect and emotion overcomes the subject as they are made weightless and set free. We observe the body becoming youthful, rejoicing in it’s expression and flawless skin texture, as it sores away from the earth. All physical and emotional expressions seem to float effortlessly upward in a positive, beautiful direction.
</blockquote>


<p>
<a href="http://www.moholyground.org/feature.htm#haussman"> GRAVITY by MICHAEL HAUSSMAN</a>

(<i>Thanks, <a href="http://nwn.blogs.com/">James</a>!</i>)





<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/KDmhif8VBBg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>This slow motion study reveals the shocking effects of gravity upon our body.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/human-bodies-mercilessly-jiggl.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/human-bodies-mercilessly-jiggl.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Astounding Beetlejuice roller-coaster made in Minecraft</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/gIas9OpwrBo/astounding-beetlejuice-roller.html</link><category>Video</category><category>fanac</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>makers</category><category>minecraft</category><category>movies</category><category>videos</category><category>youtube</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 06:45:14 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220307</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--www.youtube.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/afcudstM9zA?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>
This five-minute video takes you on a tour of the astounding <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0790731479/downandoutint-20">Beetlejuice</a> roller-coaster created by Nuropsych1 and friends. It incorporates many of the best visual elements from this outstanding film, all set to an excellent remix of the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/?_encoding=UTF8&#038;camp=1789&#038;creative=390957&#038;field-keywords=beetlejuice&#038;linkCode=ur2&#038;tag=downandoutint-20&#038;url=search-alias%3Ddigital-music">Beetlejuice soundtrack</a>, one of the great instrumental pieces of all time.

<blockquote>
<p>
This was done on the XBOX 360 in creative mode. We worked on it off and on for two months. 
</blockquote>

<p>
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afcudstM9zA">
Beetle Juice - A Minecraft Roller Coaster
</a>

(<i>Thanks, Fipi Lele!</i>)






<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/gIas9OpwrBo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>This five-minute video takes you on a tour of the astounding &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0790731479/downandoutint-20"&gt;Beetlejuice&lt;/a&gt; roller-coaster created by Nuropsych1 and friends.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/astounding-beetlejuice-roller.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/astounding-beetlejuice-roller.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Transgender teacher kills self after Daily Mail columnist Richard Littlejohn denounces her</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/Z4uAKLeHiEY/transgendered-teacher-kills-se.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob Beschizza</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 06:19:16 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220394</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/greatsadness.jpg" alt="" title="greatsadness" width="600" height="337" class="bordered size-full wp-image-220404" />

<p>Lucy Meadows was a teacher. Born male, Lucy transitioned to female later in life, a process that was supported by her employers. Writing at the <em>Daily Mail</em>&mdash;one of Britain's largest-circulation newspapers&mdash;Richard Littlejohn <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20121226073921/http:/www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-2251347/Nathan-Uptons-wrong-body--hes-wrong-job.html">publicly denounced her</a> in terms usually reserved for child abusers. Not long afterward, <a href="http://www.st-marymagdalens.lancs.sch.uk/">Meadows killed herself</a>.<span id="more-220394"></span>

<p>The <em>Daily Mail</em> took the article down upon Meadows' death, but <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20121226073921/http:/www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-2251347/Nathan-Uptons-wrong-body--hes-wrong-job.html">here it is at archive.org</a>, and here's a representative excerpt.

<blockquote><p>
What are you staring at, Johnny? Move along, nothing to see here. Get on with your spelling test. Today’s word is ‘transitioning’.

<p>Mr Upton/Miss Meadows may well be comfortable with his/her decision to seek a sex-change and return to work as if nothing has happened. The school might be extremely proud of its ‘commitment to equality and diversity’.

<p>But has anyone stopped for a moment to think of the devastating effect all this is having on those who really matter? Children as young as seven aren’t equipped to compute this kind of information. ...

<p>It should be protecting pupils from some of the more, er, challenging realities of adult life, not forcing them down their throats.

<p>These are primary school children, for heaven’s sake. Most them still believe in Father Christmas. Let them enjoy their childhood. They will lose their innocence soon enough. ... Nathan Upton is entitled to his gender reassignment surgery, but he isn’t entitled to project his personal problems on to impressionable young children.
</blockquote>

<p>You want to point out that children don't do this at all, that prejudices centered on complex cultural issues are learned from adults. You want to wonder at those who would hound people who are already widely victimized, yet remove evidence of their ostensibly principled beliefs when their targets suffer the predictable effects. You want to remark on what a miracle it is that steps toward libel reform can take place at all. You want to wonder at how the children feel at the death of their teacher, children to whom suicide must now be explained.

<p>But most of all, you just want to see Britain lose its interest in the opinions of people like Richard Littlejohn.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/Z4uAKLeHiEY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Lucy Meadows was a teacher. Born male, Lucy transitioned to female later in life, a process that was supported by her employers. Writing at the Daily Mail&amp;#8212;one of Britain's largest-circulation newspapers&amp;#8212;Richard Littlejohn publicly denounced her in terms usually reserved for child abusers. Not long afterward, Meadows killed herself. The Daily Mail took the article down [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/transgendered-teacher-kills-se.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/transgendered-teacher-kills-se.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Act now to stop the UK Leveson press-regulations from applying to blogs and individuals online!</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/NoGGu_nOPy4/act-now-to-stop-the-uk-leveson.html</link><category>Post</category><category>censorship</category><category>laws</category><category>leveson</category><category>newspapers</category><category>org</category><category>promoted</category><category>uk</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 06:05:53 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220396</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
I've written here before that the impending UK press-regulation rules coming in as a result of the Leveson report will inadvertently end up treating bloggers and other everyday Internet users as though they were newspapers, exposing them to the threat of arbitration proceedings where they will have to pay the legal costs of people who want to silence them, and be subject to "exemplary damages" -- enormous statutory fines that grossly exceed any actual harm caused. 
<p>
Now the Open Rights Group has started a campaign to warn party leaders about this in the three days we have left before Leveson becomes law. We need your help now, or bloggers and the open Internet will become collateral damage in the campaign to control Britain's awful tabloids. 
<p>
Jim from ORG writes, "The Leveson regulations are being applied to UK websites -- in ways that could catch more or less anyone who publishes a blog. Ordinary bloggers could be threatened with exemplary damages and costs. If this happens, small website publishers will face terrible risks, or burdensome regulation -- and many may simply stop publishing."
<p>
<a href="http://www.openrightsgroup.org/campaigns/leveson">Cameron, stop the Dangerous Blogs Bill </a>

(<i>Thanks, <a href="http://www.openrightsgroup.org">Jim</a>!</i>)
<p>
(<i>Disclosure: I co-founded the Open Rights Group and am proud to volunteer on its advisory board</i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/NoGGu_nOPy4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>I've written here before that the impending UK press-regulation rules coming in as a result of the Leveson report will inadvertently end up treating bloggers and other everyday Internet users as though they were newspapers, exposing them to the threat of arbitration proceedings where they will have to pay the legal costs of people who [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/act-now-to-stop-the-uk-leveson.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/act-now-to-stop-the-uk-leveson.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Interview with Peter Clines,  author of Ex-Heroes and Ex-Patriots</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/ksY08UGN6ns/interview-with-peter-clines.html</link><category>Post</category><category>books</category><category>interviews</category><category>science fiction</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 06:00:16 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220148</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0804136599/boingboing"><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/ex_patriots_cover-FINAL.jpg"  class="alignnone"></a></p>

<p>Peter Clines is the author of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0804136572/boingboing">Ex-Heroes</a>, a science fiction novel about super humans trying to save what remains of Los Angeles in a post-apocalyptic zombie wasteland. Above, the cover for the Clines' upcoming follow-up novel: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0804136599/boingboing">Ex-Patriots</a>. Below, an interview with Clines about his love of  Dr. Who. (Keep your eye out for 3 Doctor Who Novels coming out April 2: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/038534676X/boingboing">Plague of the Cybermen</a>, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0385346786/boingboing">Shroud of Sorrow</a>, and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0385346743/boingboing">The Dalek Generation</a>.)</p>

<blockquote>Originally published by a small, print-on-demand press without any publicity or marketing support and almost no physical distribution, Peter Clines&rsquo;s brilliant novels, <em>Ex-Heroes</em> and the forthcoming <em>Ex-Patriots</em> -- which combine the best of the sci-fi, thriller, horror, and adventure fiction genres -- still managed to draw an incredible cult following. Now, Broadway is thrilled to introduce <em>Ex-Heroes</em> and <em>Ex-Patriots</em> to a whole new slew of fans with the release of these paperback originals. With two more novels to follow in the series, including <em>Ex-Communication</em> (July 9, 2013), <em>Ex-Heroes</em> and <em>Ex-Patriots</em> are sure to appeal to fans of such hits as <em>Watchmen</em>, <em>World War Z</em>, and Ready <em>Player One</em>.</blockquote>



<p><h4>How big of a role did <i>Doctor Who</i> play in your decision to become a writer?</h4></p>

<p>It was a huge influence. I watched the show religiously as a kid, and even then I was aware that a good story could really help make up for cheap sets and rubber monsters (pay attention, SyFy!). I got chills from cliffhanger endings in &ldquo;The Face of Evil&rdquo; and &ldquo;The Horror of Fang Rock.&rdquo; Davros in &ldquo;Genesis of the Daleks&rdquo; was the first time I ever realized a character was evil. I always knew they were the bad guys out there, but Michael Wisher as Davros was just pure evil. And I loved the brilliant plot-twists that could be either scary or kind of sad and dramatic. Not to mention the fact that the whole show is about someone who gave up their life so they could try to make a difference. </p>

<p>It was just fantastic storytelling, and it made me want to tell stories that would get the same reactions from people. </p><span id="more-220148"></span><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0385346786/boingboing">
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/ShroudSorrow.jpg" class="alignright">
</a><h4>Of all of the actors who played Doctor Who, which was your favorite?</h4></p>

<p>I&rsquo;d have to say Tom Baker. The scarf, the hat, a dozen layers of clothing... that&rsquo;s always going to be the Doctor to me. I think Doctor Who is a lot like James Bond&mdash;the first one you&rsquo;re ever exposed to is the &ldquo;real&rdquo; one and then other actors get brought in to play the part as time goes by.</p>

<p><h4>Why do you think the character and story continues to thrill fans, old and new alike?</h4></p>

<p>The TARDIS and time travel are fun, the monsters are exciting, but at the end of the day I think it&rsquo;s the honest sense that the Doctor just wants to help people. He doesn&rsquo;t care about politics or procedure or social classes (he&rsquo;s really the antithesis of the Prime Directive). He just wants people everywhere to have good, happy lives, and he gave up his whole life on Gallifrey because he thought he should try to make that happen. That sort of selflessness is something everyone can admire. </p>

<p>I mean, what&rsquo;s one of the running gags in the series? When the Doctor needs someone out of the way, do they vanish mysteriously? Do they have an accident? Do they get fired? No, when he needs someone out of the way, they win the lottery. A recurring plot point in the show is that the Doctor gives people the life they&rsquo;ve always dreamed of just so that he can get on with what he&rsquo;s focused on doing.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/038534676X/boingboing">
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/PlagueCybermen.jpg" class="alignleft"></a><h4>What do you think is the Doctor&rsquo;s real name? Go ahead, guess. </h4></p>

<p>I would have no idea. I feel confident it isn&rsquo;t Steve, Brett, or Cliff. I like that they&rsquo;re pushing an idea from the Sylvester McCoy years, that the Doctor might be something bigger and greater than &ldquo;just&rdquo; a Time Lord. Because there&rsquo;s something fantastic and kind of scary about the idea that being the nigh-immortal last survivor of the oldest race in the universe is your cover story...</p>

<p>I could prove my geekiness by pointing out that his school nickname was Theta Sigma. And I didn&rsquo;t even have to look that up. I could even name the episode.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0385346743/boingboing">
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DalekGeneration.jpg" class="alignright">
</a><h4>If you could cast anyone as the next incarnation of the Doctor, who would it be? </h4></p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know. Lots of people want to see female Doctors and other-ethnicity Doctors, and while I don&rsquo;t see any story-logic problem with that I do think it&rsquo;d probably alienate a lot of fans. I always thought Richard Grant would make a fantastic Doctor, except now he&rsquo;s sort of been the Doctor, so that probably wouldn&rsquo;t go over well. Then again, Lalla Ward played a princess and later became the second Romana, with the logic being she was using the princess as sort of a regeneration template.</p>

<p>Y&rsquo;know who&rsquo;d be a great Doctor? Martin Freeman, from <i>Sherlock</i> and <i>The Hobbit</i>. He&rsquo;s got an ability to seem completely harmless and extremely dangerous. That&rsquo;s a fantastic quality for a Doctor.</p>


<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0804136572/boingboing">Ex-Heroes</a> | <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0804136599/boingboing">Ex-Patriots</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/ksY08UGN6ns" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Peter Clines is the author of Ex-Heroes, a science fiction novel about super humans trying to save what remains of Los Angeles in a post-apocalyptic zombie wasteland. Above, the cover for the Clines' upcoming follow-up novel: Ex-Patriots. Below, an interview with Clines about his love of Dr. Who. (Keep your eye out for 3 Doctor [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/interview-with-peter-clines.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/interview-with-peter-clines.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>MAD Artist's Edition: a massive tribute to Harvey Kurtzman</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/Q0Osv_JWsEM/mad-artists-edition-a-massi.html</link><category>Review</category><category>art</category><category>books</category><category>Comics</category><category>gift guide</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>Reviews</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 05:54:49 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220342</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8580197612_c7e1c6ccf5_z1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
<font size="-1">(<em>The cover; my feet, a KISS matrioshke, and spring-loaded gag eyeballs included for scale</em>)</font>
<p>
IDW's <a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/?_encoding=UTF8&#038;camp=1789&#038;creative=390957&#038;field-keywords=idw%20artists%20edition&#038;linkCode=ur2&#038;sprefix=idw%20artists%2Caps%2C346&#038;tag=downandoutint-20&#038;url=search-alias%3Daps">Artist's Edition</a> series is a line of enormous (15" x 22")</font> hardcover art-books that reproduce the full-page, camera-ready paste-ups used to create classic comics, from <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B008P8895M/downandoutint-20">Groo</a> to <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1613771444/downandoutint-20">Spider-Man</a>, offering a rare look at the white-outs, annotations, corrections, and pencil-marks that give tantalizing hints about the hidden workings of these amazing pages.
<p>
A recent and most welcome addition to the series is <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00B4HCM4K/downandoutint-20">MAD: Artist's Edition</a>, a spectacular tribute to the early years of the magazine and especially to the brilliant satire of Harvey Kurtzman, one of the great heroes of satire, which features an introduction by Terry Gilliam himself.
<p>
<em>MAD: Artist's Edition</em> isn't just an amazing book, it's an amazing <em>object</em>, a massive and weighty presence that drew me magnetically to it as soon as I got it back to my office. I spent the next several hours on a rug on the floor with it, clambering all around it (it's much easier to move yourself than a book this size!)</font>, marvelling and delighting at it. I snapped a few highlights (<a href="https://secure.flickr.com/photos/doctorow/tags/artistsedition/">full-rez photos here</a>)</font> to give you a sense of what's going on here. 
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8579099703_bd299ddaea_z1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
<font size="-1">(<em>Love, Kurtzman style -- from <b>Shadow!</b></em>)</font>
<p>
Let's start with the obvious: Kurtzman was a genius of parody, with a wolvertonian grasp of the grotesque and a sense of humor that was capable of expressing itself in both broad and subtle strokes. This was a man who could capture both drama and comedy, as in this sequence from <em>Smilin' Melvin'</em>, where the punchline is just a lagniappe on top of a sequence that is as illustrative as it is absurd:
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8580202490_7ef3a14337_z1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
<font size="-1">(<em>Q-Tips and the sound-barrier, from <b>Smilin' Melvin'</b></em>)</font>
<span id="more-220342"></span>
<p>
And Prince Valiant is reproduced with pitch-perfect veracity, even when he's holding his ass and screaming in agony:
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8580206588_b465614e72_z1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
<font size="-1">(<em>Love the gothic lettering on the onomatopoeia, from <b>Prince Violent</b></em>)</font>
<p>
It's that veering between styles and modes that really makes this stuff sing. Is Howdy Doody a daemonic possessed toy, or a agent of commercial forces bent at getting kids hooked on booze? Why choose?
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8579111529_4e0d689c28_z1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
<font size="-1">(<em>Stare into the eyes of madness, from <b>Howdy Doo-It?</b></em>)</font>
<p>
Not only could Kurtzman strike some wolvertonian notes, he could also write some spectacular material for Wolverton to illustrate, like the series of full-page spreads dedicated to portraits of typical MAD readers:
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8579106461_acd3f37059_z1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
<font size="-1">(<em>Wolverton and Kurtzman, a match made on MADison Ave</em>)</font>
<p>
And since this is such a big ole compendium, the IDW folks saw fit to include these illos as finished inks, later in the book:
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8579109145_fc9d6b4b39_c1.jpg" class="bordered">
<p>
It's only the book's rather smashing price-tag <font size="-1">(north of $225)</font> that stopped me from grabbing a scalpel and hacking out some of the full-page sheets and the splashes, as every one of them would make a fantastic framed piece:
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8579108323_9c34fcdbe7_c1.jpg" class="bordered">
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8580201396_52349b8f6a_c1.jpg" class="bordered">
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8580203572_8f356af5c9_z1.jpg" class="bordered">
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8579105597_561c23f80c_c1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
<font size="-1">(<em>Kurtzman's "Flesh Garden" is much classier than the pornographic "Flesh Gordon," which was a little too on-the-nose</em>)</font>
<p>
There's even a lavishly illustrated page of fake classifieds:
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8579115601_e8220dd00a_z1.jpg" class="bordered">
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8579114517_1a50bc1699_z1.jpg" class="bordered">
<p>
Every detail of this book is pretty damned special, right down to the end-papers:
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8580216994_d26afcbf55_z1.jpg" class="bordered">
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8580215556_b6abb9fa32_z1.jpg" class="bordered">


<p>
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00B4HCM4K/downandoutint-20">Mad: Artist's Edition</a>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/Q0Osv_JWsEM" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>(The cover; my feet, a KISS matrioshke, and spring-loaded gag eyeballs included for scale) IDW's Artist's Edition series is a line of enormous (15" x 22") hardcover art-books that reproduce the full-page, camera-ready paste-ups used to create classic comics, from Groo to Spider-Man, offering a rare look at the white-outs, annotations, corrections, and pencil-marks that [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/mad-artists-edition-a-massi.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/mad-artists-edition-a-massi.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Apple removes Sweatshop iOS game</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/0Lr-1zRu24U/apple-removes-sweatshop-ios-ga.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob Beschizza</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 05:36:37 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220337</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.geek.com/articles/mobile/apple-removes-sweatshop-ios-game-from-sale-because-it-made-them-uncomfortable-20130321/">Matthew Humphries:</a>

<blockquote><p>Sweatshop HD was created by BAFTA-winning creative studio Littleloud. It has tower defense gameplay mechanics, but tasks the player with running a sweatshop producing clothing and footwear. It is aimed at young people in a bid to get them thinking about where the clothes we buy come from and the conditions workers in some of these factories suffer through.</blockquote>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/0Lr-1zRu24U" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Matthew Humphries: Sweatshop HD was created by BAFTA-winning creative studio Littleloud. It has tower defense gameplay mechanics, but tasks the player with running a sweatshop producing clothing and footwear. It is aimed at young people in a bid to get them thinking about where the clothes we buy come from and the conditions workers in [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/apple-removes-sweatshop-ios-ga.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/apple-removes-sweatshop-ios-ga.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Vatican: Batman has "grown bitter and more vengeful"</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/yhPFEEPcElY/vatman.html</link><category>Short</category><category>batman</category><category>vatican</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob Beschizza</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 04:39:34 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220333</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[The Vatican reassured the Catholic faithful that it hadn't been hacked Thursday after as unusual tweet--<em><a href="http://hosted2.ap.org/APDEFAULT/aa9398e6757a46fa93ed5dea7bd3729e/Article_2013-03-21-Vatican-Hacked/id-1ef11089e84a4e71939be7fb9ef8b64a">"Holy Switcheroo! Batman has grown bitter, more vengeful with the years"</a></em>--appeared on a popular news feed.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/yhPFEEPcElY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>The Vatican reassured the Catholic faithful that it hadn't been hacked Thursday after as unusual tweet--"Holy Switcheroo! Batman has grown bitter, more vengeful with the years"--appeared on a popular news feed.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/vatman.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/vatman.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Polite boos now OK at Riverhead town board meetings</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/VjYnDS9MXhI/polite-boos-now-ok-at-riverhea.html</link><category>Short</category><category>booing</category><category>politics</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob Beschizza</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 04:34:35 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220329</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[A ban on booing has been lifted at Town Hall board meetings in Riverhead, N.Y., but officials warn that <a href="http://www.newsday.com/long-island/towns/boo-ban-lifted-at-riverhead-town-board-meetings-1.4851846">only polite booing will be permitted.</a> [Newsday]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/VjYnDS9MXhI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>A ban on booing has been lifted at Town Hall board meetings in Riverhead, N.Y., but officials warn that only polite booing will be permitted. [Newsday]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/polite-boos-now-ok-at-riverhea.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/polite-boos-now-ok-at-riverhea.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Girl, 7, brought into pepper-spray fight</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/g_lJrEBOVdo/girl-7-brought-into-pepper-s.html</link><category>Post</category><category>philadelphia</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob Beschizza</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 04:31:18 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220327</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://articles.philly.com/2013-03-21/news/37906507_1_pepper-spray-police-superintendent-michael-chitwood-daughter">Stephanie Farr, at Philly.com:</a>

<blockquote><p>A woman who had been banned from an Upper Darby dollar store doused store employees with pepper spray as they tried to escort her out on Monday, and when they tackled her to the ground, she gave the spray can to her 7-year-old daughter and told her to finish the fight, police said. "You know what to do, baby. Spray it!", Delaina Garling allegedly told her daughter.</blockquote>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/g_lJrEBOVdo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Stephanie Farr, at Philly.com: A woman who had been banned from an Upper Darby dollar store doused store employees with pepper spray as they tried to escort her out on Monday, and when they tackled her to the ground, she gave the spray can to her 7-year-old daughter and told her to finish the fight, [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/girl-7-brought-into-pepper-s.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/girl-7-brought-into-pepper-s.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Well-planned bank heist fails</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/wj2sK2QlV24/well-planned-bank-heist-a-fail.html</link><category>Short</category><category>heists</category><category>law</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob Beschizza</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 04:15:44 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220321</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[In a daring, Hollywood-style bank heist, a crack team of thieves occupied offices above their target, covered its windows to make it look like they were working on renovations, cut through a concrete floor to gain access to a secure area, bypassed an alarm system, and used hockey bags to exfiltrate $293,000 from the vault within. <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/03/21/us-bank-heist-idUSBRE92K14R20130321?feedType=RSS&#038;feedName=oddlyEnoughNews">Then they were arrested in a field</a>. [Reuters]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/wj2sK2QlV24" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>In a daring, Hollywood-style bank heist, a crack team of thieves occupied offices above their target, covered its windows to make it look like they were working on renovations, cut through a concrete floor to gain access to a secure area, bypassed an alarm system, and used hockey bags to exfiltrate $293,000 from the vault [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/well-planned-bank-heist-a-fail.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/well-planned-bank-heist-a-fail.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Donglegate</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/bPOht_qX7HM/donglegate.html</link><category>Short</category><category>Culture</category><category>donglegate</category><category>everyone is horrible</category><category>sexism</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob Beschizza</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 04:07:53 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220317</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[The fight against ingrained sexism in tech culture is gruelling indeed; but what do you do when an off-color joke about "dongles" leads not only to internet drama, but everyone&mdash;including the claimed victim&mdash;getting fired?  <em>Ars Technica</em> <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2013/03/how-dongle-jokes-got-two-people-fired-and-led-to-ddos-attacks/?utm_source=feedburner&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+arstechnica%2Findex+%28Ars+Technica+-+All+content%29">sums up "Donglegate"</a>. Adds Amanda Blum: <a href="http://amandablumwords.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/3/">everyone lost</>.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/bPOht_qX7HM" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>The fight against ingrained sexism in tech culture is gruelling indeed; but what do you do when an off-color joke about "dongles" leads not only to internet drama, but everyone&amp;#8212;including the claimed victim&amp;#8212;getting fired? Ars Technica sums up "Donglegate". Adds Amanda Blum: everyone lost.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/donglegate.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/donglegate.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Cory signing Rapture of the Nerds at Forbidden Planet London tomorrow</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/FI8zsBfN6fE/cory-signing-rapture-of-the-ne.html</link><category>Post</category><category>3d printing</category><category>events</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>london</category><category>science fiction</category><category>singularity</category><category>uk</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:55:49 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220310</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8571860448_50648e930b_c1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
Hey, Londoners! A reminder that I'll be signing the UK edition of Charlie Stross's and my novel <a href="http://craphound.com/rotn">Rapture of the Nerds</a>, <a href="http://forbiddenplanet.com/events/2013/03/23/cory-doctorow-signing-rapture-nerds/">tomorrow at 1PM at Forbidden Planet</a>. Charlie can't make it, so I have fashioned a cunning 3D printed Space Marine Stross to accompany me, which you may rub for good luck if you attend.

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/FI8zsBfN6fE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Hey, Londoners! A reminder that I'll be signing the UK edition of Charlie Stross's and my novel Rapture of the Nerds, tomorrow at 1PM at Forbidden Planet. Charlie can't make it, so I have fashioned a cunning 3D printed Space Marine Stross to accompany me, which you may rub for good luck if you attend.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/cory-signing-rapture-of-the-ne.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/22/cory-signing-rapture-of-the-ne.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>DRM-free label for all your DRM-free stuff</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/S-4Re1eMdVA/drm-free-label-for-all-your-dr.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Copyfight</category><category>drm</category><category>floss</category><category>fsf</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 21:23:29 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220163</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>

<img src="http://craphound.com/images/DRM-free label 120.en.png.jpg" align="right">
Kxra sez, "Defective by Design, the Free Software Foundation's campaign against DRM has just released a new graphic to mark DRM-free works on the web. The DRM-free label quickly communicates the DRM-free status of files, increases in value as more distributors adopt the label, and adds value to being DRM-free by linking to an informational page about DRM. The logo is already in use by O'Reilly, Momentum, the Pragmatic Bookshelf, and Magnatune. It is available in a few different styles with source files under CC-BY-SA 3.0."


<p>
<a href="http://www.defectivebydesign.org/node/2257">New and improved label for DRM-free files</a>
(<i>Thanks, Kxra!</i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/S-4Re1eMdVA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Kxra sez, "Defective by Design, the Free Software Foundation's campaign against DRM has just released a new graphic to mark DRM-free works on the web. The DRM-free label quickly communicates the DRM-free status of files, increases in value as more distributors adopt the label, and adds value to being DRM-free by linking to an informational [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/drm-free-label-for-all-your-dr.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/drm-free-label-for-all-your-dr.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Skull wedding cake</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/W7Iwkjq40-s/skull-wedding-cake.html</link><category>Post</category><category>cakes</category><category>Food</category><category>makers</category><category>not food</category><category>romance</category><category>skulls</category><category>uk</category><category>wide</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 20:18:50 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220157</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/dsc_00571.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
Baker Anna at Eat Your Heart Out Bakers made this astounding skull wedding-cake. 

<blockquote>
<p>
Food artist Annabel de Vetten, also known as Conjurer’s Kitchen, created this incredible skull wedding cake for the Eclectic Wedding Extravaganza in Birmingham this weekend. Her theme being ” ‘Til Death Do Us Part”.
<p>
It features solid chocolate skulls of 16 carrion crows, 12 domestic kittens, 3 Vervet monkeys, and 4 barn owls, all of which the artist sculpted by hand. Made from White Chocolate Mudcake, the cake took her over 100  hours to complete in total. There are two options of toppers: a chocolate conjoined kitten skull, or dried flowers from an actual wedding bouquet (ones shown here from her own).
</blockquote>
<p>
<a href="http://evilcakehead.com/2013/03/21/the-ultimate-skull-wedding-cake/">The Ultimate Skull Wedding Cake</a>

(<i>Thanks, Emma!</i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/W7Iwkjq40-s" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Baker Anna at Eat Your Heart Out Bakers made this astounding skull wedding-cake. Food artist Annabel de Vetten, also known as Conjurer’s Kitchen, created this incredible skull wedding cake for the Eclectic Wedding Extravaganza in Birmingham this weekend. Her theme being ” ‘Til Death Do Us Part”. It features solid chocolate skulls of 16 carrion [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/skull-wedding-cake.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/skull-wedding-cake.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Elf beer needs your vote</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/Xv9vmiMpe00/elf-beer-needs-your-vote.html</link><category>Short</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Rob Beschizza</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:41:39 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220234</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[Attention, users of "The Face Book": self-published indie comic ElfQuest (syndicated of late <a href="http://boingboing.net/tag/elfquest">exclusively here at Boing Boing</a> &mdash; see also <a href="http://boingboing.net/tag/tomthedancingbug">TTDB</a>, <a href="http://boingboing.net/tag/brainrot">Brain Rot</a> and <a href="http://boingboing.net/tag/wilcock">Wilcock</a>) is running neck and neck with <em>Doctor Who</em> and <em>Superman</em> in a contest to have a microbeer made in its honor for the 2013 Denver Comic-Con. So allow me to humbly suggest that you <del datetime="2013-03-22T10:57:54+00:00"><a href="https://www.facebook.com/DenverComicCon?sk=app_432976163386165&#038;app_data">vote for <em>Pike's Dreamberry Ale</em> right here</a></del>. Cheers! <strong><em>Update:</em></strong> polls closed. Not a bad showing!<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/Xv9vmiMpe00" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Attention, users of "The Face Book": self-published indie comic ElfQuest (syndicated of late exclusively here at Boing Boing &amp;#8212; see also TTDB, Brain Rot and Wilcock) is running neck and neck with Doctor Who and Superman in a contest to have a microbeer made in its honor for the 2013 Denver Comic-Con. So allow me [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/elf-beer-needs-your-vote.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/elf-beer-needs-your-vote.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>How to fix the worst law in technology</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/NoiTnm0tgC8/how-to-fix-the-worst-law-in-te.html</link><category>Post</category><category>aaronsw</category><category>cfaa</category><category>doj</category><category>politics</category><category>reasonable agreement</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:40:47 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220106</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[

<p>
Tim Wu's <em>New Yorker</em> piece on Aaron Swartz and the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act explains how Obama could, with one speech, fix the worst problem with the worst law in technology. The CFAA makes it a felony to "exceed your authorization" on a computer system, and fed prosecutors have taken the view that this means that if you violate terms of service, you're a felon, and they can put you in jail. As Wu points out, Obama doesn't need Congress to pass a law to fix this, he could just tell the DoJ that they should stop doing this. There's plenty of precedent, and it would be excellent policy.

<blockquote>
<p>
 When judges or academics say that it is wrong to interpret a law in such a way that everyone is a felon, the Justice Department has usually replied by saying, roughly, that federal prosecutors don’t bother with minor cases—they only go after the really bad guys. That has always been a lame excuse—repulsive to anyone who takes seriously the idea of a “a government of laws, not men.” After Aaron Swartz’s suicide, the era of trusting prosecutors with unlimited power in this area should officially be over...
 <p>


There is a much more immediate and effective remedy: the Justice Department should announce a change in its criminal-enforcement policy. It should no longer consider terms-of-service violations to be criminal. It can join more than a dozen federal judges and scholars, like Kerr, who adopt a reasonable and more limited interpretation. The Obama Administration’s policy will have no effect on civil litigation, so firms like Oracle will retain their civil remedies. President Obama’s DREAM Act enforcement policy, under which the Administration does not deport certain illegal immigrants despite Congress’s inability to make the act a law, should be the model. Where Congress is unlikely to solve a problem, the Administration should take care of business itself.
<p>
All the Administration needs to do is to rely on the ancient common-law principle called the “rule of lenity.” This states that ambiguous criminal laws should be construed in favor of a defendant. As the Supreme Court puts it, “When choice has to be made between two readings of what conduct Congress has made a crime, it is appropriate, before we choose the harsher alternative, to require that Congress should have spoken in language that is clear and definite.” So far, at least thirteen federal judges have rejected the Justice Department’s interpretation of the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act. If that’s not a sign that the law is unclear and should be interpreted with lenity, I don’t know what is. 
</blockquote>


<p>
<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/newsdesk/2013/03/fixing-the-worst-law-in-technology-aaron-swartz-and-the-computer-fraud-and-abuse-act.html">Fixing the Worst Law in Technology</a>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/NoiTnm0tgC8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Tim Wu's New Yorker piece on Aaron Swartz and the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act explains how Obama could, with one speech, fix the worst problem with the worst law in technology. The CFAA makes it a felony to "exceed your authorization" on a computer system, and fed prosecutors have taken the view that this [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/how-to-fix-the-worst-law-in-te.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/how-to-fix-the-worst-law-in-te.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>GoPro sends fraudulent DMCA notice to site that ran a negative review of its products</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/-d3rsIKHU7w/gopro-sends-fraudulent-dmca-no.html</link><category>Post</category><category>censorship</category><category>Copyfight</category><category>dmca</category><category>Gadgets</category><category>streisand effect</category><category>web theory</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:51:30 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220017</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
<img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/screenshot1.jpg" class="bordered"><br />
GoPro, manufacturers of small digital video cameras, sent a Digital Millennium Copyright Notice to a site called DigitalRev, which had compared GoPro's latest camera to Sony's rival <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B0090EC5MS/downandoutint-20">Action Video Camera</a>, and concluded that the Sony camera was much better. When GoPro was called on its censorship, the company said,

<blockquote>
<p>
The letter that was posted next to the review on DigitalRev was not sent in response to the review. Obviously, we welcome editorial reviews of our products. This letter was sent because DigitalRev is not an
authorized reseller of GoPro products and they were using images and had incorrect branding and representation of our product in their online commerce store. As part of our program – we ask merchants who are selling our product to use authorized images. That is why DigitalRev was contacted. But – our letter did not clearly communicate this and that is something we will correct.

</blockquote>

<p>
However, the DMCA cannot be used to remove alleged trademark violations. As the name implies, the DMCA concerns itself with <em>copyright</em>, not <em>trademark</em> (that's why it's the DMCA and not the DMTA), and it is nothing less than fraud to send a DMCA notice over an alleged trademark violation. In other words, GoPro violated the law, and then offered a lame-ass, weak-ola excuse for it. You don't need a trademark holder's permission to use its marks in a review, nor do you need to be an authorized reseller to review products. 
<p>
As GoPro surely knows.
<p>
As a reminder, apparently Sony's <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B0090EC5MS/downandoutint-20">Action Video Camera</a> kicks the GoPro camera's ass.

<P>
<a href="http://michaelczhang.wpengine.com/2013/03/20/gopro-uses-dmca-to-take-down-article-comparing-its-camera-with-rival/">GoPro Uses DMCA to Take Down Article Comparing Its Camera with Rival
</a>

(<i>Thanks, Paul!</i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/-d3rsIKHU7w" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>GoPro, manufacturers of small digital video cameras, sent a Digital Millennium Copyright Notice to a site called DigitalRev, which had compared GoPro's latest camera to Sony's rival Action Video Camera, and concluded that the Sony camera was much better. When GoPro was called on its censorship, the company said, The letter that was posted next [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/gopro-sends-fraudulent-dmca-no.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/gopro-sends-fraudulent-dmca-no.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Why did Lee Baca win Sheriff of the Year award?</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/o5DIPaCeaDI/why-did-lee-baca-win-sheriff-o.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:31:03 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220232</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The National Sheriffs&rsquo; Association (NSA) awarded LA County Sheriff Lee Baca "<a href="http://www.publicceo.com/2013/02/lee-baca-named-national-sheriff-of-the-year/">Sheriff of the Year</a>."</p>

<p>What does it take to win Sheriff of the Year?</p>

<p>1,480 wrongful incarcerations? The <a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2011/dec/25/local/la-me-wrong-id-20111225">LA Times</a> reported that "hundreds of people have been wrongly imprisoned inside the Los Angeles County Sheriff's Department jails in recent years, with some spending weeks behind bars before authorities realized those arrested were mistaken for wanted criminals."</p>

<p>Widespread prison rape? <a href="http://www.justdetention.org/en/not-on-our-watch.aspx">Just Detention International</a> reported that "Two years ago, it came to light that gangs of deputies were brutalizing jail inmates, using sexual assault and excessive force to instill a climate of terror. Sheriff Baca has repeatedly sought to <a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2011/dec/01/local/la-me-jail-commander-20111201-1">duck responsibility</a> for the crisis. Yet the Citizens&rsquo; Commission on Jail Violence placed the blame squarely on his shoulders, citing a 'failure of leadership.'"</p>

<p>Pervasive abuse of jail inmates? An <a href="http://documents.latimes.com/aclu-report-la-county-jails/">ACLU report</a> quotes Thomas Parker, a former FBI agent as saying "Of all the jails I have had the occasion to visit, tour, or conduct investigations within, domestically and internationally, I have never experienced any facility exhibiting the volume and repetitive patterns of violence, misfeasance, and malfeasance impacting the Los Angeles County Jail system..."

<p>Why did he win? Your guess is as good as mine!</p>

<p>Coincidentally, Baca is a member of the NSA <a href="http://www.sheriffs.org/content/board-directors">Board of Directors</a> and serves on its <a href="http://www.sheriffs.org/content/executive-committee">Executive Committee</a>. </p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/o5DIPaCeaDI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>The National Sheriffs&amp;#8217; Association (NSA) awarded LA County Sheriff Lee Baca "Sheriff of the Year." What does it take to win Sheriff of the Year? 1,480 wrongful incarcerations? The LA Times reported that "hundreds of people have been wrongly imprisoned inside the Los Angeles County Sheriff's Department jails in recent years, with some spending weeks [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/why-did-lee-baca-win-sheriff-o.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/why-did-lee-baca-win-sheriff-o.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Internet-of-Things answering machine from 1992, with marbles</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/lu8AZVle5kg/internet-of-things-answering-m.html</link><category>Video</category><category>design</category><category>Gadgets</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>internet of things</category><category>ui</category><category>uk</category><category>ux</category><category>videos</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:38:33 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220013</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--vimeo.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/19930744" width="600" height="456" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>
 Durrell Bishop's 1992 grad project for his design program at the  Royal College of Art was a brilliantly conceived riff on the answering machine, making use of  physical, legible interfaces that made a point of exposing the conceptual workings of the device to its users. 
 
 <blockquote>
 <p>
 Durrell Bishop is a partner in Luckybite with Tom Hulbert, working on physical interfaces, product design and interactive media. Prior to this he was a senior interaction designer at IDEO Europe. He co-founded Itch, which won a D&#038;AD Gold award for large-scale work on the Science Museum Welcome Wing, and he was a partner in Dancing Dog, working on camera-based interfaces to computer games.
 </blockquote>

<p>
<a href="http://ccdc11.wordpress.com/2011/02/15/durrell-bishops-marble-answering-machine/">Durrell Bishop’s Marble Answering Machine</a>

(<i>via <a href="http://www.elasticspace.com">Timo Arnall</a></i>)



<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/lu8AZVle5kg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Durrell Bishop's 1992 grad project for his design program at the  Royal College of Art was a brilliantly conceived riff on the answering machine.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/internet-of-things-answering-m.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/internet-of-things-answering-m.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Dominique Pruitt "He's Got It Bad" music video</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/C5ZFPCiAqzE/dominique-pruitt-hes-got-i.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Dominique Pruitt</category><category>music</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 15:39:13 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220219</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--youtu.be--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/O1OhXLw-7TU?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>Here's the wonderful Dominique Pruitt performing "He's Got It Bad."</p>

<p>Previously:</p>

<p><a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/08/31/dominique-pruitt-to-win-your.html">Dominique Pruitt "To Win Your Love" music video</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/C5ZFPCiAqzE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Here's the wonderful Dominique Pruitt performing "He's Got It Bad." Previously: Dominique Pruitt "To Win Your Love" music video</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/dominique-pruitt-hes-got-i.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/dominique-pruitt-hes-got-i.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Supercut of all the alternate endings to the Animaniacs theme</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/ktENFOT4FAs/supercut-of-all-the-alternate.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Video</category><category>animation</category><category>Copyfight</category><category>supercuts</category><category>tv</category><category>videos</category><category>youtube</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 15:33:29 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220010</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--www.youtube.com--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/HCM0jBrEfPw?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>
Here's TammieRD's compilation of all the alternate endings to the Animaniacs theme song, each better than the last. As I mentioned before <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B000O179IQ/downandoutint-20">the complete seasons 1-3 DVDs</a> are a huge hit around our house. Really some of the best kids' (and grownups') TV of the last century. 

<p>
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HCM0jBrEfPw">
Animaniacs alternate theme song lyrical endings
</a>

(<i>Thanks, Fipi Lele!</i>)






<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/ktENFOT4FAs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Here's TammieRD's compilation of all the alternate endings to the Animaniacs theme song, each better than the last.</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/supercut-of-all-the-alternate.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/supercut-of-all-the-alternate.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Why user interfaces should be visible, seamful, and explicit</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/i7mFYaxl4Uc/why-user-interfaces-should-be.html</link><category>Post</category><category>design</category><category>happy mutants</category><category>ui</category><category>ux</category><category>web theory</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 15:29:40 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220007</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<p>
Timo Arnall from the design studio BERG has makes several great and provocative points in his essay "No to NoUI" -- a well-argued piece that opposes the idea of "interfaces that disappear" and "seamless computer interfaces," arguing that by hiding the working of computers from their users, designers make it harder for those users to figure out what the computers are really doing and to solve the problems that inevitably arise.

<blockquote>
<p>
Interfaces are the dominant cultural form of our time. So much of contemporary culture takes place through interfaces and inside UI. Interfaces are part of cultural expression and participation, skeuomorphism is evidence that interfaces are more than chrome around content, and more than tools to solve problems. To declare interfaces ‘invisible’ is to deny them a cultural form or medium. Could we say ‘the best TV is no TV’, the ‘best typography is no typography’ or ‘the best buildings are no architecture’? 
<p>
...We might be better off instead taking our language from typography, and for instance talk about legibility and readability without denying that typography can call attention to itself in beautiful and spectacular ways. Our goal should be to ‘place as much control as possible in the hands of the end-user by making interfaces evident’. 
<p>
Of course the interfaces we design may become normalised in use, effectively invisible over time, but that will only happen if we design them to be legible, readable, understandable and to foreground culture over technology. To build trust and confidence in an interface in the first place, enough that it can comfortably recede into the background.
</blockquote>

<P>
<a href="http://www.elasticspace.com/2013/03/no-to-no-ui">No to NoUI</a>

(<I>via <a href="http://danhon.com/">Dan Hon</a></i>)

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/i7mFYaxl4Uc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Timo Arnall from the design studio BERG has makes several great and provocative points in his essay "No to NoUI" -- a well-argued piece that opposes the idea of "interfaces that disappear" and "seamless computer interfaces," arguing that by hiding the working of computers from their users, designers make it harder for those users to [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/why-user-interfaces-should-be.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/why-user-interfaces-should-be.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Jörg  makes an Oreo-shooting pump-action crossbow</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/5Bo4g6Ppchc/jrg-makes-an-oreo-shoot.html</link><category>Post</category><category>makers</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 14:53:47 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220208</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<!--youtu.be--><div class="video-container"><iframe width="600" height="338" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/vZj5rMECi7A?showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p>The latest from <a href="http://www.slingshotchannel.com/">The Slingshot Channel</a>: an Oreo Separation Pump Gun.</p>

<blockquote>It's a basic human desire to destroy an OREO cookie with a pump action crossbow. Some men simply love neither cookie nor creme, so sometimes a man just needs to invent a badass crossbow to do the hard work of shooting the two from a powerful homemade weapon. Today, that man is meat lover and cookie-destroyer J&ouml;rg Sprave. Watch him operate the repeating 14-shot weapon he created that separates OREO cookies into very fine (but separated) crumbles.</blockquote>

<p><em>(Thanks, Matthew!)</em></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/5Bo4g6Ppchc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>The latest from The Slingshot Channel: an Oreo Separation Pump Gun. It's a basic human desire to destroy an OREO cookie with a pump action crossbow. Some men simply love neither cookie nor creme, so sometimes a man just needs to invent a badass crossbow to do the hard work of shooting the two from [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/jrg-makes-an-oreo-shoot.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/jrg-makes-an-oreo-shoot.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>South London bridge loves Boing Boing</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/tOwiKV9C3NE/south-london-bridge-loves-boin.html</link><category>Post</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 14:36:36 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220206</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8493221634_654bedeacf_c-1.jpg"  class="alignnone"></p>
<p>We <a href="http://www.baggies.com/">&#9829;</a> you, too, South London! (Not that we condone this sort of thing).</p>

<p>(<i>Image: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/delete08/8493221634/">I heart Boing Boing</a>, a Creative Commons <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/deed.en">Attribution Non-Commercial (2.0)</a> image from delete08's photostream</i>)</p>

<p>(Thanks, Luke!<a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/109358237008912109516"></a>)</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/tOwiKV9C3NE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>We &amp;#9829; you, too, South London! (Not that we condone this sort of thing). (Image: I heart Boing Boing, a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial (2.0) image from delete08's photostream) (Thanks, Luke!)</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/south-london-bridge-loves-boin.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/south-london-bridge-loves-boin.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>How chopsticks are made</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/_arlXxi0kis/how-chopsticks-are-made.html</link><category>Post</category><category>chopsticks</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 14:26:13 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220201</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-21-at-2.22.01-PM.jpg" class="alignleft">Len says:

"A post from Xeni about <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/15/eco-headline-of-the-week-disp.html">disposable chopsticks and deforestation</a> reminded me of <a href="http://sc-smn.jst.go.jp/playprg/index/2137">this video</a>.  It's from Japan's version of 'How it's Made.'  It is hard to believe how much hands-on work goes into making them (wait 'til you get to the women at the pile).  Astonishing.  I've never been able to look at them the same since.  Great machine sounds too.  There are quite a few good episodes in there including #228 - <a href="http://sc-smn.jst.go.jp/playprg/index/2329">sumi brush making</a> and <a href="http://sc-smn.jst.go.jp/playprg/index/2190">#156 - kendo armor</a>."</p>


<blockquote>Series "The Making". How will follow the product are made familiar with what kind of technology, we convey the relationship of science and technology and the origins of things. "Chopsticks" theme is. Came to be used generally late Edo period. The reason that there is no need to turn to use, clean and has spread. Raw material is spruce. Birch, willow, cedar, and bamboo is also used for the other. Many white part, spruce is also used in building materials, is suitable for disposable chopsticks. At this plant, three types of disposable chopsticks are made. Chopsticks common "Genroku" The first. Was devised around 1887 - '30, cut the four corners of the chopsticks to make it easier course, also contains a groove in the center for easy assignment. The "cut" Heaven is the second, etc. are used in high-end Japanese restaurant. Cut diagonally (heaven) the end of the hand, I have easy to use by cutting round the tip of a chopstick. "Rikyu" third. In a way that was invented by Sen no Rikyu, was commercialized in the late Meiji period. Land can be used as chopsticks chopsticks to carry both ends mouth heaven and earth have become thin, take heaven, is also used for the tea ceremony, kaiseki.</blockquote>

<p><a href="http://sc-smn.jst.go.jp/seriessearch/result">How It's Made</a></p>

<p>Previously:
</p>
<p><a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/03/08/pickpocket-uses-chopsticks.html">Pickpocket uses chopsticks -- video</a></p>


<p><a href="http://gadgets.boingboing.net/2008/07/31/modern-chopsticks-fo.html">Modern chopsticks for the digitally imbecilic</a></p>

<p><a href="http://gadgets.boingboing.net/2008/03/26/edible-bowls-and-cho.html">Edible Bowls and Chopsticks from Hardtack</a></p>

<p><a href="http://boingboing.net/2005/03/17/chopsticks-safety-yo.html">Chopsticks safety: you are NOT the walrus! Goo goo g'jooob!</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/_arlXxi0kis" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Len says: "A post from Xeni about disposable chopsticks and deforestation reminded me of this video. It's from Japan's version of 'How it's Made.' It is hard to believe how much hands-on work goes into making them (wait 'til you get to the women at the pile). Astonishing. I've never been able to look at [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/how-chopsticks-are-made.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/how-chopsticks-are-made.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>EFF blasts plans to build DRM into HTML5</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/udsn7nH63Us/eff-blasts-plans-to-build-drm.html</link><category>Post</category><category>Copyfight</category><category>drm</category><category>eff</category><category>standards</category><category>web theory</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Cory Doctorow</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 14:22:36 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220003</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[


<p>
The Electronic Frontier Foundation has weighed in on the growing controversy over the proposal to build DRM into HTML5, the next version of the standard language for building Web pages and applications. Staff technologists Seth Schoen and Peter Eckersley have written a great essay explaining how this kind of work is totally incompatible with the mission of the W3C and how its proponents' insistence that this isn't really DRM are just hollow jokes:

<blockquote>
<p>
The EME proposal suffers from many of these problems because it explicitly abdicates responsibilty on compatibility issues and let web sites require specific proprietary third-party software or even special hardware and particular operating systems (all referred to under the generic name "content decryption modules", or CDMs, and none of them specified by EME). EME's authors keep saying that what CDMs are, and do, and where they come from is totally outside of the scope of EME, and that EME itself can't be thought of as DRM because not all CDMs are DRM systems. Yet if the client can't prove it's running the particular proprietary thing the site demands, and hence doesn't have an approved CDM, it can't render the site's content. Perversely, this is exactly the reverse of the reason that the World Wide Web Consortium exists in the first place. W3C is there to create comprehensible, publicly-implementable standards that will guarantee interoperability, not to facilitate an explosion of new mutually-incompatible software and of sites and services that can only be accessed by particular devices or applications. But EME is a proposal to bring exactly that dysfunctional dynamic into HTML5, even risking a return to the "bad old days, before the Web" of deliberately limited interoperability.
<p>
Because it's clear that the open standards community is extremely suspicious of DRM and its interoperability consequences, the proposal from Google, Microsoft and Netflix claims that "[n]o 'DRM' is added to the HTML5 specification" by EME. This is like saying, "we're not vampires, but we are going to invite them into your house".
<p>
Proponents also seem to claim that EME is not itself a DRM scheme. But specification author Mark Watson admitted that "Certainly, our interest is in [use] cases that most people would call DRM" and that implementations would inherently require secrets outside the specification's scope. It's hard to maintain a pretense that EME is about anything but DRM.

</blockquote>

<p>
<a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2013/03/defend-open-web-keep-drm-out-w3c-standards">
Defend the Open Web: Keep DRM Out of W3C Standards
</a>

(<i>via <a href="http://slashdot.org">/.</a></i>)

<p>
<blockquote>
See also:
<p>
* <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/20/html5s-overseer-says-drms.html">HTML5's overseer says DRM's true purpose is to prevent legal forms of innovation</a>
<p>
* <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/12/why-tim-berners-lee-is-wrong-a.html">Why Tim Berners-Lee is wrong about DRM in HTML5</a>
</blockquote>

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/udsn7nH63Us" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>The Electronic Frontier Foundation has weighed in on the growing controversy over the proposal to build DRM into HTML5, the next version of the standard language for building Web pages and applications. Staff technologists Seth Schoen and Peter Eckersley have written a great essay explaining how this kind of work is totally incompatible with the [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/eff-blasts-plans-to-build-drm.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/eff-blasts-plans-to-build-drm.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>The other problem with fake vaccine scares</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/QAHCixNVzyI/the-other-problem-with-fake-va.html</link><category>Short</category><category>evidence-based everything</category><category>health</category><category>medicine</category><category>pseudoscience</category><category>risks</category><category>Science</category><category>vaccines</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maggie Koerth-Baker</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 13:53:37 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220194</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[It's not just that bad information on the "dangers" of vaccines is working to reduce the number of children getting vaccines &mdash; a fact that affects herd immunity. Now, there's evidence that the <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/emilywillingham/2013/03/21/wakefield-driven-vaccine-false-alarm-threatens-real-vaccine-science/">fake scares (and efforts to debunk them) are getting in the way of scientists publishing real evidence about actual problems with certain vaccines</a>. These aren't the kind of broad "vaccines are poison" claims you're familiar with. Instead, we're talking about legitimate science documenting side effects that are usually very rare, but still have an impact on certain subsets of the population and need to be addressed. <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/QAHCixNVzyI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>It's not just that bad information on the "dangers" of vaccines is working to reduce the number of children getting vaccines &amp;#8212; a fact that affects herd immunity. Now, there's evidence that the fake scares (and efforts to debunk them) are getting in the way of scientists publishing real evidence about actual problems with certain [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/the-other-problem-with-fake-va.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/the-other-problem-with-fake-va.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Danny Hillis: The Internet could crash. We need a Plan B</title><link>http://feeds.boingboing.net/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/2W68Ep22F2k/danny-hillis-the-internet-cou.html</link><category>Post</category><category>TED2013</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mark Frauenfelder</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 13:49:41 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://boingboing.net/?p=220195</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://embed.ted.com/talks/danny_hillis_the_internet_could_crash_we_need_a_plan_b.html" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
<p>Carla enjoyed Danny Hillis' presentation at TED2013. Here's how he began the talk:</p>

<blockquote><p>So, this book that I have in my hand is a directory of everybody who had an email address in 1982. (Laughter) Actually, it's deceptively large. There's actually only about 20 people on each page, because we have the name, address and telephone number of every single person. And, in fact, everybody's listed twice, because it's sorted once by name and once by email address. Obviously a very small community. There were only two other Dannys on the Internet then. I knew them both. We didn't all know each other, but we all kind of trusted each other, and that basic feeling of trust permeated the whole network, and there was a real sense that we could depend on each other to do things.</p>

<p>So just to give you an idea of the level of trust in this community, let me tell you what it was like to register a domain name in the early days. Now, it just so happened that I got to register the third domain name on the Internet. So I could have anything I wanted other than bbn.com and symbolics.com. So I picked think.com, but then I thought, you know, there's a lot of really interesting names out there. Maybe I should register a few extras just in case. And then I thought, "Nah, that wouldn't be very nice."</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/danny_hillis_the_internet_could_crash_we_need_a_plan_b.html">Danny Hillis: The Internet could crash. We need a Plan B</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~4/2W68Ep22F2k" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Carla enjoyed Danny Hillis' presentation at TED2013. Here's how he began the talk: So, this book that I have in my hand is a directory of everybody who had an email address in 1982. (Laughter) Actually, it's deceptively large. There's actually only about 20 people on each page, because we have the name, address and [...]</description><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/danny-hillis-the-internet-cou.html/feed</wfw:commentRss><slash:comments xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">0</slash:comments><feedburner:origLink>http://boingboing.net/2013/03/21/danny-hillis-the-internet-cou.html</feedburner:origLink></item></channel></rss>
