<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Apple Hot News</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/hotnews/</link>
<description>Hot News provided by Apple.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013, Apple Inc.</copyright>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 16:02:50 PDT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 16:02:50 PDT</lastBuildDate>
<category>Apple</category>
<generator>In house</generator>
<docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss/</docs><item>
<title>Unlocking the Power of iPad for the Blind </title>
<link>http://www.bloomberg.com/video/unlocking-the-power-of-the-ipad-for-the-blind-~cj884a7S92Nn5qTInjfBg.html</link>
<description>Bloomberg West profiles Ed Summers, who, as head of accessibility at international software company SAS, “has made it his mission to help other visually impaired people unlock the power of the iPad.” Summers is traveling around the United States to teach educators how to maximize the device’s built-in accessibility features in their classrooms. Bloomberg notes that tablets are growing in popularity among educators, and Summers says iPad is “opening up a whole world” for visually impaired students. “We’re working to make sure that students and professionals of all abilities can succeed in the classroom and the 21st-century knowledge economy,” Summers says. </description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 09:34:19 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Takes Laptop Magazine’s Top Rating </title>
<link>http://blog.laptopmag.com/apple-brand-rating </link>
<description>Laptop Magazine has awarded Apple the top prize in 
its Best Brands feature for the fourth year in a row, placing first in five of the eight categories it measures. In addition, the 15-inch MacBook Pro with Retina display took honors as the magazine’s top notebook of 2012, with editors praising the screen, performance, battery life, and design. Software and tech support were also highlighted. “Apple continues to epitomize the best of the best,” say the magazine’s editors.
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 14:53:24 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can the iPad Rescue a Struggling American Education System? </title>
<link>http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2013/03/tablets-revolutionizing-education/ </link>
<description>Across the United States, teachers are using iPad and other tablets to reinvent the presentation and management of educational material. According to 
 a report in Wired magazine, “tablets’ simplicity, ease of use and the massive range of academically minded applications available are drawing teachers and educational technologists to the platform in droves.” iPad is leading this charge, as “the most popular tablet among educators,” and “Apple’s iTunes U is one tool making iPad-based course integration easier by helping teachers create and curate a wholly digital curriculum.”</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 11:36:52 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Launches iBookstore in Japan </title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2013/03/06Apple-Launches-iBookstore-in-Japan.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple has announced the launch of the iBookstore in Japan. The iBookstore has a wide selection of emerging and established authors, including Shyotaro Ikenami, Jiro Akagawa, Atsuko Asano, and Ryu Murakami. “We’re excited to launch the iBookstore in Japan with a wide selection of Japanese publishers and authors,” said Eddy Cue, Apple’s senior vice president of Internet Software and Services. “We think customers are going to love how engaging and interactive the books are to read, and how beautiful they look on iPad.”</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 15:21:58 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Creating New Possibilities in the Classroom with iPad </title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/education/profiles/burlington/#video-burlington?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>With an eye toward helping students navigate the digital world, Burlington High School outside Boston adopted the iPad one-to-one program, which provides every student with an iPad. In its first year, the program has already made a big difference — students say they’re more excited and organized than in previous years, and teachers say they see a deeper level of learning. “Having a say in your education is really powerful,” says one student. “With iPad, you feel like you’re more in charge.”</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 21:03:41 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>iTunes U Content Tops One Billion Downloads </title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2013/02/28iTunes-U-Content-Tops-One-Billion-Downloads.html </link>
<description>Apple announced that iTunes U has reached a new milestone — over one billion content downloads. iTunes U features the world’s largest online catalog of free educational content from top schools and prominent libraries, museums, and organizations. Educators are using this content to create courses that include lectures, assignments, books, quizzes, and more for iOS users around the world. “It’s inspiring to see what educators and students of all types are doing with iTunes U,” said Eddy Cue, Apple’s senior vice president of Internet Software and Services. “With the incredible content offered on iTunes U, students can learn like never before ― there are now iTunes U courses with more than 250,000 students enrolled in them, which is a phenomenal shift in the way we teach and learn.”
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 17:23:49 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fortune Names Apple World’s Most Admired Company for the Sixth Year in a Row </title>
<link>http://money.cnn.com/magazines/fortune/most-admired/2013/snapshots/670.html </link>
<description>In its annual rankings, Fortune magazine has named Apple the world’s most admired company for the sixth year in a row. Fortune calls Apple “a financial juggernaut,” citing Apple’s $13 billion in net income last quarter — earnings that made it the most profitable company in the world during that period. The magazine also applauds Apple’s “fanatical customer base” and the unprecedented success of the iPhone and iPad product lines.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 14:46:05 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>$1.99 iPhone App Saved Oscars Film </title>
<link>http://money.cnn.com/video/technology/2013/02/19/t-iphone-app-oscar-film.cnnmoney </link>
<description>In this video report from CNN, documentary film director Malik Bendjelloul talks about how he used a $1.99 iPhone app to finish shooting his Oscar-nominated film, “Searching for Sugar Man.” The film tracks the rise to fame of the Detroit musician Rodriguez, who never made it big in the United States but became a legend in South Africa. Bendjelloul started shooting the movie on film, but with just a few shots remaining, he found his budget depleted. That’s when he turned to an iPhone app called 8mm by Nexvio, which gave his video a retro feel. “It looks like real film,” says Bendjelloul. “You can’t tell the difference.” “Searching for Sugar Man” has garnered praise at the Tribeca film festival, SXSW Film, and the Los Angeles Film Festival.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 18:06:15 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Updates Processors and Prices of MacBook Pro with Retina Display </title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2013/02/13Apple-Updates-Processors-Prices-of-MacBook-Pro-with-Retina-Display.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple is making the MacBook Pro with Retina display faster and more affordable with updated processors and lower starting prices. The 13-inch MacBook Pro with Retina display now starts at $1,499 for 128GB of flash, and $1,699 for a new 2.6GHz processor and 256GB of flash. The 15-inch MacBook Pro with Retina display now features a faster 2.4GHz quad-core processor, and the top-of-the-line 15-inch notebook comes with a new 2.7GHz quad-core processor and 16GB of memory. Apple also announced that the 13-inch MacBook Air with 256GB of flash has a new lower price of $1,399. The new models are available starting today through the 
Apple Online Store, Apple Retail Stores, and Apple Authorized Resellers.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 11:47:23 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>iTunes Store Sets New Record with 25 Billion Songs Sold</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2013/02/06iTunes-Store-Sets-New-Record-with-25-Billion-Songs-Sold.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple has announced that music fans have purchased and downloaded more than 25 billion songs from the iTunes Store. “We are grateful to our users whose passion for music over the past 10 years has made iTunes the number one music retailer in the world,” said Eddy Cue, Apple’s senior vice president of Internet Software and Services. The 25 billionth song, “Monkey Drums” (Goksel Vancin Remix) by Chase Buch, was purchased by Phillip Lüpke from Germany. As the downloader of the 25 billionth song, Phillip will receive a €10,000 iTunes gift card. </description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 17:39:23 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Re-Enabled</title>
<link>http://the-magazine.org/9/re-enabled</link>
<description>Steven Aquino, who works with children with special needs and is himself visually impaired, describes in The Magazine how accessibility technologies like VoiceOver and Guided Access built into iOS “let those with disabilities use their devices with as much wonder and enjoyment as the fully abled.” Calling iOS “nothing short of a godsend,” Aquino notes that with iPad, a cognitively delayed student is able to “tap and swipe like a pro” and even master multitasking gestures without any demoing or prompting. He concludes: “Every time I pick up my 
iPhone or iPad, I feel extremely fortunate that I’m living in this time.”</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 17:39:46 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Smartphones May Be the Key to Better Health Care</title>
<link>http://rockcenter.nbcnews.com/_news/2013/01/24/16677207-the-key-to-better-health-care-may-already-be-in-your-pocket-and-its-not-your-wallet</link>
<description>The best tool to improve and keep track of your health may be in your pocket, says Dr. Eric Topol, a pioneering figure in “wireless medicine” — the practice of using apps and devices in health care. An article from NBC News describes how new apps for 
iPhone and other devices can measure vital signs and even detect whether someone is having a heart attack. “These days, I’m prescribing a lot more apps than I am medications,” says Dr. Topol. “The smartphone will be the hub of the future of medicine.”</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 10:30:37 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Reports First Quarter Results </title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2013/01/23Apple-Reports-Record-Results.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple announced financial results for its 13-week fiscal 2013 first quarter ended December 29, 2012. The company posted record quarterly revenue of $54.5 billion and record quarterly net profit of $13.1 billion, or $13.81 per diluted share. These results compare to revenue of $46.3 billion and net profit of $13.1 billion, or $13.87 per diluted share, in the 14-week year-ago quarter. “We’re thrilled with record revenue of over $54 billion and sales of over 75 million iOS devices in a single quarter,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “We’re very confident in our product pipeline as we continue to focus on innovation and making the best products in the world.”
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 17:45:04 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jorge Colombo’s iPad Finger Paintings </title>
<link>http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/culture/2013/01/cover-story-finger-paintings.html#slide_ss_0=1</link>
<description>The cover of the January 28 issue of The New Yorker features 
work by Jorge Colombo, an artist who creates his pieces exclusively on the iPad. He started out in 2009 working on the iPhone, but now enjoys the larger format of the iPad. “I became more proficient on the tablet and started using more lines and more detail,” he says. His illustration for The New Yorker, titled “Newsstand,” is the first piece Colombo created on the iPad. </description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 11:33:26 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>App Store Tops 40 Billion Downloads with Almost Half in 2012 </title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2013/01/07App-Store-Tops-40-Billion-Downloads-with-Almost-Half-in-2012.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple has announced that customers have downloaded over 40 billion apps — nearly 20 billion in 2012 alone. The App Store has over 500 million active accounts and had a record-breaking December with over two billion downloads during the month. Eddy Cue, Apple’s senior vice president of Internet Software and Services, says, “It has been an incredible year for the iOS developer community.” Developers have created over 775,000 apps for iPhone, iPad, and iPod touch and have been paid over $7 billion by Apple. </description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 11:48:44 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>iPhone 5 First Weekend Sales in China Top Two Million</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2012/12/16iPhone-5-First-Weekend-Sales-in-China-Top-Two-Million.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple today announced it has sold over two million of its new 
iPhone 5 in China, just three days after its launch on December 14. “Customer response to iPhone 5 in China has been incredible, setting a new record with the best first weekend sales ever in China,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. iPhone 5 will be available in more than 100 countries by the end of December, making it the fastest iPhone rollout ever. </description>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 17:00:05 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>iPhone 5 is Time Magazine’s ‘Gadget of the Year’</title>
<link>http://techland.time.com/2012/12/04/top-10-tech-lists/slide/iphone-5/</link>
<description>Time Magazine has named iPhone 5 its Gadget of the Year for 2012. The device is “one of the most artfully polished gadgets anyone’s ever built,” says Time’s Harry McCracken. He highlights the new thinner design and the camera’s “particularly well-done panorama mode.” McCracken concludes, “[W]hen it comes to melding hardware, software and services so tightly that the seams fade away, Apple still has no peer.” The 
MacBook Pro with Retina display also made it onto the list at number six.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 11:54:01 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple iMac Review: A Reason to Get a Desktop Computer</title>
<link>http://abcnews.go.com/Technology/apple-imac-2012-review-reason-desktop/story?id=17847986#</link>
<description>Reviewing the new iMac on ABC News, Joanna Stern says the desktop has “as much sex appeal” as iPad and iPhone. “Even if you aren’t a tech enthusiast,” Stern writes, “this is a machine — or perhaps sculpture — you can admire.” Stern says the improved display’s sharpness makes looking at photos and video “an immersive experience,” and she praises the iMac’s enhanced computing power, including Fusion Drive. “Apple has built the system with the most powerful desktop parts around,” she says.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 12:02:02 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>PC Mag: iMac is Editor’s Choice</title>
<link>http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2412808,00.asp</link>
<description>PC Mag has added Apple’s new iMac to its Editor’s Choice list for high-end all-in-one desktops. Reviewer Brian Westover says the iMac is “faster and more responsive, offering larger, smarter storage.” He put the iMac through its paces with a number of media and processing tests and found that it led competitors by a healthy margin. He concludes, “With its beautiful design and quality fabrication, the iMac 27-inch is the best all-in-one desktop we’ve ever seen.”</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 12:00:16 PST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Puts Eye into iDevices</title>
<link>http://www.smh.com.au/digital-life/computers/apple-puts-eye-into-idevices-20121128-2acch.html</link>
<description>Reporting in the Sydney Morning Herald, Garry Barker describes how Apple accessibility technology has enabled disabled users to thrive both personally and professionally. Barker tells the story of David Woodbridge, a technology manager for a large non-profit who has been blind since childhood. Woodbridge uses VoiceOver and other assistive technologies in Apple’s iOS devices daily. “With VoiceOver I can support not only myself but also my boys and my wife,” said Woodbridge. “For example, if my wife gets an SMS when she is driving I can call up VoiceOver on her iPhone to read the message to her and we can reply using Siri, which is one of the great iOS developments, getting better all the time.”</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 17:30:49 PST</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>