<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Climate Audit</title>
	<atom:link href="http://climateaudit.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://climateaudit.org</link>
	<description>by Steve McIntyre</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 15:33:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='climateaudit.org' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Climate Audit</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://climateaudit.org/osd.xml" title="Climate Audit" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://climateaudit.org/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Bent Their Core Tops In</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 17:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birdmen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marcott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[md01-2421]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MD95-2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MD95-2043]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OCE326-GGC30]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17592</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In today&#8217;s post, I&#8217;m going to show Marcott-Shakun redating in several relevant cases. The problem, as I&#8217;ve said on numerous occasions, has nothing to do with the very slight recalibration of radiocarbon dates from CALIB 6.0.1 (essentially negligible in the modern period in discussion here), but with Marcott-Shakun core top redating. Marcott et al re-dating [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17592&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In today&#8217;s post, I&#8217;m going to show Marcott-Shakun redating in several relevant cases. The problem, as I&#8217;ve said on numerous occasions, has nothing to do with the very slight recalibration of radiocarbon dates from CALIB 6.0.1 (essentially negligible in the modern period in discussion here), but with Marcott-Shakun core top redating. <span id="more-17592"></span></p>
<p>Marcott et al re-dating appears to originate from the following:</p>
<blockquote><p>Core tops are assumed to be 1950 AD unless otherwise indicated in original publication.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>MD95-2043<br />
</strong><br />
The most recent radiocarbon date for this core was at 14 cm. The radiocarbon reading (1980) was converted by the authors using CALIB4.1to 1527BP.  Marcott showed CALIB 6.0.1 upper and lower bounds, the average of which was 1535BP. Marcott showed a date of 1535BP for the alkenone sample at 14 cm.  The differences between CALIB4.1 calibrated dates and CALIB6.0.1 calibrated dates in the last two millennia are negligible &#8211; single digit years.  </p>
<p>The sedimentation rate between the final two radiocarbon points of MD95-2043 was 26.7 cm/kyr.  The original authors (Cacho et al 1999;2001) dated samples above the most recent radiocarbon date by assuming a continuation of these sedimentation rates, thus interpreting the top 14 cm as covering the period from 1537BP to a coretop of 1007.6 BP.  This implies core loss from the piston core of about 26 cm, a fairly typical result.  (Box cores are used when recovery of surface sediments is desired.)   </p>
<p>In contrast, Marcott et al 2013 dated the coretop to 0BP (1950 AD) and interpolated dates back to the radiocarbon date at 14 cm.  In effect, Marcott et al presumed that the sedimentation had fallen to one-third of previously observed rates (&#8220;unprecedented&#8221;?). The difference is shown in the graphic below, which compares the age-depth according to the original authors to the age-depth of Marcott et al. It shows that there is negligible difference between published and Marcott radiocarbon dates. </p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md95-2043.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md95-2043.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="age depth MD95-2043" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17588" /></a></p>
<p>The next graphic compares the temperature estimates using published dates to temperature estimates using Marcott et al dates. The two are essentially identical up to just before AD500. But whereas the original authors date the next few cm to late first millennium,  Marcott et al dilate the data to go from AD500 to AD1950, reassigning the core top from AD943 to AD1950.</p>
<p>Marcott state in their archive &#8211; in my opinion, with unwarranted optimism  &#8211; that there is zero uncertainty in the 0 BP dating of the core top.  </p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md95-2043-recent.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md95-2043-recent.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="MD95-2043 recent" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17589" /></a><br />
Figure 2. MD95-2043 Temperature Estimates. </p>
<p>I do not take the position that non-specialists such as Marcott, Shakun, Clark and Mix are precluded from arguing that core dating by the original authors was incorrect and proposing their own alternative dating with the reasons laid out in the sunshine for relevant specialists to assess. However, that&#8217;s not what happened here.  There was no listing of re-dated cores with the before and after core top dates.  The only hint of anything going on with core tops was the following statement in the SI: </p>
<blockquote><p>Core tops are assumed to be 1950 AD unless otherwise indicated in original publication.</p></blockquote>
<p>This seems innocuous enough on the surface, but that&#8217;s not what Marcott et al actually did.  For example, here is an excerpt from the NOAA MD95-2043 archive, where the core top is indicated to be 1007.6 BP. </p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md95-2043-excerpt.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md95-2043-excerpt.png?w=526&#038;h=142" alt="MD95-2043 excerpt" width="526" height="142" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17597" /></a></p>
<p><strong>MD95-2011</strong><br />
That core loss at surface in piston cores can be 26 cm or so should not be any surprise. Indeed, it seems to me to be a credit to the carefulness of the drillers that core losses are as low as this.  Core loss in piston cores can be approximately estimated if there is a contiguous box core. (Box cores don&#8217;t go as deep as piston cores, but have much better recovery of near-surface sediments.)</p>
<p>MD95-2011, used twice by Marcott et al (#8 and #13), is another piston core, but in this case, there is a contiguous box core JM97-948-2A.  These cores were discussed at CA in 2007 in connection with Loehle 2007.  At the time, Richard Telford mentioned that he thought that alkenone results for JM97-948-2A had been measured but not published. They remain unpublished six years later: this is too bad as this would have provided an important addition to very scarce high-resolution alkenone records.</p>
<p>Pb210 dating confirmed the modernity of the top 10 cm of box core JM-948-2A, which was dated from 5-80 BP (1870-1945AD.)  At 30.5 cm, box core JM-948-2A had a radiocarbon calibrated date of 579BP (radiocarbon 940BP), while MD95-2011 had a near contemporary date at 10.5 cm (601 BP &#8211; radiocarbon 980 BP).  The data from the box core clearly indicates core loss of somewhat more than 20 cm at MD95-2011.  </p>
<p>The original authors dated the 10.5 cm of MD95-2011 above the latest radiocarbon date to approximately 50 years, assigning the core top to 510 BP.  In contrast, Marcott et al assigned the core top to 0 BP, using the same methodology as MD95-2043. This is illustrated in the age-depth comparisons shown below.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md95-2011.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md95-2011.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="age-depth MD95-2011" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17590" /></a><br />
Figure 3. MD95-2011 and JM97-948-2A age-depth diagram.</p>
<p>As with MD95-2043, the Marcott re-dating dilates the time series after 560BP, so that data assigned by the original authors to 510BP is Marcott-dated to 0BP.</p>
<p><strong>MD01-2421 Splice </strong><br />
The above two examples illustrate one face of Marcott et al re-dating. However, there is a second and even more puzzling aspect: their re-dating of cores which actually do have 20th century samples.</p>
<p>I started analysis of this in my post two days ago in which I drew attention to Marcott et al&#8217;s truncation of the final three (highly negative) values of the MD01-2421 splice. MD01-2421 is a piston core with considerable core loss. It was combined with contiguous gravity and box cores to yield a continuous record into the 20th century. The modernity of the top portion of the box core was unequivocally confirmed by the presence of a bomb spike, a commonly used marker. Out of all the ocean cores in the Marcott network, this series undoubtedly has the best dated modern material.</p>
<p>In the graphic below, I&#8217;ve compared the age-depth diagrams from the original information to Marcott&#8217;s re-dating.  As noted yesterday, the three most recent values are truncated from Marcott calculations. Oddly the other recent values are dated somewhat younger by Marcott. The sample dated to 1922 AD by Isono et al is dated to 1939AD by Marcott (just missing inclusion in the 1940 roster.) I have no idea what they&#8217;re doing here.  It is possible that some algorithm has gone awry (as opposed to Briffa&#8217;s manual deletion &#8211; commonly and incorrectly described as &#8220;MIke&#8217;s Nature trick&#8221;).   Again, I am presently mystified.  I emailed Marcott for an explanation yesterday, but thus far no response.  In my next example, I&#8217;ll look at a related series for further clues.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md01-2421-splice.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md01-2421-splice.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="age depth MD01-2421 splice" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17594" /></a></p>
<p><strong>OCE326-GGC300</strong><br />
OCE326-GGC300 was identified in an earlier post as one of two highly negative proxies (the MD01-2421 splice was the other) that had been disappeared from the 1940 network, the removal of which &#8220;explained&#8221; the 1940 uptick in the alkenone and dependent reconstructions.</p>
<p>This series was published by Julian Sachs, an accomplished specialist. Radiocarbon dates at 0, 2.5 and 12.5 cm all have &#8220;modern&#8221; radiocarbon dates &#8211; dates that are not further resolvable using radiocarbon.  (In passing, Pb210 dating on this core would be very useful.)  Sachs showed a date of 0 BP for all measurements between 0 and 12.5 cm in his archive <a href="ftp://ftp.ncdc.noaa.gov/pub/data/paleo/contributions_by_author/sachs2007/sachs2007.txt">here</a> and in a summary <a href="ftp://ftp.ncdc.noaa.gov/pub/data/paleo/paleocean/sediment_files/complete/o326gc30-fwc.txt">here</a> dated the coretop (0.5 cm) to 0BP, an assumption that on its face is identical to the declared methodology of Marcott et al. </p>
<p>However, once again, the Marcott calculation truncated the most recent values. The diagram below is an attempt to summarize the information.  The black line shows the Sachs age-depth diagram from <a href="ftp://ftp.ncdc.noaa.gov/pub/data/paleo/paleocean/sediment_files/complete/o326gc30-fwc.txt">here</a> with the coretop (0.5 cm) dated to 0 BP. The black + points show the sample measurements as reported (with unresolved &#8220;modern&#8221; samples).  The red horizontal arrows show the radiocarbon upper and lower dates as archived by Marcott et al.  Marcott&#8217;s archive also shows radiocarbon dates for 0.5 cm and 2.5 cm which have been set to NA (shown here in blue.)   The most recent sample used in the Marcott calculation came from 12.5 cm, with the seven higher samples being excluded.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oce326-ggc30-age-depth1.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oce326-ggc30-age-depth1.png?w=560&#038;h=480" alt="OCE326-GGC30 age depth" width="560" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17599" /></a><br />
Figure ^.  OCE326-GGC Age- Depth Diagram.</p>
<p>The next diagram compares the two versions as time-temperature plots, as shown below. (Note that Published is black this time and Marcott red.)  If the coretop were dated at 0 BP and dates for samples between 0.5 and 16.5 cm interpolated, this would yield a series continuing to the present, with alkenone-indicated temperatures continuing to decline (for whatever reason.)  Instead, Marcott&#8217;s series ends in the late 18th century and does not contribute to the 20th century network (which is primarily composed of coretops from different centuries and even millennia.)  </p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oce326-ggc30-recent.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oce326-ggc30-recent.png?w=680&#038;h=480" alt="OCE326-GGC30 recent" width="680" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17600" /></a><br />
Figure ^. OCE326-GGC30 Temperature Reconstruction Comparison. Black- published; red &#8211; Marcott; blue- excluded.</p>
<p><strong>Summary</strong><br />
Both types of example result in serious errors, though of different types. </p>
<p>At this stage, I can more or less see what they did in the MD95-2043 class of examples. As noted above, if this was done intentionally and with knowledge of the effect of the re-dating on coretop dates, this should have been disclosed with red letter caveats, showing the effect of the redating on affected cores and relevant specialists should have been asked to review the reasonableness of the methodology. (I do not believe that a properly informed specialist would have signed off on this redating, let alone with no caveats.)  Nor do I believe that the actual calculations are consistent with the methodological statement &#8220;core tops are assumed to be 1950 AD unless otherwise indicated in original publication&#8221;, since core tops were re-dated to 1950 regardless of what was indicated in the original publication.  This seems just as serious to me as the problem with Gergis et al.</p>
<p>The problems with the cores with actual modern values are over and above this.  I don&#8217;t think that they manually blanked out modern values (I hope not for their sakes.) I presume that some algorithm went awry, but right now I can&#8217;t picture what sort of algorithm would yield the observed truncations.  I&#8217;m sure that we&#8217;ll find out in due course. As noted above, I&#8217;ve requested an explanation from Marcott and hopefully he will clarify things.</p>
<p>Not unexpectedly, William Connolley&#8217;s <a href="http://scienceblogs.com/stoat/2013/03/11/a-reconstruction-of-regional-and-global-temperature-for-the-past-11300-years/#comment-28436">reaction</a> to the problems with Marcott dating is the same sort of wilful obtuseness that characterized &#8220;professional&#8221; responses to Mann&#8217;s use of contaminated (and upside down) Korttajarvi sediments.   Connolley pretended that this is nothing more than recalibration of radiocarbon dates. </p>
<blockquote><p>If you think the &#8220;secret&#8221; of re-dating comes from &#8220;McIntyre&#8217;s latest analysis&#8221; you&#8217;ve been sold a pup. The re-dating is in the SOM itself: The majority of our age-control points are based on radiocarbon dates. In order to 67 compare the records appropriately, we recalibrated all radiocarbon dates.</p>
<p>So I&#8217;m curious &#8211; who sold you this pup? And why didn&#8217;t you bother check the original? -W]</p></blockquote>
<p>On the hand, Paul Dennis, in a thoughtful comment at Bishop Hill, had no difficulty in understanding the difference between core top redating and radiocarbon calibration.</p>
<blockquote><p>One can only guess at what Marcott et al were attempting to do when they made gross adjustments to core top dates. It is one thing to run a new, for example 14-C calibration, that will make small adjustments to age models but a completely different issue to redetermine core top dates by such gross margins.
</p></blockquote>
<p>As to the title of this post.  I was reminded a few weeks ago of the &#8220;Junior Birdmen&#8221; ditty, which was sung at YMCA and Cubs and camps in the 1950s &#8211; a ditty that seemed especially apt for Upside Down Mann, who serves as inspiration for Marcott and Shakun. Its chorus goes:</p>
<blockquote><p>Up in the air&#8230; the Junior Birdmen<br />
Up in the air and upside down<br />
UP in the air&#8230; the Junior Birdmen<br />
Keep their helmets to the ground</p></blockquote>
<p>The Junior Birdmen were apprentice pilots who were flying upside down. The verse talks about &#8220;box tops&#8221;, which slightly modified to the present circumstances:</p>
<blockquote><p>
And when they make&#8230; the grand announcement,<br />
That things are worse than they&#8217;ve ever been&#8230;<br />
You can be sure&#8230; the Junior Birdmen<br />
Have bent their core tops in.</p>
<p>Up in the air&#8230; the Junior Birdmen<br />
Up in the air and upside down<br />
UP in the air&#8230; the Junior Birdmen<br />
Keep their helmets to the ground</p></blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17592/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17592/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17592&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>246</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md95-2043.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">age depth MD95-2043</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md95-2043-recent.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">MD95-2043 recent</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md95-2043-excerpt.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">MD95-2043 excerpt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md95-2011.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">age-depth MD95-2011</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md01-2421-splice.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">age depth MD01-2421 splice</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oce326-ggc30-age-depth1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">OCE326-GGC30 age depth</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oce326-ggc30-recent.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">OCE326-GGC30 recent</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hiding the Decline: MD01-2421</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/17/hiding-the-decline-the-md01-2421-splice/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/17/hiding-the-decline-the-md01-2421-splice/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 16:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alkenone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marcott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[md01-2421]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17576</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As noted in my previous post, Marcott, Shakun, Clark and Mix disappeared two alkenone cores from the 1940 population, both of which were highly negative. In addition, they made some surprising additions to the 1940 population, including three cores whose coretops were dated by competent specialists 500-1000 years earlier. While the article says that ages [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17576&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As noted in my previous post, Marcott, Shakun, Clark and Mix disappeared two alkenone cores from the 1940 population, both of which were highly negative. In addition, they made some surprising additions to the 1940 population, including three cores whose coretops were dated by competent specialists 500-1000 years earlier. </p>
<p>While the article says that ages were recalibrated with CALIB6.0.1, the differences between CALIB6.0.1 and previous radiocarbon calibrations is <strong>not</strong> material to the coretop dating issues being discussed here.  Further, Marcott&#8217;s thesis used CALIB6.0.1, but had very different coretop dates.  Marcott et al stated in their SI that &#8220;Core tops are assumed to be 1950 AD unless otherwise indicated in original publication&#8221;. This is not the procedure that I&#8217;ve observed in the data.  Precisely what they&#8217;ve done is still unclear, but it&#8217;s something different. </p>
<p>In today&#8217;s post, I&#8217;ll examine their proxy #23, an alkenone series of Isono et al 2009. This series is a composite of a piston core (MD01-2421), a gravity core (KR02-06 St. A GC) and a box/multiple core (KR02-06 St A MC1), all taken at the same location.  Piston cores are used for deep time, but lose the top portion of the core. Coretops of piston cores can be hundreds or even a few thousand years old.  Box cores are shallow cores and the presently preferred technique for recovering up-to-date results.</p>
<p>There are vanishingly few alkenone series where there is a high-resolution box core accompanying Holocene data. Indeed, within the entire Marcott corpus of ocean cores, the MD01-241/KNR02-06 splice is unique in being dated nearly to the present. Its published end date was -41BP (1991AD). Convincing support for modern dating of the top part of the box core is the presence of a bomb spike: </p>
<blockquote><p>
A sample from 3 cm depth in the MC core showed a bomb spike. The high sedimentation rate (average 31 cm/ka) over the last 7000 years permits analysis at multidecade resolution with an average sample spacing of ~32 years.</p></blockquote>
<p>Despite this evidence for modern sediments, Marcott et al blanked out the top three measurements as shown below:</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md01-2421-excerpt.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md01-2421-excerpt.png?w=484&#038;h=126" alt="md01-2421 excerpt" width="484" height="126" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17577" /></a><br />
Table 1. Excerpt from Marcott et al spreadsheet</p>
<p>By blanking out the three most recent values of their proxy #23, the earliest dated value was 10.93 BP (1939.07 AD). As a result, the MD01-2421+KNR02-06 alkenone series was excluded from the 1940 population. I am unable to locate any documented methodology that would lead to the blanking out of the last three values of this dataset. Nor am I presently aware of any rational basis for excluding the three most recent values. </p>
<p>Since this series was strongly negative in the 20th century, its removal (together with the related removal of OCE326-GGC30 and the importation of medieval data) led to the closing uptick.</p>
<p>BTW in the original publication, Isono et al 2009 reported a decrease in SST from Holocene to modern times that is much larger than the Marcott NHX estimate of less than 1 deg C, reporting as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>
the SST decreased by ~5 °C to the present (16.7 °C), with high-frequency variations of ~1 °C amplitude (Fig. 2).</p></blockquote>
<p>A plot of this series is shown below, with the &#8220;present&#8221; value reported by Isono et al shown as a red dot.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md03-2421-splice.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md03-2421-splice.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="MD03-2421 splice" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17578" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17576/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17576/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17576&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/17/hiding-the-decline-the-md01-2421-splice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>237</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md01-2421-excerpt.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">md01-2421 excerpt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md03-2421-splice.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">MD03-2421 splice</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Marcott-Shakun Dating Service</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/16/the-marcott-shakun-dating-service/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/16/the-marcott-shakun-dating-service/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 18:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marcott]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17557</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Marcott, Shakun, Clark and Mix did not use the published dates for ocean cores, instead substituting their own dates. The validity of Marcott-Shakun re-dating will be discussed below, but first, to show that the re-dating &#8220;matters&#8221; (TM-climate science), here is a graph showing reconstructions using alkenones (31 of 73 proxies) in Marcott style, comparing the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17557&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marcott, Shakun, Clark and Mix did not use the published dates for ocean cores, instead substituting their own dates. The validity of Marcott-Shakun re-dating will be discussed below, but first, to show that the re-dating &#8220;matters&#8221; (TM-climate science), here is a graph showing reconstructions using alkenones (31 of 73 proxies) in Marcott style, comparing the results with published dates (red) to results with Marcott-Shakun dates (black). As you see, there is a persistent decline in the alkenone reconstruction in the 20th century using published dates, but a 20th century increase using Marcott-Shakun dates.  (It is taking all my will power not to make an obvious comment at this point.)<br />
<a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-comparison1.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-comparison1.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="alkenone-comparison" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17565" /></a><br />
Figure 1. Reconstructions from alkenone proxies in Marcott style. Red- using published dates; black- using Marcott-Shakun dates.</p>
<p>Marcott et al archived an alkenone reconstruction. There are discrepancies between the above emulation and the archived reconstruction, a topic that I&#8217;ll return to on another occasion. (I&#8217;ve tried diligently to reconcile, but am thus far unable. Perhaps due to some misunderstanding on my part of Marcott methodology, some inconsistency between data as used and data as archived or something else.)  However, I do not believe that this matters for the purposes of using my emulation methodology to illustrate the effect of Marcott-Shakun re-dating.</p>
<p><strong>ALkenone Core Re-dating<br />
</strong><br />
The table below summarizes Marcott-Shakun redating for all alkenone cores with either published end-date or Marcott end-date being less than 50 BP (AD1900). I&#8217;ve also shown the closing temperature of each series (&#8220;close&#8221;) after the two Marcot re-centering steps (as I understand them).<br />
<a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-core-redating-table1.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-core-redating-table1.png?w=439&#038;h=208" alt="alkenone core redating table" width="439" height="208" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17568" /></a></p>
<p>The final date of the Marcott reconstruction is AD1940 (BP10). Only three cores contributed to the final value of the reconstruction with published dates ( &#8220;pubend&#8221; less than 10): the MD01-2421 splice, OCE326-GGC30 and M35004-4.  Two of these cores have very negative values. Marcot et al re-dated both of these cores so that neither contributed to the closing period:  the MD01-2421 splice to a fraction of a year prior to 1940, barely missing eligibility; OCE326-GGC30 is re-dated 191 years earlier &#8211; into the 18th century.  </p>
<p>Re-populating the closing date are 5 cores with published coretops earlier than AD10, in some cases much earlier.  The coretop of MD95-2043, for example, was published as 10th century, but was re-dated by Marcott over 1000 years later to &#8220;0 BP&#8221;. MD95-2011 and MD-2015 were redated by 510 and 690 years respectively.  All five re-dated cores contributing to the AD1940 reconstruction had positive values.  </p>
<p>In a follow-up post, I&#8217;ll examine the validity of Marcott-Shakun redating. If the relevant specialists had been aware of or consulted on the Marcott-Shakun redating, I&#8217;m sure that they would have contested it.</p>
<p>Jean S had observed that the Marcott thesis had already described a re-dating of the cores using CALIB 6.0.1 as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>All radiocarbon based ages were recalibrated with CALIB 6.0.1 using INTCAL09 and its protocol (Reimer, 2009) for the site-specific locations and materials. Marine reservoir ages were taken from the originally published manuscripts.</p></blockquote>
<p>The SI to Marcott et al made an essentially identical statement (pdf, 8):</p>
<blockquote><p>The majority of our age-control points are based on radiocarbon dates. In order to compare the records appropriately, we recalibrated all radiocarbon dates with Calib 6.0.1 using INTCAL09 and its protocol (1) for the site-specific locations and materials. Any reservoir ages used in the ocean datasets followed the original authors’ suggested values, and were held constant unless otherwise stated in the original publication.</p></blockquote>
<p>However, the re-dating described above is SUBSEQUENT to the Marcott thesis. (I&#8217;ve confirmed this by examining plots of individual proxies on pages 200-201 of the thesis.  End dates illustrated in the thesis correspond more or less to published end dates and do not reflect the wholesale redating of the Science article.</p>
<p>I was unable to locate any reference to the wholesale re-dating in the text of Marcott et al 2013. The closest thing to a mention is the following statement in the SI:</p>
<blockquote><p>Core tops are assumed to be 1950 AD unless otherwise indicated in original publication.
</p></blockquote>
<p>However, something more than this is going on.  In some cases, Marcott et al have re-dated core tops indicated as 0 BP in the original publication. (Perhaps with justification, but this is not reported.)  In other cases, core tops have been assigned to 0 BP even though different dates have been reported in the original publication.  In another important case (of YAD061 significance as I will later discuss), Marcott et al ignored a major dating caveat of the original publication.</p>
<p>Examination of the re-dating of individual cores will give an interesting perspective on the cores themselves &#8211; an issue that, in my opinion, ought to have been addressed in technical terms by the authors. More on this in a forthcoming post.</p>
<p>The moral of today&#8217;s post for ocean cores. Are you an ocean core that is tired of your current date? Does your current date make you feel too old? Or does it make you feel too young?  Try the Marcott-Shakun dating service. Ashley Madison for ocean cores.  Confidentiality is guaranteed.  </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17557/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17557/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17557&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/16/the-marcott-shakun-dating-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>272</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-comparison1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alkenone-comparison</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-core-redating-table1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alkenone core redating table</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Marcottian Upticks Arise</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/how-marcottian-upticks-arise/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/how-marcottian-upticks-arise/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 22:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marcott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uptick]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17543</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m working towards a post on the effect of Marcott re-dating, but first I want to document some points on the methodology of Marcott et al 2013 and to remove some speculation on the Marcott upticks, which do not arise from any of the main speculations. In the graphic below, I&#8217;ve plotted Marcott&#8217;s NHX reconstruction [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17543&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m working towards a post on the effect of Marcott re-dating, but first I want to document some points on the methodology of Marcott et al 2013 and to remove some speculation on the Marcott upticks, which do not arise from any of the main speculations. </p>
<p>In the graphic below, I&#8217;ve plotted Marcott&#8217;s NHX reconstruction against an emulation (weighting by latitude and gridcell as described in script) using proxies with <strong>published</strong> dates rather than Marcott dates. (I am using this version because it illustrates the uptick using Marcott methodology. Marcott re-dating is an important issue that I will return to.)  The uptick in the emulation occurs in 2000 rather than 1940; the slight offset makes it discernible for sharp eyes below.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/emulation-nh.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/emulation-nh.png?w=680&#038;h=380" alt="emulation -NH" width="680" height="380" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17544" /></a><br />
Figure 1. Marcott NHX reconstruction (red) versus emulation with non-redated proxies (yellow). The dotted lines at the left show the Younger Dryas. Marcott began their reported results shortly after the rapid emergence from the Younger Dryas, which is not shown in the graphics.</p>
<p>I have consistently discouraged speculation that the Marcott uptick arose from splicing Mannian data or temperature data. I trust that the above demonstration showing a Marcottian uptick merely using proxy data will put an end to such speculation. </p>
<p>The other &#8220;explanation&#8221; is that the uptick results from high-frequency swings in individual proxies. Marcott&#8217;s email to me encouraged such speculation. However, this is <strong>NOT</strong> what causes the uptick. Below I show the series that contribute to the NHX weighted average before and after the uptick.  The proxy values shown below have been re-centered to reflect Marcott recentering: (1) by -0.66 deg C to reflect the re-centering from mid-Holocene to 500-1450AD; (2) by -0.08 deg C to match the observed mean of Marcottian reconstructions in 500-1450 AD. </p>
<p>Readers will observe that there are 6 contributing series in the second-last step, of which 5 are negative, some strongly. Their weighted average is negative (not quite as negative as the penultimate Marcott value in 1920, but you see the effect.)  Only one series is present in the final step, one that, after the two rescaling steps, is slightly positive. Thus, the uptick. None of the contributing series have sharp high-frequency: their changes are negligible. Ironically, the one continuing series (Lake 850) actually goes down a little in the period of the uptick.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-nh-unredated.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-nh-unredated.png?w=636&#038;h=79" alt="excerpt nh unredated" width="636" height="79" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17547" /></a></p>
<p>Marcottian <del datetime="2013-03-15T21:59:11+00:00">uptricks</del> upticks arise because of proxy inconsistency: one (or two) proxies have different signs or quantities than the larger population, but continue one step longer. This is also the reason why the effect is mitigated in the infilled variation.  In principle, downticks can also occur &#8211; a matter that will be covered in my next post which will probably be on the relationship between Marcottian re-dating and upticks.</p>
<p>I have been unable to replicate some of the recent features of the Marcott zonal reconstructions. I think that there may be some differences in some series between the data as archived and as used in their reported calculations, though it may be a difference in methodology. More on this later.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17543/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17543/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17543&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/how-marcottian-upticks-arise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>77</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/emulation-nh.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">emulation -NH</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-nh-unredated.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">excerpt nh unredated</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CG3: The Gold Medalist</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/cg3-the-gold-medalist/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/cg3-the-gold-medalist/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 21:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cg3]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17539</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last summer during the London Olympics, Josh had some fun with the &#8220;Climate Olympics&#8221;, with Mann at left in the iconic gold medal pose of Usain Bolt, the famous runner. Little did we know that during an earlier Olympics, Jones was disappointed at being silver medalist in statistical abuse &#8211; to gold medalist Mann. CG3 [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17539&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bolt_mann.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bolt_mann.png?w=360" alt="bolt_mann" width="360" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-17540" /></a>  Last summer during the London Olympics, Josh had some fun with the &#8220;Climate Olympics&#8221;, with Mann at left in the iconic gold medal pose of Usain Bolt, the famous runner.</p>
<p>Little did we know that during an earlier Olympics, Jones was disappointed at being silver medalist in statistical abuse &#8211; to gold medalist Mann.  CG3 1093965453:</p>
<blockquote><p>date: Tue Aug 31 11:17:33 2004<br />
from: Phil Jones
<p>
subject: Fwd: On the Role of Statistics in Climate Research, Tim Lambert, Phil Jones et al?<br />
to: Rasmus Benestad </p>
<p>    Rasmus and Mike,<br />
…<br />
In the email below, Mike seems to have won the gold medal for statistical abuse and I have the silver. I seemed to have tried too hard to explain my techniques. I tried really hard to get the gold medal &#8211; Mike has a degree in maths/stats ! I&#8217;ll have to redeem myself in AR4 and switch the places for the 2008 Olympiad &#8211; the AR4 coming out in 2007 should put me well in the lead.</p>
<p>I clearly didn&#8217;t allow for the knowledge of the judges &#8211; I think I&#8217;ll appeal!<br />
…<br />
Cheers<br />
Phil
</p></blockquote>
<p>The category remains hotly contested, with many new contestants. Jones, whatever his other sins, has tended to use fairly simple methods and I find it hard to picture him maintaining a spot on the podium. Mann, of course, has a repertoire of upside-down techniques that are highly regarded by climate referees and which make it very difficult for new contestants to seize the gold medal.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17539/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17539/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17539&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/cg3-the-gold-medalist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bolt_mann.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bolt_mann</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marcott&#8217;s Zonal Reconstructions</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/marcotts-zonal-reconstructions/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/marcotts-zonal-reconstructions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17521</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m going to do a detailed post on my diagnosis of the Marcott uptick, but before I do so, I want to comment on the reconstructions for NH and SH extratropics, neither of which have attracted sufficient notice though both are very remarkable. In a substantive sense, because orbital changes have different effects on NH [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17521&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m going to do a detailed post on my diagnosis of the Marcott uptick, but before I do so, I want to comment on the reconstructions for NH and SH extratropics, neither of which have attracted sufficient notice though both are very remarkable. In a substantive sense, because orbital changes have different effects on NH and SH, the difference between NHX and SHX proxies is a source of substantive interest and is what ought to have been reported on.</p>
<p>In the running text, Marcott et al had emphasized that their reconstruction was &#8220;indistinguishable within uncertainty&#8221;. This was illustrated in their Figure 1E, which showed the Mann08 GLB and NH reconstructions (which of several versions is not denoted in the caption), Moberg 2005 (NH) and the Wahl-Ammann version of MBH98 (NH). </p>
<blockquote><p>
Our global temperature reconstruction for the past 1500 years is indistinguishable within uncertainty from the Mann et al. (2) reconstruction&#8230; This similarity confirms that published temperature reconstructions of the past two millennia capture long-term variability, despite their short time span (3, 12, 13). </p></blockquote>
<p>The zonal (NHX, SHX and tropics) reconstructions were illustrated in Marcott Figure 2I,J,K, but Marcott et al conspicuously did not compare their zonal reconstructions with previous NH and SH reconstructions, instead comparing them to proxies often considered to be precipitation proxies. In their text, they stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>Trends in regional temperature reconstructions show strong similarities with high-resolution precipitation records, consistently associating greater warmth with greater wetness (Fig. 2, H to J). For example,  extratropical Northern Hemisphere mid-to- high–latitude temperature correlates well with records of Asian monsoon intensity (14, 15 -Dongge O18) and the position of the Atlantic intertropical convergence zone (16 &#8211; Cariaco) (Fig. 2H), tropical temperatures track precipitation proxies from speleothems in Borneo (17) and Indonesia (18) (Fig. 2I), and extratropical Southern Hemisphere temperatures parallel speleothem proxies of precipitation and temperature from South Africa (19) and South America (20) that are independent of our reconstruction</p></blockquote>
<p>Their decision not to compare their reconstruction to popular hemispherical versions was a curious one and I&#8217;ve remedied this apparent oversight below.</p>
<p><strong>Northern Hemisphere</strong><br />
First here is a comparison of the Marcott NH Extratropic reconstruction with the Moberg 2005 reconstruction (which Marcott et al showed in connection with their GLB reconstruction).  I suspect that some readers will not find these two series to be &#8220;remarkably similar&#8221; (TM- climate science). (For greater certainty, Marcott et al did not say that these two series were &#8220;remarkably similar&#8221;, he said that the Moberg NH reconstruction was similar to his GLB reconstruction, but omitted any direct comparison with his NHX reconstructions.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/moberg-vs-marcott.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/moberg-vs-marcott.png?w=720&#038;h=480" alt="moberg-vs-marcott" width="720" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17522" /></a><br />
Figure 1. Moberg NH versus Marcott et al NHX. Red dot shows 1990-2010 average HadCRU temperature. Dotted vertical black line at 1890 is period after which reconstruction already admitted to be &#8220;not robust&#8221;. </p>
<p>Next here is a comparison of the Marcott NHX reconstruction with two Mann reconstructions: the Mann 2008 NH EIV iHAD variation (which in effect splices temperature from 1850 on) and the MBH NHX version (extracted from Briffa et al 2001 SI). I am not persuaded that Marcott&#8217;s NHX reconstruction is &#8220;indistinguishable within uncertainty&#8221; from the corresponding NH reconstructions, making one wonder why the GLB reconstruction is are supposedly &#8220;indistinguighable within uncertainty&#8221;.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-vs-marcott.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-vs-marcott.png?w=720&#038;h=480" alt="mann-vs-marcott" width="720" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17524" /></a><br />
Figure 2. Marcott NHX versus M08 NH EIV iHAD and MBH98-99 NHX (from Briffa et al 2001). As Figure 1. </p>
<p><strong>Southern Hemisphere</strong><br />
In the figure below, I&#8217;ve first compared the Marcott et al SHX reconstruction to the SH reconstruction of Mann and Jones 2003.  After readers recover from their awe at the remarkable similarity (TM-climate science) between the two reconstructions, they will note that the Marcott reconstruction began a pronounced and dramatic increase in the 18th century and reached its maximum in AD1900, which, in their Northern Hemisphere reconstruction, was the coldest year since the LGM. Marcott&#8217;s estimated AD1900 temperatures in SHX were much higher than even recent temperatures (1990-2010 HadCRU SH average denoted by red dot.) </p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mj03-vs-marcott_sh.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mj03-vs-marcott_sh.png?w=720&#038;h=480" alt="mj03-vs-marcott_SH" width="720" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17527" /></a><br />
Figure 3. Marcott SHX vs Mann and Jones 2003 SH.</p>
<p>Finally, here is a comparison of Mann 2008 SH EIV-CRU and CPS-CRU versus Marcott. There are important inconsistencies between Mannian EIV and CPS results, improving the odds of matching at least one of them. (Why anyone would regard Mannian EIV as an &#8220;improvement&#8221; on anything is a continuing source of puzzlement to me, but that is another day&#8217;s story.) Even doubling the odds of a match, I find the correspondence between the Mannian and Marcottian version to be underwhelming, though perhaps not so underwhelming as to preclude them being &#8220;remarkably similar TM-climate science&#8221;.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-vs-marcott_sh.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-vs-marcott_sh.png?w=720&#038;h=480" alt="mann-vs-marcott_SH" width="720" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17528" /></a></p>
<p>I will return to details of the uptick later. For now, I&#8217;ll close with this graphic showing the NHX and SHX reconstructions against the GLB reconstruction shown as the Marcott base.  While one expects a difference between NHX and SHX in the Holocene, the remarkable difference between NHX and SHX not just in the 20th century, but in the 19th century is a source of considerable interest.  According to Marcott, NHX temperatures increased by 1.9 deg C between 1920 and 1940, a surprising result even for the most zealous activists.  But for the rest of us, given the apparent resiliency of our species to this fantastic increase over a mere 20 years, it surely must provide a small measure of hope for resiliency in the future.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure1b-loop1.gif"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure1b-loop1.gif?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="figure1B-loop" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17531" /></a><br />
Figure ^. SHX (blue) and NHX (red) shown against global.  Third zone (tropics) not shown only to emphasize contrast.  Full spaghetti would include a third zone.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17521/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17521/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17521&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/marcotts-zonal-reconstructions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>69</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/moberg-vs-marcott.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">moberg-vs-marcott</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-vs-marcott.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mann-vs-marcott</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mj03-vs-marcott_sh.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mj03-vs-marcott_SH</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-vs-marcott_sh.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mann-vs-marcott_SH</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure1b-loop1.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">figure1B-loop</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>No Uptick in Marcott Thesis</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/14/no-uptick-in-marcott-thesis/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/14/no-uptick-in-marcott-thesis/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 23:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marcott]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17511</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reader ^ drew our attention to Marcott&#8217;s thesis (see chapter 4 here. Marcott&#8217;s thesis has a series of diagrams in an identical style as the Science article. The proxy datasets are identical. However, as Jean S alertly observed, the diagrams in the thesis lack the closing uptick of the Science. Other aspects of the modern [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17511&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Reader ^ drew our attention to Marcott&#8217;s thesis (see chapter 4 <a href="http://ir.library.oregonstate.edu/xmlui/bitstream/handle/1957/21129/MarcottShaunA2011.pdf?sequence=2">here</a>.  Marcott&#8217;s thesis has a series of diagrams in an identical style as the Science article. The proxy datasets are identical.</p>
<p>However, as Jean S alertly observed, the diagrams in the thesis lack the closing uptick of the Science.  Other aspects of the modern period also differ dramatically.</p>
<p>Here is Figure 1C of the Science article.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure-1c.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure-1c.png?w=593&#038;h=377" alt="figure 1C" width="593" height="377" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17512" /></a></p>
<p>Now here is the corresponding diagram from the thesis<br />
<a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thesis-short1.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thesis-short1.png?w=594&#038;h=377" alt="thesis-short1" width="594" height="377" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17513" /></a></p>
<p>The differences will be evident to readers. In addition to the difference in closing uptick, important reconstruction versions were at negative values in the closing portion of the thesis graphic, while they were at positive  values in the closing portion of the Science graphic.</p>
<p>I wonder what accounts for the difference. </p>
<p>A similar phenomenon occurs with the simulation diagram, that has been widely distributed as Stick support. Here is a blowup of the recent portion in Sciencemag:<br />
<a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/si-figure3-simulation-blowup.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/si-figure3-simulation-blowup.png?w=493&#038;h=556" alt="SI figure3 simulation blowup" width="493" height="556" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17518" /></a></p>
<p>Here is a corresponding blowup from the thesis.<br />
<a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thesis-simulation-blowup.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thesis-simulation-blowup.png?w=363&#038;h=536" alt="thesis simulation blowup" width="363" height="536" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17519" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17511/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17511/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17511&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/14/no-uptick-in-marcott-thesis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>124</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure-1c.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">figure 1C</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thesis-short1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thesis-short1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/si-figure3-simulation-blowup.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SI figure3 simulation blowup</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thesis-simulation-blowup.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thesis simulation blowup</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marcott Mystery #1</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/13/marcott-mystery-1/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/13/marcott-mystery-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 00:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marcott]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17498</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Marcott et al 2013 has received lots of publicity, mainly because of its supposed vindication of the Stick. A number of commenters have observed that they are unable to figure out how Marcott got the Stick portion of his graph from his data set. Add me to that group. The uptick occurs in the final [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17498&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marcott et al 2013 has received lots of publicity, mainly because of its supposed vindication of the Stick.  A number of commenters have observed that they are unable to figure out how Marcott got the Stick portion of his graph from his data set. Add me to that group.   </p>
<p>The uptick occurs in the final plot-point of his graphic (1940) and is a singleton. I wrote to Marcott asking him for further details of how he actually obtained the uptick, noting that the enormous 1920-to-1940 uptick is not characteristic of the underlying data. Marcott&#8217;s response was unhelpful: instead of explaining how he got the result, Marcott stated that they had &#8220;clearly&#8221; stated that the 1890-on portion of their reconstruction was &#8220;not robust&#8221;.  I agree that the 20th century portion of their reconstruction is &#8220;not robust&#8221;, but do not feel that merely describing the recent portion as &#8220;not robust&#8221; does full justice to the issues. Nor does it provide an explanation.</p>
<p>The uptick problems are even more pronounced in the zonal temperature reconstructions (NH and SH extratropics on which I will be posting) and in the reconstructions from individual proxies (alkenone, Mg/Ca).  In today&#8217;s post, I&#8217;ll illustrate the uptick problem from the alkenone temperature stack on the premise that there are fewer moving parts in the alkenone reconstruction and therefore this will facilitate diagnosis of the uptick mystery.<span id="more-17498"></span></p>
<p>The first figure below shows the Marcott alkenone reconstruction. Alkenones are the largest single class of Marcott proxies (31 of 73). According to the alkenone reconstruction, temperatures in 1920 were at their lowest value in 11,300 years (Marcott&#8217;s selection of 11,300 years begs the question of what happened just before the left frame of the graphic &#8211; an interesting issue that I&#8217;ll return to on another occasion.)  </p>
<p>Between 1920 and 1940, Marcott&#8217;s alkenone reconstruction increased by a remarkable 1.4 deg C, returning to values of the start of the reconstruction as shown. Marcott&#8217;s 1940 value (0.39 deg C reference 1961-90) was considerably above the 1961-90 reference zero and higher than the 1990-2010 average, shown as red &#8220;+&#8221; for reference.  Interesting as this figure may be, I don&#8217;t wish to dwell at present on what it might or might not show about temperature history (a topic that I&#8217;ll return to on another day.)</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-long2.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-long2.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="alkenone-long" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17508" /></a><br />
Figure 1. Marcott 2013 Alkenone reconstruction. (From SI spreadsheet sheet 2).  Red &#8220;+&#8221; point denotes 1990-2010 average HadCRU temperature. Dotted line is at final value for reference.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s post is merely about the mysterious uptick from 1920 to 1940, an uptick that is not observed in any of the actual alkenone data.</p>
<p>Despite the recent popularity of alkenone series over the Holocene, there are vanishingly few high-resolution alkenone series over the last two millenia for comparison. I keep my eye out for such series and their absence is very frustrating.  Only one of Marcott&#8217;s 31 alkenone series (MD01-2421; KR02-06 St.A GC; KR02-06 St.A MC&#8217;s 31 series) has a published date after 1950. Two others have published end dates of &#8220;0 BP&#8221;. This conventional date can be problematic, but again this is a story for another day.  There is negligible change in any of three series:  overall, there is an average decrease of one-hundredth of a degree, with none of the individual series changing as much as a tenth.  In alkenone series with published values in both 1920 and 1940, nothing happens to yield Marcott&#8217;s 1.4 deg C uptick.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-three-alkenones.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-three-alkenones.png?w=451&#038;h=67" alt="excerpt three alkenones" width="451" height="67" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17502" /></a></p>
<p>Marcott (in my opinion, unwisely) re-dated the modern portion of many cores, including numerous alkenone series. (I will write a separate post on this small and unwise adventure.) I don&#8217;t believe that this re-dating is at the root of today&#8217;s mystery (but neither can I completely exclude it.) As re-dated by Marcott, there are now five cores with alkenone measurements in both 1920 and 1940, again with negligible change between periods.  On average, there is a decline of 0.002 deg C.  (Interestingly, only one core is in common between the two cases.) </p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-marcott-alkenones.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-marcott-alkenones.png?w=637&#038;h=68" alt="excerpt marcott alkenones" width="637" height="68" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17504" /></a></p>
<p>In small samples with inconsistent proxies, the dropping out of a highly negative or highly positive proxy can produce seeming changes to a mean.  To consider this possibility, here are the values for proxies (after mid-Holocene centering) with &#8220;Marcott&#8221; values in either 1920 or 1940.  Marcott redated the MD01-2421 series (which is strongly negative in the 20th century); after redating, it drops out between 1920 and 1940, thereby producing an increase in the mean of available proxies.  Whereas the average of the five proxies with values in both periods has no change, the average of available values for the seven proxies shown below increases by 0.36 deg C &#8211; a (spurious) increase that is still far short of Marcott&#8217;s 1.4 deg C.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-marcott-alkenones-2.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-marcott-alkenones-2.png?w=893&#038;h=65" alt="excerpt marcott alkenones 2" width="893" height="65" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17505" /></a></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t believe that the baffling uptick has anything to do with splicing of instrumental or Mannian series, as speculated elsewhere. (One of the reasons for working on the alkenone version was to minimize this moving part.)  However, I am at present totally baffled. I&#8217;m disappointed that Marcott refused to explain the phenomenon when asked politely.  It is clear that the uptick is, at a minimum, &#8220;not robust&#8221;.  My own surmise is that the situation is worse than that: that the uptick in the alkenone (and other reconstructions) is an artifact, but of what I don&#8217;t know.  </p>
<p>As alluded to in this post, many other things about this article concern me. I&#8217;ll try to cover them in future posts.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17498/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17498/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17498&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/13/marcott-mystery-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>118</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-long2.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alkenone-long</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-three-alkenones.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">excerpt three alkenones</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-marcott-alkenones.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">excerpt marcott alkenones</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-marcott-alkenones-2.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">excerpt marcott alkenones 2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>More News from RC/FOIA</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/13/more-news-from-rcfoia/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/13/more-news-from-rcfoia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 16:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17495</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tom Nelson and Bishop Hill have released the following letter from Mr FOIA. I was one of several people who received the following letter: It&#8217;s time to tie up loose ends and dispel some of the speculation surrounding the Climategate affair. Indeed, it&#8217;s singular &#8220;I&#8221; this time. After certain career developments I can no longer [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17495&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tom Nelson and Bishop Hill have released the following letter from Mr FOIA. I was one of several people who received the following letter: </p>
<blockquote><p>
It&#8217;s time to tie up loose ends and dispel some of the speculation surrounding the Climategate affair.</p>
<p>Indeed, it&#8217;s singular &#8220;I&#8221; this time.  After certain career developments I can no longer use the papal plural <img src='http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';-)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p>If this email seems slightly disjointed it&#8217;s probably my linguistic background and the problem of trying to address both the wider audience (I expect this will be partially reproduced sooner or later) and the email recipients (whom I haven&#8217;t decided yet on).</p>
<p>The &#8220;all.7z&#8221; password is [deracted] DO NOT PUBLISH THE PASSWORD.  Quote other parts if you like.</p>
<p>Releasing the encrypted archive was a mere practicality.  I didn&#8217;t want to keep the emails lying around.</p>
<p>I prepared CG1 &amp; 2 alone.  Even skimming through all 220.000 emails would have taken several more months of work in an increasingly unfavorable environment.</p>
<p>Dumping them all into the public domain would be the last resort.  Majority of the emails are irrelevant, some of them probably sensitive and socially damaging.</p>
<p>To get the remaining scientifically (or otherwise) relevant emails out,  I ask you to pass this on to any motivated and responsible individuals who could volunteer some time to sift through the material for eventual release.</p>
<p>Filtering\redacting personally sensitive emails doesn&#8217;t require special expertise.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not entirely comfortable sending the password around unsolicited, but haven&#8217;t got better ideas at the moment.  If you feel this makes you seemingly &#8220;complicit&#8221; in a way you don&#8217;t like, don&#8217;t take action.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t expect these remaining emails to hold big surprises.  Yet it&#8217;s possible that the most important pieces are among them.  Nobody on the planet has held the archive in plaintext since CG2.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s right; no conspiracy, no paid hackers, no Big Oil.  The Republicans didn&#8217;t plot this.  USA politics is alien to me, neither am I from the UK.  There is life outside the Anglo-american sphere.</p>
<p>If someone is still wondering why anyone would take these risks, or sees only a breach of privacy here, a few words&#8230;</p>
<p>The first glimpses I got behind the scenes did little to  garner my trust in the state of climate science &#8212; on the contrary.  I found myself in front of a choice that just might have a global impact.</p>
<p>Briefly put, when I had to balance the interests of my own safety, privacy\career of a few scientists, and the well-being of billions of people living in the coming several decades, the first two weren&#8217;t the decisive concern.</p>
<p>It was me or nobody, now or never.  Combination of several rather improbable prerequisites just wouldn&#8217;t occur again for anyone else in the foreseeable future.  The circus was about to arrive in Copenhagen.  Later on it could be too late.</p>
<p>Most would agree that climate science has already directed where humanity puts its capability, innovation, mental and material &#8220;might&#8221;.  The scale will grow ever grander in the coming decades if things go according to script.  We&#8217;re dealing with $trillions and potentially drastic influence on practically everyone.</p>
<p>Wealth of the surrounding society tends to draw the major brushstrokes of a newborn&#8217;s future life.  It makes a huge difference whether humanity uses its assets to achieve progress, or whether it strives to stop and reverse it, essentially sacrificing the less fortunate to the climate gods.</p>
<p>We can&#8217;t pour trillions in this massive hole-digging-and-filling-up endeavor and pretend it&#8217;s not away from something and someone else.</p>
<p>If the economy of a region, a country, a city, etc.  deteriorates, what happens among the poorest? Does that usually improve their prospects? No, they will take the hardest hit.  No amount of magical climate thinking can turn this one upside-down.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s easy for many of us in the western world to accept a tiny green inconvenience and then wallow in that righteous feeling, surrounded by our &#8220;clean&#8221; technology and energy that is only slightly more expensive if adequately subsidized.</p>
<p>Those millions and billions already struggling with malnutrition, sickness, violence, illiteracy, etc.  don&#8217;t have that luxury.  The price of &#8220;climate protection&#8221; with its cumulative and collateral effects is bound to destroy and debilitate in great numbers, for decades and generations.</p>
<p>Conversely, a &#8220;game-changer&#8221; could have a beneficial effect encompassing a similar scope.</p>
<p>If I had a chance to accomplish even a fraction of that, I&#8217;d have to try.  I couldn&#8217;t morally afford inaction.  Even if I risked everything, would never get personal compensation, and could probably never talk about it with anyone.</p>
<p>I took what I deemed the most defensible course of action, and would do it again (although with slight alterations &#8212; trying to publish something truthful on RealClimate was clearly too grandiose of a plan <img src='http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';-)' class='wp-smiley' /> .</p>
<p>Even if I have it all wrong and these scientists had some good reason to mislead us (instead of making a strong case with real data) I think disseminating the truth is still the safest bet by far.</p>
<p>Big thanks to Steve and Anthony and many others.  My contribution would never have happened without your work (whether or not you agree with the views stated).</p>
<p>Oh, one more thing.  I was surprised to learn from a &#8220;progressive&#8221; blog, corroborated by a renowned &#8220;scientist&#8221;, that the releases were part of a coordinated campaign receiving vast amounts of secret funding from shady energy industry groups.</p>
<p>I wasn&#8217;t aware of the arrangement but warmly welcome their decision to support my project.  For that end I opened a bitcoin address: [redacted for now].</p>
<p>More seriously speaking, I accept, with gratitude, modest donations to support The (other) Cause.  The address can also serve as a digital signature to ward off those identity thefts, which are part of climate scientists&#8217; repertoire of tricks these days.</p>
<p>Keep on the good work.  I won&#8217;t be able to use this email address for long so if you reply, I can&#8217;t guarantee reading or answering.  I will several batches, to anyone I can think of.</p>
<p>Over and out.</p>
<p>Mr. FOIA
</p></blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17495/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17495/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17495&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/13/more-news-from-rcfoia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>148</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mike&#8217;s AGU Trick</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/02/mikes-agu-trick/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/02/mikes-agu-trick/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 17:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17336</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There has been considerable recent discussion of the fact that observations have been running cooler than models &#8211; see, for example, Lucia&#8217;s discussion of IPCC AR5 SOD Figure 9.8 (see here). However, Michael Mann at AGU took an entirely different line. Mann asserted that observations were running as hot or hotter than models. Mann&#8217;s assertion [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17336&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There has  been considerable recent discussion of the fact that observations have been running cooler than models &#8211; see, for example, Lucia&#8217;s discussion of IPCC AR5 SOD Figure 9.8 (see <a href="http://rankexploits.com/musings/2012/things-i-can-see-in-figure-9-8-of-the-ar5-sod/">here</a>). However, Michael Mann at AGU took an entirely different line. Mann asserted that observations were running as hot or hotter than models. Mann&#8217;s assertion was taken even further by Naomi Oreskes, who asserted that climate models were <strong>under-estimating</strong> relative to observations. Oreskes squarely placed the blame for the supposed underestimates on climate skeptics.  </p>
<p>In today&#8217;s post, I&#8217;ll look closely at the illustration in Mann&#8217;s AGU presentation, an illustration that gave an entirely different impression than the figure in the IPCC draft report.  The reason for the difference can be traced to what I&#8217;ve termed here as &#8220;Mike&#8217;s AGU Trick&#8221;. <span id="more-17336"></span></p>
<p><strong>The IPCC AR5 SOD Graphic</strong><br />
An excerpt from IPCC AR5 SOD Figure 9.8 is shown below, clearly showing that the multimodel ensemble (red) is running noticeably hotter than observations (black).  In my opinion, the difference is not merely &#8220;noticeable&#8221; but &#8220;statistically significant&#8221;, but that&#8217;s a story for a different day.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure9-8-excerpt-rescaled.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure9-8-excerpt-rescaled.png?w=420&#038;h=420" alt="figure9.8 excerpt-rescaled" width="420" height="420" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17393" /></a><br />
Figure 1. Excerpt from IPCC AR5 SOD Figure 9.8, comparing model ensemble to observations.<br />
<strong><br />
Mann&#8217;s AGU Presentation</strong><br />
However, Mann at AGU asserted that observations were running as hot or hotter than models. Mann&#8217;s model comparandum was Hansen&#8217;s Scenario B, which is widely regarded as the most reasonable scenario to use to interpret Hansen&#8217;s &#8220;forecast&#8221; &#8211; see past CA points on this issue.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/mann-agu.jpg"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/mann-agu.jpg?w=720&#038;h=540" alt="mann-agu" width="720" height="540" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17338" /></a><br />
Figure 2. Mann&#8217;s AGU slide comparing observations to Hansen&#8217;s 1988 Scenario B projection.</p>
<p>I took the photo with a new phone, with which I was then unfamiliar and unfortunately can only provide a muddy zoom on the graphic. Despite the muddiness, you can see that observations (red) appear to cohere with Hansen&#8217;s 1988 forecast (blue). In the loop below, I&#8217;ve overplotted data for models and observations to show more clearly what was shown to the AGU audience. (There was a bit of detective work in figuring this out &#8211; see below.)  Click on the figure below for a loop illustrating the components of the zoomed figure). (Note: see below for Mann&#8217;s use of his AGU Trick to hide the divergence in a presentation a few months earlier at Rutgers).</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-agu-loop1.gif"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-agu-loop1.gif?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="mann-agu-loop" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17396" /></a> Figure 3. Blowup of Mann&#8217;s slide comparing Hansen&#8217;s Scenario B to observations. Blue &#8211; Hansen&#8217;s Scenario B; red &#8211; &#8220;observations&#8221;. </p>
<p>Mann&#8217;s AGU slide obviously has a completely different rhetorical impression than the IPCC graphic. Whereas the discrepancy between observations and models was immediately noticeable in the IPCC graphic, Mann&#8217;s AGU graphic showed no such discrepancy. There were two reasons for the difference, the combination of which I&#8217;ll call &#8220;Mike&#8217;s AGU Trick&#8221; and will analyse below.</p>
<p><strong>Hansen 1988 versus Observations<br />
</strong><br />
First, I&#8217;ll show that Mike&#8217;s AGU Trick does not result from using Hansen&#8217;s Scenario B, as opposed to the IPCC multimodel ensemble.  The next graphic compares Hansen&#8217;s original graphic (with Scenario B highlighted in blue) against observed GISS global land-and-ocean temperature (red). During the past decade, as with the IPCC multimodel ensemble, a noticeable divergence between observations and Scenario B has developed, reaching over 0.5 degrees C in 2012.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hansen-1988_annotated.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hansen-1988_annotated.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="hansen-1988_annotated" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17394" /></a><br />
Figure 4. Annotated version of Hansen 1988 showing Scenario B (blue) and observed GISS land-and-ocean (red.) All data centered on 1958-1977.   <em>In the preparation of this graphic, I noticed something interesting about the centering of Hansen&#8217;s scenarios &#8211; an issue that occasioned considerable controversy in blog commentary:  Hansen&#8217;s Scenarios are almost certainly centered on 1958-1977. The averages of both Scenario B and Scenario C are 0 to five significant digits with this centering. All data was accordingly centered on 1958-1977 for the present comparison. For GISS observations, the difference between 1958-1977 and 1951-1980 centering is -.0175 deg C &#8211; the difference is not material to comparisons, but there&#8217;s no reason not to do it as precisely as possible.</em> </p>
<p><strong>Mann and Kump, 2008<br />
</strong><br />
Analysis of Mann&#8217;s AGU graphic is fortuitously assisted by the use of a similar graphic in Mann and Kump, <em>Dire Predictions</em>, as illustrated in the loop below.  Mann and Kump, published in July 2008, compared Hansen&#8217;s Scenario B to observations to <strong>2005</strong>, though data was then available up to 2007. In addition, although GISS model results are obviously for Land-and-Ocean, Mann and Kump used Land-Only data (which runs hotter) [click on figure for loop]</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-kump-loop1.gif"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-kump-loop1.gif?w=600&#038;h=348" alt="mann-kump-loop" width="600" height="348" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17399" /></a><br />
Figure 5. Comparison of Hansen 1988 to observations in Mann and Kump, Dire Predictions &#8211; see <a href="https://www.e-education.psu.edu/meteo469/node/141" rel="nofollow">https://www.e-education.psu.edu/meteo469/node/141</a></p>
<p><strong>Mike&#8217;s AGU Trick<br />
</strong><br />
There were two components to Mann&#8217;s AGU trick. First, as in Mann and Kump, Mann compared model projections for land-and-ocean to observations for land-only. In addition, like Santer et al 2008, Mann failed to incorporate up-to-date data for his comparison.  The staleness of Mann&#8217;s temperature data in his AGU presentation was really quite remarkable: the temperature data in Mann&#8217;s presentation (December 2012) ended in <strong>2005</strong>! Obviously, in the past (notably MBH98 and MBH99), Mann used the most recent (even monthly data) when it was to his advantage. So the failure to use up-to-date data in his AGU presentation is really quite conspicuous.</p>
<p>Had Mann shown a comparison of Hansen&#8217;s Scenario B to up-to-date Land-and-Ocean observational data, the discrepancy would have been evident to the AGU audience, as shown in the loop below.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-agu-loop-loti1.gif"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-agu-loop-loti1.gif?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="mann-agu-loop-loti" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17402" /></a><br />
Figure 6. Excerpt from Mann&#8217;s AGU presentation. Loop 1- showing Mann&#8217;s actual diagram with GISS Land-Only to 2005; Loop 2 &#8211; showing GISS Land-and-Ocean to 2012. </p>
<p><strong>Pierrehumbert Condemns Data Truncation</strong><br />
In a 2007 <a href="http://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2007/12/les-chevaliers-de-lordre-de-la-terre-plate-part-ii-courtillots-geomagnetic-excursion/">realclimate article</a>, Raymond Pierrehumbert condemned use of non-updated temperature data, when the effect of the failure to use up-to-date data was that the image gave an entirely different impression to the reader. In that situation, Pierrehumbert even called into question the ethics of the author. </p>
<blockquote><p>
there is no legitimate reason — in a paper published in 2007 — for truncating the temperature record at 1992 as they did. There is, however, a very good illegitimate reason, in that truncating the curve in this way helps to conceal the strength of the trend from the reader, and shortens the period in which the most glaring mismatch &#8230; occurs.</p></blockquote>
<p>There does not  appear to be any relevant difference between Mann&#8217;s AGU technique and the graphic so vehemently criticized by Pierrehumbert, though, to my knowledge, Pierrehumbert has not taken exception to Mann&#8217;s AGU Trick.</p>
<p><strong>Wingman Naomi<br />
</strong><br />
Mann&#8217;s AGU Trick appears to have wrongfooted his mini wingman, Naomi Oreskes.</p>
<p>Like Mann, Oreskes gave three AGU presentations (sessions PA13B &#8211; Countering Denial and Manufactured Doubt of 21st Century Science I; GC22B &#8211; Communicating Climate Science—Seeking the Best of Old and New Paradigms I;  GC33F &#8211; Construing Uncertainty in Climate Science I). Oreskes&#8217; starting point was that models had supposedly <strong>under-estimated</strong> relative to observations &#8211; a starting-point that seems oddly disconnected to the IPCC graphic shown above but, hey, Oreskes is an expert in manufactured disinformation.  If Oreskes was not in fact wrongfooted by Mann, then one would like to know the provenance of her assertion that models were &#8220;underestimating&#8221; observed temperature increases.</p>
<p>Oreskes then purported to ponder on the institutional factors that supposedly caused such under-estimates by climate scientists. Oreskes had no doubt as to where the &#8220;blame&#8221; lay. Not with the scientists themselves. of course not. Oreskes placed the blame squarely on climate skeptics. According to Oreskes, their intimidation had led climate scientists to pull their punches and make forecasts that were too conservative.  </p>
<p>[Note (March 2, 2013 4:22 pm.] While I was mostly offline, it turns out, as a reader below points out and as Pielke Jr has communicated to me by email, that Oreskes has published the argument outlined in her AGU presentation <a href="http://history.ucsd.edu/_files/oreskes/esld.pdf">here</a>. Pielke Jr has an excellent review of the Oreskes article <a href="http://rogerpielkejr.blogspot.co.uk/2013/02/science-is-shortcut.html">here</a>. Pielke Jr quoted the following from the Oreskes article &#8211; a quote which is very much consistent with the AGU presentation:</p>
<blockquote><p>[O]ne possible reason why scientists may have underestimated the threat of anthropogenic warming is the fear that if they don’t, they will be accused by contrarians (as was Schneider) of being alarmist fear-mongers. That is to say, pressure from skeptics and contrarians and the risk of being accused of alarmism may have caused scientists to understate their results.</p></blockquote>
<p>In other words &#8211; and this is the implication of Oreskes&#8217; presentation not what she told the audience &#8211; were it not for the moderating influence of climate skeptics, the discrepancy between observations and the models that climate scientists would have presented in an Oreskes world, would have been even larger than the present discrepancy.  </p>
<p>Surely this is an outcome that should cause Oreskes to thank skeptics, rather than condemn them.  But, needless to say, no such thanks were forthcoming at the AGU of Oreskes, Gleick, Lewandowsky and Mann. </p>
<p>Update: As reader DGH observed in a comment below, Mann&#8217;s <a href="http://www.meteo.psu.edu/holocene/public_html/Misc/HSCW_Rutgers_Sep12.pdf">presentation</a> at Rutgers also employed Mann&#8217;s AGU Trick to hide the divergence between Hansen Scenario B and observed temperature, not showing data after 2005. As noted above, not using up-to-date data in virtually identical circumstances was characterized by Pierrehumbert as &#8220;ugly&#8221; and &#8220;illegitimate&#8221;: </p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hansen1988-rutgers.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hansen1988-rutgers.png?w=600" alt="hansen1988-rutgers" width="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17418" /></a><br />
Figure ^. Excerpt from Mann&#8217;s September 2012 presentation at Rutgers.</p>
<p>As reader ZT pointed out, Mann also used his AGU Trick to hide the divergence in his TEDx talk<br />
<a href="http://tedxtalks.ted.com/video/TEDxPSU-Michael-Mann-A-Look-Int">here</a>.<br />
<a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hansen1988-mann-tedx.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hansen1988-mann-tedx.png?w=600" alt="hansen1988 mann tedx" width="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17422" /></a></p>
<p>As reader ^ pointed out, in 2006, Hansen did his own comparison of his 1988 scenarios to observations, a diagram that appears to be the iconographic predecessor of Mann&#8217;s AGU diagram, a diagram that clearly shows an important difference between Hansen&#8217;s ethics and Mann&#8217;s ethics.  Hansen&#8217;s article included up-to-date temperature data.  In contrast, Mann&#8217;s AGU diagram, over 6 years later, still used 2005 data.  In addition, Hansen showed both Land-Only and Land-and-Ocean data sets, showing the greater divergence between models and Land-and-Ocean data (arguing, not entirely convincingly, for an intermediate.) In contrast, Mann only showed the most advantageous version.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hansen-2006-figure2.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hansen-2006-figure2.png?w=502&#038;h=403" alt="hansen-2006-figure2" width="502" height="403" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17425" /></a><br />
Figure ^. From Hansen et al 2006 (PNAS)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17336/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17336/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17336&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/02/mikes-agu-trick/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>319</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure9-8-excerpt-rescaled.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">figure9.8 excerpt-rescaled</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/mann-agu.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mann-agu</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-agu-loop1.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mann-agu-loop</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hansen-1988_annotated.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hansen-1988_annotated</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-kump-loop1.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mann-kump-loop</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-agu-loop-loti1.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mann-agu-loop-loti</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hansen1988-rutgers.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hansen1988-rutgers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hansen1988-mann-tedx.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hansen1988 mann tedx</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hansen-2006-figure2.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hansen-2006-figure2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
