<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Climate Audit</title>
	<atom:link href="http://climateaudit.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://climateaudit.org</link>
	<description>by Steve McIntyre</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 11:52:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='climateaudit.org' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Climate Audit</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://climateaudit.org/osd.xml" title="Climate Audit" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://climateaudit.org/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Marcott Filibuster</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/31/the-marcott-filibuster/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/31/the-marcott-filibuster/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 17:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marcott]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17658</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Marcott et al have posted their long-promised FAQ at realclimate here. Without providing any links to or citation of Climate Audit, they now concede: 20th century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions. Otherwise, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17658&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marcott et al have posted their long-promised FAQ at realclimate <a href="http://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2013/03/response-by-marcott-et-al/">here</a>. Without providing any links to or citation of Climate Audit, they  now concede:  </p>
<blockquote><p>20th century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions.</p></blockquote>
<p>Otherwise, their response is pretty much a filibuster, running the clock on questions that have not actually been asked and certainly not at issue by critics. For questions and issues that I&#8217;ve actually raised, for the most part, they merely re-iterate what they already said. Nothing worth waiting for.<span id="more-17658"></span></p>
<p>They did not discuss or explain why they deleted modern values from the Md01-2421 splice at CA <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/17/hiding-the-decline-the-md01-2421-splice/">here</a> and <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/">here</a>. Or the deletion of modern values from OCE326-GGC300 as asked <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/">here</a>. </p>
<p>Nor do they discuss the difference between the results that had (presumably) been in the submission to Nature (preserved as a chapter in Marcott&#8217;s thesis).</p>
<p>Nor did they discuss the implausibility of their coretop redating of MD95-2043 and MD95-2011 as discussed <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/">here.</a> </p>
<p>Instead of dealing with actual questions, for the most part, their &#8220;FAQ&#8221; filibusters about questions that no one was asking in connection with this study. </p>
<p>Eventually, they get to a question about their redating:</p>
<blockquote><p>
Q. Why did you revise the age models of many of the published records that were used in your study?
</p></blockquote>
<p>But here too they filibuster. They spend 3.5 paragraphs pontificating about radiocarbon recalibration &#8211; a topic that was not an issue. Indeed, on several occasions, including a comment on a similar filibuster by William Connolley, I clearly distinguished between radiocarbon recalibration and coretop redating, taking issue only with coretop redating.  Nonetheless, Marcott et al adopted the same filibuster that Connolley had used. </p>
<p>When they eventually get to coretop redating, they say only:</p>
<blockquote><p>
In geologic studies it is quite common that the youngest surface of a sediment core is not dated by radiocarbon, either because the top is disturbed by living organisms or during the coring process. Moreover, within the past hundred years before 1950 CE, radiocarbon dates are not very precise chronometers, because changes in radiocarbon production rate have by coincidence roughly compensated for fixed decay rates. For these reasons, and unless otherwise indicated, we followed the common practice of assuming an age of 0 BP for the marine core tops.</p></blockquote>
<p>This is nothing more than a re-iteration of the statement in their SI that I had quoted in my <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/">Core Tops post</a>: </p>
<blockquote><p>Core tops are assumed to be 1950 AD unless otherwise indicated in original publication.</p></blockquote>
<p>This is not an answer or justification of what they did. I urge interested readers to re-read the <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/">Core Tops post</a> and more generally the <a href="http://www.climateaudit.org/tag/marcott">Marcott sequence.<br />
</a></p>
<p>Nor did they directly answer questions about the questionable uptick. They pose the question for themselves as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>Q: What do paleotemperature reconstructions show about the temperature of the last 100 years?
</p></blockquote>
<p>They give a &#8220;short&#8221; and &#8220;technical&#8221; answer. First they stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>A: Our global paleotemperature reconstruction includes a so-called “uptick” in temperatures during the 20th-century. However, in the paper we make the point that this particular feature is of shorter duration than the inherent smoothing in our statistical averaging procedure, and that it is based on only a few available paleo-reconstructions of the type we used. Thus, the 20th century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions. Our primary conclusions are based on a comparison of the longer term paleotemperature changes from our reconstruction with the well-documented temperature changes that have occurred over the last century, as documented by the instrumental record. Although not part of our study, high-resolution paleoclimate data from the past ~130 years have been compiled from various geological archives, and confirm the general features of warming trend over this time interval (Anderson, D.M. et al., 2013, Geophysical Research Letters, v. 40, p. 189-193; <a href="http://www.agu.org/journals/pip/gl/2012GL054271-pip.pdf" rel="nofollow">http://www.agu.org/journals/pip/gl/2012GL054271-pip.pdf</a>).
</p></blockquote>
<p>Although they now apparently concede that &#8220;the 20th century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions&#8221;, this was definitely not the impression left by the authors when the article was published, when it was hailed as supposed confirmation of the Hockey Stick.  </p>
<p>Andy Revkin, an extremely experienced reporter, certainly didn&#8217;t interpret Marcott et al as taking the position that their reconstruction wasn&#8217;t &#8220;statistically robust&#8221; in the modern portion: he titled his <a href="http://dotearth.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/03/07/scientists-find-an-abrupt-warm-jog-after-a-very-long-cooling/">article</a> &#8220;Scientists Find an Abrupt Warm Jog After a Very Long Cooling&#8221;. (Note: see Revkin&#8217;s fresh commentary <a href="http://dotearth.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/03/31/fresh-thoughts-from-authors-of-a-paper-on-11300-years-of-global-temperature-changes/">here</a>).</p>
<p>Further, their present admission that their reconstruction has no statistical skill in its modern portion completely refutes the previous claim that it had somehow vindicated Mann&#8217;s Hockey Stick, the distinguishing characteristic of which was supposed to be its &#8220;statistical skill&#8221; in reconstructing temperatures since 1850 (its calibration and verification periods.)  If as Marcott et al now admit, their reconstruction is &#8220;not statistically robust&#8221; during the Mannian calibration and verification periods, it cannot &#8220;confirm&#8221; the Mann Hockey Stick.</p>
<p>later in the article, they take another run at this question as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>A: Here we elaborate on our short answer to this question above. We concluded in the published paper that </p>
<blockquote><p>
“Without filling data gaps, our Standard5×5 reconstruction (Figure 1A) exhibits 0.6°C greater warming over the past ~60 yr B.P. (1890 to 1950 CE) than our equivalent infilled 5° × 5° area-weighted mean stack (Figure 1, C and D). However, considering the temporal resolution of our data set and the small number of records that cover this interval (Figure 1G), this difference is probably not robust.” </p></blockquote>
<p>This statement follows from multiple lines of evidence that are presented in the paper and the supplementary information:<br />
(1) the different methods that we tested for generating a reconstruction produce different results in this youngest interval, whereas before this interval, the different methods of calculating the stacks are nearly identical (Figure 1D),<br />
(2) the median resolution of the datasets (120 years) is too low to statistically resolve such an event,<br />
(3) the smoothing presented in the online supplement results in variations shorter than 300 yrs not being interpretable, and<br />
(4) the small number of datasets that extend into the 20th century (Figure 1G) is insufficient to reconstruct a statistically robust global signal, showing that there is a considerable reduction in the correlation of Monte Carlo reconstructions with a known (synthetic) input global signal when the number of data series in the reconstruction is this small (Figure S13).
</p></blockquote>
<p>Again, this is adding little to nothing to what was known more or less on day one.  In Marcott&#8217;s original email to me, he had referred to the above paragraph in the article, arguing that the above sentence (which stated that the <strong>difference</strong> between <em>reconstruction versions</em> was not robust constituted a statement that the reconstruction itself in the modern portion was not statistically robust.  I certainly do not read the original sentence this way and do not agree that it says what the authors now contend that it says. Nor does it clearly and unequivocally say what the authors now say:</p>
<blockquote><p>the 20th century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions.
</p></blockquote>
<p>Nor do the above caveats of non-robustness properly deal with the dependence of their 20th century uptick on their deletion of 20th century data points from critical series and the importation of earlier data points into the 20th century by unjustifiable coretop re-dating. </p>
<p>As a closing point, in Simonsohn&#8217;s widely publicized discussions of academic fraud last year e.g. <a href="http://news.sciencemag.org/scienceinsider/2012/06/fraud-detection-method-called-cr.html">here</a>, Simonsohn stated that compliant articles ought to disclose &#8220;failed&#8221; calculations, as well as the ones reported (see Simmons et al 2011 <a href="http://pss.sagepub.com/content/22/11/1359">here.</a>)  In the SI to Marcott et al, the authors reported on a wide variety of sensitivity studies, most of which will be of little interest to any reader.</p>
<p>However, they conspicuously did not report the results prior to the coretop redating that have been preserved in Marcott&#8217;s thesis and were presumably the ones in the article rejected by Nature. This version lacked the distinctive Marcott uptick. Under Simonsohn&#8217;s standards, disclosure of this &#8220;failed&#8221; calculation would have been obligatory. Comparing the two results shows sensitivity to Marcott core re-dating &#8211; a topic that ought to have been brought to the attention of reviewers by Marcott et al themselves.  The authors are then free to argue for the merits of their coretop redating. </p>
<p>Although the authors now argue that the coretop redating doesn&#8217;t &#8220;matter&#8221;, it clearly did cause a difference between the present results and the results submitted to Nature and clearly did &#8220;matter&#8221;.</p>
<p>This is not to say that this issue affects &#8220;everything&#8221; in the paper, which, as the authors now argue, dealt with other issues.  However, if these other issues are the ones that really &#8220;matter&#8217;, as they now say, then they should not have embarked on the coretop redating that resulted in a spurious uptick.</p>
<p>I think that their decision to take guidance from Realclimate was exceedingly unwise.  It would have been better to simply respond to questions in a natural way when they were initially raised. </p>
<p>Update 1:51 pm) Andy Revkin has a comment on the FAQ <a href="http://dotearth.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/03/31/fresh-thoughts-from-authors-of-a-paper-on-11300-years-of-global-temperature-changes">here</a>, pointedly commenting: </p>
<blockquote><p>there’s also room for more questions — one being how the authors square the caveats they express here with some of the more definitive statements they made about their findings in news accounts.</p></blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17658/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17658/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17658&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/31/the-marcott-filibuster/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>140</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aging as a State of Mind</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/29/aging-as-a-state-of-mind/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/29/aging-as-a-state-of-mind/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17640</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Bobbie Hasselbring, editor of Real Food Traveller, has an article on &#8220;Aging as a State of Mind&#8221;. Her article concludes as follows: Katherine McIntyre is 89 years old. She’s the oldest person ever to have zip lined at High Life Adventures. She’s a working travel journalist. And she kept me from even wondering whether I’m [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17640&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.realfoodtraveler.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSC_46011-269x300.jpg" class="alignleft" alt="" />   Bobbie Hasselbring, editor of Real Food Traveller, has an article on &#8220;Aging as a State of Mind&#8221;.  Her <a href="http://www.realfoodtraveler.com/2013/03/aging-as-a-state-of-mind/">article</a> concludes as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>Katherine McIntyre is 89 years old. She’s the oldest person ever to have zip lined at High Life Adventures. She’s a working travel journalist. And she kept me from even wondering whether I’m afraid of heights.  And, you know what? I’m not afraid. Because Katherine isn’t afraid and she’s one of my heroes.</p></blockquote>
<p>Mine as well. </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17640/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17640/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17640&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/29/aging-as-a-state-of-mind/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.realfoodtraveler.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSC_46011-269x300.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lewandowsky Doubles Down</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/28/lewandowsky-doubles-down/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/28/lewandowsky-doubles-down/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 17:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lewandowsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17385</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last fall, Geoff Chambers and Barry Woods established beyond a shadow of a doubt that no blog post linking to the Lewandowsky survey had ever been published at the Skeptical Science (SKS) blog. Chambers reasonably suggested at the time that the authors correct the claim in the article to reflect the lack of any link [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17385&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last fall, Geoff Chambers and Barry Woods established beyond a shadow of a doubt that no blog post linking to the Lewandowsky survey had ever been published at the Skeptical Science (SKS) blog.  Chambers reasonably suggested at the time that the authors correct the claim in the article to reflect the lack of any link at the SKS blog.  I reviewed the then available information on this incident in September 2012 <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2012/09/14/the-sks-link-to-the-lewandowsky-survey/">here</a>. </p>
<p>Since then, information obtained through <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/tag/lewandowsky/">FOI by Simon Turnill</a> has shown that responses by both Lewandowsky and Cook to questions from Chambers and Woods were untrue. Actually, &#8220;untrue&#8221; does not really do justice to the measure of untruthfulness, as the <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/tag/lewandowsky/">FOI correspondence</a> shows that the untruthful answers were given deliberately and intentionally.  Chambers, in a post entitled <a href="http://geoffchambers.wordpress.com/2013/02/07/lewandowsky-the-liar/">Lewandowsky the Liar</a>, minced no words in calling Lewandowsky &#8220;a liar, a fool, a charlatan and a fraud.&#8221; </p>
<p>Even though the untruthfulness of Lewandowsky and Cook&#8217;s stories had been clearly demonstrated by Geoff Chambers in a series of blog articles (e.g. <a href="http://geoffchambers.wordpress.com/2013/02/09/lews-lies-2-trick-or-tweet/">here</a>), in the published version of the <em>Hoax</em> paper, instead of correcting prior untrue claims about SKS, Lewandowsky doubled down, repeating and substantially amplifying the untrue claim.<span id="more-17385"></span></p>
<p>Contrary to one of the many untrue claims in <em>Fury,</em> the first interest of the few people to originally interest themselves in the Hoax paper (primarily Geoff Chambers and Barry Woods) was the identity of the eight &#8220;pro-science&#8221; blogs which had supposedly published a link to the Lewandowsky survey. Woods emailed Lewandowsky, who promptly replied with a list of the eight blogs, all of which were stridently anti-skeptic. The most prominent of the eight were SKS, Deltoid and Tamino. Chambers, Woods and others sharply criticized the idea of trying a survey of skeptics at stridently anti-skeptic blogs, a criticism that has remains unrefuted.</p>
<p>Chambers and Woods quickly located referring blogposts at all of the blogs except SKS. They were able to locate a contemporary <a href="https://twitter.com/skepticscience/status/22332844414">tweet</a> from John Cook, but no SKS blogpost.  Close examination of the Wayback machine archive showed beyond any doubt that there was no SKS blogpost on the Lewandowsky survey in August/September 2010 (see my previous post <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2012/09/14/the-sks-link-to-the-lewandowsky-survey/">here</a>.)</p>
<p>Woods directly asked Lewandowsky in early August 2012 for the location of the alleged SKS blog post. Lewandowsky unequivocally told Woods that Cook had &#8220;posted it&#8221; and that he (Lewandowsky) had &#8220;made a note&#8221; of it, though he had not kept the &#8220;actual URL&#8221;. Lewandowsky speculated that Cook had deleted the post when the survey was closed (highly atypical blog behavior, to say the least):</p>
<blockquote><p>I worked with John Cook directly at the time and he posted it (and <strong>I made a note of it</strong>), but I don’t have the actual URL to the survey dating back to the time when he posted it. I suspect he removed it when the survey was closed because then the link would have been dead.</p></blockquote>
<p>The idea that Cook had deleted the SKS link to the Lewandowsky survey seemed highly implausible to, among others, Geoff Chambers, who asked about the incident in early September 2012 in comments at SKS <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1540#84306">here</a></p>
<blockquote><p>Could you, John Cook, please clarify whether SkS posted a link to Lewandowsky&#8217;s survey between Aug and Oct 2010, or helped in any other way, eg by providing email addresses of potential respondents?</p></blockquote>
<p>Cook replied with an inline comment that re-iterated Lewandowsky&#8217;s assertion to Woods, saying as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>Skeptical Science did link to the Lewandowsky survey back in 2011 but now when I search the archives for the link, it&#8217;s no longer there so the link must&#8217;ve been taken down once the survey was over.</p></blockquote>
<p>The 2011 date was clearly an error and was immediately challenged. Cook promptly conceded that the 2011 date was not correct and should have been 2010, commenting as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>My apologies, it was 2010, not 2011 (have updated the original response).</p></blockquote>
<p>The idea that Cook had deleted the referring blogpost remained implausible. Chambers continued to press for information, asking whether anyone at SKS remembered a blog post on the survey. Chambers&#8217; questions were cut off by an SKS moderator who told him to take up the matter with Cook in offline emails:</p>
<blockquote><p>You have already received a public response from John Cook. Should you wish more detail, please submit an email to him. This is a forum founded and administered by him. Therefore questions of the nature you have been posting should more rightly be submitted to him in private correspondence. Continuance in this behavior now constitutes grandstanding and sloganeering, and will be moderated accordingly. FYI.</p></blockquote>
<p>Much to Chambers&#8217; surprise, Cook contacted him directly with a contact email address:</p>
<blockquote><p>JC: Hi Geoff, you can email me via this email address if you have any direct questions, although there&#8217;s not much more that I can add other than what I&#8217;ve mentioned in the comment threads.</p></blockquote>
<p>Chambers then re-iterated his question about the &#8220;missing&#8221; SKS blog post, asking additionally for information about contemporary blog comments (which had been revealing at Deltoid and Tamino):</p>
<blockquote><p>Thanks John. My interest comes from the fact that, of the eight “pro-science” blogs contacted by Lewandowsky, SkS is by far the most important. One might therefore expect that the majority of respondents to the survey came from SkS (depending on the coverage you gave it, and the date at which you posted it, etc.)<br />
At two of the six (Tamino’s and Deltoid) there was significant discussion of the survey, with people criticising and taking up positions. This, too, is interesting when it comes to interpreting the survey. So here are my questions:<br />
- The date the survey was posted<br />
- The date the post was deleted<br />
- Were there comments to the post? If so, how many, and are they still available, or were they deleted along with the original post?</p></blockquote>
<p>Cook&#8217;s reply was unresponsive to Chambers&#8217; question. Cook said that all he could find was an email from Lewandowsky on August 28 asking Cook to link to the survey:</p>
<blockquote><p>Hi Geoff, sorry for the delay in replying, very behind in my email correspondence at the moment plus for this email, had to fire up the old machine that I was using back in 2010 to find any email correspondence back then. All I can find is an email from Steve on 28 August 2010 asking for me to link to his survey.</p></blockquote>
<p>Chambers, increasingly frustrated, again asked Cook whether he did &#8220;in fact link to the survey&#8221;, suggesting that Cook had perhaps forgotten to post the link and that Lewandowsky&#8217;s count of blogs in his article was incorrect &#8211; nothing more than a &#8220;silly mistake&#8221; that Lewandowsky could &#8220;easily correct&#8221;:</p>
<blockquote><p>GC: Hi John. Thanks for the reply. So did you in fact link to his survey? It looks to me that you just forgot and didn&#8217;t post the link. So Stephan just assumed you had posted, and put in his paper the reference to eight blogs he&#8217;d contacted, including yours and the dormant NZ one. A silly mistake easily corrected. All he has to do is correct the &#8220;eight blogs&#8221; in his paper to six. Can you confirm that his survey was not in fact linked from Skeptical Science?</p></blockquote>
<p>Rather than conceding the point, Cook re-iterated that he had linked to the Lewandowsky survey:</p>
<blockquote><p>I did provide a link to the survey.</p></blockquote>
<p>Increasingly frustrated, Chambers once again asked Cook for details on when the supposed link had been put up:</p>
<blockquote><p>GC: Hi John. Any chance of telling us when you put up the link? Sorry to keep pestering you but you are being a bit coy.</p></blockquote>
<p>In response, Cook reported that he had &#8220;no records in the blog archives&#8221;, but claimed that he had found email correspondence between himself and Lewandowsky confirming that Lewandowsky had asked him to post a link to the survey and that Cook had replied on the same day that he had posted the link. Cook described the quality of the confirmation as &#8220;forensic evidence&#8221;.</p>
<blockquote><p>I&#8217;ve given you everything I&#8217;ve got &#8211; I have no records in the blog archives (I searched the database for kwiksurvey, came up empty) so I must&#8217;ve either deleted the text link or deleted the blog post once the survey had closed. <strong>The only forensic evidence I could find was the email from Stephan asking for me to post a link and my reply that I posted it on the same day.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Subsequently, the actual email correspondence between Cook and Lewandowsky has been obtained through FOI.  It completely confirms Chambers&#8217; original surmise that Cook had sent out a tweet but forgot or otherwise failed to place a linking blogpost at SKS. It shows that Lewandowsky&#8217;s claim to have &#8220;made a note&#8221; of the linking blogpost was untrue. And as to Cook&#8217;s claim that his email correspondence was &#8220;forensic evidence&#8221; containing his &#8220;reply that I posted it on the same day&#8221;? Surely it can only be described as a baldfaced lie.</p>
<p><strong>The <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/tag/lewandowsky/">FOI Correspondence</a> from August 2010<br />
</strong><br />
On August 28, 2010, Lewandowsky emailed Cook as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>Hi , I am ready to launch my internet-based survey &#8230; I think I mentioned this to you before; the instrument is now ready to rock-n-roll. The link is shown below: <a href="http://www" rel="nofollow">http://www</a>. kwiksurveys. com/online-survey. php ?surveyiD=HKMKNG ee191483</p>
<p>As you are my first &#8220;customer&#8221; I am not exactly sure how best to launch this, but ideally it would be some sort of flashing button that says &#8220;Contribute to Research-Record your attitudes about science by clicking here&#8221; or some such. Not sure the flashing button will work, but maybe you&#8217;ve got some idea? If you do write a post about it, maybe best not to mention my name but just anonymously refer to &#8220;researchers at the UWA&#8221; or some such?</p>
<p>let me know what you think &#8230; I am happy to draft something if you need me to.<br />
Cheers Steve</p>
<p>PS: I will circulate this among the planet30 folks once I&#8217;ve got a good way sorted with you in how to link into this.</p></blockquote>
<p>The &#8220;planet30 folks&#8221; is a reference to the private <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?hl=en&amp;fromgroups#!forum/planet30">planet3.0 googlegroup</a>, which is composed of activists and from which skeptics are excluded. In addition to Lewandowsky, other participants include Tim Lambert (Deltoid), Grant Foster (Tamino), Barry Bickmore, Coby Beck (Ill Considered) , Scott Mandia and Gareth ^ (Hot Topic).</p>
<p>At 11:20 am on August 28, Cook replied that he had filled out the survey. Cook ironically noted that his only information on the JFK assassination came from Oliver Stone, a prominent advocate of JFK conspiracy theory: </p>
<blockquote><p>Well, I filled out the survey. Problem is after you click Finish, it just goes to the kwiksurveys.com homepage so there&#8217;s no message saying you&#8217;ve filled it out correctly. I think this is a bit of a faux pas as far as web functionality goes &#8211; people like to know whether their results were received.</p>
<p>Some of those conspiracy theories, I have no clue about &#8211; Oliver Stone is the only source of info I have for the JFK assassination <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':-)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p></blockquote>
<p>Cook suggested that he simply start off with a tweet:</p>
<blockquote><p>
<strong>How about I start off with a tweet, something like: Help UWA research attitudes about science &#8211; fill out this online survey</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Lew replied that a &#8220;tweet for starters&#8221; was fine:</p>
<blockquote><p>Hi , a tweet for starters sounds good. I&#8217;ll see what I can do about the end-of-survey message; this is obviously constrained by the software.</p></blockquote>
<p>Cook asked if Lewandowsky wanted to make further changes to the survey before Cook sent out a tweet:</p>
<blockquote><p>Let me know if you&#8217;d like me to tweet now or would like to tweak the system first.</p></blockquote>
<p>Lewandowsky confirmed that Cook might as well send out his tweet:</p>
<blockquote><p>Hi &#8230; umm, tweet now. Not sure I can tweak much.</p></blockquote>
<p>Cook sent out the tweet which Woods had already located (<a href="https://twitter.com/skepticscience/status/22332844414">online here</a>). It was word-for-word identical to his email to Lewandowsky. </p>
<p>Cook told Lewandowsky that Cook was &#8220;hoping&#8221; to do his own online survey and that he would &#8220;probably&#8221; mention Lewandowsky&#8217;s at the same time:</p>
<blockquote><p>I&#8217;m hoping to post my own (much simpler) survey online shortly &#8211; when I blog post about that. I&#8217;ll probably include mention yours at the same time if show you the blog post when I&#8217;m ready to go).</p></blockquote>
<p>Lewandowsky agreed with the plan:</p>
<blockquote><p>thanks, sounds good.</p></blockquote>
<p>As noted above, Cook&#8217;s failure to post a link at SKS can be unequivocally verified on the Wayback machine, as Chambers, Woods and others had reported at the time and as summarized at CA <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2012/09/14/the-sks-link-to-the-lewandowsky-survey/">here</a>.  The Wayback archive took a <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20100830081833/http://www.skepticalscience.com/">screenshot</a> of the SkS home page on August 30. Below is a screenshot of the SKS homepage showing all posts bracketing August 28, the date that Lewandowsky and Cook claimed that SKS had posted a link. It does not show any post linking to the Lewandowsky survey, (Nor does it appear in the <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20100905061442/http://www.skepticalscience.com/">screenshot</a> for the following week which shows posts starting on August 31.)</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sks-screenshot-1.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sks-screenshot-1.png?w=537&#038;h=747" alt="" title="sks screenshot 1" width="537" height="747" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16760" /></a></p>
<p>The &#8220;forensic evidence&#8221; &#8211; which Cook had characterized as containing his &#8220;reply [to Lewandowsky] that [Cook] posted it [the blog link] on the same day&#8221; &#8211; clearly contradicts Cook&#8217;s assertion to Chambers.  The email correspondence unequivocally shows that Cook did not put up an SKS blog post as he had claimed.  The email correspondence is entirely consistent with Chambers&#8217; original surmise: that Cook had only sent out a tweet, but had not done a blog post.</p>
<p>Worse, when one places the actual email correspondence against Cook&#8217;s statement to Chambers about the email, it is evident that Cook had consulted the 2010 emails in question and had deliberately misrepresented them to Chambers.</p>
<p>In an email to Cook on February 14, 2013, I sent a detailed review of the above events and asked Cook to defend himself, concluding my email as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>Not to put too fine a point on it, it appears to me that you lied, when you asserted that your correspondence with Lewandowsky on 28 August 2010 was “forensic evidence” that showed that you had posted a link at Skeptical Science to the Lewandowsky survey on that day.  I use the word “lie” because you had clearly examined the 28 August 2010 correspondence at the time of your email to Chambers and knew that this correspondence did not show that you had posted a link at Skeptical Science to the Lewandowsky survey on 28 August 2010 or any other day. </p>
<p>Before I make any public statements about this matter, I am offering you an opportunity to rebut the belief that the statement bolded above was a lie. </p></blockquote>
<p>Cook did not respond.</p>
<p><strong>The <em>Hoax</em> SI</strong><br />
As Chambers had originally pointed out, it would have been easy enough for Lewandowsky to slightly amend the text of the <em>Hoax</em> article, to say that links had been posted on <em>seven</em> blogs, rather than eight blogs.  Lewandowsky was aware of the evidence showing that there never was any SKS blogpost since a side comment in the contemporary CA <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2012/09/14/the-sks-link-to-the-lewandowsky-survey/">post</a> about the fictitious SKS blogpost was cited in <em>Fury</em>. </p>
<p>However, in the final published version of the <em>Hoax</em>, Lewandowsky not only continued to assert that he had contacted eight blogs, but added a discussion of blog participants at SKS. </p>
<p>In the &#8220;accepted&#8221; article (and in the published version), Lewandowsky had merely stated:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Participants:</em>  Visitors to climate blogs voluntarily completed an online questionnaire between August and October 2010 (N = 1377). Links were posted on 8 blogs (with a pro-science science stance but with a diverse audience); a further 5 &#8220;skeptic&#8221; (or &#8220;skeptic&#8221;-leaning) blogs were approached but none posted the link.
</p></blockquote>
<p>However, in the SI to the published version, Lewandowsky substantially amplified the discussion, with multiple references to SKS as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>
<em>Prevalence of &#8220;skeptics&#8221; among blog visitors </em> All of the blogs that carried the link to the survey broadly endorsed the scientific consensus on climate change (see Table S1). As evidenced by the comment streams, however, their readership was broad and encompassed a wide range of view on climate change. To illustrate, a content analysis of 1067 comments from unique visitors to <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com" rel="nofollow">http://www.skepticalscience.com</a>, conducted by the proprietor of the blog, revealed that around 20% (N = 222) held clearly &#8220;skeptical&#8221; views, with the remainder (N = 845) endorsing the scientific consensus. At the time the research was conducted (September 2010), <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com" rel="nofollow">http://www.skepticalscience.com</a> received 390,000 monthly visits. Extrapolating from the content analysis of the comments, this translates into up to 78,000 visits from &#8220;skeptics&#8221; at the time when the survey was open (although it cannot be ascertained how many of the visitors actually saw the link.) </p>
<p>For comparison, a survey of the U. S. public in June 2010 pegged the proportion of &#8220;skeptics&#8221; in the population at 18% (Leiserowitz, Maibach, Roser-Renouf, &amp; Smith, 2011). Comparable surveys in other countries (e. g., Australia; Leviston &amp; Walker, 2010) yielded similar estimates for the same time period. The proportion of &#8220;skeptics&#8221; who comment at <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com" rel="nofollow">http://www.skepticalscience.com</a> is thus roughly commensurate with their proportion in the population at large.</p></blockquote>
<p>Lewandowsky&#8217;s claim that &#8220;it cannot be ascertained how many of the visitors [to SKS} actually saw the link&#8221; is merely the latest untrue claim.  In fact, the number of SKS visitors who saw an SKS link to the Lewandowsky survey can be precisely ascertained: it was <strong>zero</strong>.  </p>
<p>Nor, as was observed at various blogs last fall, can readership figures be extrapolated from SKS to the other even more more antagonistic blogs. The relevant content analysis is not at SKS, but at Deltoid and Tamino, blogs where the Lewandowsky link was actually published and where &#8220;skeptic&#8221; comments are few and far between.</p>
<p>Last fall, long before Lewandowsky had expanded his accusations of &#8220;conspiracist ideation&#8221; to include the UK Met Office, one of Lewandowsky&#8217;s coauthors (presumably Cook) observed that Lewandowsky&#8217;s critics were actually accusing him of &#8220;lying/deceiving/incompetence&#8221; rather than &#8220;conspiracy&#8221;:</p>
<blockquote><p>Maybe we should address more head-on the inevitable criticism that they’re not accusing you of conspiracy because lying/deceiving/incompetence doesn’t necessarily involve conspiring. </p></blockquote>
<p>On this point at least &#8211; the need for Lewandowsky to address issues of &#8220;Lying/deceiving/incompetence&#8221; &#8211; even Lewandowsky&#8217;s coauthors and critics appear to have found common ground. </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17385/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17385/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17385&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/28/lewandowsky-doubles-down/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>184</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sks-screenshot-1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sks screenshot 1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bent Their Core Tops In</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 17:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birdmen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marcott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[md01-2421]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MD95-2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MD95-2043]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OCE326-GGC30]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17592</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In today&#8217;s post, I&#8217;m going to show Marcott-Shakun redating in several relevant cases. The problem, as I&#8217;ve said on numerous occasions, has nothing to do with the very slight recalibration of radiocarbon dates from CALIB 6.0.1 (essentially negligible in the modern period in discussion here), but with Marcott-Shakun core top redating. Marcott et al re-dating [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17592&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In today&#8217;s post, I&#8217;m going to show Marcott-Shakun redating in several relevant cases. The problem, as I&#8217;ve said on numerous occasions, has nothing to do with the very slight recalibration of radiocarbon dates from CALIB 6.0.1 (essentially negligible in the modern period in discussion here), but with Marcott-Shakun core top redating. <span id="more-17592"></span></p>
<p>Marcott et al re-dating appears to originate from the following:</p>
<blockquote><p>Core tops are assumed to be 1950 AD unless otherwise indicated in original publication.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>MD95-2043<br />
</strong><br />
The most recent radiocarbon date for this core was at 14 cm. The radiocarbon reading (1980) was converted by the authors using CALIB4.1to 1527BP.  Marcott showed CALIB 6.0.1 upper and lower bounds, the average of which was 1535BP. Marcott showed a date of 1535BP for the alkenone sample at 14 cm.  The differences between CALIB4.1 calibrated dates and CALIB6.0.1 calibrated dates in the last two millennia are negligible &#8211; single digit years.  </p>
<p>The sedimentation rate between the final two radiocarbon points of MD95-2043 was 26.7 cm/kyr.  The original authors (Cacho et al 1999;2001) dated samples above the most recent radiocarbon date by assuming a continuation of these sedimentation rates, thus interpreting the top 14 cm as covering the period from 1537BP to a coretop of 1007.6 BP.  This implies core loss from the piston core of about 26 cm, a fairly typical result.  (Box cores are used when recovery of surface sediments is desired.)   </p>
<p>In contrast, Marcott et al 2013 dated the coretop to 0BP (1950 AD) and interpolated dates back to the radiocarbon date at 14 cm.  In effect, Marcott et al presumed that the sedimentation had fallen to one-third of previously observed rates (&#8220;unprecedented&#8221;?). The difference is shown in the graphic below, which compares the age-depth according to the original authors to the age-depth of Marcott et al. It shows that there is negligible difference between published and Marcott radiocarbon dates. </p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md95-2043.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md95-2043.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="age depth MD95-2043" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17588" /></a></p>
<p>The next graphic compares the temperature estimates using published dates to temperature estimates using Marcott et al dates. The two are essentially identical up to just before AD500. But whereas the original authors date the next few cm to late first millennium,  Marcott et al dilate the data to go from AD500 to AD1950, reassigning the core top from AD943 to AD1950.</p>
<p>Marcott state in their archive &#8211; in my opinion, with unwarranted optimism  &#8211; that there is zero uncertainty in the 0 BP dating of the core top.  </p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md95-2043-recent.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md95-2043-recent.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="MD95-2043 recent" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17589" /></a><br />
Figure 2. MD95-2043 Temperature Estimates. </p>
<p>I do not take the position that non-specialists such as Marcott, Shakun, Clark and Mix are precluded from arguing that core dating by the original authors was incorrect and proposing their own alternative dating with the reasons laid out in the sunshine for relevant specialists to assess. However, that&#8217;s not what happened here.  There was no listing of re-dated cores with the before and after core top dates.  The only hint of anything going on with core tops was the following statement in the SI: </p>
<blockquote><p>Core tops are assumed to be 1950 AD unless otherwise indicated in original publication.</p></blockquote>
<p>This seems innocuous enough on the surface, but that&#8217;s not what Marcott et al actually did.  For example, here is an excerpt from the NOAA MD95-2043 archive, where the core top is indicated to be 1007.6 BP. </p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md95-2043-excerpt.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md95-2043-excerpt.png?w=526&#038;h=142" alt="MD95-2043 excerpt" width="526" height="142" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17597" /></a></p>
<p><strong>MD95-2011</strong><br />
That core loss at surface in piston cores can be 26 cm or so should not be any surprise. Indeed, it seems to me to be a credit to the carefulness of the drillers that core losses are as low as this.  Core loss in piston cores can be approximately estimated if there is a contiguous box core. (Box cores don&#8217;t go as deep as piston cores, but have much better recovery of near-surface sediments.)</p>
<p>MD95-2011, used twice by Marcott et al (#8 and #13), is another piston core, but in this case, there is a contiguous box core JM97-948-2A.  These cores were discussed at CA in 2007 in connection with Loehle 2007.  At the time, Richard Telford mentioned that he thought that alkenone results for JM97-948-2A had been measured but not published. They remain unpublished six years later: this is too bad as this would have provided an important addition to very scarce high-resolution alkenone records.</p>
<p>Pb210 dating confirmed the modernity of the top 10 cm of box core JM-948-2A, which was dated from 5-80 BP (1870-1945AD.)  At 30.5 cm, box core JM-948-2A had a radiocarbon calibrated date of 579BP (radiocarbon 940BP), while MD95-2011 had a near contemporary date at 10.5 cm (601 BP &#8211; radiocarbon 980 BP).  The data from the box core clearly indicates core loss of somewhat more than 20 cm at MD95-2011.  </p>
<p>The original authors dated the 10.5 cm of MD95-2011 above the latest radiocarbon date to approximately 50 years, assigning the core top to 510 BP.  In contrast, Marcott et al assigned the core top to 0 BP, using the same methodology as MD95-2043. This is illustrated in the age-depth comparisons shown below.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md95-2011.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md95-2011.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="age-depth MD95-2011" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17590" /></a><br />
Figure 3. MD95-2011 and JM97-948-2A age-depth diagram.</p>
<p>As with MD95-2043, the Marcott re-dating dilates the time series after 560BP, so that data assigned by the original authors to 510BP is Marcott-dated to 0BP.</p>
<p><strong>MD01-2421 Splice </strong><br />
The above two examples illustrate one face of Marcott et al re-dating. However, there is a second and even more puzzling aspect: their re-dating of cores which actually do have 20th century samples.</p>
<p>I started analysis of this in my post two days ago in which I drew attention to Marcott et al&#8217;s truncation of the final three (highly negative) values of the MD01-2421 splice. MD01-2421 is a piston core with considerable core loss. It was combined with contiguous gravity and box cores to yield a continuous record into the 20th century. The modernity of the top portion of the box core was unequivocally confirmed by the presence of a bomb spike, a commonly used marker. Out of all the ocean cores in the Marcott network, this series undoubtedly has the best dated modern material.</p>
<p>In the graphic below, I&#8217;ve compared the age-depth diagrams from the original information to Marcott&#8217;s re-dating.  As noted yesterday, the three most recent values are truncated from Marcott calculations. Oddly the other recent values are dated somewhat younger by Marcott. The sample dated to 1922 AD by Isono et al is dated to 1939AD by Marcott (just missing inclusion in the 1940 roster.) I have no idea what they&#8217;re doing here.  It is possible that some algorithm has gone awry (as opposed to Briffa&#8217;s manual deletion &#8211; commonly and incorrectly described as &#8220;MIke&#8217;s Nature trick&#8221;).   Again, I am presently mystified.  I emailed Marcott for an explanation yesterday, but thus far no response.  In my next example, I&#8217;ll look at a related series for further clues.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md01-2421-splice.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md01-2421-splice.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="age depth MD01-2421 splice" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17594" /></a></p>
<p><strong>OCE326-GGC300</strong><br />
OCE326-GGC300 was identified in an earlier post as one of two highly negative proxies (the MD01-2421 splice was the other) that had been disappeared from the 1940 network, the removal of which &#8220;explained&#8221; the 1940 uptick in the alkenone and dependent reconstructions.</p>
<p>This series was published by Julian Sachs, an accomplished specialist. Radiocarbon dates at 0, 2.5 and 12.5 cm all have &#8220;modern&#8221; radiocarbon dates &#8211; dates that are not further resolvable using radiocarbon.  (In passing, Pb210 dating on this core would be very useful.)  Sachs showed a date of 0 BP for all measurements between 0 and 12.5 cm in his archive <a href="ftp://ftp.ncdc.noaa.gov/pub/data/paleo/contributions_by_author/sachs2007/sachs2007.txt">here</a> and in a summary <a href="ftp://ftp.ncdc.noaa.gov/pub/data/paleo/paleocean/sediment_files/complete/o326gc30-fwc.txt">here</a> dated the coretop (0.5 cm) to 0BP, an assumption that on its face is identical to the declared methodology of Marcott et al. </p>
<p>However, once again, the Marcott calculation truncated the most recent values. The diagram below is an attempt to summarize the information.  The black line shows the Sachs age-depth diagram from <a href="ftp://ftp.ncdc.noaa.gov/pub/data/paleo/paleocean/sediment_files/complete/o326gc30-fwc.txt">here</a> with the coretop (0.5 cm) dated to 0 BP. The black + points show the sample measurements as reported (with unresolved &#8220;modern&#8221; samples).  The red horizontal arrows show the radiocarbon upper and lower dates as archived by Marcott et al.  Marcott&#8217;s archive also shows radiocarbon dates for 0.5 cm and 2.5 cm which have been set to NA (shown here in blue.)   The most recent sample used in the Marcott calculation came from 12.5 cm, with the seven higher samples being excluded.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oce326-ggc30-age-depth1.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oce326-ggc30-age-depth1.png?w=560&#038;h=480" alt="OCE326-GGC30 age depth" width="560" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17599" /></a><br />
Figure ^.  OCE326-GGC Age- Depth Diagram.</p>
<p>The next diagram compares the two versions as time-temperature plots, as shown below. (Note that Published is black this time and Marcott red.)  If the coretop were dated at 0 BP and dates for samples between 0.5 and 16.5 cm interpolated, this would yield a series continuing to the present, with alkenone-indicated temperatures continuing to decline (for whatever reason.)  Instead, Marcott&#8217;s series ends in the late 18th century and does not contribute to the 20th century network (which is primarily composed of coretops from different centuries and even millennia.)  </p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oce326-ggc30-recent.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oce326-ggc30-recent.png?w=680&#038;h=480" alt="OCE326-GGC30 recent" width="680" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17600" /></a><br />
Figure ^. OCE326-GGC30 Temperature Reconstruction Comparison. Black- published; red &#8211; Marcott; blue- excluded.</p>
<p><strong>Summary</strong><br />
Both types of example result in serious errors, though of different types. </p>
<p>At this stage, I can more or less see what they did in the MD95-2043 class of examples. As noted above, if this was done intentionally and with knowledge of the effect of the re-dating on coretop dates, this should have been disclosed with red letter caveats, showing the effect of the redating on affected cores and relevant specialists should have been asked to review the reasonableness of the methodology. (I do not believe that a properly informed specialist would have signed off on this redating, let alone with no caveats.)  Nor do I believe that the actual calculations are consistent with the methodological statement &#8220;core tops are assumed to be 1950 AD unless otherwise indicated in original publication&#8221;, since core tops were re-dated to 1950 regardless of what was indicated in the original publication.  This seems just as serious to me as the problem with Gergis et al.</p>
<p>The problems with the cores with actual modern values are over and above this.  I don&#8217;t think that they manually blanked out modern values (I hope not for their sakes.) I presume that some algorithm went awry, but right now I can&#8217;t picture what sort of algorithm would yield the observed truncations.  I&#8217;m sure that we&#8217;ll find out in due course. As noted above, I&#8217;ve requested an explanation from Marcott and hopefully he will clarify things.</p>
<p>Not unexpectedly, William Connolley&#8217;s <a href="http://scienceblogs.com/stoat/2013/03/11/a-reconstruction-of-regional-and-global-temperature-for-the-past-11300-years/#comment-28436">reaction</a> to the problems with Marcott dating is the same sort of wilful obtuseness that characterized &#8220;professional&#8221; responses to Mann&#8217;s use of contaminated (and upside down) Korttajarvi sediments.   Connolley pretended that this is nothing more than recalibration of radiocarbon dates. </p>
<blockquote><p>If you think the &#8220;secret&#8221; of re-dating comes from &#8220;McIntyre&#8217;s latest analysis&#8221; you&#8217;ve been sold a pup. The re-dating is in the SOM itself: The majority of our age-control points are based on radiocarbon dates. In order to 67 compare the records appropriately, we recalibrated all radiocarbon dates.</p>
<p>So I&#8217;m curious &#8211; who sold you this pup? And why didn&#8217;t you bother check the original? -W]</p></blockquote>
<p>On the hand, Paul Dennis, in a thoughtful comment at Bishop Hill, had no difficulty in understanding the difference between core top redating and radiocarbon calibration.</p>
<blockquote><p>One can only guess at what Marcott et al were attempting to do when they made gross adjustments to core top dates. It is one thing to run a new, for example 14-C calibration, that will make small adjustments to age models but a completely different issue to redetermine core top dates by such gross margins.
</p></blockquote>
<p>As to the title of this post.  I was reminded a few weeks ago of the &#8220;Junior Birdmen&#8221; ditty, which was sung at YMCA and Cubs and camps in the 1950s &#8211; a ditty that seemed especially apt for Upside Down Mann, who serves as inspiration for Marcott and Shakun. Its chorus goes:</p>
<blockquote><p>Up in the air&#8230; the Junior Birdmen<br />
Up in the air and upside down<br />
UP in the air&#8230; the Junior Birdmen<br />
Keep their helmets to the ground</p></blockquote>
<p>The Junior Birdmen were apprentice pilots who were flying upside down. The verse talks about &#8220;box tops&#8221;, which slightly modified to the present circumstances:</p>
<blockquote><p>
And when they make&#8230; the grand announcement,<br />
That things are worse than they&#8217;ve ever been&#8230;<br />
You can be sure&#8230; the Junior Birdmen<br />
Have bent their core tops in.</p>
<p>Up in the air&#8230; the Junior Birdmen<br />
Up in the air and upside down<br />
UP in the air&#8230; the Junior Birdmen<br />
Keep their helmets to the ground</p></blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17592/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17592/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17592&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>334</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md95-2043.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">age depth MD95-2043</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md95-2043-recent.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">MD95-2043 recent</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md95-2043-excerpt.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">MD95-2043 excerpt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md95-2011.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">age-depth MD95-2011</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/age-depth-md01-2421-splice.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">age depth MD01-2421 splice</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oce326-ggc30-age-depth1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">OCE326-GGC30 age depth</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oce326-ggc30-recent.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">OCE326-GGC30 recent</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hiding the Decline: MD01-2421</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/17/hiding-the-decline-the-md01-2421-splice/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/17/hiding-the-decline-the-md01-2421-splice/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 16:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alkenone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marcott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[md01-2421]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17576</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As noted in my previous post, Marcott, Shakun, Clark and Mix disappeared two alkenone cores from the 1940 population, both of which were highly negative. In addition, they made some surprising additions to the 1940 population, including three cores whose coretops were dated by competent specialists 500-1000 years earlier. While the article says that ages [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17576&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As noted in my previous post, Marcott, Shakun, Clark and Mix disappeared two alkenone cores from the 1940 population, both of which were highly negative. In addition, they made some surprising additions to the 1940 population, including three cores whose coretops were dated by competent specialists 500-1000 years earlier. </p>
<p>While the article says that ages were recalibrated with CALIB6.0.1, the differences between CALIB6.0.1 and previous radiocarbon calibrations is <strong>not</strong> material to the coretop dating issues being discussed here.  Further, Marcott&#8217;s thesis used CALIB6.0.1, but had very different coretop dates.  Marcott et al stated in their SI that &#8220;Core tops are assumed to be 1950 AD unless otherwise indicated in original publication&#8221;. This is not the procedure that I&#8217;ve observed in the data.  Precisely what they&#8217;ve done is still unclear, but it&#8217;s something different. </p>
<p>In today&#8217;s post, I&#8217;ll examine their proxy #23, an alkenone series of Isono et al 2009. This series is a composite of a piston core (MD01-2421), a gravity core (KR02-06 St. A GC) and a box/multiple core (KR02-06 St A MC1), all taken at the same location.  Piston cores are used for deep time, but lose the top portion of the core. Coretops of piston cores can be hundreds or even a few thousand years old.  Box cores are shallow cores and the presently preferred technique for recovering up-to-date results.</p>
<p>There are vanishingly few alkenone series where there is a high-resolution box core accompanying Holocene data. Indeed, within the entire Marcott corpus of ocean cores, the MD01-241/KNR02-06 splice is unique in being dated nearly to the present. Its published end date was -41BP (1991AD). Convincing support for modern dating of the top part of the box core is the presence of a bomb spike: </p>
<blockquote><p>
A sample from 3 cm depth in the MC core showed a bomb spike. The high sedimentation rate (average 31 cm/ka) over the last 7000 years permits analysis at multidecade resolution with an average sample spacing of ~32 years.</p></blockquote>
<p>Despite this evidence for modern sediments, Marcott et al blanked out the top three measurements as shown below:</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md01-2421-excerpt.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md01-2421-excerpt.png?w=484&#038;h=126" alt="md01-2421 excerpt" width="484" height="126" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17577" /></a><br />
Table 1. Excerpt from Marcott et al spreadsheet</p>
<p>By blanking out the three most recent values of their proxy #23, the earliest dated value was 10.93 BP (1939.07 AD). As a result, the MD01-2421+KNR02-06 alkenone series was excluded from the 1940 population. I am unable to locate any documented methodology that would lead to the blanking out of the last three values of this dataset. Nor am I presently aware of any rational basis for excluding the three most recent values. </p>
<p>Since this series was strongly negative in the 20th century, its removal (together with the related removal of OCE326-GGC30 and the importation of medieval data) led to the closing uptick.</p>
<p>BTW in the original publication, Isono et al 2009 reported a decrease in SST from Holocene to modern times that is much larger than the Marcott NHX estimate of less than 1 deg C, reporting as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>
the SST decreased by ~5 °C to the present (16.7 °C), with high-frequency variations of ~1 °C amplitude (Fig. 2).</p></blockquote>
<p>A plot of this series is shown below, with the &#8220;present&#8221; value reported by Isono et al shown as a red dot.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md03-2421-splice.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md03-2421-splice.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="MD03-2421 splice" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17578" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17576/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17576/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17576&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/17/hiding-the-decline-the-md01-2421-splice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>240</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md01-2421-excerpt.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">md01-2421 excerpt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/md03-2421-splice.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">MD03-2421 splice</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Marcott-Shakun Dating Service</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/16/the-marcott-shakun-dating-service/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/16/the-marcott-shakun-dating-service/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 18:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marcott]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17557</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Marcott, Shakun, Clark and Mix did not use the published dates for ocean cores, instead substituting their own dates. The validity of Marcott-Shakun re-dating will be discussed below, but first, to show that the re-dating &#8220;matters&#8221; (TM-climate science), here is a graph showing reconstructions using alkenones (31 of 73 proxies) in Marcott style, comparing the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17557&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marcott, Shakun, Clark and Mix did not use the published dates for ocean cores, instead substituting their own dates. The validity of Marcott-Shakun re-dating will be discussed below, but first, to show that the re-dating &#8220;matters&#8221; (TM-climate science), here is a graph showing reconstructions using alkenones (31 of 73 proxies) in Marcott style, comparing the results with published dates (red) to results with Marcott-Shakun dates (black). As you see, there is a persistent decline in the alkenone reconstruction in the 20th century using published dates, but a 20th century increase using Marcott-Shakun dates.  (It is taking all my will power not to make an obvious comment at this point.)<br />
<a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-comparison1.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-comparison1.png?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="alkenone-comparison" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17565" /></a><br />
Figure 1. Reconstructions from alkenone proxies in Marcott style. Red- using published dates; black- using Marcott-Shakun dates.</p>
<p>Marcott et al archived an alkenone reconstruction. There are discrepancies between the above emulation and the archived reconstruction, a topic that I&#8217;ll return to on another occasion. (I&#8217;ve tried diligently to reconcile, but am thus far unable. Perhaps due to some misunderstanding on my part of Marcott methodology, some inconsistency between data as used and data as archived or something else.)  However, I do not believe that this matters for the purposes of using my emulation methodology to illustrate the effect of Marcott-Shakun re-dating.</p>
<p><strong>ALkenone Core Re-dating<br />
</strong><br />
The table below summarizes Marcott-Shakun redating for all alkenone cores with either published end-date or Marcott end-date being less than 50 BP (AD1900). I&#8217;ve also shown the closing temperature of each series (&#8220;close&#8221;) after the two Marcot re-centering steps (as I understand them).<br />
<a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-core-redating-table1.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-core-redating-table1.png?w=439&#038;h=208" alt="alkenone core redating table" width="439" height="208" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17568" /></a></p>
<p>The final date of the Marcott reconstruction is AD1940 (BP10). Only three cores contributed to the final value of the reconstruction with published dates ( &#8220;pubend&#8221; less than 10): the MD01-2421 splice, OCE326-GGC30 and M35004-4.  Two of these cores have very negative values. Marcot et al re-dated both of these cores so that neither contributed to the closing period:  the MD01-2421 splice to a fraction of a year prior to 1940, barely missing eligibility; OCE326-GGC30 is re-dated 191 years earlier &#8211; into the 18th century.  </p>
<p>Re-populating the closing date are 5 cores with published coretops earlier than AD10, in some cases much earlier.  The coretop of MD95-2043, for example, was published as 10th century, but was re-dated by Marcott over 1000 years later to &#8220;0 BP&#8221;. MD95-2011 and MD-2015 were redated by 510 and 690 years respectively.  All five re-dated cores contributing to the AD1940 reconstruction had positive values.  </p>
<p>In a follow-up post, I&#8217;ll examine the validity of Marcott-Shakun redating. If the relevant specialists had been aware of or consulted on the Marcott-Shakun redating, I&#8217;m sure that they would have contested it.</p>
<p>Jean S had observed that the Marcott thesis had already described a re-dating of the cores using CALIB 6.0.1 as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>All radiocarbon based ages were recalibrated with CALIB 6.0.1 using INTCAL09 and its protocol (Reimer, 2009) for the site-specific locations and materials. Marine reservoir ages were taken from the originally published manuscripts.</p></blockquote>
<p>The SI to Marcott et al made an essentially identical statement (pdf, 8):</p>
<blockquote><p>The majority of our age-control points are based on radiocarbon dates. In order to compare the records appropriately, we recalibrated all radiocarbon dates with Calib 6.0.1 using INTCAL09 and its protocol (1) for the site-specific locations and materials. Any reservoir ages used in the ocean datasets followed the original authors’ suggested values, and were held constant unless otherwise stated in the original publication.</p></blockquote>
<p>However, the re-dating described above is SUBSEQUENT to the Marcott thesis. (I&#8217;ve confirmed this by examining plots of individual proxies on pages 200-201 of the thesis.  End dates illustrated in the thesis correspond more or less to published end dates and do not reflect the wholesale redating of the Science article.</p>
<p>I was unable to locate any reference to the wholesale re-dating in the text of Marcott et al 2013. The closest thing to a mention is the following statement in the SI:</p>
<blockquote><p>Core tops are assumed to be 1950 AD unless otherwise indicated in original publication.
</p></blockquote>
<p>However, something more than this is going on.  In some cases, Marcott et al have re-dated core tops indicated as 0 BP in the original publication. (Perhaps with justification, but this is not reported.)  In other cases, core tops have been assigned to 0 BP even though different dates have been reported in the original publication.  In another important case (of YAD061 significance as I will later discuss), Marcott et al ignored a major dating caveat of the original publication.</p>
<p>Examination of the re-dating of individual cores will give an interesting perspective on the cores themselves &#8211; an issue that, in my opinion, ought to have been addressed in technical terms by the authors. More on this in a forthcoming post.</p>
<p>The moral of today&#8217;s post for ocean cores. Are you an ocean core that is tired of your current date? Does your current date make you feel too old? Or does it make you feel too young?  Try the Marcott-Shakun dating service. Ashley Madison for ocean cores.  Confidentiality is guaranteed.  </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17557/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17557/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17557&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/16/the-marcott-shakun-dating-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>276</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-comparison1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alkenone-comparison</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/alkenone-core-redating-table1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alkenone core redating table</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Marcottian Upticks Arise</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/how-marcottian-upticks-arise/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/how-marcottian-upticks-arise/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 22:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marcott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uptick]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17543</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m working towards a post on the effect of Marcott re-dating, but first I want to document some points on the methodology of Marcott et al 2013 and to remove some speculation on the Marcott upticks, which do not arise from any of the main speculations. In the graphic below, I&#8217;ve plotted Marcott&#8217;s NHX reconstruction [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17543&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m working towards a post on the effect of Marcott re-dating, but first I want to document some points on the methodology of Marcott et al 2013 and to remove some speculation on the Marcott upticks, which do not arise from any of the main speculations. </p>
<p>In the graphic below, I&#8217;ve plotted Marcott&#8217;s NHX reconstruction against an emulation (weighting by latitude and gridcell as described in script) using proxies with <strong>published</strong> dates rather than Marcott dates. (I am using this version because it illustrates the uptick using Marcott methodology. Marcott re-dating is an important issue that I will return to.)  The uptick in the emulation occurs in 2000 rather than 1940; the slight offset makes it discernible for sharp eyes below.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/emulation-nh.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/emulation-nh.png?w=680&#038;h=380" alt="emulation -NH" width="680" height="380" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17544" /></a><br />
Figure 1. Marcott NHX reconstruction (red) versus emulation with non-redated proxies (yellow). The dotted lines at the left show the Younger Dryas. Marcott began their reported results shortly after the rapid emergence from the Younger Dryas, which is not shown in the graphics.</p>
<p>I have consistently discouraged speculation that the Marcott uptick arose from splicing Mannian data or temperature data. I trust that the above demonstration showing a Marcottian uptick merely using proxy data will put an end to such speculation. </p>
<p>The other &#8220;explanation&#8221; is that the uptick results from high-frequency swings in individual proxies. Marcott&#8217;s email to me encouraged such speculation. However, this is <strong>NOT</strong> what causes the uptick. Below I show the series that contribute to the NHX weighted average before and after the uptick.  The proxy values shown below have been re-centered to reflect Marcott recentering: (1) by -0.66 deg C to reflect the re-centering from mid-Holocene to 500-1450AD; (2) by -0.08 deg C to match the observed mean of Marcottian reconstructions in 500-1450 AD. </p>
<p>Readers will observe that there are 6 contributing series in the second-last step, of which 5 are negative, some strongly. Their weighted average is negative (not quite as negative as the penultimate Marcott value in 1920, but you see the effect.)  Only one series is present in the final step, one that, after the two rescaling steps, is slightly positive. Thus, the uptick. None of the contributing series have sharp high-frequency: their changes are negligible. Ironically, the one continuing series (Lake 850) actually goes down a little in the period of the uptick.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-nh-unredated.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-nh-unredated.png?w=636&#038;h=79" alt="excerpt nh unredated" width="636" height="79" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17547" /></a></p>
<p>Marcottian <del datetime="2013-03-15T21:59:11+00:00">uptricks</del> upticks arise because of proxy inconsistency: one (or two) proxies have different signs or quantities than the larger population, but continue one step longer. This is also the reason why the effect is mitigated in the infilled variation.  In principle, downticks can also occur &#8211; a matter that will be covered in my next post which will probably be on the relationship between Marcottian re-dating and upticks.</p>
<p>I have been unable to replicate some of the recent features of the Marcott zonal reconstructions. I think that there may be some differences in some series between the data as archived and as used in their reported calculations, though it may be a difference in methodology. More on this later.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17543/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17543/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17543&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/how-marcottian-upticks-arise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>78</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/emulation-nh.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">emulation -NH</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/excerpt-nh-unredated.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">excerpt nh unredated</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CG3: The Gold Medalist</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/cg3-the-gold-medalist/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/cg3-the-gold-medalist/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 21:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cg3]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17539</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last summer during the London Olympics, Josh had some fun with the &#8220;Climate Olympics&#8221;, with Mann at left in the iconic gold medal pose of Usain Bolt, the famous runner. Little did we know that during an earlier Olympics, Jones was disappointed at being silver medalist in statistical abuse &#8211; to gold medalist Mann. CG3 [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17539&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bolt_mann.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bolt_mann.png?w=360" alt="bolt_mann" width="360" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-17540" /></a>  Last summer during the London Olympics, Josh had some fun with the &#8220;Climate Olympics&#8221;, with Mann at left in the iconic gold medal pose of Usain Bolt, the famous runner.</p>
<p>Little did we know that during an earlier Olympics, Jones was disappointed at being silver medalist in statistical abuse &#8211; to gold medalist Mann.  CG3 1093965453:</p>
<blockquote><p>date: Tue Aug 31 11:17:33 2004<br />
from: Phil Jones
<p>
subject: Fwd: On the Role of Statistics in Climate Research, Tim Lambert, Phil Jones et al?<br />
to: Rasmus Benestad </p>
<p>    Rasmus and Mike,<br />
…<br />
In the email below, Mike seems to have won the gold medal for statistical abuse and I have the silver. I seemed to have tried too hard to explain my techniques. I tried really hard to get the gold medal &#8211; Mike has a degree in maths/stats ! I&#8217;ll have to redeem myself in AR4 and switch the places for the 2008 Olympiad &#8211; the AR4 coming out in 2007 should put me well in the lead.</p>
<p>I clearly didn&#8217;t allow for the knowledge of the judges &#8211; I think I&#8217;ll appeal!<br />
…<br />
Cheers<br />
Phil
</p></blockquote>
<p>The category remains hotly contested, with many new contestants. Jones, whatever his other sins, has tended to use fairly simple methods and I find it hard to picture him maintaining a spot on the podium. Mann, of course, has a repertoire of upside-down techniques that are highly regarded by climate referees and which make it very difficult for new contestants to seize the gold medal.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17539/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17539/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17539&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/cg3-the-gold-medalist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bolt_mann.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bolt_mann</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marcott&#8217;s Zonal Reconstructions</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/marcotts-zonal-reconstructions/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/marcotts-zonal-reconstructions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17521</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m going to do a detailed post on my diagnosis of the Marcott uptick, but before I do so, I want to comment on the reconstructions for NH and SH extratropics, neither of which have attracted sufficient notice though both are very remarkable. In a substantive sense, because orbital changes have different effects on NH [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17521&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m going to do a detailed post on my diagnosis of the Marcott uptick, but before I do so, I want to comment on the reconstructions for NH and SH extratropics, neither of which have attracted sufficient notice though both are very remarkable. In a substantive sense, because orbital changes have different effects on NH and SH, the difference between NHX and SHX proxies is a source of substantive interest and is what ought to have been reported on.</p>
<p>In the running text, Marcott et al had emphasized that their reconstruction was &#8220;indistinguishable within uncertainty&#8221;. This was illustrated in their Figure 1E, which showed the Mann08 GLB and NH reconstructions (which of several versions is not denoted in the caption), Moberg 2005 (NH) and the Wahl-Ammann version of MBH98 (NH). </p>
<blockquote><p>
Our global temperature reconstruction for the past 1500 years is indistinguishable within uncertainty from the Mann et al. (2) reconstruction&#8230; This similarity confirms that published temperature reconstructions of the past two millennia capture long-term variability, despite their short time span (3, 12, 13). </p></blockquote>
<p>The zonal (NHX, SHX and tropics) reconstructions were illustrated in Marcott Figure 2I,J,K, but Marcott et al conspicuously did not compare their zonal reconstructions with previous NH and SH reconstructions, instead comparing them to proxies often considered to be precipitation proxies. In their text, they stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>Trends in regional temperature reconstructions show strong similarities with high-resolution precipitation records, consistently associating greater warmth with greater wetness (Fig. 2, H to J). For example,  extratropical Northern Hemisphere mid-to- high–latitude temperature correlates well with records of Asian monsoon intensity (14, 15 -Dongge O18) and the position of the Atlantic intertropical convergence zone (16 &#8211; Cariaco) (Fig. 2H), tropical temperatures track precipitation proxies from speleothems in Borneo (17) and Indonesia (18) (Fig. 2I), and extratropical Southern Hemisphere temperatures parallel speleothem proxies of precipitation and temperature from South Africa (19) and South America (20) that are independent of our reconstruction</p></blockquote>
<p>Their decision not to compare their reconstruction to popular hemispherical versions was a curious one and I&#8217;ve remedied this apparent oversight below.</p>
<p><strong>Northern Hemisphere</strong><br />
First here is a comparison of the Marcott NH Extratropic reconstruction with the Moberg 2005 reconstruction (which Marcott et al showed in connection with their GLB reconstruction).  I suspect that some readers will not find these two series to be &#8220;remarkably similar&#8221; (TM- climate science). (For greater certainty, Marcott et al did not say that these two series were &#8220;remarkably similar&#8221;, he said that the Moberg NH reconstruction was similar to his GLB reconstruction, but omitted any direct comparison with his NHX reconstructions.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/moberg-vs-marcott.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/moberg-vs-marcott.png?w=720&#038;h=480" alt="moberg-vs-marcott" width="720" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17522" /></a><br />
Figure 1. Moberg NH versus Marcott et al NHX. Red dot shows 1990-2010 average HadCRU temperature. Dotted vertical black line at 1890 is period after which reconstruction already admitted to be &#8220;not robust&#8221;. </p>
<p>Next here is a comparison of the Marcott NHX reconstruction with two Mann reconstructions: the Mann 2008 NH EIV iHAD variation (which in effect splices temperature from 1850 on) and the MBH NHX version (extracted from Briffa et al 2001 SI). I am not persuaded that Marcott&#8217;s NHX reconstruction is &#8220;indistinguishable within uncertainty&#8221; from the corresponding NH reconstructions, making one wonder why the GLB reconstruction is are supposedly &#8220;indistinguighable within uncertainty&#8221;.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-vs-marcott.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-vs-marcott.png?w=720&#038;h=480" alt="mann-vs-marcott" width="720" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17524" /></a><br />
Figure 2. Marcott NHX versus M08 NH EIV iHAD and MBH98-99 NHX (from Briffa et al 2001). As Figure 1. </p>
<p><strong>Southern Hemisphere</strong><br />
In the figure below, I&#8217;ve first compared the Marcott et al SHX reconstruction to the SH reconstruction of Mann and Jones 2003.  After readers recover from their awe at the remarkable similarity (TM-climate science) between the two reconstructions, they will note that the Marcott reconstruction began a pronounced and dramatic increase in the 18th century and reached its maximum in AD1900, which, in their Northern Hemisphere reconstruction, was the coldest year since the LGM. Marcott&#8217;s estimated AD1900 temperatures in SHX were much higher than even recent temperatures (1990-2010 HadCRU SH average denoted by red dot.) </p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mj03-vs-marcott_sh.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mj03-vs-marcott_sh.png?w=720&#038;h=480" alt="mj03-vs-marcott_SH" width="720" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17527" /></a><br />
Figure 3. Marcott SHX vs Mann and Jones 2003 SH.</p>
<p>Finally, here is a comparison of Mann 2008 SH EIV-CRU and CPS-CRU versus Marcott. There are important inconsistencies between Mannian EIV and CPS results, improving the odds of matching at least one of them. (Why anyone would regard Mannian EIV as an &#8220;improvement&#8221; on anything is a continuing source of puzzlement to me, but that is another day&#8217;s story.) Even doubling the odds of a match, I find the correspondence between the Mannian and Marcottian version to be underwhelming, though perhaps not so underwhelming as to preclude them being &#8220;remarkably similar TM-climate science&#8221;.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-vs-marcott_sh.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-vs-marcott_sh.png?w=720&#038;h=480" alt="mann-vs-marcott_SH" width="720" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17528" /></a></p>
<p>I will return to details of the uptick later. For now, I&#8217;ll close with this graphic showing the NHX and SHX reconstructions against the GLB reconstruction shown as the Marcott base.  While one expects a difference between NHX and SHX in the Holocene, the remarkable difference between NHX and SHX not just in the 20th century, but in the 19th century is a source of considerable interest.  According to Marcott, NHX temperatures increased by 1.9 deg C between 1920 and 1940, a surprising result even for the most zealous activists.  But for the rest of us, given the apparent resiliency of our species to this fantastic increase over a mere 20 years, it surely must provide a small measure of hope for resiliency in the future.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure1b-loop1.gif"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure1b-loop1.gif?w=600&#038;h=480" alt="figure1B-loop" width="600" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17531" /></a><br />
Figure ^. SHX (blue) and NHX (red) shown against global.  Third zone (tropics) not shown only to emphasize contrast.  Full spaghetti would include a third zone.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17521/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17521/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17521&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/15/marcotts-zonal-reconstructions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>69</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/moberg-vs-marcott.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">moberg-vs-marcott</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-vs-marcott.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mann-vs-marcott</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mj03-vs-marcott_sh.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mj03-vs-marcott_SH</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mann-vs-marcott_sh.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mann-vs-marcott_SH</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure1b-loop1.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">figure1B-loop</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>No Uptick in Marcott Thesis</title>
		<link>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/14/no-uptick-in-marcott-thesis/</link>
		<comments>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/14/no-uptick-in-marcott-thesis/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 23:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve McIntyre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marcott]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://climateaudit.org/?p=17511</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reader ^ drew our attention to Marcott&#8217;s thesis (see chapter 4 here. Marcott&#8217;s thesis has a series of diagrams in an identical style as the Science article. The proxy datasets are identical. However, as Jean S alertly observed, the diagrams in the thesis lack the closing uptick of the Science. Other aspects of the modern [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17511&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Reader ^ drew our attention to Marcott&#8217;s thesis (see chapter 4 <a href="http://ir.library.oregonstate.edu/xmlui/bitstream/handle/1957/21129/MarcottShaunA2011.pdf?sequence=2">here</a>.  Marcott&#8217;s thesis has a series of diagrams in an identical style as the Science article. The proxy datasets are identical.</p>
<p>However, as Jean S alertly observed, the diagrams in the thesis lack the closing uptick of the Science.  Other aspects of the modern period also differ dramatically.</p>
<p>Here is Figure 1C of the Science article.</p>
<p><a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure-1c.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure-1c.png?w=593&#038;h=377" alt="figure 1C" width="593" height="377" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17512" /></a></p>
<p>Now here is the corresponding diagram from the thesis<br />
<a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thesis-short1.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thesis-short1.png?w=594&#038;h=377" alt="thesis-short1" width="594" height="377" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17513" /></a></p>
<p>The differences will be evident to readers. In addition to the difference in closing uptick, important reconstruction versions were at negative values in the closing portion of the thesis graphic, while they were at positive  values in the closing portion of the Science graphic.</p>
<p>I wonder what accounts for the difference. </p>
<p>A similar phenomenon occurs with the simulation diagram, that has been widely distributed as Stick support. Here is a blowup of the recent portion in Sciencemag:<br />
<a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/si-figure3-simulation-blowup.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/si-figure3-simulation-blowup.png?w=493&#038;h=556" alt="SI figure3 simulation blowup" width="493" height="556" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17518" /></a></p>
<p>Here is a corresponding blowup from the thesis.<br />
<a href="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thesis-simulation-blowup.png"><img src="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thesis-simulation-blowup.png?w=363&#038;h=536" alt="thesis simulation blowup" width="363" height="536" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17519" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17511/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/climateaudit.wordpress.com/17511/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=climateaudit.org&#038;blog=1501837&#038;post=17511&#038;subd=climateaudit&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/14/no-uptick-in-marcott-thesis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>126</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c39665ed80f29aa88a4313b7bc9b877?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevemcintyre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/figure-1c.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">figure 1C</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thesis-short1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thesis-short1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/si-figure3-simulation-blowup.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SI figure3 simulation blowup</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://climateaudit.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thesis-simulation-blowup.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thesis simulation blowup</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
