<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Digg Top Stories</title>
        <description>Digg - What the Internet is talking about right now</description>
        <link>http://digg.com/rss/top.rss</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 15:18:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 15:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <ttl>15</ttl>

         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Meet The Ultimate Endurance Athlete</title>
            <description>Kilian Jornet Burgada is the most dominating endurance athlete of his generation. He has run across entire landmasses­ (Corsica) and mountain ranges (the Pyrenees), nearly without pause. He regularly runs all day eating only wild berries and drinking only from streams.</description>
            <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/24/magazine/creating-the-all-terrain-human.html?partner=rss&amp;emc=rss</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/16J3lqx</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 12:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Why Did Apple Hire A Guy Who Once Ran Over An iPhone With A Steam Roller?</title>
            <description>Just hours after word leaked that Apple had poached Adobe's chief technology officer, the Internet is ablaze with the question of what, exactly, the iPhone maker plans to do with Kevin Lynch.</description>
            <link>http://appleinsider.com/articles/13/03/19/why-did-apple-hire-adobe-cto-kevin-lynch</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZZ4Cob</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 11:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Here Is President Obama Speaking Hebrew For Three Seconds</title>
            <description>As he began a three-day trip to Israel, the West Bank, and Jordan today, President Obama delighted his hosts by speaking stilted Hebrew for three seconds during a speech on the tarmac at Tel Aviv's airport.</description>
            <link>http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2013/03/obama-speaking-hebrew-video-israel-tel-aviv.html?mid=twitter_nymag</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15qBWGn</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 14:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Never Lose Your Photos – Or Videos – Again</title>
            <description>Remember how Picturelife makes backing up and showing all your photos as easy as taking them? Yeah, well now they're doing the same with video, no matter the file size. If you haven't given them a shot, here's your chance.</description>
            <link>https://picturelife.com/digg</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10fFJXu</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 02:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Complete Guide To Taking Notes Effectively At Work</title>
            <description>Here’s everything you need to know about taking notes at work, but never bothered to ask.</description>
            <link>http://qz.com/64539/complete-guide-to-taking-notes-effectively-at-work/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WD8j44</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 11:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Problem With Google, As Seen Through Its NCAA Bracket</title>
            <description>Here’s the current state of things. If you search for “NCAA bracket”, Google pops up a March Madness bracket with the full schedule. It’s not even using a sidebar at this point and is only showing the bracket.</description>
            <link>http://thenextweb.com/google/2013/03/20/google-ncaa-bracket/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Y2PBpG</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 12:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Watch A Drone Fly Between Two Tesla Coils</title>
            <description>Here's a drone flying between two tesla coils.</description>
            <link>http://www.liveleak.com/view?i=20b_1363759259</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/16J0xd2</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 11:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Hilarious Notes On Modern Classics From Clueless Studio Executives</title>
            <description>The image of non-creative types mucking about with (and screwing up) movies and television shows is nothing new — we’ve seen it in everything from Barton Fink to The Player to The Larry Sanders Show. Here are a few real life examples.</description>
            <link>http://flavorwire.com/378212/hilarious-notes-on-modern-classics-from-clueless-studio-executives/view-all</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/16Jed7U</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:44:51 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Greatest MIT Hacks Of All-Time</title>
            <description>MIT is the birthplace of the hacker. Back in the science-loving 1950s, MIT's Tech Model Railroad club developed the ethos that would help drive the evolution of Unix, the internet, open-source software, and so many other cool hacker ideas that echo even today.</description>
            <link>http://www.wired.com/wiredenterprise/2013/03/mit-hacks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wired%2Findex+%28Wired%3A+Top+Stories%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/13b0bwK</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 12:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>1 In 50 School Kids Have Autism</title>
            <description>Health officials say the new number doesn't mean autism is occurring more often. But it does suggest that doctors are diagnosing autism more frequently, especially in children with milder problems.</description>
            <link>http://bigstory.ap.org/article/health-officials-1-50-school-kids-have-autism</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Yq1SyT</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Japanese Subway Stations Totally Look Like Role-Playing Game Dungeons</title>
            <description>Recently, a Japanese net user posted a photo of the Tokyo Metro's Shibuya Station, aka &quot;Shibuya Dungeon.&quot; For a few years now, it's been dubbed as such.</description>
            <link>http://kotaku.com/5991254/japanese-subway-stations-totally-look-like-role+playing-game-dungeons</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15XHPNw</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 12:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>World's Strongest Coffee Has 200% More Caffeine Than Normal Cup</title>
            <description>Overdosing on caffeine to keep your eyes from hitting the floor during your 16-hour office shift has a distinct possibility of putting you in an early grave. However, an American company has decided to embrace this by bringing out a blend of coffee named Death Wish, which it has dubbed ‘The World’s Strongest Coffee’.</description>
            <link>http://metro.co.uk/2013/03/19/death-wish-coffee-worlds-strongest-coffee-200-per-cent-stronger-than-normal-cuppa-3548670/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/137Iy0Y</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 01:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Did This 911 Call Stop A School Shooting On Monday?</title>
            <description>After noticing his roommate James Seevakumaran acting strangely and then spotting him with a gun, a University of Central Florida student called 911 from inside a locked bathroom early Monday — a call authorities say might have saved the lives of other students on campus.</description>
            <link>http://articles.orlandosentinel.com/2013-03-19/features/os-911-call-ucf-death-20130319_1_fire-alarm-assault-rifle-ucf-police</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Yqw7ph</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Finally, Honest Hand Dryer Instructions</title>
            <description>It's always felt like something's missing from your local public bathroom's hand dryer tutorial. Something simple, yet crucial. Something like, say, this missing third step that Doghouse Diaries has so smartly proposed.</description>
            <link>http://gizmodo.com/5991480/finally-honest-hand-dryer-instructions</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/16J79rQ</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:12:45 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Untold Story Of The Women Behind The Atomic Bomb</title>
            <description>From janitor to chemist, the women of Oak Ridge worked hard and talked little.</description>
            <link>http://www.brainpickings.org/index.php/2013/03/20/the-girls-of-atomic-city/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+brainpickings%2Frss+%28Brain+Pickings%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/14bAonT</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 12:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Where The Money Is Going In The Media Business</title>
            <description>The Pew Research Center put out its annual State of the Media report. In it, we can see where the economic growth in media platforms is coming from.</description>
            <link>http://www.businessinsider.com/chart-of-the-day-where-the-money-is-going-in-the-media-business-2013-3?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Falleyinsider%2Fsilicon_alley_insider+%28Silicon+Alley+Insider%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WBQeTT</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 21:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How Barrett Brown Went From Anonymous PR To Federal Target</title>
            <description>It started innocently enough, but Barrett Brown's exploits with and around Anonymous sucked him into a situation where he faces years in jail if convicted.</description>
            <link>http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2013/mar/20/barrett-brown-anonymous-pr-federal-target</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YVu1A6</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 12:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Meet Wikipedia, The Encyclopedia Anyone Can Code</title>
            <description>It began as the encyclopedia anyone can edit. And now it’s also the encyclopedia anyone can program.</description>
            <link>http://www.wired.com/wiredenterprise/2013/03/wikipedia-lua/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wired%2Findex+%28Wired%3A+Top+Stories%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZbFPuH</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 19:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>South Korea Network Attack Just 'A Virus'?</title>
            <description>Disruption that paralysed the computer networks of broadcasters and banks in South Korea appears to have been caused by a virus..</description>
            <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-21855051</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/14bgc5t</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>What 420,000 Insecure Devices Reveal About Web Security</title>
            <description>Using a simple technique, a researcher creates a benign botnet to survey the breadth of the Internet, and finds a back door flung wide open and beckoning the bad guys.</description>
            <link>http://news.cnet.com/8301-1009_3-57574919-83/what-420000-insecure-devices-reveal-about-web-security/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/16F5dRg</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 01:21:39 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Why Are Celebrities Injecting Their Faces With Blood?</title>
            <description>The science of the &quot;vampire facial.&quot;</description>
            <link>http://www.popsci.com/science/article/2013-03/fyi-what-blood-facial-it-safe</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YS5tI8</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 18:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>A Partial History Of Headphones</title>
            <description>The history of headphones dates back further than the 1980s. Like many commercial electronics, modern headphones (and stereo sound) originated, in part, in the military.</description>
            <link>http://blogs.smithsonianmag.com/design/2013/03/a-partial-history-of-headphones/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZHUErA</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 01:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>McDonald’s China Offers Sausage Double Beef Burger</title>
            <description>Similar to the Nuremburger sometimes offered at McDonald’s Germany, McDonald’s China is now serving Sausage Double Beef Burgers.</description>
            <link>http://foodbeast.com/content/2013/03/19/the-buns-are-an-afterthought-mcdonalds-china-offers-sausage-double-beef-burger/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+foodbeast+%28FOODBEAST%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15n1Yuc</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 18:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Domestic Drones Are Here, But The Law's Still Catching Up</title>
            <description>An explosion of advanced flying vehicles is about to hit the skies, but regulation lags way behind technology.</description>
            <link>http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/19/4120548/calm-before-the-swarm-domestic-drones-are-here</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/11aOOQz</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 17:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>After 'Fascist' Accusations, Ukrainian Parliament Brawls</title>
            <description>You thought our politics were bad. If you need a fresh reminder that it could be worse: Official business at Ukraine's parliament was suspended for a short time, while MPs exchanged punches.</description>
            <link>http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2013/03/19/174762007/watch-after-fascist-accusations-ukrainian-parliament-brawls?ft=1&amp;f=1001&amp;sc=tw&amp;utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Y1btls</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 20:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Children Of Two Veterans Are Still Receiving Soldiers' Pensions</title>
            <description>The U.S. Civil War officially ended 148 years ago this spring, and will likely be unofficially wrapping up any day now. But not quite yet. According to the AP, two children of veterans are still receiving benefits as a result of their fathers' service.</description>
            <link>http://gawker.com/5991317/1865-civil-war-update-the-children-of-two-veterans-are-still-receiving-soldiers-pensions</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/138NWke</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 19:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Annoyed By Radio Ads? We've Been Trying To Get Rid Of Them For 80 Years</title>
            <description>In the early 1930s, Professor Gleason W. Kenrick of what is now Tufts University developed a machine that could be attached to a radio to automatically “delete” ads.</description>
            <link>http://www.psmag.com/blogs/time-machine/music-ads-advertisement-pandora-spotify-54058/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YoAbWY</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 18:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Chinese Are Also Building Smart Watches And Smart Shoes</title>
            <description>Wearable computing is not just a Made In America phenomenon. China is getting in on the act, too.</description>
            <link>http://pandodaily.com/2013/03/19/smart-watches-and-smart-shoes-will-be-made-in-china-too/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/16GWU7f</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 17:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Adam Scott And 11 Other Actors Who Originally Auditioned For ‘The Office’</title>
            <description>Rainn Wilson posted the original sign-in sheet for &quot;The Office&quot; auditions, and besides finding out that he tried out for the roles of both Michael Scott and Dwight Schrute, we also found out several other people who auditioned for various roles in the series.</description>
            <link>http://www.uproxx.com/tv/2013/03/adam-scott-and-11-other-actors-who-originally-auditioned-for-the-cast-of-the-office/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15XZQLt</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 16:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>If You Smoke, Your Grandchildren Could Pay For It</title>
            <description>One of the first things kids used to learn in high school biology is the folly of Lamarckian evolution- the idea that environmental and behavioral forces can shape heredity. Studies like this one from however, suggest that Lamarckian thinking may not be totally wrong after all.</description>
            <link>http://www.boston.com/bostonglobe/ideas/brainiac/2013/03/over_the_last_d.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15mymgn</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 16:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Cobra Takes To Kickstarter To Rebuild After Latest Foiling By G.I. Joe</title>
            <description>Times are tough for terrorist organizations right now, especially the long suffering agents of Cobra.</description>
            <link>http://www.geekosystem.com/cobra-kickstarter/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZXkGqo</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 14:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How To Get Out Of Quicksand</title>
            <description>Is it possible to survive being stuck in quicksand?</description>
            <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a2VJqud3Ls8&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=1m12s</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WUhHmd</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 01:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>What It's Like To Write A Video Game</title>
            <description>Modern video games are showing signs of morphing into other, still more subtle and complicated forms; among other things, they’re becoming an increasingly sophisticated vehicle for storytelling.</description>
            <link>http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/books/2013/03/gears-of-war-writer-tom-bissell-on-video-games-and-storytelling.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15YCl57</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 19:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Building The World's Largest Ship (In 76 Seconds)</title>
            <description>A timelapse of the construction of Maersk Line's very first Triple-E vessel at the DSME shipyard in Okpo, Korea.</description>
            <link>http://vimeo.com/channels/staffpicks/62085613</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/XnI5jg</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 22:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        
 
</channel>
</rss>
