<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Digg Top Stories</title>
        <description>Digg - What the Internet is talking about right now</description>
        <link>http://digg.com/rss/top.rss</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 23:39:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 23:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <ttl>15</ttl>

         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Controversial Science Of Transgender Athletes In Combat Sports</title>
            <description>Can punching someone in the face really be gender neutral?</description>
            <link>http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/21/4131174/fallon-fox-mma-science-transgender-fighting-athletes</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/11lfJct</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Where Pakistani Muslims Go To Secretly Party</title>
            <description>The Kalash people spurn Islamic law by drinking, taking drugs, and partying. So for decades, usually law-abiding Muslims have ventured into their home valleys to party with them.</description>
            <link>http://www.vice.com/read/facedown-in-chitral-000273-v20n3</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YIbqEv</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Russian Daredevil Hangs On From Great Heights</title>
            <description>Russia has proven to have an endless supply of daredevils who get a rush out of climbing sky-scraping towers and monstrous cranes, but one guy who goes by the pseudonym Mustang Wanted tempts gravity by not only scaling his lofty destination but by then hanging off of it.</description>
            <link>http://www.mymodernmet.com/profiles/blogs/mustang-wanted-daredevil-photography</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Y27P8A</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 20:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>3-D Holograms On Your Phone: No Glasses Required</title>
            <description>In theaters, 3-D movies are everywhere. But how about a 3-D holographic movie on your mobile phone?</description>
            <link>http://news.discovery.com/tech/gear-and-gadgets/hologram-your-phone-no-glasses-required-130320.htm#mkcpgn=rssnws1</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15rO0am</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 19:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>This Lizard-Inspired Robot Can Scamper Across Sand</title>
            <description>Designing a robot that can easily move across loose terrain—say, a rover meant to traverse the surface of Mars—poses a unique engineering challenge: Wheels commonly sink into what engineers call “flowable ground” (mixtures of sand, soil, mud and grass).</description>
            <link>http://blogs.smithsonianmag.com/science/2013/03/video-this-lizard-inspired-robot-can-scamper-across-sand/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WH1KNZ</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 20:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Poor-Quality Chinese Concrete Could Lead To Skyscraper Collapses</title>
            <description>A sand scandal is brewing in China, with concerns that low-quality concrete has been used in the construction of many of the country’s largest buildings — putting them at risk of collapse.</description>
            <link>http://www.wired.com/design/2013/03/poor-quality-chinese-concrete-could-lead-to-skyscraper-collapses/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wired%2Findex+%28Wired%3A+Top+Stories%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Yrw0g8</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Wil Wheaton Story That Will Make You Sob In Your Cheerios</title>
            <description>Last night, I was checking Facebook on my phone, when I ran across a story that many of you have may have also seen on your Facebook walls. I’m not sure what compelled me to read it, but five minutes later, my heart may have swollen 3 sizes and there was definitely something in my eye.</description>
            <link>http://www.uproxx.com/tv/2013/03/the-wil-wheaton-story-that-will-make-you-sob-in-your-cheerios/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/14emmSg</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Internet-Demanded, Partially Scientific Testing Of Ultra-Ever Dry</title>
            <description>You've seen the amazing YouTube videos, right? Someone tries to wet a surface with water and it amazingly just beads up and runs off. So one reporter had to find out if the stuff really worked.</description>
            <link>http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2013/03/the-internet-demanded-partially-scientific-testing-of-ultraeverdry-in-hd/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZWek9u</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 14:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Yes, Cyberattacks Are Perfectly Legal Under The Laws Of War</title>
            <description>The term &quot;cyberwarfare&quot; is meaningless in the worst way—it puts the imagination into paranoid overdrive and is not limited by any legal definitions. All the rules we’ve got on armed conflict today apply to ye olde bombs and bullets, not viruses and botnets.</description>
            <link>http://www.nationaljournal.com/tech/yes-cyberattacks-are-perfectly-legal-under-the-laws-of-war-20130321</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/149VXF0</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 15:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Cyclist Hits Antelope, Antelope Wins</title>
            <description>This week sees the Cape Epic, a 433-mile trek through western South Africa. During Monday's stage, Austrian Robert Mennen had a close encounter with a stupid, stupid antelope that darted out from the bush.</description>
            <link>http://deadspin.com/cyclist-hits-antelope-antelope-wins-458231301?utm_campaign=socialflow_deadspin_twitter&amp;utm_source=deadspin_twitter&amp;utm_medium=socialflow</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZOvLdE</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:51:27 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Is This The Last Big Gay-Marriage Fight?</title>
            <description>Next week, the Supreme Court is expected to issue its decision on the two gay marriage cases in front of it. Either decision could legalize the practice in one quick blow. So a bumper crop of organizations and activists are weighing in now, while there's still a reason to.</description>
            <link>http://www.theatlanticwire.com/politics/2013/03/gay-marriage-fight-supreme-court/63378/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/102mWN9</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 14:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>What Would Life Be Like In A World Without The Internet?</title>
            <description>Not being able to dick off at work all day? Actually talking to friends? Meeting cute strangers on the street in the course of getting directions? NOOOOOOOOOO!</description>
            <link>http://www.uproxx.com/webculture/2013/03/uproxx-video-life-without-internet/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZASB9x</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Where's Voyager 1?</title>
            <description>For about three hours on Wednesday, Voyager 1 had left the solar system — before a rewritten news release headline pulled it back in. So where exactly is it?</description>
            <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/21/science/space/nasas-voyager-1-not-yet-out-of-the-solar-system.html?smid=tw-nytimes</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/102vXWC</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 15:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>PETA Euthanized 90% Of The Animals In Its Shelter</title>
            <description>Critics are charging PETA — renowned for its aggressive anti-cruelty campaigns — with hypocrisy after the group's euthanasia statistics were posted on the website of the Virginia Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</description>
            <link>http://www.livescience.com/28091-peta-euthanasia.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10nYlVv</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>iPads Have Taken Over The Cockpit</title>
            <description>The FAA has finally approved the use of the iPad Electronic Flight Bag. So what's it like to fly with an iPad in the cockpit?</description>
            <link>http://www.gadling.com/2013/03/20/cockpit-chronicles-the-ipad-flight-bag-is-finally-here-video/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10i3Eps</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Kids In Vietnam Are Crazy Good At Programming</title>
            <description>11th graders in Vietnam are so good at programming that they could easily pass an interview at Google.</description>
            <link>http://neil.fraser.name/news/2013/03/16/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/102oBV6</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 15:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How Background Checks For Guns Really Work</title>
            <description>The Senate and several states are considering measures to require background checks for every firearm purchase. Here's how those checks work.</description>
            <link>http://www.bloomberg.com/infographics/2013-03-21/how-gun-background-checks-work.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/102mrTb</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 13:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Pot Industry's Most Politically Important Dispensary</title>
            <description>In the eyes of the federal government, there is no such thing as “medical marijuana.” But there’s a dispensary just blocks from the Capitol.</description>
            <link>http://www.nationaljournal.com/congress/the-pot-industry-s-most-politically-important-dispensary-20130321/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/149Y9wc</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How One Man's Makeshift Google Reader Logo Became The 'Default'</title>
            <description>&quot;Five years ago, I was wanting to install Google Reader on my desktop with Fluid but noticed I couldn’t find a good icon for it at all. So I made one, and posted it to Flickr.&quot;</description>
            <link>http://mgalligan.com/post/45919481419/my-google-reader-logo</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15w6xlR</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Inside 'Apple Anonymous': The Secret Society Of Apple’s Retail Army</title>
            <description>Even with strict, Apple Corporate-implemented policies on social media usage of its employees, a portion of Apple retail employees have formed an under-the-radar, “Apple Anonymous” community.</description>
            <link>http://9to5mac.com/2013/03/21/inside-apple-anonymous-the-secret-society-of-apples-retail-army/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+9To5Mac-MacAllDay+%289+to+5+Mac+-+Apple+Intelligence%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10mO7or</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>It Turns Out That Great White Sharks Eat Even More Than We Thought</title>
            <description>And we already thought that they ate a lot.</description>
            <link>http://news.discovery.com/animals/sharks/great-white-sharks-eat-more-130321.htm#mkcpgn=rssnws1</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WGmcyp</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 14:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Weirdest Aircraft Of The 20th Century</title>
            <description>The 20th Century gave us the Wright Brothers, the 747 and the Concorde. But it also gave us some of the strangest things ever to take to the skies. Here are some of the most insane aircraft ever conceived.</description>
            <link>http://io9.com/the-weirdest-aircraft-of-the-20th-century-456552834</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Xqv7RM</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Why I'm Walking Every Single Block In New York City</title>
            <description>The goal of my quest to walk every block of every street in all five boroughs in New York City is to know nothing. To tear down all the generalizations about the city and its people and its neighborhoods that I’ve absorbed without thinking during my time here.</description>
            <link>http://www.good.is/posts/why-i-m-walking-every-single-block-in-new-york-city/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/102IFVa</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>A Surprising Map Of The Countries That Are Most And Least Welcoming To Foreigners</title>
            <description>Buried several hundred pages into a new World Economic Forum report on global tourism, past the sections on air travel infrastructure and physician density (by which they mean the number of physicians per capita, not the mass-per-cubic-meter of individual doctors), are some very interesting numbers.</description>
            <link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/worldviews/wp/2013/03/21/a-fascinating-map-of-countries-color-coded-by-their-openness-to-foreigners/?k</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WWMPSb</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 12:15:49 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>There Is One Color You Need To Wear On Your Dating Profile</title>
            <description>If you want to stand out, this is the color you should be wearing when you take your dating selfie.</description>
            <link>http://www.slate.com/articles/double_x/doublex/2013/03/new_book_drunk_tank_pink_argues_red_is_the_color_for_dating_profiles.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15uS3Te</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 12:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>A Father-Daughter Dance — In Jail</title>
            <description>For a few hours on this Saturday afternoon, the incarcerated fathers will be allowed to take part in an American tradition, the father-daughter dance. “A Dance of Their Own,” thought to be the only event of its kind in the country, will be in the jail’s small, windowless multipurpose room.</description>
            <link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/style/a-father-daughter-dance--in-jail/2013/03/20/b1833af4-90a9-11e2-9abd-e4c5c9dc5e90_story.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZUJvlH</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>New 'Star Trek Into Darkness' Trailer Shows Off Homicidal Cumberbatch</title>
            <description>The latest 'Stark Trek Into Darkness' trailer focuses on a very determined and very evil Benedict Cumberbatch.</description>
            <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=yhz4A5BCMAA</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/1499WLc</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 11:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>British Airways To Hold A Hackathon At 34,000 Feet</title>
            <description>British Airways is inviting 100 guests to participate in an 11-hour hackathon during a transatlantic flight from San Francisco to London.</description>
            <link>http://venturebeat.com/2013/03/20/british-airways-will-host-an-11-hour-hackathon-in-the-sky/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/XqJeGV</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 11:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>This Woman Is The Ultimate Woman-Hater</title>
            <description>Meet Claire Khaw, a British “anti-feminist” who wants nothing more than to “restore the patriarchy by means of establishing a one-party theocracy based on the Koranic principles that will replace the immorality of feminism.”</description>
            <link>http://www.vice.com/read/which-type-of-mangina-are-you</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Y1DEhH</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>35 Facts About Mr. Rogers</title>
            <description>The beloved Fred Rogers would have been 85 yesterday. In celebration, here are 35 facts that you probably didn't know about him.</description>
            <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=4Xck2ByutMg</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YGCaoS</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 12:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Can You Train Yourself To Get By On Less Sleep?</title>
            <description>Margaret Thatcher did it. So did Salvador Dali. They survived the day with only a few hours of sleep. The question is whether you can force yourself to do the same.</description>
            <link>http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20130320-can-you-get-by-on-less-sleep</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZVvXXb</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 11:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        
 
</channel>
</rss>
