<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Digg Top Stories</title>
        <description>Digg - What the Internet is talking about right now</description>
        <link>http://digg.com/rss/top.rss</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 15:25:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 15:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <ttl>15</ttl>

         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>What Are The Winklevoss Brothers Up To Now?</title>
            <description>If revenge is a dish — like a lobster roll — best served cold, then the Winklevii are feasting.</description>
            <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/24/fashion/winklevoss-brothers-move-on-from-facebook.html?_r=0</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Zc0fHo</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 13:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How To Get Real Eggs On Your McDonald's Breakfast Sandwich</title>
            <description>You can get your McDonald's biscuit sandwiches (or any breakfast sandwich, for that matter) made with a 100% real egg, cracked and cooked fresh on-premises.</description>
            <link>http://www.seriouseats.com/2013/03/want-real-eggs-at-mcdonalds-just-ask.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/11oqSZS</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Ford Is Forced To Apologize For Horrendously Offensive Ads</title>
            <description>Ford and its ad agency issued apologies for a tasteless Ford Figo ad — in which former Italian PM Silvio Berlusconi is shown with a bunch of gagged and crying women in the trunk of his car — that was never meant to see the light of day.</description>
            <link>http://www.businessinsider.com/ford-wpp-apologizes-for-offensive-car-ad-2013-3</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/105jTnA</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The 17 Worst Mascots Of March Madness</title>
            <description>From oranges to blobs to animals who are better suited for a petting zoo, here are the most absurd mascots of the top 68 teams vying for the NCAA Championship this Year.</description>
            <link>http://keepingscore.blogs.time.com/2013/03/22/the-17-worst-mascots-of-march-madness/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/11pLctR</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 20:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>American English Has Become Way More Emotional Than British English</title>
            <description>A study comparing mood-related words in U.S. and British books shows that Americans increasingly use emotional words more often.</description>
            <link>http://www.popsci.com/science/article/2013-03/american-english-has-become-way-more-emotional-british-english?src=SOC&amp;dom=tw</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Z8sKWG</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 12:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Could An Asbestos Contaminated Tarantula Be On The Loose?</title>
            <description>It's a scenario seemingly designed to give arachnophobes nightmares, but it's one that an asbestos team working in an attic in Cardiff this week have encountered.</description>
            <link>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/arachnophobes-look-away-now-could-an-asbestos-contaminated-tarantula-be-on-the-loose-in-cardiff-8544532.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YJRTU4</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Shedding Light On The CIA's Black-Site Program</title>
            <description>What became of terror suspects held by the CIA in its network of “black-site” prisons around the world? Or disappeared into foreign cells in extraordinary renditions?</description>
            <link>http://www.propublica.org/article/a-public-indictment-could-shed-light-on-c.i.as-secret-program</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10s37RL</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Is It OK For Evangelicals To Give Their Son A Bar Mitzvah?</title>
            <description>Of all the surprises promised by the recent TLC reality show “The Sisterhood,” which followed the lives of five Atlanta preachers’ wives, the only one that truly amazed me was the Christian bar mitzvah, an event organized by Pastor Tara Lewis and her husband, Pastor Brian, for their son, Trevor.</description>
            <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/24/magazine/oy-vey-christian-soldiers.html?ref=magazine&amp;_r=2&amp;amp&amp;pagewanted=all&amp;</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZFFFiO</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 18:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Twitter Needs To Deal With Misinformation. Here's How</title>
            <description>How do you correct something as fleeting as a tweet?</description>
            <link>http://www.nationaljournal.com/tech/twitter-needs-to-deal-with-misinformation-here-s-how-20130322</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/11tbkb4</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 20:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>World’s First ‘Edible Hotel’ Has Fudge Windowsills And Carpets Made From Cake</title>
            <description>You know how some people (like, hypothetically) eat their way through vacation? A new pop-up hotel that recently opened in London is taking that concept quite literally, creating hotel rooms made entirely out of edible goods.</description>
            <link>http://betabeat.com/2013/03/worlds-first-edible-hotel-has-fudge-windowsills-and-carpets-made-from-cake/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YgSIKO</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 17:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Explorers Club Digs Its Teeth Into Exotic Cuisine</title>
            <description>The evening's crowd-pleasers included &quot;ostrich, we had ostrich done a number of ways. That was a highlight. The alligator recipes I think were a hit. The insects of course, they're always a hit. We did not have enough tarantulas, cockroaches, worm salad.&quot;</description>
            <link>http://gothamist.com/2013/03/19/explorers_club.php#photo-10</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/16HdN1U</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 17:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>A Symphony Of Lullabies, Played By 40 Jogging Mice</title>
            <description>Fabio Di Salvo and Bernardo Vercelli have a way with coaxing interesting harmonies out of unexpected sources. Known together as Quiet Ensemble, their latest endeavor allowed mice to remix works by famous composers.</description>
            <link>http://www.fastcodesign.com/1672165/watch-a-symphony-of-lullabies-played-by-40-jogging-mice</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/16MTrEc</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 13:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Nitrous Oxide Goes Mainstream</title>
            <description>Authorities say the use of nitrous oxide as a recreational drug has grown from a rave party phenomenon to mainstream use in recent years.</description>
            <link>http://www.foxnews.com/us/2013/03/22/nitrous-oxide-goes-mainstream-southern-california-sees-surge-in-quick-and-cheap/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/104s2IS</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 18:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Microchip Beneath The Skin Is A Health Laboratory</title>
            <description>Researchers in France have created a tiny medical device, designed to be implanted beneath the skin, that uses enzymes to analyse the quality of a patient's blood. The result is a micro-laboratory inside the body that can help doctors diagnose disease and possibly treat cancer more effectively.</description>
            <link>http://bigthink.com/ideafeed/microchip-beneath-the-skin-is-a-health-laboratory?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+bigthink%2Fmain+%28Big+Think+Main%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YdMtaK</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 01:47:14 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Why You Are Afraid Of The Dark?</title>
            <description>The dark is an unknown area. What we used to know so well is eclipsed in blackness and regular objects take new shape with the help of our imagination. Today’s graphic delves into the reason why our species is afraid of the dark.</description>
            <link>http://dailyinfographic.com/why-you-are-afraid-of-the-dark-infographic?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+DailyInfographic+%28Daily+Infographic%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZExNhl</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 13:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Where In The World Are All The Billionaires?</title>
            <description>For the 27th annual Forbes billionaires list, our team of reporters spent months tracking down the wealthiest people around the globe. Ultimately, we found 1,426 billionaires who are together worth a total of $5.4 trillion — a record sum.</description>
            <link>http://www.forbes.com/sites/ricardogeromel/2013/03/22/forbes-billionaires-map/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15Av4X1</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 17:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>'Stop The Cyborgs' Launches Public Campaign Against Google Glass</title>
            <description>&quot;It destroys having multiple identities, and I find that quite a scary concept.&quot;</description>
            <link>http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2013/03/stop-the-cyborgs-launches-public-campaign-against-google-glass/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+arstechnica%2Findex+%28Ars+Technica+-+All+content%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/13j3Ys4</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>On Hitler's Paradoxical Relationship To Books</title>
            <description>Adolf Hitler loved books—that nasty bent for book burning notwithstanding—and the book industry loves him back.</description>
            <link>http://chronicle.com/article/Reason-EmotionHitler/137883/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/119PVDP</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 18:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>A Private Mission To Mars Can Take Risks NASA Can't</title>
            <description>Impossible it isn't, but the Inspiration Mars Foundation's proposed mission would run the risk of catastrophic failure.</description>
            <link>http://www.guardian.co.uk/science/blog/2013/mar/22/mars-bust-private-mission-red-planet</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YJCSBR</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 16:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Agent Who Protected Presidents On The Factual Accuracy Of 'Olympus Has Fallen'</title>
            <description>'Olympus Has Fallen' director Antoine Fuqua sought out a good deal of Secret Service advice on how to craft his thriller. One of the technical consultants was Dr. Joe Bannon who has protected scores of presidents and even the popemobile.</description>
            <link>http://www.motherjones.com/mixed-media/2013/03/olympus-has-fallen-secret-service-agent-gerard-butler-joe-bannon</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZEoZIl</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 12:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Twitter Sued For $50M For Refusing To Reveal Anti-Semites</title>
            <description>In January, a French court ruled that Twitter must hand over the details of people who had tweeted racist and anti-semitic remarks, and set up a system that would alert the police to any further such posts as they happen. Twitter has ignored that ruling.</description>
            <link>http://www.wired.co.uk/news/archive/2013-03/22/twitter-sued-france-anti-semitism</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15AzFIK</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 20:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Jihadist From Phoenix</title>
            <description>Eric Harroun claims to have joined up with an al Qaeda-linked group fighting in Syria’s brutal civil war. We tracked him down, but getting the truth was more difficult.</description>
            <link>http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2013/03/22/the_jihadist_from_phoenix_eric_harroun</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/16NRZBu</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 20:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Jihadi Web Forums Are Losing Members To Twitter, Facebook, Death</title>
            <description>This may have been a fake jihadi Facebook page from 2010, but a prominent terror theorist is lamenting that the real thing is killing off online extremist forums.</description>
            <link>http://www.wired.com/dangerroom/2013/03/jihadi-forums/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wired%2Findex+%28Wired%3A+Top+Stories%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15wKYli</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 12:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Online News Outlet That Pays Its Staff Only In High Fives</title>
            <description>Felice News is a Canadian organization that labels itself as &quot;the world's largest and most popular all-positive news outlet,&quot; and claims that it is &quot;all run by reporters aged 12 to 25.&quot; All of the reporters and staff are so all-positive, it turns out, that they don't even need to get paid.</description>
            <link>http://motherboard.vice.com/blog/the-worlds-largest--most-popular-all-positive-news-outlet-wants-to-pay-its-staff-in-high-fives</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZGffgO</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 20:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Entrepreneurship Program Gives Former Prostitutes A Fresh Start</title>
            <description>A program at Imperial College London helps women who have been forced into prostitution start a new life as entrepreneurs.</description>
            <link>http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2013-03-22/entrepreneurship-program-gives-former-prostitutes-a-fresh-start</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/105krtz</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 16:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        
 
</channel>
</rss>
