<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Digg Top Stories</title>
        <description>Digg - What the Internet is talking about right now</description>
        <link>http://digg.com/rss/top.rss</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 16:12:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 16:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <ttl>15</ttl>

         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How Pi Was Nearly Changed To 3.2 And Copyrighted</title>
            <description>This story has all the makings of weirdo Americana: bad amateur science, commercial ventures based upon the same, and a state legislature eager to embrace it all.</description>
            <link>http://www.openculture.com/2013/03/how_pi_was_nearly_changed_to_32_and_copyrighted.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/164iqlm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>North Korean Video Features Its Army Taking 150,000 American Hostages</title>
            <description>North Korea released a new promotional video in which the DPRK's army stages a massive attack on South Korea with paratroopers landing in Seoul and proceeding to take 150,000 U.S. citizens hostage.</description>
            <link>http://www.liveleak.com/view?i=d40_1363941530</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/104EIzt</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 12:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Blackberry CEO Calls iPhone Outdated, Manages To Keep A Straight Face</title>
            <description>Thorsten Heins made a comment that raised some eyebrows on the eve of the much-delayed launch of the new touchscreen BlackBerry in the United States.</description>
            <link>http://techland.time.com/2013/03/22/blackberry-ceo-says-iphone-is-outdated/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+timeblogs%2Fnerd_world+%28TIME%3A+Techland%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WRBL7S</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 12:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Shooting At Quantico Leaves 3 Dead, Including Gunman</title>
            <description>A Marine shot and killed two of his fellow service members at a Virginia base on Thursday night before turning the gun on himself.</description>
            <link>http://www.cnn.com/2013/03/22/us/virginia-quantico-shooting/index.html?hpt=hp_t1</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/11qP6Xh</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>When The Whole World Has Drones</title>
            <description>The precedents the U.S. has set for robotic warfare may have fearsome consequences as other countries catch up.</description>
            <link>http://www.nationaljournal.com/magazine/when-the-whole-world-has-drones-20130321?page=1</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YsDboy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 12:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>These Two Seconds Of Hockey Generated 44 Penalty Minutes</title>
            <description>Want to watch something exciting and unusual that happened on the ice during an NHL game? Watch this video! Want to watch some hockey? Well, then don't watch this video.</description>
            <link>http://deadspin.com/these-two-seconds-of-hockey-generated-44-penalty-minute-458321417</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZEMAsi</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Day Child Porn Went Viral On Facebook</title>
            <description>A video of unknown origin appearing to show a grown man sexually abusing an infant girl went viral overnight on Facebook, garnering as many as 32,000 shares and over 5,000 likes before finally being removed by the website.</description>
            <link>http://gawker.com/5991876/the-day-child-porn-went-viral-on-facebook</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/11rUhGk</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Secret Gingrich-Santorum 'Unity Ticket' That Nearly Toppled Romney</title>
            <description>It’s one of the great untold stories of the 2012 presidential campaign, a tale of ego and intrigue that nearly upended the Republican primary contest and might even have produced a different nominee: As Mitt Romney struggled in the weeks leading up to the Michigan primary, Newt Gingrich and Rick Santorum nearly agreed to form a joint “Unity Ticket” to consolidate conservative support and topple Romney.</description>
            <link>http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2013-03-22/the-secret-gingrich-santorum-unity-ticket-that-nearly-toppled-romney</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15xlqVc</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How One Brave Skateboarder Jumped Over The Subway Tracks</title>
            <description>It's not fake, but it was scary, said the photographer Allen Ying, who took the shot from below, on the tracks.</description>
            <link>http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2013/03/skateboarder-jumps-over-nyc-subway-tracks.html?mid=facebook_nymag</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/103fiCl</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 12:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Inhalable 'Whisky Tornado' That Can Get You Drunk</title>
            <description>Ever feel like getting drunk but don't want to actually consume any liquids? There's now a solution to this non-existant problem.</description>
            <link>http://designtaxi.com/news/356649/An-Inhalable-Whisky-Tornado-That-Can-Get-You-Drunk/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WFuo1U</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Newly Discovered Letter By Oscar Wilde Contains Writing Tips From The Author</title>
            <description>Oscar Wilde believed his success as a writer was due to him never relying on the craft as a source of income, a previously unseen letter by the author has revealed.</description>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/books/9939664/Literary-success-Dont-give-up-the-day-job-advised-Oscar-Wilde.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZXmmAb</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Why Mini-Skirts Could Become Illegal In South Korea</title>
            <description>In the 1970s, the dictatorship controlling South Korea stipulated the length of women's skirts. Now, due to a new law, some in South Korea worry that those days are returning.</description>
            <link>http://kotaku.com/5991862/why-mini+skirts-could-become-illegal-in-south-korea</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WIzVoj</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Do Conservatives Or Liberals Have Better Gaydar?</title>
            <description>Luckily, there's a new study out that answers this very important question.</description>
            <link>http://www.motherjones.com/mojo/2013/03/do-conservatives-have-better-gaydar</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZQYuyx</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Life Of A Gun Repo Man</title>
            <description>California is the only state that takes legally obtained weapons away from citizens who are no longer supposed to have them. Meet the team that performs this dangerous task.</description>
            <link>http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2013-03-21/californias-gun-repo-men-have-a-nerve-racking-job#r=rss</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/XuvyKS</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Is It Legal To Appear In Public Wearing Only Body Paint?</title>
            <description>The clothing retailer American Eagle posted an advertisement for spray-on jeans on its website this week, calling the product “our skinniest jeans ever.” The ad appears to be a prank, but painting models is now old hat. Is it legal to appear in public wearing nothing but body paint?</description>
            <link>http://www.slate.com/articles/life/explainer/2013/03/body_painting_does_it_run_afoul_of_public_nudity_laws.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15wL3W2</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 02:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Gay Marriage Opponents' Obsession With Sex</title>
            <description>For them, marriage is no longer about love or parenting. It's about penises and vaginas.</description>
            <link>http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/jurisprudence/2013/03/gay_marriage_and_sex_why_do_defenders_of_doma_and_prop_8_worship_coitus.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Z5j3Ip</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Is There Such A Thing As Photographic Memory?</title>
            <description>It’s the kind of thing that seems too good to be true; does anyone really have a memory as accurate as a camera?</description>
            <link>http://www.mentalfloss.com/article/49543/there-such-thing-photographic-memory</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YdUDzR</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 02:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>We Now Live In A World Where More People Have Mobile Phones Than Clean Toilets</title>
            <description>Surprisingly, the UN reports there are now more people with mobile phones (six billion for world population of seven billion) on earth than there are with access to clean toilets (4.5 billion).</description>
            <link>http://qz.com/65980/we-now-live-in-a-world-where-more-people-have-mobile-phones-than-clean-toilets/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WIUH7h</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 13:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Don't Hate CISPA</title>
            <description>Cybersecurity and privacy should not be mutually exclusive.</description>
            <link>http://www.wired.com/opinion/2013/03/dont-hate-cispa-fix-it/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wired%2Findex+%28Wired%3A+Top+Stories%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YvITD0</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Apple Removes Sweatshop iOS Game Because It Made Them Uncomfortable</title>
            <description>When Apple removes a game or other app from the App Store it’s usually because one or more of the many rules has been broken. But in the case of Sweatshop HD, the game just made Apple uncomfortable, and it’s hard to argue your case as a developer against that.</description>
            <link>http://www.geek.com/articles/mobile/apple-removes-sweatshop-ios-game-from-sale-because-it-made-them-uncomfortable-20130321/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WO07iN</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>What A Poverty Line Budget Buys You Around The World</title>
            <description>What happens when a photographer and an economist work together to document poverty around the world? When Stefen Chow and his wife, Hui-yi Lin, set out to answer that question, they came up with a photo project, The Poverty Line.</description>
            <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-21855427</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WPK3No</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 01:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Google Is Building A Smartwatch</title>
            <description>According to a recent report, Google might also be getting into the smartwatch game.</description>
            <link>http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/21/4133428/is-google-building-a-smart-watch-of-its-own</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/16Mdov4</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>'Baghdad Bob' And His Ridiculous, True Predictions</title>
            <description>Ten years later, Iraq's insane-sounding information minister turns out to be quite the soothsayer.</description>
            <link>http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2013/03/baghdad-bob-and-his-ridiculous-true-predictions/274241/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Y1FeQS</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 02:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>What If Marriage Were Temporary?</title>
            <description>With the divorce rate hovering between 40 and 50 percent, one could argue half of marriages are temporary, anyway.</description>
            <link>http://qz.com/65658/what-if-marriage-were-temporary/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/102PVjU</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 02:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Mapping The Early Universe</title>
            <description>The Planck satellite has taken the most detailed images yet of the early universe.</description>
            <link>http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2013/03/21/science/space/0321-universe.html?_r=0</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZPfeq1</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 01:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Shepard Fairey Obeys Space Station Request To Create Mission Badges</title>
            <description>He’s made indelible images for President Obama AND Neil Young. Next stop: outer space.t</description>
            <link>http://www.fastcocreate.com/1682635/shepard-fairey-obeys-space-station-request-to-create-mission-badges?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+fastcocreate%2Ffeed+%28Co.Create%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Y25SsV</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How To Get Hot, Fresh Fries Each And Every Time</title>
            <description>You know how sometimes you’ll go to McDonald’s and the fries are absolutely amazing, warm and crisp and just the best, best fries you’ve ever had? And other times, they taste like a stale, mushy vat of the Mondays?</description>
            <link>http://foodbeast.com/content/2013/03/21/til-how-to-get-hot-fresh-fries-each-and-every-time/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZOW5Ew</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 20:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Wil Wheaton Story That Will Make You Sob In Your Cheerios</title>
            <description>Last night, I was checking Facebook on my phone, when I ran across a story that many of you have may have also seen on your Facebook walls. I’m not sure what compelled me to read it, but five minutes later, my heart may have swollen 3 sizes and there was definitely something in my eye.</description>
            <link>http://www.uproxx.com/tv/2013/03/the-wil-wheaton-story-that-will-make-you-sob-in-your-cheerios/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/14emmSg</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        
 
</channel>
</rss>
