<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Digg Top Stories</title>
        <description>Digg - What the Internet is talking about right now</description>
        <link>http://digg.com/rss/top.rss</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:24:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <ttl>15</ttl>

         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>North Korean Photo Reveals 'U.S. Mainland Strike Plan'</title>
            <description>In a photo published in the Korea Worker’s Party paper plans for a strike on the U.S. mainland are clearly –and therefore probably deliberately– visible.</description>
            <link>http://www.nknews.org/2013/03/breaking-north-korean-photo-reveals-u-s-mainland-strike-plan/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10mbuw9</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Weight Of The World</title>
            <description>The average body mass index (BMI) values for adults around the globe compared.</description>
            <link>http://visual.ly/weight-world?utm_campaign=website</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/14qWRNu</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 16:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>A Shocking Number Of Americans Think Jesus Is Coming Back Really Soon</title>
            <description>Christian views in America on the return of Christ.</description>
            <link>http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/map_of_the_week/2013/03/pew_study_shows_christian_views_on_second_coming_of_christ.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10f88LH</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>This Is The Best Military Photography Of The Year</title>
            <description>The photographers and videographers employed by the U.S. armed forces are often some pretty talented artists. Here's their best work from the past year.</description>
            <link>http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2013/03/28/combat_camera_military_photography</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10m8oYQ</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Cops Ineptly Pretending To Be Punk Rockers On The Internet</title>
            <description>The Boston police go undercover on the Internet to stop the city’s most dreaded scourge: DIY indie-rock shows.</description>
            <link>http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/crime/2013/03/boston_police_catfishing_indie_rockers_cops_pose_as_punks_on_the_internet.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/1066X1K</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 13:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>FireMe! Site Exposes People Tweeting Horrible Things About Their Jobs</title>
            <description>Like some previous attempts at scaring the pants off social media users, the FireMe! site offers a tool that allows you to “check yourself” to see what your firing potential is, based on your own inappropriate tweets.</description>
            <link>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/28/fireme/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/13BkFPA</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 19:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>From The Stone Age To The Digital Age In One Big Leap</title>
            <description>Deep in the Amazon, an isolated Brazilian tribe almost vanished when it first had contact with the modern world. Now, the Surui tribe may be the most technology-savvy tribe in the Amazon.</description>
            <link>http://www.npr.org/2013/03/28/175580980/from-the-stone-age-to-the-digital-age-in-one-big-leap</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/11TTjiy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 01:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How Obama Decided God Was OK With Marriage Equality</title>
            <description>The last great mystery of Obama’s marriage shift.</description>
            <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/evanmcsan/how-obama-decided-god-was-ok-with-marriage-equality</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YNiwZp</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Filipino Man Crucified For 27th Time Takes Good Friday Seriously</title>
            <description>To many around the world, Good Friday is the start of a three-day weekend or a bitchin’ Black Crowes song. To strict devotees in the Philippines’ Pampanga province, it’s a chance to reenact crucifixion of Jesus Christ.</description>
            <link>http://hypervocal.com/news/2013/filipino-man-crucified-good-friday/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10jCY45</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 13:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Soviet Ghost Town In The Czech Republic</title>
            <description>There’s a little bit of the Soviet empire left in the middle of the Czech Republic, but it’s abandoned, decaying, and almost completely forgotten.</description>
            <link>http://www.vice.com/en_au/read/the-soviet-ghost-town-in-the-czech-republic</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/11VoWwb</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>What Was It Like To Be A Writer On A TGIF Comedy?</title>
            <description>What was it like to work on an ABC family comedy during the eighties and nineties? Vulture tracked down five veteran scribes from the Age of TGIF and asked them to bare their souls.</description>
            <link>http://www.vulture.com/2013/03/tales-from-the-tgif-writers-rooms.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YLRa5Y</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 16:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Man Charged With Hunting Deer In A Walmart Parking Lot</title>
            <description>Arcangelo Bianco Jr. wasn’t at Walmart to hunt for bargains. Instead, the Pennsylvania man has been charged with hunting deer in the parking lot of the super store, the Indiana Gazette reports this week.</description>
            <link>http://newsfeed.time.com/2013/03/29/man-arrested-for-hunting-in-a-walmart-parking-lot/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/11W8Sq0</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 13:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Enormous Storm Spans The Width Of The Atlantic Ocean</title>
            <description>This incredible storm stretches from Newfoundland to Portugal and is as intense as a category 3 hurricane.</description>
            <link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/capital-weather-gang/wp/2013/03/28/incredible-storm-spans-atlantic-ocean-coast-to-coast/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/14s5xmR</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Animals Dressed Like Humans</title>
            <description>&quot;Zoo Portraits&quot; is a funny photo series by Barcelona-based photographer Yago Partal that pairs animal heads with human bodies.</description>
            <link>http://www.mymodernmet.com/profiles/blogs/yago-partal-zoo-portraits</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/11NppjP</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 18:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Barbara Walters To Retire—Really</title>
            <description>After nearly 60 years of groundbreaking television, the ABC icon is reportedly stepping down in May 2014. A talk with Dan Rather, Mika Brzezinski, Connie Chung, and other colleagues who are in shock.</description>
            <link>http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2013/03/29/barbara-walters-to-retire-really.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Xg4Zyb</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Google's Self-Driving Robot Cars Are Ruining My Commute</title>
            <description>Away from the general unease they stir up, the Google self-driving cars come with very real consequences.</description>
            <link>http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2013-03-28/googles-self-driving-robot-cars-are-ruining-my-commute</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YFZJCb</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 22:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The One Woman Screwing Up North Dakota's Plan To End Abortion</title>
            <description>She's the only abortion provider in a state that just passed crazy restrictions. And she’s not backing down.</description>
            <link>http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2013/03/29/the-one-woman-screwing-up-north-dakota-s-plan-to-end-abortion.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/16lkLsi</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How Mud Found Off A Tiny Japanese Island May Change The Gadget Economy</title>
            <description>Japanese geologists have found a cache of rare earth elements buried in high concentrations in sea mud.</description>
            <link>http://motherboard.vice.com/blog/how-deep-sea-mud-found-off-a-tiny-japanese-island-may-change-the-gadget-economy</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YJzQhK</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 18:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Watch This Magnetic Putty Absorb A Block</title>
            <description>Here's a time lapse of magnetic putty as it absorbs a rare-earth magnet.</description>
            <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=LcQ3GWpy22Y</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YLGxzO</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 15:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Mind-Bending Enemy Within</title>
            <description>Truth is stranger than fiction when it comes to the extraordinary abilities of parasites to hijack other creatures minds... including our own.</description>
            <link>http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20130328-the-mind-bending-enemy-within</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/XgzmVi</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How Far-Right Extremists Recruit On The Internet</title>
            <description>It’s not hard to find extremists on the internet. But it’s really hard finding out who’s the most successful at spreading extremism, which can make counteracting their influence difficult.</description>
            <link>http://www.wired.com/dangerroom/2013/03/twitter-extremists/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZsgkFQ</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>All The Cool Japanese Schoolgirls Are Recreating 'Dragon Ball' Fights</title>
            <description>Even if you didn’t while away the hours in middle school by watching episode after episode of Dragon Ball while the world happened outside, you probably know what the “Kamehameha” attack looks like, even if you don’t realize it.</description>
            <link>http://www.uproxx.com/webculture/2013/03/all-the-cool-japanese-schoolgirls-are-recreating-dragon-ball-fights/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YMlRrv</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 22:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Game Developers Conference Features Sexy Dancing Ladies</title>
            <description>Last night, the International Game Developer's Association (IGDA) threw a party, which featured scantily clad female dancers gyrating around a stage.</description>
            <link>http://jezebel.com/5992787/game-developers-conference-features-sexy-dancing-ladies-because-tech-is-super-welcoming-to-women</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10Whoq1</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 21:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Art Stolen For Art's Sake</title>
            <description>Adam Parker Smith has a gallery opening today, but none of the pieces are his.</description>
            <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/29/arts/design/adam-parker-smiths-thanks-at-lu-magnus-gallery.html?hp&amp;_r=1&amp;</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10jncpX</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Humans Are Speeding Up Evolution</title>
            <description>Turns out evolution isn't always slow. Scientists in Nebraska have discovered a bird evolving right before our eyes.</description>
            <link>http://news.discovery.com/videos/humans-are-speeding-up-evolution.htm#mkcpgn=rssnws1</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10l7M5L</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 17:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Game Buried In Nevada Desert Will Launch Window In About 2,700 Years</title>
            <description>Jason Rohrer's latest creation, a board game titled A Game for Someone, is currently buried somewhere in a Nevada desert where Rohrer intends it to stay for the next 2,700 years.</description>
            <link>http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2013/03/game-buried-in-nevada-desert-has-a-launch-window-of-about-2700-years/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+arstechnica%2Findex+%28Ars+Technica+-+All+content%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10lKLj8</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 23:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Mysterious New Virus Deadlier Than SARS Discovered</title>
            <description>Mysterious coronavirus, though not less infectious, has a higher mortality rate and infects many species, Hong Kong researchers find</description>
            <link>http://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/article/1201377/hk-researchers-find-mysterious-new-coronavirus-could-be-deadlier-sars</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/14p4wvO</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 14:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>This Beautiful Mexico City Building Eats The City’s Smog</title>
            <description>Using a new type of tile that converts the chemicals in pollution into less toxic substances, the Torre de Especialidadesis is fighting the city’s bad air--and looking good in the process.</description>
            <link>http://www.fastcoexist.com/1681660/this-beautiful-mexico-city-building-eats-the-citys-smog#1</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/11RFWiX</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 19:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Ghost-Hunting Basquiat In His Old East Village Apartment</title>
            <description>Jean-Michel Basquiat’s “ex-girlfriend” has been hiding a trove of previously-unseen artifacts for thirty years in the apartment they shared in 1979-80. Now there's an avalanche of non-art media piling at her doorstep who all want to see a mural, a radiator and a door.</description>
            <link>http://www.animalnewyork.com/2013/basquiat-east-village-apartment/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10Vn5EP</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 18:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>This Massive Jellyfish Is Really An Aquatic Spy Robot</title>
            <description>This five-and-a-half-foot robot jellyfish could be the future of Navy underwater surveillance. Seriously. Maybe. Certainly, if a team of engineers from Virginia Tech gets its way.</description>
            <link>http://www.wired.com/dangerroom/2013/03/robot-jellyfish/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wired%2Findex+%28Wired%3A+Top+Stories%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10lJY1B</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 22:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>China's One-Child Policy: Corpse Brides And Forced Abortions</title>
            <description>China's one-child policy has created a long list of horrors that, besides child trafficking, includes infanticide, infant abandonment, and forced abortions, all used by families desperate to meet the set child quotas.</description>
            <link>http://www.vice.com/read/chinas-one-child-policy-is-still-ruining-lives</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YMya7l</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 22:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        
 
</channel>
</rss>
