<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Digg Top Stories</title>
        <description>Digg - What the Internet is talking about right now</description>
        <link>http://digg.com/rss/top.rss</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 12:15:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 12:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <ttl>15</ttl>

         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Gitmo Is Killing Me</title>
            <description>One man here weighs just 77 pounds. Another, 98. Last thing I knew, I weighed 132, but that was a month ago. I’ve been on a hunger strike since Feb. 10 and have lost well over 30 pounds. I will not eat until they restore my dignity.</description>
            <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/15/opinion/hunger-striking-at-guantanamo-bay.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/1347n9P</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 04:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How The U.S. Knew What North Korea Was Capable Of</title>
            <description>When you're playing a game of international diplomacy and the stakes are nuclear war, it's nice to know you hold the trump card. So how did the U.S. know just how far along North Korea's nuclear program really was?</description>
            <link>http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2013/04/15/exclusive-u-s-recovered-north-korean-rocket-head.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/XBoRde</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Secret Code Of Times Square's Mascots</title>
            <description>Times Square’s costumed pests are so merciless about squeezing unsuspecting tourists for tips that they’ll follow you for a block hissing their demands for cash — and use hand signals to spread the word about perceived cheapskates.</description>
            <link>http://www.nypost.com/p/news/local/manhattan/times_square_mascot_mafia_oleNLYRUuAO3fQxXIPtRJO</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/118XXZx</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Man Shoots Himself In The Head During NRA 500 In Texas</title>
            <description>A medical examiner says a man who died in the infield during the NRA 500 at Texas Motor Speedway shot himself in the head.</description>
            <link>http://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/nascar/2013/04/14/fan-death-investigation-texas-motor-speedway/2081395/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZtRXaV</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 03:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The NYPD Is Just Leaving Stuff Lying Around To Entrap Thieves</title>
            <description>Sometimes the bait is a small amount of cash in a stray wallet. Or a credit card. Even a pack of cigarettes can do the trick.</description>
            <link>http://bigstory.ap.org/article/take-bait-nypd-anti-theft-tactics-criticized#overlay-context=article/gunmen-attack-mogadishu-court-complex-witnesses</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15dxPCj</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 20:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Best Moments From The MTV Movie Awards</title>
            <description>Mark Wahlberg crashes ‘Catfish.’ Rebel Wilson grinds to Macklemore. James Franco heads to Oz.</description>
            <link>http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2013/04/14/mtv-movie-awards-2013-best-moments-rebel-wilson-more-video.html?utm_source=feedburner</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YVTyef</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 02:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>TurboTax Goes Down At The Worst Possible Moment And Doesn't Handle It Well</title>
            <description>TurboTax ran into some problems Sunday night and didn't do a great job of mitigating the fallout on Twitter.</description>
            <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeednews/turbotax-falters-at-the-worst-possible-moment</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/XBh5jr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Psy's Follow-Up To 'Gangnam Style' Smashes Single-Day Hits Record On YouTube</title>
            <description>&quot;Gangnam Style&quot; star Psy's new music video had received more than 50 million views on YouTube by Monday, re-writing the video-sharing site's records for single-day hits.</description>
            <link>http://m.phys.org/news/2013-04-psy-gentleman-video-youtube.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZrHXjx</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Live Apple Bicycle Photographed In Natural Habitat</title>
            <description>Most people know about Google’s famous multi-colored bikes. They’re hard to miss, scattered around the company’s Mountain View campus like hundreds of discarded toys. But you may not realize that Apple runs its own bike operation, and it too spans hundreds of bikes.</description>
            <link>http://www.wired.com/wiredenterprise/2013/04/apple_bike/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wired%2Findex+%28Wired%3A+Top+Stories%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/116v8va</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Re-Live Adam Scott's Electric Masters Win</title>
            <description>Here's how one of the greatest finishes in golf's greatest event went down.</description>
            <link>http://www.theatlanticwire.com/entertainment/2013/04/adam-scott-masters-win/64214/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/115uPRc</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 02:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>When Luxury Cars Become Beautiful Pieces Of Furniture</title>
            <description>Cars aren't just a means of getting from A to B — they're also beautiful design classics that express your personality. So it's not surprising that people are turning some of the world's most beautiful vehicles into part of their home decor.</description>
            <link>http://io9.com/theres-nothing-more-stylish-than-a-bookcase-or-bed-mad-472393677</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZM6GoT</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 23:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>A BBC Crew Snuck Into North Korea Posing As Students To Shoot A Documentary</title>
            <description>The BBC has insisted it will broadcast a controversial Panorama documentary about North Korea, despite protests from the London School of Economics (LSE) that journalist John Sweeney put its staff working abroad at risk by posing as a student from the institution to gain access to the communist state.</description>
            <link>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2013/apr/14/bbc-north-korea-panorama-film</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Yn5B0d</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 18:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>A Surprising Map Of The Countries Where Banks Are Most And Least Trusted</title>
            <description>Just under half of adults in 18 of the world’s most important economies say they trust banking institutions “to do the right thing,” according to a new study by the public relations firm Edelman.</description>
            <link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/worldviews/wp/2013/04/12/a-surprising-map-of-the-countries-where-banks-are-most-and-least-trusted/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZPCZTT</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 20:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Wait, Men Fake Orgasms?</title>
            <description>A new book delivers surprising news about male sexuality -- including that, yes, some guys are really fooling you.</description>
            <link>http://www.salon.com/2013/04/13/wait_men_fake_orgasms/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/17y4SjH</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 14:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How Five Real Economists Think About Bitcoin's Future</title>
            <description>Instead of trying to determine future scenarios in a world I don’t understand and because Twitter has turned everyone into armchair professors, I reached out to a number of practicing economists who were either former professors or classmates, or had friends make introductions, and asked them to chime in briefly on a future with Bitcoin.</description>
            <link>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/14/iterations-how-five-real-economists-think-about-bitcoins-future/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10VgIPv</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Why China's Communist Party Isn't Really Afraid Of The Internet</title>
            <description>China's control of the internet is so deeply entrenched and sophisticated that concerns about it getting out of hand are pure theater.</description>
            <link>http://qz.com/74013/chinas-communist-party-isnt-really-afraid-of-the-internet/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YTD321</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 13:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Russia, U.S. Fighting A 'War Of Lists'</title>
            <description>Russia and the United States are in the middle of a sanction-off.</description>
            <link>http://www.theatlanticwire.com/global/2013/04/russia-united-states-fighting-war-lists/64204/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/15bE6OO</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 13:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>10 Incredible Repurposed Train Stations</title>
            <description>The heyday of railway travel may have passed, but the nostalgic allure of architecturally striking infrastructure has ensured that it’s not the end of the line for many historic station buildings.</description>
            <link>http://flavorwire.com/384627/10-incredible-repurposed-train-stations/view-all</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YFsrVu</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 15:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How The CIA Helped Disney Conquer Florida</title>
            <description>With advice from former CIA operatives and lawyers, Disney bought up the land for Florida’s Disney World and orchestrated a unique legal situation—and set up an unconstitutional form of government.</description>
            <link>http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2013/04/14/how-the-cia-helped-disney-conquer-florida.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+thedailybeast%2Farticles+%28The+Daily+Beast+-+Latest+Articles%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZuiyVs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 13:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Surprisingly Simple Trick That Makes You Think You Have An Invsible Hand</title>
            <description>Hold your hand up in front of your face. It is patently obvious that the five-fingered thing in front of you is your hand, and the empty space next to it is not. But this ability to recognise your own body is more complicated than it first appears, and can be fooled through a surprisingly simple trick.</description>
            <link>http://phenomena.nationalgeographic.com/2013/04/14/the-invisible-hand-illusion/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZiVJb9</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 17:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The High-Tech Sex Workers Of Silicon Valley</title>
            <description>From accepting mobile payments to live Tweeting their cam shows, Bay Area sex workers have adopted the technology developed in the area for their own businesses.</description>
            <link>http://money.cnn.com/video/technology/2013/04/12/t-high-tech-sex-workers-silicon-valley.cnnmoney</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/12STYoP</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 17:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Justin Bieber Left An Incredibly Idiotic Message At The Anne Frank House</title>
            <description>The pop singer is criticized for a note he wrote at the guestbook of the Amsterdam museum.</description>
            <link>http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/earshot/justin-bieber-at-anne-frank-439291</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/1793MaU</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 15:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        
 
</channel>
</rss>
