<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Digg Top Stories</title>
        <description>Digg - What the Internet is talking about right now</description>
        <link>http://digg.com/rss/top.rss</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:35:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <ttl>15</ttl>

         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Why All Of Your Favorite Shows Are Ratings Disasters</title>
            <description>The new rules of the hyper-social, data-driven, actor-friendly, super-seductive platinum age of television.</description>
            <link>http://www.wired.com/underwire/2013/03/nielsen-family-is-dead/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WT04Df</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 13:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Iraq War In Photos</title>
            <description>It's been 10 years since U.S.-led forces waged war in Iraq. In this collection of some of Reuters iconic images from the conflict, the photographers provide a personal account of the events they captured.</description>
            <link>http://blogs.reuters.com/fullfocus/2013/03/19/photographers-notebook-iraq-war/#a=1</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/137VDHx</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 13:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Ian McKellen To Officiate Patrick Stewart’s Wedding</title>
            <description>Fanfic writers, your dreams are coming true: Magneto is marrying Professor X.</description>
            <link>http://popwatch.ew.com/2013/03/18/ian-mckellen-patrick-stewart-wedding/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/XWJsv6</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 12:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Google Expected To Unify Chat Under The Name Babble</title>
            <description>Google’s quest to continue unifying their products is about to enter its next phase. According to multiple sources, the company’s next step includes unifying their messaging platforms into a single service, which is expected to be called Babble.</description>
            <link>http://www.geek.com/articles/mobile/google-expected-to-unify-chat-under-the-name-babble-20130318/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YjQY0D</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 12:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Kings Of Q*bert</title>
            <description>Why do we play arcade games for hundreds of hours?</description>
            <link>http://www.grantland.com/story/_/id/9053237/q*bert-video-game-marathoning-trend-aftermath-king-kong</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YMjLu6</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 03:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The School Tuitions Of The NCAA Bracket</title>
            <description>It is once again time for the NCAA &quot;March Madness&quot; basketball tournament. The eventual champions will get to bask in the national spotlight until the next cruise-ship disaster/shark attack/episode of &quot;Girls&quot;/baseball season/ happens. And sure, winning a basketball title is worth bragging about; but we all know the real champion is the institution of higher education that can charge the most tuition and still have enough students to keep its rejection letter printer warm.</description>
            <link>http://www.theawl.com/2013/03/2013-march-madne-the-school-tuitions-of-the-ncaa-bracket?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheAwl+%28The+Awl%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/108OB1j</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 14:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Of Course Samsung Is Also Developing A Smartwatch</title>
            <description>Samsung is developing a wristwatch as Asia’s biggest technology company races against Apple to create a new industry of wearable devices that perform similar tasks as smartphones.</description>
            <link>http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-19/samsung-preparing-wristwatch-as-it-races-apple-for-sales.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/XVQSNd</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 11:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How One Rule Change Could Blow Up Your NCAA Bracket</title>
            <description>Filling out an NCAA tournament bracket with accurate predictions is no easy task. That only got tougher this year, thanks to a significant tweak in the way the selection committee determined the matchups.</description>
            <link>http://theweek.com/article/index/241521/how-one-rule-change-could-blow-up-your-ncaa-bracket</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZWeTkX</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 02:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Gun Industry's Big Bet On Silencers</title>
            <description>The silencer industry says its product is for shooting groundhogs, so how come their ads feature military-style gunmen?</description>
            <link>http://www.motherjones.com/politics/2013/03/guns-nra-national-rifle-association-wants-states-legalize-silencers-supressors</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/1456BwJ</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 11:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Inauguration Of Pope Francis</title>
            <description>The eyes of Catholics around the globe were on the Vatican this morning for the inaugural mass of Jorge Bergoglio as Pope Francis.</description>
            <link>http://www.theatlanticwire.com/global/2013/03/live-inauguration-pope-francis/63263/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/ZPu3qY</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 13:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>What Would A North Korean War Do To DMZ Wildlife?</title>
            <description>Should open warfare between North and South Korea break out, the approximately 400 square miles of wilderness in the Demilitarized Zone, would likely be one of the first casualties. Ironically, peace might also be problematic for the wildlife of the DMZ.</description>
            <link>http://news.discovery.com/earth/what-would-a-new-korean-war-do-to-dmz-wildlife-130318.htm#mkcpgn=rssnws1</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WysRvU</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 17:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Are Americans Ready To Use Nuclear Weapons?</title>
            <description>On the tenth anniversary of America’s optional war, how ready would Americans be to nuke another country?</description>
            <link>http://www.psmag.com/politics/how-we-learned-to-set-aside-our-moral-qualms-and-love-the-bomb-54048/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+miller-mccune%2Fmain_feed+%28Pacific+Standard+-+Main+Feed%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/114bba2</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 11:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>This Painting Was Made By Injecting Paint In Bubble Wrap</title>
            <description>Bradley Hart has an obsession with Bubble Wrap… then again, who doesn’t? Hart, however, has taken this object to entirely new artistic levels. While he originally painted discarded materials and the exterior of bubble wrap creating abstract artworks, his newest pieces see him injecting each bubble with paint. The result is a fantastic analog/digital picture fitting of our modern era.</description>
            <link>http://www.visualnews.com/2013/03/19/paintings-made-by-injecting-paint-in-bubble-wrap/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed:+TheVisualNews+(Visual+News)</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10czIuT</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 13:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>A Love Letter From The Past</title>
            <description>A letter written 60 years ago finally shows up.</description>
            <link>http://www.southbendtribune.com/news/sbt-a-special-delivery-a-letter-from-the-past-20130317,0,2361304.column?track=rss</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WQ0Zo7</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 01:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>A Semi-Insane, Semi-Logical Classification Of All 68 Tournament Teams</title>
            <description>Rather than look at the bracket or obsess about matchups, this is about identifying the essential core trait of all 68 tournament teams. Could they win the title? Are they tragically flawed? Are they doomed from the get-go? Are they Wisconsin?</description>
            <link>http://www.grantland.com/blog/the-triangle/post/_/id/54555/a-semi-insane-semi-logical-classification-of-all-68-tournament-teams</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/YLFemT</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 04:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Fighters Who Smile Before Bouts Are More Likely To Lose</title>
            <description>A new study has analysed photographs taken at dozens of pre-fight encounters and found that competitors who smile are more likely to lose the match the next day.</description>
            <link>http://bps-research-digest.blogspot.com/2013/03/smiling-fighters-more-likely-to-lose.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/10BPuBX</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 12:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Should We Bring Extinct Species Back To Life?</title>
            <description>The revival of an extinct species is no longer a fantasy. But is it a good idea?</description>
            <link>http://ngm.nationalgeographic.com/2013/04/species-revival/zimmer-text?src=longreads</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/134jLuB</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 15:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The CIA Actually Thought Saddam Had Drones Full Of Bioweapons</title>
            <description>Few things age as poorly as bad intelligence. And while there was no shortage of terrible intelligence undergirding the Iraq war, there was no more bewildering claim given credulity by the CIA and the Bush administration than the idea that Saddam Hussein was going to use drones to unleash a merciless biological attack.</description>
            <link>http://www.wired.com/dangerroom/2013/03/drone-bioweapons/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wired%2Findex+%28Wired%3A+Top+Stories%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Yo6YLX</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 11:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Is George Will Homophobic?</title>
            <description>In a conservative movement seized by extremists, George Will is one of the sane ones. But his recent rejection of social science as having any role to play in the gay marriage debate is wildly off the mark.</description>
            <link>http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/politics/2013/03/george_will_on_gay_marriage_the_conservative_columnist_s_rejection_of_the.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Z9HTU1</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 03:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Why Do Some People Faint When They See Blood?</title>
            <description>It's a phobia, but other phobias don't give you that same woozy feeling.</description>
            <link>http://www.popsci.com/science/article/2013-03/fyi-why-do-some-people-faint-when-they-see-blood</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/115fDFu</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 17:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Car Industry’s Lame Attempts To Entice Women</title>
            <description>Why does the auto industry get women so wrong?</description>
            <link>http://www.slate.com/articles/double_x/doublex/2013/03/car_ads_for_women_does_the_industry_get_it_all_wrong.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/XYTf3M</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 11:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Star Wars Family Tree</title>
            <description>The various relationships of Star Wars characters, whether that be romance, a significant battle or otherwise.</description>
            <link>http://www.joe-stone.co.uk/portfolio/swfamilytree.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/107A1Hi</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 00:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Abandoned Spaces Given Graffiti Facelifts</title>
            <description>Russian street artist Nomerz transforms old buildings into wonderfully realistic faces.</description>
            <link>http://www.environmentalgraffiti.com/news-fantastic-graffiti-makes-architectural-faces</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/147BMHV</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 11:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>How To Make A Batarang</title>
            <description>All you need is a plasma cutter and a 1,500-degree furnace to make a very pointy, very sharp version of Batman's classic weapon.</description>
            <link>http://news.cnet.com/8301-17938_105-57574859-1/armorer-makes-batman-batarangs-sharp-as-an-ax/?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=title</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/XUUfGl</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 17:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>An iPhone In Different Colors Looks Fantastically Fun</title>
            <description>I've never wanted an iPhone in different colors. Black with a tint of gloss or white with a silver lining has always been plenty enough. But then I saw these renders of what an iPhone in different colors would look like and man, a red iPhone looks like so much fun.</description>
            <link>http://gizmodo.com/5991119/an-iphone-in-different-colors-looks-fantastically-fun</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/143xXU1</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 17:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>The Stressful Life Of A King Amidst Chaos</title>
            <description>As the Arab Spring swirls around him, can King Abdullah II, the most pro-American Arab leader in the Middle East, liberalize Jordan and modernize its economy, without losing his kingdom to Islamic fundamentalists?</description>
            <link>http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2013/04/monarch-in-the-middle/309270/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/Xwwkg6</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 01:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Swallows May Be Evolving To Dodge Traffic</title>
            <description>Road-kill numbers of roadside-nesting cliff swallows have dropped as birds shorten their wings to become more agile.</description>
            <link>http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=swallows-may-be-evolving-to-dodge-traffic</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WzIwcV</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 22:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>In British Columbia, Unmarried Couples Are Now Technically Married</title>
            <description>A new law that took effect Monday in British Columbia turned thousands of unmarried couples into married couples -- at least from a property perspective.</description>
            <link>http://bigthink.com/ideafeed/in-british-columbia-unmarried-couples-are-now-technically-married?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+bigthink%2Fmain+%28Big+Think+Main%29</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/WzLHCL</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 22:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>What Egg McMuffin Sales Say About The US Economy</title>
            <description>Looking for confirmation that nascent US economic recovery is for real? Watch breakfast sales at the Golden Arches.</description>
            <link>http://qz.com/64294/what-egg-mcmuffin-sales-say-about-the-us-economy/</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/XlA12D</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 23:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Porn Hurts Like Hell</title>
            <description>The performers may look like they're in ecstasy, but the physical pain and endurance that goes into sex for the camera would make an NFL linebacker weep.</description>
            <link>http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2013/03/18/blood-sweat-and-sex-my-hard-life-in-porn.html</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/105KZwX</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 23:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
         
            
            
            
            
            
            
            
        <item>
            <title>Morbid Find Suggests Adam Lanza Plotted Massacre For Years</title>
            <description>Law enforcement reportedly discovers a sickeningly thorough 7-foot-long, 4-foot-wide spreadsheet with names, body counts and weapons from previous mass murders and even attempted killings.</description>
            <link>http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/lupica-lanza-plotted-massacre-years-article-1.1291408?print</link>
            <guid>http://on.digg.com/1167qkx</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 00:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        
 
</channel>
</rss>
