<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>kottke.org</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/" />
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.kottke.org/main" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2009-08-11:05118</id>
    <updated></updated>
    <subtitle>Jason Kottke&apos;s weblog, home of fine hypertext products</subtitle>

    <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type 4.2</generator>

<entry>
    <title>&quot;You my Midga&quot;</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/you-my-midga" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23413</id>

    <published>2013-04-04T20:05:32Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T20:05:32Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>I'm reading back through <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Roger%20Ebert">my archive</a> of stuff written by and about Roger Ebert and I realized I've never written about my favorite piece of his: <a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20050501/COMMENTARY/50429001">Dwarfs, Little People and the M-Word</a>. It's nothing particularly earthshattering or insightful, but the piece demonstrates what I really liked about Ebert: humanist, happy to be corrected when in the wrong, not afraid to poke fun at himself, and a lover of both language and knowledge.</p>

<blockquote><p>I had no idea the word "midget" was considered offensive, and you are the only person who has ever written to me about it. In my mind it is a descriptive term, like "dwarf." "Little People" has seemed to me to have a vaguely condescending cuteness to it. If I am now informed that "midget" is offensive, I will no longer use it. What is your feeling about "dwarf?" Is "Little Person" always the preferred term? Our newspaper's style book, based on Associated Press, does not consider "midget" or "dwarf" to be offensive terms, but perhaps we have not caught up.</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Roger Ebert">Roger Ebert</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/language">language</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Roger Ebert, RIP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/roger-ebert-rip" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23412</id>

    <published>2013-04-04T19:46:42Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T19:46:42Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Earlier today, I linked to <a href="http://blogs.suntimes.com/ebert/2013/04/a_leave_of_presense.html">a post by Roger Ebert</a> announcing his leave of presence. The Chicago Sun-Times <a href="http://www.suntimes.com/news/metro/17320958-418/roger-ebert-dies-at-70-after-battle-with-cancer.html">has announced that Ebert died today at 70</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Ebert, 70, who reviewed movies for the Chicago Sun-Times for 46 years and on TV for 31 years, and who was without question the nation's most prominent and influential film critic, died Thursday in Chicago. He had been in poor health over the past decade, battling cancers of the thyroid and salivary gland.</p>

<p>He lost part of his lower jaw in 2006, and with it the ability to speak or eat, a calamity that would have driven other men from the public eye. But Ebert refused to hide, instead forging what became a new chapter in his career, an extraordinary chronicle of his devastating illness that won him a new generation of admirers. "No point in denying it," he wrote, analyzing his medical struggles with characteristic courage, candor and wit, a view that was never tinged with bitterness or self-pity.</p>

<p>Always technically savvy - he was an early investor in Google - Ebert let the Internet be his voice. His rogerebert.com had millions of fans, and he received a special achievement award as the 2010 "Person of the Year" from the Webby Awards, which noted that "his online journal has raised the bar for the level of poignancy, thoughtfulness and critique one can achieve on the Web." His Twitter feeds had 827,000 followers.</p>

<p>Ebert was both widely popular and professionally respected. He not only won a Pulitzer Prize - the first film critic to do so - but his name was added to the Hollywood Walk of Fame in 2005, among the movie stars he wrote about so well for so long. His reviews were syndicated in hundreds of newspapers worldwide.</p></blockquote>

<p>Rest in peace, Roger. And fuck cancer.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/movies">movies</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/obituaries">obituaries</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Roger Ebert">Roger Ebert</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Healthy fast food?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/healthy-fast-food" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23407</id>

    <published>2013-04-04T19:39:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T19:39:39Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Mark Bittman <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/07/magazine/yes-healthful-fast-food-is-possible-but-edible.html?pagewanted=all">explores the world of healthy fast food</a> and discovers that's slowly becoming a thing.</p>

<blockquote><p>Good Fast Food doesn't need to be vegan or even vegetarian; it just ought to be real, whole food. The best word to describe a wise contemporary diet is flexitarian, which is nothing more than intelligent omnivorism. There are probably millions of people who now eat this way, including me. My own style, which has worked for me for six years, is to eat a vegan diet before 6 p.m. and then allow myself pretty much whatever I want for dinner. This flexibility avoids junk and emphasizes plants, and Lyfe Kitchen, which offers both "chickin" and chicken -- plus beans, vegetables and grains in their whole forms (all for under 600 calories per dish) -- comes closest to this ideal. But the menu offers too much, the service raises prices too high and speed is going to be an issue. My advice would be to skip the service and the wine, make a limited menu with big flavors and a few treats and keep it as cheap as you can. Of course, there are huge players who could do this almost instantaneously. But the best thing they seem able to come up with is the McWrap or the fresco menu.</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/food">food</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Mark Bittman">Mark Bittman</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Ebert&apos;s cancer is back</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/eberts-cancer-is-back" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23408</id>

    <published>2013-04-04T18:13:21Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T18:13:21Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Sad news from Chicago: Roger Ebert's cancer has returned and <a href="http://blogs.suntimes.com/ebert/2013/04/a_leave_of_presense.html">he's taking what he calls a "leave of presence"</a> to focus on recovery and a few different projects.</p>

<blockquote><p>What in the world is a leave of presence? It means I am not going away. My intent is to continue to write selected reviews but to leave the rest to a talented team of writers handpicked and greatly admired by me. What's more, I'll be able at last to do what I've always fantasized about doing: reviewing only the movies I want to review.</p>

<p>At the same time, I am re-launching the new and improved Rogerebert.com and taking ownership of the site under a separate entity, Ebert Digital, run by me, my beloved wife, Chaz, and our brilliant friend, Josh Golden of Table XI. Stepping away from the day-to-day grind will enable me to continue as a film critic for the Chicago Sun-Times, and roll out other projects under the Ebert brand in the coming year.</p></blockquote>

<p>Love that first sentence. Get well soon, Roger.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/cancer">cancer</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/movies">movies</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Roger Ebert">Roger Ebert</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The 80s!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/the-80s" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23406</id>

    <published>2013-04-04T17:02:16Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T17:02:16Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>After an exhaustive search, I have decided this photo most exemplifies life in these United States during the 1980s:</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/roger-minick-sightseer.jpg" width="640" height="640" border="0" alt="Roger Minick Sightseer" /></p>

<p>And if not that one, then one of several other possible candidates from Roger Minick's <a href="http://sightseerseries.com/">Sightseer project</a>, for which he took photos of tourists at popular US tourist destinations during the early 1980s and into the 2000s.</p>

<blockquote><p>When I approached people for a portrait, I tried to make my request clear and to the point, making it clear that I was not trying to sell them anything. I explained that my wife and I were traveling around the country visiting most of the major tourist destinations so that I could photograph the activity of sightseeing. I would quickly add that I hoped the project would have cultural value and might be seen in years to come as a kind of time capsule of what Americans looked like at the end of the Twentieth Century; at which, to my surprise, I would see people often begin to nod their heads as if they knew what I was talking about.</p></blockquote>

<p>Slate did <a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/behold/2013/03/27/roger_minick_sightseers_looks_at_tourists_across_the_united_states_over.html">a feature</a> on this series last week.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/photography">photography</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Roger Minick">Roger Minick</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/travel">travel</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/USA">USA</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Retouching the classics</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/retouching-the-classics" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23399</id>

    <published>2013-04-04T16:05:35Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T16:05:35Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>For his <a href="http://www.alphabeauties.com/">Alpha Beauties</a> project, artist Nazareno Crea retouches paintings and sculpture from throughout history, a process which normalizes each period's ideal of female beauty to that of the present day. That is, much skinnier, with smaller noses, higher cheekbones, and larger breasts.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/alpha-beauties-mona.jpg" width="640" height="473" border="0" alt="Alpha Beauties Mona" /></p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/alpha-beauties-venus.jpg" width="640" height="431" border="0" alt="Alpha Beauties Venus" /></p>

<p>Similar projects: <a href="http://www.annautopiagiordano.it/venus-ita.html">Venus</a> and <a href="http://cargocollective.com/oldschoolashell/IRREAL-IDEAL">Eye of the Beholder</a>.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/art">art</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Nazareno Crea">Nazareno Crea</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/remix">remix</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Date for new Arrested Development: May 26th</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/date-for-new-arrested-development-may-26th" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23403</id>

    <published>2013-04-04T15:10:23Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T15:10:23Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Netflix <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/4/4182210/arrested-development-season-4-release-date-may-26">has announced</a> that the 15 episodes of the new season of Arrested Development will be released, all at once, on May 26th. Netflix did not announce that later that day, all 15 episodes will be available on BitTorrent.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Arrested Development">Arrested Development</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Netflix">Netflix</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/TV">TV</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The anti-drone hoodie</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/the-anti-drone-hoodie" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23402</id>

    <published>2013-04-04T14:44:33Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T14:44:33Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Designer Adam Harvey, who gave the world <a href="http://ahprojects.com/projects/camoflash">the anti-paparazzi purse</a> and <a href="http://ahprojects.com/projects/cv-dazzle">dazzle camouflage for the face</a>, has <a href="http://ahprojects.com/projects/stealth-wear">developed a hoodie</a> that makes the wearer invisible to the sort of thermal imaging utilized by surveillance drones.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/anti-drone-hoodie.jpg" width="640" height="320" border="0" alt="Anti Drone Hoodie" /></p>

<p>This is the most <a href="http://new-aesthetic.tumblr.com/about">New Aesthetic</a> thing I have ever seen. <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/artanddesign/2013/mar/31/anti-drone-hoodie-big-brother">The Guardian has more</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>"These are primarily fashion items and art items," Harvey tells me. "I'm not trying to make products for survivalists. I would like to introduce this idea to people: that surveillance is not bulletproof. That there are ways to interact with it and there are ways to aestheticise it."</p></blockquote>

<p>I imagine that at some point, anti-drone clothing will eject <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chaff_(countermeasure)">chaff</a> as a countermeasure against incoming drone-launched missiles. (via <a href="https://twitter.com/DavidGrann">@DavidGrann</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Adam Harvey">Adam Harvey</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/art">art</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/design">design</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/drones">drones</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/fashion">fashion</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/New Aesthetic">New Aesthetic</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Earliest known aerial photograph is of Boston</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/earliest-known-aerial-photograph-is-of-boston" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23401</id>

    <published>2013-04-04T14:12:43Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T14:12:43Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Aaron Cohen</name>
        <uri>http://www.unlikelywords.com</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/oldest-surviving-aerial.jpg" width="640" height="754" border="0" alt="oldest surviving aerial photograph" /></p>

<p>While French balloonist Gaspard-F&eacute;lix Tournachon first photographed Paris by air in 1858, those photos were lost, and <a href="http://www.petapixel.com/2013/04/02/the-oldest-surviving-aerial-photograph/">this photograph of Boston from 1860 by James Wallace Black</a> is the earliest known aerial photo. The title is 'Boston, as the Eagle and the Wild Goose See It.' If I had to guess where in Boston this is, I'd say somewhere along Atlantic Ave.</p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong> Several people have identified the steepled building at center left as the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_South_Meeting_House">Old South Meeting House</a>, which Wikipedia <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:1860_Boston_AsTheEagle_AndThe_WildGoose_SeeIt_byJWBlack.jpg">confirms</a>: "Depicts area resembling Old South Meeting House; Milk Street; India Wharf, Central Wharf; and vicinity." Looks <a href="https://twitter.com/scheeko/status/319826507147132928">a bit different</a> these days.</p>

<p>But more importantly, <a href="http://www.moma.org/collection/object.php?object_id=57657">a photo of Providence, RI taken by Black in August of 1860</a> predates his Boston photograph by two months. The print, which is part of the MoMA's collection, is badly damaged but it looks like some detail would be discernable in person.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/oldest-surviving-aerial-2.jpg" width="336" height="420" border="0" alt="oldest surviving aerial photo" /></p>

<p>So for some sufficiently flexible definition of "surviving", Black's photo of Providence is the oldest surviving aerial photo. (thx, david)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Boston">Boston</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/photography">photography</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>On the 40th anniversary of the first cellphone call</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/on-the-40th-anniversary-of-the-first-cellphone-call" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23400</id>

    <published>2013-04-04T01:57:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T01:57:39Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/motorola-microtac.jpg" width="640" height="690" border="0" alt="Motorola Microtac" /></p>

<p>I still remember the first time I saw a guy at a restaurant talking on one of those prehistorically massive cellphones. My dad leaned over and said, "Look at that poor guy. Never let that happen to you. Never take a job that's so all-consuming that you have to carry a phone around, even during lunch." A lot has changed since then (although I still often see a lot of validity in my dad's initial response to these devices) and in the forty years since Motorola engineer Martin Cooper made the first cellphone call. Wired takes a look back at <a href="http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2013/04/influential-cellphones/?viewall=true">the twelve cellphones that changed our world forever</a>.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/lists">lists</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/telephony">telephony</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Stretching before exercise considered harmful</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/stretching-before-exercise-considered-harmful" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23398</id>

    <published>2013-04-04T00:35:36Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T00:35:36Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Or at least unbeneficial. A comprehensive study out of Croatia complements other evidence that <a href="http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/04/03/reasons-not-to-stretch/">stretching your muscles before exercise results in less strength, power, and performance</a> than if you hadn't stretched.</p>

<blockquote><p>The numbers, especially for competitive athletes, are sobering. According to their calculations, static stretching reduces strength in the stretched muscles by almost 5.5 percent, with the impact increasing in people who hold individual stretches for 90 seconds or more. While the effect is reduced somewhat when people's stretches last less than 45 seconds, stretched muscles are, in general, substantially less strong.</p>

<p>They also are less powerful, with power being a measure of the muscle's ability to produce force during contractions, according to Goran Markovic, a professor of kinesiology at the University of Zagreb and the study's senior author. In Dr. Markovic and his colleagues' re-analysis of past data, they determined that muscle power generally falls by about 2 percent after stretching.</p>

<p>And as a result, they found, explosive muscular performance also drops off significantly, by as much as 2.8 percent. That means that someone trying to burst from the starting blocks, blast out a ballistic first tennis serve, clean and jerk a laden barbell, block a basketball shot, or even tick off a fleet opening mile in a marathon will be ill served by stretching first. Their performance after warming up with stretching is likely to be worse than if they hadn't warmed up at all.</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/medicine">medicine</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/science">science</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Rdio introduces streaming video service</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/rdio-introduces-streaming-video-service" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23397</id>

    <published>2013-04-03T18:42:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-03T18:42:12Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Streaming music service <a href="http://rdio.com">Rdio</a> (which I have been enjoying the hell out of for the past couple months<sup id="t-0403131"><a href="#f-0403131">1</a></sup>) is <a href="http://blog.rdio.com/us/2013/04/introducing-vdio.html">launching a streaming video service called Vdio</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>The first thing you'll notice about Vdio is that it's designed to solve the "what to watch" problem. It's not just that we've got amazing content, but that the experience is now geared to get you from searching to watching faster. We're introducing the notion of Sets -- playlists for TV shows and movies -- so anyone can make and share lists of their favorites, making it easier than ever to discover new stuff. Or, you can just check out what your friends are watching in the moment and jump in. Beyond that, Vdio has the beautiful design and social features that people love about Rdio, with plenty more to come.</p></blockquote>

<p>I haven't played with it too much, but it looks like it's not an all-you-can-eat service like Rdio...you buy/rent movies and TV shows just like iTunes, Amazon, etc.</p>

<p><a id="f-0403131"></a>[1] And that's actually a huge understatement. I ignored streaming music services like Rdio and Spotify when they came out, opting for the familiarity of iTunes, but Rdio has completely reignited my love of music over the past two months. Should write a whole post about this at some point. <a href="#t-0403131">&#8617;</a></p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/movies">movies</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/music">music</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Rdio">Rdio</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Vdio">Vdio</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>How a differential gear works</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/how-a-differential-gear-works" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23367</id>

    <published>2013-04-03T14:11:59Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-03T14:11:59Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>I've posted this before, but it's so good, here it is again: a super-simple explanation of why differential gears are necessary in cars and how they work.</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="480" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/F40ZBDAG8-o?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>(via <a href="https://twitter.com/stevenstrogatz">@stevenstrogatz</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/cars">cars</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/science">science</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video">video</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Lester Bangs&apos; obituary for Elvis Presley</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/lester-bangs-obituary-for-elvis-presley" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23396</id>

    <published>2013-04-02T20:12:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-02T20:12:45Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>When Elvis Presley died in 1977, legendary rock critic Lester Bangs <a href="http://josephwaldman.livejournal.com/43782.html">wrote a piece on the singer for the Village Voice</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>I got taken too the one time I saw Elvis, but in a totally different way. It was the autumn of 1971, and two tickets to an Elvis show turned up at the offices of Creem magazine, where I was then employed. It was decided that those staff members who had never had the privilege of witnessing Elvis should get the tickets, which was how me and art director Charlie Auringer ended up in nearly the front row of the biggest arena in Detroit. Earlier Charlie had said, "Do you realize how much we could get if we sold these fucking things?" I didn't, but how precious they were became totally clear the instant Elvis sauntered onto the stage. He was the only male performer I have ever seen to whom I responded sexually; it wasn't real arousal, rather an erection of the heart, when I looked at him I went mad with desire and envy and worship and self-projection. I mean, Mick Jagger, whom I saw as far back as 1964 and twice in '65, never even came close.</p></blockquote>

<p>(via <a href="https://twitter.com/gavinpurcell">@gavinpurcell</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Elvis Presley">Elvis Presley</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Lester Bangs">Lester Bangs</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/music">music</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/obituaries">obituaries</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The Beaver Trilogy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/the-beaver-trilogy" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23368</id>

    <published>2013-04-02T16:26:26Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-02T16:26:26Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Caught a rerun of <a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/radio-archives/episode/226/reruns">an episode of This American Life on reruns</a> the other day. The first segment is about a movie I'd never heard about before, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Beaver_Trilogy">The Beaver Trilogy</a>. I don't want to spoil it too much (the Wikipedia page contains spoilers as well) but the first part of the film features documentary footage of a kid from Beaver, Utah doing impressions and putting on a talent show. The second and third parts are recreations of that footage featuring, well, just listen to the story or watch the first two parts of the movie for yourself (<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wgVTrafoCHA">one</a>, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2s7FkZXiCNE">two</a>). (thx, <a href="https://twitter.com/eventi">@eventi</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/movies">movies</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/The Beaver Trilogy">The Beaver Trilogy</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Supercut of movie scenes that break the fourth wall</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/supercut-of-movie-scenes-that-break-the-fourth-wall" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23393</id>

    <published>2013-04-02T14:48:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-02T14:48:38Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Leigh Singer gathered more than 50 clips from movies that break the fourth wall (where the characters acknowledge they're in a movie).</p>

<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/60845952?color=1db4c2" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Sadly my favorite broken fourth wall moment didn't make the list: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=emvySA1-3t8">Billy Ray Valentine in Trading Places getting a commodities lesson from the Dukes</a>. (via <a href="http://smarterinfive.com/19/the-fourth-wall/">smarter in five</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Leigh Singer">Leigh Singer</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/movies">movies</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video">video</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Rising global temps not keeping pace with soaring greenhouse-gas emissions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/rising-global-temps-not-keeping-pace-with-soaring-greenhouse-gas-emissions" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23395</id>

    <published>2013-04-01T21:35:14Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T21:35:14Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Climate scientists have been wrestling with a curious fact lately: the rise in global temperature has been flat over the past decade or more even as we pump ever-increasing rates of carbon dioxide into the atmosphere. <a href="http://www.economist.com/news/science-and-technology/21574461-climate-may-be-heating-up-less-response-greenhouse-gas-emissions">The Economist discusses what that might mean for the climate and climate science</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Over the past 15 years air temperatures at the Earth's surface have been flat while greenhouse-gas emissions have continued to soar. The world added roughly 100 billion tonnes of carbon to the atmosphere between 2000 and 2010. That is about a quarter of all the CO&#x2082; put there by humanity since 1750. And yet, as James Hansen, the head of NASA's Goddard Institute for Space Studies, observes, "the five-year mean global temperature has been flat for a decade."</p>

<p>Temperatures fluctuate over short periods, but this lack of new warming is a surprise. Ed Hawkins, of the University of Reading, in Britain, points out that surface temperatures since 2005 are already at the low end of the range of projections derived from 20 climate models. If they remain flat, they will fall outside the models' range within a few years.</p>

<p>The mismatch between rising greenhouse-gas emissions and not-rising temperatures is among the biggest puzzles in climate science just now. It does not mean global warming is a delusion. Flat though they are, temperatures in the first decade of the 21st century remain almost 1&deg;C above their level in the first decade of the 20th. But the puzzle does need explaining.</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/climate">climate</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/global warming">global warming</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/science">science</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Bees still dying at a fantastic rate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/bees-still-dying-at-a-fantastic-rate" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23394</id>

    <published>2013-04-01T19:54:25Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T19:54:25Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Despite progress in recent years on causes and cures, <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/29/science/earth/soaring-bee-deaths-in-2012-sound-alarm-on-malady.html?pagewanted=all">colony collapse disorder has wreaked havoc on honeybee colonies across the country</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>A mysterious malady that has been killing honeybees en masse for several years appears to have expanded drastically in the last year, commercial beekeepers say, wiping out 40 percent or even 50 percent of the hives needed to pollinate many of the nation's fruits and vegetables.</p></blockquote>

<p>Which is like, yeah, big whoop, it's just bees, right? Except that:</p>

<blockquote><p>The Agriculture Department says a quarter of the American diet, from apples to cherries to watermelons to onions, depends on pollination by honeybees.</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/bees">bees</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/biology">biology</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/colony collapse disorder">colony collapse disorder</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/food">food</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/science">science</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Sartorial zoo animals</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/sartorial-zoo-animals" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23392</id>

    <published>2013-04-01T17:40:13Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T17:40:13Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Yago Partal pictures <a href="http://www.zooportraits.com/">animals dressed up in their finest duds</a>. Some of these are better than others...this is one of my favorites:</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/yago-partal.jpg" width="600" height="600" border="0" alt="Yago Partal" /></p>

<p>Prints are available.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/art">art</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Yago Partal">Yago Partal</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Two 90-year-olds do the 100 meter dash</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/two-90-year-olds-do-the-100-meter-dash" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23389</id>

    <published>2013-04-01T15:46:24Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T15:46:24Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>If you need a little pick-me-up, try this video of two nonagenarians racing each other in the 100-meter dash. Seems like there's gonna be a clear winner from the start but...</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/QYLVd7plaV8?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Both men were born in 1918; if the video were filmed this year, that would make them 95. (via <a href="https://twitter.com/gavinpurcell">@gavinpurcell</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/sports">sports</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/track and field">track and field</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video">video</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Crouching government, hidden compartment</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/crouching-government-hidden-compartment" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23391</id>

    <published>2013-04-01T14:42:49Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T14:42:49Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Alfred Anaya was really good at putting secret compartments into cars and he thought he was in the clear if he didn't know what his customers were putting in these compartments. <a href="http://www.wired.com/threatlevel/2013/03/alfred-anaya/all/">He was wrong</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Alfred Anaya took pride in his generous service guarantee. Though his stereo installation business, Valley Custom Audio Fanatics, was just a one-man operation based out of his San Fernando, California, home, he offered all of his clients a lifetime warranty: If there was ever any problem with his handiwork, he would fix it for the cost of parts alone-no questions asked.</p>

<p>Anaya's customers typically took advantage of this deal when their fiendishly loud subwoofers blew out or their fiberglass speaker boxes developed hairline cracks. But in late January 2009, a man whom Anaya knew only as Esteban called for help with a more exotic product: a hidden compartment that Anaya had installed in his Ford F-150 pickup truck. Over the years, these secret stash spots-or traps, as they're known in automotive slang-have become a popular luxury item among the wealthy and shady alike. This particular compartment was located behind the truck's backseat, which Anaya had rigged with a set of hydraulic cylinders linked to the vehicle's electrical system. The only way to make the seat slide forward and reveal its secret was by pressing and holding four switches simultaneously: two for the power door locks and two for the windows.</p>

<p>Esteban said the seat was no longer responding to the switch combination and that no amount of jiggling could make it budge. He pleaded with Anaya to take a look.</p>

<p>Anaya was unsettled by this request, for he had suspicions about the nature of Esteban's work. There is nothing intrinsically illegal about building traps, which are commonly used to hide everything from pricey jewelry to legal handguns. But the activity runs afoul of California law if an installer knows for certain that his compartment will be used to transport drugs. The maximum penalty is three years in prison. Anaya thus thought it wise to deviate from his standard no-questions-asked policy before agreeing to honor his warranty. "There's nothing in there I shouldn't know about, is there?" he asked. Esteban assured him that he needn't worry.</p></blockquote>

<p>Read all the way to the end for author Brendan Koerner's conclusions about our government's position of the moral neutrality of technology.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Alfred Anaya">Alfred Anaya</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Brendan Koerner">Brendan Koerner</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/cars">cars</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/crime">crime</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/drugs">drugs</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>YouTube is the dominant force in music</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/04/youtube-is-the-dominant-force-in-music" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23390</id>

    <published>2013-04-01T13:51:02Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T13:51:02Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2013/03/how-memes-are-orchestrated-by-the-man/274466/">This is a nice article</a> about how memes are often made or promoted deliberately by financial interests and not because of a spontaneous popular uprising, but mostly I wanted to highlight this statement:</p>

<blockquote><p>Google's YouTube, not Apple's iTunes, is now the dominant force in music.</p></blockquote>

<p>I've been convinced for awhile now that YouTube and not Android or Google+ will be their main source of revenue if/when Google's search business wanes. (via <a href="http://twitter.com/claytoncubitt">@claytoncubitt</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Google">Google</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/music">music</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/YouTube">YouTube</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The 91-year-old cobbler</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/the-91-year-old-cobbler" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23388</id>

    <published>2013-03-29T20:33:15Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T20:33:15Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Dustin Cohen made a lovely little film about shoemaker Frank Catalfumo, who has been making and repairing shoes in Brooklyn since before World War II.</p>

<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/62731783?color=cc0025" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<blockquote><p>Frank Catalfumo is a 91 year old shoemaker and repairer in Bensonhurst, Brooklyn. He first opened the doors to F&amp;C Shoes in 1945 and continues to work five days a week alongside his son Michael. If you're ever in the area, make sure to stop by the shop and listen to one of Frank's amazing stories about life in Brooklyn back in the day.</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Dustin Cohen">Dustin Cohen</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Frank Catalfumo">Frank Catalfumo</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video">video</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>How climate change could affect coffee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/how-climate-change-could-affect-coffee" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23387</id>

    <published>2013-03-29T18:02:15Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T18:02:15Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Earlier in the week <a href="http://kottke.org/13/03/how-climate-change-is-affecting-wine">I posted about</a> how climate change is affecting wine. Turns out that <a href="http://www.usnews.com/news/articles/2013/03/27/buzzkill-how-climate-change-could-eventually-end-coffee">coffee is in trouble as well</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>But in recent years, keeping the world's coffee drinkers supplied has become increasingly difficult: The spread of a deadly fungus that has been linked to global warming and rising global temperatures in the tropical countries where coffee grows has researchers scrambling to create new varieties of coffee plants that can keep pace with these new threats without reducing quality.</p>

<p>While coffee researchers can do little to prevent climate change, they're hard at work to keep up as Earth braces for temperature increases of several degrees over the next several decades.</p>

<p>"Coffee is the canary in the coal mine for climate change," says Ric Rhinehart, executive director of the Specialty Coffee Association of America. "If you can't think about the long term risk for planetary impacts, think about the short term risk for your coffee. Know that a day without coffee is potentially around the corner."</p></blockquote>

<p>(via <a href="http://nextdraft.com/">nextdraft</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/coffee">coffee</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/food">food</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/global warming">global warming</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Man caught with 21 tons of stolen cheese</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/man-caught-with-21-tons-of-stolen-cheese" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23385</id>

    <published>2013-03-29T15:42:05Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T15:42:05Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Aaron Cohen</name>
        <uri>http://www.unlikelywords.com</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Veniamin Konstantinovich Balika recently used false paperwork to load his 18 wheeler with <a href="http://www.channel3000.com/news/Man-found-with-200K-worth-of-stolen-cheese-police-say/-/1648/19490212/-/f48cjw/-/index.html">42,000 pounds of Muenster cheese worth about $200K</a>. Balika's plan was to sell the cheese to retailers on the east coast. </p>

<blockquote><p>"There's a black market for everything," said Sissman. "We've seen everything stolen. We've found stolen beer, stolen food, stolen machine parts, but this is the first time, we've found stolen cheese.</p></blockquote>

<p>I wanted the opinion of an industry professional so I reached out to Aaron Foster, Head Buyer at <a href="http://www.murrayscheese.com/">Murray's Cheese Shop</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>I've seen a lot of people wondering how the culprit was planning to unload 40,000 lbs of cheese without raising suspicion. Is there such a thing as a cheddar fence? In my opinion, it really wouldn't be that hard. While the larger retailers and chains -- and, of course, Murray's -- have all become much more conscious of food safety and food security, there remains plenty of retailers who would jump at the chance to buy their product for pennies on the dollar, no questions asked. Literally as I wrote this, I received a vague email with the subject "RE: Special sale - Mega aged WI Cheddar". I'll pass, thanks. Groceries, specialty shops, and bodegas that work with perishables need every edge they can get to scrape by. Think about that next time you order your egg and cheese from the corner store.</p></blockquote>

<p>And then I couldn't help but find out more about stolen cheese. Cheese theft isn't actually that uncommon. In fact, <a href="http://gothamist.com/2011/10/19/cheese_the_most_stolen_food_on_the.php">cheese is the most stolen food item of all</a> with up to 4% of all cheese stolen at some point in it's journey from maker to mouth. A cursory Google search turned up <a href="http://www.clickondetroit.com/news/Men-Arrested-With-Trunk-Full-Of-Stolen-Cheese/-/1719418/1786254/-/12cjacdz/-/index.html">trunks full of stolen cheese in Michigan</a>, <a href="http://www.sott.net/article/210985-Naked-Man-Arrested-At-Library-With-Stolen-Cheese">52-year old naked library denizens arrested with knives and stolen cheese</a>, <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/1983/06/11/nyregion/the-city-3-seized-in-search-for-stolen-cheese.html">stolen government cheese in 1983</a>(!), <a href="http://iowacity.patch.com/articles/man-accused-of-stolen-spreading-cheese-dip-all-over-hy-vee-men-s-restroom-iowa-city-police-blotter-march-3">stolen cheese spread all over a Hy-Vee men's room</a>, <a href="http://www.kgw.com/news/Whole-cheese-wheels-stolen-from-Bend-Whole-Foods-123021633.html">video of brazen cheese wheel thieves</a>, "<a href="http://www.naturalnews.com/038919_Morningland_Dairy_government_raid_raw_milk.html#ixzz2Os5rFIc3">the crushing authoritarianism of the Crown of England</a>," <a href="http://www.brooklynpaper.com/stories/35/8/kc_cheesethief_2012_02_24_bk.html">a cheese thief in Brooklyn</a>, and <a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/news/4049490/TV-chef-Antony-Worrall-Thompson-sorry-over-cheese-theft-from-Tesco.html">a shoplifting celebrity chef</a>. (thx, drew)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Aaron Foster">Aaron Foster</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/cheese">cheese</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/crime">crime</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/food">food</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The former future of the year 2000</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/the-former-future-of-the-year-2000" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23386</id>

    <published>2013-03-29T14:46:43Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T14:46:43Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://medium.com/editors-picks/cbd6bdc6b283">David Bauer writes</a> about how the year 2000, which used to seem futuristic, seems very distant now.</p>

<blockquote><p>After a refreshing shower -- pretty much like you remember it from 2013 -- you make yourself comfortable at the breakfast table. You're an early adopter, so you have your laptop right there with you to check the news. While you wait for the computer to start up, you have time to brew some coffee.</p>

<p>Time to check Twitter for the latest...ah well, no Twitter yet. So let's see what your friends are up to over on Face...doesn't exist either. Not even MySpace. Heck, not even Friendster.</p>

<p>The upside is this: You're in for distraction-free news reading. You head over to Newsunlimited.com, the online version of The Guardian, then to The New York Times On The Web. You glance at the newspaper across the table, knowing it provides the better news fix.</p></blockquote>

<p>I turned 27 in 2000, lived in San Francisco, worked as a web designer, and had been using the web since 1994...and most of the people I knew were similar. We were a bunch of outliers, people with lots of knowledge about and access to technology and the internet. So a lot of what he writes doesn't ring true to me, especially the bit above, and extra especially the newspaper providing "the better news fix".</p>

<p>News sites worked just fine in 2000 and the growing network of weblogs worked even better...they were news and social networks all rolled up into one. Google Maps didn't exist, but Mapquest did. Wikipedia didn't exist, but you could still find information about Ghana through Google and Altavista. I owned <a href="http://www.epi-centre.com/reports/9711dcs.html">a digital camera</a> in 1998 and many people I knew had them in 2000. Napster (and the other P2P networks that sprung up around that time) was an amazing music discovery resource. Sharing relatively large files with friends a la Dropbox was possible because we all had our own web sites and FTPing something to your server so someone else could grab it was simple. Things went viral through weblogs and mailing lists. Travel was easy to book online; Expedia launched in 1996. You could shop for groceries online. You could get almost anything delivered same-day to your door with Kosmo.</p>

<p>So yeah, there were no iPods or wifi-enabled laptops or iPhones or Twitter, but if you were an early adopter who lived in a big US city and spent lots of time online, 2000 isn't as distant as it might seem for everyone else.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/David Bauer">David Bauer</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Tumblr of the day: What Ali Wore</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/tumblr-of-the-day-what-ali-wore" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23384</id>

    <published>2013-03-28T20:30:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T20:30:39Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Zoe Spawton often photographs a particularly well-dressed man who passes her cafe in Berlin each day. She's documenting the results at <a href="http://alioutfit.tumblr.com/">What Ali Wore</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/what-ali-wore.jpg" width="640" height="475" border="0" alt="What Ali Wore" /></p>

<p>Wonderful. Ali used to be a doctor but is now working as a tailor.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/fashion">fashion</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/photography">photography</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Zoe Spawton">Zoe Spawton</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>New details about Wes Anderson&apos;s new film</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/new-details-about-wes-andersons-new-film" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23383</id>

    <published>2013-03-28T19:01:21Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T19:01:21Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Anderson has finished filming his next movie, The Grand Budapest Hotel, with the likes of Tilda Swinton, Jude Law, Bill Murray, and Owen Wilson. <a href="http://www.screendaily.com/news/distribution/searchlight-takes-grand-budapest/5053392.article">Screen Daily</a> has some plot details:</p>

<blockquote><p>The Grand Budapest Hotel tells of a legendary concierge at a famous European hotel between the wars and his friendship with a young employee who becomes his trusted prot&eacute;g&eacute;. The story involves the theft and recovery of a priceless Renaissance painting, the battle for an enormous family fortune and the slow and then sudden upheavals that transformed Europe during the first half of the 20th century.</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/movies">movies</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/The Grand Budapest Hotel">The Grand Budapest Hotel</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Wes Anderson">Wes Anderson</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The quick rise of cigarette smoking</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/the-quick-rise-of-cigarette-smoking" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23381</id>

    <published>2013-03-28T17:26:14Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T17:26:14Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>I'm currently reading <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B003UYUP58/ref=nosim/0sil8">The Emperor of All Maladies: A Biography of Cancer</a> (which is excellent) and I'm up to the chapters on prevention, specifically the prevention of lung cancer through reduction of cigarette smoking. I had no idea cigarette smoking was so uncommon in the US as recently as 1870...but we caught up quickly.</p>

<blockquote><p>In 1870, the per capita consumption in America was less than one cigarette per year. A mere thirty years later, Americans were consuming 3.5 billion cigarettes and 6 billion cigars every year. By 1953, the average annual consumption of cigarettes had reached thirty-five hundred per person. On average, an adult American smoked ten cigarettes every day, an average Englishman twelve, and a Scotsman nearly twenty.</p></blockquote>

<p>For <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/worldviews/wp/2012/10/19/who-smokes-most-a-surprising-map-of-smoking-rates-by-country/">some context</a> on that 3500/yr per person number (and the unbelievable 7000/yr Scottish rate), the current rate in the US is around 1000/yr and the highest current rate in the world is in Serbia at almost 2900/yr per person.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/books">books</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/cancer">cancer</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/medicine">medicine</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/smoking">smoking</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/The Emperor of All Maladies">The Emperor of All Maladies</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>TurboTax makers lobbying for more complex tax laws</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/turbotax-makers-lobbying-for-more-complex-tax-laws" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23382</id>

    <published>2013-03-28T16:52:20Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T16:52:20Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>In some countries, filing taxes is a fast and simple process. But in the U.S., it only seems to get more complex and laborious. There are a lot of reasons we haven't reached simplicity. But <a href="http://www.propublica.org/article/how-the-maker-of-turbotax-fought-free-simple-tax-filing">as ProPublica points out</a>, "it doesn't help that it's been opposed for years by the company behind the most popular consumer tax software -- Intuit, maker of TurboTax."</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Intuit">Intuit</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/taxes">taxes</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The 25 least visited countries in the world</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/the-25-least-visited-countries-in-the-world" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23380</id>

    <published>2013-03-28T15:36:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T15:36:44Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.garfors.com/2013/01/the-25-least-visited-countries-in-world.html">A somewhat surprising list of the least visited countries in the world</a> in that North Korea is not even in the top 15. Somalia, with 500 annual tourists, is #2:</p>

<blockquote><p>Why so few?<br />
War, lack of a government for many years, violent muslim extremists, sharia law. The reputation of Somalia is extremelly close to rock bottom.</p>

<p>Why you may still want to visit<br />
The government has started to function again. Mogadishu is now relatively safe and businesses are thriving. Turkish Airlines has even opened a direct twice weekly route from Istanbul.</p>

<p>What else<br />
Go to the beach just outside Mogadishu or visit the Bakaara market where you can even buy your own semi-genuine Somalian passport. You may not want to use it anywhere, though. Your travel experience doesn't extend beyond the Bahamas, Paris or Gran Canaria, you say? First of all; Why are you reading this blog post? Secondly, do not go to Somalia!</p></blockquote>

<p>The author of the list, Gunnar Garfors, has visited 196 of the 198 countries in the world; he's hitting the last two in the next few months: Kiribati and Cape Verde. (via <a href="https://twitter.com/DavidGrann">@DavidGrann</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Gunnar Garfors">Gunnar Garfors</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/lists">lists</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/travel">travel</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Updates on previous entries for Mar 27, 2013*</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/updates-on-previous-entries-for-mar-27-2013" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23379</id>

    <published>2013-03-28T05:11:04Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T05:11:04Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://kottke.org/13/03/intricate-body-calligraphy">Intricate body calligraphy</a> <em class="dimsmaller">orig. from Mar 27, 2013</em></p>

<p class="smaller">* Q: Wha? A: These previously published entries have been updated with new information in the last 24 hours. <a href="http://www.kottke.org/tag/post%20updates">You can find past updates here</a>.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/post updates">post updates</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Transcript of Raiders of the Lost Ark brainstorming session</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/transcript-of-raiders-of-the-lost-ark-brainstorming-session" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23378</id>

    <published>2013-03-27T21:43:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T21:43:12Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Wow. In 1978, George Lucus gathered together Steven Spielberg and screenwriter Lawrence Kasdan to go over ideas for a film Lucas had wanted to make about a swashbuckling archeologist, i.e. Raiders of the Lost Ark. Their sessions were recorded and <a href="http://maddogmovies.com/almost/scripts/raidersstoryconference1978.pdf">there's a transcript available online</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Lucas - Now, several aspects that we've discussed before: The image of him which is the strongest image is the "Treasure Of Sierra Madre" outfit, which is the khaki pants, he's got the leather jacket, that sort of felt hat, and the pistol and holster with a World War One sort of flap over it. He's going into the jungle carrying his gun. The other thing we've added to him, which may be fun, is a bull whip. That's really his trade mark. That's really what he's good at. He has a pistol, and he's probably very good at that, but at the same time he happens to be very good with a bull whip. It's really more of a hobby than anything else. Maybe he came from Montana, someplace, and he... There are freaks who love bull whips. They just do it all the time. It's a device that hasn't been used in a long time.</p>

<p>Spielberg - You can knock somebody's belt off and the guys pants fall down.</p>

<p>Lucas - You can swing over things, you can...there are so many things you can do with it. I thought he carried it rolled up. It's like a Samurai sword. He carries it back there and you don't even notice it. That way it's not in the way or anything. It's just there whenever he wants it.</p>

<p>Spielberg - At some point in the movie he must use it to get a girl back who's walking out of the room. Wrap her up and she twirls as he pulls her back. She spins into his arms. You have to use it for more things than just saving himself.</p>

<p>Lucas - We'll have to work that part out. In a way it's important that it be a dangerous weapon. It looks sort of like a snake that's coiled up behind him, and any time it strikes it's a real threat.</p>

<p>Kasdan - Except there has to be that moment when he's alone with a can of beer and he just whips it to him.</p></blockquote>

<p>Patrick Radden Keefe at the New Yorker read through the whole thing and <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/culture/2013/03/spitballing-indy.html">has some highlights and general thoughts</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Over the intervening decades of enormous wealth and success, both Lucas and Spielberg have carefully tended their public images, so there is a voyeuristic thrill to seeing them converse in so unguarded a manner. As the screenwriters Craig Mazin and John August pointed out recently on the Scriptnotes podcast, one delight of reading the transcript is watching Spielberg throw out bad ideas, and then noting how Lucas gently shuts him down. Spielberg, who had sought to direct a Bond movie-and, astonishingly, been rejected-thought that their hero should be an avid gambler. Lucas replied that perhaps they shouldn't overload him with attributes. (Lucas himself had briefly entertained, then mercifully set aside, the notion that his archaeologist might also be a practitioner of kung fu.) There's a good reason we seldom get to spy on these conversations: really good spitballing, like improv comedy, requires a high degree of social disinhibition. So the writers' room, like a therapist's office, must remain inviolable.</p></blockquote>

<p>(via <a href="https://twitter.com/jcn">@jcn</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/George Lucas">George Lucas</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Indiana Jones">Indiana Jones</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Lawrence Kasdan">Lawrence Kasdan</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/movies">movies</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Raiders of the Lost Ark">Raiders of the Lost Ark</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Steven Spielberg">Steven Spielberg</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>How climate change is affecting wine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/how-climate-change-is-affecting-wine" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23377</id>

    <published>2013-03-27T19:53:48Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T19:53:48Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Food and beverages where <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terroir">terroir</a> is a big factor will be the first to be affected by climate change. <a href="http://news.discovery.com/earth/global-warming/climate-change-rewrites-world-wine-list-130326.htm">This is already happening in the world of wine</a>...wine production is happening in Denmark, French wines are changing flavors, and some places may become too hot to grow grapes at all.</p>

<blockquote><p>As new frontiers for grape growing open up, the viability of some traditional production areas is under threat from scorching temperatures and prolonged droughts.</p>

<p>And in between the two extremes, some long-established styles are being transformed. Some whites once renowned for being light and crisp are getting fatter and more floral while medium-bodied reds are morphing into heavyweight bruisers.</p></blockquote>

<p>(via <a href="https://twitter.com/CharlesCMann">@CharlesCMann</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/global warming">global warming</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/wine">wine</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Intricate body calligraphy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/intricate-body-calligraphy" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23376</id>

    <published>2013-03-27T17:33:28Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T17:33:28Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Israeli artist Ronit Bigal does <a href="http://www.saatchionline.com/ronitbigal">intricate calligraphy on the human body</a> and photographs the results.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/ronit-bigal.jpg" width="640" height="416" border="0" alt="Ronit Bigal" /></p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong> I read the page wrong...the calligraphy is printed on the photographs to follow the contour of the skin, not on the skin itself. Still cool. (thx, <a href="https://twitter.com/Lorp">@lorp</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/art">art</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/photography">photography</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Ronit Bigal">Ronit Bigal</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>How the internet worked in 1995</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/how-the-internet-worked-in-1995" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23375</id>

    <published>2013-03-27T15:03:47Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T15:03:47Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>This is an episode of Computer Chronicles from 1995 showing what you could do on the internet.</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="480" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XluovrUA6Bk?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>(via <a href="http://mentalfloss.com/article/49676/what-internet-looked-1995">mental floss</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video">video</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Beautiful horizon rainbow in Paris</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/beautiful-horizon-rainbow-in-paris" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23374</id>

    <published>2013-03-27T13:59:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T13:59:51Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Paris even does rainbows better than the rest of the world. This is <a href="http://ptrenard.skyrock.com/3149491670-Arc-Parisien.html">a photo of a horizon rainbow</a> taken over the Parisian skyline last week by Bertrand Kulik.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/paris-rainbow.jpg" width="640" height="447" border="0" alt="Paris Rainbow" /></p>

<p>What the heck is going on there? Astronomy Picture of the Day <a href="http://apod.nasa.gov/apod/ap130327.html">explains</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Why is this horizon so colorful? Because, opposite the Sun, it is raining. What is pictured above is actually just a common rainbow. It's uncommon appearance is caused by the Sun being unusually high in the sky during the rainbow's creation. Since every rainbow's center must be exactly opposite the Sun, a high Sun reflecting off of a distant rain will produce a low rainbow where only the very top is visible -- because the rest of the rainbow is below the horizon.</p></blockquote>

<p>(via <a href="https://twitter.com/DavidGrann">@DavidGrann</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Bertrand Kulik">Bertrand Kulik</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Paris">Paris</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/photography">photography</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>New weather site: Forecast</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/new-weather-site-forecast" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23373</id>

    <published>2013-03-26T19:36:34Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T19:36:34Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>From the team that brought you <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/dark-sky-weather-radar-hyperlocal/id517329357?mt=8&amp;partnerId=30&amp;siteID=ckdAAyOoBpI">Dark Sky</a>, an app that has saved (or at least kept dry) my bacon more times than I can count, comes <a href="http://forecast.io">Forecast</a>, a weather web site that incorporates several of the features that made Dark Sky great. From <a href="http://blog.forecast.io/post/46290267206/announcing-forecast">the announcement</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Rather than cram these things into Dark Sky, we decided to do something grander: create our own full-featured weather service from scratch, complete with 7-day forecasts that cover the whole world, beautiful weather visualizations, and a time machine for exploring the weather in the past and far future. You can access it from all of your devices, whether it be your laptop, iPhone, Android phone, or tablet.</p>

<p>On top of all that, we're providing this data to other developers, in the hopes that a truly independent weather community can thrive in the era of increasing corporate consolidation.</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/weather">weather</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Lovely simple chess set</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/lovely-simple-chess-set" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23372</id>

    <published>2013-03-26T18:13:29Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T18:13:29Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Pentagram's Daniel Weil <a href="http://www.designweek.co.uk/news/daniel-weil-redesigns-the-chess-set/3036205.article">has designed a new chess set</a> that is currently being used at the World Chess Championship Candidates Tournament in London. The set is beautifully iconic and simple.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/chess-weil.jpg" width="600" height="546" border="0" alt="Chess Weil" /></p>

<p>The set is <a href="http://www.sac-games.com/product.php?id_product=164">available for sale</a> for &pound;200 or <a href="http://www.sac-games.com/product.php?id_product=166">with the board</a> for &pound;300.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/chess">chess</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Daniel Weil">Daniel Weil</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/design">design</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Print your own gun</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/print-your-own-gun" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23371</id>

    <published>2013-03-26T15:26:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T15:26:12Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Vice made a 24-minute documentary film about Cody Wilson, who is designing a semi-automatic weapon that can be printed out on a 3-D printer. You just <a href="http://defcad.org/">download the plans</a>, print it out, and there you go.</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/DconsfGsXyA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>"Gun control is a fantasy" indeed.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/3D printing">3D printing</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Cody Wilson">Cody Wilson</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/guns">guns</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video">video</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>



</feed>
