<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>kottke.org</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/" />
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.kottke.org/main" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2009-08-11:05118</id>
    <updated></updated>
    <subtitle>Jason Kottke&apos;s weblog, home of fine hypertext products</subtitle>

    <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type 4.2</generator>

<entry>
    <title>Typographica&apos;s favorite typefaces of 2012</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/typographicas-favorite-typefaces-of-2012" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23351</id>

    <published>2013-03-22T18:28:57Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T18:28:57Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Stephen Coles of Typographica says that 2012 was "a strong year" for new typefaces. He asked dozens of designers and font makers to nominate their favorite 2012 typefaces and <a href="http://typographica.org/features/our-favorite-typefaces-of-2012/">here's what they had to say</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>The independent foundry has also cemented its place as the new foundation of the industry. Most of this year's selections are from very small shops, several of which are entirely new to the market. It's also significant that, in addition to offering their fonts through retailers like FontShop, MyFonts, and the newly revived Fonts.com, most of these indie foundries now sell directly to customers through their own sites. In some cases they have eschewed outside distribution altogether. The "majors" have not simply laid down, however. Monotype, Linotype, Font Bureau, FontFont, and H&amp;FJ are all represented in this year's list, each with releases that are remarkably characteristic of their respective brands.</p></blockquote>

<p>(via <a href="http://daringfireball.net/">df</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/best of">best of</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/best of 2012">best of 2012</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/lists">lists</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Stephen Coles">Stephen Coles</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/typography">typography</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Literally separated at birth</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/literally-separated-at-birth" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23358</id>

    <published>2013-03-22T15:46:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T15:46:58Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1746892989/twinsters">Twinsters</a> is a project on Kickstarter by a pair of women who look <em>very</em> similar, were both born in South Korea, both born on November 19, 1987, both adopted three months after birth, and have never met. They're raising funds to make a documentary about their first meeting and to test their DNA to see if they are twins.</p>

<blockquote><p>On February 21, 2013, Samantha, an American actor living in Los Angeles, received a message via Facebook that would drastically change her life. It was from Ana&iuml;s, a French fashion design student living in London. Ana&iuml;s' friends viewed a KevJumba YouTube video featuring Samantha. They were immediately blown away by the identical appearance of Samantha &amp; Ana&iuml;s. After a few light Google stalking sessions, Ana&iuml;s &amp; her friends discovered that both girls were born on November 19, 1987 &amp; adopted shortly after. Ana&iuml;s knew immediately that it was possible for Samantha to be her biological twin sister &amp; reached out to her through Twitter &amp; Facebook.</p></blockquote>

<p>(thx, bethany)</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>iKids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/ikids" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23359</id>

    <published>2013-03-22T13:32:25Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T13:32:25Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<blockquote><p>We have a rule of no screen time during the week ... On the weekends, they can play. I give them a limit of half an hour and then stop. Enough. It can be too addictive, too stimulating for the brain.</p></blockquote>

<p>That quote is from a parent who develops apps for kids. The Atlantic's Hanna Rosin went to a developer's conference and what she heard from the parents there might surprise you: <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2013/04/the-touch-screen-generation/309250/?single_page=true">The Touch-Screen Generation</a>.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/parenting">parenting</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Apple&apos;s halo car</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/apples-halo-car" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23357</id>

    <published>2013-03-22T02:30:41Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T02:30:41Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>I really enjoyed <a href="http://hypercritical.co/2013/03/08/the-case-for-a-true-mac-pro-successor">this piece</a> by John Siracusa about why Apple should continue to make a high-end personal computer (like the Mac Pro) even though it's not a big seller or hugely profitable. Basically, the Mac Pro is Apple's halo car:</p>

<blockquote><p>In the automobile industry, there's what's known as a "halo car." Though you may not know the term, you surely know a few examples. The Corvette is GM's halo car. Chrysler has the Viper.</p>

<p>The vast, vast majority of people who buy a Chrysler car get something other than a Viper. The same goes for GM buyers and the Corvette. These cars are expensive to develop and maintain. Due to the low sales volumes, most halo cars do not make money for car makers. When Chrysler was recovering from bankruptcy in 2010, it considered selling the Viper product line.</p></blockquote>

<p>But car companies continue to make halo cars in part because they are great cars, or at least have the potential to be great cars, and when a car company stops caring about making great cars, they lose their identity and credibility...with consumers, with employees, with investors, and with competitors. Halo cars are the difference between being a car company and being a company that sells cars.</p>

<p>Normally I'm not a big fan of advice like "do what big car companies do", but what Siracusa's piece demontrates is one of the things that's problematic about data: there are important things about business and success that you can't measure. And I would go so far as to say that these unmeasurables are the most important things, the stuff that makes or breaks a business or product or, hell, even a relationship, stuff that you just can't measure quantitatively, no matter how Big your Data is. (via <a href="http://daringfireball.net/">df</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Apple">Apple</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/business">business</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/cars">cars</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/John Siracusa">John Siracusa</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The music that inspired Daft Punk</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/the-music-that-inspired-daft-punk" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23339</id>

    <published>2013-03-21T20:23:48Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T20:23:48Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>For <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B000000WCV/ref=nosim/0sil8">Homework</a>, their 1997 debut album, Daft Punk drew on a large number of musical influences. Here's two wonderful hours of the music that influenced them.</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="http://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F81879682&show_artwork=true"></iframe></p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Daft Punk">Daft Punk</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/music">music</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>LEGO paper airplane folding machine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/lego-paper-airplane-folding-machine" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23356</id>

    <published>2013-03-21T16:19:04Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T16:19:04Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Aaron Cohen</name>
        <uri>http://www.unlikelywords.com</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>It does what it says on the tin.</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/TDiIOTjyHzU?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>My favorite part is how it shoots the airplane out at the end. "Be gone, good sir, I am quite done with you!" (thx, Alex)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Legos">Legos</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/robots">robots</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video">video</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The tea-bag effect of aged spirits</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/the-tea-bag-effect-of-aged-spirits" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23350</id>

    <published>2013-03-21T14:48:59Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T14:48:59Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Aaron Cohen</name>
        <uri>http://www.unlikelywords.com</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Because of <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/life/drink/2013/03/superaged_spirits_how_old_is_too_old_for_whiskey_gin_and_chartreuse.single.html">the tea-bag effect</a>, after a point, spirits don't necessarily get better the longer they age. Bottled liquors don't age positively at all which doesn't have anything to do with tea bags.</p>

<blockquote><p>What distinguishes these two approaches is what Pickerell refers to as "the tea-bag effect": The first time a tea bag (or barrel) is used, there's more flavor to draw out. Resting in brand-new barrels, bourbon needs less time to extract what Pickerell calls "wood goodies" -- it sucks vanilla and caramel flavors, as well as spice-like notes, out of the wood with ease. Many of those same bourbon barrels, once emptied, make their way to Scotland, where they are used to age Scotch whisky. At this point, most of the "wood goodies" have been depleted, so scotch often needs a longer aging time to suck out the remainders. Evaporation plays a role, too: In the dry climate favored by bourbon distillers, liquid evaporates more quickly, and the product becomes concentrated more quickly.</p></blockquote>

<p>Also, according to the article, the ideal age range for whisk(e)y is as follows:<br />
Rye whiskey: 9-11 years.<br />
Bourbon: 6-10 years.<br />
Scotch: 20 years.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/whiskey">whiskey</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Images of Iraq from the ten years since the invasion</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/images-of-iraq-from-the-ten-years-since-the-invasion" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23355</id>

    <published>2013-03-21T02:17:49Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T02:17:49Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/iraq-gun-flower.jpg" width="660" height="455" border="0" alt="Iraq Gun Flower" /></p>

<p>Maybe the most depressing part of this <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/infocus/2013/03/iraq-wars-10th-anniversary-the-invasion/100475/">three</a> <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/infocus/2013/03/iraq-wars-10th-anniversary-occupation-and-insurgency/100476/">part</a> <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/infocus/2013/03/iraq-wars-10th-anniversary-after-the-war/100477/">series</a> of photographs of Iraq from the past ten years is not the photos of all the horrible things people are capable of doing to each other, not the [God, I can't even think of the right set of rage-adjectives here] faces of Bush, Cheney, and Rumsfeld, but the fact that there is a part two to this series that starts in 2003, just after the fucking asinine MISSION ACCOMPLISHED banner.</p>

<p>But maybe it was all worth it? To see <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/infocus/2013/03/iraq-wars-10th-anniversary-after-the-war/100477/#img26">these happy faces</a> riding an amusement ride? Or <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/infocus/2013/03/iraq-wars-10th-anniversary-after-the-war/100477/#img30">these young people</a> able to express themselves? Was it the right thing done the wrong way for the wrong reasons? I dunno. I just don't know.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Iraq">Iraq</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/photography">photography</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/war">war</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Congressional gun control legislation is falling apart</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/congressional-gun-control-legislation-is-falling-apart" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23354</id>

    <published>2013-03-20T19:30:05Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T19:30:05Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Feeling totally depressed and sad and useless about this: <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/newsdesk/2013/03/the-nra-wins-again.html">the NRA wins again</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>After Sandy Hook, after twenty children were shot and killed at a place where they should have been safe from all harm, there was some optimism among supporters of gun control: perhaps now, finally, both Democrats and Republicans could see the light -- and the suffering-and revive the assault -- weapons ban. It was a futile hope.</p>

<p>Less than a week after Adam Lanza shot up an elementary school, it was already basically clear that an assault-weapons ban could not pass Congress-that it probably couldn't even get through the Democratic-controlled Senate, never mind the House. So it was hardly a surprise when, three months later, Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid announced that the ban would be removed from a larger gun-control package that is making its way through the upper chamber and given a separate vote that it will not survive. The scale of the defeat suffered by the ban's supporters, though, is shocking. This wasn't a close call; it was a body blow.</p></blockquote>

<p>I haven't forgotten Sandy Hook. We drive by there every time we go to Vermont. I think about those kids almost every day. Sometimes when I think about them, I close my eyes and see my 5-year-old son cowering in the corner of his classroom as a black-clad figure toting a machine gun bears down on him. And then the tears come. I can't stand that this is what America is; that we trade our children's lives for the opportunity to purchase items specifically invented for killing. I can't stand it. It's pathetic and embarrassing and barbaric.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/guns">guns</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/legal">legal</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/politics">politics</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Mind over mountain: the all-terrain human being</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/mind-over-mountain-the-all-terrain-human-being" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23353</id>

    <published>2013-03-20T17:31:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T17:31:51Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/24/magazine/creating-the-all-terrain-human.html?pagewanted=all">Kilian Jornet Burgada might be the world's best and most dominating athlete</a>. Or at least he derserves to be <a href="http://kottke.org/11/08/two-for-tennis">in the conversation</a>. Jornet competes in a number of sports but his two main ones are endurance running and ski mountaineering.</p>

<blockquote><p>His versatility amazes other runners, including Jurek, who today is a friend. Jornet has been able to run the very short mountain races like a vertical kilometer race that's over in a couple of hours, Jurek says -- and then, he adds, Jornet can turn around and win the Western States 100-Mile Endurance Run in California's Sierra mountains, arguably the world's most prestigious ultrarun. (Jurek himself won the Western States seven consecutive times between 1999 and 2005.) It's a little like an Olympic-champion sprinter winning the Boston Marathon.</p></blockquote>

<p>How is Jornet able to do these things? In part because of his upbringing in the mountains:</p>

<blockquote><p>Even among top athletes, Jornet is an outlier. Take his VO2 max, a measure of a person's ability to consume oxygen and a factor in determining aerobic endurance. An average male's VO2 max is 45 to 55 ml/kg/min. A college-level 10,000-meter runner's max is typically 60 to 70. Jornet's VO2 max is 89.5 -- one of the highest recorded, according to Daniel Brotons Cuixart, a sports specialist at the University of Barcelona who tested Jornet last fall. Jornet simply has more men in the engine room, shoveling coal. "I've not seen any athletes higher than the low 80s, and we've tested some elite athletes," says Edward Coyle, director of the Human Performance Laboratory at the University of Texas at Austin, who has studied the limits of human exercise performance for three decades.</p></blockquote>

<p>He also seems at one with nature and the mountains more than most people:</p>

<blockquote><p>Observers and competitors describe him as someone who draws endurance and vitality, Samson-like, from being among high peaks. Runners who have served as pacesetters for him have told me with amazement how, when he was midrace at Lake Tahoe, Jornet didn't run with his head down in focused misery but instead brushed the hairgrass and corn lily that grew along the trail with his fingertips and brought the smell to his nose, as if he were feeding off the scenery. Sometimes in his all-day solitary runs, stopping only to eat berries, he can seem half-feral, more mountain goat than human. He likes to move fast and touch rock and feel wild, he told me; he feels most at ease and performs best when wrapped by the silence and beauty of the mountains. He can't abide cities for more than a few hours. The sea -- its unrelenting horizontality -- scares him. Leading long races like Western States, he's been known to stop and exclaim at a sunrise, or wait for friends to catch up so he can enjoy the mountains with them instead of furthering his lead. "It's almost insulting," Krupicka told me. But it's just Kilian being Kilian, Krupicka said. "He's not rubbing it in anyone's face. He's truly enjoying being out there in the mountains, and he's expressing that."</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Kilian Jornet Burgada">Kilian Jornet Burgada</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/sports">sports</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Ridiculous Fishing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/ridiculous-fishing" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23352</id>

    <published>2013-03-20T16:33:52Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T16:33:52Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>The new iOS gaming hotness is <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=ckdAAyOoBpI&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https%253A%252F%252Fitunes.apple.com%252Fus%252Fapp%252Fridiculous-fishing-tale-redemption%252Fid601831815%253Fmt%253D8%2526uo%253D4%2526partnerId%253D30">Ridiculous Fishing</a>. In it, you try to get your hook as deep as you can, then catch as many fish as you can on the way up, and finally shoot as many of the fish as you can with a gun. There are also chainsaws and an in-game Twitter clone called Byrdr. This game is ten times more charming than that Arnold on Green Acres and fun as hell. Highly recommended. If you need an extra nudge, here's the trailer:</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="480" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/vzKcJ8QFbMk?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/iPad games">iPad games</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Ridiculous Fishing">Ridiculous Fishing</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video games">video games</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Hexagonal rocks</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/hexagonal-rocks" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23344</id>

    <published>2013-03-20T15:44:47Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T15:44:47Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>This is an Icelandic waterfall called <a href="http://photography.nationalgeographic.com/photography/photo-of-the-day/litlanesfoss-waterfall-iceland/">Litlanesfoss</a> and the naturally occurring rock formation is <a href="http://volcano.oregonstate.edu/education/facts/col_joint.html">columnar jointed basalt</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/litlanesfoss.jpg" width="640" height="640" border="0" alt="Litlanesfoss" /></p>

<blockquote><p>The columns form due to stress as the lava cools. The lava contracts as it cools, forming cracks. Once the crack develops it continues to grow. The growth is perpendicular to the surface of the flow. Entablature is probably the result of cooling caused by fresh lava being covered by water. The flood basalts probably damned rivers. When the rivers returned the water seeped down the cracks in the cooling lava and caused rapid cooling from the surface downward. The division of colonnade and entablature is the result of slow cooling from the base upward and rapid cooling from the top downward.</p></blockquote>

<p>One of the coolest things I have ever seen. Looks totally fake, like they built it for Fractal Falls in Polygon Gorge at Disneyland or something. Giants Causeway in Northern Ireland <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=Giants+Causeway&amp;hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;source=lnms&amp;tbm=isch&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=k65HUfDVCYyY8gTev4HYDQ&amp;ved=0CAoQ_AUoAQ&amp;biw=1133&amp;bih=730">looks amazing</a> as well. Check out <a href="http://www.theworldgeography.com/2013/01/basalt-formations.html">several similar formations</a> from around the world.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/geology">geology</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Empathy and vulnerability</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/empathy-and-vulnerability" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23346</id>

    <published>2013-03-20T14:03:53Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T14:03:53Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://the-pastry-box-project.net/sara-wachter-boettcher/2013-march-2013/">Sara Wachter-Boettcher on the relationship between vulnerability and empathy</a>, especially when it comes to making things for other people to use.</p>

<blockquote><p>[Empathy] means being open -- truly open -- to feeling emotions we may not want to feel. It means allowing another's experiences to gut us. It means ceding control.</p>

<p>Empathy begins with vulnerability. And being vulnerable, especially in our work, is fucking terrifying.</p></blockquote>

<p>(via <a href="https://twitter.com/beep">@beep</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Sara Wachter-Boettcher">Sara Wachter-Boettcher</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Big break in the Gardner Museum Heist</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/big-break-in-the-gardner-museum-heist" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23349</id>

    <published>2013-03-20T01:05:50Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T01:05:50Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Aaron Cohen</name>
        <uri>http://www.unlikelywords.com</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, <a href="http://www.boston.com/metrodesk/2013/03/18/thieves-identified-gardner-museum-theft-rembrandt-and-vermeer-paintings/VmSiOGRgKbRakLJr1wCA3I/story.html">the FBI announced major advances in solving the biggest art heist in history</a>. The break in occurred at the Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum in 1990 <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isabella_Stewart_Gardner_Museum#Art_theft_of_1990">when a night watchman opened the door to men dressed as police</a>. Works by Vermeer, Rembrandt, Degas, and Manet valued at over $500M were taken and have not been seen since. </p>

<blockquote><p>"The FBI believes with a high degree of confidence in the years after the theft the art was transported to Connecticut and the Philadelphia region and some of the art was taken to Philadelphia where it was offered for sale by those responsible for the theft. With that confidence, we have identified the thieves, who are members of a criminal organization with a base in the mid-Atlantic states and New England," Richard DesLauriers, special agent in charge of the Boston office of the FBI, said.</p></blockquote>

<p>The guard who opened the door, Richard Abath, <a href="http://bostonglobe.com/metro/2013/03/10/guard-who-opened-door-robbers-notorious-gardner-museum-heist-under-suspicion-years-later/1TUiDyi1GbcnBgQT64oISP/story.html">was looked at pretty closely again last week</a>, though he's not mentioned specifically this week.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/art">art</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Boston">Boston</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/crime">crime</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The Image Toaster</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/the-image-toaster" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23345</id>

    <published>2013-03-20T00:22:50Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T00:22:50Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>There's <a href="http://www.evilmadscientist.com/2007/finally-cnc-toast/">prior art</a>, but <a href="http://cargocollective.com/scottvh/The-Image-Toaster">this image toaster</a> is still pretty cool.</p>

<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/57392144?color=1db4c2" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Toastagram? Toastr? I foresee <a href="http://berglondon.com/">BERG</a> putting out a smaller version of this, perhaps printing out the day's news on a small-crumb cocktail bread; they'll call it Little Toaster. (via <a href="http://slyoyster.com/cheap-thrills/2013/eat-the-morning-news-on-your-toast/">sly oyster</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/food">food</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video">video</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Hands On a Hardbody available again</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/hands-on-a-hardbody-available-again" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23336</id>

    <published>2013-03-19T19:59:22Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T19:59:22Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Hands On a Hardbody, a 1997 documentary about contestants vying to win a brand-new pickup truck, is <a href="http://handsonahardbodythemovie.com/">now available in digital format for $10</a> (remastered and DRM-free, no less).</p>

<blockquote><p>In S.R. Bindler's 1997 cult classic, Hands On a Hardbody, two dozen small-town Texans compete for a brand-new "Hardbody" pickup truck at a local car dealership. The event is a contest of endurance and sleep-deprivation -- whoever can remain standing the longest with one hand on the truck will get to drive it home. Capturing several days of lunacy, laughter, struggle and heartbreak, Hands On a Hardbody is more than a documentary about winning a truck. It is a remarkable study of competition, camaraderie, faith and determination-the ultimate human drama.</p></blockquote>

<p>For an extra $5, you get 90 minutes of bonus material. The film has been unavailable in any format for years. I still have an original DVD in my squirreled-away DVD collection...it's one of my favorite documentaries. (via <a href="https://twitter.com/gavinpurcell">@gavinpurcell</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Hands On a Hardbody">Hands On a Hardbody</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/movies">movies</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Advertising from the Mad Men era</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/advertising-from-the-mad-men-era" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23337</id>

    <published>2013-03-19T17:41:13Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T17:41:13Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>If the advertising parts of Mad Men are your favorite bits of the show, might I recommend <a href="http://www.taschen.com/pages/en/catalogue/popculture/all/04461/facts.mid_century_ads.htm">Taschen's two-volume Mid-Century Ads</a> (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/3836528347/ref=nosim/0sil8">on Amazon</a>).</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/vw-think-small.jpg" width="640" height="813" border="0" alt="VW Think Small" /></p>

<p>It's a beautiful set of books, tons of ads from the 50s and 60s presented in large format.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/advertising">advertising</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/books">books</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Mad Men">Mad Men</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Mid-Century Ads">Mid-Century Ads</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/TV">TV</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Unbelievable scooter tricks</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/unbelievable-scooter-tricks" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23343</id>

    <published>2013-03-19T15:14:31Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T15:14:31Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>If it's got wheels, extreme sports enthusiasts will do tricks on it. The push scooter your five-year-old rides at the playground is no exception:</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/K6jEzM-I6FA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>If they ever to a Back to the Future reboot, they know who to call for the downtown Hill Valley chase scene. (via <a href="https://twitter.com/DavidSimkins1">@DavidSimkins1</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video">video</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Stupidity captured at 2500 frames/sec</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/stupidity-captured-at-2500-framessec" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23348</id>

    <published>2013-03-19T02:22:25Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T02:22:25Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>A Danish TV show called Dumt &amp; Farligt (which translates as Stupid &amp; Dangerous) films all sorts of crazy things at 2500 frames/sec with a super HD camera. You may have seen <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lUZ-e2SkeMI">the first video</a> from last April...here's a follow-up that just came out:</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ntZPeosma2c?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>The highlights for me were the bottle of red wine in the microwave and the rocket-powered drying rack from the first video and the bottle of Diet Coke shot with a bullet and gas leak in a camper. The Diet Coke scene is almost cinematic, the way the bottle's clothes are blown off and "arms" flap around as the bottle spins, wobbles, and finally falls to the ground. (via <a href="http://digg.com">digg</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/slow motion">slow motion</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video">video</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Simplicity is...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/simplicity-is" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23347</id>

    <published>2013-03-19T01:56:32Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T01:56:32Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>There are a zillion definitions of simplicity. <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/culture/2013/03/christoph-niemann-petting-zoo-app.html">Here is Christoph Niemann's</a>, which he applied in building his new iOS app, <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=ckdAAyOoBpI&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=https%253A%252F%252Fitunes.apple.com%252Fus%252Fapp%252Fpetting-zoo-by-christoph-niemann%252Fid602773895%253Fmt%253D8%2526uo%253D4%2526partnerId%253D30">Petting Zoo</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Simplicity is not about making something without ornament, but rather about making something very complex, then slicing elements away, until you reveal the very essence.</p></blockquote>

<p>(via <a href="https://twitter.com/djacobs">@djacobs</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Christoph Niemann">Christoph Niemann</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/design">design</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/iPad apps">iPad apps</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Upstream Color at IFC</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/upstream-color-at-ifc" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23338</id>

    <published>2013-03-18T17:56:32Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T17:56:32Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Starting on April 4, <a href="http://www.ifccenter.com/films/upstream-color/">Upstream Color begins its run at IFC</a> in New York. Star/director Shane Carruth will be in attendance for post-screening Q&amp;As for several of the shows.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/movies">movies</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/NYC">NYC</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Shane Carruth">Shane Carruth</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Upstream Color">Upstream Color</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Early McDonald&apos;s menus</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/early-mcdonalds-menus" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23335</id>

    <published>2013-03-18T15:59:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T15:59:51Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>McDonald's started out as <a href="http://blogs.loc.gov/inside_adams/2010/05/mcdonald%E2%80%99s-bar-b-que/">McDonald's Bar-B-Q</a> in San Bernardino, CA in 1940. Here's a copy of the menu from that time:</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/original-mcdonalds-menu-00.jpg" width="600" height="448" border="0" alt="original McDonald's menu" /></p>

<p>The drive-in BBQ restaurant was a great success:</p>

<blockquote><p>The restaurant had carhops serving guests and would often see 125 cars crowding the lot on weekends.  They quickly saw their annual sales topping $200,000 on a regular basis.</p></blockquote>

<p>But competitors opened similar restaurants and they were selling more hamburgers than barbequed ham so the McDonald brothers closed their place for three months to retool. They reopened as plain old McDonald's, serving cheap fare (like hamburgers) quickly. This is what <a href="http://www.retronaut.com/2012/07/the-first-mcdonalds-1948/">an early version of the menu</a> looked like:</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/original-mcdonalds-menu-01.jpg" width="640" height="449" border="0" alt="original McDonald's menu" /></p>

<p>The original McDonald's served potato chips and pie, which were swapped out for french fries and milkshakes after the first year; that photo must have been taken sometime after the switch. Ray Kroc got involved in 1955 and opened the first McDonald's franchise east of the Mississippi in Des Plaines, Illinois:</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/krocs-first-mcdonalds.jpg" width="640" height="862" border="0" alt="Kroc's first Mcdonalds" /></p>

<p>The version of the menu currently going around (on <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/1adx96/original_mcdonalds_menu/">Reddit</a>; I found it <a href="https://twitter.com/iA/status/312815490999390208">here</a>) looks like it's from the Kroc era, the arches having been introduced in 1953, shortly before he got involved:</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/original-mcdonalds-menu-02.jpg" width="583" height="833" border="0" alt="original McDonald's menu" /></p>

<p>It's interesting to compare these early McDonald's menus to the current menus of places like <a href="http://www.in-n-out.com/">In-N-Out Burger</a> and <a href="http://www.fiveguys.com/">Five Guys</a>, especially in comparison with <a href="http://www.mcdonalds.com/us/en/full_menu_explorer.html">the sprawling McDonald's menu of today</a>:</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/in-n-out-menu.jpg" width="640" height="386" border="0" alt="In N Out Menu" /></p>

<p>After reading all these menus, you're probably getting hungry. So <a href="http://www.epicconstructions.com/mirror/mcd/">here's how to make a hamburger that tastes like an original McDonald's hamburger from 1948</a> (as well as recipes for a bunch of other McDonald's menu items, from McNuggets to the McRib to the dipping sauces). Enjoy!</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/food">food</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/McDonald's">McDonald's</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/restaurants">restaurants</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The Bolshoi Ballet acid attack</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/the-bolshoi-ballet-acid-attack" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23341</id>

    <published>2013-03-18T13:58:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T13:58:44Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Writing for the New Yorker, <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2013/03/18/130318fa_fact_remnick?currentPage=all">David Remnick covers the Bolshoi acid attack and the larger ills that afflict the historic ballet company</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>At around eleven, Filin, feeling tired and eager to see his wife, steered the Mercedes into a parking lot outside his building and headed for his door. The snow was icy and thick. Filin was reaching for the security buzzer when he heard someone behind him call out his name. Then the voice said, "Tebye privet!" -- literally, "Hello to you!," but more abrupt and menacing, as though someone were relaying an ominous greeting from a third party.</p>

<p>Filin turned and saw a man in front of him. He was neither tall nor short. He wore a woolly hat and a scarf wrapped around his face. His right arm was crooked behind him, as if he were concealing something.</p>

<p>A gun, Filin thought, in that flash of confrontation: He's holding a gun and I am dead. Bolt! But, before he could move, his attacker swung his arm out in front of him. In his hand was a glass jar filled with liquid, and he hurled its contents at Filin's face. A security camera in the parking lot fixed the time at 23:07.</p>

<p>The liquid was sulfuric acid -- the "oil of vitriol," as medieval alchemists called it. Depending on the concentration, it can lay waste to human skin as quickly as in a horror movie. Scientists working with sulfuric acid wear protective goggles; even a small amount in the eyes can destroy the cornea and cause permanent blindness.</p>

<p>Filin was in agony. The burning was immediate and severe. His vision turned to black. He could feel the scalding of his face and scalp, the pain intensifying all the time.</p></blockquote>

<p>Always good to read Remnick on Russia...he was The Washington Post's Moscow correspondent for a few years in the late 1980s.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/ballet">ballet</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Bolshoi Ballet">Bolshoi Ballet</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/crime">crime</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/David Remnick">David Remnick</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Russia">Russia</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>RIP Google Reader</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/rip-google-reader" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23342</id>

    <published>2013-03-18T12:49:14Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T12:49:14Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>You may have heard by now that <a href="http://googlereader.blogspot.com/2013/03/powering-down-google-reader.html">Google is shutting down Google Reader</a>, their RSS reading service. It'll be gone by July 4. Fortunately you can export your subscriptions and use another service...here are some suggestions from <a href="http://a.wholelottanothing.org/2013/03/thoughts-surrounding-google-readers-demise.html">Matt Haughey</a> and <a href="http://gizmodo.com/5990540/8-google-reader-alternatives-that-will-ease-your-rss-pain">Gizmodo</a>. Or you can wait for <a href="http://blog.digg.com/post/45355701332/were-building-a-reader">Digg's reader</a>.</p>

<p>If you want to forego RSS readers altogether but still want to keep up with kottke.org without having to visit the site regularly, try following kottke.org on <a href="https://twitter.com/kottke">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/kottke.org">Facebook</a>, or <a href="http://bonus.kottke.org/">Tumblr</a>.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Google">Google</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Google Reader">Google Reader</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/kottke.org">kottke.org</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/RSS">RSS</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Nixon sabotaged Vietnam peace talks</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/nixon-sabotaged-vietnam-peace-talks" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23340</id>

    <published>2013-03-17T03:14:06Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T03:14:06Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>In 1968, Richard Nixon, then a candidate for President, <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-21768668">used backchannel negotiations to scuttle peace talks that may have ended the Vietnam War</a>. Nixon was afraid an end to the war meant an end to his campaign.</p>

<blockquote><p>By the time of the election in November 1968, LBJ had evidence Nixon had sabotaged the Vietnam war peace talks -- or, as he put it, that Nixon was guilty of treason and had "blood on his hands".</p></blockquote>

<p>The war went on for seven more bloody years, most of them under Nixon's watch. Shameful.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Lyndon Johnson">Lyndon Johnson</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/politics">politics</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Richard Nixon">Richard Nixon</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Vietnam War">Vietnam War</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/war">war</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Wingsuit flying in Rio de Janeiro</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/wingsuit-flying-in-rio-de-janeiro" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23334</id>

    <published>2013-03-17T00:09:31Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T00:09:31Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Watch as Ludovic Woerth &amp; Jokke Sommer fly through a hole in a building in central Rio de Janeiro that looks not much more than 15 feet wide. Jesus.</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/GFmvMHPQ1k8?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>And speaking of Jesus, another pair of wingsuiters <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7g5Vnhj3rIY">flew under the arms of the Christ the Redeemer statue in Rio</a> a few years ago. (via <a href="https://twitter.com/rands">@rands</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Rio de Janeiro">Rio de Janeiro</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/sports">sports</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video">video</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Using compressed air as green energy storage</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/using-compressed-air-as-green-energy-storage" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23104</id>

    <published>2013-03-15T20:46:42Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T20:46:42Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://lightsailenergy.com/">LightSail Energy</a>, headed up by 25-year-old Danielle Fong, is <a href="http://www2.technologyreview.com/tr35/profile.aspx?trid=1302">developing technology to store energy as compressed air</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>A stumbling block to increasing our reliance on electricity from cleaner energy sources such as solar panels and wind farms has always been figuring out how to efficiently store the energy for use when the wind isn't blowing and the sun isn't shining. Danielle Fong could make clean energy significantly more practical on a large scale by introducing a novel way to use tanks of compressed air for energy storage. "It could radically reorient the economics of renewable energy," she says.</p>

<p>The idea of using compressed air to store energy is not new. Electricity from solar panels or wind turbines can turn a motor that's used to compress the air in a large tank, and the air pressure can then be converted into power to drive a generator when the power is needed. The problem is that during compression the air reaches temperatures of almost 1,000 ^0C. That means energy is lost in the form of heat, and storage in conventional steel vessels becomes impractical.</p>

<p>Fong stumbled on a possible solution while skimming through a nearly century-old book: water spray is great at cooling air.  She asked, why not spray water into the air while compressing it, so that the air stays cool? To make the process practical, she developed a technique for separating the heated water from the compressed air and diverting the water into a tank, so the heat can be recaptured to minimize energy loss. The process is about as efficient as the best batteries: for every 10 kilowatt-hours of electricity that goes into the system, seven kilowatt-hours can be used when needed.</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Danielle_Fong">Fong</a> sounds like an impressive person; she dropped out of middle school at 12 to attend college, graduating five years later with degrees in physics and computer science.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Danielle Fong">Danielle Fong</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/energy">energy</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/LightSail Energy">LightSail Energy</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Glitch art blankets and textiles</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/glitch-art-blankets-and-textiles" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23092</id>

    <published>2013-03-15T18:18:53Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T18:18:53Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Artist Phillip Stearns makes <a href="http://phillipstearns.wordpress.com/machine-knit-glitch-blankets/">blankets</a> and <a href="http://phillipstearns.wordpress.com/jacquard-woven-glitch-tapestries/">tapestries</a> out of glitch art. Some of the source images are taken from intentionally short-circuited digital cameras.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/glitch-blanket.jpg" width="640" height="427" border="0" alt="Glitch Blanket" /></p>

<p>All items are woven in the US and cost $200 and up (plus shipping).</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/art">art</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/fashion">fashion</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Phillip Stearns">Phillip Stearns</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Fact-checking at The New Yorker</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/fact-checking-at-the-new-yorker" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23097</id>

    <published>2013-03-15T15:40:26Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T15:40:26Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Excerpted from a book called <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B008Z1Q5K0/ref=nosim/0sil8">The Art of Making Magazines</a>, <a href="http://www.cjr.org/critical_eye/fact-checking_at_the_new_yorker.php?page=all">a piece on how fact-checking works at the New Yorker</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>So that was the old New Yorker. The biggest difference between David Remnick's New Yorker today and the Shawn New Yorker is timeliness. During the Shawn years, book reviews ran months, even years out of sync with publication dates. Writers wrote about major issues without any concern for news pegs or what was going on in the outside world. That was the way people thought, and it was really the way the whole editorial staff was tuned.</p>

<p>All this changed when Tina Brown arrived. Whereas before, editorial schedules were predictable for weeks or a month in advance, under Tina we began getting 8,000-, 10,000-, 12,000-word pieces in on a Thursday that were to close the following Wednesday. But something else changed in a way that is more important. Prior to Tina, the magazine really had been writer-driven, and I think this is why they gave the writers so much liberty. They wanted the writers to develop their own, often eccentric, interests.</p>

<p>Under Tina, writing concepts began to originate in editors' meetings, and assignments were given out to writers who were essentially told what to write. And a lot of what the editors wanted was designed to be timely and of the moment and tended to change from day to day. So the result was that we were working on pieces that were really much more controversial and much less well-formulated than anything we had dealt with previously, and often we would put teams of checkers to work on these pieces and checking and editing could go on all night.</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/books">books</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/journalism">journalism</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/The Art of Making Magazines">The Art of Making Magazines</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/The New Yorker">The New Yorker</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>1995-style opening title sequences for contemporary dramas</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/1995-style-opening-title-sequences-for-contemporary-dramas" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23333</id>

    <published>2013-03-15T13:55:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T13:55:58Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>A nascent trend on YouTube is to take contemporary dramas and imagine what their 1995-style opening credits sequences might look like. The first one appears to be <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9C6tE4Mblks">this Walking Dead one</a>, followed by Breaking Bad, which is the best of the bunch:</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="480" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZFjsOZDjnJA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>The Game of Thrones one is pretty great as well:</p>

<p><iframe width="640" height="480" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/2fPgIIB67bw?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>These seem to be a variation on the recut trailers meme, e.g. <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KmkVWuP_sO0">The Shining as a romantic comedy</a> or <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BuNF7Z7sAt8">Toy Story as a horror film</a>. (via <a href="https://twitter.com/aaroncoleman0">@aaroncoleman0</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Breaking Bad">Breaking Bad</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Game of Thrones">Game of Thrones</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/remix">remix</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/TV">TV</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/video">video</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Saving &quot;You Bet Your Life&quot;</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/saving-you-bet-your-life" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23332</id>

    <published>2013-03-15T03:39:56Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T03:39:56Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Andy Marx <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/03/12/the-day-my-grandfather-groucho.html">shares the story</a> of how a lunch with his grandfather, Groucho, and a few of his grandfather's guests ended up helping save every episode of the seminal 50s TV show You Bet Your Life.</p>

<blockquote><p>No longer out of the limelight, my grandfather was enjoying his status as a cultural icon now that such classic Marx Brothers films as "Duck Soup" and "A Night at the Opera" had been discovered by a whole new generation eager for something to go with the free-wheeling attitudes and politics of the late '60s and early '70s. Groucho and his brothers fit the bill perfectly and my grandfather was more than happy to oblige his new-found fans, many of them Hollywood celebrities. Among my favorite celebrity sightings at my grandfather's house in those days were Alice Cooper and Rolling Stones guitarist Ronnie Wood.</p>

<p>This particular day, my grandfather asked me to be ready to accompany him on the piano, since he planned to sing for the invited guests: Jack Nicholson, Elliot Gould and the great French mime, Marcel Marceau. As I said, you never knew who would arrive for lunch with Groucho.</p></blockquote>

<p>(also via <a href="http://daringfireball.net/">df</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Andy Marx">Andy Marx</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Groucho Marx">Groucho Marx</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/TV">TV</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/You Bet Your Life">You Bet Your Life</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Kids from around the world photographed with their favorite things</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/kids-from-around-the-world-photographed-with-their-favorite-things" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23331</id>

    <published>2013-03-15T02:33:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T02:33:00Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Gabriele Galimberti takes photos of <a href="http://www.gabrielegalimberti.com/projects/toys-2/">kids with their most prized possessions</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/gabriele-galimberti-toys.jpg" width="640" height="640" border="0" alt="Gabriele Galimberti Toys" /></p>

<blockquote><p>But how they play can reveal a lot. "The richest children were more possessive. At the beginning, they wouldn't want me to touch their toys, and I would need more time before they would let me play with them," says the Italian, who would often join in with a child's games before arranging the toys and taking the photograph. "In poor countries, it was much easier. Even if they only had two or three toys, they didn't really care. In Africa, the kids would mostly play with their friends outside."</p></blockquote>

<p>This reminds me of <a href="http://www.time.com/time/photogallery/0,29307,1626519,00.html">Peter Menzel's photos</a> of what families from different parts of the world eat in a typical week. (via <a href="http://daringfireball.net/">df</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Gabriele Galimberti">Gabriele Galimberti</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/photography">photography</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The lost tribes of the Amazon</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/the-lost-tribes-of-the-amazon" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23300</id>

    <published>2013-03-14T14:33:05Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T14:33:05Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>From Joshua Hammer at Smithsonian magazine, <a href="http://www.smithsonianmag.com/ideas-innovations/The-Lost-Tribes-of-the-Amazon-192124351.html?c=y&amp;story=fullstory">an update on the so-called "uncontacted" tribes of people living deep in the Amazon rain forest</a> and what's being done to help them stay isolated.</p>

<blockquote><p>After two hours, we docked at a pier at the Maloca Bar&uacute;, a traditional longhouse belonging to the 30,000-strong Ticuna tribe, whose acculturation into the modern world has been fraught with difficulties. A dozen tourists sat on benches, while three elderly Indian women in traditional costume put on a desultory dance. "You have to sell yourself, make an exhibition of yourself. It's not good," Matapi muttered. Ticuna vendors beckoned us to tables covered with necklaces and other trinkets. In the 1960s, Colombia began luring the Ticuna from the jungle with schools and health clinics thrown up along the Amazon. But the population proved too large to sustain its subsistence agriculture-based economy, and "it was inevitable that they turned to tourism," Franco said.</p>

<p>Not all Ticunas have embraced this way of life. In the nearby riverside settlement of Nazareth, the Ticuna voted in 2011 to ban tourism. Leaders cited the garbage left behind, the indignity of having cameras shoved in their faces, the prying questions of outsiders into the most secret aspects of Indian culture and heritage, and the uneven distribution of profits. "What we earn here is very little," one Ticuna leader in Nazareth told the Agence France-Presse. "Tourists come here, they buy a few things, a few artisanal goods, and they go. It is the travel agencies that make the good money." Foreigners can visit Nazareth on an invitation-only basis; guards armed with sticks chase away everyone else.</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Joshua Hammer">Joshua Hammer</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The 2012 Feltron Annual Report</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/the-2012-feltron-annual-report" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23330</id>

    <published>2013-03-13T22:55:20Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-13T22:55:20Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Aside from 2005's installment, I have a copy of every Feltron Annual Report ever produced and I am <a href="http://feltron.com/ar12_01.html">eagerly awaiting the 2012 version</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/feltron-2012.jpg" width="640" height="800" border="0" alt="Feltron 2012" /></p>

<p>Order yours <a href="http://feltron.bigcartel.com/product/feltron-2012-report">here</a>.</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Nicholas Felton">Nicholas Felton</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Lifelike baby dolls and the people who love them</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/lifelike-baby-dolls-and-the-people-who-love-them" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23322</id>

    <published>2013-03-13T21:53:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-13T21:53:51Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Photographer <a href="http://www.rebeccamartinez.com/">Rebecca Martinez</a> photographs <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reborn_doll">reborn dolls</a> and the people who collect/care for them.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/reborn-babies.jpg" width="640" height="427" border="0" alt="Reborn babies" /></p>

<blockquote><p>Babies create strong emotions for the bearer, holder, and observer. I have discovered this holds true even when it is known the baby is not real.</p>

<p>I am photographing dolls that are created to look and feel like living babies. They are constructed and weighted to feel like infants, which includes a head that must be supported while in one's arms. They are the most powerful objects I have ever worked with, I am struck by the strong and palpable emotional reactions they produce. They provoke the dominant biological instinct to nurture and the entire spectrum of human behavior.</p></blockquote>

<p>Some of the collectors care for their reborn dolls <a href="http://www.fastcodesign.com/1671923/eerie-photos-of-a-subculture-devoted-to-life-like-baby-dolls">as if they were their own children</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Many of the women involved have an especially strong passion for the stage of mothering babies and this is a method to keep this stage permanently in their lives. There is a wide range of personal stories and motivations for being involved in this community. Some create or collect these dolls because they cannot continue to give birth to living babies, or have lost a child, or cannot have one of their own. Some women admire the art form and are doll collectors, others create nurseries in their homes and integrate the babies as part of their families and lives.</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://lens.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/02/19/motherhood-reborn-and-everlasting">Sometimes literally</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Sometimes, women who have lost a newborn have commissioned artists to make a reborn doll that looks exactly like their deceased baby. Modeled after photographs of the real infant, these dolls are called portrait babies.</p></blockquote>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/reborn-babies-2.jpg" width="640" height="427" border="0" alt="Reborn babies" /></p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/parenting">parenting</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/photography">photography</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Rebecca Martinez">Rebecca Martinez</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>An atlas of world maps by illustrators and storytellers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/an-atlas-of-world-maps-by-illustrators-and-storytellers" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23319</id>

    <published>2013-03-13T19:47:43Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-13T19:47:43Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>This looks beautiful: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/3899554698/ref=nosim/0sil8">A Map of the World</a> is a collection of maps by illustrators and storytellers. I've featured at least a few of the maps in the book here on kottke.org. Here's a sample:</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/map-of-the-world-book.jpg" width="640" height="431" border="0" alt="Map Of The World Book" /></p>

<p>You can see more of the maps in the book <a href="http://usshop.gestalten.com/shopwindow/a-map-of-the-world.html">on the publisher's web site</a>. (via <a href="http://instagram.com/p/WnXp2aQ9Ld/">raul</a>, who says "This book is insanely beautiful. Buy it if you love maps. It will make you happy.")</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/A Map of the World">A Map of the World</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/books">books</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/maps">maps</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>How well did Galileo observe Jupiter&apos;s moons?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/how-well-did-galileo-observe-jupiters-moons" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23323</id>

    <published>2013-03-13T17:41:30Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-13T17:41:30Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>In the pages of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sidereus_Nuncius">Sidereus Nuncius</a>, Galileo described the four large moons of Jupiter in a series of 64 sketches which looked a lot like ASCII art in the text:</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/sidereus-nuncius.jpg" width="640" height="648" border="0" alt="Sidereus Nuncius" /></p>

<p>Using an online tool for computing the positions of Jupiter's moons, <a href="http://home.comcast.net/~erniew/astro/sidnunj.html">Ernie Wright compared Galileo's sketches to the moons' actual motions</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/galileo-moons-compare.jpg" width="640" height="142" border="0" alt="Galileo moons" /></p>

<p>Click through for an animated GIF of all the comparisons. Not bad for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_the_telescope#The_first_known_telescopes">the telescopic state of the art in 1610</a>. For a taste of how celestial objects actually appeared when viewed through Galileo's telescope, check out <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nzXnnwxJmSg">this video</a> starting around 7:30. (thx, john)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/astronomy">astronomy</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/books">books</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Galileo">Galileo</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/science">science</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Sidereus Nuncius">Sidereus Nuncius</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/space">space</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Professional deep water divers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/professional-deep-water-divers" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23301</id>

    <published>2013-03-13T14:58:20Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-13T14:58:20Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nybooks.com/articles/archives/2013/feb/07/diving-deep-danger/?pagination=false">A fascinating piece by Nathaniel Rich about deep water diving</a>. I had no idea that people building marine oil wells live for weeks at a time at depths of 1000 feet.</p>

<blockquote><p>Not everybody is cut out for the job. A diver cannot be claustrophobic or antisocial, because he must spend much of his time in a tiny sealed capsule with several other divers. He must be well-disciplined and perceptive, for he is likely to encounter a variety of unexpected hazards on the job. Many divers are military veterans, or have worked as roofers or mechanics. "The best are those who have a great deal of confidence in themselves and their abilities," one former diver, Phil Newsum, told me. "You have to be willing to adapt to any situation. Philosophically, when you go out on a dive job, you're expecting something is going to go wrong."</p>

<p>Often, because of the depth, the job is performed in the dark, with only a headlamp to light the way. Divers have told me stories of sudden encounters with manta rays, bull sharks, and wolf eels, which can grow eight feet long and have baleful, recessed eyes, a shovel-shaped snout, and a wide, snaggletoothed mouth. One diver sent me a video, filmed from a camera in the diver's helmet, of an enormous turtle that was playing a game of trying to bite off the diver's feet and hands every few minutes. The diver finally sent the animal swimming away by pressing a power drill to its head. Someone else sent me a photograph of a diver riding a speckled whale shark, as if on a rodeo bronco.</p>

<p>Newsum, who is now the director of an industry group called the Association of Diving Contractors International (ADCI), estimates that only three of every fifteen people who graduate from commercial diving school are able to withstand the rigor of the profession for a full career. Many are enticed by the high salaries, but few can endure the job's physical and psychological toll. Those who stick it out tend to do so out of a passion for the job's eccentricities.</p>

<p>The life of a commercial diver is somewhat less stable than that of a traveling salesman or mercenary soldier. He does not make his own schedule and has little control over his own fate, which is one reason why divers between jobs have a reputation for, as Newsum puts it, "living hard." The diver never knows when his next job will come, but as soon as he gets called for an assignment, he must head directly to the nearest port or helicopter pad. A successful diver will work offshore about 160 days a year, cumulatively. A job might last a day, or two months. Work is most consistent, at least in the Gulf of Mexico, in the warmer months, from late March through November, but hurricane season falls within that period. Hurricanes are a mixed blessing-they disrupt ongoing jobs, but they create new ones.</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Nathaniel Rich">Nathaniel Rich</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/oil">oil</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Where to sit?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/where-to-sit" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23320</id>

    <published>2013-03-12T22:12:25Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-12T22:12:25Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Alex Cornell has constructed <a href="http://blog.alexcornell.com/musical-chairs-choosing-the-right-seat">a handy infographic</a> to help you decide where to sit at a restaurant or dinner party table.</p>

<blockquote><p>7 Person Rectangle: It's very easy to get screwed in this scenario. While it may appear like you can sit anywhere except the ends, this is not so. You are at risk of sitting next to the lonely end-seat, which requires you to speak soley to that person for the duration of the meal.</p></blockquote>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Alex Cornell">Alex Cornell</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/how to">how to</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Escaping the waves</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://kottke.org/13/03/escaping-the-waves" />
    <id>tag:kottke.org,2013://5.23317</id>

    <published>2013-03-12T20:07:47Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-12T20:07:47Z</updated>

    <author>
        <name>Jason Kottke</name>
        <uri>http://www.kottke.org</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://kottke.org/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Mark Tipple <a href="http://www.marktipple.com/summer2012">takes underwater photos of people swimming under crashing waves</a>, which happens to be my favorite genre of surfing photography.</p>

<p><img src="http://also.kottke.org/misc/images/mark-tipple.jpg" width="640" height="427" border="0" alt="Mark Tipple" /></p>

<p>Prints <a href="http://www.marktipple.com/purchase">are available</a>. (via <a href="https://twitter.com/DavidGrann">@DavidGrann</a>)</p>]]><![CDATA[ <strong>Tags:</strong> <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/Mark Tipple">Mark Tipple</a>&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://kottke.org/tag/photography">photography</a>]]>
    </content>
</entry>



</feed>
