<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Rudy Jahchan</title>
    <link>http://rudyjahchan.com/</link>
    
    <description>
      
    </description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 12:42:53 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 12:42:53 -0800</lastBuildDate>

    
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/rudyjahchan" /><feedburner:info uri="rudyjahchan" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><item>
      <title>Bonsai-ing my Social Trees</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/B40gmKAHfPo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2013/01/10/bonsaing-my-social-tree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my &lt;a href='http://rudyjahchan.com/2013/01/01/hello-new-year/'&gt;New Year&amp;#8217;s resolutions&lt;/a&gt; was to &amp;#8220;bonsai&amp;#8221; my social tree. This goes beyond cutting swathes of people, friends, fans, or what-have-yous from my social networks, which is why I didn&amp;#8217;t call this post &amp;#8220;Pruning my Social Trees&amp;#8221;. For while I do agree with the &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunbar&amp;apos;s_number'&gt;Dunbar Number&lt;/a&gt;, the needs of a content creator requires us to find a balance between staying connecting with initimates and being able to reach an audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why bother to do this at all, though? To belabor the &amp;#8220;tree&amp;#8221; metaphor, without proper maintenance your social tree will wither. My own situation demonstrates this. In the madgrab of &amp;#8220;building an audience&amp;#8221; I&amp;#8217;ve added too many branches to the point that I no longer see the roots of the whole thing. Automatic reposting has resulted in the same item being listed multiple times on the same network. And more importantly I am doing a terrible job of feeding content into the tree, whether creating my own or sharing from my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided to take action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I am going do a better job of creating more content, whether its code, stories, or posts. More importantly, I will more actively support the works of my friends and peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I decided the &amp;#8220;role&amp;#8221; each network plays; what content I expect to see and post there and how it interacts with other networks. Decisions were also made on who to follow and cuts made without any malicious intent; I am not adverse to anyone requesting to join my network, just as long as they do so on the right one. For my part, when I have no expectations when I make a request and don&amp;#8217;t campaign for a connection; I expect most peope are the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some networks are &amp;#8220;roots&amp;#8221;, the primary point for each piece of work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://path.com'&gt;Path&lt;/a&gt; is going to be my &lt;em&gt;private&lt;/em&gt; life. I&amp;#8217;m only &lt;em&gt;try&lt;/em&gt; to follow my closest friends and family there, and am honored when they let me. In exchange, I will never campaign about my projects here except to celebrate or vent any related emotions. It will never repost to another network.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://instagram.com/rudyjahchan'&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, despite the privacy and rights brou-ha-ha a few weeks ago, is still my main real-time, in-the-moment chronicle of my &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; life and the behind the scenes of whatever I am working on. It will post to most of the other networks, and I&amp;#8217;ll be following mainly people I know whose adventures I find entertaining.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://github.com/rudyjahchan'&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='https://gist.github.com/rudyjahchan'&gt;Gist&lt;/a&gt; is where my code monkey activities resides, with anything notable being highlighed as a post on the &lt;a href='http://blog.carbonfive.com'&gt;Carbon Emmiter&lt;/a&gt;. I will be promoting these on other networks as well.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Like Charlie Brown trying to kick that damn football, I keep trying to get into shape, and I&amp;#8217;ve found the best network to track that has been &lt;a href='http://nikeplus.nike.com/plus/profile/rudyjahchan/'&gt;Nike+&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s been set to automatically post achievements to other networks.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;And of course, there is this &lt;a href='http://rudyjahchan.com/blog/'&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://timeywimey.tv'&gt;Timey Wimey TV&lt;/a&gt; and my other creative works that you can specifically follow if you are interested, though you can expect to see them mentioned alot elsewhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The roots feed into &amp;#8220;trunks&amp;#8221;, the popular mainstays we are all familar with. I expect to see people sharing here, campaigning for their own works, and generally making a spectacle of their lives; I know I will!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.linkedin.com/in/rudyjahchan/'&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; is promoted to my preferred &amp;#8220;networking&amp;#8221; network. If we&amp;#8217;ve chatted at a meetup or you want to pitch a project to me, this is how to reach me. I will respond, I promise. It may not be affirmative to going forward at this time, but I &lt;em&gt;WILL&lt;/em&gt; respond.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://twitter.com/rudy'&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; is probably my favorite network, and could be a &amp;#8220;root&amp;#8221; in its own right as I post statuses and observations there. I follow people who continually delight and entertain me as real friends or thought leaders. It&amp;#8217;s the zeitgeist of my world.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://facebook.com/rudyjahchan'&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; will see the most change as I move a lot of people into subscribers and track friends and families there from all walks of life. My posts will be public, however, open to commentary though messaging is reserved for people I actually know and have met.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others networks I consider &amp;#8220;leafs&amp;#8221;, usually an endpoint of themselves that can occassionaly give back to the whole tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://pinterest.com/rudyjahchan/'&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; has surprised even me in how much I use it. It&amp;#8217;s my moodboard that I mostly do for myself, and where I snapshot things I want to keep long term to reference and inspire me. I&amp;#8217;ve been posting back to other networks as well, but trust me when I say I try to be judicious of when I do so.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/coderonin/'&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt; came roaring back this year at an opportune time and I played around with the iOS app for a week as an Instagram replacement. And while it was very shiny, its lack of automatic updating keeps it as an archive of my photos, though I will be interacting more there in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there are the &amp;#8220;buds&amp;#8221;, networks I am still trying to decide what I am doing with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://plus.google.com/102403331307606219198/posts'&gt;Google Plus&lt;/a&gt; shows a lot of promise, and I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to form circles around areas of interest. It may take the role of a Facebook equivalent with more public interaction but I want to get into the habit of regularly posting there first.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To be honest, &lt;a href='http://rudy.tumblr.com/'&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; is something I am still trying to &amp;#8220;get&amp;#8221;. There is clearly a language of memes that is used to communicate there that I need to learn.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Hearing that all the kids are hopping on &lt;span&gt;snapchat&lt;/span&gt;, this old man hopped on to figure out a way to use it &amp;#8230; and is waiting for someone he knows to show up!&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;And I&amp;#8217;ve also been making a daily post to &lt;a href='http://www.chee.rs/'&gt;Chee.rs&lt;/a&gt;, a place to share appreciation of people, places and things some friends of mine have launched.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, as this is about &amp;#8220;social&amp;#8221; platforms, you play a part in this process. I encourage you to connect to me on the networks you prefer and, more importantly, &lt;em&gt;disconnect&lt;/em&gt; from those where it will be redundent or irrelevant, even if that means all of them. No ill will be taken or given as it is all about building real healthy relationships. And this process should de done continually, as like a living tree, our networks are continually growing and changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what are your thoughts on this matter? I would love to hear them below, or on any of the networks listed above!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2013/01/10/bonsaing-my-social-tree/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, New Year!</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/Uq2i2DRVrSs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2013/01/01/hello-new-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year, all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year was a good one for our household. I won the &lt;a href='http://youtu.be/NxvOVZvsrA0?t=58m'&gt;IAWTV Awards for Non-Fiction Writing&lt;/a&gt;. Made a short film - &lt;a href='https://www.facebook.com/DNEDoNotErase'&gt;D.N.E&lt;/a&gt; - which won best sci-fi short at &lt;a href='http://dailydragon.dragoncon.org/contests-awards/film-festival-award-winners/'&gt;Dragon*Con&lt;/a&gt;. Was granted a green card, sponsored by my wonderful workplace &lt;a href='http://carbonfive.com'&gt;Carbon Five&lt;/a&gt;. And best of all, I &lt;a href='http://youtu.be/-m2Yt1DcJi0'&gt;proposed&lt;/a&gt; and got &lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/caseymckinnon/sets/72157632044476389/'&gt;married&lt;/a&gt; to the love of my life &lt;a href='http://caseymckinnon.com'&gt;Casey McKinnon&lt;/a&gt;. Not too shabby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what to do this year? Well, let&amp;#8217;s start some resolutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write a Novel&lt;/strong&gt; There is a tale that has been brewing in me for a couple of year&amp;#8217;s now, that in my more innocent years (2010?) I thought could be a web series. But with the inspiration of my friend &lt;a href='http://lizlet.tumblr.com/'&gt;Liz Shannon Miller&lt;/a&gt; publishing her own &lt;a href='http://liztellsfrank.com/book/'&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;, Casey putting out &lt;a href='http://santaisanatheist.caseymckinnon.com/'&gt;Santa is an Atheist&lt;/a&gt;, I am going to get it down and publish it.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publish an App&lt;/strong&gt; I am actually already working on a couple of things with the genius known as &lt;a href='http://barrettgarese.com'&gt;Barrett Garese&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run a Marathon&lt;/strong&gt; I love running, when I do. It&amp;#8217;s just a matter of finding time. And with a year of experimentation, the best time seems to be early in the morning, on the way to work. It&amp;#8217;s not the best for getting some sun, but it is the best for getting it done.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn to Fight&lt;/strong&gt; Tied with running is learning new skills. And this year it&amp;#8217;s going to be fighting. I&amp;#8217;m going to stop wasting a Krav Maga membership. And I&amp;#8217;m going to learn to sword-fight, if only to be better prepared for &lt;a href='http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/260688528/clang'&gt;CLANG!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribute Code&lt;/strong&gt; As passionately as I love writing, I love coding, and I am lucky enough to get paid for it. And yet I&amp;#8217;ve been very shy about showing my code. Mostly because I KNOW it&amp;#8217;s not the best. But I am beginning to believe it&amp;#8217;s good enough. So I&amp;#8217;ll be maintaining a couple of repos as well as helping making pull requests on &lt;a href='http://github.com/rudyjahchan'&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonsai my Social Network&lt;/strong&gt; Finally, I count among the blessings I have in my life the many, many friends I have made and all the ways I can reach out to them. But I have to do a better job of maintaining that tree, not only in ensuring it brings good things to me, but more importantnly that it brings good things to my friends. Tomorrow, I am setting some ground rules for myself to make that happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it. Six &amp;#8220;simple&amp;#8221; resolutions to abide by. What are yours?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2013/01/01/hello-new-year/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Wedding Favors</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/jE8s9ch8yHQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2012/12/04/writing-wedding-favors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much of the magic of our &lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/caseymckinnon/sets/72157632044476389/'&gt;wedding&lt;/a&gt; was due to the massive pre-preparation of my brilliant and beautiful bride &lt;a href='http://caseymckinnon.com'&gt;Casey McKinnon&lt;/a&gt;; I just stayed out of the way and lent a hand when asked. One of the many great ideas she had was to have &lt;a href='http://www.jonessoda.com/custom-labels'&gt;Jones Soda with custom labels&lt;/a&gt; as our wedding favors. It would be something different and hence memorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We selected our flavors and found three pictures we felt represented the depth and range of our relationship. Then came the fun bit for me, the resident family writer: coming up with the label text. On normal Jones bottles the label speaks of the quality ingredients that go into the soda and blah blah blah whatever. I just relished the challenge of coming up with fun little tales about the photo in 300 characters!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for those who were unable to attend, here are the photos we used, the labels I came up with, and the backstory behind each of them. Hope you enjoy them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='sugar_cane_cola'&gt;Sugar Cane Cola&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://s3.amazonaws.com/rudyjahchan/mexican-cola.jpeg' alt='Sugar Cane Cola' /&gt; Photo by &lt;a href='http://jpd.me/' title='Jason DeFillippo'&gt;Jason DeFillippo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;div class='hero-unit'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a battle for the ages. Mexico's two greatest superheroes - El Luchadore and The Killer Bee - fought for days on end with a passion. A passion which turned to love for each other ... and the refreshing taste of pure cane cola with no high-fructose corn syrup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above photo was taken at the wedding-reception/Halloween-party of our friends &lt;a href='http://seanbonner.com'&gt;Sean Bonner&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://taratigerbrown.com/'&gt;Tara &amp;#8220;Tiger&amp;#8221; Brown&lt;/a&gt;. Casey and I went with a &amp;#8220;Mexican&amp;#8221; theme; I was a luchadore and she was a &amp;#8220;Killer Bee&amp;#8221; from the &lt;a href='http://www.hulu.com/watch/1476'&gt;classic Saturday Night Live sketch&lt;/a&gt;. We actually have this photo framed in our home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='root_beer'&gt;Root Beer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://s3.amazonaws.com/rudyjahchan/root-beer.jpeg' alt='Root Beer' /&gt; &lt;div class='hero-unit well-small'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the lovely couple. Don't they look wonderful? She's so pretty. And he ... well, he's there. But behind those smiles lies a dirty secret. They were already married. Terrible, right? Leaves a bad taste in your mouth. Which can be washed away with the medicinal sweetness of root beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s true! Before our big wedding ceremony we actually had a quickie earlier that year, mere weeks after &lt;a href='http://youtu.be/-m2Yt1DcJi0'&gt;I proposed&lt;/a&gt;. We kept it quiet so as not to remove any &amp;#8220;specialness&amp;#8221; of the day we were sharing with our family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='berry_lemonade'&gt;Berry Lemonade&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://s3.amazonaws.com/rudyjahchan/berry-lemonade.jpeg' alt='Berry Lemonade' /&gt; Photo by &lt;a href='http://www.burmeisterphotography.com/' title='Mark Burmeister'&gt;Mark Burmeister&lt;/a&gt; &lt;div class='hero-unit'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not an "engagement photo" on this bottle. It's from our honeymoon. 
Our future selves accelerated it to 88mph and &lt;em&gt;*BLAM*&lt;/em&gt; its back from our future.
Except we don't know where we're going; they cropped the photo too tight and blurred the background.
Jerks. At least berry lemonade is tasty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This photo actually was from our engagement photos &amp;#8230; but though it was technically BEFORE our wedding it was taken AFTER our first marriage ceremony as mentioned above! The &amp;#8220;timey-wimey&amp;#8221; nature of all this (a subject &lt;a href='http://timeywimey.tv'&gt;very dear to my heart&lt;/a&gt;) and the bright, almost radioactive blue shade of the drink inspired the sci-fi tale in the label. Plus, hey, anyway to mention one of &lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0054OGQOQ/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0054OGQOQ&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=rudyjahchanco-20'&gt;the greatest movies ever made&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2012/12/04/writing-wedding-favors/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moved from Wordpress to Jekyll Part 2</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/6DXhgVZ_4ls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2012/11/24/moved-from-wordpress-to-jekyll-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well so much for &lt;a href='http://jekyllrb.com'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; encouraging me to &lt;a href='/2012/08/14/moved-from-wordpress-to-jekyll-part-1/'&gt;blog more&lt;/a&gt;! But it has been a busy year since I got my site redesign up. Namely, my short film &lt;a href='http://www.facebook.com/DNEDoNotErase'&gt;D.N.E.&lt;/a&gt; won &lt;a href='http://dailydragon.dragoncon.org/contests-awards/film-festival-award-winners/'&gt;BEST SCI-FI SHORT&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href='http://dragoncon.org/'&gt;Dragon*Con&lt;/a&gt;, I got my U.S. Permanent residency, and, oh yeah, &lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/caseymckinnon/sets/72157632044476389/'&gt;I got married&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But excuses aside! Let us delve into the technical details of my moving to Jekyll. Or if you want, &lt;a href='#tldr'&gt;skip ahead&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='migrating_my_old_posts'&gt;Migrating my old Posts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll&amp;#8217;s documentation provides &lt;a href='https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/blog-migrations'&gt;two ways to migrate posts from Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;. The first method was unfortunately a non-starter; the blog was being hosted on a shared server instance, which severely restricted my ability to install gems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I went with generating an export file, functionality available in any Wordpress install, and running the &amp;#8220;wordpressdotcom&amp;#8221; migrator. This worked for the most part &amp;#8230; Except for a bunch of bad character encodings in the posts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly line breaks, quotations, and other common characters were coming out all wrong. So wrong that Jekyll could not even start up properly! Using various &lt;a href='http://ubuntuforums.org/showthread.php?t=1486493'&gt;sed&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://hints.macworld.com/article.php?story=20001206164827794'&gt;PERL&lt;/a&gt; commands I managed to clean up most files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, as Google had already indexed my site, in order to ensure that search results did not lead to dead-links, I needed to maintain the paths of posts. This was done simply enough in the &lt;code&gt;config.yml&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src='https://gist.github.com/4142545.js?file=config.yml'&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;h2 id='stylishly_bootstrapping'&gt;Stylishly Bootstrapping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up was laying out the site both structurally and design-wise. After many years of playing the CSS reset, redefine, and tweaking game, I was getting frustrated with having to establish on all the basic styles of a site over and over again, none of which turned out particularly well; you just have to take a look at &lt;a href='http://galacticast.com'&gt;Galacticast&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; for proof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is why &lt;a href='http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/'&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; to developers like me. Yes, there have been many styling frameworks that provide grid layouts and other components. But Bootstrap goes beyond by establishing a decent, pleasant style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now keep in mind, I didn&amp;#8217;t avoid all the hard work. I still had to go through the &amp;#8220;tweak&amp;#8221; step, adding site specific styling behavior. Sometimes this was simply a matter of using the &amp;#8220;appropriate&amp;#8221; class to get the behavior I wanted, like declaring the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;section /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; containing the content of posts a &lt;code&gt;hero-unit&lt;/code&gt; to get the larger, readable font. Hackish I know, but it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But some behavior required a lot of labour. Particularly, while Bootstrap provides &lt;a href='http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/scaffolding.html#responsive'&gt;responsive functionality&lt;/a&gt;, I spent a lot of time recreating the transforming navigation bar I had seen on other sites. Still, I can definitively say this would have been much harder without Bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='responsive_video'&gt;Responsive Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another responsive effect I wanted was to scale video to fill the width of the main column across any device. As many of you know, video has been a big part of my web-life, so showcasing on any platform was very important. Luckily, better people than me have &lt;a href='http://webdesignerwall.com/tutorials/css-elastic-videos'&gt;already solved this problem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added the following to my site CSS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src='https://gist.github.com/4142545.js?file=responsive-video.css'&gt; &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then all I have to do for any video embed is ensure it&amp;#8217;s placed within a &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt; tag with a &lt;code&gt;video&lt;/code&gt; style class. Loverly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='flying_without_plugins_and_databases'&gt;Flying without Plugins and Databases&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big part of Wordpress&amp;#8217; appeal was the built-in commenting and the ability to extend functionality with plugins like &lt;a href='http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/jetpack/'&gt;Jetpack&lt;/a&gt;. The flat-files Jekyll generates can&amp;#8217;t actually DO anything on the server side; can&amp;#8217;t store anything, can&amp;#8217;t process form responses, etc. Commenting is easily provided with &lt;a href='http://disqus.com'&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href='http://developers.facebook.com/docs/reference/plugins/comments/'&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;; I chose the former as I didn&amp;#8217;t want to favor any particular social network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my contact form I went with &lt;a href='http://getsimpleform.com'&gt;Simpleform&lt;/a&gt; which delivers exactly what its name promises. You signup with the email you want form data to be sent to, and you will receive a token which you then pass back in the &lt;code&gt;action&lt;/code&gt; path you submit the form to. And that&amp;#8217;s it! Any fields you place in your HTML form are captured with no further configuration. For example, here is my form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src='https://gist.github.com/4142545.js?file=contact_form.html'&gt; &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for other functionality like sharing plugins, and auto-formatting? Well, the other benefit of moving to Jekyll hosted on &lt;a href='http://github.com'&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; was that alot of that stuff became difficult, if not impossible. Which made me realize that I really didn&amp;#8217;t need it in the first place. The goal, after all, was simplification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='feeding_the_feeds'&gt;Feeding the Feeds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, as feeds are not automatically provided by Jekyll, I had to generate my own. Plenty of examples exist in the repos of other Jekyll based sites, including the &lt;a href='https://github.com/mojombo/mojombo.github.com'&gt;original&lt;/a&gt;. Here is mine for RSS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src='https://gist.github.com/4142545.js?file=rss.xml'&gt; &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Atom:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src='https://gist.github.com/4142545.js?file=atom.xml'&gt; &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally the site map for search engines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src='https://gist.github.com/4142545.js?file=sitemap.xml'&gt; &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note in all cases the need to set &lt;code&gt;layout: nil&lt;/code&gt; in the YAML front-matter. Otherwise, it would be wrapping them in the default layout of the site, which would produce invalid XML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='next'&gt;Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well there you have it, some of the small tips and tricks I used in moving to Jekyll from my Wordpress install. What will I do next? I may try to re-introduce tags or categories to my posts. But in the meantime I am happy with what I have and look forward to get into the blogging groove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a name='tldr'&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h2 id='tldr'&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many options to &lt;a href='https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/blog-migrations'&gt;migrate Wordpress data&lt;/a&gt; but be prepared to fix the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/'&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; provides a great foundation for responsive site design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;a href='http://disqus.com'&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; for commenting and &lt;a href='http://getsimpleform.com'&gt;simpleform&lt;/a&gt; for contact forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember to generate your own feeds; sample templates can be found in multiple repos or &lt;a href='https://gist.github.com/4142545'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2012/11/24/moved-from-wordpress-to-jekyll-part-2/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moved from Wordpress to Jekyll Part 1</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/03Qx39OTKqY/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2012/08/14/moved-from-wordpress-to-jekyll-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my redesigned website!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many changes are abounding, not the least of which is that I have moved off of using a self-hosted &lt;a href='http://wordpress.org'&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; to having the site generated by &lt;a href='http://jekyllrb.com'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href='http://github.com'&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. It seems something of a tradition that the first post on a Jekyll based site after such a move is to cover the whys and whatfors, so here is my take on it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='whats_wrong_with_wordpress'&gt;What&amp;#8217;s Wrong with Wordpress?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing. Everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;
  Saladin,
  &lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000EHSVQ4/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000EHSVQ4&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=rudyjahchanco-20'&gt; Kingdom of Heaven: Director's Cut &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src='http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=rudyjahchanco-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B000EHSVQ4' border='0' height='1' alt='' width='1' style='border:none !important;
  margin:0px !important; width: 1px !important; height: 1px !important;' /&gt;, 2005
&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the nearly 8 years(!!!) I have been using &lt;a href='http://wordpress.org'&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;, it has grown in leaps and bounds from a simple blogging platform into a fully extensible CMS. It was/is my go-to platform for getting a site up for my creative projects and for my friends and &lt;a href='http://caseymckinnon.com'&gt;loved ones&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, personally, with that growth came a lot of headaches. Nearly every time I created a site I would be writing my own themes, plugins and &lt;a href='http://www.galacticast.com/2006/07/23/galacticast-secrets-multiple-video-formats-support-in-wordpress/'&gt;hacks&lt;/a&gt; to provide some extra desired bit of functionality. These would become a hassle to maintain with each new version of Wordpress, as functions I relied on would change. This problem also plagued plugins that I was using written by &lt;em&gt;others&lt;/em&gt; and so would trigger even more cycles of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the rub of it; &lt;em&gt;IT WAS ALL MY FAULT!!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given this great, flexible platform I went crazy, putting a lot of time into building a site with a lot of features that were meant to save time - automatic video player generation, RSS media enclosures, etc - only to spend a lot of more time keeping it working. Add to that ongoing issues with spam and security, warnings about resource usage, a distaste of PHP, and a growing need to go minimal in my life &amp;#8230; and suddenly blogging became an unpleasent, cluttered experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was time to move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='why_jekyll'&gt;Why Jekyll?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://jekyllrb.com'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; was first introduced to me by my &lt;a href='http://carbonfive.com'&gt;Carbon Five&lt;/a&gt; colleague &lt;a href='http://quietdynamite.com/'&gt;Rit Li&lt;/a&gt; when he heard me complaining about how long it took to simply save and preview a post&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;. Furthermore, I did not appreciate the cold, brusque responses my host gave when I reached out to them for help resolving these problems. Rit suggested switching to Jekyll and having my site &lt;a href='https://help.github.com/articles/user-organization-and-project-pages'&gt;hosted on Github for &lt;em&gt;FREE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. That piqued my interest and I read into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href='http://jekyllrb.com'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, you write your posts and pages as simple &lt;a href='http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/'&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; or HTML files, which are then transformed using templates in those same formats, a process you trigger from the command-line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no database; the final result is simply dumped to your filesystem for you to do whatever you wish whether browse it locally or upload to a server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no theme sytem; you use straight CSS with some logic control through &lt;a href='http://liquidmarkup.org/'&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt; tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plugins but that doesn&amp;#8217;t matter because &lt;a href='http://github.com'&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, where I planned to host the site, doesn&amp;#8217;t allow them anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In brief; it&amp;#8217;s simple, fast, and limited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is that a good thing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it addressed my fundamental problem; given a wealth of options I got distracted by using them. Here was a system restricted to very simple functionality that required little to no resources except the developer skills I was already familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sold. But there was a lot of work ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='do_as_i_say_not_as_i_do'&gt;Do As I Say, Not as I Do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to one last thought&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://jekyllrb.com'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is not for everyone and it doesn&amp;#8217;t answer every need. I wouldn&amp;#8217;t recommend it for anyone unfamiliar with &lt;a href='http://git-scm.com/'&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; and basic command-line usage. If my non-codemonkey friends ask me what should they run their own sites on, I quickly say &lt;a href='http://wordpress.org'&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; or, if they have a bit of money, &lt;a href='http://squarespace.com'&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for me and my issues, it fits the bill. The fact that this site and others have laid stagnant for a couple of years are a result of my laziness. But when I did build up the willpower and login, suddenly noticing a bunch of fixes and tweaks that needed attention did not help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://jekyllrb.com'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is easy to maintain and helps me focus on what it most important; &lt;em&gt;working my site&amp;#8217;s content instead of its infrastructure!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next post will cover some of the technical tips, tricks, and traps I learned moving my site into &lt;a href='http://jekyllrb.com'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I would love to hear your thoughts or questions; post them here, message me on &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/rudy'&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or feel free to send an email; I am sure you can guess the address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h5 id='footnotes'&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am aware of the various caching solutions available as plugins to Wordpress. But again, these plugins themselves require maintenance!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2012/08/14/moved-from-wordpress-to-jekyll-part-1/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bumps In the Night - An Exorcise in Futility</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/DWyFCYKH1Ag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2010/06/19/bumps-in-the-night-an-exorcise-in-futility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class='video'&gt;&lt;object height='386' width='700'&gt;&lt;param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/6OYaICXUi6Q?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /&gt;&lt;embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/6OYaICXUi6Q?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' height='386' width='700' /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over two months ago, I was whining to &lt;a href='http://www.jennipowell.com/'&gt;Jenni Powell&lt;/a&gt; how I didn&amp;#8217;t get to collaborate anymore. So did the logical thing? Told me to shut up and invited me to guest-direct an episode of the horror-comedy show she produces called &lt;a href='http://bumpsinthenight.tv'&gt;Bumps in the Night&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great opportunity for me, as I hadn&amp;#8217;t called the shots in over two years since we last produced &lt;a href='http://galacticast.com'&gt;Galacticast&lt;/a&gt;, and this would be only the second time I directed somebody else&amp;#8217;s material (the first was an amazing screenplay that &lt;a href='http://www.g14productions.com/'&gt;Matthew Balthrop&lt;/a&gt; wrote for us).&amp;#160;I learned (and re-learned) many things along the way, which will make for great future posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have so many people to thank for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jenni Powell for inviting me in (hope she doesn&amp;#8217;t regret it too much) * test&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The writers and stars of Bumps; Emmet Furey, John Reha, and Greg Benevent. You constantly surprised and amazed me with your delivery. We have to work together again sometime.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Our guest stars&amp;#160;&lt;a href='http://aprilbillingsley.com/' target='_blank'&gt;April Billingsley&lt;/a&gt; and&amp;#160;Daniel Weiss. Their patience and advice to this humble director was very much appreciated.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To editor Andrew Seeley; he was going to sit this one out as I rampaged through the editing, but came to our rescue when we needed him.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;And finally, to my love, &lt;a href='http://caseymckinnon.com/' target='_blank'&gt;Casey McKinnon&lt;/a&gt;, not only for her cameo appearance(s), but for tolerating many super late nights of her frustrated guy focused on his computer instead of cuddling with her. You&amp;#8217;re the best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2010/06/19/bumps-in-the-night-an-exorcise-in-futility/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Mediacracy Episode 13: The One About the IAWTV</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/EkoGgTdl9lA/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2010/05/14/new-mediacracy-13-the-one-about-the-iawtv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href='http://newmediacracy.com/2010/05/episode-13-the-one-about-the-iawtv.html#comments'&gt;&lt;img src='http://29.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l2df188eIy1qz56moo1_500.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to sit among the many brilliant minds at this session of New Mediacracy. Chris McCaleb and I talked about why we love doing these, and it like verbal jazz sessions, where we all riff off of each others&amp;#8217; thoughts. I tried weakly comparing this episode to Led Zeppelin&amp;#8217;s No Quarter. Yeah, I know, that&amp;#8217;s quite a stretch.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://newmediacracy.com'&gt;New Mediacracy Episode 13: The One About the IAWTV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a lively one, and a bigger group than usual joins us on this episode, which we recorded immediately after the first Los Angeles meeting of the &lt;a href='http://iawtv.org'&gt;IAWTV&lt;/a&gt; which took place at the &lt;a href='http://wga.org'&gt;WGA&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/metonyv'&gt;Tony Valenzuela&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/caseymckinnon'&gt;Casey McKinnon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/spytap'&gt;Barrett Garese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/brettregister'&gt;Brett Register&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/rudy'&gt;Rudy Jahchan&lt;/a&gt; join regulars &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/chrismccaleb'&gt;Chris McCaleb&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/zadi'&gt;Zadi Diaz&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/stevewoolf'&gt;Steve Woolf&lt;/a&gt; to share their thoughts on the meeting and what it means for the future of the first organized member body dedicated to web video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spend some time talking about the &lt;a href='http://streamys.org'&gt;Streamys&lt;/a&gt;, but a lot more time talking about the things we took away from the meeting and what the ramifications are for everyone invested in making web video a sustainable, progressive medium. Also, we drink wine and laugh a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, listen and leave a comment so we can get some outside feedback on the topics we discuss, such as the idea of the new gatekeepers, why we are trying so hard to replicate tv and film models, the vision of the IAWTV, and Chris McCaleb jumping out of planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2010/05/14/new-mediacracy-13-the-one-about-the-iawtv/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow Friday</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/zanP4D3OuJ4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2010/05/14/follow-friday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/shovellingson/2624060661/' title='Twitter - New &amp;apos;Over Capacity&amp;apos; Graphic by Shovelling Son, on Flickr'&gt;&lt;img src='http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3069/2624060661_a7797d3dee.jpg' height='375' alt='Twitter - New &amp;apos;Over Capacity&amp;apos; Graphic' width='500' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Twitter tradition I have only vaguely dabbled in is Follow Friday; the way people dump the hash tag and a huge list of names turned me off. I like it when they take the time to explain WHY we should follow them. And I was simply to lazy to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my five people below 10,000 followers (apart from my beautiful partner &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/caseymckinnon' target='_blank'&gt;Casey McKinnon&lt;/a&gt;) I follow and why you should too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href='http://twitter.com/carbonfive.com' target='_blank'&gt;CarbonFive&lt;/a&gt; - The great coding crew I work with. I love that I'm the stupidest person in the room, as I get to learn so much everyday, and so can you; we regularly post a lot of practical and innovative development tips, covering everything from Java and Rails, to the latest iP(whatever) tricks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href='http://twitter.com/ElizaBayne' target='_blank'&gt;Eliza Bayne&lt;/a&gt; - The looks of Katherine Heigl with the comedic genius of Sarah Silverman, dear 'liza is quite the package of enterainment. Eliza has produced and starred in content of all formats and styles, but it's her twitter messages I love the most; each an injection of hilarity into my day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href='http://twitter.com/BrettRegister' target='_blank'&gt;Brett Register&lt;/a&gt; - the mad, overproductive creator of innumerable web shows. I follow him because he reminds me of myself four years ago (I am an internet dinosaur), except he is far more talented. I also hope that by doing so I can encourage him to twitter more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href='http://twitter.com/ericmortensen' target='_blank'&gt;Eric Mortensen&lt;/a&gt; - Watch him when he goes on a web video advice tear. Deeper words of wisdom you will never hear. All that, and he has remarkable taste in all cultural things. Cheers, my friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href='http://twitter.com/tarynoneill' target='_blank'&gt;Taryn O'Neill&lt;/a&gt; - Taryn has been an inspiration personally not only with our mutual desire (and her successful accomplishment) of getting fit, but in the way she consistently, professionally, almost procedurally pursues acting work. One day, I hope I can supply her that work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo courtesy of &lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/shovellingson/2624060661/' target='_blank'&gt;Shovelling Son&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2010/05/14/follow-friday/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Dismantle a Shia LaBomb</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/ct2bM0jPx6g/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/09/09/how-to-dismantle-a-shia-labomb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class='video'&gt; &lt;object class='image'&gt; &lt;param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/o8XanqiBnOI'&gt; &lt;/param&gt; &lt;embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/o8XanqiBnOI' type='application/x-shockwave-flash'&gt; &lt;/embed&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is the core of what I dub the Shia LaBomb. Notice the stylish use of crotch shots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the full Shia LaBouef is the above video playing as the DESKTOP BACKGROUND of its intended target MacOSX system. Yes, a terrible weapon, but these terrible times demand nothing less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assembling your own is easy, and I post them here for the sake of mutually assured destruction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, collect &lt;a href='http://www.shialabeouf.us/'&gt;images from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Then, use some &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eBGIQ7ZuuiU'&gt;long forgotten music&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Assemble the above with your favorite video editor into a loving montage of the man in question. I used iMovie.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Grab this &lt;a href='http://s.sudre.free.fr/Software/SaveHollywood.html'&gt;freeware screen-saver&lt;/a&gt; that let&amp;#8217;s you play movies.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Load the video in question.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Using Apple&amp;#8217;s Script Editor, create an application using this code test: &lt;script src='https://gist.github.com/3350546.js'&gt; &lt;/script&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;You run it to turn on/off the currently selected screensaver. Run it to start the ball rolling and and voila, instant Shia LaBomb!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what could bring me to develop such a monstrous creation? Well &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night, we had a last-minute get together with &lt;a href='http://shey.net/'&gt;Tim Shey&lt;/a&gt;, his beautiful wife Rachel, and our friends (and leaders in the independent show producers field) &lt;a href='http://epicfu.com/'&gt;Zadi Diaz and Steve Woolf&lt;/a&gt;. Among the catch-up and laughs, Casey and my horrible seekrit came out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;#8217;t like Shia LaBouef.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually only I don&amp;#8217;t like him. &lt;a href='http://caseymckinnon.com/'&gt;Casey&lt;/a&gt; LOATHES him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, its nothing personal, and I respect he&amp;#8217;s a working actor. I just want to see him move beyond frustrated joe reacting to shit that&amp;#8217;s so much cooler than him. Not entirely his fault I realize but hey, I am pathetic enough to funnel my anger at a meaningless target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When rumors emerged of &lt;a href='http://io9.com/5028007/shia-the-last-man-in-2010'&gt;Shia possibly starring in the adaptation of one of our favorite comic-book series, Y: The Last Man&lt;/a&gt;, it came with a shocking image. Probably photoshopped but who knows. For us Shia-haters, it&amp;#8217;s just painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joked with Casey that one day I would play the nasty trick of setting her desktop to that image. Well, that didn&amp;#8217;t go over well, so she went for the preemptive strike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/coderonin/2845044562/' title='Shia&amp;apos;ed!!! by Rudy Jahchan, on Flickr' class='image'&gt;&lt;img src='http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3211/2845044562_1a99984e15.jpg' height='313' alt='Shia&amp;apos;ed!!!' width='500' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course you realize this meant war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe in shock and awe (but don&amp;#8217;t ask me about a follow-up), so created the Shia LaBomb, and left it running on her laptop, enjoying her twittered reactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WARNING: It came at a terrible cost. For the rest of the day, images of Shia and how he wouldn&amp;#8217;t never gonna let me down haunted me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/09/09/how-to-dismantle-a-shia-labomb/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: The Black Diamond</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/kYbAA__Y69s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2008 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/08/24/review-the-black-diamond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/coderonin/2791974570/' title='Black Diamond by Rudy Jahchan, on Flickr' class='image'&gt;&lt;img src='http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3251/2791974570_fd39d92c96.jpg' height='375' alt='Black Diamond' width='500' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A comicbook review! Bear with me, as this needs some set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who haven&amp;#8217;t figured it out, &lt;a href='http://acomicbookorange.com/'&gt;I love me some comics&lt;/a&gt;. This is a constant for me; if I ever want to cheer up, get some brain candy, I hit up a few stores and grab some pages of &amp;#8220;4 color&amp;#8221; fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My other pop culture tastes are always in flux. Sure I will always love westerns, zombies, iconic heroes, deep space, etc. But I usually obsess over a single genre for weeks on end, with a white hot flame of curiosity until it burns itself out. Otaku am I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, that obsession is cars. Partly due to our LA move. With no wheels of our own, and in a city where they are a necessary part of life, the hunt begins. And for me hunting is not just about hitting the pavement and crunching the numbers. That&amp;#8217;s just nasty reality stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s also about the dream. Like renting a Mustang for the first two weeks to see how we like it (another day). Or thinking &amp;#8221;y&amp;#8217;know, best nexus of fuel efficiency and performance is a Lotus&amp;#8221; (my soul brutha &lt;a href='http://www.barrettgarese.com/post/41118381/serendipity'&gt;Barrett knows what I am talking about it&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;#8217;s also about seeing the dreams of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you got your classic car chase movies like &lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0062765/'&gt;Bullit&lt;/a&gt;. I prefer &lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0122690/'&gt;Ronin&lt;/a&gt;, as I like the taste of McGuffin in the morning. And I am SUPREMELY pissed I couldn&amp;#8217;t find my copy of the stunning BMW funded series &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hire'&gt;The Hire&lt;/a&gt; starring Clive Owen from a few years back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But under the hot LA sun, in the long, boring, maddening hour long lurch that is the morning commute, with gas prices arising and the American dream turning nightmare, it&amp;#8217;s the apocalyptic masterpiece that is &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Road_Warrior'&gt;Mad Max 2: The Road Warrior&lt;/a&gt; curls my lips in a sneer of joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I heard that Larry Young and Jon Proctor&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href='http://ait-planetlar.com/blackdiamonds.shtml'&gt;The Black Diamond&lt;/a&gt; was finally being collected, I said &amp;#8220;Oh yeah.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The premise is great. In the near future, America raises a cross-continental mega-highway. Called the Black Diamond, years down the line it&amp;#8217;s become a no-man&amp;#8217;s land of muscle cars and gangs with their own subcultures, and while the government begins steps to take it back, a young dentist must race from his practice on the West Coast to Washington DC to rescue his kidnapped wife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comics + post-apocalyptic car action != fail, right? With a terrific introduction Graeme McMillian of &lt;a href='http://io9.com/'&gt;io9.com&lt;/a&gt; I tore into it &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; and was left incredibly disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upfront, the art is not the best. The style itself is not bad, and the cars are gorgeous (as they have to be, even being traced). But the rendering of people and their faces are a random affair of meh to sloppy work. Funny enough, while some people have criticized the coloring of the book, I think it captures the feel of the 70s movies the creators are trying to evoke. But most sequences give no sense of the action taking place, despite some cool ideas and visuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big crime here is that while the world the story takes place is ripe for exploration, I don&amp;#8217;t feel that we see any of it! There&amp;#8217;s a lot of talking about the world by characters you never really connect with. Worse, as the story progresses, it (and the artwork) moves from really straightforward primal ideas to a vague, abstract symbolism with no real conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t want pure symbolism in my apocalyptic car story! I want paint scraping, bone jarring, tire squealing driving! I want DIY mechanical weapon bad-assery! I want to SEE more of the dynamics of this world, not have it TOLD to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some may say there is a fundamental problem in trying to render the dynamic beast that is a car chase in the &amp;#8220;static&amp;#8221; images of a comicbook. I say bullshit. Matt Fraction and Kieron Dwyer&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href='http://www.ait-planetlar.com/loti.shtml'&gt;The Last of the Independents&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://www.acomicbookorange.com/2007/06/14/pirates-of-coney-island/'&gt;Pirates of Coney Island&lt;/a&gt; by Rick Spears and Vasilis Lolos are two personal favorites that come to mind. There is a way to do violent, thumping, end-of-world, vehicle of death action!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Black Diamond is simply not the right route to take.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/08/24/review-the-black-diamond/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vote for my SXSW Panel: Soapbox Speilbergs</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/8nmy9zU2leA/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/08/14/vote-for-my-sxsw-panel-soapbox-speilbergs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href='http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/ideas/view/2061' title='My SXSW Panel by Rudy Jahchan, on Flickr' class='center'&gt;&lt;img src='http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3031/2763790968_8503c179ae.jpg' height='188' alt='My SXSW Panel' width='500' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off: &lt;a href='http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/ideas/view/2061'&gt;GO VOTE FOR THIS PANEL&lt;/a&gt;!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the story behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, &lt;a href='http://shey.net/'&gt;Tim Shey&lt;/a&gt; is a bastard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I went over to &lt;a href='http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/'&gt;vote for panels for SXSW 2009&lt;/a&gt;, I was surprised to see very few digital film-making panel propositions. What I did see was great, and I tossed my big-time votage to video &lt;del datetime='2008-08-14T20:42:25+00:00'&gt;peers&lt;/del&gt; betters &lt;a href='http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/ideas/view/775'&gt;Kent Nichols&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/ideas/view/1352'&gt;Ben Cote&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href='http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/ideas/view/1704'&gt;Michael Verdi&lt;/a&gt;, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned it to Tim, &lt;a href='http://nextnewnetworks.com/'&gt;NNN&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s founder and hamster in the wheel that keeps it going. We bounced the idea that we should have submitted a panel about doing effects on a budget, like we do on &lt;a href='http://galacticast.com/'&gt;Galacticast&lt;/a&gt; and the talented Erik Beck and Justin Johnson do on &lt;a href='http://indymogul.com/'&gt;IndyMogul&lt;/a&gt;. Tim said he could get it on the panel picker; I thought it was great to try, but didn&amp;#8217;t want to get too excited, so as to avoid disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the lesson of the day is &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT DOUBT TIM SHEY&lt;/strong&gt;! He did get it on the panel picker. So now I&amp;#8217;ve got to step and make sure it not only gets attention, but also reestablish Galacticast as an entertainment and effects show to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bastard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/08/14/vote-for-my-sxsw-panel-soapbox-speilbergs/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to California</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/93NJW246FPc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/08/13/going-to-california/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/coderonin/2758105122/' title='Daily Self Portrait - August 12th 2008 by Rudy Jahchan, on Flickr' class='image'&gt;&lt;img src='http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3213/2758105122_40c4686654.jpg' height='375' alt='Daily Self Portrait - August 12th 2008' width='500' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the song says, going to California to make a new start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year has been a busy year for me. But not in accomplishing the goals I set out as &lt;a href='http://www.rudyjahchan.com/2008/01/02/happy-new-year/'&gt;my resolutions&lt;/a&gt;. One big reason is the my day-job began taking over more time as we moved on a major goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was until last Friday Director of Technology of &lt;a href='http://webmd.com/'&gt;WebMD&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s Montreal office, nee Conceptis. Which basically meant development team lead, architect, analyst, advocate, and general tech dude. I worked with an amazing group of guys, and through the larger WebMD family met equally talented people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first half of this year was occupied by the launching of Montreal&amp;#8217;s flagship sight &lt;a href='http://www.theheart.org/'&gt;theheart.org&lt;/a&gt;, playing catch up with the latest design trends and best practices the rest of the &amp;#8216;net. Layouts, comments, RESTful architecture. It was quite a challenge, made greater by the fact that we had to pull this off on legacy systems and a legacy code-base. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We succeeded to an extent, and I am pleased it what we accomplished in so brief a time. But as the project wrapped up, it made me realise how stagnant I had become. Apart from missing my own goals, and the continued delay of &lt;a href='http://galacticast.com/'&gt;Galacticast&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s return, it had become quite some time since I learned something new on the job, apart from the odd bug in JAVA or the way systems worked together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when an opportunity to work in LA popped up, I had to snap at it. I&amp;#8217;ll be working at &lt;a href='http://carbonfive.com/'&gt;CabonFive&lt;/a&gt; out of Marina Del Rey, in developing applications for a wide range of clients. The way they work, the people involved, and just the change of responsibilities has me excited about showing up to work again. And you should always feel that about your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those concerned about &lt;a href='http://galacticast.com/'&gt;Galacticast&lt;/a&gt;, don&amp;#8217;t be. Bringing it back is still my primary personal goal. We have a new season drawn out, and having actually calculated our expenditures for making the show over two years, we know exactly making an episode costs us. I&amp;#8217;ll be upfront; our immediate goal is to look for someone to fund it. So if you&amp;#8217;re interested or know anyone who may be, reach out to our (himself very talented) agent, &lt;a href='mailto:gruiz@icmtalent.com'&gt;George Ruiz&lt;/a&gt;, or hit me if you want a preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#8217;s it. Big unknown future ahead of me. Rebooting goals of physical fitness (environment will help), creatively (ideas I have a plenty, time to launch them), and building my data-cloud (this is the first of daily, srsly I swears).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/08/13/going-to-california/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judging a Video Copyfight Content; Join In!</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/aHq8K67UOk4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/07/17/judging-a-video-copyfight-content-join-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class='video'&gt;&lt;object&gt;&lt;param name='movie' value='http://www.youtube.com/v/igu-7jDIjSU?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowFullScreen' value='true' /&gt;&lt;param name='allowscriptaccess' value='always' /&gt;&lt;embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/igu-7jDIjSU?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0' allowfullscreen='true' type='application/x-shockwave-flash' allowscriptaccess='always' /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am really honored to be among the awesome panelists selected by Michael Geist for his video contest &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=igu-7jDIjSU'&gt;C-61 in 61 seconds&lt;/a&gt;. The goal is to create videos raising awareness of the many flaws with bill C-61, commonly referred to as the Canadian DMCA act. The last time they tried to ram this idea down our throats was the subject of the &lt;a href='http://www.galacticast.com/2007/12/27/a-copyright-carol/'&gt;last Galacticast we released&lt;/a&gt;, so you know the issue is near and dear to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, Galacticast could never have come to be without the fair use and play policies we all execute in our daily lives. The portability of media, the rapid turnaround time, the out and out parodies - all these things would be killed in sad, silent ways if this bill is not stopped. And while I am now thinking that more original content is the future our our brave, little show, it will work under the same principles of openess and fairness that we have always believed in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To read more about the bill, check out &lt;a href='http://www.michaelgeist.ca/'&gt;Michael Geist&amp;#8217;s informative blog&lt;/a&gt; and the amazing &lt;a href='http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=6315846683'&gt;Facebook group&lt;/a&gt; that has grown up around the cause.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/07/17/judging-a-video-copyfight-content-join-in/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galacticast's "The Supermarios" shown at MIFF</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/5N0b76NBJDI/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/07/17/galacticasts-the-supermarios-shown-at-miff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style='text-align:center;'&gt;
&lt;a href='http://miff.ca' title='The Supermarios by Casey McKinnon, on Flickr' class='image'&gt;&lt;img src='http://farm1.static.flickr.com/155/412484997_8f58cf8696_o.jpg' height='270' alt='The Supermarios' width='480' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Galacticast video &lt;a href='http://www.galacticast.com/2007/03/06/the-supermarios/'&gt;The Supermarios&lt;/a&gt; was screened at the &lt;a href='http://miff.ca/'&gt;Mississauga Independent Film Festival&lt;/a&gt; on Sunday, July 13th, at 11am in the &lt;a href='http://miff.ca/?page_id=49'&gt;Short Progrm&lt;/a&gt; category. I would love to see some footage of this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to brothers-in-arms &lt;a href='http://mattcampagna.com/'&gt;Matt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://www.jeffcampagna.com/'&gt;Jeff Campagna&lt;/a&gt;. Read of their awesomeness in &lt;a href='http://www.theglobeandmail.com/servlet/story/LAC.20080704.MIFF04/TPStory/TPEntertainment/Movies/'&gt;The Globe and Mail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/07/17/galacticasts-the-supermarios-shown-at-miff/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galacticast in LaPresse</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/0N2ymiwfn-U/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2008 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/06/09/galacticast-in-lapresse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href='http://www.cyberpresse.ca/article/20080607/CPARTS/806071039/5155/CPACTUALITES' class='image'&gt;&lt;img src='http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3145/2564226005_f39699767c_o.gif' height='61' alt='logo_lapresse' width='267' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://caseymckinnon.com'&gt;Casey&lt;/a&gt; and I were interviewed by the LaPresse. To my embarassment, I am quoted heavily and seem to have inspired the title of the article. Here&amp;#8217;s the &lt;a href='http://www.cyberpresse.ca/article/20080607/CPARTS/806071039/5155/CPACTUALITES'&gt;original&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href='http://translate.google.ca/translate?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.cyberpresse.ca%2Farticle%2F20080607%2FCPARTS%2F806071039%2F5155%2FCPACTUALITES&amp;amp;sl=fr&amp;amp;tl=en&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8'&gt;translation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/06/09/galacticast-in-lapresse/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Movies!</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/DO3E0kWWn5w/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/05/30/in-the-movies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;a href='http://www.imdb.com/name/nm2980232/' class='image'&gt;&lt;img src='http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2271/2449867064_d80990dc7a.jpg' height='316' alt='I&amp;apos;m on IMDB' width='500' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days after &lt;a href='http://www.caseymckinnon.com/2008/05/26/now-on-imdb/'&gt;Casey&lt;/a&gt; I too am now listed on IMDB. It&amp;#8217;s for our cameo appearance in &lt;a href='http://www.sixreasonswhy.com/'&gt;Six Reasons Why&lt;/a&gt;, the post-apocalyptic spaghetti western love song to Sergio Leone by the talented Campagna brothers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to fill that listing up with more roles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2008/05/30/in-the-movies/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drinks with the Devil</title>
      <link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/rudyjahchan/~3/KFaPLhaInoI/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Rudy Jahchan</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://rudyjahchan.com/2007/12/06/drinks-with-the-devil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originally posted on my old blog &lt;a href='http://www.coderonin.net/2004/12/01/drink-with-the-devil/'&gt;coderonin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The urine ran slow and warm down my leg when I realized who he was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Pleased to meet you,&amp;#8221; he said, extending a hand. The Devil grinned. &amp;#8220;I see you guessed my name.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He laughed at the joke. A braying honk of laughter passed crooked, yellow teeth. A smell on his breath; not enough to drive you away, just enough to torment you. It finished the job of sobering me up, and I didn&amp;#8217;t take his hand. He kept it out there for a few moments before shrugging and grabbing a drink in front of him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Another round?&amp;#8221; he asked urgently, offering the glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much for sobriety, as my first instinct was to shout &amp;#8220;Hell, yeah!&amp;#8221; But who knew how The Devil would interpret that. I managed to choke it off to a hesitant grunt that turned into a panicked headshake. The Devil caught the reaction change though. Surprisingly, he looked hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Oh c&amp;#8217;mon,&amp;#8221; he urged. &amp;#8220;I promise, it&amp;#8217;s on me. Won&amp;#8217;t cost you a thing.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He placed the drink in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I insist,&amp;#8221; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh God, he insisted. What was I to do? Literally damned if I did, damned if I didn&amp;#8217;t. My focus shifted nervously between the glass and The Devil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Won&amp;#8217;t cost a thing,&amp;#8221; he said again, nodding with that charming, awful smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take the drink. Slugged it back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Except your SOUL!&amp;#8221; said the Devil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drink spewed from my mouth. Coughs wracked my body. The Devil roared with laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Oh, oh, that&amp;#8217;s always classic!&amp;#8221; he said. &amp;#8220;The look on your face!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said nothing. Too scared shitless. Funny thing is I believe that&amp;#8217;s what quieted him down so quickly. His laughter died out and he again appeared to be in some pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Hey, hey,&amp;#8221; he said. &amp;#8220;I was only kidding. Your soul&amp;#8217;s fine.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stared at me anxiously, waiting for a response. Felt hot under that stare, so I nodded to get it over with. That seemed to please him. He clapped his long, pale hands (a kind of wet sound) and giggled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Good, good,&amp;#8221; he said. He waved over the horrified bar tender. &amp;#8220;Another two for me and my friend here.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Sir, I  I think you&amp;#8217;ve had enough,&amp;#8221; began the bartender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will never forget the heat, sight, and sound of that poor man&amp;#8217;s head melting in flames. Lucky to have its smoking remains crash turned away from me. The scalded back of his skull was bad enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Devil looked significantly at the other bartender and nodded once. Our drinks were prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;#8217;t stand it any longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;What do you want from me?&amp;#8221; I said. More like whimpered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned to me with surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Why, nothing.&amp;#8221; An offended tone. More urine down my leg. &amp;#8220;You came to me.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was right. I did come to him. Drunk from a night of trying to forget her. Looked over to see the first face that seemed to understand the blackness in me now that she was gone. Needed that understanding, so I came over. We shared a few great drinks, shared many great laughs. Until he clued me in to who he was. I wasn&amp;#8217;t laughing anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which was what was irritating him. Nothing had really changed, had it? Just who I knew him as. It was still true that he understood the blackness in me. Who could ever understand it more than The Devil? And it still had been my decision to come over for a drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;But I never wanted to drink with the Devil,&amp;#8221; was all I could say in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;No one ever does, buddy,&amp;#8221; he sighed. &amp;#8220;No one ever does.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://rudyjahchan.com/2007/12/06/drinks-with-the-devil/</feedburner:origLink></item>
    

  </channel> 
</rss>
