<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/wp-atom.php">
	<title type="text">Mark's Daily Apple</title>
	<subtitle type="text">Serving up health and fitness insights (daily, of course) with a side of irreverence.</subtitle>

	<updated>2013-03-23T15:00:38Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" />
	<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/feed/atom/</id>
	

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.5.1">WordPress</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/MarksDailyApple" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="marksdailyapple" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">MarksDailyApple</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><entry>
		<author>
			<name>Worker Bee</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Smoked Bacon Oysters]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/smoked-bacon-oysters/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35728</id>
		<updated>2013-03-22T05:16:29Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-23T15:00:38Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Recipes" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smoked Bacon Oysters are crispy little morsels of pure pleasure, an addictive snack and appetizer, or a tasty breakfast side for scrambled eggs. The flavor of bacon dominates (never a bad thing). Smoked oysters add a sweet and smoky flavor that pairs perfectly with the salty bacon. The texture is also perfect: crispy bacon and [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/smoked-bacon-oysters/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" alt="SmokedBaconOysters" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/SmokedBaconOysters.jpg" width="320" height="212" title="Smoked Bacon Oysters" /&gt;Smoked Bacon Oysters are crispy little morsels of pure pleasure, an addictive snack and appetizer, or a tasty breakfast side for scrambled eggs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flavor of &lt;a title="A Quick Guide to Bacon" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/a-quick-guide-to-bacon/#axzz2O0x9LomC"&gt;bacon&lt;/a&gt; dominates (never a bad thing). Smoked &lt;a title="A Guide to Crustaceans, Bivalves and Molluscs, or Why You Should Be Eating Exoskeleton-Bearing Aquatic Invertebrates " href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/types-of-shellfish/"&gt;oysters&lt;/a&gt; add a sweet and smoky flavor that pairs perfectly with the salty bacon. The texture is also perfect: crispy bacon and a creamy melt-in-your-mouth oyster middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recipe can potentially serve 4 as an appetizer, but only if you have enough willpower not to pop half of them in your own mouth right out of the oven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35728"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serves:&lt;/strong&gt; 4, as a light appetizer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time in the Kitchen:&lt;/strong&gt; 30 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="ingredients 55" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/ingredients-55.jpg" width="540" height="360" title="Smoked Bacon Oysters" /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tins smoked oysters* (3 ounces/85 grams each)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 strips of bacon (12 ounces/340 g)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* When buying smoked oysters, look for brands packed in olive oil rather than cottonseed or other oils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instructions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 400º F (204 ºC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drain the oil from the oysters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrap each oyster in a single layer of bacon. If some oysters are especially small, wrap up two of them together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To wrap the oysters set an oyster on the end of a piece of bacon. Roll the strip of bacon once so it wraps the oyster in a single layer. Use a toothpick to secure the bacon around the oyster. Use scissors (the easiest way) or a knife to cut the wrapped oyster off from the remaining bacon strip. One strip of bacon will wrap about 3 oysters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="Roll Bacon" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/Roll_Bacon.jpg" width="540" height="360" title="Smoked Bacon Oysters" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set the wrapped oysters on a broiler pan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(A broiler pan works better than a regular pan because the grease will drip through the holes to the pan below. In a regular pan, the grease pools around the oysters, making them greasier and less crispy. If you don’t have a broiler pan, you can bake the oysters on a cooling rack set on a rimmed sheet pan.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bake the oysters for about 20 minutes, until the bacon is crisp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These bacon wrapped oysters taste best right out of the oven, but are still tasty at room temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="SmokedBaconOysters" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/SmokedBaconOysters.jpg" width="540" height="360" title="Smoked Bacon Oysters" /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get All Three Primal Cookbooks, an Apron and More in &lt;a title="The Primal Blueprint Chef Kit" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/The-Primal-Blueprint-Chef-Kit.html" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Blueprint Chef Kit&lt;/a&gt; Today!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/Zezp418dHTo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/smoked-bacon-oysters/#comments" thr:count="0" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/smoked-bacon-oysters/feed/atom/" thr:count="0" />
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[How the 21-Day Challenge Helped Me]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-the-21-day-challenge-helped-me/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35732</id>
		<updated>2013-03-22T05:52:59Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-22T15:00:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Success Stories" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s Friday, everyone! And that means another Primal Blueprint Real Life Story from a Mark&#8217;s Daily Apple reader. If you have your own success story and would like to share it with me and the Mark’s Daily Apple community please contact me here. I’ll continue to publish these each Friday as long as they keep [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-the-21-day-challenge-helped-me/">&lt;div class="breakout"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s Friday, everyone! And that means another &lt;a title="Success Stories" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/category/success-story-summaries/"&gt;Primal Blueprint Real Life Story&lt;/a&gt; from a Mark&amp;#8217;s Daily Apple reader. If you have your own success story and would like to share it with me and the Mark’s Daily Apple community please contact me &lt;a title="Contact Me!" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-book/share-success-story/" target="_self"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I’ll continue to publish these each Friday as long as they keep coming in. Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" title="Primal Blueprint Real Life Story" alt="real life stories stories 1 2" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA2009/real_life_stories_stories-1-2.jpg" width="320" height="240" /&gt;Hi Mark,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been slowly getting my feet wet with the paleo/primal nutritional way of living for around a year now. It started with a better way of cutting the highly addictive sugar out of my diet. Many of those types of diets don’t address the need for higher fat consumption though and they don’t consider behavioral changes that need to be made as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I want to tell my weight loss journey story right, I have to start at the beginning. I was obese my entire life. I remember being called “Miss Piggy” in second grade by classmates. I remember writing to diet and weight loss scam ads in the back of teen magazines begging for help as a preteen. But nothing ever changed and I stayed obese until I moved across the country (away from my family’s environment) and started the process at the age of 26. My entire family is obese, so I have to admit that I didn’t see a lot of hope for losing weight based on lies my Mom shared with us our wholes lives (that we are supposed to be this way).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35732"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="285041 2298966632951 7306851 n" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/285041_2298966632951_7306851_n.jpg" width="540" height="405" title="How the 21 Day Challenge Helped Me" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started my weight loss journey, it was not the healthiest choice I could have made in going about doing it. I joined a local gym (the first one I had ever stepped foot into) and started doing repetitive cardio before going to work and after work each day (6 days a week). I also worked 8 hours a day on my feet. I tracked everything I ate obsessively and broke down every macronutrient. I strived to eat 1200-1400 calories a day with a 30/40/30 ratio. I wore a heart rate monitor 24/7 to make sure that I expended more calories than I consumed each day. I was preoccupied with becoming my own “biggest loser” and whipping the weight off of me as quickly as possible. And I did. It took me around seven months to go from 285 pounds to 154. On the outside, this appeared to be a great success, but on the inside I caused new problems for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some problems that resulted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was so focused on losing weight and exercising that my relationship failed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The result of a lifetime of being obese and losing weight very quickly left me with loose skin. I felt defeated that I still was not happy with my appearance even after all of the hard work and dedication. I will never look good naked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My obsession with tracking food and restricting what I ate caused disordered eating patterns for me. I suffered with bouts of binge eating for the next two years during stressful times. The only way I managed to keep the binge weight off was to go back to restricted eating again and excessive exercise (like running marathons).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an effort to try to get over my preoccupation with food (especially sugars), I read every sugar addiction book available and even attended Overeaters Anonymous meetings for four months. The meetings were inviting and helpful at first, but then they stopped helping because everyone wallowed in their own self-pity about their addiction to donuts or ice cream. It just made me want to run to comfort food even more. The books were insightful, but the diets they promoted were not. I could not give up all refined sugars and keep the rest of my diet the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around this time, I ventured into the paleo lifestyle and it made more sense to me, but like most people, I was scared to start eating that much fat in my diet (no matter if it was healthy or not). So, I introduced certain ideas from the paleo plans into my life slowly. I started eating more organic meat, avocados, nuts, and eggs. The problem was that I still had grains, legumes, soy, and sweeteners in my diet. After a few more months, I read somewhere that the paleo diet was actually credited with helping some people with eating disorders to overcome them. Maybe this was the golden ticket I was looking for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began to realize that living healthy wasn’t just about eating healthy and working out. It was a complete behavior shift. I suffer from Obsessive-Compulsive Personality Disorder (not OCD), so I tend to be perfectionistic and rigid in my way of living anyways. My goal has been to accept myself the way that I am and have more compassion for myself when I fail and allow my life to just flow instead of being scheduled all of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How the 21-day challenge helped me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finally gave up stevia in my morning coffee/tea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finally gave up my morning oatmeal for eggs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I am hungry, I have the mindset now to eat something with more fat and protein.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I stand at my desk now for at least 2 or 3 hours a day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I take time to myself now to avoid getting too overwhelmed or stressed out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ask for help from my fiancé with chores around the house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can now do over 40 pushups in a row.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still cannot do a full pull-up, but I’m getting closer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can see my abs for the first time in my life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don’t need to obsessively workout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ve started fermenting my own sauerkraut.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I purchased a slackline and use it for fun and entertainment with friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spend more quality time with my fiancé (not talking about food or exercise).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;img alt="1X3EYig7VkxRLwHZ5tWGqg5rAd587" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/1X3EYig7VkxRLwHZ5tWGqg5rAd587.jpg" width="540" height="378" title="How the 21 Day Challenge Helped Me" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My journey has not been easy. When people ask me how I lost the weight, I could say “With diet and exercise”, but that really discounts all of the physical and mental struggle and anguish I went through because I chose to lose weight the somewhat unhealthy way and I have a personality disorder that controls much of how I behave on any given day. The paleo nutrition plan is simple, which is great because I tend to over-complicate things. It was really hard for me to believe that something so easy could actually work. But I figured that 21 days of eating and behaving this way couldn’t hurt to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="419038 4659445003435 1644896030 n" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/419038_4659445003435_1644896030_n.jpg" width="540" height="520" title="How the 21 Day Challenge Helped Me" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a full month of eating paleo, I weighed and measured myself for the first time. I dropped 8 pounds on the scale and am currently at my lowest body fat percentage. Even when I weighed 154 pounds, my body fat was slightly higher than what it is now at 165 pounds. The best part is the difference I could see in my “after” photos this time. I can actually see more definition in my stomach and arms. A friend also kindly pointed out to me that she noticed a big difference also… I’m smiling! I never smiled when I was obese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="205383 4205994027444 888106029 n" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/205383_4205994027444_888106029_n.jpg" width="540" height="398" title="How the 21 Day Challenge Helped Me" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you Mark and the whole paleo community for opening my eyes to an easier way of living my healthiest life (mentally and physically)! I hope to be able to write to you in the future to let you know that the disordered eating patterns have completely vanished (and I’ve gotten even healthier).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="314749 2548848639845 103023516 n" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/314749_2548848639845_103023516_n.jpg" width="540" height="432" title="How the 21 Day Challenge Helped Me" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Naomi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Start Your Own &lt;a title="The 2012 Primal Blueprint 21-Day Challenge" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-blueprint-101/#21daychallenge"&gt;21-Day Challenge&lt;/a&gt; Today! Order a copy of &lt;a title="The Primal Blueprint 21-Day Total Body Transformation" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/The-Primal-Blueprint-21%252dDay-Total-Body-Transformation.html" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Blueprint 21-Day Total Body Transformation&lt;/a&gt; for the Complete Program.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/0vZE1pqovD0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-the-21-day-challenge-helped-me/#comments" thr:count="112" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-the-21-day-challenge-helped-me/feed/atom/" thr:count="112" />
		<thr:total>112</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Do Fear and Anxiety Define Your Health Journey?]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/does-fear-and-anxiety-define-your-health-journey/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35684</id>
		<updated>2013-03-21T21:41:42Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-21T15:00:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Personal Improvement" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Think for a minute about the health messaging sources in our culture. Think of the pharmaceutical ads in every magazine and television show. Think of the medical talk shows and evening exposes on obscure conditions, the nightly newscasts depicting the ravages of epidemics in far flung corners of the globe and “expert” sound bytes warning [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/does-fear-and-anxiety-define-your-health-journey/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" alt="fear" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/fear.jpg" width="320" height="212" title="Do Fear and Anxiety Define Your Health Journey?" /&gt;Think for a minute about the health messaging sources in our culture. Think of the pharmaceutical ads in every magazine and television show. Think of the medical talk shows and evening exposes on obscure conditions, the nightly newscasts depicting the ravages of epidemics in far flung corners of the globe and “expert” sound bytes warning of pathogens closer to home. Then there are the messages themselves. How many doom and gloom health statistics and inflammatory stock images do you encounter in a day? How many times do you hear “Ask your doctor if [insert medication] is right for you”? This doesn’t, of course, even begin to scratch the surface, but you get my point. Aside from the marketing blitzes telling us why this pharmaceutical is the next best thing or this box of snack food is heart healthy (hint: it’s not), the most commonly viewed/heard “health” related information spinning around in our culture &lt;a title="How the News Impacts Your Health" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-the-news-impacts-your-health-and-what-you-can-do-about-it/"&gt;paints a pretty negative, agitating picture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35684"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On an individual level, some people are genuinely facing emergency level, literally do-or-die situations. It might be the diagnosis of an acute condition or the long seen crescendo of a chronic, un-/under-attended lifestyle disease. &lt;strong&gt;But too often, we’re gripped by an anxiety beyond reason, without reason.&lt;/strong&gt; On the clinical end of the spectrum, experts &lt;a title="Health anxiety is not a joke – it can ruin lives" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/2010/jul/27/health-anxiety-on-the-increase" target="_blank"&gt;estimate&lt;/a&gt; about 1-2% of the population suffers from what’s considered “pathological health anxiety,” although it’s likely around 10% for people who have had serious health problems in the past. True hypochondria can be destructive enough to unravel a person’s life, and experts agree the condition is fed by fears that go much deeper than the latest health headlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond this extreme condition, however, are the “worried well” among us who request unwarranted, radiation-laden scans, &lt;a title="Statin Insanity" href="www.marksdailyapple.com/statin-insanity/"&gt;risky medications&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a title="The Value of Lab Values" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-value-of-lab-values/"&gt;unnecessary labs&lt;/a&gt; because we’re so anxious about our health. Sure, sometimes it’s doctors who fear litigation if they don’t go down every avenue or hospitals who want to profit from expensive testing procedures, but it’s often the will of the patients, too. Increasingly, it’s the patient who’s looking to go down a checklist of his own. Blame the ratings-hungry sensationalist media, self-diagnosis on the Internet, or the general sense that we’re all going to hell in a hand basket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All this hand-wringing, however, doesn’t seem to do much good in the collective sense. It’s enough to trump up fear and loathing but not enough to inspire much &lt;a title="It's Time to Get Real" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/get-real-achieve-your-health-goals-lose-weight-get-ripped-stay-motivated/"&gt;meaningful lifestyle change&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Our anxiety is too often misplaced. We have no problem eating fast food multiple times a week, but fear the flu or &lt;a title="H1ow N1ot to Get Swine Flu" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-not-to-get-swine-flu/"&gt;the next pandemic is waiting to grab us like the bogeyman in the night&lt;/a&gt;. Ebola is a mere plane flight away from stealing our children. Food poisoning is lurking in every meal. We can never have enough triclosan, &lt;a title="A Sanitized World is a Healthy World?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/immune-system-strength/"&gt;Purell&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a title="The Problems with Antibiotics: More Fallout from Killing Your Flora " href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-problems-with-antibiotics-more-fallout-from-killing-your-flora/"&gt;antibiotics&lt;/a&gt; to quiet our nerves, but here’s a caramel mochachino to take the edge off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backdrop on all this, of course, is the real state of affairs. We’re in sad physiological shape as a society, and that’s the understatement of the century. Truth be told, we have plenty of reason to worry &amp;#8211; except worry isn’t the answer. No one ever gets healthy cowering in a corner or gnashing their teeth. &lt;strong&gt;I think you have to opt out of the game in general &amp;#8211; the fear, the escapism, the distraction, the preoccupation. It’s instead about embracing something else entirely.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejecting health anxiety isn’t about putting our heads in the sand. The effective opposite of anxiety isn’t denial. It’s reason, power, &lt;a title="Don't Let the Perfect Be the Enemy of the Good" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/dont-let-the-perfect-be-the-enemy-of-the-good/"&gt;perspective&lt;/a&gt;. I’d argue it’s about &lt;a title="Is it Time to Retire the Low Carb Diet Fad?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/is-it-time-to-retire-the-low-carb-diet-fad/"&gt;learning to read the reality behind statistics&lt;/a&gt;, realizing what’s worth your concern and what’s not, and then taking responsibility for today &amp;#8211; right now. You have to stop dodging what you don’t want and take what you do. &lt;strong&gt;It’s about &lt;a title="Are You Living an Active or Passive Life?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/are-you-living-an-active-or-passive-life/"&gt;embracing the life you want for yourself&lt;/a&gt; and fixing your attention on that every day.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether you see health through a lens of fear or aspiration, that’s the principle that will define &amp;#8211; or limit &amp;#8211; it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last musing, and let me know your thoughts on this. I wonder what the results would be if a study was conducted on people who were either exposed to all of the anxiety-provoking, disease-focused messages of our culture or to only positive messages about &lt;a title="Thriving, Not Just Surviving" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/thrive-survive/"&gt;thriving&lt;/a&gt; and enjoying health. Anxiety versus enthusiasm, if you will. Which group would end up making the healthier choices? Which group would end up not only better adjusted but less medicated? Which group would feel more in control of their well-being and actually use that control to their advantage?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, everyone. Have a great end to the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grab a Copy of &lt;a title="Amazon.com: The Primal Connection" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0984755101/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=marsdaiapp07-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0984755101" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Connection: Follow Your Genetic Blueprint to Health and Happiness&lt;/a&gt; Today!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/XNnoeQgMoVE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/does-fear-and-anxiety-define-your-health-journey/#comments" thr:count="75" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/does-fear-and-anxiety-define-your-health-journey/feed/atom/" thr:count="75" />
		<thr:total>75</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[10 Full Body Workouts You Can Do in 10 Minutes Flat]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/10-full-body-workouts-you-can-do-in-10-minutes-flat/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35521</id>
		<updated>2013-03-20T03:55:33Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-20T15:00:31Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Fitness" /><category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Lift Heavy Things" /><category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Play" /><category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Sprint" /><category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Workout of the Week (WOW)" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It&#8217;d be nice if regular activity was woven into our daily lives so that we could stay lean, strong, and fit without really thinking about it, but that&#8217;s not the world most of us live in. We have to set aside time to move our bodies. But, as I always say, this doesn&#8217;t mean we [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/10-full-body-workouts-you-can-do-in-10-minutes-flat/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" title="Kettlebells" alt="kettlebells" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/kettlebells.jpg" width="320" height="212" /&gt;It&amp;#8217;d be nice if regular activity was woven into our daily lives so that we could stay lean, strong, and fit without really thinking about it, but that&amp;#8217;s not the world most of us live in. We have to set aside time to move our bodies. But, as I always say, this doesn&amp;#8217;t mean we have to exercise atop a conveyor belt with a TV in front of it doing everything we can to forget that we&amp;#8217;re even exercising in the first place. It doesn&amp;#8217;t mean the workouts have to take an hour to complete. And it certainly doesn&amp;#8217;t mean you need a gym to get in some good activity. That&amp;#8217;s why I started writing the &lt;a title="Workout of the Week (WOW) Archive" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-blueprint-fitness/workout-of-the-week-archive/#axzz2NNRcKsK5"&gt;Workouts of the Week&lt;/a&gt;, a compendium of fun, effective, varied workouts for you to try. Readers still visit the archives to shake up their routines, so be sure to check them out if you&amp;#8217;re in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I add ten additional fast but effective workouts to the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35521"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Max Reps Multiplied&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose two movements &amp;#8211; one upper body focused, one lower body focused &amp;#8211; that are complementary and do not conflict with each other. Pullups and &lt;a title="Dear Mark: Can’t Squat, Please Help; Plus, High CRP, No Symptoms, and Glutathione" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/squatting-advice-high-crp-glutathione/"&gt;squats&lt;/a&gt;, good. Deadlifts and squats, not so good. For each movement, perform the maximum amount of consecutive reps you can do. Multiply that number by four to give you a target amount of total reps. You have ten minutes to reach the target rep count in each exercise using any set and rep scheme you desire. So if you were able to do eight pullups and six front squats in a row, you need to do 32 more &lt;a title="How-To: Proper Pullup/Chinup Technique" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-proper-pullup-chinup-technique/"&gt;pullups&lt;/a&gt; and 24 more front squats. For weighted movements, 50 reps (including your initial max set) is the upper limit. For &lt;a title="Introducing Primal Blueprint Fitness" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/introducing-primal-blueprint-fitness/"&gt;bodyweight&lt;/a&gt; movements like air squats and pushups, the upper limit is 100 reps. If you reach the upper limit, add weight next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Baby Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very few of us launched right into full-blown bipedalism out of the womb. Instead, we &lt;a title="The “Grok Crawl”" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-grok-crawl/"&gt;crawled&lt;/a&gt;, crawled, and crawled some more. Contrary to the popular belief that crawling is just a useless placeholder for walking, moving around on all fours develops shoulder mobility and strength and contralateral awareness, plus the basic ability to move around and explore the environment. Adults should crawl too. It&amp;#8217;s a little different for us, though. We&amp;#8217;re heavier than babies,  so crawling can be taxing, particularly on the upper body. We&amp;#8217;re also not used to crawling, so it&amp;#8217;s a new movement all over again for many of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to learn how to crawl correctly is to start on the hands and knees. Assume the position. Place your left hand/left knee close together and your right hand/right knee further from each other. &amp;#8220;Step&amp;#8221; forward with your left hand and right knee, then follow with the right hand and left knee. Continue in this contralateral fashion. You can certainly try to crawl ipsilaterally (right hand/right knee forward), but your movement will be suboptimal. Once you&amp;#8217;re comfortable on your knees, move to the balls of your feet and hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the workout, crawl for seven minutes out of the allotted ten. The three minutes of break time can be divided into as many break periods as you like (e.g. three 1-minute breaks, or ten 18-second breaks, etc.). Crawl forward, crawl backward, crawl uphill, crawl downhill. Crawl sideways. Just explore the environment from the vantage point of a big baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Short and Heavy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than a description of Gimli son of Glóin, this is a prescription for heavy &lt;a title="Kettlebellin’ for Strength" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/kettlebellin-for-strength/"&gt;kettlebell&lt;/a&gt; swings and short sprints. Every minute on the minute, do ten swings with a weight that&amp;#8217;s heavy for you and follow it immediately up with a short 5 second all-out sprint. Because the actual workout part of the workout will be short (but very intense), put every fiber of your being into the swinging and especially the sprinting. It doesn&amp;#8217;t sound like much, but it will be after ten minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;#8217;t have a kettlebell, any weighted object that&amp;#8217;s able to safely pass between your legs will work. &lt;a title="The Sandbag Workout" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-sandbag-workout/"&gt;Sandbag&lt;/a&gt;, weight plate, dumbbell, small child, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic kettlebell swing is detailed in &lt;a title="dan john perfecting the kettlebell swing" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tVEReOq5Jgs" target="_blank"&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by Dan John. Watch it if you need to know how to perform the swing correctly. To switch things up from the standard swing, check out &lt;a title="kb swing varieties" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=azWPopipanU" target="_blank"&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; from Clifton Harski for some ideas on how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Park Play&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here in the United States, a single guy is liable to get the cops called if he so much as glances at a jungle gym set. Heck, most of the ones I see actually have signs explicitly forbidding childless adults from being there, so for this workout, you&amp;#8217;re going to have to be covert about it. Stick to times when the playground is empty, partly for your security and partly so you don&amp;#8217;t bowl over any kids during your workout. Or, bring a kid (hopefully your own) to join in with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The makeup of this workout depends on the equipment at your disposal. Most jungle gyms allow you to do some sort of pullup, so do some of those. If you can swing across from bar to bar, all the better. Climb poles, vault over barriers. Avoid taking the stairs and instead climb the structure itself. Crawl up slides, then slide back down and finish with a roll onto the ground. Just keep moving as if you&amp;#8217;re a kid on a candy-fueled bender. Maybe there are some hot lava monsters afoot, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend ten minutes doing everything you can think of to move around on and interact with the playground equipment. Ten minutes is long enough to get a great workout but short enough to evade suspicion. For more ideas watch &lt;a title="Primal on the Playground" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-blueprint-fitness-primal-on-the-playground/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Primal Workouts in a Modern City" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-blueprint-fitness-primal-workouts-in-a-modern-city/"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Primal Blueprint Fitness Elementary Workout" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-blueprint-fitness-elementary-workout/#axzz2O2ufXFhD"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Primal Blueprint Fitness College Play" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-blueprint-fitness-college-play/#axzz2O2ufXFhD"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Primal Blueprint Fitness Obstacle Course" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-blueprint-fitness-obstacle-course/#axzz2O2ufXFhD"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; Primal Blueprint Fitness videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Burpee Ladder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a title="Prison Workout" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/prison-workout/#axzz2NNISeGxV"&gt;burpee&lt;/a&gt; is a simple yet humbling exercise. You begin with a pushup &amp;#8211; that&amp;#8217;s easy enough, right? &amp;#8211; and spring up to the bottom of a squat, then stand and jump as high as you can before repeating the movement pattern. The first seven or eight burpees are always pretty easy, because you&amp;#8217;re so focused on doing the movement that you barely realize the amount of taxation your body is accumulating. Once you finish that first set, though, the realization that you&amp;#8217;re in for a rough time sets in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do ten of these the first minute, nine the second, eight the third, and so on. The faster you perform the burpees, the more rest you&amp;#8217;ll get until the next set. The slower you perform the burpees, the less rest you&amp;#8217;ll need since the burpees will be easier. What do you choose? Where do you strike the balance between intensity and rest? That&amp;#8217;s for you to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dig, Dug&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this one, you&amp;#8217;ll need a couple pieces of equipment. First, a medium sized garbage can. Second, a bunch of sand, diggable dirt, or gravel (the beach would work nicely here). Third, a shovel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the shovel (or your hands if you prefer), fill the can at least a quarter of the way for women and halfway full for men. Once the can is at the requisite fullness, &lt;a title="How to Regain and Maintain Hip Mobility" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-regain-and-maintain-hip-mobility/"&gt;squat&lt;/a&gt; down so that you&amp;#8217;re straddling the can and wrap your arms around it. Pull the can toward you (bear-hug style), maintain proper neutral spine, and stand up with the can in your arms. Perform three sets of 5 squats. If the can isn&amp;#8217;t full enough to be a challenge, add a bit more material in between sets. After the third set, spend the rest of the allotted ten minutes filling the can up the rest of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Travel Rearrangement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often find that traveling affords me unique and effective ways to exercise. Either the place I&amp;#8217;m staying at has a great gym with all the equipment I&amp;#8217;d ever need, or perhaps the location is such that outdoor activities are encouraged and unavoidable. But sometimes you end up in those joints with a few mismatched dumbbells, a broken elliptical trainer, and surrounding environs comprised entirely of strip malls and parking lots. When that&amp;#8217;s the case, how&amp;#8217;s a guy supposed to get a good workout in? Burpees in the bathroom and dips on the chairs are effective, but those get old fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time you&amp;#8217;re stuck in a hotel room, antsy to work out, consider rearranging the furniture. I&amp;#8217;m serious here. That old CRT TV that weighs a million pounds? Move it over to the opposite corner. The entertainment center? Slide it across the floor to the other side. Flip the sofa up and over, flip the mattress, lift the easy chair. Pull, push, slide, lift, carry, and heave furniture around. Do this for ten minutes and work up a great sweat. But of course, be careful. We wouldn&amp;#8217;t want any damage charges added to your hotel bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Beach Sprints, Modified&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;#8217;t seen my &lt;a title="Mark's Beach Sprints" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/marks-beach-sprints/#axzz2NNRcKsK5"&gt;old beach sprint video&lt;/a&gt;, check it out now. The cool thing about sprinting on the beach is that it&amp;#8217;s easier on the &lt;a title="Osteoarthritis is Not Your Destiny" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/arthritis-diet/"&gt;joints&lt;/a&gt; and yet harder on your muscles because you&amp;#8217;re working with a softer, more forgiving surface that absorbs a lot of the impact. How about we take it a step further and move toward the surf?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Beach Sprints, Modified, you&amp;#8217;ll be sprinting through shin to knee deep water. Wade out to where the water is lapping at your thighs and run sprints up and down the beach. Do 30 seconds on, one minute off, until the ten minutes are up. Classic beach sprints are also a dependable staple, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll need a partner for this, partly to steer the car and partly because you&amp;#8217;re going to need a rest. You&amp;#8217;ll also need a car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose a street or parking lot with a slight elevation. It shouldn&amp;#8217;t be such that you have to turn your wheels toward the curb when parking. In fact, it should be barely perceptible to the naked eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have your partner sit behind the wheel with the car in neutral, the engine off, and the parking break released. Get behind the back bumper, face the car, and push the car up the slight incline. I recommend around 20-30 yards depending on the weight/size of the car. Don&amp;#8217;t sprint it so much as walk it. Think of this as a test of your strength rather than something to throw yourself blindly upon. It&amp;#8217;ll be a grind. Take full steps and be sure to place your heel on the ground with each step. Take a minute to rest, then push the car back the other way, slightly downhill, only going twice the distance as the first run, and sprint. You&amp;#8217;ll find you go about twice as fast going downhill. It&amp;#8217;s a very different feeling than the grind-it-out sensation of the uphill push.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switch places with your partner and try to get another round of pushing in before the ten minutes is up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try not to throw up. And again, be extremely careful when attempting this challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Could You Carry Your Prepubescent Self?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgive the convoluted name, but it makes sense when you learn what the workout entails: carrying a weight equal to 1/3 to 1/2 your current bodyweight for a full ten minutes. Use a barbell loaded with the requisite weight, a heavy sandbag, or an actual prepubescent version of yourself. Carry it for ten minutes using any method desired; just don&amp;#8217;t put the weight down. Carry it on one shoulder, or both. Carry it in the front rack position, or placed on your traps. It doesn&amp;#8217;t matter, and variety is actually probably best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While merely standing there might seem like the easiest way to reach ten minutes, from my experience you&amp;#8217;ll end up focusing too much on the weight and get discouraged. Instead, try walking around. Be the crazy guy who walks around the neighborhood with a barbell. Walk around your yard. If you&amp;#8217;re game, throw in a few lunges and presses while you&amp;#8217;re at it. Just don&amp;#8217;t drop the weight until the ten minutes have passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a little more than ten minutes and access to the outdoors, might I recommend the &lt;a title="Outdoor Stamina" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S7FZMVLol7w" target="_blank"&gt;Outdoor Stamina&lt;/a&gt; workout?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s it, guys. Hope you&amp;#8217;re able to get some use out of these workouts. I definitely have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about you? What are your favorite ten minute go-to workouts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get the &lt;a title="Mark's Daily Apple Feeds" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/feeds/" target="_self"&gt;Primal Blueprint Fitness eBook, Free Health Tips and Primal Recipes&lt;/a&gt; Delivered to Your Inbox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/UZfy7FZnR4w" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/10-full-body-workouts-you-can-do-in-10-minutes-flat/#comments" thr:count="94" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/10-full-body-workouts-you-can-do-in-10-minutes-flat/feed/atom/" thr:count="94" />
		<thr:total>94</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make Turkey Jerky (That’s Super Easy and Tastes Like Thanksgiving)]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-make-turkey-jerky-thats-super-easy-and-tastes-like-thanksgiving/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35532</id>
		<updated>2013-03-18T22:00:02Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-19T15:00:18Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Recipes" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I&#8217;m pleased to have our friend David Maren of Tendergrass Farms pen today&#8217;s guest post. He’s written this great how-to for making your own delicious pastured turkey jerky. And don’t miss the coupon code that he’s generously provided below! Most folks who make turkey jerky just make beef jerky out of turkey. They tend to use [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-make-turkey-jerky-thats-super-easy-and-tastes-like-thanksgiving/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" alt="pic1 1" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/pic1-1.png" width="320" height="212" title="How to Make Turkey Jerky (That’s Super Easy and Tastes Like Thanksgiving)" /&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;#8217;m pleased to have our friend David Maren of &lt;a title="Tendergrass Farms" href="https://www.grassfedbeef.org/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tendergrass Farms&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; pen today&amp;#8217;s guest post. He’s written this great how-to for making your own delicious pastured turkey jerky. And don’t miss the coupon code that he’s generously provided below!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most folks who make turkey jerky just make beef jerky out of turkey. &lt;/strong&gt;They tend to use lots of teriyaki sauce, sugar, and Worcestershire sauce to mask the turkey-ness of the turkey. To each his own, but in my opinion this is a real shame. After all, turkey is super scrumptious! Especially if you go to the trouble of getting some good quality pastured turkey, you’ll want to preserve its essential turkey flavor as a special feature of your turkey jerky. We’ve discovered an extremely simple way to make delicious, high-protein, sugar-free, turkey jerky that will not only taste and look nothing like beef jerky, but will also magically transport you back to your childhood Thanksgiving dinner table. In fact, between you and me, I think it tastes a lot like buttery mashed potatoes and gravy. But no worries &amp;#8211; it’s about as primal as primal can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35532"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This recipe is the very pinnacle of culinary simplicity. You’ll need:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="pic2" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/pic2.png" width="540" height="361" title="How to Make Turkey Jerky (That’s Super Easy and Tastes Like Thanksgiving)" /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turkey breast&lt;/strong&gt;, at least about 2 LBS (preferably from a good pastured turkey)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Salt and pepper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An oven (no fancy dehydrator necessary)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few kabob skewers (or wooden chop sticks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothin’ else!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’ll take about 10 minutes of prep time and then the jerky will need to be in the oven for 6 to 10 hours&lt;/strong&gt; (depending on your oven and how thinly you cut the turkey strips).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="pic3" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/pic3.png" width="540" height="360" title="How to Make Turkey Jerky (That’s Super Easy and Tastes Like Thanksgiving)" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You should really think about supporting a family farmer by purchasing some decent pastured turkey breast to make your jerky with.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a title="Eat Wild" href="http://www.eatwild.com/products/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;EatWild.com&lt;/a&gt; has a helpful directory of grass-based farmers across the USA, Canada, and beyond that would love your support. If you can’t find any local pastured turkey sources our little cooperative online meats shop, Tendergrass Farms, offers &lt;a title="Organic Turkey Breast" href="http://www.grassfedbeef.org/beyond-Organic-Turkey-Breast.html" target="_blank"&gt;pastured turkey breast&lt;/a&gt; that we can ship right to your doorstep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In fact, in the spirit of family farm generosity, we’ve created a coupon code that’ll give you four (4) free jumbo boneless skinless roasts of our &lt;a title="Organic Turkey Breast" href="http://www.grassfedbeef.org/beyond-Organic-Turkey-Breast.html" target="_blank"&gt;pastured turkey breast&lt;/a&gt; with all orders over $199 (a $99.96 value), which will also qualify your order for &lt;a title="Shipping Info" href="http://www.grassfedbeef.org/Shipping-Info.html" target="_blank"&gt;Free Shipping&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Head over to the &lt;a title="Tendergrass Farms" href="http://www.grassfedbeef.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Tendergrass Farms&lt;/a&gt; site and once you’ve added $199 of our &lt;a title="Grass Fed Beef" href="http://www.grassfedbeef.org/Grass-Fed-Beef/" target="_blank"&gt;grass fed beef&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Organic Pork" href="http://www.grassfedbeef.org/Beyond-Organic-Pork/" target="_blank"&gt;pastured pork&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Organic Chicken" href="http://www.grassfedbeef.org/Beyond-Organic-Chicken/" target="_blank"&gt;pastured chicken&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a title="Organic Turkey" href="http://www.grassfedbeef.org/Beyond-Organic-Turkey/" target="_blank"&gt;pastured turkey&lt;/a&gt; to your cart, just view your cart and apply the coupon code &lt;strong&gt;FARMERS-RULE-123&lt;/strong&gt; and four 2 lb. pastured turkey breast roasts will be automatically added to your cart with a price of $0.00 (expires 9/30/13, limited to 150 redemptions). Pretty cool, huh? I guess we just figure what comes around goes around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;i&gt;If $199 sounds like a big first order just grab a couple friends from the gym and place an order together.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once you’ve procured some good turkey breast, the first step is to cut it into very thin slices.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;There’s no danger of cutting them too thin, so just get a nice sharp knife and cut the pieces as thinly as you can. It’s best to keep them as even in thickness as possible to help them dehydrate at the same rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="pic4" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/pic4.png" width="540" height="318" title="How to Make Turkey Jerky (That’s Super Easy and Tastes Like Thanksgiving)" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second step is to sprinkle the turkey strips with a little salt and pepper. &lt;/strong&gt;Salt and pepper the turkey just a little more than you would any other food that you were about to eat. The purpose of the salt and pepper is simply to bring out the natural flavor of the turkey, not to mummify it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="pic5" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/pic5.png" width="540" height="359" title="How to Make Turkey Jerky (That’s Super Easy and Tastes Like Thanksgiving)" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The third and final step is to skewer the strips of seasoned turkey with your kabob skewers (or wooden chop sticks) and hang the skewers from the upper rack of your oven. &lt;/strong&gt;Just make sure than the strips are spaced out well to allow the strips to evenly dehydrate. Turn your oven on to 200 ºF, but don’t quite close your oven door. It works well to stick a nice big wooden spoon or other similar object in the door of the oven to allow just an inch or so opening for the humidity to escape from the oven as the turkey dehydrates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="pic6 1" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/pic6-1.png" width="540" height="359" title="How to Make Turkey Jerky (That’s Super Easy and Tastes Like Thanksgiving)" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check on it periodically.&lt;/strong&gt; At 200 ºF, with the oven slightly cracked open, it may take anywhere from 6 to 10 hours. This depends entirely on the thickness of your turkey strips and your particular oven, so it could be slightly shorter or longer depending on those factors. When the strips are completely hard to the touch with no hint of soft raw meat texture, your jerky’s done! It’s best to keep it in zip-top bags in the freezer, especially if you don’t think you’ll eat it all within a week or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="pic1 1" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/pic1-1.png" width="540" height="359" title="How to Make Turkey Jerky (That’s Super Easy and Tastes Like Thanksgiving)" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;David Maren is a husband, father, farmer, and co-founder of &lt;/i&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a title="Tendergrass Farms" href="https://www.grassfedbeef.org/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tendergrass Farms&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;i&gt;. Tendergrass Farms is a cooperative online grass fed meats shop that exists as a bridge between the often geographically isolated family farmer and committed grass fed meats enthusiasts like yourself. The &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a title="About Us" href="http://www.grassfedbeef.org/About-Us.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tendergrass Farms vision&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; is to sustain family farms through making it easy for you to purchase their meats by taking advantage of appropriate technology and ultra-efficient transportation models that enable their meats to be shipped to fans all around the USA. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;If you’re not already a huge fan of Tendergrass Farms, you’re missing out: Go bookmark &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a title="Tendergrass Farms" href="http://www.grassfedbeef.org" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;their site&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;, like their &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a title="Facebook: Tendergrass Farms" href="http://www.facebook.com/tendergrass" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Facebook page&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;, and &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a title="Twitter: Tendergrass Farms" href="http://www.twitter.com/tendergrassfed" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;follow them on Twitter&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/B9d9M5sPXRY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-make-turkey-jerky-thats-super-easy-and-tastes-like-thanksgiving/#comments" thr:count="72" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-make-turkey-jerky-thats-super-easy-and-tastes-like-thanksgiving/feed/atom/" thr:count="72" />
		<thr:total>72</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Mark: Brain Caloric Expenditure, Muscle Preservation, Potassium, and Iron Supplements]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/brain-caloric-expenditure-muscle-preservation-potassium-iron-supplements/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=34928</id>
		<updated>2013-03-17T22:00:03Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-18T15:00:36Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Dear Mark" /><category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Supplements" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For today&#8217;s edition of Dear Mark, I&#8217;m covering four of your questions. First up is a question from Rachel, an English major who finds herself growing ravenous once exam time rolls around. I discuss whether or not her increased cognitive activity is increasing the amount of fuel her brain is burning through, and whether this [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/brain-caloric-expenditure-muscle-preservation-potassium-iron-supplements/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" alt="thinking" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/thinking.jpg" width="320" height="212" title="Dear Mark: Brain Caloric Expenditure, Muscle Preservation, Potassium, and Iron Supplements" /&gt;For today&amp;#8217;s edition of &lt;a title="Dear Mark" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/category/dear-mark/"&gt;Dear Mark&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;m covering four of your questions. First up is a question from Rachel, an English major who finds herself growing ravenous once exam time rolls around. I discuss whether or not her increased cognitive activity is increasing the amount of fuel her brain is burning through, and whether this affects her hunger. Next I provide a few tips to a young athlete who&amp;#8217;s injured and has to rest, but doesn&amp;#8217;t want to lose any muscle mass or curtail his fitness pursuits in the process. Luckily, there are a few dietary modifications he can make to preserve that lean mass. Third, I discuss the importance of potassium. It plays a few vital roles in the maintenance of our health, and if you want enough, you&amp;#8217;ll have to consume some plants. Finally, I field a question from a woman who&amp;#8217;s worried about iron supplementation. She&amp;#8217;s not doing it, thinks she might need it, and wants my take on the subject. I explain why it&amp;#8217;s probably better to get your iron from food, rather than supplements &amp;#8211; which may do more harm than good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-34928"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I LOVE your site!!! I&amp;#8217;ve been reading it for a while, but just made the change from a CW &amp;#8220;healthy&amp;#8221; diet to a primal one this past October and I&amp;#8217;m NEVER looking back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My question is this: I&amp;#8217;m a college student, and I always get SUPER HUNGRY during exams. I&amp;#8217;m an English major, so exam time actually usually means LESS stress and MORE sleep for me since papers and readings are finished. Does studying intensely actually increase your fuel demand?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rachel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our brains are incredible energy hogs, making up only 2% of our body mass while using up about 20% of the energy we take in. So during a period of heavy thinking, say, finals week, you&amp;#8217;d expect the energy demands to increase and our overall caloric intake to follow. It seems like that should be the case, but the evidence is mixed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a title="Cerebral metabolic effects of a verbal fluency test: a PET scan study." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/3265709" target="_blank"&gt;one study&lt;/a&gt;, subjects performing a verbal fluency test increased the cerebral glucose metabolic rate by 23% (for the duration of the test) compared to the resting control group. Subjects who did better on the test burned less glucose, probably because their brains were more efficient at performing the task. Oddly enough, this other &lt;a title="Evaluation of a “mental effort” hypothesis for correlations between cortical metabolism and intelligence ☆" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0160289695900179" target="_blank"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; found that high aptitude subjects (people for whom the tasks were easier) used more glucose than lower aptitude subjects (people for whom the tasks were more difficult). Clearly, it&amp;#8217;s not quite as simple as &amp;#8220;hard task = more fuel required.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another &lt;a title="Cognitive demand and blood glucose." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11495663" target="_blank"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; found that a period of &amp;#8220;intense cognitive processing&amp;#8221; led to measurably lower levels of blood glucose than a period of resting, indicating that actively using your brain burns more glucose than not using it. In one of my favorite books, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a title="Amazon.com: Why Zebras Don't Get Ulcers" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0006SHMIO/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=marsdaiapp07-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399373&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0006SHMIO" target="_blank"&gt;Why Zebras Don&amp;#8217;t Get Ulcers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;Robert Sapolsky notes that top chess players engaged in intense competition often have metabolic requirements similar to top athletes during training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walking, which uses fuel, has been shown to improve cognition. And I don&amp;#8217;t mean walking regularly makes you smarter through a training effect (&lt;a title="Physical Activity, Including Walking, and Cognitive Function in Older Women FREE" href="http://jama.jamanetwork.com/article.aspx?articleid=199487" target="_blank"&gt;although that&amp;#8217;s also true!&lt;/a&gt;); I mean that walking &lt;a title="The effect of acute treadmill walking on cognitive control and academic achievement in preadolescent children." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19356688" target="_blank"&gt;improves your brain function immediately&lt;/a&gt;. If improving brain function were as simple as increasing glucose availability, this shouldn&amp;#8217;t happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not totally convinced that mental tasks have no effect on fuel consumption. I think part of it is that recreating the frantic mental atmosphere of finals week can&amp;#8217;t really be replicated in a lab setting. One to two hour studies where subjects are being paid to memorize numbers or colors or perform &amp;#8220;arduous&amp;#8221; mental tasks just don&amp;#8217;t measure up to the reality of studying as if your future depends on it (it probably doesn&amp;#8217;t, but it sure does feel like it!) for a week straight. The Sapolsky mention of chess players&amp;#8217; metabolic demands lends credence to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s also the stress component. You say you&amp;#8217;re not very stressed out because you&amp;#8217;re getting plenty of &lt;a title="17 Ways to Improve Your Sleep" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/17-ways-to-improve-your-sleep/#axzz26gx2mK1P"&gt;sleep&lt;/a&gt; and don&amp;#8217;t have to worry about papers, but studying for an exam &amp;#8211; or multiple exams &amp;#8211; is generally not a pleasant, enjoyable experience. Watching a gripping documentary or reading a great novel? It&amp;#8217;s stimulating and requires brain activity, but it&amp;#8217;s ultimately experienced as a pleasurable encounter, and you don&amp;#8217;t leave the theater exhausted or the library starving. Scary movies, on the other hand, &lt;a title="Scare yourself thin: horror movies help burn calories, study finds" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/2012/oct/29/horror-movies-help-burn-calories" target="_blank"&gt;do increase caloric output&lt;/a&gt;, probably because they are slightly stressful. By definition, studying for the big exam is placing stress on your system, and the body responds by increasing &lt;a title="The Definitive Guide to Stress, Cortisol and the Adrenals" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/cortisol/"&gt;cortisol&lt;/a&gt;, adrenaline, and turning on a bunch of physiological processes which burn through fuel reserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is that if studying is making you hungrier than normal, studying is increasing your fuel demand, whether it&amp;#8217;s because of increased &lt;a title="The Physical Toll of Negative Emotions" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-physical-toll-of-negative-emotions/"&gt;stress&lt;/a&gt;, increased metabolic demand by the brain, or both. Maybe you forgot to eat. Whatever the cause, you should probably eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi Mark,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an 18 year old male from Australia who regularly competes in middle-distance athletics (800-3000m) events, but recently rendered sedentary with a painful varicocele. In order to best maintain muscle mass and CV fitness should I up my fats, limit any carbohydrates, and up protein? What do you think are the most essential foods/drinks for fitness maintenance whilst completely inactive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks a lot,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jonny&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry to hear it &amp;#8211; that&amp;#8217;s tough. I know &lt;a title="My Knee is Killing Me… No, Really. " href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/paleo-lifespan/"&gt;how hard it is to sit out&lt;/a&gt;, and I have a few bits of advice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to retaining lean body mass while on bed rest, &lt;a title="Protecting muscle mass and function in older adults during bed rest." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19898232" target="_blank"&gt;protein is king&lt;/a&gt;. Try to get a gram of &lt;a title="Dear Mark: How Much Protein Can You Absorb and Use from One Meal?   " href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/dear-mark-how-much-protein-can-you-absorb-and-use-from-one-meal/#axzz2NYbNzEmI"&gt;protein&lt;/a&gt; per pound of lean body mass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might also look into branched chain amino acids (&lt;a title="Dear Mark: Superfoods, BCAAs and Fasted Training, Hot Sauce, and Three More Questions" href="https://www.marksdailyapple.com/superfoods-bcaas-and-fasted-training-hot-sauce/"&gt;BCAAs&lt;/a&gt;), which &lt;a title="Attenuation of the protein wasting associated with bed rest by branched-chain amino acids." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17684207" target="_blank"&gt;have been shown&lt;/a&gt; to attenuate the loss of lean body mass and protein wastage during bed rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try not to restrict calories too much. Since you&amp;#8217;ll be inactive, your needs will probably be lower, but dropping them even further will only &lt;a title="Calorie restriction accelerates the catabolism of lean body mass during 2 wk of bed rest." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17684207" target="_blank"&gt;speed up the catabolic process&lt;/a&gt; and cause you to lose even more lean mass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, just keep eating nutrient-dense food. You probably won&amp;#8217;t be as hungry as usual, so make sure you&amp;#8217;re not &amp;#8220;wasting&amp;#8221; your calories on junk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there&amp;#8217;s not much you can do to maintain your cardiovascular fitness while doing absolutely nothing. The good news, however, is twofold: keeping as much lean mass as possible and being a young guy will help you bounce back faster. You won&amp;#8217;t lose much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Mark,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve have begun to use FitDay to ensure I&amp;#8217;m getting all my essential vitamins and minerals. It seems I&amp;#8217;m consistently low in potassium (around 80% RDA). My diet consists entirely of meats, seafood, veggies (mostly raw), nuts, and berries (every other day). I&amp;#8217;ve been cramming veggies to make up the imbalance. Is this what I should be doing? Perhaps the RDA is higher than I need on this diet? Or should I consider a supplement?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mark in DC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That sounds like a solid, healthy diet, for the most part. However, if you&amp;#8217;re coming up short on potassium, you probably want to take care of that. Potassium is a very important mineral, performing a range of functions in the body:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It regulates blood pressure, with some &lt;a title="The importance of potassium in managing hypertension." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21403995" target="_blank"&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt; even showing that it&amp;#8217;s more important in the fight against hypertension than sodium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potassium regulates the excretion of calcium in the urine, which is probably why its consumption is &lt;a title="The effects of high potassium consumption on bone mineral density in a prospective cohort study of elderly postmenopausal women." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18575949" target="_blank"&gt;associated with high bone mineral density&lt;/a&gt;. More potassium, less bone in your pee. You don&amp;#8217;t want to urinate bone, do you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans also aren&amp;#8217;t very good at preserving potassium &lt;a title="Relationship and Interaction between Sodium and Potassium" href="http://www.jacn.org/content/25/suppl_3/262S.full" target="_blank"&gt;in a state of deficiency&lt;/a&gt;, which indicates to me that we likely evolved in a dietary environment where potassium-rich plants were readily available. It also indicates that potassium is a crucial micronutrient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considerable evidence exists that it&amp;#8217;s not the absolute amounts of potassium or sodium that are so important, but rather the &lt;a title="Study Finds Sodium-Potassium Ratio Strongly Tied to Mortality and CV Disease" href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/larryhusten/2011/07/12/study-finds-sodium-potassium-ratio-strongly-tied-to-mortality-and-cv-disease/" target="_blank"&gt;potassium:sodium ratio&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; &lt;a title="Association of urinary sodium/potassium ratio with blood pressure: sex and racial differences." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22114147" target="_blank"&gt;particularly in men&lt;/a&gt;. Track your sodium intake for a week. Shoot for around three to four times as much potassium as sodium, but preferably more than that. Bonus of eating more potassium? You can eat more salt &lt;a title="Hemodynamic and endocrine changes associated with potassium supplementation in sodium-loaded hypertensives." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/6373586?dopt=Abstract" target="_blank"&gt;without negatively affecting your blood pressure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the usual potassium-rich suspects (spinach, &lt;a title="A Visual Guide to Yams and Sweet Potatoes (plus How They Fit Into a Primal Eating Plan)" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/difference-yams-sweet-potatoes/"&gt;sweet potatoes&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a title="Is Samwise Gamgee Right About Potatoes?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/paleo-potatoes/"&gt;potatoes&lt;/a&gt;, avocados, bananas, most &lt;a title="Top 9 Most Important Foods to Buy Organic" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/top-9-most-important-foods-to-buy-organic/"&gt;plant foods&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a title="Dairy and Its Effect on Insulin Secretion (and What It Means for Your Waistline)" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/dairy-insulin/"&gt;dairy&lt;/a&gt; products like yogurt are surprisingly high in potassium. &lt;em&gt;If&lt;/em&gt; you do dairy, consider adding a cup or two of dairy a day. Fresh meat also has potassium, but we end up cooking most of it out. Consume your meat on the rarer side, or toss it into stews and soups, and you&amp;#8217;ll consume more potassium that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Should women eating a Primal Blueprint diet and taking your damage control supplements take additional iron supplementation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for all you do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;S.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably not. Iron supplements have a &lt;a title="Dietary fortificant iron intake is negatively associated with quality of life in patients with mildly active inflammatory bowel disease " href="http://www.nutritionandmetabolism.com/content/10/1/9/abstract" target="_blank"&gt;generally poor track record&lt;/a&gt;, which is partially why I kept them out of my supplements. They have a history of &lt;a title="Intravenous iron sucrose versus oral iron supplementation for the treatment of iron deficiency anemia in patients with inflammatory bowel disease--a randomized, controlled, open-label, multicenter study." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16279906" target="_blank"&gt;exacerbating gastrointestinal distress&lt;/a&gt;, and, if you don&amp;#8217;t actually have a need for supplementary iron, iron overload. Having too much iron is associated with &lt;a title="Newly recognized causes of atherosclerosis: the role of microorganisms and of vascular iron overload." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/8201257" target="_blank"&gt;atherosclerosis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Increase in type II collagen turnover after iron depletion in patients with hereditary haemochromatosis." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20097904" target="_blank"&gt;cartilage degeneration&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Iron in fatty liver and in the metabolic syndrome: a promising therapeutic target." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21718726" target="_blank"&gt;fatty liver&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Body iron stores and heme-iron intake in relation to risk of type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22848554" target="_blank"&gt;type 2 diabetes&lt;/a&gt; and a host of other maladies. Among anemic women, &lt;a title="Oral iron supplementation leads to oxidative imbalance in anemic women: a prospective study." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20888091" target="_blank"&gt;iron supplementation increases oxidative stress&lt;/a&gt; even as it corrects the anemia, making &amp;#8220;blind supplementation&amp;#8221; all the more dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, there are so many easy ways to obtain iron from your diet, particularly one of the Primal variety. Eating meat, even &lt;a title="A randomized controlled trial in young women of the effects of consuming pork meat or iron supplements on nutritional status and feeling of well-being. " href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23204154" target="_blank"&gt;one that isn&amp;#8217;t particularly famous for its iron content like pork&lt;/a&gt;, is as good as or better than iron supplements at repleting iron stores &lt;a title="Heme iron-based dietary intervention for improvement of iron status in young women." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22951158" target="_blank"&gt;with fewer side effects&lt;/a&gt;. Something like beef, lamb, or &lt;a title="6 Sneaky Ways to Work Offal Into Your Diet" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/6-sneaky-ways-to-work-offal-into-your-diet/"&gt;organ meats&lt;/a&gt; will be even better sources of iron (in addition to tons of other important micronutrients like zinc and vitamin A).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you worry about iron, figure out if you even have an iron issue. Get a full iron panel done, and be sure to test for ferritin (the storage form of iron). Only then should you explore actively increasing your iron intake, whether by food or supplementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, guys. Take care and &lt;a title="What Does it Mean to Grok on?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/what-does-it-mean-to-grok-on/"&gt;Grok on!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grab &lt;a title="The Primal Blueprint Cookbook" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/The-Primal-Blueprint-Cookbook.html" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Blueprint Cookbook&lt;/a&gt; Today and Receive Free S&amp;amp;H and a Free Primal Blueprint Poster&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/stAuw_xm-uA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/brain-caloric-expenditure-muscle-preservation-potassium-iron-supplements/#comments" thr:count="42" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/brain-caloric-expenditure-muscle-preservation-potassium-iron-supplements/feed/atom/" thr:count="42" />
		<thr:total>42</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekend Link Love]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/weekend-link-love-234/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35551</id>
		<updated>2013-03-17T20:51:54Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-17T15:00:21Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Health" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Registration for the 2013 Ancestral Health Symposium in Atlanta is now open to the general public. Check your schedule, move some things around if you have to, just get there because it&#8217;s going to be another amazing weekend. Big thanks to my buddy Flavio, who shot me for this article in Brazil&#8217;s largest newspaper. Flavio [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/weekend-link-love-234/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" alt="chain 1" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/chain-1.jpg" width="320" height="282" title="Weekend Link Love" /&gt;Registration for the &lt;a title=" Ancestral Health Society" href="http://www.ancestryfoundation.org/ahs13.html" target="_blank"&gt;2013 Ancestral Health Symposium&lt;/a&gt; in Atlanta is &lt;a title="2013 Ancestral Health Symposium" href="http://ahs13.eventbrite.com/" target="_blank"&gt;now open&lt;/a&gt; to the general public. Check your schedule, move some things around if you have to, just get there because it&amp;#8217;s going to be another amazing weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000; font-family: Arial; font-size: small;"&gt;Big thanks to my buddy Flavio, who shot me for &lt;a title="Dieta 'paleolítica' prega hábitos primitivos e atrai famosos nos EUA" href="http://www1.folha.uol.com.br/serafina/1234510-dieta-paleolitica-prega-habitos-primitivos-e-atrai-famosos-nos-eua.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; in Brazil&amp;#8217;s largest newspaper. Flavio &lt;a title="Leaf Wedding Photography" href="http://leafweddingphotography.com/" target="_blank"&gt;specializes in weddings&lt;/a&gt; in the SoCal area.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Research of the Week&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How night owls &lt;a title="Evening Types Are At Higher Risk of Most Things" href="http://www.drsharma.ca/evening-types-are-at-higher-risk-of-most-things.html" target="_blank"&gt;are at greater risk for&lt;/a&gt;, well, pretty much everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dogs are Primal, confirmed. The first domesticated dog was around at least &lt;a title="Ancient DNA Analysis Affirms the Canid from Altai as a Primitive Dog" href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0057754" target="_blank"&gt;33,000 years ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35551"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In rats, &lt;a title="Intense Sweetness Surpasses Cocaine Reward" href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info:doi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0000698" target="_blank"&gt;intense sweetness hits the reward center of the brain&lt;/a&gt; harder than medical-grade cocaine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another study &lt;a title="Meat consumption and diet quality and mortality in NHANES III" href="http://www.nature.com/ejcn/journal/vaop/ncurrent/abs/ejcn201359a.html" target="_blank"&gt;fails to find&lt;/a&gt; an association between meat (even the processed stuff) and mortality. I eagerly await the torrential flood of articles reporting the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Interesting Blog Posts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all hear how important it is to shut out the chatter and be in the here and now. Here&amp;#8217;s how to &lt;a title="Mind The Gap: How To Clear Mind Chatter &amp;amp; Be In The Now" href="http://app4mind.com/level-2-thinking/" target="_blank"&gt;actually go about doing it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do paleo or ancestral diets cause gout? Chris Kresser &lt;a title="Will Eating a Paleo Diet Cause Gout?" href="http://chriskresser.com/will-eating-a-paleo-diet-cause-gout" target="_blank"&gt;explores the topic&lt;/a&gt;. (Short answer: no).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Media, Schmedia&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the &lt;a title="Allan Savory: How to green the desert and reverse climate change" href="http://www.ted.com/talks/allan_savory_how_to_green_the_world_s_deserts_and_reverse_climate_change.html" target="_blank"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; every vegan (and heck, every person who&amp;#8217;s ever looked down their nose at someone for the effect of &amp;#8220;all that meat eating&amp;#8221; on the environment) needs to watch. Twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to watch the first &lt;a title="STATIN NATION (First 13 mins)" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ry1Z8buyd8I&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be" target="_blank"&gt;13 minutes&lt;/a&gt; of the upcoming documentary S&lt;i&gt;tatin Nation: The Great Cholesterol Cover-up.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Everything Else&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a title="The Mechanics of the Pull-Up (and Why Women Can Absolutely Do Them)" href="http://blogs.scientificamerican.com/guest-blog/2013/03/14/the-mechanics-of-the-pull-up-and-why-women-can-absolutely-do-them/" target="_blank"&gt;physics of the pullup&lt;/a&gt; (plus, why women &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How the pharmaceutical industry &lt;a title="The Environmental Impact of the Pharmaceuticals Industry" href="http://www.kwikmed.org/environmental-impact-pharmaceutical-industry/" target="_blank"&gt;affects the environment&lt;/a&gt;, and why you should dispose of pharmaceuticals properly (my particular favorite method is never needing them in the first place).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Recipe Corner&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember Nacho Rubio? He&amp;#8217;s back, &lt;a title="Baked Veggies by Nacho Rubio (subs Español)" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mn2yU40Q3CI" target="_blank"&gt;in vlog form&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fusion of Western and Eastern tradition: &lt;a title="Recipe: Chai Tea Infused Marble Easter Eggs" href="http://realfoodforager.com/recipe-chai-tea-infused-marble-easter-eggs/" target="_blank"&gt;chai-infused marble Easter eggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Time Capsule&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One year ago (Mar 17 – Mar 23)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="Detaching Yourself From the Outcome" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/detaching-yourself-from-the-outcome/"&gt;Detaching Yourself From the Outcome&lt;/a&gt; – Outcomes are nice and all when they go your way, but things get a whole lot more pleasant when you stop worrying about them so much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="12 Tools That Can Help You Achieve Your Health and Fitness Goals   " href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/12-tools-that-can-help-you-achieve-your-health-and-fitness-goals/"&gt;12 Tools That Can Help You Achieve Your Health and Fitness Goals&lt;/a&gt; – Check out these online tools to help you get to where you need and want to be &amp;#8211; health and fitness-wise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Comment of the Week&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’m pretty sure white bread buns, strange goopy seed oil sauces, and french fries all play their role, too.” – don’t forget the tomato jam!! &lt;img alt="icon smile" src="http://cdn.marksdailyapple.com/wordpress/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" title="Weekend Link Love" /&gt; that’s my personal pet peeve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- &amp;#8220;Tomato jam.&amp;#8221; I &lt;a title="Dear Mark: Is Meat Going to Kill Me (Again)?  " href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/processed-meat-death-mortality-study/#comments"&gt;like&lt;/a&gt; it! I think I&amp;#8217;ll have to start using that one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get All Three Primal Cookbooks, an Apron and More in &lt;a title="The Primal Blueprint Chef Kit" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/The-Primal-Blueprint-Chef-Kit.html" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Blueprint Chef Kit&lt;/a&gt; Today!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/UNhKmda7djM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/weekend-link-love-234/#comments" thr:count="44" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/weekend-link-love-234/feed/atom/" thr:count="44" />
		<thr:total>44</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Worker Bee</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Chicken in Buttery Caper Sauce]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/chicken-in-buttery-caper-sauce/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35526</id>
		<updated>2013-03-13T23:45:54Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-16T15:00:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Recipes" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The star of this recipe is a simple sauce with bold, memorable flavor. Three easy ingredients &#8211; capers, parsley, butter &#8211; plus one secret ingredient (the brine from the caper jar) come together into a rich and piquant sauce that will have you licking the plate. The caper sauce pairs really well with chicken; in [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/chicken-in-buttery-caper-sauce/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" title="Chicken in Buttery Caper Sauce" alt="CaperChicken2" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/CaperChicken2.jpg" width="320" height="240" /&gt;The star of this recipe is a simple sauce with bold, memorable flavor. Three easy ingredients &amp;#8211; capers, parsley, &lt;a title="Is All Butter Created Equal?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/grass-fed-butter/#axzz2NLvDZw6t"&gt;butter&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; plus one secret ingredient (the brine from the caper jar) come together into a rich and piquant sauce that will have you licking the plate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The caper sauce pairs really well with chicken; in this case, boneless, skinless breasts pounded thin to reduce the cooking time to just 6 minutes. However, if you have a little more time on your hands the sauce can certainly be served with thicker skin-on breasts or thighs, a pork chop or tenderloin, a pan-seared fillet of fish or roasted vegetables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35526"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiny, briny capers are actually flower buds that have been sun-dried and pickled in vinegar. The tart, lemony flavor of capers adds a bright, tangy boost to food. Keep a jar in the fridge (they never really seem to go bad) to throw into other dishes or to make this fantastic sauce whenever the mood strikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serves:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time in the Kitchen&lt;/strong&gt;: 30 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="ingredients 54" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/ingredients-54.jpg" width="540" height="360" title="Chicken in Buttery Caper Sauce" /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 boneless, skinless chicken breasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 tablespoons olive oil (60ml)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons of capers, plus 3 tablespoons of brine from the jar (45 ml)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons unsalted butter (60 g)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/3 cup finely chopped parsley (80 ml)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instructions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slice each chicken breast in half horizontally. Place each half between sheets of plastic wrap and pound with a meat mallet (or small skillet) until 1/4 inch (6 mm) thick or less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="Step1 4" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/Step1-4.jpg" width="540" height="405" title="Chicken in Buttery Caper Sauce" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generously season chicken with salt and pepper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a large skillet heat 2 tablespoons (30 ml) of olive oil. Add half of the chicken and cook for 3 minutes on each side until nicely browned. Remove the chicken from the skillet and set aside on a plate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="Step2 4" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/Step2-4.jpg" width="540" height="363" title="Chicken in Buttery Caper Sauce" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat 2 more tablespoons of olive oil. Add the remaining raw chicken and brown for 3 minutes on each side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove the chicken from the pan, adding it to the plate of cooked chicken, but keep the heat on under the skillet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the skillet, add 3 tablespoons of brine from the jar of capers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="capers" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/capers.jpg" width="540" height="360" title="Chicken in Buttery Caper Sauce" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the brine boils, scrape up any bits of meat stuck to the pan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stir in the butter, parsley and capers. Just before the butter begins to brown, add the chicken and any juices that have accumulated on the plate back to the skillet. Keep the chicken in the skillet just long enough to re-heat it and coat the breasts in sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="Step3" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/Step3.jpg" width="540" height="360" title="Chicken in Buttery Caper Sauce" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serve immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="CaperChicken1" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/CaperChicken1.jpg" width="540" height="349" title="Chicken in Buttery Caper Sauce" /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get All Three Primal Cookbooks, an Apron and More in &lt;a title="The Primal Blueprint Chef Kit" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/The-Primal-Blueprint-Chef-Kit.html" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Blueprint Chef Kit&lt;/a&gt; Today!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/2t_zaHZm2Qw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/chicken-in-buttery-caper-sauce/#comments" thr:count="47" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/chicken-in-buttery-caper-sauce/feed/atom/" thr:count="47" />
		<thr:total>47</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[It Will Pass and I Will Be Stronger]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/it-will-pass-and-i-will-be-stronger/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35457</id>
		<updated>2013-03-06T04:41:10Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-15T15:00:55Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Success Stories" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s Friday, everyone! And that means another Primal Blueprint Real Life Story from a Mark&#8217;s Daily Apple reader. If you have your own success story and would like to share it with me and the Mark’s Daily Apple community please contact me here. I’ll continue to publish these each Friday as long as they keep [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/it-will-pass-and-i-will-be-stronger/">&lt;div class="breakout"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s Friday, everyone! And that means another &lt;a title="Success Stories" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/category/success-story-summaries/"&gt;Primal Blueprint Real Life Story&lt;/a&gt; from a Mark&amp;#8217;s Daily Apple reader. If you have your own success story and would like to share it with me and the Mark’s Daily Apple community please contact me &lt;a title="Contact Me!" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-book/share-success-story/" target="_self"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I’ll continue to publish these each Friday as long as they keep coming in. Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" title="Primal Blueprint Real Life Story" alt="real life stories stories 1 2" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA2009/real_life_stories_stories-1-2.jpg" width="320" height="240" /&gt;Dear Mark,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been completely Primal for just over a year, and working towards that for almost three years. It has changed my life from feeling like I was living in an unlit and windowless room, to really participating in life and finding fulfillment. It&amp;#8217;s been that dramatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was an active, healthy kid with a good diet until I was twelve. My home life became very unstable. I was moved around a lot, and lived with several different relatives and attended different schools. It was hard on me. I was a very introverted kid to begin with, and I didn&amp;#8217;t make friends. I read books and did homework and ate. I quickly became very sedentary, and very sad, and I had access to a lot of processed, sugary foods that my mother had never kept in my childhood home. I was given a lot of autonomy over my diet, and I quickly became addicted to these foods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35457"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/image.jpeg" width="540" height="540" title="It Will Pass and I Will Be Stronger" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I was 16, I weighed 240 lbs at 5&amp;#8217;7&amp;#8243; and I was extremely depressed, bulimic and very unhealthy, with bad skin. That was the year I was also diagnosed with PCOS, an explanation for my painful, irregular periods and other symptoms. I tried to lose weight by restricting calories, but when I was depressed I would care less about my long-term health than my need for something comforting to eat. So I would binge, and feel guilty, and purge, and my bulimia got worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/image_1.jpeg" width="540" height="540" title="It Will Pass and I Will Be Stronger" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I was 18 and living on my own, I was very sick. I was binging and purging more or less all day long, sometimes close to ten times a day. I remember feeling very scared the first time I threw up and had blood start pouring like water from my nose. I was more scared to stop throwing up, though. I wasn&amp;#8217;t having periods at all, but occasionally I would go to the bathroom and find that there was nothing but blood in the toilet. That scared me, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was 20, living alone and in college, my depression and bulimia continued, and I also started drinking, alone, most nights. The nights I didn&amp;#8217;t drink alcohol, I would do other drugs. I also started smoking. Once I was intoxicated, I would go out for a walk, alone, in my very bad neighborhood at three in the morning. I would occasionally get bursts of energy, and in one such burst, I got a new roommate, a new job, and I joined a community group. Then I was assaulted by someone I thought was my friend. I felt like my depression was a black hole sucking me in, that my life would just feel worse and worse until I died. I wanted so badly to die, but I was afraid to kill myself. I was hoping, I think, that the world would take care of it for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was 22, I had another one of these moments when my depression lifted. I bought a gym membership this time. I started going all the time, I would use the gym sometimes, and run on the treadmill. I wanted to know what to do at the gym, so I was looking at lots of online resources. I found &lt;a title="Nerd Fitness" href="http://nerdfitness.com" target="_blank"&gt;nerdfitness.com&lt;/a&gt;, and through them, I found Mark&amp;#8217;s Daily Apple. I remembered that a customer at my old job had, a couple of times, mentioned that he ate a caveman diet, but I hadn&amp;#8217;t cared to look into it at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I did read about eating like a caveman, it resonated with me. I had started learning how to cook, and I was enjoying it, so the idea of a diet made of whole, unprocessed ingredients appealed to the chef in me. I love reading about science, so the more I read, the more it appealed to me, and the more Primal principles I started to apply to my own life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found that not counting calories and not throwing up was nerve-wracking. I gained weight at first, started purging again. I stopped weighing myself. The better my diet gets, the less I get an urge to binge. With no binging, I don&amp;#8217;t purge. I slip up once in a while, but those incidents are getting further and further apart. I also got a physical job that I love: working in the produce department at the grocery store. I lost a lot of weight. My high weight was around 290 lbs, and now I weigh between 155 and 165 lbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/image_3.jpeg" width="540" height="405" title="It Will Pass and I Will Be Stronger" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My depression started to lift even more after I eliminated grains and sugar from my diet. Within 3 months I could feel a major shift. I no longer had long periods of apathy and hopelessness interrupted by the occasional &amp;#8220;good month.&amp;#8221; I now feel very calm and still inside. I feel tethered, and even when I do get sad (because it&amp;#8217;s got to rain sometimes), it no longer feels like I&amp;#8217;m getting sucked into a black hole of depression. It will pass, and I&amp;#8217;ll be stronger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am stronger. I get stronger all the time, and calmer, and happier. That&amp;#8217;s what keeps me doing this caveman gig. I&amp;#8217;m so strong, in fact, that this spring I&amp;#8217;m leaving on an adventure, I&amp;#8217;m going to walk across the USA, from my home on Vancouver Island, to my parents&amp;#8217; home in Connecticut!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for giving me the tools I needed to save myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/image_2.jpeg" width="540" height="405" title="It Will Pass and I Will Be Stronger" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lindsey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grab a Copy of &lt;a title="Amazon.com: The Primal Connection" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0984755101/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=marsdaiapp07-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0984755101" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Connection: Follow Your Genetic Blueprint to Health and Happiness&lt;/a&gt; Today!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/bVnf5Ya8944" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/it-will-pass-and-i-will-be-stronger/#comments" thr:count="162" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/it-will-pass-and-i-will-be-stronger/feed/atom/" thr:count="162" />
		<thr:total>162</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[How Simplifying Your Life Can Help You Refocus on What&#8217;s Important]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-simplifying-your-life-can-help-you-refocus-on-whats-important/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35538</id>
		<updated>2013-03-14T06:09:33Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-14T15:00:14Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Personal Improvement" /><category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Worker Bees' Weekly Bites" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this week I ran across a study that demonstrated a “simple lifestyle” can decrease our contact with toxic endocrine disrupting chemicals. The researchers looked at lifestyle elements like transportation, personal care products, and homegrown versus purchased food in their participants. I was struck by the study’s suggestion itself but also by the larger metaphoric [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-simplifying-your-life-can-help-you-refocus-on-whats-important/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" alt="simplicity" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/simplicity.jpg" width="320" height="212" title="How Simplifying Your Life Can Help You Refocus on Whats Important" /&gt;Earlier this week I ran across a &lt;a title="Lifestyle behaviors associated with exposures to endocrine disruptors" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0161813X12001313 " target="_blank"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; that demonstrated a “simple lifestyle” can decrease our contact with toxic endocrine disrupting chemicals. The researchers looked at lifestyle elements like transportation, personal care products, and homegrown versus purchased food in their participants. I was struck by the study’s suggestion itself but also by the larger metaphoric significance. A simpler code of life can spare us some of the inherent &lt;a title="The Definitive Guide to Stress, Cortisol, and the Adrenals: When ‘Fight or Flight’ Meets the Modern World" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/cortisol/"&gt;stress&lt;/a&gt; and damage of our modern lives. As this study showed, the principle certainly holds for physical health, and I easily venture it holds for mental well-being, too. Living simply offers a multi-layered protective benefit. That’s worth taking apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35538"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heart of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a title="The Primal Blueprint - Paperback Edition" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/The-Primal-Blueprint%3A-Updated-and-Expanded-%28Paperback-Edition%29.html" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Blueprint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, as broadly applicable as it is for many people, is pretty simple, but &lt;strong&gt;I wonder how and when it inspires simplicity itself&lt;/strong&gt;. We simplify our food by choosing fresh options based on what our ancestors ate for tens of thousands of years. We simplify our fitness by letting go of the need to follow every &amp;#8220;latest and greatest, end-all&amp;#8221; fad and just adopt &lt;a title="How to Succeed with the Primal Blueprint" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-succeed-with-the-primal-blueprint/#fitness"&gt;some easy Primal movement principles&lt;/a&gt;. We simplify our priorities by putting a premium on &lt;a title="The Definitive Guide to Sleep" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-definitive-guide-to-sleep/#axzz26gx2mK1P"&gt;sleep&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Forest Bathing" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/forest-bathing/#axzz23HTckodo"&gt;outdoor time&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a title="Social Wellness, or Why Friendship Should Be a Health Priority" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/social-wellness-health-research/#axzz28IRjCiwj"&gt;social connections&lt;/a&gt;. In many ways, it’s kind of about getting back to basics &amp;#8211; ancestral style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do all this, of course, while we live in a culture that loves to complicate. In fact, we moderns have an uncanny way of making life difficult for ourselves. We stay up late, eat crap, guzzle caffeine, and wonder why we crash and recover multiple times a day. We surround ourselves with so many “things,” &lt;a title="Interactions of Top-Down and Bottom-Up Mechanisms in Human Visual Cortex" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3072218/" target="_blank"&gt;the clutter impairs our own ability to focus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re strivers, analyzers, and accumulators but wonder why we burn ourselves and our relationships out on stress, self-chatter, and anxiety. &lt;strong&gt;Most of us have so much &amp;#8211; much more than the majority of the world at least (and more than &lt;a title="Who is Grok?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/about-2/who-is-grok/"&gt;our primal ancestors&lt;/a&gt; ever dreamed of), yet we live with a misplaced sense of deprivation.&lt;/strong&gt; Too often, we neglect or undervalue what we need (e.g. time to &lt;a title="Are Humans Hard Wired for a Limited Social Circle?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/dunbars-number-group-size/#axzz26gvjHyXL"&gt;foster close relationships&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Vitamin D: Sun Exposure, Supplementation and Doses" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/vitamin-d-sun-exposure-supplementation-and-doses/"&gt;time in the sun&lt;/a&gt;, time to sleep) but elevate aspects of life that are tangential at best. We give our positions and possessions more power than they deserve in the grand scheme of life &amp;#8211; let alone human history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s true of how we experience our own lives and how we look at others’. In our culture, we tend to attach status, even maturity and identity to the elaborateness of a home, vehicle, or outfit. Some of us overwork ourselves for a nice house we barely get to enjoy. Others forgo a vacation but spend money on collections that could easily pay for time away. Too often, we accumulate instead of experience. How much sense would any of this make to our ancestors? We’re stuck circling in a cul-de-sac of our own making. This would be the time to abandon the car and just trample through the manicured yards to get out of dodge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it’s all about coming back to yourself. The freedom comes, I think, in identifying your core interests and values and centering your life around them. &lt;strong&gt;Although I’m not one for austerity, I think there’s something to simplicity &amp;#8211; the mental, logistical, and physical spareness that brings a few key priorities into focus.&lt;/strong&gt; If you can avoid the literal and figurative toxins of modern life while you’re doing it, all the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I don’t think it’s about formulas or absolutes or right answers. Everyone’s different. I think simplicity is about proportion &amp;#8211; about aspects of our lives finding their “right” size in respect to everything else. In assessing these proportions, we recognize the influence each choice has on another as well as the impact of action on mentality. Researchers at the University of New Hampshire and Yale University, for example, &lt;a title="The More Secure You Feel, the Less You Value Your Stuff, UNH Research Shows" href="http://www.unh.edu/news/cj_nr/2011/mar/lw03value.cfm" target="_blank"&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; that those who felt less loved and accepted within relationships rated material possessions as more monetarily valuable. Underscoring this study, the researchers explain, is the source of our security and comfort. It’s worth asking, with what or whom do we situate our sense of personal security and comfort? &lt;strong&gt;Do our life choices and investments of time and energy appear to follow these priorities?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think about how I’ve changed over the last several years, I come back to that question. Although I’ve never been a complicated, high maintenance guy, I know I’ve changed as I’ve defined living Primally. These days I wear pretty much the same shoes &amp;#8211; &lt;a title="Primal Resources" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-resource-guide/"&gt;my Vibrams&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; wherever I go. I don’t think I’ve ever given much thought to clothes, and that’s certainly true now. I eat more or less &lt;a title="A Week in the Life of Mark Sisson" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/a-week-in-the-life-of-mark-sisson/"&gt;the same thing for lunch each day&lt;/a&gt;. I like to work from home to avoid the hassle of traffic. Unless I have to be on the road for work, I pretty much follow the same schedule with some room for a spontaneous hike in the hills near my home or dinner with friends. I’ve never considered myself an accumulator of things or gadgets, and that remains true today. Maybe it’s in part the journey of later adulthood, but I know at this point what I like and what I need. I’ve decided what matters to me and what doesn’t. For example, I enjoy good food and a comfortable bed. I love to travel (sometimes) and then simply being home for long stretches where I can be with family and spend time in the ocean. When it comes to my personal life, these are the things in which I invest my time, resources, and attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, I think &lt;strong&gt;we embrace simplicity when we pare down our lives to a point at which we’re not overwhelmed or &lt;a title="Mired in Media" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/mired-in-media/"&gt;diverted by our inputs&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; our stuff, our choices, our responsibilities, or our aspirations.&lt;/strong&gt; “More of everything!” seems to be a chant distinctive of our modern age. Although ambition and even a degree of materialistic interest might be part of human nature, gone are the traditional codes that kept those in check. People too often mistake this for inevitable progress and justification. When you take the original context away, however, natural impulses end up not making sense. Living Primally, I think, is about living conscious and respectful of that original context, however we choose to envision it at work in our &lt;a title="It's a Journey, Not a Race" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/its-a-journey-not-a-race/"&gt;personal health and life journey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks for reading today, everyone. Let me know your thoughts on living simply and how the Primal Blueprint illuminates or contributes to that motivation. Have a great end to the week.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grab a Copy of &lt;a title="Amazon.com: The Primal Connection" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0984755101/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=marsdaiapp07-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0984755101" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Connection: Follow Your Genetic Blueprint to Health and Happiness&lt;/a&gt; Today!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/r32OQdUxFPg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-simplifying-your-life-can-help-you-refocus-on-whats-important/#comments" thr:count="116" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-simplifying-your-life-can-help-you-refocus-on-whats-important/feed/atom/" thr:count="116" />
		<thr:total>116</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed><!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.851 seconds. --><!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-23 08:01:01 -->
