<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/wp-atom.php">
	<title type="text">Mark's Daily Apple</title>
	<subtitle type="text">Serving up health and fitness insights (daily, of course) with a side of irreverence.</subtitle>

	<updated>2013-04-04T15:00:35Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" />
	<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/feed/atom/</id>
	

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.5.1">WordPress</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/MarksDailyApple" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="marksdailyapple" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">MarksDailyApple</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[8 Ways to Cultivate Health Integrity]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/8-ways-to-cultivate-health-integrity/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35945</id>
		<updated>2013-04-04T04:51:37Z</updated>
		<published>2013-04-04T15:00:35Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Personal Improvement" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In last week’s post “Why Health Integrity Matters,” I suggested that owning your own health journey comes down to willingness &#8211; how willing you are to accept full responsibility for each choice you make. I appreciated everyone’s comments and &#8211; as always &#8211; loved to see how people extended the idea with their own experiences, [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/8-ways-to-cultivate-health-integrity/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" alt="integrity" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/integrity.jpg" width="320" height="212" title="8 Ways to Cultivate Health Integrity" /&gt;In last week’s post “&lt;a title="Why Health Integrity Matter" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/why-health-integrity-matters-or-the-power-of-being-honest-with-yourself/#axzz2PSJWsZ6N"&gt;Why Health Integrity Matters&lt;/a&gt;,” I suggested that owning your own health &lt;a title="It's a Journey, Not a Race" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/its-a-journey-not-a-race/"&gt;journey&lt;/a&gt; comes down to willingness &amp;#8211; how willing you are to accept full responsibility for each choice you make. I appreciated everyone’s comments and &amp;#8211; as always &amp;#8211; loved to see how people extended the idea with their own experiences, wisdom, and admissions. Quite a few declared it was a post meant for them and where they were in their personal journey. For various reasons, they needed the reboot, so to speak. I imagine we’re all there at some point &amp;#8211; at the skeptical beginnings of major changes, the less than stellar times we lose our footing or the crises of confidence that can settle in when we’re going through a &lt;a title="How to Deal with Common Primal Stumbling Blocks" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-deal-with-common-primal-stumbling-blocks/"&gt;rough patch of life&lt;/a&gt;. How do we cultivate health integrity? Let me offer some thoughts &amp;#8211; some wholly practical and a couple a little unorthodox. I hope you’ll add your own additions to the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35945"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Make an excuse board.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put it all out there &amp;#8211; every last &lt;a title="Today, We Shoot Down Excuses" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/health-fitness-excuses-rebuttals/"&gt;whine, reason and justification you use for not living healthily&lt;/a&gt;. Make columns for eating crap, chronically skipping exercise (&lt;a title="Rest Days" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/rest-days/"&gt;everyone legitimately needs rest days&lt;/a&gt;), going to bed late, &lt;a title="The Definitive Guide to Alcohol" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/low-carb-alcohol/"&gt;drinking&lt;/a&gt; too much, stressing yourself sick, etc. Every time you use one of those excuses, give yourself a gold star next to it. At the end of the week/month, see how much you’ve excelled at cheating yourself. Harsh, yes, but effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accept your own resistance.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s not gloss over the fact: there are times when we don’t feel like showing up for ourselves. Every one of us probably would pin a different reason on that one, but we’ve all been there. For some, it comes out in our health related choices. For others, it can take a different form (e.g. money, alcohol, etc.). But here’s the rub. We don’t have to like “showing up.” Seriously. You don’t always have to relish making the healthy choice. If you’re generally living well &amp;#8211; &lt;a title="Primal Blueprint Recipes" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-blueprint-recipes/"&gt;eating Primally&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="The Definitive Guide to Walking" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-definitive-guide-to-walking/"&gt;moving frequently&lt;/a&gt;, challenging yourself enjoyably, sleeping soundly, &lt;a title="10 Ways to De-stress" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/10-ways-to-de-stress/"&gt;destressing&lt;/a&gt; regularly &amp;#8211; you know the benefits. Likewise, if you’ve ever &lt;a title="Falling Off the Wagon" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/health-fitness-excuses-rebuttals/"&gt;backslid&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; by choice or circumstance &amp;#8211; you also know how much you can pay a price. Still, we move through however many &lt;a title="The Mood Diet" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-mood-diet/"&gt;moods&lt;/a&gt; and challenges each day. Accept that you’re going to be more willing some times than others, but still stick with your basic intention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deal with serious underlying issues.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes there are deep and difficult reasons behind our tendencies toward &lt;a title="Entitled Sabotage" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/entitled-to-sabotage/"&gt;self-sabotage&lt;/a&gt;. Be honest with yourself about the internalized messages and ongoing compulsions that keep weighing you down. Get the help you need to sort it out, and grant yourself permission to &lt;a title="How to Use the Friday Success Stories to Grok On and Keep Evolving" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-use-the-friday-success-stories-to-grok-on-and-keep-evolving/"&gt;believe you’re capable of a better life&lt;/a&gt;. Surround yourself with &lt;a title="Primal Blueprint Support, Events and Education" href="http://primalblueprint.com/pages/support-events-education"&gt;the support&lt;/a&gt; and engage in the self care you need to see yourself differently. Accept that it may be a life long commitment and not a single “fix.” While it’s not your fault you were left with the baggage, it’s a choice whether you let it hang around your neck each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Plan for your weaknesses.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep some Primal worthy &lt;a title="Primal Blueprint Snacks" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-blueprint-snacks/"&gt;snacks&lt;/a&gt; at work for the days you have to work late. Put a list of last-minute &lt;a title="10 Primal Meal in 15 Minutes or Less" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/10-primal-meals-in-15-minutes-or-less/"&gt;simple recipes&lt;/a&gt; on the fridge for mornings you don’t have time to make what you’d planned. Don’t let the weekend pass without cooking your stash of meat and chopping veggies if you know it means you’re setting yourself up for failure come Monday’s dinner. Keep up on your life enough that you’re not testing yourself unnecessarily. Some things won’t rattle you. Other things will. Be &lt;a title="Mindful Eating: The Art of Being Present at the Dinner Table" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/mindful-eating-the-art-of-being-present-at-the-dinner-table/"&gt;mindful&lt;/a&gt; of what will, and be preemptive however you reasonably can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accept that you can’t plan for everything.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As good as it is to plan and prepare, it’s important to not make the journey one massive control trip. Loosen up, lighten up, and cultivate enough self-possession that you don’t go nuclear if you forget your lunch one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Track your day.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to argue with hard numbers. Seeing the concrete rundown of all you’ve done (or not done) in a day can be affirming &amp;#8211; or sobering. Either way, you’re facing empirical fact, and that’s a level of accountability itself. There are numerous programs and gadgets you can use to do this: everything from &lt;a title="7 Tech Tools for Better Primal Living" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/7-tech-tools-for-better-primal-living/#axzz2PSSLbEgM"&gt;pedometers to sleep monitors, FitDay to the CHRON-O-Meter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Partner or team up.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be easy to skip an open ended group like a run club (not that they aren’t great for other reasons). Skip your &lt;a title="Adult Sports Leagues, and Why You Should Join One" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/adult-sports-leagues-and-why-you-should-join-one/"&gt;team’s basketball match-up&lt;/a&gt; with a rival office, however, and you’re gonna hear about it. Likewise, you wouldn’t leave a friend hanging by herself ready for your a.m. run at the park while you hit the snooze for the fourth time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Write letters to yourself.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve mentioned before an old friend who used to leave notes for himself that aren’t suitable for a general audience. As severe as they were, it was his brand of motivation. I’m not suggesting leaving profanity laced post-its around your home (especially if you have children), but write two letters to yourself and keep them where you can either see them or easily find them. Keep a copy at work or in your inbox. One is to congratulate yourself on taking care of yourself (e.g. “Thank you for not feeding me those awful sugar bomb donuts Phyllis always leaves in the break room. And, by the way, there’s always dog hair on them.). Put a picture of yourself happy and healthy in the letter. For extra emotional tug, put the kids in there, too. Make the other letter a “plead your own case” letter. Make it as imploring, guilt-inspiring, or ruthless as befits your personality. Attach the label of the prescription drug you finally got yourself off of or an old picture you’d rather not remember. If you’re tempted to stay up late for the third night playing Candy Crush on Facebook (No, I do not play this.) or eat the bag of Doritos your brother-in-law left in the cabinet at his last visit, it will be your job to read this letter. You’ll know what you need to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, let me turn this topic over to you. How do you cultivate self-honesty and responsibility in your Primal life? Share your thoughts, reflections, and good humor. Have a great end to the week, everybody.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grab a Copy of &lt;a title="Amazon.com: The Primal Connection" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0984755101/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=marsdaiapp07-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0984755101" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Connection: Follow Your Genetic Blueprint to Health and Happiness&lt;/a&gt; Today!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/wk7R3ZGYt-E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/8-ways-to-cultivate-health-integrity/#comments" thr:count="0" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/8-ways-to-cultivate-health-integrity/feed/atom/" thr:count="0" />
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Is It All Just a &#8220;Paleofantasy&#8221;?]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/is-it-all-just-a-paleofantasy/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35921</id>
		<updated>2013-04-03T09:17:36Z</updated>
		<published>2013-04-03T15:00:18Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Reviews" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[So this is my review of the new book Paleofantasy: What Evolution Really Tells Us About Sex, Diet, and How We Live. It&#8217;s been making the rounds for a few weeks now, and although some other people have already weighed in, I&#8217;ll add my two cents. At the outset, I’d like to make very clear that [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/is-it-all-just-a-paleofantasy/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Amazon.com: PaleoFantasy" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0393081370/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0393081370&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=marsdaiapp07-20" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" alt="paleofantasy" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/paleofantasy.jpg" width="300" height="420" title="Is It All Just a Paleofantasy?" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;So this is my review of the new book &lt;a title="Amazon.com: PaleoFantasy" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0393081370/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0393081370&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=marsdaiapp07-20" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paleofantasy: What Evolution Really Tells Us About Sex, Diet, and How We Live&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s been making the rounds for a few weeks now, and although some other people have already weighed in, I&amp;#8217;ll add my two cents. At the outset, I’d like to make very clear that I actually agree with a decent portion of Marlene Zuk’s individual arguments. Though it may surprise you to know that Mark Sisson agrees with the most prominent paleo debunker du jour on several topics, I&amp;#8217;m not saying I support the overall product or her final conclusions. In fact, &lt;em&gt;Paleofantasy&lt;/em&gt; is an odd, meandering book whose ultimate purpose I&amp;#8217;m not really sure I truly understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main problems with the book, as I see it. First, she&amp;#8217;s working against a &lt;a title="Wikipedia: Straw Man" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Straw_man" target="_blank"&gt;straw man&lt;/a&gt;. Many of the arguments she debunks, like &amp;#8220;eyeglasses aren&amp;#8217;t paleo&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;the paleo diet was carnivorous,&amp;#8221; seems to have been dug up from some random Internet commenter or drawn from fringe camps. In other words, they aren&amp;#8217;t arguments people like Robb Wolf, Chris Kresser, Paul Jaminet, or me (or our readers) are making. Second, many of her counterarguments or &amp;#8220;nuanced approaches&amp;#8221; are the very same ones we&amp;#8217;ve been exploring at length for years! After reading the book, John Durant &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/johndurant/status/311281463742054400"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; “Paleofantasy shouldn’t have been a book in 2013, it should have been a blog post in 2010,” and that’s as good a description as I can think of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35921"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#8217;s all very uncontroversial:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is no one paleo diet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&amp;#8217;s saying that? Humans have spanned the globe for millennia, surviving and even thriving in environments ranging from tropical to temperate, from arctic to near-aquatic, all the while subsisting on the wild foods available to those regions. Same basic diet of animals and plants, different configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evolution doesn&amp;#8217;t just stop and humans didn&amp;#8217;t just reach a state of perfect adaptation back before agriculture from which we&amp;#8217;ve never progressed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure. I talked about how &lt;a title="How Much Have Human Dietary Requirements Evolved in the Last 10,000 Years?" href="https://www.marksdailyapple.com/are-humans-still-evolving/"&gt;we&amp;#8217;re still &amp;#8220;evolving&amp;#8221; last year&lt;/a&gt;, even mentioning Zuk&amp;#8217;s favorite topics &amp;#8211; lactase persistence (35% worldwide, which is far from 100%) and amylase production. She discusses a few more recent changes, like malaria resistance, adaptation to high altitude, and earwax differentiation, but that&amp;#8217;s it. If she wanted to, I&amp;#8217;m sure she &amp;#8220;could keep adding to the list&amp;#8221; and mount an overwhelming case for widespread genetic adaptations to grain consumption, chronic stress tolerance, and sedentary living, but she&amp;#8217;s saving up material for the next book. Or something. Either way, I&amp;#8217;m not very convinced by her &amp;#8220;list&amp;#8221; of rapid evolutionary changes, especially considering most of them have little to do with the mismatches we discuss in this community and none of them are even present in a majority of humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zuk is also quick to misrepresent &amp;#8220;our&amp;#8221; arguments so she can swoop in and take the sensible position &amp;#8211; positions the ancestral health community has long occupied!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In her exercise chapter, she characterizes paleo exercise proscriptions as “short and intense” and “literal-minded,” mimicking activities like “having to run down a rabbit for dinner.” We type away at our computers on caveman forums, spend a little while lifting weights and running sprints, and sit back down. Then, Zuk explains that contrary to our reenactment fantasies, the real problem and the real divergence from our past is that modern humans sit too often. It is our inactivity, our hours and hours spent doing nothing physical that hurt us. What we should be doing is lots of slow moving, steady low-level activity like walking, hiking, gardening, yard work, house work, rather than sitting all day and trying to make up for it with a hard gym session. Hmm - &lt;a title="You May Want to Sit Down For This" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/sitting-unhealthy/#axzz2POF9jt4U"&gt;where&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="How-to Guide: Standing at Work" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/standing-at-work/"&gt;have&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="Why We Don’t Walk Anymore (plus a Primal Health Challenge)" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/why-we-dont-walk-anymore/"&gt;I&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="The Art of Work: Avoiding the Pitfalls of a Sedentary Job  " href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/sedentary-work-obesity/#axzz2PM5UGZB6"&gt;heard&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="The Definitive Guide to Low Level Aerobic Activity  " href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/health-benefits-moderate-exercise/#axzz2PM5gPutC"&gt;that&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="The Importance of Play, Long Walks and Outdoor Workouts, or Why the Optional Stuff Isn’t Actually Optional  " href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-importance-of-play-long-walks-and-outdoor-workouts-or-why-the-optional-stuff-isnt-actually-optional/#axzz2PM68hqK1"&gt;kind&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="Sitting is Killing You" href="http://thatpaleoguy.com/2011/05/12/sitting-is-killing-you/" target="_blank"&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="How to walk 10,000 steps a day if you’re a desk jockey" href="http://chriskresser.com/how-to-walk-10000-steps-a-day-if-youre-a-desk-jockey" target="_blank"&gt;stuff&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="The Definitive Guide to Walking" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-definitive-guide-to-walking/"&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;? Why hasn’t the ancestral health community addressed this pernicious force in our lives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, she rightly claims that paleo authors are suspicious of endurance training, mocking my position that the idea that “natural selection redesigned our simian shapes to run the Boston Marathon is&amp;#8230; ludicrous.” As support for her claims, she cites Louis Liebenberg’s persistence hunting studies (&lt;a title="Persistence Hunting by Modern HunterGatherers" href="http://www.mattmetzgar.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/08/persistence_hunting.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;) with the Kalahari bushmen of Botswana where men would go on hunts lasting “two to five hours, with an average running speed of 6.3 kilometers (about 4 miles) per hour.” Those are fifteen minute miles. If you were running the Boston Marathon at a 15 minute-mile pace, you’d finish in six and a half hours (roughly). That’s an easy run (fast walk?), especially for someone who’s reasonably fit. You could hold a conversation at that speed. You could get up and do it again the next day at that pace. That’s not &lt;a title="Dear Mark: Maximum 4,000 Calories a Week of Exercise?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/dear-mark-maximum-4000-calories-a-week-of-exercise/"&gt;chronic cardio&lt;/a&gt;. That’s not a competitive time for an endurance athlete &amp;#8211; the dogged pursuit of which is precisely what I’ve always warned against. It&amp;#8217;s easy aerobic activity, the kind I promote!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when she acknowledges the potential utility of an evolutionary approach to analyzing health or current environmental “mismatches,” they are glossed over or relegated to a single sentence buried in a paragraph. Zuk spends an entire chapter explaining how traditional child-rearing, with its extended family members available for childcare, extended &lt;a title="Nursing and the Primal Blueprint Diet" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/nursing-primal-blueprint-diet/"&gt;breastfeeding&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Co-Sleeping: How to Do It Safely" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/co-sleeping-how-to-do-it-safely/"&gt;co-sleeping&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Why You Should Wear (or Carry) Your Baby (At Least Some of the Time)" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/why-you-should-wear-or-carry-your-baby/"&gt;baby-wearing&lt;/a&gt;, parental &amp;#8220;indulgence&amp;#8221; of crying babies, is likely the biological and evolutionary norm for human infants, citing Dr. James McKenna&amp;#8217;s extensive research on the benefits of the aforementioned methods&amp;#8230; and then ends the chapter by saying &amp;#8220;most children grow up fine&amp;#8221; so let&amp;#8217;s not bother with it. Let&amp;#8217;s just keep on keepin&amp;#8217; on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to the idea that limiting artificial light at night and getting plenty of natural light during the day might improve sleep and preserve our &lt;a title="How to Conduct a Personal Experiment: Yellow Light Exposure (plus an Announcement)" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-conduct-a-personal-experiment-yellow-light-exposure-plus-an-announcement/"&gt;circadian rhythms&lt;/a&gt;, she asks “is this really the solution to our health problems?” She creates an argument that we are all apparently positing &amp;#8211; that smashing light bulbs and waking up at dawn are the cure to all our health problems &amp;#8211; and then proceeds to dismiss it, to laugh it off. And yeah, it’s ridiculous to say that unnatural light is the &lt;em&gt;cause of all our health ills&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8230; but who’s saying that? Who’s making this argument but her? And on that note, &lt;em&gt;what about the negative effects of artificial light at night&lt;/em&gt;? Aren&amp;#8217;t they worth investigating? Isn&amp;#8217;t the &lt;a title="How Blue Light Affects Your Sleep" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-light-affects-our-sleep/#axzz2POBRzNdu"&gt;data we already have&lt;/a&gt; fairly compelling?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(If you notice me asking a lot of questions in apparent exasperation, it&amp;#8217;s because I&amp;#8217;m puzzled and exasperated and driven to inquiry by some of these &amp;#8220;arguments.&amp;#8221; Forgive me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A worrisome theme starts to emerge: that the past is murky and we need more data so let&amp;#8217;s not make any sudden changes to the way we live, especially not if they&amp;#8217;re couched in evolution. I disagree.&lt;/strong&gt; Whatever most people are doing isn&amp;#8217;t really working for most people, whereas whatever we&amp;#8217;re doing (whether it&amp;#8217;s a paleofantasy or not) &lt;a title="Success Story Summaries" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/category/success-story-summaries/"&gt;seems to be working&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To her credit, Zuk doesn&amp;#8217;t throw out the idea of evolutionary mismatch altogether (although you could have fooled me).&lt;/strong&gt; She just rails against &amp;#8220;denouncing modern living as unsuitable to our Stone Age genes,&amp;#8221; calling for research into &amp;#8220;just what parts of that life send us too far out of our evolutionary zone of tolerance,&amp;#8221; as if she&amp;#8217;s stumbled upon some revolutionary concept. Really, though, we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; exploring and identifying the specific aspects of modern life that trigger a mismatch. We &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; gathering data. Academics and scientists and bloggers and lay individuals are figuring out, in fits and starts and lurches and &lt;a title="Why Self Experimentation Matters" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/why-self-experimentation-matters/"&gt;self-experiments&lt;/a&gt; and clinical trials and study analyses, just what works about modern life and what does not work. We&amp;#8217;re not resting on our laurels, on our assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we kind of agree, even though it appears she doesn&amp;#8217;t know it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t necessarily blame Marlene Zuk for her failure to comb the ancestral health community&amp;#8217;s tomes, read all the blogs, study the comment sections (although she seems to have a fondness for anonymous blog commenters), attend the symposiums and conferences (although much of the material is available online for free), and explore the message boards. There&amp;#8217;s a lot of material to cover. It&amp;#8217;d probably take years to really do a thorough job. But if she hoped to publish a relevant critique of the community, she probably should have understood its actual claims instead of erecting a straw man for easy defeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In John Hawks&amp;#8217; &lt;a title="My review of &amp;quot;Paleofantasy&amp;quot;" href="http://johnhawks.net/weblog/reviews/books/paleofantasy-zuk-2013.html#gsc.tab=0" target="_blank"&gt;favorable review&lt;/a&gt; of the book, he says that we must &amp;#8220;play with hypotheses, explore their predictions and try very hard to falsify them.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completely agree. I think Zuk agrees, too, and I think I may have divined her ultimate goal with this book. In her &lt;a title="The Evolutionary Search for Our Perfect Past" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/01/20/health/views/20essa.html?_r=0" target="_blank"&gt;2009 NY Times piece&lt;/a&gt; on the same subject, she said &amp;#8220;we shouldn’t flagellate ourselves for having modern bodies, and we shouldn’t assume that tweaking our diets or our posture will rescue us from all our current ills.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;She thinks people are rushing headlong into such dangerous lifestyle changes as &lt;a href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-quit-grains/"&gt;giving up grains&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="The Definitive Guide to Sugar" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-definitive-guide-to-sugar/"&gt;sugar&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a title="The Definitive Guide to Oils" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/healthy-oils/"&gt;seed oils&lt;/a&gt; without doing their due diligence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll have no arguments from me. Assume nothing, test/tweak/research everything.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;#8217;s not like I&amp;#8217;m sitting here typing away, conjuring up fantastical stories about the past and making big lifestyle proscriptions based on said stories. Those &lt;a title="Success Story Summaries" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/category/success-story-summaries/"&gt;success stories&lt;/a&gt; are actual success stories from actual people. Those studies cited are actual studies from real journals. I suppose you could make the argument that all these folks losing weight and gaining muscle and getting off meds and regaining their lives after adopting a Primal way of eating, living, and moving cannot definitively establish the lifestyle was the precipitating factor. They can&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8220;prove&amp;#8221; it works. It could all be a big dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big paleofantasy. I could be making this entire world up in my head as I go along, a lonely brain in some amniotic sac with electrodes attached, my entire history and the blog and the books and my relationships all constructs of my mind. I don&amp;#8217;t think I am, though. I think this is real, flesh-and-blood stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are improved blood sugars, better blood lipids, a hundred pounds of weight loss, newly emergent abs, steady midday energy, improvement of autoimmune disease, and new leases on life paleofantasies? No.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are sitting in front of an LCD screen until 2 AM, spending zero &lt;a title="Getting Back to Nature" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/getting-back-to-nature/"&gt;time in nature&lt;/a&gt;, living off of Cheetos and Coke, walking under a thousand steps a day, and working 20 hour days at a miserable job evolutionary mismatches with drastic health consequences as shown by current science (and hinted at by anthropology)? Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;#8217;s what it comes down to in the end: results. We got &amp;#8216;em, and people recognize that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you read &lt;em&gt;Paleofantasy&lt;/em&gt;? What do you think? Let everyone know in the comment board, and thanks for reading!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grab a copy of &lt;a title="Primal Blueprint Quick &amp;amp; Easy Meals" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/Primal-Blueprint-Quick-%26-Easy-Meals.html" target="_blank"&gt;Primal Blueprint Quick &amp;amp; Easy Meals&lt;/a&gt; for over 100 Primal Recipes You Can Prepare in 30 Minutes or Less&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/JIlzcFJgiRE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/is-it-all-just-a-paleofantasy/#comments" thr:count="228" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/is-it-all-just-a-paleofantasy/feed/atom/" thr:count="228" />
		<thr:total>228</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use the Friday Success Stories to Grok On and Keep Evolving]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-use-the-friday-success-stories-to-grok-on-and-keep-evolving/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35904</id>
		<updated>2013-04-03T04:29:45Z</updated>
		<published>2013-04-02T15:00:27Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Personal Improvement" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a guest post from Susan Alexander of app4Mind.com. I study behavior modification like Mark studies nutrition, movement, and lifestyle. He&#8217;s created a paradigm of related principles for Primal living, as I&#8217;ve created a paradigm for self-chosen life change. Our similar interests, along with the fact that I&#8217;m a longtime member of the MDA [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-use-the-friday-success-stories-to-grok-on-and-keep-evolving/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" alt="4M" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/4M.jpg" width="320" height="240" title="How to Use the Friday Success Stories to Grok On and Keep Evolving" /&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post from Susan Alexander of &lt;a title="app4mind.com" href="http://app4mind.com" target="_blank"&gt;app4Mind.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I study behavior modification like Mark studies nutrition, movement, and lifestyle. He&amp;#8217;s created a paradigm of related principles for Primal living, as I&amp;#8217;ve created a paradigm for self-chosen life change. Our similar interests, along with the fact that I&amp;#8217;m a longtime member of the MDA community, is how I&amp;#8217;ve come to write this post. Reading the &lt;a title="Success Stories" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/category/success-stories/"&gt;Success Stories&lt;/a&gt; every Friday for as long as Mark&amp;#8217;s been posting them, I&amp;#8217;ve figured something out. There are common threads running through these stories that explain why so many different kinds of people, in so many different circumstances and walks of life, have been able to transform themselves through the PB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is about those common threads. They happen to be the essential behavioral principles that enable us to make a substantial life change and sustain it &amp;#8211; which is what we&amp;#8217;re all endeavoring to do here in becoming and being Primal. None of us has it completely nailed. The point of the PB is to keep evolving. The point of this post is to help everyone do just that. So let&amp;#8217;s get started, shall we? Here are the common threads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35904"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Evolutionary belief&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Success Story writers share the basic core belief that they can evolve themselves throughout their lives. In other words, they believe this basic idea: “The way I am now is not the way I always have to be.” This belief is known as the &lt;strong&gt;growth mindset&lt;/strong&gt;, identified and studied over a 20 year period by Stanford psychologist Carol Dweck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://app4mind.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Mindset_solo1.gif"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright size-full wp-image-8650" alt="Mindset solo1" src="http://app4mind.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Mindset_solo1.gif" width="105" height="140" title="How to Use the Friday Success Stories to Grok On and Keep Evolving" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Mindset is reflected in what people do &amp;#8211; as we see over and over again in the Success Stories. People who &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; they can evolve themselves &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; evolve themselves. We see a wide array of approaches to getting started, all of which worked. See e.g. &lt;a title="The AHA Moment" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-aha-moment-when-clarity-happens-and-real-change-begins/#axzz2NbUwWu1M"&gt;Ed &amp;amp; Amy&lt;/a&gt; (“it struck a beautiful chord with us &amp;#8230;. we tossed everything in the house”); &lt;a title="Drug Free for the First Time in Five Years" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/drug-free-for-the-first-time-in-five-years/#axzz2Av1sVARk"&gt;Michael&lt;/a&gt; (“After reading MDA for a day I decided to abandon the vegetarian path entirely and take the plunge into the Primal lifestyle”); &lt;a title="Not Your Typical Before and Afters" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/not-your-typical-before-and-afters/#axzz2NbYu6z5s"&gt;Katie&lt;/a&gt; (“I wasn’t totally convinced of the fat thing right away &amp;#8230;. over the course of a year I made small changes”); &lt;a title="My Health Lifestyle Was Killing Me" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/my-healthy-lifestyle-was-killing-me/#axzz235YajzMB"&gt;Myra&lt;/a&gt; (“I decided to give this Primal thing a try for a week.”); &lt;a title="Not Only Did I Break Past My Plateau, I Demolished It" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/not-only-did-i-break-past-my-plateau-i-demolished-it-2/#axzz2NbYu6z5s"&gt;Lee&lt;/a&gt; (“Without a lot of thought or effort, I transitioned into it.”); &lt;a title="My Health Is Better Than It Has Ever Been" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/my-health-is-better-than-it-has-ever-been/#axzz2NbYu6z5s"&gt;Adina&lt;/a&gt; (“I spent the next few months reconsidering why I’d become vegan.”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opposite of the growth mindset is the &lt;strong&gt;fixed mindset&lt;/strong&gt;. As Primal followers, we hear it all the time in people who say things like: “I could never do that;” “I don’t have the genes for that kind of body;” “The treadmill is fine for me.” The bottom line is this: fixed mindset people don’t think they can change very much. They think their skills, aptitudes, and temperament are fixed, so they themselves are fixed. That&amp;#8217;s why they&amp;#8217;re not open to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone in the non-Primal world has a fixed mindset. There are plenty of growth mindset people out there who just haven&amp;#8217;t heard of the PB or decided to try it yet. As for the fixed mindset people out there, there&amp;#8217;s hope. Switching from a fixed mindset to a growth mindset is easier than you might think. Just knowing about the two mindsets enables you to spot the thoughts that go with each one. You’ll start catching yourself in fixed mode, and from there, you can consciously switch into growth mode. After a while, it won&amp;#8217;t take so much conscious effort. The growth mindset just becomes yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Takeaway #1&lt;/strong&gt;: The growth mindset is, by its nature, evolutionary. It’s the simple belief that we can change and grow throughout life, through our own efforts. This belief is a major common thread running through the Success Stories. Its opposite is the fixed mindset belief that the way we are now is the way we always have to be. If you’re on the fence about going Primal, or you’re already Primal but you’re feeling stuck, there may be some fixed mindset thoughts going on in your head that are holding you back. Work on a mindset switch first. Read some &lt;a title="Success Stories" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/category/success-stories/"&gt;success stories&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s a great way to get some growth mindset optimism. Then try something new or different from what you&amp;#8217;re doing now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Evolutionary action&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another common thread running through the Success Stories is evolutionary action. We see all the writers evolving their efforts (and themselves) over time, in a continuous, iterative way. They all see the Primal Blueprint as exactly what it is &amp;#8211; a continuing, lifelong process (as opposed to a “diet,” a quick fix, or something they’re doing just for now). See e.g. &lt;a title="Primal Evolution" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-evolution-change-within-weeks-transformation-in-mere-months/#axzz235YajzMB"&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; (“My idea of fun is bettering myself and continuing to learn”); &lt;a title="My Health Lifestyle Was Killing Me" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/my-healthy-lifestyle-was-killing-me/#axzz235YajzMB"&gt;Myra&lt;/a&gt; (“My Primal journey continues as I try out different things and continue to learn how my body wants me to live.”); &lt;a title="I Am a Strong, Happy, Healthy Life-Loving Man" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/i-am-a-strong-happy-healthy-life-loving-man/#axzz2NblzDcbq"&gt;Jeffrey&lt;/a&gt; (“This has become much more than a way to lose weight for me, it is ingrained into who I am”); &lt;a title="Not Your Typical Before and Afters" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/not-your-typical-before-and-afters/#axzz2NbmLDuAd"&gt;Katie&lt;/a&gt; (“I’m still learning and tweaking every day”); &lt;a title="We Are Talking About A Drastic Increase in Quality of Life" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/we-are-talking-about-a-drastic-increase-in-quality-of-life/"&gt;Jesse &amp;amp; Vickie&lt;/a&gt; (“We knew we wouldn’t be ripped in just 21 days”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://app4mind.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/motion-solo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright size-full wp-image-8927" alt="motion solo" src="http://app4mind.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/motion-solo.jpg" width="149" height="164" title="How to Use the Friday Success Stories to Grok On and Keep Evolving" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This continuous, iterative approach to Primal is reflective of what I call the &lt;strong&gt;motion loop&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; which is simply my illustrated distillation of &lt;strong&gt;the classic trial and error process through which all species in the universe evolved&lt;/strong&gt;. When it comes to evolving ourselves throughout life, we follow the same course. To find what works for us &amp;#8211; in all that we do &amp;#8211; we do as the arrows say: we try things out, we learn from the results of our efforts, and rework what we&amp;#8217;ve done. Then we try out our rework, learn from that, and rework again. To keep evolving our efforts and ourselves, we keep looping, over and over, just like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see in the Success Stories that the motion loop is not a theory. It&amp;#8217;s how effective people work in real life. We see each of the writers embracing the PB over time in just this way, without the objective of getting &amp;#8220;done.&amp;#8221; See e.g. &lt;a title="A Way of Life Has No Finish Line" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/a-way-of-life-has-no-finish-line/#axzz2C9Zdv1HS"&gt;Sean&lt;/a&gt; (“The Primal life is not a diet to me and has no ultimate finish line&amp;#8221;); &lt;a title="The Unconquerable Dave: Still Unconquerable" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-unconquerable-dave-still-unconquerable/#axzz2Nbf0qXc1"&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt; (“Learning is something I will do forever and this way is a great place to learn &amp;#8230; to live &amp;#8230; to experiment and find your space that works for you”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Takeaway #2&lt;/strong&gt;: The motion loop reflects the classic trial and error process by which all species in the universe evolved. On an individual level, it’s our means of self-evolution. By staying in the motion loop with whatever we’re doing, whether it’s the PB or something else, we keep evolving our efforts and ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Evolutionary feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evolution is chaos with feedback. &amp;#8211; Joe Ford&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next common thread running through the Success Stories is the reliance on feedback. All the writers rely on it to keep their Primal journeys evolving. As we’ve already seen, feedback is an integral part of the motion loop. It’s precisely what the writers look to (and all of us must look to ) in order learn from our efforts and keep the motion loop going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main kinds of feedback running through the Success Stories: &lt;strong&gt;feeling and tracking&lt;/strong&gt;. Let’s look at both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Feeling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every single story details the feelings that arose from going Primal. The writers recount a wide range of physical to emotional feelings, with a lot of overlap. See e.g. &lt;a title="I Knew a Change Had to Be Made" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/i-knew-a-change-had-to-be-made/#axzz2NbnFbRAR"&gt;Heath&lt;/a&gt; (“I now feel that I have a new lease on life”); &lt;a title="Rejecting the Status Quo" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/rejecting-the-status-quo-saying-no-to-a-common-life/#axzz2NbhDaQ1n"&gt;J.P.&lt;/a&gt; (“I started to become more patient with people &amp;#8230; and overall felt better emotionally. I literally was becoming happier”); &lt;a title="Finally, I Am Me" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/finally-i-am-me/#axzz29l7P2mOC"&gt;Nikki&lt;/a&gt; (“I feel like I’m living my life the way I should be”); &lt;a title="What Does It Mean to Be a Fat-Burning Beast?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-fat-burning-beast-2/#axzz2NbhDaQ1n"&gt;Cynthia &amp;amp; Paul&lt;/a&gt; (“feeling super fit and healthy all while training less and being true to our Primal selves&amp;#8221;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feelings are a crucial source of feedback in any change we make, whether it&amp;#8217;s going Primal, trying something new in our Primal journey, or some other change. Why are feelings so crucial? Because how something makes us feel has everything to do with whether we keep doing it. Decades of research by preeminent psychologist Mihalyi Csikszentmihalyi explains why. His work can be distilled into this simple idea: Extrinsic motivation may be present somewhere in the background, but it&amp;#8217;s rarely the main reason we do what we do. &lt;strong&gt;We humans like the feeling of evolving ourselves&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; by building skills, overcoming challenges, and being part of a process that leads to a higher level of harmony in life &amp;#8211; so when we find something that gives us this feeling, and it&amp;#8217;s learnable and accessible to us, we keep doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another way to view evolution is to see it not as the selective survival of life forms such as dinosaurs or elephants, but of information. Inside each person there is a wonderful capacity to reflect on the information that the various sense organs register, and to direct and control these experiences &amp;#8230;. [H]aving a self-reflective consciousness allows us to write our own programs for action, and make decisions for which no genetic instructions existed before. &amp;#8211; Mihalyi Csikszentmihalyi&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PB is precisely that something, for everyone who’s written a Success Story and for the whole MDA community. There are lots of specific reasons we all can list for being Primal, but in its simplest terms, what’s really going on is this: We do it because we like it. We like it because it feels good. &lt;strong&gt;Self-evolution is inherently likable&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’ve been skimming this post, this is a good time to start reading every word, because what I’m about to tell you will change your life&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a particular feeling that shows up again and again in the Success Stories that’s not well understood but very powerful. Acclaimed author and psychiatrist Edward Hallowell calls it mastery. I&amp;#8217;ve renamed it slightly. I call it &lt;strong&gt;micro-mastery&lt;/strong&gt; to differentiate it from what we normally think of when we hear the word mastery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Micro-mastery isn’t full mastery, as in the way Picasso mastered art or Wayne Gretzky mastered hockey. It’s something completely different. As Dr. Hallowell explains, it is not an accomplishment or the reaching of a goal. Instead, it’s that simple feeling of “Now I get it!” or “I can do it!” that comes when you’ve been trying hard to do something, and you do a small part of it just well enough to give you that feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it. That’s all micro-mastery is – &lt;strong&gt;a feeling&lt;/strong&gt;. It seems small, but it’s huge. Because we humans like that feeling. So when we feel it, we’ll work to feel it again and again. When we’ll work to feel something, it means we’re intrinsically motivated. Thus, micro-mastery is a source of &lt;strong&gt;intrinsic motivation we make ourselves, through our own actions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Success Stories are a beautiful treasure trove of written accounts of self-made motivation brought on by micro-mastery. Over and over, we see writers come right out and say, unequivocally, that when they felt one part of the PB working, even just a little bit, it motivated them to go farther in their Primal journeys. Great examples are Andy, Keri, and Jenna:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="I Feel Alive for the First Time in Years" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/i-feel-alive-for-the-first-time-in-years/#axzz2Nbi4HTxZ"&gt;Andy&lt;/a&gt; saw his weight drop a bit in each of his first 3 weeks of going Primal. “Talk about motivation!” he wrote. By his own account, it’s precisely what lead to his gradual, linear pursuit of athletic goals (a 5k, a 10K, and a 1/2 marathon).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="I Just Had to Find the Right Path" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/i-just-had-to-find-the-right-path/#axzz2Nbi4HTxZ"&gt;Keri&lt;/a&gt; found herself where a lot of women runners do: gaining weight while training. Stumbling on MDA lead her to shift her macronutrient balance (to more protein and fat and fewer carbs). From that, she felt herself &lt;a title="A Metabolic Paradigm Shift, or Why Fat is the Preferred Fuel for Human Metabolism" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/a-metabolic-paradigm-shift-fat-carbs-human-body-metabolism/"&gt;transform from a sugar burner into a fat burner&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;she loved the feeling&lt;/em&gt;. Finding she could train on fewer carbs and have great race results, her motivation shifted as well. It became more intrinsic and less extrinsic. Here are her exact words: “I am not sure where my running will take me in the future but I know that the motivation will be from the pure enjoyment of getting outside every morning &amp;#8230; not the calories burned.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="I Now Have Respect and Love for My Own Body" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/i-now-have-respect-and-love-for-my-own-body/"&gt;Jenna&lt;/a&gt; felt her breathing improve and her weight drop a little. That motivated her to start exercising &amp;#8211; and she soon started liking the feeling of exercise, so she didn’t have to make herself do it anymore. She did it because she wanted to. She wrote: &amp;#8220;There are so many gifts I have gotten from following the PB. My health, my motivation, my identity &amp;#8230;. I am getting stronger, and exercising more because I enjoy it now, not because it’s a chore.&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Takeaway #3&lt;/strong&gt;: Feedback from feelings fuels the the Primal process, because how something makes us feel has everything to do with whether we keep doing it. As we see in the Success Stories, many different kinds of feelings serve as valuable feedback. One of those feelings is micro-mastery. It&amp;#8217;s important because it&amp;#8217;s a source of intrinsic motivation. Once we feel micro-mastery, we&amp;#8217;re on our way to being intrinsically motivated, because we like the feeling so much that we want to feel it again and again. Thus, &lt;strong&gt;it’s not true that we have to be motivated first, before we get started making a change in our lives&lt;/strong&gt;. We can get started even when we don’t want to, and even when we think we’re not “ready.” Because motivation kicks in during the process. We create it ourselves by reaching micro-mastery, over and over in the motion loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tracking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracking is another common thread running through the Success Stories. By tracking, I mean that the writers used metrics of some kind to gauge what works and what doesn’t. Their metrics reflected their reasons for going Primal. For example, &lt;a title="From Cancer Back to Health" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/from-cancer-back-to-health/#axzz22oVb4CpP"&gt;PaleoBird&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="100 Days of Change" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/100-days-of-change-my-transformation-story/#axzz2NdN4kliA"&gt;Andrew&lt;/a&gt; went Primal to lose weight (among other reasons). Through self-experimentation, they both found that carb reduction alone wasn&amp;#8217;t effective, so they both restricted calories as well. So their metrics and tracking focused on those things in the weight loss part of their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While weight loss is a common reason for going Primal, it&amp;#8217;s not the only reason. The Success Stories make this clear. The writers had many other concerns, and they chose the PB, at least in part, as a means to healing themselves in some way or addressing medical conditions. As such, their metrics reflected those things. &lt;a title="No Grains Equals No Migraines" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/no-grains-equals-no-migraines/#axzz2J0RJodJG"&gt;Katie&lt;/a&gt; created pie charts of the foods she was eating to get at the cause of her migraines (among other reasons). &lt;a title="I Have Never Felt Better in My Life" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/i-have-never-felt-better-in-my-life/#axzz2NdAzonKg"&gt;Michael&lt;/a&gt; kept medical stats relating to an array of health concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does seem that a few writers geeked out over going Primal for the pure enjoyment of geeking out, and that&amp;#8217;s a great thing. It got them into the flow of their Primal Journeys and kept them focused. See e.g. &lt;a title="384 Days of Primal" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/384-days-of-primal-focusing-on-the-process-to-see-results/#axzz2NdhXwbK6"&gt;Shane&lt;/a&gt; (charted his entire first year of being Primal); &lt;a title="From Sugar Burn to Fat Burner: A Transformation Story" href="https://www.marksdailyapple.com/from-sugar-burner-to-fat-burner-a-transformation-story/"&gt;Jason&lt;/a&gt; (tracked weight, carb count, and blood work in his transformation from sugar burner to fat burner). There&amp;#8217;s much to learn from their efforts, so be sure to have a look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracking doesn&amp;#8217;t have to to be elaborate, and it doesn&amp;#8217;t even have to include numbers. You can keep a simple &lt;a title="The Primal Blueprint 90-Day Journal" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/The-Primal-Blueprint-90%252dDay-Journal.html" target="_blank"&gt;journal&lt;/a&gt; and write whatever is meaningful and helpful to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Takeaway #4&lt;/strong&gt;: Tracking is a powerful source of feedback. There are as many ways to track as there are people tracking. The idea is to track what&amp;#8217;s important to you in a way that makes sense for you and the change you&amp;#8217;re making. The same is true for metrics. It&amp;#8217;s where we get our much-needed answers to these fundamental questions: What are the effects of what I’m trying? What’s working? What isn’t? What’s next? Should I keep doing what I’m doing, or tweak and adjust it, or change courses entirely? It’s getting to these answers that propels us through the Motion loop of change, i.e. that powerful, continuing circle of try, learn, rework, that keeps us evolving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summing it all up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common threads running through the Success Stories comprise the essential behavioral principles that enable us to make a substantial life change and sustain it. That&amp;#8217;s what we&amp;#8217;re all trying to do here, in becoming and being Primal. Knowing what these essential principles are, and seeing how so many people have put them into action, will help you evolve all your Primal endeavors and any other change or self-evolution you have in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For those interested, I&amp;#8217;ve taken these essential principles of change and created a &amp;#8220;mind app&amp;#8221; out of them. It&amp;#8217;s called &lt;a href="http://app4mind.com"&gt;app4Mind&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;#8217;re all welcome to use it to change your life and &lt;a title="What Does it Mean to Grok on?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/what-does-it-mean-to-grok-on/"&gt;Grok on&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Order Your Copy of &lt;a title="The Primal Blueprint 90-Day Journal" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/The-Primal-Blueprint-90%252dDay-Journal.html" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Blueprint 90-Day Journal &lt;/a&gt;Today to Grok On and Keep Evolving&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/trMFbBo4MeY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-use-the-friday-success-stories-to-grok-on-and-keep-evolving/#comments" thr:count="91" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-use-the-friday-success-stories-to-grok-on-and-keep-evolving/feed/atom/" thr:count="91" />
		<thr:total>91</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Mark: Eggs, More Eggs, and Marathon Man]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/too-many-eggs-paleo-primal-marathon-man/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35893</id>
		<updated>2013-04-01T16:46:00Z</updated>
		<published>2013-04-01T15:00:34Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Dear Mark" /><category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Fitness" /><category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Nutrition" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For today&#8217;s edition of Dear Mark, we&#8217;re talking eggs, eggs, and marathons. First up are egg allergies/intolerances as determined by blood test. It&#8217;s not exactly clear what blood test was used to determine the inflammatory response to eggs, but regardless: the test was done and the reader is now worried about eggs, previously one of [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/too-many-eggs-paleo-primal-marathon-man/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" alt="eggs 2" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/eggs-2.jpg" width="320" height="212" title="Dear Mark: Eggs, More Eggs, and Marathon Man" /&gt;For today&amp;#8217;s edition of &lt;a title="Dear Mark" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/category/dear-mark/"&gt;Dear Mark&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;#8217;re talking &lt;a title="Dear Mark: Powdered Egg Alternatives and Heating Olive Oil" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/powdered-egg-alternatives-and-heating-olive-oil/"&gt;eggs&lt;/a&gt;, eggs, and &lt;a title="How to Fuel Ultra-Distances: The World’s Toughest Mudder" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-fuel-ultra-distances-the-worlds-toughest-mudder/"&gt;marathons&lt;/a&gt;. First up are egg allergies/intolerances as determined by blood test. It&amp;#8217;s not exactly clear what blood test was used to determine the inflammatory response to eggs, but regardless: the test was done and the reader is now worried about eggs, previously one of her favorite foods. Can she reintroduce eggs? Should she even worry at all? Next are eggs and blood lipids. Our reader&amp;#8217;s naturopath has warned against four times daily egg consumption because of elevated LDL, and she wants to know if there&amp;#8217;s really any reason to follow the advice. I lay out some of the evidence in favor of egg consumption; hopefully it&amp;#8217;s enough to satisfy. Finally, I discuss the curious case of Stefaan Engels, the man who ran 365 marathons in 365 days. Does he discredit my whole view of fitness, &lt;a title="Dear Mark: Maximum 4,000 Calories a Week of Exercise?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/dear-mark-maximum-4000-calories-a-week-of-exercise/"&gt;chronic cardio&lt;/a&gt;, and endurance training? Should you therefore take up daily marathoning? Read on to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35893"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had blood work done that showed eggs, and especially egg whites, were the number one food allergy causing inflammation in me. Eggs are one of my very favorite foods and because of the tests I have all but eliminated them from my diet. Is it possible that eggs can be reintroduced into my diet after some time on the primal blueprint?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for any suggestions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gayle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d be interested to hear exactly what this blood work consisted of, because if it was IgG allergy testing, I&amp;#8217;m not very convinced. Egg allergy is one thing, where you have a bite of food containing eggs and end up going into anaphylactic shock. That&amp;#8217;s bad, that&amp;#8217;s dangerous, and you can&amp;#8217;t really ignore it. If eggs are an imminent threat to your life and you feel awful eating them, by all means, listen to the blood work and eliminate the eggs. The simple fact that they are one of your favorite foods, however, makes me think that &lt;a title="Dear Mark: Egg Shell Calcium, Fully Hydrogenated Oils, HG Walking, Gorging, and Frozen Produce" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/dear-mark-egg-shell-calcium-fully-hydrogenated-oils-hg-walking-gorging-and-frozen-produce/"&gt;eggs&lt;/a&gt; aren&amp;#8217;t having a noticeable impact on your health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it was an IgG allergy test, there are serious doubts as to its accuracy and usefulness in identifying allergies or sensitivities. Chris Kresser, in one &lt;a title="RHR: Can Autoimmune Disease Be Prevented And Reversed?" href="http://chriskresser.com/rhr-can-autoimmune-disease-be-prevented-and-reversed" target="_blank"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, recounts how he once received back completely different results after sending two vials of his blood to the same lab for testing. And one &lt;a title="Patterns of immunoglobulin G responses to egg and peanut allergens are distinct: ovalbumin-specific immunoglobulin responses are ubiquitous, but peanut-specific immunoglobulin responses are up-regulated in peanut allergy." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17883730" target="_blank"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; even found that every subject tested positive for ovalbumin-specific (egg white) IgG levels, whether they had active egg allergies, resolved egg allergies, or were completely free of egg allergies. The authors suspect that &amp;#8220;strong IgG responses to OVA may be a normal physiological response to a protein frequently ingested from infancy.&amp;#8221; Another &lt;a title="High levels of IgG4 antibodies to foods during infancy are associated with tolerance to corresponding foods later in life." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18346097" target="_blank"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; found that children who had higher IgG responses to egg protein as infants actually &lt;em&gt;showed greater tolerance&lt;/em&gt; of egg protein later in life. If everyone has positive responses to egg-specific IgG levels regardless of allergic status, what&amp;#8217;s the point of testing? And if higher IgG responses to proteins have even been shown to indicate greater tolerance of said proteins, are IgG tests really useful in determining intolerances?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did they determine that they&amp;#8217;re causing &lt;a title="My Top 6 Anti-Inflammatory Foods" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/top-6-anti-inflammatory-foods/"&gt;inflammation&lt;/a&gt; in your body? Did you get a C-reactive protein test? Did they test for specific inflammatory cytokines? Or do you get symptoms of inflammation upon egg consumption &amp;#8211; achy joints, irritated skin, gastrointestinal upset? Or is the &amp;#8220;inflammation&amp;#8221; an abstract thing purely represented by numbers on a lab test? A blood test is rarely sufficient, particularly absent subjective symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may very well be sensitive to eggs. Many people are. But most people who are sensitive to eggs don&amp;#8217;t consider them a favorite food. You could be suffering from inconspicuous inflammation, doing damage to yourself without really knowing it. But in the absence of obvious symptoms, I&amp;#8217;d hesitate to banish eggs entirely from your diet. Eggs are nearly unparalleled in the nutrition realm. They&amp;#8217;re an excellent source of highly assimilable protein and vitamins like A, &lt;a title="2 More Common Nutrient Deficiencies (and What to Do About Them)" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/2-more-common-nutrient-deficiencies-and-what-to-do-about-them/"&gt;choline&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="5 Common Nutrient Deficiencies (and What to Do About Them)" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/5-common-nutrient-deficiencies-and-what-to-do-about-them/"&gt;K2&lt;/a&gt;, and folate, and they can be a good source of &lt;a title="Is It Primal? – Cod Liver Oil, Sunflower Butter, Mead, and Other Foods Scrutinized" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-paleo-cod-liver-oil-sunflower-butter-mead-maple-syrup-pectin/"&gt;omega-3s&lt;/a&gt; if the hen&amp;#8217;s diet is right.  Take them out for a few weeks to see how you react, sure. Nothing wrong with an elimination diet. That way, you&amp;#8217;ll get actual answers in about 30 days, and you&amp;#8217;ll be able to determine whether or not eggs are causing problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look into your intestinal permeability, too. Oftentimes errant food proteins worm their way into our blood stream by way of an overly permeable intestinal wall, thereby prompting an immune response. Eat more &lt;a title="Is It Primal? – Pork Rinds, Cottage Cheese, Monk Fruit Sweetener, and Other Foods Scrutinized" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-paleo-pork-rinds-cottage-cheese-monk-fruit-sweetener-sago-elderberry-syrup/"&gt;gelatin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Cooking with Bones" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/cooking-with-bones/"&gt;bone broth&lt;/a&gt;, consider &lt;a title="Putting Out the Fire: Gut Flora and the Inflammatory Cycle" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/gut-flora-inflammation/"&gt;probiotics&lt;/a&gt;, and eat some &lt;a title="A Primal Primer: Prebiotics" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/prebiotics/"&gt;fermentable fiber&lt;/a&gt; to improve your gut health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One final note: if it&amp;#8217;s egg white you&amp;#8217;re worried about and sensitive to, just eat the yolks. The yolks are the best part, anyway. If you trust your eggs, there&amp;#8217;s no better multivitamin than a few raw pastured egg yolks in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am seeing a naturopath and she is a bit worried about my LDL cholesterol, and is concerned I am eating too many eggs (3-4 for breakfast every day and the odd extra one with dinner). She says she normally doesn&amp;#8217;t worry about eggs but in my case maybe it&amp;#8217;s time to pull it back a bit&amp;#8230;.but hang on, everything I have read in paleo-land tells me that eggs are fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She said another comment that intruiged me, that because I fry my eggs (in coconut oil) or make an omelette that the yolk is exposed to air and they oxidise, and this may be the problem. She recommended cutting back to 2 eggs a day and only poaching under water or boiling. Have you ever heard such a thing and could it have any credence&amp;#8230;or is it time to find a new naturopath!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am one of your many readers from Australia and send you a big thanks for the work you do from Down Under.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Simone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of the evidence shows that egg consumption has either no effect or a favorable effect on &lt;a title="Are Eggs Really As Bad For Your Arteries as Cigarettes?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/are-eggs-really-as-bad-for-your-arteries-as-cigarettes/"&gt;serum lipids&lt;/a&gt;, particularly if you&amp;#8217;re eating low-carb/high-protein (terms which are usually synonymous in the medical literature):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Dietary cholesterol from eggs increases plasma HDL cholesterol in overweight men consuming a carbohydrate-restricted diet." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18203890" target="_blank"&gt;Dietary cholesterol from eggs increases HDL in overweight men on a low-carb diet and reduces markers of metabolic syndrome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of a high-protein diet, &lt;a title="Egg consumption as part of an energy-restricted high-protein diet improves blood lipid and blood glucose profiles in individuals with type 2 diabetes" href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21134328" target="_blank"&gt;egg consumption improves blood lipid and blood glucose profiles in type 2 diabetics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heck, if you&amp;#8217;re eating low-carb, eggs might actually make it work even better than a low-carb diet without eggs, probably due to the &lt;a title="Eggs modulate the inflammatory response to carbohydrate restricted diets in overweight men." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18289377" target="_blank"&gt;cholesterol increasing HDL and improving antioxidant function&lt;/a&gt;. Or, it might be the increase in HDL and LDL particle size (and probable reduction in HDL and LDL particle number) along with the &lt;a title="Eggs distinctly modulate plasma carotenoid and lipoprotein subclasses in adult men following a carbohydrate-restricted diet." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19369056" target="_blank"&gt;higher levels of circulating antioxidants&lt;/a&gt; doing the trick. Or both. Either way, eggs fit quite nicely into a Primal eating plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you could be a rare poor responder to eggs. Some people experience increases in cholesterol (although it&amp;#8217;s usually both HDL and LDL, so it ends up a wash in a sense). It probably won&amp;#8217;t hurt to spend a few weeks at a lower daily egg intake just to see what happens to your lipids. They might drop. You might feel even better than before. They could also drop, and you end up feeling worse. After all, cholesterol is converted into important hormones like pregnenolone and &lt;a title="Testosterone: Not So Manly After All?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/testosterone-women/"&gt;testosterone&lt;/a&gt; and vital prohormones like &lt;a title="Deconstructing Vitamin D" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/deconstructing-vitamin-d/"&gt;vitamin D&lt;/a&gt;. Lipoproteins also deliver nutrients (beyond just cholesterol) to cells. Lower cholesterol &amp;#8211; even LDL &amp;#8211; isn&amp;#8217;t always better. Don&amp;#8217;t ignore subjective measurements of health, like energy levels, &lt;a title="A Guide to Maintaining a Healthy Sex Drive" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/a-guide-to-maintaining-a-healthy-sex-drive/"&gt;libido&lt;/a&gt;, workout performance, and general feelings of awesomeness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxidized cholesterol from overcooked eggs might be able to increase the portion of oxidized cholesterol in your LDL particles, but I haven&amp;#8217;t seen any evidence that it would increase circulating levels of LDL. It&amp;#8217;s just that the LDL in your LDL particles might be a &lt;a title="The role of dietary oxidized cholesterol and oxidized fatty acids in the development of atherosclerosis." href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16270280" target="_blank"&gt;bit more oxidized and therefore prone to trigger atherosclerosis&lt;/a&gt;. Overall, I think the fear of oxidized cholesterol because you cooked up an omelet is overblown. High-heat, high-pressure spray drying of eggs? Yeah, &lt;a title="Quantification of Cholesterol Oxidation Products In Egg Yolk Powder Spray-dried with Direct Heating" href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1365-2621.1992.tb05420.x/abstract" target="_blank"&gt;that&amp;#8217;ll oxidize the cholesterol&lt;/a&gt;. Cooking them up in coconut oil? Scrambling and subjecting them to a hot buttered pan for a couple minutes? I don&amp;#8217;t think you have much to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I am quite partial to soft boiled eggs. I just pop three or four in my pressure cooker with a cup of water, set it to steam for three minutes, and immediately immerse them in cold water. The white comes out soft, smooth, and fully-cooked while the yolk remains warm and runny. I mostly do it because it&amp;#8217;s easy (I can just set the timer and walk away) and tasty (a runny yolk is paramount), but I can see it being &amp;#8220;healthier&amp;#8221; in that it eliminates any chance of cholesterol oxidation (not that I think we need to worry too much).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you explain Stefaan Engels? He ran a marathon everyday for a year, ate whatever he wanted, and showed no muscle or cartilage damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keerthana&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engels is certainly impressive, but he&amp;#8217;s pretty easy to explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;#8217;s an outlier, well-suited for marathon running. I&amp;#8217;ve never argued that you can&amp;#8217;t &lt;a title="Dear Mark: Fenugreek and HGH, Marathons and Strength Training, Gluten and Eczema, and Insect Nutrition" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/dear-mark-fenugreek-and-hgh-marathons-and-strength-training-gluten-and-eczema-and-insect-nutrition/"&gt;run marathons&lt;/a&gt; and be healthy. I&amp;#8217;ve merely argued that running and (most importantly) training for marathons at an elite level usually means avoiding other beneficial ways to train, and results in aches, pains, and injuries. Just because lots of &lt;a title="Why We Don’t Walk Anymore (plus a Primal Health Challenge)" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/why-we-dont-walk-anymore/"&gt;slow moving&lt;/a&gt;, some sprinting, and heavy lifting (and even some endurance work alongside) builds more lean mass and more well-rounded fitness in a fraction of the time doesn&amp;#8217;t mean marathoning means certain death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to take anything away, but it was a parlor trick. He took an average of four hours to complete each marathon, which means he was taking a little over nine minutes per mile. For him, an elite endurance athlete (and accomplished triathlete), he probably never got past 60% of his max heart rate, which might not even qualify as chronic cardio in his case. A 9+ minute/mile pace is far better than most people could do, but it&amp;#8217;s not very hard for him. He was taking it relatively easy. Engels&amp;#8217; best time was 2:56, and 4:00 is an easy jog for a guy with a sub 3:00 marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for eating whatever he wanted, exactly! When you&amp;#8217;re training for marathons like I was, you have to be willing to shovel just about anything in, purely for the easy and quick calories. Superhuman levels of athletics often require superhuman levels of consumption &amp;#8211; just look at Michael Phelps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing against Engels or his feats, mind you. But his situation really isn&amp;#8217;t applicable to the average Joe, for whom I write my books and my blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were runners in the 1970s who regularly did 250 training miles a week and then raced hard and fast. My friend Dave McGillivray &lt;a title="Cool Running" href="http://www.coolrunning.com/dmse/davecontr.htm" target="_blank"&gt;ran across the USA (3,452 miles) in 80 days&lt;/a&gt;. He turned out fine, but most of the other guys are dead or ailing now. Many of my triathlon buds had no signs of damage during their careers, but years later had big problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, you can do it, but it doesn&amp;#8217;t mean you should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s it for this week, guys. Thanks for reading and be sure to leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grab a Copy of &lt;a title="Amazon.com: The Primal Connection" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0984755101/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=marsdaiapp07-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0984755101" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Connection: Follow Your Genetic Blueprint to Health and Happiness&lt;/a&gt; Today!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/bqME8DGUHGQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/too-many-eggs-paleo-primal-marathon-man/#comments" thr:count="87" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/too-many-eggs-paleo-primal-marathon-man/feed/atom/" thr:count="87" />
		<thr:total>87</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekend Link Love]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/weekend-link-love-236/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35870</id>
		<updated>2013-03-29T00:19:18Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-31T15:00:03Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Health" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last-minute tickets for PrimalCon Oxnard 2013 (April 11-14) are now available due to some cancellations. Space is limited. Order your tickets today before spots run out! Tickets for PrimalCon Austin 2013 are also available. Join us June 6-9 for an event you&#8217;ll never forget. Thank you for sharing your excitement for upcoming Primal Blueprint books [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/weekend-link-love-236/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" alt="chain 1" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/chain-1.jpg" width="320" height="282" title="Weekend Link Love" /&gt;Last-minute tickets for &lt;a title="PrimalCon Oxnard 2013" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/PrimalCon-Oxnard-2013.html"&gt;PrimalCon Oxnard 2013&lt;/a&gt; (April 11-14) are now available due to some cancellations. Space is limited. Order your tickets today before spots run out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets for &lt;a title="PrimalCon Austin 2013" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/PrimalCon-Austin-2013.html"&gt;PrimalCon Austin 2013&lt;/a&gt; are also available. Join us June 6-9 for an event you&amp;#8217;ll never forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for sharing your excitement for &lt;a title="10 New Primal Blueprint Books" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/10-new-primal-blueprint-books-plus-a-prize-package-giveaway/"&gt;upcoming Primal Blueprint books&lt;/a&gt; and your ideas for new titles last week. The randomly selected winner of the prize package giveaway is &lt;a title="Susy Fry's Comment" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/10-new-primal-blueprint-books-plus-a-prize-package-giveaway/comment-page-12/#comment-924027"&gt;Susy Fry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Research of the Week&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transfer of &amp;#8220;lean&amp;#8221; gut flora into the sterile guts of obese mice triggered rapid fat loss in a &lt;a title="New Way to Lose Weight? Changing Microbes in Guts of Mice Resulted in Rapid Weight Loss" href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2013/03/130327144124.htm" target="_blank"&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35870"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were far from human subjects, but &lt;a title="Fruit Flies Fed Organic Diets Are Healthier Than Flies Fed Nonorganic Diets, Study Finds" href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2013/03/130326121732.htm" target="_blank"&gt;fruit flies fed an organic diet enjoyed better health outcomes&lt;/a&gt; than fruit flies fed a non-organic diet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Interesting Blog Posts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How one Primal kid &lt;a title="My Plate and Schools….What We Did in Response!" href="http://aprimalfamily.com/2013/03/21/my-plate-and-schools-what-we-did-in-response/" target="_blank"&gt;fought back against MyPlate&lt;/a&gt; and came up with his own &amp;#8211; far superior, in my opinion &amp;#8211; version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Roberts&lt;/strong&gt; recently explored &lt;a title="Earwax Transplant Story" href="http://blog.sethroberts.net/2013/03/24/earwax-transplant-story/" target="_blank"&gt;earwax transplantations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Media, Schmedia&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logan LaPlante &lt;a title="13 year old Logan LaPlante: Hackschooling Makes Me Happy" href="http://www.social-consciousness.com/2013/03/hackschooling-makes-me-happy-13yo-logan-laplante.html" target="_blank"&gt;knows what he wants to be when he grows up&lt;/a&gt;: happy. What about you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwyneth Paltrow may get a lot of flak for deciding not to feed her kids empty carbs, but &lt;a title="Why Gwyneth Paltrow's no-carb diet for children makes perfect sense" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/shortcuts/2013/mar/13/gwyneth-paltrow-no-carb-diet-perfect-sense" target="_blank"&gt;not everyone agrees with the criticism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Everything Else&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/carter_allan/status/316695343599345664/photo/1" target="_blank"&gt;No one can fully digest gluten&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;#8221; said the Mayo Clinic doc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ability to truly connect with other human beings is a physiological entity that must be trained and maintained or else wither into dystrophy, like muscle. &lt;a title="Your Phone vs. Your Heart" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/24/opinion/sunday/your-phone-vs-your-heart.html?ref=opinion&amp;amp;_r=1&amp;amp;" target="_blank"&gt;Does excessive smartphone usage trigger empathy detraining&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Recipe Corner&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leafy greens are one thing conventional health advice gets right, and sometimes we need a reminder. Here&amp;#8217;s a nice, simple, delicious recipe for &lt;a title="German-Style Simmered Spinach" href="http://thedomesticman.com/2013/03/26/german-style-simmered-spinach/" target="_blank"&gt;German-style simmered spinach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="Zucchini Waffle Sandwiches" href="http://thesaffrongirl.com/zucchini-waffle-sandwiches/" target="_blank"&gt;Zucchini waffle sandwiches&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Time Capsule&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One year ago (Mar 31 – Apr 6)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="Is Eating Meat Ethical?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/is-eating-meat-ethical/"&gt;Is Eating Meat Ethical?&lt;/a&gt; – My entry for the infamous NY Times essay contest on ethical meat eating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="Why Fast? Part Four - Brain Health" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/fasting-brain-function/"&gt;Why Fast? Part Four &amp;#8211; Brain Health&lt;/a&gt; – How skipping breakfast can impact your neurological function for the better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Comment of the Week&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post is starting to sound like some bizarre game of foodie one-upmanship:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The most exotic thing I’VE ever had was manatee muzzle sauteed in badger bile!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, is that anything like camel colon smothered in snake snot?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- For &lt;a title="Primal Abroad: Food Adventures from Around the World  " href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-abroad-food-adventures-from-around-the-world/#ixzz2OsreOMNm"&gt;what it&amp;#8217;s worth&lt;/a&gt;, camel colon is high in butyrate and snake snot is a rich source of DHA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get All Three Primal Cookbooks, an Apron and More in &lt;a title="The Primal Blueprint Chef Kit" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/The-Primal-Blueprint-Chef-Kit.html" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Blueprint Chef Kit&lt;/a&gt; Today!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/0GNBVSEYM_U" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/weekend-link-love-236/#comments" thr:count="15" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/weekend-link-love-236/feed/atom/" thr:count="15" />
		<thr:total>15</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Worker Bee</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese Five Spice Pork Chops with Sautéed Escarole]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/chinese-five-spice-pork-chops-sauteed-escarole/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35872</id>
		<updated>2013-03-28T23:22:39Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-30T15:00:05Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Recipes" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Escarole is mostly thought of as a salad green, but like most greens, it’s capable of so much more than that. In this recipe, a hint of vinegar, a pat of butter and a scant drizzle of maple syrup turn escarole into a warm side dish that’s perfect with pork. It’s a bold medley of [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/chinese-five-spice-pork-chops-sauteed-escarole/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" alt="EscaroleampPork2" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/EscaroleampPork2.jpg" width="320" height="212" title="Chinese Five Spice Pork Chops with Sautéed Escarole" /&gt;Escarole is mostly thought of as a salad green, but like most &lt;a title="Why You Should Eat Leafy Greens" href="https://www.marksdailyapple.com/why-you-should-eat-leafy-greens/"&gt;greens&lt;/a&gt;, it’s capable of so much more than that. In this recipe, a hint of &lt;a title="How to Make Red Wine Vinegar" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-make-red-wine-vinegar/"&gt;vinegar&lt;/a&gt;, a pat of &lt;a title="Is All Butter Created Equal?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/grass-fed-butter/"&gt;butter&lt;/a&gt; and a scant drizzle of &lt;a title="Is Maple Syrup Healthy?" href="https://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-paleo-cod-liver-oil-sunflower-butter-mead-maple-syrup-pectin/"&gt;maple syrup&lt;/a&gt; turn escarole into a warm side dish that’s perfect with pork. It’s a bold medley of sweet, salty and pleasantly bitter flavors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bitter flavor of escarole can be a “love it” or “hate it” thing. This recipe is meant to woo both sides. The bitterness is still noticeable, but tamed by a magic combination of pork, butter and maple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35872"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chops are seasoned with Chinese Five Spice, giving the pork both a little heat and the sweet aromatic flavor of cinnamon, cloves and fennel. The butter and maple syrup further balance out the bitter flavor of the escarole, but you don’t have to add maple syrup to make this dish great. Skip it, and you’ll still have a delicious meal with bold flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very large head of escarole wilts down to four small servings when cooked. Plan to serve another side with the meal, or, if you really love escarole, cook two heads instead of one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serves:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time in the Kitchen:&lt;/strong&gt; 35 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="ingredients 56" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/ingredients-56.jpg" width="540" height="360" title="Chinese Five Spice Pork Chops with Sautéed Escarole" /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 pork chops, about 1-inch thick (2.5 cm)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon Chinese five spice (5 ml)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon salt (2.5 ml)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/4 teaspoon black pepper (1.25 ml)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon olive oil (15 ml)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 large head of escarole (about 1 pound)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon apple cider vinegar (15 ml)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon maple syrup (5ml)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons butter (30 ml)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instructions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preheat the oven to 350 ºF (176 ºC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the pork chops out of the refrigerator so they come to room temperature. Season both sides of the pork chops with Chinese Five Spice, salt and black pepper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cut the bottom stem off the escarole and wash the leaves well since they tend to hold dirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="escarole" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/escarole.jpg" width="540" height="360" title="Chinese Five Spice Pork Chops with Sautéed Escarole" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before or after washing the leaves, tear them into bite-sized pieces. Ideally the leaves should be as dry as possible before cooking them. A salad spinner works well for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heat a large ovenproof skillet over medium-high heat and add olive oil (or coconut oil, or a combination of olive oil and butter). When the oil is nice and hot add the chops, searing for 3 minutes without moving them. Flip the chops and sear for 1 minute more then put the pan in the oven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start checking the chops after 3 minutes to gauge if they’re done. The temperature in the thickest part of the chop should be around 140 ºF. (60 ºC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="Step1 5" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/Step1-5.jpg" width="540" height="360" title="Chinese Five Spice Pork Chops with Sautéed Escarole" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove the chops from the skillet and set the meat aside. Put the skillet back on the stove over medium-high heat and immediately add the vinegar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it boils scrape the bits of meat up off the bottom of the skillet. The vinegar will quickly evaporate – when it’s evaporated by at least half and almost gone add the butter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="Step2 5" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/Step2-5.jpg" width="540" height="360" title="Chinese Five Spice Pork Chops with Sautéed Escarole" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swirl it around the skillet, when it’s mostly melted add the maple syrup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the escarole. It probably won’t all fit in the skillet at once. Let the first batch wilt a little bit, then add the rest. Sauté, stirring frequently, for 5 to 8 minutes until the leaves are tender but not totally limp. Overcooked escarole tends to be soggy or even slimy, so get it out of the skillet sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="Step3 1" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/Step3-1.jpg" width="540" height="342" title="Chinese Five Spice Pork Chops with Sautéed Escarole" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finish the pork and escarole with a sprinkle of &lt;a href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/pepper-and-salt-varieties/"&gt;sea salt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="EscaroleampPork1" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/EscaroleampPork1.jpg" width="540" height="360" title="Chinese Five Spice Pork Chops with Sautéed Escarole" /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get All Three Primal Cookbooks, an Apron and More in &lt;a title="The Primal Blueprint Chef Kit" href="http://primalblueprint.com/products/The-Primal-Blueprint-Chef-Kit.html" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Blueprint Chef Kit&lt;/a&gt; Today!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/LXyZ44eOAEs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/chinese-five-spice-pork-chops-sauteed-escarole/#comments" thr:count="30" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/chinese-five-spice-pork-chops-sauteed-escarole/feed/atom/" thr:count="30" />
		<thr:total>30</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[I Am Now Blessed with Radiant Health and Boundless Energy]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/i-am-now-blessed-with-radiant-health-and-boundless-energy/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35880</id>
		<updated>2013-03-28T23:56:02Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-29T15:00:44Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Success Stories" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s Friday, everyone! And that means another Primal Blueprint Real Life Story from a Mark&#8217;s Daily Apple reader. If you have your own success story and would like to share it with me and the Mark’s Daily Apple community please contact me here. I’ll continue to publish these each Friday as long as they keep [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/i-am-now-blessed-with-radiant-health-and-boundless-energy/">&lt;div class="breakout"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s Friday, everyone! And that means another &lt;a title="Success Stories" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/category/success-story-summaries/"&gt;Primal Blueprint Real Life Story&lt;/a&gt; from a Mark&amp;#8217;s Daily Apple reader. If you have your own success story and would like to share it with me and the Mark’s Daily Apple community please contact me &lt;a title="Contact Me!" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-book/share-success-story/" target="_self"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I’ll continue to publish these each Friday as long as they keep coming in. Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" title="Primal Blueprint Real Life Story" alt="real life stories stories 1 2" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA2009/real_life_stories_stories-1-2.jpg" width="320" height="240" /&gt;Hi Mark,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up with two parents as doctors, I always felt like I had a basic understanding of health and wellness. I was always a lively, active and rambunctious child, but struggled with a myriad of digestive health issues from the early age of 14. My problems seemed to appear during my sophomore year in high school. During the middle of the school year, I transitioned from the Atkins Diet to a full-fledged bout of Mononucleosis (Mono). For four straight weeks, I ate nothing but Jack In The Box milkshakes (Vanilla or Chocolate, sometimes a swirl of both&amp;#8230;). When I finally started eating solid food again, my stomach was completely wrecked, and things didn&amp;#8217;t work themselves out the way I anticipated. All of the sudden, I had a sluggish digestive system and on the daily was plagued with chronic abdominal discomfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35880"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it became apparent that my issues weren&amp;#8217;t just a temporary affliction from my illness, my mother and I saw several different gastroenterologists hoping to bring some sort of relief to my seemingly chronic issues. Not one doctor ever mentioned that my abdominal issues could be diet related. NOT ONE. Every physician I saw decided that a supplement of some bark-tasting-sort would be the cure-all-end-all of my issues, and wrote me a prescription and sent me on my way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After zero success and many dollars down the drain, I started to feel like I was blessed with a body that would cause me pain for the rest of my life. I retained weight, had little energy to get through my day and developed a deep love for a quadruple shot sugar-filled coffee beverage to start my morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="beforefunny" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/beforefunny.jpg" width="540" height="405" title="I Am Now Blessed with Radiant Health and Boundless Energy" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was 21, I came home from college on vacation and visited my grandparents in Eugene, Oregon. My grandmother has Celiac Disease, and for the first time, I was inquisitive as to what that actually meant. I picked my grandfather&amp;#8217;s brain, and after talking, I became convinced that gluten was the root of all of my problems. I went back to school after doing hours and hours of research and decided to do a controlled study with my diet. I eliminated all gluten-containing products, and almost instantly, it seemed that all of my digestive problems had gone away. After several years of struggling and many visits to the doctor, I was finally sure that I figured out the root of my problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="before 2" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/before-2.jpg" width="540" height="405" title="I Am Now Blessed with Radiant Health and Boundless Energy" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward another two years. I was 23, graduated from college, traveling the world, teaching yoga and practicing a strict vegetarian diet. I developed adult acne, ovarian cysts, kidney stones and had extreme hormonal imbalance. I was exercising several times a week, and couldn&amp;#8217;t sleep enough during the day because of chronic fatigue. I began to think, again, maybe my sickness and lack of well-being has to do with my diet. I started integrating animal protein back into my diet which made me feel 100% better, but all of the sudden, my digestive issues presented themselves again. I was still eating gluten-free, I was doing all of the right things, I thought, and I couldn&amp;#8217;t seem to fix the chronic problem. It was infuriating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make a short story long, I had the blessed opportunity to stumble upon your website. I had been gluten-free, vegetarian, raw, vegan and anything in between. I  finally knew I felt more energized and healthier eating meat, but never considered other grains to have any influence on my gut. I figured if it didn&amp;#8217;t have gluten, it was healthy, so I ate my weight in grains, especially corn (psuedo grain), on the daily. I decided to adopt the Primal lifestyle, and it has completely flipped my life upside down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="after" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/after.jpg" width="540" height="405" title="I Am Now Blessed with Radiant Health and Boundless Energy" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now, for the last year and a half, blessed with radiant health, boundless energy and a stomach free of any digestive issues whatsoever. My weight, for the first time in my life, is stable. I am completely off of hormones from birth control, and my mood stays stable and my skin stays clear. I don&amp;#8217;t experience brutal hunger pains, and intermittent fasting is easy. My mother, a physician, has also adopted this ancestral lifestyle, and is transitioning out of standard medicine into the field of anti-aging, utilizing ancestral, primal nutritional counseling with her patients. I, at the age of 24, am about two weeks away from opening my first restaurant in Austin, TX called Picnik, a reclaimed shipping container/mobile food truck which is 100% primal, gluten-free and grain-free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only has this information changed my health and wellness forever, it has also catapulted me onto a brand new path in my life and work. I can&amp;#8217;t thank you enough for the teachings you provide, and I look forward to seeing you at &lt;a title="Facebook: Picnik Austin" href=" http://www.facebook.com/pages/Picnik-Austin/488539137873535?ref=hl" target="_blank"&gt;Picnik&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="glamshot" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/glamshot.jpg" width="540" height="405" title="I Am Now Blessed with Radiant Health and Boundless Energy" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Naomi&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a title="Facebook: Picnik Austin" href=" http://www.facebook.com/pages/Picnik-Austin/488539137873535?ref=hl" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="picnik" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/picnik.jpg" width="270" height="140" title="I Am Now Blessed with Radiant Health and Boundless Energy" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grab a Copy of &lt;a title="Amazon.com: The Primal Connection" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0984755101/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=marsdaiapp07-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0984755101" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Connection: Follow Your Genetic Blueprint to Health and Happiness&lt;/a&gt; Today!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/tjVozrgcXBo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/i-am-now-blessed-with-radiant-health-and-boundless-energy/#comments" thr:count="84" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/i-am-now-blessed-with-radiant-health-and-boundless-energy/feed/atom/" thr:count="84" />
		<thr:total>84</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Health Integrity Matters, or The Power of Being Honest with Yourself]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/why-health-integrity-matters-or-the-power-of-being-honest-with-yourself/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35839</id>
		<updated>2013-03-28T05:59:44Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-28T15:00:31Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Personal Improvement" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once upon a hunter-gather time, people generally lived in accordance with what made them healthy. Before we put Grok and his clan on a idyllic pedestal, it’s important to note they had little choice. They otherwise weren’t likely to see the next chapter of the Paleolithic story. Even in the best of personal circumstances and [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/why-health-integrity-matters-or-the-power-of-being-honest-with-yourself/">&lt;img class="alignright" alt="yoga 1" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/yoga-1.jpg" width="300" height="300" title="Why Health Integrity Matters, or The Power of Being Honest with Yourself" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a hunter-gather time, people generally lived in accordance with what made them healthy. Before we put &lt;a title="Who is Grok?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/about-2/who-is-grok/"&gt;Grok&lt;/a&gt; and his clan on a idyllic pedestal, it’s important to note they had little choice. They otherwise &lt;a title="My Knee is Killing Me… No, Really." href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/paleo-lifespan/"&gt;weren’t likely to see the next chapter of the Paleolithic story&lt;/a&gt;. Even in the best of personal circumstances and choices, many succumbed to all manner of prehistorical threats. Still, in terms of lifestyle, the health imperative was there. They had to move. They had to &lt;a title="It's time to &amp;quot;Get Real&amp;quot;" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/get-real-achieve-your-health-goals-lose-weight-get-ripped-stay-motivated/"&gt;eat real food&lt;/a&gt;. They lived and slept generally speaking by the cycle of their &lt;a title="Circadian Rhythms: Zeitgebers, Entrainment, and Non-Photic Stimuli" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/circadian-rhythms-zeitgebers-entrainment-and-non-photic-stimuli/"&gt;circadian rhythms&lt;/a&gt;. They got &lt;a title="Vitamin D: Sun Exposure, Supplementation and Doses" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/vitamin-d-sun-exposure-supplementation-and-doses/"&gt;sun&lt;/a&gt;. They &lt;a title="Social Wellness, or Why Friendship Should Be a Health Priority" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/social-wellness-health-research/#axzz28IRjCiwj"&gt;socialized&lt;/a&gt;. There just wasn’t reason to question any of it because few if any alternatives existed: next &lt;a title="Are Humans Hard Wired For A Limited Social Circle?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/dunbars-number-group-size/#axzz26gvjHyXL"&gt;band&lt;/a&gt;, same options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35839"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we have infinite possibilities, and we suffer as well as benefit a great deal for it. We have the option of sitting on the couch all weekend watching a Game of Thrones marathon. We have the potential to eat at McDonald&amp;#8217;s for thirty days straight. We can buy a pack of cigarettes despite the fact we’re hooked up to an oxygen tank. We can have our doctor up our &lt;a title="The Definitive Guide to Insulin, Blood Sugar &amp;amp; Type 2 Diabetes (and you’ll understand it)" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/diabetes/insulin"&gt;insulin&lt;/a&gt; dosage and buy a large Slurpee or a Krispy Kreme on the way home. We can &lt;a title="The Definitive Guide to Stress, Cortisol and the Adrenals" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/cortisol/"&gt;stress&lt;/a&gt; ourselves to our last, pathetic nerve (and &lt;a title="When Listening to Your Body Doesn't Work - Part 2" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/when-listening-to-your-body-doesnt-work-part-2/"&gt;adrenal exhaustion&lt;/a&gt;) by living on too much work, too little sleep, too much worry, and too many stimulants. &lt;strong&gt;We have the choice &amp;#8211; and that’s exactly what it is: a choice. Whatever our past, whatever our present condition, however, we are always free to &lt;a title="What I Mean by “Reprogram Your Genes”" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/epigenetics/"&gt;make a different next choice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can talk physiology until we’re blue in the face. We can read and learn what’s really healthy until we could fill a book or a blog ourselves. We can have a kitchen full of healthy cookbooks. We can listen to our doctors’ most enlightened (shout out to &lt;a title="Primal Docs" href="http://primaldocs.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Primal Docs&lt;/a&gt;!), encouraging words. &lt;strong&gt;In the end, however, it doesn’t come down to know-how or how-tos. It’s about how willing we are to accept personal responsibility for our health.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responsibility. It’s a hard and, for some, harsh word. In a culture that glorifies rampant immaturity and immediate gratification, the concept can seem like a major buzz kill. When it comes to health, I think the association is especially true. It’s okay to work out, for example, but no one wants to be seen taking it too seriously. Even major athletes joke about the junk they eat and rake in the bucks starring in fast food ads. It’s okay to shell out for grass-fed beef, but the minute you &lt;a title="How to Politely Pass on Dessert" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/how-to-politely-pass-on-dessert/"&gt;turn down dessert&lt;/a&gt;, you’re a killjoy who’s trying to make other people feel bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, the massive health problems in our country are in part fueled by &lt;a title="Statin Insanity" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/statin-insanity/"&gt;false medical messaging&lt;/a&gt; that leads well-intentioned people down the wrong roads in search of health. Much of it, however, can simply be attributed to an unwillingness to buck up, take responsibility choice by choice, and live with health integrity. By health integrity, I mean &lt;strong&gt;an honesty to one’s self, a commitment that begins and ends with one’s self, an inner compass that has nothing to do with the outside world&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To cultivate that kind of health integrity, we have to acknowledge that everything counts. There are no games, no hiding, no pretending, &lt;a title="Stare Your Excuses in the Face, and Take Control of Your Health" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/stare-your-excuses-in-the-face-and-take-control-of-your-health/#axzz2OnzQnCe3"&gt;no excuses&lt;/a&gt;. That doesn’t mean people with health integrity don’t eat a dessert sometimes, but there’s no emotional ruse or hand-wringing to it. You own it &amp;#8211; &lt;a title="Will Momentary Compromises Derail Your Efforts?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/will-momentary-compromises-derail-your-efforts/"&gt;for all the good and bad&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a title="The Blame Game" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/the-blame-game/"&gt;You don’t blame outside pressures or people&lt;/a&gt;. You don’t deal in &lt;a title="Reflect, Regroup, Resolve" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/reflect-regroup-resolve/"&gt;regret&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the problem is a misplaced fascination with the transgressive. Somehow cheating ourselves is the ultimate gratification. &lt;strong&gt;We mistake indulgence for decadence, discipline for deprivation.&lt;/strong&gt; Healthy behaviors are assigned the boring, white-hat, “moral” role in our culture. Being healthy is about hard work and &lt;a title="Is the Primal Blueprint a Type of Asceticism?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/ascetic-diet/"&gt;asceticism&lt;/a&gt;. Choosing health is about saying “no.” At least that’s the message we get. On the other side of the spectrum is the Mountain Dew adventure and Doritos-inspired hilarity that could fill our days &amp;#8211; if we were only so bold and rebellious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You live with health integrity when you truly own your journey, when you realize it’s yours and yours alone.&lt;/strong&gt; You stop living the old blame game and buying into the false dichotomies, the pedantic guilt trips, the bullsh** marketing messages, the cultural labels, the past-imposed limitations and identities. There’s a real freedom in that decision. It doesn’t matter whether you’re at the beginning of your &lt;a title="It's a Journey, Not a Race" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/its-a-journey-not-a-race/"&gt;journey&lt;/a&gt; with a hundred pounds to lose and a collection of lifestyle conditions to beat or if you’re at your &lt;a title="Dear Mark: Healthy Body Weight?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/healthy-body-weight/"&gt;ideal weight&lt;/a&gt; and healthy but want to know what it is to &lt;a title="Thriving, Not Just Surviving" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/thrive-survive/"&gt;thrive&lt;/a&gt; in new ways.&lt;strong&gt; It’s your journey, and from here on out, you get to define it.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t make the rules of physiology, but you do get to design the vision you will live out each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that way, living with health integrity suggests a level of authenticity and self-determination. Once you accept (not the cerebral, oh-it’s-good-for-me kind of logical acknowledgement but the gut-level, psychically moving, surrendering to, kind of assimilation) your journey as your own, you take pride in your health. Cultivating a sense of well-being opens up your life rather than restricts it. &lt;strong&gt;It’s not about self-restraint but self-possession.&lt;/strong&gt; The more you practice and hone it, the more you come into yourself. Discipline encourages creativity rather than resentment. It’s less about control than composure in the face of daily challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, as much as health integrity calls us to live from a personal center, it doesn’t make us self-centered. When we’re good with our selves, when we have genuine self-respect, we can live in relationships more &lt;a title="Primal Actualization: Realizing Your Inner Potential" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-actualization-realizing-your-inner-potential/"&gt;authentically&lt;/a&gt; and productively with others. No longer an enabler to ourselves, we can offer &lt;a title="Prodding Parents to Get Healthy" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/prodding-parents-to-get-healthy/"&gt;honest and meaningful help to others&lt;/a&gt;. Again and again, I hear readers say how much they appreciate the sense of genuine &lt;a title="MDA Forum" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/forum/"&gt;community&lt;/a&gt; they feel here, and it’s one of the main reasons I’ve made this my primary vocation. I love to see how people, when empowered themselves, contribute to the empowerment of others. It brings our intention and success full circle, and we can appreciate them all the more in doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks for reading today, everyone. Let me know what you think, and have a great weekend ahead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grab a Copy of &lt;a title="Amazon.com: The Primal Connection" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0984755101/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=marsdaiapp07-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0984755101" target="_blank"&gt;The Primal Connection: Follow Your Genetic Blueprint to Health and Happiness&lt;/a&gt; Today!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/1Rr8aeolgVU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/why-health-integrity-matters-or-the-power-of-being-honest-with-yourself/#comments" thr:count="158" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/why-health-integrity-matters-or-the-power-of-being-honest-with-yourself/feed/atom/" thr:count="158" />
		<thr:total>158</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[10 New Primal Blueprint Books (Plus a Prize Package Giveaway)]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/10-new-primal-blueprint-books-plus-a-prize-package-giveaway/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35785</id>
		<updated>2013-03-27T23:20:51Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-27T15:00:11Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Announcements" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As I mentioned back in my New Year&#8217;s post, Primal Blueprint Publishing has launched, and my team and I are on a mission to change lives, one book at a time! Last month, we released Mira and Jayson Calton&#8217;s Rich Food, Poor Food, and early reader feedback has been incredibly positive. With ten more books either [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/10-new-primal-blueprint-books-plus-a-prize-package-giveaway/">&lt;img class="alignright" alt="DSC01191 2" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/DSC01191-2.jpg" width="320" height="238" title="10 New Primal Blueprint Books (Plus a Prize Package Giveaway)" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned back in my &lt;a title="New Year, New You" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/new-year-new-you-making-2013-your-best-year-yet/"&gt;New Year&amp;#8217;s post&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Primal Blueprint Publishing" href="http://primalblueprintpublishing.com" target="_blank"&gt;Primal Blueprint Publishing&lt;/a&gt; has launched, and my team and I are on a mission to change lives, one book at a time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, we released Mira and Jayson Calton&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a title="Rich Food, Poor Food" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/introducing-rich-food-poor-food/#axzz2NYBifydG"&gt;Rich Food, Poor Food&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, and early reader feedback has been incredibly positive. With ten more books either nearing release or in development and with many of you emailing me asking for details, I thought I&amp;#8217;d take a moment to share with you what I have in the pipeline. Whether you&amp;#8217;re just starting or are a Primal veteran, I think there&amp;#8217;s something here for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Prize Package Giveaway&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d love to hear what you think. In the comment board below, &lt;strong&gt;let me know which of the ten books below you&amp;#8217;re most excited about and why, and tell me your idea(s) for a book you think Primal Blueprint Publishing needs to publish&lt;/strong&gt;. Do those two things and you&amp;#8217;ll be entered to win all eight Primal Blueprint books pictured to the right. The lucky winner will be chosen at random. &lt;strong&gt;This contest ends at 11:59 pm, Thursday, Mar. 28.&lt;/strong&gt; Many thanks to everyone that shares their thoughts and, in so doing, helps me make better books for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First up, a look at the books with 2013 release dates:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35785"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a title="The Hidden Plague" href="http://www.primalblueprintpublishing.com/books/the-hidden-plague/" target="_blank"&gt;The Hidden Plague&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/b&gt; by &lt;a title="Tara Grant" href="http://www.primalblueprintpublishing.com/authors/tara-grant/" target="_blank"&gt;Tara Grant&lt;/a&gt;. This book is for sufferers of &lt;i&gt;Hidradenitis supprativa&lt;/i&gt;, a painful skin condition that is poorly understood by the mainstream medical community and strongly associated with the Standard American Diet. Tara suffered for decades before taking matters into her own hands, modifying her diet, and curing herself. There are an estimated 12 million sufferers of this condition in the USA, with many of them unaware of their condition. Tara provides a field guide to managing and overcoming this disease using evolutionary health principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a title="Primal Cravings" href="http://www.primalblueprintpublishing.com/books/primal-cravings/" target="_blank"&gt;Primal Cravings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;/b&gt;by &lt;a title="Megan and Brandom Keatley" href="http://www.primalblueprintpublishing.com/authors/megan-and-brandon-keatley/" target="_blank"&gt;Megan and Brandon Keatley&lt;/a&gt;. Well the title says it all here! Welcome back all the comfort foods that you&amp;#8217;ve disciplined yourself to avoid in pursuit of Primal/paleo dietary principles. This creative, beautifully photographed book is the work of Brandon and Megan Keatley, Crossfit trainers in South Carolina who have dabbled and experimented and reclaimed some of the most indulgent foods you can imagine as Primal/paleo approved! See for yourself, starting with the delicious burger on the cover!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a title="Paleo Primer" href="http://www.primalblueprintpublishing.com/paleo-primer/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Paleo Primer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. This book from the British couple &lt;a title="Keris Marsden and Matt Whitmore" href="http://www.primalblueprintpublishing.com/authors/keris-marsden-and-matt-whitmore/" target="_blank"&gt;Keris Marsden and Matt Whitmore&lt;/a&gt; sets forth the Primal/paleo living principles in a fun, simple manner, making it a great book to introduce newcomers to the movement. It&amp;#8217;s filled with creative and delicious recipes, and memorable, humorous cartoons that capture the essence of Primal/paleo living at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upcoming Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a look at some exciting projects in development for 2014 release:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Death by Food Pyramid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, by Denise Minger. Denise has done numerous guests posts on MDA (&lt;a href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/will-eating-whole-grain-fiber-help-you-live-longer/#axzz2NYDPaDV4" target="_blank"&gt;Will Eating Whole Grains Help You Live Longer?&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Permanent Link to Will Eating Red Meat Kill You?" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/will-eating-red-meat-kill-you/" rel="bookmark"&gt;Will Eating Red Meat Kill You?&lt;/a&gt;), and has her own avid following at her &lt;a title="Raw Food SOS" href="http://rawfoodsos.com/about/" target="_blank"&gt;Raw Food SOS blog.&lt;/a&gt; Denise has been hard at work for a great many months now on an exquisitely researched expose on how &amp;#8220;&lt;i&gt;Shoddy Science, Sketchy Politics, and Shady Special Interest Groups Have Conspired to Ruin the Health of America&amp;#8221;,&lt;/i&gt;  and what you can do to avoid succumbing to such bad influences. She absolutely skewers the bestseller &lt;a title="The China Study" href="http://rawfoodsos.com/the-china-study/" target="_blank"&gt;The China Study&lt;/a&gt; for their flawed data collection and distorted conclusions, and generally goes to great lengths to set the record straight about the flawed conventional wisdom we have been fed our entire lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The South Asian Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, by Dr. Ronesh Sinha. Dr. Ron, an internal medicine specialist in Los Altos, CA, is doing some great stuff in the Bay Area, treating high risk South Asian patients and Silicon Valley employees with unique solutions that respect the evolutionary health model. South Asians, who are mostly Asian Indians, are one of the most insulin resistant ethnic groups on the planet, with rampant diabetes and early heart disease. His approach has successfully engaged and motivated South Asians to improve their health and reduce their risk while still respecting their cultural lifestyle preferences.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primal Pregnancy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, by Michele Blackwell, MD: This respected Ob/Gyn from Webster, Texas provides a detailed manual for a healthy and successfully pregnancy and childbirth, with a focus on integrating modern medical advice while still adhering to Primal living principles. Dr. Michele will cover a wide range of topics, including fertility, successful conception, all the trimesters, a healthy birth, nursing, and recovering your old self by the time the little one&amp;#8217;s first steps are taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Primal Prescription&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. In this hard-hitting expose on America&amp;#8217;s dysfunctional health care system, &lt;a title="Dr. Doug McGuff" href="http://www.bodybyscience.net/home.html/?page_id=11" target="_blank"&gt;Dr. Doug McGuff&lt;/a&gt;, fitness author and emergency physician from Seneca, South Carolina details how we came to spend over 7 trillion dollars per year on health care, yet rank 49th world wide for health outcomes and life expectancy. Dr. McGuff uses the concept of &amp;#8220;signal disruption&amp;#8221; to demonstrate how top-down controls have created an unholy alliance between the Government, Big Pharma, Big Agra, and Medical providers to create the ultimate &amp;#8220;sick care system&amp;#8221;. You will see how government intervention allows Big Agra to create the diseases that Big Pharma produces drugs for, so that doctors can &amp;#8220;manage&amp;#8221; your illness, so that you can stay just well enough to remain addicted to what made you sick in the first place. Having detailed the road to health care serfdom, Doug will show you the way out. By focusing on yourself and applying Primal lifestyle, dietary and exercise principles you will learn how to extract yourself from the belly of the beast, and enjoy the vibrant health that is your birthright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primal Woman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, by Carrie Sisson. As I hinted at in a &lt;a title="What Do You Want from Upcoming Book, Primal Woman? " href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/contest-what-do-you-want-from-upcoming-book-primal-woman/"&gt;recent post&lt;/a&gt;, Carrie is shaping a story that touches on subjects of her particular interest and expertise: aging gracefully, dealing with empty nest syndrome, sorting through misinformation about menopause and hormones that women are subjected to, and fine-tuning the Primal living style from a female perspective. Carrie has a degree in Spiritual Psychology and injects a mystical, spiritual element to some of the everyday topics at hand. I can&amp;#8217;t wait to read this! (Nope, I&amp;#8217;m not even allowed a peek just yet&amp;#8230;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perfect Balance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;b&gt;, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;a Primal Approach to Overcoming Negativity with Food, Dieting, and Body Image,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;by &lt;a title="Evolutionary Psychiatry" href="http://evolutionarypsychiatry.blogspot.com.au/" target="_blank"&gt;Emily Deans, MD&lt;/a&gt;. Dr. Deans is a Massachusetts psychiatrist who explores the causes behind out modern obsession with and, for many, dysfunctional relationship with food. By hormonally, psychologically, and metabolically disengaging from processed food dependency, those who struggle with food issues have a better chance to heal from the psychological factors that contribute to their condition. &lt;em&gt;Perfect Balance&lt;/em&gt; helps the reader eat and enjoy great, wholesome, natural foods without trending into a neurotic need to adhere to a Primal or paleo-style diet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primal Endurance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, by Mark Sisson. Yep, I&amp;#8217;m going back to my roots, this time to tell enthusiasts who insist on pursuing extreme endurance goals how to do it right! First and foremost is how to &amp;#8220;go long&amp;#8221; in training and racing without being a carb addict. Yep, it&amp;#8217;s possible to be a high-functioning endurance machine when you become truly fat and keto-adapted. This refreshing concept is raising interest in the staid endurance community, as folks like &lt;a title="Ben Greenfield" href="http://www.bengreenfieldfitness.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Ben Greenfield&lt;/a&gt;, Dr.&amp;#8217;s Phinney and Volek in &lt;i&gt;&lt;a title="The Art and Science of Low Carbohydrate Performance" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0983490716/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0983490716&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=marsdaiapp07-20" target="_blank"&gt;The Art and Science of Low Carbohydrate Performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, and even the world&amp;#8217;s foremost endurance exercise physiologist, &lt;a title="Timothy Noakes" href="http://www.amazon.com/Timothy-Noakes/e/B001IXPXEG/?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;tag=marsdaiapp07-20" target="_blank"&gt;Dr. Timothy Noakes &lt;/a&gt;of South Africa, are out on the cutting edge spreading the word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignright" alt="PBP logo big rgb" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/PBP/PBP-logo-big-rgb.jpg" width="300" height="300" title="10 New Primal Blueprint Books (Plus a Prize Package Giveaway)" /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Author Services&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve partnered with my old friend &lt;a title="Write It. Print It. Sell It." href="http://writeitprintitsellit.com/index.htm" target="_blank"&gt;Matthew Bennett&lt;/a&gt; to provide support to both aspiring authors who want to bring their dream and their story to life, as well as authors who have their manuscript and want to market and sell it effectively. Matthew is a respected coach and lecturer for authors, and a master of creative marketing methods that identify niche volume buyers for your work. Matthew and I are in development with author support products right now, but we want to hear from you in order to present the services and materials that are of most interest. If you are an aspiring author, or have a manuscript that you wish to sell and promote, please take some time to complete the comment form at this &lt;a title="Author Services" href="http://www.primalblueprintpublishing.com/author-services/" target="_blank"&gt;Author Services link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Queries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My team and I are always on the lookout for detailed book proposals or completed manuscripts that promote well being from an evolutionary health perspective. Visit this &lt;a title="Queries" href="http://www.primalblueprintpublishing.com/queries/" target="_blank"&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; for details on how to engage with us about your masterpiece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t Forget to Share Your Thoughts Below for a Chance to Win a Primal Blueprint Book Prize Package (See Details Above)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/1HE8E9O9dPk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/10-new-primal-blueprint-books-plus-a-prize-package-giveaway/#comments" thr:count="1714" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/10-new-primal-blueprint-books-plus-a-prize-package-giveaway/feed/atom/" thr:count="1714" />
		<thr:total>1714</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Sisson</name>
						<uri>http://www.marksdailyapple.com</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Primal Abroad: Food Adventures from Around the World]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-abroad-food-adventures-from-around-the-world/" />
		<id>http://www.marksdailyapple.com/?p=35757</id>
		<updated>2013-03-26T00:00:45Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-26T15:00:46Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.marksdailyapple.com" term="Health" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a guest post from Eric Bach, primal enthusiast and member of The Modern Gypsies. You may know The Gypsies as the winners of the 2011 adventure race television show Expedition Impossible, and perhaps remember them from this MDA interview. Well, their adventures didn&#8217;t end after the show. Since then, they&#8217;ve ventured out on [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-abroad-food-adventures-from-around-the-world/">&lt;img class="alignright" alt="IMG 0319" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/IMG_0319.jpg" width="320" height="212" title="Primal Abroad: Food Adventures from Around the World" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post from Eric Bach, primal enthusiast and member of &lt;a title="The Modern Gypsies" href="http://www.themoderngypsies.com/" target="_blank"&gt;The Modern Gypsies&lt;/a&gt;. You may know The Gypsies as the winners of the 2011 adventure race television show Expedition Impossible, and perhaps remember them from this &lt;a title="Expedition Impossible Team Goes Primal" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/expedition-impossible-team-goes-primal/#axzz2OW6rILMW"&gt;MDA interview&lt;/a&gt;. Well, their adventures didn&amp;#8217;t end after the show. Since then, they&amp;#8217;ve ventured out on a &amp;#8220;Compassionate Adventure&amp;#8221; of their own making, and have been met with some, let&amp;#8217;s say, diverse dishes along the way. Enter Eric.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so you know the story, eat fresh, organic, unprocessed foods which includes meat, veggies, nuts and seeds. It&amp;#8217;s simple and straightforward, the primal way of life is second nature to you. In your neighborhood there&amp;#8217;s that quaint little butcher that always has your grass-fed beef, or you can swing by Whole Foods and make a rainbow assortment of varied nuts and seeds; oh and while you&amp;#8217;re there, you may as well pick up a can of organic coconut oil. Everything is readily available, taunting you with attractive labels and promises of grass-fed, high omega-3, non GMO goodness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-35757"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now picture this, you&amp;#8217;re high up in the Ecuadorian highlands, you just reached the 19,347 ft summit of one of the tallest peaks in the country, Cotopaxi, and after the glorious descent your body is yearning for primal fuel. What are the options? Sure there is a plethora of potatoes and corn (the standard diet of most villagers in Ecuador). However, you just got your ass handed to you by Mount Doom and you need some proper sustenance. After asking local villagers in broken spanglish about the whereabouts of cooked meats, they point to a bag on the ground. You open this bag, expecting freshly grilled goodies, only to discover a pack of adorable, furry Guinea Pig friends. You grew up with a guinea pig, his name was Biscuit and now you are confronted with beautiful childhood memories. Quickly you snap to your senses, wiping the goofy smirk off of your face. Here, Biscuit is food and you&amp;#8217;ve got a decision to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignright" alt="IMG 1676" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/IMG_1676.jpg" width="320" height="428" title="Primal Abroad: Food Adventures from Around the World" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the situation that confronted us this past year in Ecuador. Myself, along with my two teammates Taylor Filasky and John Post, had been in the country for several weeks on a &amp;#8220;Compassionate Adventure.&amp;#8221; Our group, &amp;#8220;The Modern Gypsies&amp;#8221; had utilized our fan base to vote, raise funds and help to complete a clean water project for over 400 people, as well as summit the stratovolcano, Cotopaxi. Our goal for this trip was to complete one major act of compassion, have one epic adventure and, with a small camera crew, document the experience (guinea pig snacks and all). We truly believe that it is crucially important to not only push your limits physically, but also to give back to the communities whom you encounter along the way. Little did we know, one of the ways we would test our boundaries would be with the long-lost relatives of a childhood pet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been in this questionable consumption situation before; wriggling, fat grubs in Myanmar, Balut (half developed duck embryo) in the Philippines, crickets, chicken heads, scorpions and many unknown meats that I simply cannot put into words (mostly in India). However, staring at a bald, dead guinea pig on a stick, did not give me the traditional Pavlovian salivating response. Then I took a step back and looked at the process. Here we were in the middle of the beautiful Ecuadorian countryside in the tiny village of Gulahuayco. During the days we worked side by side with the men, women and children of the village, digging over 2 kms of trenching and eventually laying the pipe which would bring clean water to the entire community. We were all exhausted; the work was strenuous and our tools for completing the project were…well, they were &amp;#8220;primal&amp;#8221;. Yet here we were again working side by side, heating up a giant cauldron, husking corn, peeling potatoes and killing guinea pigs (not as glamorous as I make it sound&amp;#8230;). Everyone was smiling and laughing, mostly at us. Our common bond was hard work and a desire to better the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="IMG 0134" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/IMG_0134.jpg" width="547" height="547" title="Primal Abroad: Food Adventures from Around the World" /&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt=" DSC4054" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/_DSC4054.jpg" width="540" height="359" title="Primal Abroad: Food Adventures from Around the World" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we went for it. A large group came together in a small dining hall and we all ate together. The guinea pig was tough, but tasted fairly mild, like a chewier, gamier chicken. Thankfully they cut the heads off (which by way of the Ecuadorians were the first to go for some reason). Upon putting a piece in your mouth, you might still end up with a paw or tiny ear, which was cute. While the dish may not be on the top of my list, the experience of eating the meal together is one I will always remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone" alt="grillingguineas" src="http://i247.photobucket.com/albums/gg158/MDA2008/MDA%202011/grillingguineas.jpg" width="540" height="359" title="Primal Abroad: Food Adventures from Around the World" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes in life, we have to make interesting decisions regarding what we put into our mouths. I have been confronted with many of these situations and what I&amp;#8217;ve learned is to not think too deeply, or too &amp;#8220;Westernized,&amp;#8221; into it. Following a primal way of life, we are always thinking about what is going into our mouths and what effect it will have on our body. However, when traveling to exotic corners of the earth, this privileged way of thinking can often be a major hindrance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you know, one of the keys to living a successful primal lifestyle is varying your routine. This can come in the form of exercise, diet or life experience. When traveling to foreign lands, partaking in the local dining experience is not just a choice, in my opinion it is your duty. Don&amp;#8217;t you worry, you&amp;#8217;ll usually have the standard options of chicken, beef, or fish. It&amp;#8217;s cool, you know what it will taste like, you know the consistency and your vanilla palette will be satisfied…you did good, you stayed primal! However, in the sense of adventure and life experience, when presented with a more &amp;#8220;unique&amp;#8221; option, stop thinking and go for it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/46824150" height="303" width="540" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow &lt;a title="Facebook: The Modern Gypsies" href="http://www.facebook.com/themoderngypsies" target="_blank"&gt;The Modern Gypsies on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and check out the first episode of their Ecuador Compassionate Adventure at &lt;a title="The Modern Gypsies" href="http://www.themoderngypsies.com/" target="_blank"&gt;TheModernGypsies.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MarksDailyApple/~4/Kn47Nf1EuRU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-abroad-food-adventures-from-around-the-world/#comments" thr:count="130" />
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.marksdailyapple.com/primal-abroad-food-adventures-from-around-the-world/feed/atom/" thr:count="130" />
		<thr:total>130</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed><!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.950 seconds. --><!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-04 08:01:30 -->
