<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ask a Manager</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.askamanager.org/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.askamanager.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 20:57:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>when should I insist on a consulting fee for my former employer&#8217;s questions?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/when-should-i-insist-on-a-consulting-fee-for-my-former-employers-questions.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/when-should-i-insist-on-a-consulting-fee-for-my-former-employers-questions.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 20:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[workplace practices]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5752</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: Shortly before I retired a few months ago, the company I worked for declined my offer to come back and work for them on contract, as needed. Now a coworker is calling me, from time to time, for professional advice. This is not &#8220;where&#8217;s the X file&#8221; or &#8220;what&#8217;s the password&#8221; kind [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>Shortly before I retired a few months ago, the company I worked for declined my offer to come back and work for them on contract, as needed. Now a coworker is calling me, from time to time, for professional advice.</em></p>
<p><em>This is not &#8220;where&#8217;s the X file&#8221; or &#8220;what&#8217;s the password&#8221; kind of advice. It&#8217;s &#8220;we&#8217;ve tried X, X, X, and X, and it still isn&#8217;t in spec. What would you do?&#8221; It took me 7 years of college in a math and science field, and over 30 years of highly specialized training and experience become an expert, and be able to answer such questions.</em></p>
<p><em>The days of corporate paternalism toward loyal, hard-working employees are long past, and after experiencing the change in corporate culture the last ten or so years, I do not feel especially generous to my old employer. I do value the friendship of the coworker making the call, however. The company downsized recently and there is too much work for too few workers. Getting him in hot water is the last thing I want to do.</em></p>
<p><em>Perhaps time to again offer the company my contract services, without telling them they&#8217;ve already been getting them?</em></p>
<p>Since they already turned down the idea, I don&#8217;t think you&#8217;ll have more luck offering the company consulting this services this time, particularly if you don&#8217;t tell them that you&#8217;ve already been advising your former coworker. But I wouldn&#8217;t approach them and explain that you have been doing that, either, because you risk making the former coworker look a little bad in the process &#8212; the subtext being, &#8220;Joe can&#8217;t do his job without my help.&#8221; And if he&#8217;s just been asking you informally because he finds your perspective helpful, without thinking of it as consulting per se &#8212; which is likely &#8212; then you risk causing weirdness for him and tension in your relationship.</p>
<p>Instead, I&#8217;d say something directly to him. For instance: &#8220;You know, I&#8217;d be glad to set up a consulting arrangement to answer some of this stuff. Is that worth talking about?&#8221;</p>
<p>If your coworker has any ability to pick up on cues, he&#8217;s going to understand that this means that without such an arrangement, he can&#8217;t keep coming to you for help. And if he doesn&#8217;t pick up on cues and he continues to ask, then you say directly, &#8220;I&#8217;d love to help, but at this point I think we probably need to set up a consulting contract.&#8221;</p>
<p>He&#8217;ll then either (a) stop bringing his questions to you or (b) make the case for a consulting contract to whoever would have to approve it. But prepared for the company not to go for that unless your former coworker really goes to bat for it and lays out a strong case for why it&#8217;s necessary. That&#8217;s because, while I&#8217;m sure you <em>are</em> making his job easier, businesses generally feel able to go on after someone leaves &#8212; while still being quite happy to accept their help for free if they&#8217;re offering it. In other words, be prepared for the fact that however helpful your former coworker finds talking to you, it still might not reach the level that would justify a consulting gig. Or it might &#8212; who knows.</p>
<p>But either way, you&#8217;ll have set up some boundaries and have made it clear that you aren&#8217;t going to be providing advice for free.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/when-should-i-insist-on-a-consulting-fee-for-my-former-employers-questions.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>why don&#8217;t managers appreciate transferable skills?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/why-dont-managers-appreciate-transferable-skills.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/why-dont-managers-appreciate-transferable-skills.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 16:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[job searching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5750</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I got a PhD in medieval studies. Not exactly the most practical field, but I learned a lot about abstract thinking, analytical skills, and data mining. Transcribing and translating medieval Latin isn&#8217;t exactly easy, after all. However, it took me over a year and a half to find a job in the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I got a PhD in medieval studies. Not exactly the most practical field, but I learned a lot about abstract thinking, analytical skills, and data mining. Transcribing and translating medieval Latin isn&#8217;t exactly easy, after all.</em></p>
<p><em>However, it took me over a year and a half to find a job in the private field. And what happened? I&#8217;ve excelled so much that, since I was hired, my entire department had its budget doubled, and my manager has credited me with most of our success.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m not trying to brag, but I want to make a point: nowadays, if you have a degree in making green widgets, hiring managers will throw your application in the trash if the job is making brown widgets. This is simply messed up and stupid. The fact is that there are a lot of very intelligent, well-educated people who could easily do great jobs if they were given a chance.</em></p>
<p><em>So my question: why can&#8217;t managers appreciate transferrable skills and hire more very qualified, intelligent people?</em></p>
<p>Because you&#8217;re unproven, and you&#8217;re competing against candidates who <em>are</em> proven.</p>
<p>In this job market, there are tons of well-qualified candidates for nearly every opening. Employers have no incentive to take a risk on someone without a track record in what they&#8217;re looking for when they have plenty of good candidates who do have that track record.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s like asking why you&#8217;d hire the smart, warm nanny applicant who has a track record of doing a good job taking care of kids over the smart, warm nanny applicant who has only cared for animals in the past. There are some transferable skills there &#8212; but you&#8217;re probably going to go with the person with the track record actually doing the work you&#8217;re hiring for, unless there&#8217;s something about the other person that really impresses you, enough to trump the experience issue. The other candidate might have turned out to be fantastic at the job &#8212; but you&#8217;d rather not let your kids be her testing ground.</p>
<p>And it&#8217;s not like it&#8217;s a question of smart, capable people with no direct experience but transferable skills against not-so-smart-or-capable people with direct experience. There are smart, capable people in both groups, so of course the smart, capable people with direct experience are the most attractive.</p>
<p>Furthermore, hiring is in part about managing risk. You might decide in some extenuating circumstances to take a risk on someone untested, but it&#8217;s certainly no way to hire as a matter of general routine. That doesn&#8217;t mean that the people you&#8217;re rejecting would all have performed poorly; it just means that you&#8217;re going with the more certain option.</p>
<p>Now, none of this means that hiring managers never take a chance on people who are less tested. They do &#8212; you&#8217;re a prime example of that. But surely you can understand why that&#8217;s more the exception than the rule when employers have plenty of options, right?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/why-dont-managers-appreciate-transferable-skills.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>260</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>can staying at the same job too long hurt you?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/can-staying-at-the-same-job-too-long-hurt-you.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/can-staying-at-the-same-job-too-long-hurt-you.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 14:13:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[job searching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5748</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I’ve been at the same company for nearly 12 years, and during that time, the company has nearly tripled in sales and number of employees. I started as basically a clerk and as the company grew, I eventually worked my way into a manager’s position with 6 employees in my department. My [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I’ve been at the same company for nearly 12 years, and during that time, the company has nearly tripled in sales and number of employees. I started as basically a clerk and as the company grew, I eventually worked my way into a manager’s position with 6 employees in my department. My level of responsibility has steadily increased and I’ve continued my education and have obtained specific certifications for my field, raising the sophistication in the operation of my department. I feel that within a few years, I may be ready to move on beyond what the company can provide in terms of challenge and opportunity.</em></p>
<p><em>I have recently had some conversations with recruiters and other hiring types, and have been told that while longevity was once a good thing to have, these days potential employers could look at my length of time at the same company as a strike against me. They’re saying that someone could look at me and think that I’m either locked into my present company’s way of thinking and that could be hard to break, or that I’ve simply become stale, stuck in a rut, and will always be there. I think I’ve gotten to where I am in part because I’ve always challenged the current way of thinking, including my own sometimes, so this is definitely not the case with me. Is this a trend in hiring? If so, how would I address this when I do start searching?</em></p>
<p>It&#8217;s true that there&#8217;s a point where staying too long at one place can raise questions about how you’ll adapt to new environments. I can’t pinpoint exactly when that is — it’s somewhere more than 8 years but well before 20.</p>
<p>The worry is that you&#8217;ll be stuck in one company’s way of doing things, won’t have been exposed to a wider variety of practices and cultures, and thus won’t adapt easily. So anything you can do to demonstrate that’s not the case is helpful. Certainly being able to show a progression in responsibilities and job titles &#8212; as you can &#8212; is helpful, and you should think about what else you can use to demonstrate that you&#8217;re flexible, open to change, and don&#8217;t have an insular viewpoint.</p>
<p>And for anyone who&#8217;s now worrying about what this means for them, this isn&#8217;t necessarily a deal-breaker and it certainly doesn&#8217;t mean that you should leave a job you love before you want to &#8230; but you should be aware that it could be a potential concern for future employers, and balance it against other factors.</p>
<p>And this is <em>not</em> a license to engage in <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/02/06/are-you-a-job-hopper">job-hopping</a>, which is far, far more harmful to your ability to get the future jobs you want.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/can-staying-at-the-same-job-too-long-hurt-you.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>terse answer Thursday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/terse-answer-thursday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-28.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/terse-answer-thursday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-28.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 04:03:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5746</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s terse answer Thursday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Can you submit mileage reimbursements for only a few dollars? I&#8217;m filling out last month&#8217;s out of pocket expenses and find myself wanting to make several mileage reimbursement requests for a few dollars each. Normally I might have one [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s terse answer Thursday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Can you submit mileage reimbursements for only a few dollars?</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m filling out last month&#8217;s out of pocket expenses and find myself wanting to make several mileage reimbursement requests for a few dollars each. Normally I might have one or two requests a month for about $20 or $30, but last month I had to make several errand runs for work.</em></p>
<p><em>As a manager, would you see the low mileage reimbursement requests as petty? I hate to be seen as someone who nickels and dimes the company, but I&#8217;m short on money and get nickle and dimed a lot myself. I usually don&#8217;t request reimbursement for the 50 cents I stick into the parking meters when I have to park in the city. I also can&#8217;t request mileage reimbursement if I have to travel to our site that&#8217;s further away (because it&#8217;s considered a &#8220;normal&#8221; part of my job duties to work there several times a year.) That trip alone is 70 miles round trip extra than I normally commute and I didn&#8217;t understand that I wouldn&#8217;t get reimbursed when I took this job. I guess I feel like at least by requesting a few dollars here and there, I can make up some of the losses I take as part of work. But I don&#8217;t want to hurt my relationship with my boss or company to do so.</em></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t give it another thought. You spent the money on a work expense that they&#8217;ve told you they reimburse, so it&#8217;s fine to submit it. I wouldn&#8217;t question it at all if an employee submitted low mileage reimbursements like this.</p>
<p><strong>2. I regret making a counteroffer to an employee</strong></p>
<p><em>I am a manager of a team of four analysts in a small field office overseas. Recently, one of my staff received an outside offer at another company. I gave him a modest counteroffer, including an upgrade in title from analyst to senior analyst. While his work is decent, it is not outstanding, and I would have not promoted him under normal circumstances, although I would have considered it in the next 8-10 months. He does an equally OK job as to someone I would hire new, so I promoted him to retain him, not because of his performance.</em></p>
<p><em>So, I have read your posts on <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/09/why-you-shouldnt-use-counteroffers-to-prevent-employees-from-leaving.html">counteroffers</a>, and now have a related question. As predicted, the day after this person&#8217;s promotion, another staff came to me completely demotivated. She has worked at our organization in the same role for the same amount of time. While she does have some issues, when you get down to it, she does outperform the newly promoted staff. She came to me asking for clarity about how one actually gets promoted at our organization.</em></p>
<p><em>I regret making the counteroffer/promotion, and realize it was my mistake. However, now I am stuck with it. How do I deal? I am trying to manage the newly promoted person to perform better and live up to his new title. But, what messages do I give to the rightfully disgruntled staff? Obviously, I can&#8217;t take her aside and say, &#8220;Hey, I know your coworker is kind of crappy, but got another job offer and I didn&#8217;t want to hire somebody else, so tough luck!&#8221; How do I manage my way out of this one?</em></p>
<p>I wish I had an answer, but I don&#8217;t. You can&#8217;t really justify promoting someone whose work doesn&#8217;t merit it, or even justify trying to retain the person by other means if their work isn&#8217;t outstanding. And because there&#8217;s no justification, I can&#8217;t think of any way to explain this to the coworker or mollify her very understandable frustration. (And to make matters worse, you might end up losing the better employee because of the attempt to keep the worse employee.) This is a clusterfudge.</p>
<p><strong>3. Putting a school career day presentation on my resume</strong></p>
<p><em>I presented at a school career day as a representative of an organization that I volunteer with. Should I include this as an achievement on my resume? I don’t have any children that attend the school (I don’t have children at all) so this was not something that I had to do. I was honored to be asked to present (although I don’t feel I really have a career at the moment) and I think that I did a great job. What do you think? For background, I would like you to know that I didn’t just talk. I created an experiment and conducted it in front of the students. In one class, I had the students separated into groups and they did the experiments with the help of the teachers and my instructions.</em></p>
<p>It&#8217;s cool that you did it (and I am sort of obsessed with school career days), but it&#8217;s not really resume-worthy. It was a one-day (one hour, probably) thing without accompanying evaluation or accountability, so it doesn&#8217;t really meet the bar for a resume.</p>
<p><strong>4. Applying for a job when a friend works in the same department</strong></p>
<p><em>I am applying for a position for a company that I am totally excited about. I meet the qualifications for the position that I am applying for, and I feel like I would excel in the work environment that they project. A college friend whom I haven&#8217;t kept in much contact with (I&#8217;m only a few years out), has worked for the company for 3+ years in the department that I am applying for. What is the most appropriate way to request her help? Ideally, I would love her to put a word in for me. How do I approach this situation without being presumptuous that she would do so?</em></p>
<p>Email her and let her know that you applied for the position, and tell her that you&#8217;d love any advice that she has. You don&#8217;t need to ask her to put in a good word for you; most people will do that on their own if they think you&#8217;d be a good candidate, and asking for it directly can be awkward, since the subtext of &#8220;I&#8217;m applying for a job on your team&#8221; is generally going to be &#8220;and I&#8217;d like the job and would love your help.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>5. Is it ever okay to call to follow up after an interview?</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m contemplating when and how to follow-up after a final interview I had with an organization on March 19. It was 2.5 hours of back-to-back interviews with 3 people, which I thought went quite well. Of course, I have debated that issue many times in my head since. The hiring manager said that she would get back to me by the that Friday, but didn&#8217;t seem 100% sure about that. I sent my thank-you&#8217;s, and one of the 3 people said that they had one more candidate to interview that week before making a decision.</em></p>
<p><em>Friday passed. The following Thursday I hadn&#8217;t heard anything yet, so (based on my findings on your site) I sent an email asking for a timeline update in the afternoon. Still no response. A friend told me that I should call &#8230; Is it ever ok to call? If I were to call, I think I should at least give them a week after I asked for the update.</em></p>
<p><em>This is a junior-level management position at a large non-profit. Technically it is a new position that they want to fill &#8220;immediately.&#8221; They are reorganizing the management to create a more effective team.</em></p>
<p>Well, here&#8217;s the thing: If they want to make you a job offer, they are going to contact you and do it. They&#8217;re not going to be dragging their feet and only remember when you call them. So calling is likely to result only in (a) another lack of response, (b) a vague response (&#8220;we&#8217;ll be in touch once we have a decision&#8221;), or (c) a rejection. And yes, a rejection would give you closure, but frankly, you&#8217;re better off giving yourself closure right now and mentally moving on, and letting it be a pleasant surprise if they do offer you the job. Trust that if they want to hire you, they&#8217;ll get in touch.</p>
<p><strong>6. Listing a childcare business on my resume when my field is accounting</strong></p>
<p><em>Several years ago, I had to quit a job because the child custody and child support legal battle got to be too much for me to handle as a professional accountant and mother. I took a 6-month break then to plan a childcare business, which thrived for about a 16 months. Although this is a break in my accounting experience, I proudly list it on my resume because (a) I need to account for the time and (b) it shows the entrepreneurship in me. A girlfriend says I should list the childcare business in a section captioned &#8220;Other Experience.&#8221; What is your advice?</em></p>
<p>I agree with her. I wouldn&#8217;t kick off your main experience section with it because it&#8217;s not what you want to most showcase, but an &#8220;other experience&#8221; section is perfect for it.</p>
<p><strong>7. Getting an MA while job-searching</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m getting conflicting advice about this from my friends, so wanted to get your opinion. I am in the process of job hunting, and I have been looking for about 3 months now and finally got my first phone interview coming up this week. I decided a few weeks ago to apply for my MA in intercultural and international communications, because I need a plan B. If finding a job is going to take me several months (perhaps even a year), I want to make good use of my time, and getting my MA has always been on my &#8220;don&#8217;t want to call it a bucket list-bucket list.&#8221; The university is in another province, but it is about 80% online. I would have to go to the campus for two weeks in September or October for the in-class portion of the program, and the following year I will be out of country for three weeks for the placement portion of the program. But other than that, I can do the coursework at home. Therefore, I can continue to do this even if I got a job, which is why this program works so well for me.</em></p>
<p><em>First, does studying for my MA help bridge the gap in my resume? I am currently unemployed and have been since the end of November. I recently moved back to the country which is the reason for my unemployment. I figure the longer it takes to find a job, the bigger the gap will be since my last job. Second, when in the interview process should I bring up the part about needing two weeks to attend university classes as part of my MA? Would this be a deal-breaker for most hiring managers? In my opinion, improving my education and skills will only benefit my employer, as this program compliments most of the positions I am applying for and matches well with my skill set.</em></p>
<p>Since the program is one that you&#8217;re arguing won&#8217;t interfere with full-time work, it&#8217;s not quite as good of a resume gap-filler as a traditional program would be &#8230; but it&#8217;s not nothing either, and you can certainly use it.</p>
<p>As for when to bring up the time you&#8217;ll need off, I&#8217;d wait until you have an offer and negotiate it then as part of your overall negotiations. The two weeks shouldn&#8217;t be a deal-breaker for most jobs (although you might need to take it unpaid if you don&#8217;t have enough vacation accrued by then). The three weeks next year will be more unusual for most jobs, so make sure that you include that as part of your negotiations too &#8212; you don&#8217;t want to find out next year that they won&#8217;t let you take three weeks at once.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/terse-answer-thursday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-28.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>164</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>company offered me a job but wants an answer the same day</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/company-offered-me-a-job-but-wants-an-answer-the-same-day.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/company-offered-me-a-job-but-wants-an-answer-the-same-day.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 18:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[job offers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I&#8217;m currently working for a company I&#8217;ve been with for nearly a decade. The positions I can promote to are very few and unlikely to be vacated anytime soon. I&#8217;ve been at my level now for 3+ years. It&#8217;s time to move on. I interviewed with a promising young company (let&#8217;s call [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m currently working for a company I&#8217;ve been with for nearly a decade. The positions I can promote to are very few and unlikely to be vacated anytime soon. I&#8217;ve been at my level now for 3+ years. It&#8217;s time to move on.</em></p>
<p><em>I interviewed with a promising young company (let&#8217;s call them PYC) this morning, and by lunchtime they reached out with an enthusiastic offer below my current base salary, which won&#8217;t work for me. I countered with a base salary match and indicated that if the upside was worth the risk (meaning a generous stack of options), we&#8217;d be a lot closer to a deal. PYC stressed that they&#8217;d get back to me by the end of the day with numbers so that I could proceed with giving two weeks notice right away, as they want someone to start ASAP.</em></p>
<p><em>To complicate things, I have more interviews with other companies this week &#8212; exciting, big time companies! &#8212; and while they&#8217;ll almost certainly come with higher pay, it&#8217;s doubtful they&#8217;ll match that critical risk/upside component. While both are important to me, this offer is putting me on the spot! If PYC offers a base salary match, the same amount of vacation, a title upgrade AND enough options to calm my nerves, is that a good offer, or am I jumping the gun? The rush is spooking me a little; it&#8217;s not the way I&#8217;m used to making decisions. Should I be rightfully spooked or is this just my decade of being off-market showing?</em></p>
<p><em>I think they&#8217;re going to be extremely successful. I want to be part of it, the folks I met today were great, and the ship appears to be in great shape.</em></p>
<p>There are really two separate questions here: Should you be spooked that they&#8217;re moving so quickly and pressuring you to as well, and can you slow them down?</p>
<p>First, should you be spooked? Maybe. There are certainly companies that move this quickly, and it doesn&#8217;t mean that people don&#8217;t end up happy there. But at a minimum, they&#8217;re probably not great at hiring if they&#8217;re offering people jobs only hours after interviewing them for the first time. (They&#8217;re almost certainly not checking references, for one thing, although maybe they had already talked informally with people who have worked with you.) And if they&#8217;re not great at hiring, that means that you&#8217;re probably going to have some less-than-great coworkers, unless they&#8217;re really good at cleaning up hiring mistakes quickly.</p>
<p>They&#8217;re also assuming that <em>you</em> can and should make a decision as quickly as they have. But deciding where to work is a big, big decision, and they should want you to think it through and be absolutely sure that it&#8217;s right for you. The fact that they&#8217;re not thinking of it that way indicates that they&#8217;re either pretty inexperienced or not quite reasonable in their expectations. Those can both be bad, in different ways. If they&#8217;re inexperienced, what else haven&#8217;t they thought through or had experience dealing with yet, and how will that affect (a) their business and (b) your quality of life as an employee? (Are they experienced enough to make reliable revenue projections? Is your health insurance going to lapse because they&#8217;re clueless about what needs to be done to keep it current? And so forth.) Or, if they&#8217;re experienced enough but just not quite reasonable in what they expect of people, will their expectations be any more reasonable when it comes to things like time off, workload, etc.?</p>
<p>Now, despite what it might sound like, I&#8217;m not pre-judging this. This might be a great offer that you should be excited to take. But these are all things you want to think through without blinders on.</p>
<p>As for the second question &#8230; You should absolutely be able to slow them down. It&#8217;s entirely reasonable to say, &#8220;I&#8217;m really interested in joining you, and I&#8217;m excited about the position. However, I need some time to think over the offer and the position and make sure that it&#8217;s right for me. Can I give you my answer by Monday?&#8221; (And in the meantime, you should feel free to ask for an additional conversation if you have unanswered questions, which you probably do &#8212; or should &#8212; after only a single interview.)</p>
<p>They might be hesitant about waiting a full week, but they should at least give you a <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/06/how-long-should-employers-give-candidates-to-respond-to-a-job-offer.html">few days</a>. And if they push you for an answer faster than that, I&#8217;d consider that a much bigger red flag than the fast offer itself. They should want you to be sure about your decision &#8212; both for your own comfort and for theirs; people pressured to accept a job offer faster than they&#8217;re ready to are at high risk for reneging later.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/company-offered-me-a-job-but-wants-an-answer-the-same-day.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>when my coworkers &#8220;work from home,&#8221; they&#8217;re not really working</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/when-my-coworkers-work-from-home-theyre-not-really-working.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/when-my-coworkers-work-from-home-theyre-not-really-working.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 15:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advice about your coworkers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5744</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: Many of my colleagues have an agreement with our boss that they can work from home on Fridays. All of them happen to be moms of young children. I am married but do not have children. I am all for a flexible work environment, but I feel that they take advantage of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>Many of my colleagues have an agreement with our boss that they can work from home on Fridays. All of them happen to be moms of young children. I am married but do not have children.</em></p>
<p><em>I am all for a flexible work environment, but I feel that they take advantage of the situation. They constantly post on Facebook that they are at karate tournaments, music class, etc. or tell team members they can&#8217;t participate in client calls because they have to pick up their kids at school. I realize I am not a parent so I don&#8217;t understand the balance or struggles of being a working mother, but I am expected to be in the office five days a week, while they essentially work four.</em></p>
<p><em>I don&#8217;t want to be the group tattle tale but it&#8217;s really starting to affect the morale of those who are childless when we see empty offices on Fridays. Thoughts on how to approach this, or do I just suck it up and deal with it?</em></p>
<p>Well, first, you want to make sure that you&#8217;re right that they&#8217;re not working much on their Fridays at home. It&#8217;s possible that they&#8217;re simply working flexible hours that day. For instance, if someone worked from 7-11, went to their kid&#8217;s karate tournament from 11-2, worked more from 2-4:30, and then put in another hour and half over the weekend, that would total eight hours of work.</p>
<p>And to some people, that&#8217;s the point of a flexible schedule and working from home: It allows you to fit life in, and schedule work around it.</p>
<p>Of course, it&#8217;s entirely possible that that&#8217;s not how your coworkers are using the flexibility. Maybe they&#8217;re working 9-5 from home but taking tons of time off in the middle of the day that they never make up. But do you <em>know</em> that, or are you just assuming it?</p>
<p>And if you <em>do</em> know that they&#8217;re abusing it, then what you have is a management problem, because no good manager is going to neglect to notice that hmmm, the people who work from home on Fridays seem to produce less work than everyone else. That doesn&#8217;t make it any less frustrating &#8212; in fact, it makes it more frustrating &#8212; but it&#8217;s worth being clear that that&#8217;s what&#8217;s going on.</p>
<p>Of course, the one thing that you do know for sure is that these coworkers are at least sometimes missing client calls on those days, and that&#8217;s potentially a legitimate issue. But even there, the question is how much that matters. Are they missing these calls more than someone else might miss them for occasional dentist appointments or other conflicts? And what&#8217;s the impact on their work?</p>
<p>If there <em>is</em> an impact and you&#8217;re concerned about it, then you should handle that just like you would any other concern with a coworker&#8217;s work that impacts you: First talk to the coworker, and then to your manager if the problem remains. In this case, that might mean saying to the coworker, &#8220;I&#8217;ve noticed you often can&#8217;t make client calls when we schedule them on Fridays, and I know that Client X really likes having you there. Is there a different time we can schedule them so you&#8217;re able to call in?&#8221; Or, depending on the situation, &#8220;I know there&#8217;s not much notice, but they&#8217;re usually in the afternoons. Is there a way for you to keep that time free?&#8221;</p>
<p>And if you remain concerned, then you&#8217;d talk to your manager, just as you would about anything else that was affecting your work. For instance: &#8220;I love that we have schedule flexibility, but I&#8217;m having trouble getting what I need on Fridays from people who are working at home and often can&#8217;t get people on client calls when I need them. I wonder if we could give people clearer guidelines on how accessible they should be when they&#8217;re working out of the office.&#8221;</p>
<p>But overall, you want to (a) keep the focus on the impact on your work, and (b) assume that if these are otherwise good coworkers with a strong work ethic, you have no reason to think they aren&#8217;t putting in a full day&#8217;s work even if it&#8217;s spread out in an untraditional way &#8212; unless you really know for sure that that isn&#8217;t true.</p>
<p>And last, I&#8217;m assuming that this benefit isn&#8217;t just offered to parents in your workplace, so there&#8217;s no reason you couldn&#8217;t responsibly take advantage of the flexibility too, if you want to.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/when-my-coworkers-work-from-home-theyre-not-really-working.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>217</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>what&#8217;s the best career advice you ever got?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/whats-the-best-career-advice-you-ever-got.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/whats-the-best-career-advice-you-ever-got.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 13:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5730</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We talk about bad advice a lot here &#8212; bad advice people get from their parents, from campus career centers, from friends and significant others, and even from the career advice industry. I&#8217;d like to hear about good advice for a change. What&#8217;s the best career advice you ever got? Who gave it to you, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>We talk about bad advice a lot here &#8212; bad advice people get from their <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/08/ignore-your-parents-they-know-not-what-they-say.html">parents</a>, from campus <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/03/college-career-office-being-pushed-to-give-students-bad-advice.html">career centers</a>, from friends and significant others, and even from the <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2011/10/awful-advice-lie-and-cold-call-your-way-into-a-job.html">career advice industry</a>.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d like to hear about good advice for a change. What&#8217;s the best career advice you ever got? Who gave it to you, and &#8212; importantly &#8212; why was it so good?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/whats-the-best-career-advice-you-ever-got.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>277</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>wee answer Wednesday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/wee-answer-wednesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-30.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/wee-answer-wednesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-30.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 04:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5742</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s wee answer Wednesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Mentioning that I&#8217;d take a more junior position I am in an interview process. Tomorrow morning, I have a second interview for a middle management position. I do not know how things will evolve. Meanwhile, the company advertised a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s wee answer Wednesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Mentioning that I&#8217;d take a more junior position</strong></p>
<p><em>I am in an interview process. Tomorrow morning, I have a second interview for a middle management position. I do not know how things will evolve. Meanwhile, the company advertised a position that involves less responsibilities &#8212; assistant manager. If I receive a NO for the manager position or feel that things are not going in the right direction, I am tempted to mention that I would be open for the less senior position. Any idea how I should approach them on this, and still look professional?</em></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t do this in the midst of an interview for the higher level position. If you don&#8217;t get that job, at that point you can mention that you&#8217;re interested in the more junior position &#8212; but if you mention while you&#8217;re being interviewed for the more senior role, you risk making yourself look like you&#8217;re not confident in your own skills. They&#8217;re giving you a second interview &#8212; they think you&#8217;re a viable candidate for this job, and so you should too.</p>
<p><strong>2. Do different companies compare notes on their candidates?</strong></p>
<p><em>During my latest job search, I came across a situation that made me uncomfortable. I had interviews with three different companies: Company A, then B, and lastly C. Company B gave me an offer the day before my interview with Company C. Talking to HR in Company A and C afterwards, they both knew I had an offer from Company B.</em></p>
<p><em>I would like to look for a job in a different state and use a recruiting agency to help, but I am concerned with my current company finding out in the same way the other companies did last time. Is this kind of &#8220;comparing notes&#8221; between HRs of different companies normal?</em></p>
<p>It&#8217;s not especially common, but it can happen in particularly close-knit industries where all the players know each other. Generally, though, I&#8217;d assume it&#8217;s not happening.</p>
<p><strong>3. Being paid as a contractor when I&#8217;m treated as an employee</strong></p>
<p><em>I recently came across the following information in one of your blog posts: &#8220;Your employer can&#8217;t pay you as a contractor while treating you like an employee. If your employer controls when, where, and how you work, the government says you&#8217;re an employee—and your company needs to pay your payroll taxes and offer you the same benefits it offers to regular employees.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>Is this a federal law? Or does it vary by state? Where can I find this information outlined so I can show it to my employer? My employer takes advantage of me and my pay requirements, and although I work as an employee he gave me a 1099 for my salary this year. I think he should pay whatever I owe.</em></p>
<p>It&#8217;s a federal law, although it&#8217;s commonly broken, and you can read about it <a href="http://www.irs.gov/Businesses/Small-Businesses-&amp;-Self-Employed/Independent-Contractor-(Self-Employed)-or-Employee%3F  ">here</a>.</p>
<p>For whatever it&#8217;s worth, you don&#8217;t need to wait to be issued a tax form to find out how your employer is paying you; if taxes aren&#8217;t being taken out of your checks each pay period, you&#8217;re being paid as an independent contractor (legally or illegally).</p>
<p><strong>4. I&#8217;ve been promoted but don&#8217;t know what to do</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m 23 and have been working since I left school at 16. I&#8217;ve never had a sick day off work, I&#8217;m always 30 minutes early and the last one to leave. Finally after many years of hard work, a new project has come up at work and my manager and his business manager think I&#8217;m the perfect guy to help run the show. My promotion is leading me to run a team of six people, letting agreements, and marketing. Only problem is I know little about these subjects, but they really do think I&#8217;m the perfect person for the job. This has lead me to quite a few sleepless nights! It got worse today when the business manager asked me to help her write the job descriptions for the new positions, and it seemed like she was getting annoyed that I wasn&#8217;t putting much input in. I&#8217;ve been working so hard since I left school to reach a promotion like this and it&#8217;s my ticket to a successful career. But I really don&#8217;t know what to do, and don&#8217;t want to show them my weakness.</em></p>
<p>They promoted you for a reason, and since you&#8217;ve worked with them before, they have a pretty good idea of your skills. But it&#8217;s fine to admit when you don&#8217;t know something &#8212; in fact, the most confident people are usually the ones most willing to admit that, because it doesn&#8217;t threaten them. Why not go to your manager and ask for guidance in what you can do to get up to speed? If there are specific things you&#8217;re wondering about, ask about those too. Ask for help, and ask for feedback. That&#8217;s how you&#8217;ll learn the new role &#8212; don&#8217;t feel you need to walk in already having it mastered.</p>
<p><strong>5. Should I ask for a raise now that I have new responsibilities?</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve been at my current positon for a year and recieved the standard 3% pay increase this week. Since I&#8217;ve been at this company, I&#8217;ve taken on new responsibilities. It&#8217;s been a great learning curve and I feel that I&#8217;ve grown a lot in this role. I&#8217;m also working at stepping up my skills in areas where my manager and I mutually agree I can improve. Recently, I was asked to be the main coordinator in an area where I&#8217;ve only had a supporting role before &#8212; that is, I&#8217;m responsible for tasks that I was only assisting with before. Right now I feel a bit shaky in this area as I&#8217;m learning the ropes, but I know I&#8217;m capable of doing an excellent job once I get the hang of it. I&#8217;m writing to ask, would you advise on asking for a higher raise at this point, or do you believe I would be in a better position to do so once I&#8217;ve demonstrated more value to the company through handling my new tasks?</em></p>
<p>You just got a raise. You need to demonstrate that you can excel at your new responsibilities &#8212; and that you&#8217;ve addressed the areas where you and your manager agreed you&#8217;d improve &#8212; before you ask for another one.</p>
<p><strong>6. Can I reopen salary negotiations after starting work?</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve been doing some consulting work for a company a few hours a week from home. A couple months ago, they let me know about an opening for a different, but related position in their office. As we went through the hiring process there was talk about rolling my consulting duties into this new job, but nothing concrete was decided on. The new job doesn&#8217;t require an extra credential that I have, and that is reflected in the salary. I was still interested because of the potential to get full time employment and benefits with this company.</em></p>
<p><em>I figured that if I was offered the job, we would go over the details of how to handle my consulting work and I would negotiate a rate increase if they wanted to roll those duties into the new job. However, when I got the packet to look over, it was an acceptance packet with a start date and nothing to sign or negotiate. I missed my offer negotiation and went straight from interview to acceptance!</em></p>
<p><em>I started the job two weeks ago and while I haven&#8217;t been doing the duties from when I was consulting, last week my manager mentioned that I would be able to start doing those tasks again and that it&#8217;s no big deal because they could fall into &#8220;other duties as assigned.&#8221; I want to do the work that I had been doing as a consultant, but I want to be paid for that specialized skill. I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s fair to say it&#8217;s part of &#8220;other duties&#8221; because if they had hired someone who didn&#8217;t have my background that person wouldn&#8217;t be able to do it. </em><em>Do I have any leverage to say that I won&#8217;t do it until we&#8217;ve agreed on a rate for adding those duties? Please help me fix this, I&#8217;ve neglected my growth opportunities for so long and just started reading your blog and want to get my career on track!</em></p>
<p>First, you guys need to stop accepting job offers without negotiating just because the employer doesn&#8217;t proactively offer you a chance to negotiate. You can still bring up salary yourself.</p>
<p>However, at this point, you&#8217;ve missed your window of opportunity; you&#8217;ve already accepted the job at the rate they offered. I also wouldn&#8217;t try to ask for more now based on the fact that the new job includes your consulting work. First, they&#8217;d already mentioned previously that they might roll that into the position so they&#8217;re not springing this on you out of nowhere &#8230; and second, the fact that you could do this stuff is probably part of the reason they hired you and not someone else. You don&#8217;t really have standing to go back and negotiate now. The time to do that was when the offer was made, and you can&#8217;t do it weeks later.</p>
<p><strong>7. Employer said a letter is in the mail</strong></p>
<p><em>I had an interview for a secretary position 12 days ago. I called yesterday to see if the position had been filled and was asked if I received a letter in the mail. When I said no, the interviewer said she couldn&#8217;t tell me anything until I get the letter in the mail. I&#8217;m assuming this means I didn&#8217;t get the job, but wanted to know what your thoughts were on this. Is there any chance it could be a good thing? The position was with the State of TN Dept of Human Services office. They interviewed several people and said we would be notified when the position was filled. I assumed it would be by email because that&#8217;s my preferred method of contact.</em></p>
<p>It probably means that you didn&#8217;t get the job, but with government hiring, who knows. It&#8217;s entirely possible that they deliver job offers by putting them in bottles and throwing them into the ocean.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/wee-answer-wednesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-30.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>38</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>how to resign when you&#8217;re about to go to a 3-day conference</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/how-to-resign-when-youre-about-to-go-to-a-3-day-conference.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/how-to-resign-when-youre-about-to-go-to-a-3-day-conference.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 21:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[resigning]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5738</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I just had a terrific second interview interview and was verbally offered a job yesterday, and I am over the moon about it. It&#8217;s a huge jump in title and salary. The CEO said, pending my reference checks, I will have the offer in writing on Friday. They are small and scrappy, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I just had a terrific second interview interview and was verbally offered a job yesterday, and I am over the moon about it. It&#8217;s a huge jump in title and salary. The CEO said, pending my reference checks, I will have the offer in writing on Friday. They are small and scrappy, and they need me to start as soon as I can, so I said I would give notice two weeks after I have the offer in writing.</em></p>
<p><em>However, the organization I work with now (another lovely nonprofit, but very large and resource-rich) is sending me to a three day conference on Sunday &#8212; flight, hotel, the whole nine yards. My boss will be at the conference too &#8212; and she&#8217;s not a very positive person to be around as it is. She has a mean vindictive streak, which is part of why I am so excited about moving on.</em></p>
<p><em>How should I handle this? I don&#8217;t want to ruin both of our conference experiences by giving notice on Friday and then enduring awkwardness, and I don&#8217;t want to look like a jerk who purposefully planned a free conference out of this and then gave notice on my first day back. (It was a total coincidence &#8212; this organization even recruited me, I wasn&#8217;t job hunting!) Should I back out of the conference altogether? The fees/hotel/airfare are all paid and non-refundable, nor are they transferable, so it&#8217;s not like I could send someone else in my stead.</em></p>
<p><em>I have great relationships with the whole team at my current organization, except my boss. I want to do the right thing here. What do you recommend?</em></p>
<p>Talk to her your manager and give your notice on Friday, after you have the written offer (and have accepted it). Tell her that you will do whatever she prefers regarding the conference &#8212; go or not go, whatever she thinks makes the most sense.</p>
<p>From there, it&#8217;s up to her. You&#8217;ll have been open and transparent and willing to do what the organization prefers. And some job offers just aren&#8217;t perfectly timed; reasonable people understand that.</p>
<p>That said, if you&#8217;d really rather not attend the conference now and you don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s any benefit to the organization for you attending since you&#8217;re leaving, it&#8217;s fine to push the scales a little in that direction, by saying something like, &#8220;I realize that it won&#8217;t be very useful to the organization to send me to the conference now, so I could stay home but see if I can negotiate refunds for us from the hotel and the conference.&#8221; (You have better chances of succeeding at refunds with those two, even if they&#8217;re allegedly non-refundable, than with the airline tickets.) And even if you can&#8217;t get any refunds, not going will still save the organization some money &#8212; your meals, cabs, etc. So it&#8217;s worth offering.</p>
<p>But don&#8217;t wait until you&#8217;re back. Be transparent, give the organization as much notice as you can, and let them decide how they want to handle this.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/how-to-resign-when-youre-about-to-go-to-a-3-day-conference.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>manager is forcing coworker to wear a wedding ring even though she&#8217;s not married</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/manager-is-forcing-coworker-to-wear-a-wedding-ring-even-though-shes-not-married.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/manager-is-forcing-coworker-to-wear-a-wedding-ring-even-though-shes-not-married.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 16:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advice about your boss]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5736</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I have a question regarding a coworker of mine. I realize it is technically none of my business, I am in a different department and it doesn&#8217;t affect me directly, but it really bothers me and wanted to get your opinion of how slimy this is. My coworker is fairly young, 23, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I have a question regarding a coworker of mine. I realize it is technically none of my business, I am in a different department and it doesn&#8217;t affect me directly, but it really bothers me and wanted to get your opinion of how slimy this is. My coworker is fairly young, 23, very pretty, and has an outgoing personality. She is in the sales/member services department of our company and has only been here about 3 months. It is part of her job to attend conferences with the manager of that department (she is older) and they are supposed to talk to other companies about joining our company. At the last conference, several men had hit on her, and I guess her manager was annoyed by it and felt this was distracting from her &#8220;doing her job.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>This manager &#8220;requested&#8221; (more like insisted) she buy a fake wedding ring and wear it during this conference, and future conferences. She basically told her, &#8220;Either wear that or I am going to have to reconsider bringing you to these conferences.&#8221; I am not going to ask the &#8220;is that even legal&#8221; question &#8212; but on a scale of 1-10, how inappropriate is this? I would imagine if it was my coworker&#8217;s idea, I might feel differently about it, but she didn&#8217;t feel she was doing anything wrong at the conference. And as far as I am concerned, it is not likely that a wedding ring (fake OR real) is going to ward off men who are attracted to her and hitting on her in the first place.</em></p>
<p><em>I feel for her because of the fact that she is so young, and new, and feels she can&#8217;t say no, but is uncomfortable with the situation. I just feel it is wrong and violates her to some degree. This young coworker does have a boyfriend, and says she talks to everyone at the conferences (not just the men) and has no interest in seeing them, dating them, etc&#8230;she is just doing her job by talking to them and explaining our company to these people. She asked me for advice, and I am not sure what to tell her. I don&#8217;t want her to go against what her boss is telling her, but still don&#8217;t think it is right.</em></p>
<p>What the &#8230;.?!</p>
<p>This is totally inappropriate and not okay. If the manager has a problem with how your coworker is conducting herself, she should address that &#8212; but it sounds like that&#8217;s not the issue at all; she just doesn&#8217;t like the fact that men flirt with her.</p>
<p>It would be one thing to give her advice about how to quickly shut that down &#8212; and even to tell her that she needs to do so, although it&#8217;s pretty hard to insist on that when it&#8217;s in the context of talking to someone about your company&#8217;s products. Hell, it wouldn&#8217;t even be all that egregious for her to say, &#8220;You know, if you want to ward some of this off, one way is to wear a ring.&#8221; (I happen to think that&#8217;s a ridiculous solution, and I agree with you that it won&#8217;t stop the flirting, but simply mentioning it isn&#8217;t egregious.)</p>
<p>But telling her that she&#8217;ll reconsider taking her to conferences if she doesn&#8217;t do it is so far, far over the line of what&#8217;s okay that I cannot imagine how her manager thinks this is acceptable to do.</p>
<p>Moreover, there probably <em>are</em> legal issues in play here. The manager is telling your coworker that she will change her assignments at work (the conferences) and stop giving her this particular professional opportunity if your coworker doesn&#8217;t take steps to make herself less appealing to men, which gets into some pretty sticky discrimination issues. I&#8217;m not saying it&#8217;s a slam-dunk case, because it&#8217;s not, but it&#8217;s certainly something no responsible company would want to spend the legal fees to find out for sure.</p>
<p>In any case &#8230; ideally, your coworker would say to her manager, &#8220;I am not comfortable wearing a wedding ring when I&#8217;m not married. I am conducting myself professionally and not doing anything to invite inappropriate behavior. If there&#8217;s something specific you&#8217;d like me to do differently in the way I handle myself at these conferences, I&#8217;m very open to the feedback, but I&#8217;m not comfortable wearing a fake ring, and I certainly hope that won&#8217;t impact the opportunities you give me here.&#8221;</p>
<p>If you have an HR department, she should also get them in the loop on this, because they will probably shut her boss down pretty quickly &#8212; and she can also ask them to ensure there&#8217;s no retaliation against her for this.</p>
<p>However, there&#8217;s open retaliation and there&#8217;s more subtle retaliation, and the latter is a lot harder to police. The fact is, your coworker is working for a manager who has issues with the way men respond to her, so she&#8217;s going to need to be prepared to assert herself against future weirdness as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/manager-is-forcing-coworker-to-wear-a-wedding-ring-even-though-shes-not-married.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>258</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>I stepped down from a promotion and now my boss hates me</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/i-stepped-down-from-a-promotion-and-now-my-boss-hates-me.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/i-stepped-down-from-a-promotion-and-now-my-boss-hates-me.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 15:15:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advice about your boss]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5728</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I&#8217;ve been at my current job for two years and really enjoyed working here until the last six months. In a nutshell, I was given an account management position when the old acct manager quit, and was left doing a two-person job by myself until I finally announced I was not prepared for this [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve been at my current job for two years and really enjoyed working here until the last six months. In a nutshell, I was given an account management position when the old acct manager quit, and was left doing a two-person job by myself until I finally announced I was not prepared for this and wanted to step down. It was decided I would still be doing most of the account manager duties, but that my supervisor would be the &#8220;face&#8221; of the company when dealing with clients. It&#8217;s still a lot more work than I was used to, but I find it manageable and even enjoyable most of the time. </em></p>
<p><em>At the time I stepped down, my boss was very sympathetic and supportive. Now, however, she seems to be going out of her way to make me feel like an idiot. Whenever I ask a question in a meeting or make some sort of comment, her reply is always impatient and often sarcastic. This is something I have much difficulty dealing with; I can take it once in a while, but not multiple times every single day, and I&#8217;m at the point where I just can&#8217;t keep my mouth shut. Whenever she makes some rude or sarcastic remark, I find myself firing right back at her, even in front of others (including my direct supervisor). I&#8217;m just not sure what I did to inspire her attitude toward me, or what I can do to make it better. I&#8217;m not sure what she expects of me. Any insight would be much appreciated.</em></p>
<p>You can read <a href="http://quickbase.intuit.com/blog/2013/04/02/360-answers-i-stepped-down-from-a-promotion-and-now-my-boss-hates-me/" target="_blank">my answer to this question over at the Fast Track blog by Intuit QuickBase today</a>. Three other career experts weigh in on the answer as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/i-stepped-down-from-a-promotion-and-now-my-boss-hates-me.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>want me to review your resume?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/want-me-to-review-your-resume-2.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/want-me-to-review-your-resume-2.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 13:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5725</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I get a lot of requests to give people feedback on their resumes, but because it&#8217;s time-consuming to do it well, I usually turn them down unless they&#8217;re friends or family. But for a short time, I&#8217;m re-opening the resume review offer that I&#8217;ve run a couple of times before When I&#8217;ve offered this in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>I get a lot of requests to give people feedback on their resumes, but because it&#8217;s time-consuming to do it well, I usually turn them down unless they&#8217;re friends or family. But for a short time, I&#8217;m re-opening the resume review offer that I&#8217;ve run a couple of times before</p>
<p><strong>When I&#8217;ve offered this in the past, the response has been so overwhelming that I&#8217;ve had to close the offer after just a few days, so reserve this now if you&#8217;re interested!</strong></p>
<p><strong>The cost:</strong> $99</p>
<p><strong>What you&#8217;ll get:</strong> As you can probably tell by the price, I&#8217;m not going to entirely rewrite your resume for you. People who do that charge a lot more. What you&#8217;ll get for 99 bucks: I&#8217;ll read your resume, I&#8217;ll give you suggestions for improving it, I&#8217;ll tell you where I think it&#8217;s weak and where I think it&#8217;s strong. I&#8217;ll tell you if your design sucks. I&#8217;ll tell you if you&#8217;re coming across as generic and/or unimpressive and how to fix it if you are. I&#8217;ll tell you what you need to change to have a resume that will make a hiring manager excited to interview you.</p>
<p>(And because I obsessively edit things, I might not be able to stop myself from editing it too. Fair warning.)</p>
<p>To be clear, this isn&#8217;t multiple rounds of revisions, or a rewrite service, or anything like that. It&#8217;s really just a bunch of notes on what I&#8217;d like to see you doing differently &#8212; what a hiring manager might think when looking at your resume.</p>
<p><strong>Limited time:</strong> I don&#8217;t want to be a full-time resume reviewer, so this offer is only good for this week, not something I&#8217;ll be offering regularly. So if you want it, lock it in now.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.askamanager.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/closed1.gif"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2379" alt="closed" src="http://www.askamanager.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/closed1.gif" width="126" height="83" /></a></p>
<p>(And because I know not everyone can afford that, I&#8217;m also offering a discount on my my ebook, <strong><em><a href="http://www.askamanager.org/how-to-get-job-e-book">How to Get a Job: Secrets of a Hiring Manager</a>, </em></strong>where you&#8217;ll find lots of resume advice &#8212; just not customized to your particular resume. You can get a 20% discount this week by using this code: <em>april2013 )</em></p>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> <em>Due to the level of demand today, please be aware that for any reviews purchased after 6 p.m. on April 2, you might not receive your feedback until late April. (Although if you need it faster, email me and I&#8217;ll see what I can do.)</em></p>
<p><strong>Update 2:</strong> <em>This offer is now closed. But it might come around again later this year! </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/want-me-to-review-your-resume-2.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>terse answer Tuesday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/terse-answer-tuesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-7.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/terse-answer-tuesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-7.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 04:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5729</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s terse answer Tuesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Should freelancers bill as time is incurred or at the end of a project? I have a question about freelance etiquette. Is it customary to bill for my time as it&#8217;s incurred &#8212; i.e., the hours I worked in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s terse answer Tuesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Should freelancers bill as time is incurred or at the end of a project?</strong></p>
<p><em>I have a question about freelance etiquette. Is it customary to bill for my time as it&#8217;s incurred &#8212; i.e., the hours I worked in the previous two weeks &#8212; or to bill when the final product is &#8220;delivered?&#8221; I have an new, ongoing freelance assignment to work 15 hours a week or so for a company, but my work is editorial, so there&#8217;s often some back-and-forth before projects are completed. So if I worked 12 hours on something one week that won&#8217;t be finalized for two more weeks, when&#8217;s the best time to send my invoice for that work? Maybe I&#8217;m overthinking this.</em></p>
<p>Different freelancers do it differently, but lots of people &#8212; including me &#8212; will tell you to bill as your time is incurred. Billing monthly is perfectly reasonable, and can minimize the trouble you might sometimes have collecting on a bill once a project is over. Good clients will always pay you without hassle, but not every client is a good one, and they have much more incentive to pay you when they still need you to do more work for them. Plus, if you&#8217;re going to have problems collecting, it&#8217;s better to find that out sooner rather than after you&#8217;ve put in hundreds of hours.</p>
<p>Generally, it&#8217;s a good idea to lay out your payment terms with a new client at the start of working with them, but if you didn&#8217;t, there&#8217;s no reason you can&#8217;t send over an invoice now with a note that simply says, &#8220;Here&#8217;s my invoice for my work in March.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>2. Candidate cried when we asked whether her current employer would make a counteroffer</strong></p>
<p><em>We just interviewed a candidate for a managerial job at our company. The interview went rather well, particularly during the skill test exercises and the case studies problem resolution process. But when we asked her what would happen once we offer her the job &#8212; will her current employer try to retain her? &#8212; she reacted emotionally, started crying, and went to the washroom to wipe off her tears.</em></p>
<p><em>She said that she got emotional because she and her current employer had a discussion where her manager did not want to raise her salary. According to her, her current employer under-values her worth and had his opportunity to respond to her requests for more recognition (salary-wise), so she suggested that once we offer her a job, her current employer will not up the offer or revisit her request &#8212; he simply had his opportunity, according to her.</em></p>
<p><em>Nevertheless, why did she become so emotional regarding the question? How do you deal with this as a prospective employer? Do you not continue forward with an offer for employment?</em></p>
<p>Oooh, this is troubling. First of all, she&#8217;s basically telling you that if her current employer did counter-offer, she might take it (but that she believes they won&#8217;t). Second, while this reaction might be something you&#8217;d overlook for a junior or a non-managerial position, I&#8217;d be concerned about hiring her for a managerial job, where she&#8217;s going to need to have much tougher conversations with people and remain calm and unemotional. Yes, everyone has emotional moments, including great managers, but this would make me wary.</p>
<p><strong>3. Leaving a temp job earlier than planned</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve been consulting part-time on the side for another organization, with the hopes that it would turn into something full-time eventually. It&#8217;s a new organization, and they&#8217;re still figuring out budgets, etc., and I was told several weeks ago that it would likely be a little while before they could hire anyone full-time. However, about 2 weeks later, their financial situation changed, and they are now more flexible with their hiring timeline. I had just agreed to a temp position running for several months, and reiterated my willingness to continue part-time for the new organization, with the hope that we could work out something full-time after the temp position was over.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve since started the temp position (last week), and it is just not a good fit &#8212; not enough work, definitely more basic than I had been led to believe &#8212; and I&#8217;d really like to approach the first organization and let them know that the temp position isn&#8217;t a good fit, and I&#8217;d like to give my two weeks notice, if they are still interested in hiring me full-time. (Wording it more eloquently than that, of course.)</em></p>
<p><em>Does initially telling the first organization that I had agreed to a temp position, and now backing out of it look really, really bad? And how bad is it/how many bridges does it burn for me to be leaving a temp position much sooner than expected? To be fair, I didn&#8217;t sign a contract or anything, and the position with the other organization is one I had been pursuing long before this temp position opened up. But I worry that it looks flaky/will ruin my reputation with the temp agency (although I would be giving the standard 2 weeks notice that the agency requests).</em></p>
<p>This stuff happens with temp jobs &#8212; few people will turn down full-time employment in favor of a short-term temp job. You agency may not be willing to send you out for other long-term jobs if you go back to them in the future, but it&#8217;s not a heinous crime.</p>
<p>That said, I&#8217;d word your message to the first organization a little differently &#8212; don&#8217;t talk about why it&#8217;s not a good fit. Just say something like, &#8220;Things have changed a bit on my side, and I could be available for full-time work within two weeks if you&#8217;d like me to.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>4. When a hiring contact changes</strong></p>
<p><em>I am in the process of sending out last-minute applications for summer internships. I applied to my dream organization about a month ago, and the directions on the website originally told me to send my resume, cover letter, and writing sample to Contact A. I checked the company&#8217;s website again today, and noticed that the directions on the website now stipulate that I send my resume, cover letter, etc. to Contact B.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m trying to resist my panicked temptation to re-send my materials, but at the same time I don&#8217;t want to be disqualified from the applicant pool for not sending my materials to the new coordinator. Advice?</em></p>
<p>Just be straightforward. Email Contact B with a note that says, &#8220;I earlier submitted these materials to Contact A but just that the instructions now state they should go to you. I&#8217;d love to talk with you about the opening if you think I might be a strong fit.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>5. Recovering after you bomb a skills test during a job interview</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m currently going through the hiring process for a communications and marketing position. As part of the process, the hiring company has asked me to complete a standardized test. This test was basically the SATs for business and, like the SATs, I completely bombed the math portion leaving quite a few questions blank and ultimately running out of time. In reality, I&#8217;m quite good at crunching numbers, running reports and overall sticking to budgets, but have never been great at taking timed tests. I feel as though my initial interview went really well and I had a great rapport, but now I&#8217;m a bit nervous that these results have potentially knocked me out of the running completely. What do employers hope to gain from the results of tests like this?</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve toyed with the idea of following up with the hiring manager, via email, to provide a bit more insight into my experience and also how I make adjustments in the real world. My experience to date has always been interpreting data related to charts/graphs that I&#8217;ve set up and I can provide insight on the fly, so this really has never been an issue professionally. Is there value in doing this, or would it just serve to annoy the hiring manager? If there is value, any suggestions on how to phrase it? This is definitely one of the better opportunities available in my area so I&#8217;d hate to be passed over because of a standardized test that I don&#8217;t feel accurately reflects my experience or capabilities.</em></p>
<p>Sure, you can do that. Say that you had the sense that you didn&#8217;t do well on the test, but that while timed tests have never been your strength, you&#8217;ve been very successful at using the skills being tested in real-world work situations. Then give concrete examples of how you&#8217;ve excelled using those skills. Be specific, and make sure that whatever you offer up speaks as directly as possible to what the hiring manager&#8217;s concern is likely to be: that you don&#8217;t possess the skills the test was assessing.</p>
<p><strong>6. Negotiating higher severance</strong></p>
<p><em>I was laid off two days ago. I worked for a major corporation that had financial issues and needed to downsize the workforce. The severance package offered is 2 months paid with full benefits, then a lump sum of cash. I get my tuition reimbursement issued and all of my PTO will be paid out. Two people have advised me to negotiate my severance. In addition to higher payout (or more months of employment), I&#8217;d like to ask for copies of my most recent performance reviews (is that weird?).</em></p>
<p><em>Also, as an aside, I&#8217;m not angry over the whole situation. The company is going through hard times and the decision was based solely off of business needs and nothing personal. I know I had great rapport with coworkers and management and my monthly and yearly reviews were stellar.</em></p>
<p>To get more severance, there usually needs to be some incentive for the employer to give you more &#8212; such as that they want you to agree to stay longer and train a replacement or transition operations, or that they&#8217;re concerned you might otherwise sue over a real or perceived legal issue like harassment or discrimination (because you sign a release relinquishing any legal claims in exchange for severance). If you don&#8217;t have anything like that to use as incentive, they&#8217;re not likely to give you more just because you ask &#8230; although you can certainly still ask, because you never know.</p>
<p>You can also certainly ask for copies of your performance evaluations; you may or may not get them, but there&#8217;s nothing wrong with asking (and you should explain that you want them to document your performance for future prospective employers, since otherwise they may think you want to use them as ammunition to challenge the layoff decision in some way).</p>
<p><strong>7. Online applications that ask for &#8220;additional information to support your application&#8221;</strong></p>
<p><em>When filling out an application form and they ask for &#8220;additional information to support your application,&#8221; what are they expecting in that box? I&#8217;ve already filled in education and employment details, as well as a section on why I want/would be good for the job, and I&#8217;m drawing a blank. Am I missing something obvious?</em></p>
<p>If there&#8217;s anything you would include in a cover letter that you didn&#8217;t already include in the section on why you want and would be good at the job, include it here. Otherwise, it&#8217;s fine to ignore it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/terse-answer-tuesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-7.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>79</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>when you keep uncovering errors made by your well-loved predecessor</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/when-you-keep-uncovering-errors-made-by-your-well-loved-predecessor.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/when-you-keep-uncovering-errors-made-by-your-well-loved-predecessor.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 18:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advice about your coworkers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5727</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I just started a new job at a nonprofit organization, taking over for a beloved employee who was here for 20 years and is still a big part of our organization&#8217;s community. He was very successful, but I am coming across a lot of pretty substantial errors he made. A good example [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I just started a new job at a nonprofit organization, taking over for a beloved employee who was here for 20 years and is still a big part of our organization&#8217;s community.</em></p>
<p><em>He was very successful, but I am coming across a lot of pretty substantial errors he made. A good example is a grant proposal in which he basically ignored the guidelines, although we got the grant anyway. Now I am working on this year&#8217;s proposal for that grant; I have to follow the guidelines and I think I really ought to tell my boss about the discrepancies and about what I am doing differently this year. But I am hesitant to do so, because this would be about my 10th time alerting her to something I came across that he kind of messed up. I don&#8217;t want to seem as though we have a pattern of &#8220;now look at THIS thing Joe screwed up,&#8221; and really I don&#8217;t want to speak ill of him at all, especially when there never have been negative consequences (such as missing out on a grant). But she is the executive director and she should be aware of everything, especially when I am doing things very differently than he did. Any advice on how to navigate this?</em></p>
<p>Well, when you say he was &#8220;very successful,&#8221; what exactly does that mean? If it means that he achieved unusually good results, then it&#8217;s important to keep that mind when you&#8217;re assessing the mistakes you&#8217;re coming across. The grant application might be a good example of this &#8212; he didn&#8217;t follow the guidelines, but the organization got the grant anyway, so it seems like he did something right. Sure, it&#8217;s possible that that was a fluke, but if the outcome was successful, you&#8217;re probably going to have a hard time convincing people that it was a problem that he didn&#8217;t follow the guidelines. (And yes, of course it&#8217;s possible that if he had a habit of not following grant guidelines, there were other grants he applied for that the organization <em>didn&#8217;t</em> get &#8230; but it&#8217;s also possible that he was good enough at the job that he knew what could be ignored and what really mattered.)</p>
<p>Is it possible that the other mistakes you&#8217;re finding fit this profile? If something is technically a mistake or not a best practice but he got fantastic results anyway, it might be worth considering that he knew other, different ways of being effective.</p>
<p>Of course, maybe that&#8217;s not the case at all and the grant application example is just misleading me. If in fact you&#8217;re uncovering things that were genuinely messed up &#8212; things where the long-term results were not as good as they could have been because of his mistakes &#8212; then that&#8217;s different. But start by making sure that you&#8217;re really being objective about whether that&#8217;s the situation or not.</p>
<p>Either way, it&#8217;s not uncommon that you&#8217;d do things a bit different from your predecessor. So when you feel that you need to bring something to your manager&#8217;s attention &#8212; whether it&#8217;s because there&#8217;s a problem he caused that she needs to know about or because you want her to understand why you&#8217;re handling something differently &#8212; approach it as simply keeping your manager in the loop. For example: &#8220;I wanted to let you know that I&#8217;m doing the grant proposal a little differently than it was done in the past, because I&#8217;ve found that they&#8217;ll sometimes reject you if you don&#8217;t follow their guidelines to a T.&#8221; You could even ask, &#8220;I noticed that Joe didn&#8217;t strictly follow them, and I wonder if that&#8217;s because we had a more informal relationship with this foundation or whether there&#8217;s any other context like that that I should know about?&#8221;</p>
<p>As long as you&#8217;re not presenting this stuff in a tone of &#8220;here&#8217;s <em>another</em> thing I&#8217;ve uncovered,&#8221; your manager isn&#8217;t likely to think you&#8217;re being unnecessarily hard on Joe.</p>
<p>But what you don&#8217;t want is to find yourself in a situation where your predecessor was successful precisely because he knew when he could and couldn&#8217;t break the rules and then end up coming across yourself as someone who doesn&#8217;t have that nuanced level of understanding. So be sure that you&#8217;re assessing what you&#8217;re finding not just as &#8220;is this done correctly?&#8221; but rather as &#8220;did this get good long-term results for the organization?&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/when-you-keep-uncovering-errors-made-by-your-well-loved-predecessor.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>65</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>ask the readers: what do people do at conferences?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/ask-the-readers-what-do-people-do-at-conferences.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/ask-the-readers-what-do-people-do-at-conferences.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 16:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[networking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5719</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I am now two months into my new job and I am really enjoying it. I am really excited about a huge conference that is coming up soon and my boss has registered both of us to go. Since this is my first professional job after college, I have never been to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I am now two months into my new job and I am really enjoying it. I am really excited about a huge conference that is coming up soon and my boss has registered both of us to go. Since this is my first professional job after college, I have never been to a conference, and really have no idea what to do at conferences. I know that there will be different sessions, discussions and networking events, but I am a little nervous because I will be mostly on my own and I am so new to the industry. What should I wear? (My industry is in philanthropy, if that helps.) What do people do at conferences? How do I use this opportunity to network?</em></p>
<p>Readers, want to lend your wisdom to help this conference novice? Weigh in with your advice in the comments section.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/ask-the-readers-what-do-people-do-at-conferences.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>99</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>how much notice should you give when you resign?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/how-much-notice-should-you-give-when-you-resign.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/how-much-notice-should-you-give-when-you-resign.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5723</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You’re preparing to leave your job, and it looks like you’ll be getting a job offer any day now. When should you let your current employer know that you’re going to be leaving, and how much notice should you give when you do? You want to proceed carefully here. While you might be getting excited, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/04/01/how-much-notice-should-you-give-when-you-resign"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2095" alt="featured-on-usn" src="http://www.askamanager.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/featured-on-usn1.jpg" width="90" height="60" /></a>You’re preparing to leave your job, and it looks like you’ll be getting a job offer any day now. When should you let your current employer know that you’re going to be leaving, and how much notice should you give when you do?</p>
<p>You want to proceed carefully here. While you might be getting excited, there’s potential for doing real harm if you misstep. Over at U.S. News &amp; World Report, I lay out <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/04/01/how-much-notice-should-you-give-when-you-resign">two cardinal rules to follow</a> when it comes to when and how to tell your employer that you’re resigning.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/how-much-notice-should-you-give-when-you-resign.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>39</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>mini answer Monday &#8212; 6 short answers to 6 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/mini-answer-monday-6-short-answers-to-6-short-questions-3.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/mini-answer-monday-6-short-answers-to-6-short-questions-3.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5722</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s mini answer Monday &#8212; six short answers to six short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. HR called to tell me they &#8220;couldn&#8217;t afford me,&#8221; then said that they could I am currently employed in a managerial position at a major corporation. It is a good job but I feel like I have outgrown it [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s mini answer Monday &#8212; six short answers to six short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. HR called to tell me they &#8220;couldn&#8217;t afford me,&#8221; then said that they could</strong></p>
<p><em>I am currently employed in a managerial position at a major corporation. It is a good job but I feel like I have outgrown it in the 3 years I have been there. Recently a contact reached out and told me about a great position at a smaller, action-oriented company. I applied and had one phone interview with the hiring manager and a second interview with the other managers in the department. Both went very well and I am scheduled for an on-site interview next week. Up until last Wednesday, I was very excited about the opportunity.</em></p>
<p><em>Last week, after my second interview, I received a call from a member of the HR department. Before he even introduced himself, he bluntly asked what salary I currently made and what I was expecting. I gave my current salary and before I could get another word out, he stated, &#8220;We can&#8217;t afford you.&#8221; He then gave me a maximum salary of only about 70% of what I currently make. He said he thinks that the hiring manager was only interviewing me to please my influential contact and that even though they can&#8217;t afford me, he would be happy to give my resume to another larger company because &#8220;they would go nuts&#8221; for someone with my qualifications. I politely asserted my interest in this job and expressed my confusion because the hiring manager and I had discussed my salary requirements previously. He stated he would follow up with the hiring manager and would let me know ASAP if they could not afford me as he suspected.</em></p>
<p><em>A couple hours later, he calls me back and &#8220;good news,&#8221; they can afford me after all. But now I have this sinking feeling in my gut that by pursuing this opportunity I am stepping into a position with bad management. Am I being too sensitive to what seemed to be a very rude and confusing discussion? I had good experiences with everyone else in the company, but I can&#8217;t shake this interaction. Can you give me some perspective?</em></p>
<p>Ask your interviewer about it when you meet. Say, &#8220;Bob called me last week to tell me that he was sure you couldn&#8217;t afford me, but then called back a few hours later to say that it wouldn&#8217;t be a problem. I was confused by that, and wonder if you can shed any light on it for me.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>2. When do I tell an employer about my scheduling needs?</strong></p>
<p><em>I’m in the process of looking for a new job and I’ve run into a bit of an issue. My young son is disabled and requires a lot of doctor and therapy appointments. My husband and I split this up as much as possible and always try to keep our time scheduled in the most effective way, but it is still not unusual to have to leave work for 2-3 appointments a month. It is very important that I work for an employer with flexible time-off and/or flexible scheduling. But it is also very important for me to be in a company with a culture accepting of my sometimes-crazy schedule.</em></p>
<p><em>I don’t want to set myself up for failure or find myself in a situation where – while everything looked great on paper – my coworker/boss is annoyed by my situation. What is the best way to deal with this? Is it appropriate to bring up my family situation in the later stages of the interview process? Is there a way to find out about this aspect of the company culture without scaring potential bosses away thinking I’m going to be chronically absent?</em></p>
<p>Wait until you have an offer, because at that point they&#8217;ve already decided that they want you (whereas if you bring it up earlier, you risk them being scared off). Talk in concrete specifics about the situation&#8217;s impact on your schedule (for instance, an average of X appointments per month, two of them without much notice, most requiring you to leave two hours early &#8212; or whatever it is). Then pay attention to the reaction. Do they sound hesitant? Worried? Annoyed? Supportive? They way they respond, as well as what they actually say, will tell you a lot.</p>
<p><strong>3. Should I tell on my boss for working a side job from our office?</strong></p>
<p><em>I noticed that my boss, the CFO, always has a laptop on his desk in addition to his regular desktop computer. I wondered why he needed two computers but didn&#8217;t think much of it. Today I found out that he has a second job and that&#8217;s what the laptop is for. When I walk by his office he is more often working on the laptop than on his desktop. The worst part is that we are a struggling non-profit and we desperately need a competent CFO whose only focus is on fixing the financial problems in our organization. He has only been with the company for four months and I haven&#8217;t been impressed by his management style, nor have I seen any changes or improvements. There are hundreds of people employed by this agency and we run important programs that the community depends on. I work for a nonprofit because I care about our mission and I&#8217;m appalled that someone who is so high up in the company would take advantage like this.</em></p>
<p><em>The CFO told another employee about his second job, and that employee told me. Should I tell the Interim Executive Director about this? We get along great and I don&#8217;t think there would be any backlash on me for telling, but I&#8217;m just not sure if its my place to do so. If you would tell, how would you approach that conversation?</em></p>
<p>Yes, because in a nonprofit, you have a responsibility to the issue the organization works on or the people it serves to speak up in this kind of situation. Now, it&#8217;s possible that the organization&#8217;s management knows about what your boss is doing and has given permission for it &#8212; but it&#8217;s also possible that they have no idea. I&#8217;d say something like this: &#8220;I feel awkward mentioning this, but I feel more uncomfortable not saying anything. I realize this might be something you know about and are okay with, but in case you don&#8217;t, I felt obligated to talk to you about it.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>4. Denying an employee&#8217;s training request</strong></p>
<p><em>An employee has requested to attend an out-of-town training that I feel is beyond his scope of work, but I don&#8217;t want to discourage him by using this as an excuse in denying his request. This person has been a problem employee for years and will create a big incident if I refuse his request. I would appreciate your advice on how to deny this request gracefully.</em></p>
<p>Well, the bigger problem is why you&#8217;ve allowed a problem employee to stay a problem employee for years. You should be managing him out of the organization, not allowing him to stay on your staff and make you shy away from making responsible decisions.</p>
<p>As for the training, tell him that it&#8217;s not in the scope of his work, that you don&#8217;t have an unlimited budget for trainings, and that you need to save it for XYZ. And if he creates a &#8220;big incident,&#8221; use that as the starting point in tackling that problem &#8212; make your standards of behave clear, require him to adhere to them, and replace him if he doesn&#8217;t.</p>
<p><strong>5. Salary negotiations when your salary is public record</strong></p>
<p><em>I work for state government (Minnesota), and I am beginning to look for a new job. As I think about and plan salary negotiations, I have been reading your instructions to avoid telling prospective employers your current salary. The problem is that the state of Minnesota salaries for individual employees are very easily googleable, especially if you&#8217;re looking at my work history. How, if at all should I address this in salary negotiations? I have been saying &#8220;Because my salary is a public record, I&#8217;ll just tell you that the dollar amount is $X, not including any benefits or retirement.&#8221; Or should I just ignore it and let them find it if they know to find it?</em></p>
<p>There&#8217;s no reason to bring it up proactively. If they ask what you&#8217;ve been making, you can say, &#8220;As a state employee, my salary is public record, but I&#8217;m seeking a salary of $X, because of ____ (fill in with why you deserve $X).&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>6. Including 360 comments on your resume</strong></p>
<p><em>My current employer, like many others, has a 360 review process that’s performed annually for employees and their managers to get anonymous performance feedback from others in the organization they work with. What are your thoughts on including those comments on a resume? I’m on the fence because on one hand, the testimonials are a pretty strong endorsement which the recruiter would not have access to. On the other hand 1) it adds to the length of the resume and 2) the hiring company may have a similar program and consider it a violation of trust to turn around and use that data to get a new job.</em></p>
<p>I dont think it&#8217;s a violation of trust, but I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;ll be particularly effectively, because anonymous feedback rarely is &#8212; you need to know the source to know how much weight to put on it. If there&#8217;s something in there that&#8217;s particularly strong (like, <em>really</em> strong, not just pretty good), or if there&#8217;s a particularly theme to the commentary, you could briefly mention that in your cover letter, but I wouldn&#8217;t put it on a resume.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/04/mini-answer-monday-6-short-answers-to-6-short-questions-3.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>75</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>can you walk out of an interview before it starts?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/can-you-walk-out-of-an-interview-before-it-starts.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/can-you-walk-out-of-an-interview-before-it-starts.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[interviewing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5721</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I have a unique situation that I ran into and would like your perspective on it. I went to an interview, and as soon as I opened the door, I knew it was not the place for me. I already had some reservations going in, but was trying to keep an open [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I have a unique situation that I ran into and would like your perspective on it. I went to an interview, and as soon as I opened the door, I knew it was not the place for me. I already had some reservations going in, but was trying to keep an open mind. But opening that door to the office shut it right away for me.</em></p>
<p><em>The first indication was the size of the office. I thrive in a medium to large environment and this was the exact opposite. I tried to research this beforehand but was unable to find exact information. The second indication was that I want a place with other colleagues to interact with, who aren&#8217;t afraid to talk to each other, that has a life to it, and this was definitely not the place for that. It felt more like the living room in a house that was just for show and not a place to be in.</em></p>
<p><em> The other thing is that, perhaps odd to say, I think you can tell a lot when you walk into a place by the energy/feeling around it. Are employees happy, is there a sense of life, etc.? When I opened the door, all I felt was despair and stress. It was just sad. Which confirmed my initial feelings from a phone conversation.</em></p>
<p><em>While waiting to be interviewed, I was debating even if I should go forward. What are your thoughts? Should I have just told the interviewer right away that I knew it was not the place for me? Or would that have been rude and it is proper to go forward with the interview?</em></p>
<p>I&#8217;d say to do the interview anyway. Announcing that just from looking at their offices you know it&#8217;s not the place for you is a pretty dramatic statement. I&#8217;m not saying it&#8217;s not a valid one &#8212; but it&#8217;s the kind of thing that&#8217;s going to be fairly shocking to be on the receiving end of, and that those people will remember forever. And you might not care if they do, but they also might be connected to some other job that you&#8217;re applying for some day, a job that you do want, and you don&#8217;t want them to say, &#8220;Oh, her! We were supposed to interview her, but she arrived at our office and immediately said it wasn&#8217;t the right fit, without even talking to us.&#8221;</p>
<p>Now, if this were an all-day interview or involved some other major investment of time and energy, then I&#8217;d say it would be more okay to back out &#8230; but even then, I&#8217;d still talk with them for a while before backing out, so that you could more credibly tell them &#8212; based on that conversation &#8212; you don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s the right fit, and then excuse yourself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/can-you-walk-out-of-an-interview-before-it-starts.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>50</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>turning down an interview at a dysfunctional organization</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/turning-down-an-interview-at-a-dysfunctional-organization.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/turning-down-an-interview-at-a-dysfunctional-organization.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[interviewing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5718</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I recently interviewed with a nonprofit organization and was asked to come back for a second interview with their chief philanthropy officer. During the first interview, I found out that a local colleague had done some work with the capital campaign. I followed up with him to get the inside scoop. Unfortunately, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I recently interviewed with a nonprofit organization and was asked to come back for a second interview with their chief philanthropy officer.</em></p>
<p><em>During the first interview, I found out that a local colleague had done some work with the capital campaign. I followed up with him to get the inside scoop. Unfortunately, he told me about all of their internal dysfunction (board, governance and leadership). I am looking to move to a more stable nonprofit so it doesn&#8217;t seem like this would be a right fit for me. However, it&#8217;s an organization I would consider working for in the future &#8212; if they got their act together.</em></p>
<p><em>How do I decline a second interview without burning bridges? Should I mention speaking with someone (unidentified) who gave me more insight into the workings of the organization? Or should I just keep it general &#8212; have decided to pursue other opportunities, etc.</em></p>
<p>Do not say that you spoke with someone who told you that the organization is dysfunctional. That will achieve nothing other than making your contact there really uncomfortable. And, really, what are they supposed to say to that? &#8220;Yes, we <em>are</em> a mess&#8221;?</p>
<p>It also serves no purpose &#8212; because what are they going to do with that information? Someone anonymous said that they have problems. Either they do and they know it, and hearing it from an outsider isn&#8217;t going to change anything. Or they don&#8217;t know it, in which case this will just be annoying to hear. Or they&#8217;re actually fine and your friend is wrong, and now they have to worry about what&#8217;s being said about them. There&#8217;s no purpose to any of that. And it&#8217;s not like they&#8217;re going to fix their issues and call you in a year and say, &#8220;We&#8217;re all cleaned up now, so we&#8217;d love to talk to you again.&#8221;</p>
<p>Instead, keep it general. You&#8217;re focusing on other jobs that seem like a better fit for you right now, etc.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/turning-down-an-interview-at-a-dysfunctional-organization.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>should you hug former colleagues when you see them at a job interview?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-hug-people-you-know-when-you-go-for-a-job-interview.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-hug-people-you-know-when-you-go-for-a-job-interview.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 17:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[interviewing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5717</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: A year ago, after a long tenure at a large corporation, I decided it was time for a change. The company had been undergoing significant turmoil, and a number of my peers had already been laid off or had left on their own. The position that I took is at a very [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>A year ago, after a long tenure at a large corporation, I decided it was time for a change. The company had been undergoing significant turmoil, and a number of my peers had already been laid off or had left on their own. The position that I took is at a very nice company, and I like the corporate culture here. However, I am just not finding the role to be quite the right fit, and I find my manager unprofessional (at best). I&#8217;ve done some scouting around here to see if I could switch managers and that doesn&#8217;t seem to be an option, at least not any time soon. HR has given me some strategies to deal with my manager, and it&#8217;s helped a bit, but I&#8217;m a working mom with young children, and if I am going to have my little ones in daycare, it&#8217;s going to be for a job that I really like.</em></p>
<p><em>What I decided to do is to see if there are opportunities at companies where there are clumps of employees from my former employer. I&#8217;ve kept in touch with a lot of people and LinkedIn made this process easy. There are four local companies that fit the bill. One of these happens to have an opening which sounds like a great fit, and as an an added bonus, it&#8217;s very close to my home. I applied (and I took the time to write a cover letter only because of your blog, so thank you). I then right away reached out via email to the two most senior people at this new company who I know. They both immediately offerred to help me out, and one of them even walked my resume into the hiring manager&#8217;s office for me (the CFO). I had the phone screen scheduled within a few hours, and I am waiting to hear when an interview will be scheduled next week. In the phone screen that I had earlier today, the recruiter made it clear that she had already asked around about me, and that I have the support of several people behind me in my candidacy for this job.</em></p>
<p><em>Here&#8217;s my question: I know about ten people at this company. I&#8217;m friendly with a lot of my coworkers, but I tend (for various reasons, some of which have to do with my work role) to keep my work life and my personal life separate. I mean, I chat with my coworkers and we&#8217;re friends, but I don&#8217;t see very many people outside of work, and I tend to drink very little at company events. So when I go into the office for the interview, if I see old coworkers who I know, do I hug them hello? I don&#8217;t want this to be awkward, and have I mentioned how very appreciative I am of the support? But the idea of hugging people hello while in a new office on an interview &#8230; I am concerned how the recruiter might view this. I definitely don&#8217;t want to give the impression that I am taking it as a given that I am getting the job because I have connections. What do you think?</em></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t hug them.</p>
<p>Greet them warmly, look pleased to see them, ask them with interest how they&#8217;ve been &#8212; but don&#8217;t hug them.</p>
<p>I know there are lots of huggers out there, and there are even some offices where hugging is normal (to my enormous discomfort), but there are far more offices where hugging as a greeting &#8212; even when you haven&#8217;t seen the person in a while &#8212; doesn&#8217;t generally happen. So it&#8217;s certainly not expected, and it&#8217;s not going to look weird if you don&#8217;t.</p>
<p>Of course, if someone moves in for a hug to you, return it &#8212; don&#8217;t pull away in horror or anything. (Assuming it&#8217;s not <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/09/our-employee-wont-stop-hugging-people.html">this woman</a>.) But there&#8217;s absolutely no need for you to go in planning on hugging anyone.</p>
<p>And no one will be offended by that. It&#8217;s an office, you&#8217;re former colleagues, not close friends, and you&#8217;re there for a job interview, not cuddles and embraces.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-hug-people-you-know-when-you-go-for-a-job-interview.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>asking your interviewer what&#8217;s next in the hiring process</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/asking-your-interviewer-whats-next-in-the-hiring-process.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/asking-your-interviewer-whats-next-in-the-hiring-process.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[interviewing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5716</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: What is your take on the candidate asking the interviewer, &#8220;What is next in the hiring process&#8221; or &#8220;Where do we go from here&#8221; types of questions? In short, I&#8217;m having a large disagreement with someone about the opinion and thinking behind this type of question. This person thinks that as a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>What is your take on the candidate asking the interviewer, &#8220;What is next in the hiring process&#8221; or &#8220;Where do we go from here&#8221; types of questions?</em></p>
<p><em>In short, I&#8217;m having a large disagreement with someone about the opinion and thinking behind this type of question. This person thinks that as a candidate, you have a right to know what the next steps in the hiring process are and when, as a candidate, you should expect a response by.</em></p>
<p><em>I don&#8217;t disagree with this, but I think asking this question ends up putting the interviewer on the spot and could therefore set up the candidate to be flagged as impatient and aggressive, which could cause problems later on.</em></p>
<p><em>I read your article on <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2011/07/asking-hard-sell-closing-questions-in-job-interviews.html">&#8220;closing&#8221; interview questions</a>, but it seems those questions are more geared toward wanting to know where you stand as opposed to, in this case, wanting to know when you should hear back from a company (and possibly where you stand). I&#8217;m not sure if the specific type of interview question falls under this category or not. What is your take on these types of questions?</em></p>
<p>It&#8217;s totally reasonable to ask about next steps and a likely timeline for them. In fact, I strongly urge that you never leave an interview without having asked, &#8220;What&#8217;s your timeline for next steps?&#8221;</p>
<p>That&#8217;s because otherwise you&#8217;re likely to go home and agonize and wonder when you should hear from them, and if you should have heard from them by now, and what it means that you haven&#8217;t heard from them by now. Asking about their timeline means that you&#8217;ll have some idea of whether it&#8217;s likely to be days or weeks (or longer), and it also means that if that timeframe passes and you haven&#8217;t heard from them, you have a reason to email them to check back in.</p>
<p>Asking about an interviewer&#8217;s timeline isn&#8217;t at all putting them on the spot. It&#8217;s a reasonable question that you&#8217;d ask at the end of lots of business meetings, not just interviews, and there&#8217;s nothing presumptuous, impatient, or aggressive about it. If they don&#8217;t know, they&#8217;ll just tell you that they don&#8217;t know.</p>
<p>Now, questions like &#8220;did I get the job?&#8221; or &#8220;is there any reason I wouldn&#8217;t be a great candidate for this job?&#8221; <em>are</em> too aggressive and pushy, and they do put the interviewer on the spot.</p>
<p>But no reasonable interviewer is going to bristle at being asked for a likely timeline for when you should expect to hear something.</p>
<p>Your friend wins this bet!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/asking-your-interviewer-whats-next-in-the-hiring-process.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>open thread</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/open-thread-5.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/open-thread-5.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5713</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s our monthly open thread! The comment section on this post is open for discussion with other readers on anything you want to talk about. If you want an answer from me, emailing me is still your best bet, but this is a chance to talk to other readers.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><a href="http://www.askamanager.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/photo-2.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-5715" alt="photo 2" src="http://www.askamanager.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/photo-2.jpg" width="113" height="151" /></a>It’s our monthly open thread!</p>
<p>The comment section on this post is open for discussion with other readers on anything you want to talk about.</p>
<p>If you want an answer from me, emailing me is still your best bet, but this is a chance to talk to other readers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/open-thread-5.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>882</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>fast answer Friday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/fast-answer-friday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-27.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/fast-answer-friday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-27.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 04:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5711</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s fast answer Friday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Should I interview my ex for a job managing me? I&#8217;m assisting in the hiring for an open position at my company. Unless I change departments (which is feasible), this new hire will be my direct supervisor. I&#8217;m mid-level [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s fast answer Friday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Should I interview my ex for a job managing me?</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m assisting in the hiring for an open position at my company. Unless I change departments (which is feasible), this new hire will be my direct supervisor. I&#8217;m mid-level and the position is senior but not executive level.</em></p>
<p><em>Someone I dated a few years ago is applying for the position and is likely to be a candidate we want to interview. We only dated for about 6 months and it ended amicably. I think he might be great at the job, and I&#8217;d be very comfortable working with him but uncomfortable with him being my boss. Do I interview him just like I would any other candidate? Do I excuse myself due to a personal relationship? If he is hired, is there a way to work out the situation without the whole office knowing we used to be together?</em></p>
<p><em>(My ex knows the situation, but he knows I am considering leaving the company within the next year or so for other reasons entirely. At this point, I&#8217;m most concerned about how to handle the interview process because I think there will be options for altering my reporting structure if it gets to that point.)</em></p>
<p>Stop keeping this to yourself, and tell whoever is handling the hiring for this position. If you don&#8217;t speak up now but end up having to disclose it later, it&#8217;s going to seem really weird that you didn&#8217;t say something earlier! Go to whoever is handling the hiring and say, &#8220;This is a little weird, because I used to date this candidate. I do think he&#8217;d be good at the job, but obviously I think I should recuse myself from interviewing him.&#8221;</p>
<p>If he does progress in the hiring process, then talk to whoever&#8217;s appropriate about ensuring that you don&#8217;t report to him &#8212; no one is going to have trouble understanding why that&#8217;s necessary (and frankly, it may be make his candidacy prohibitive, but that&#8217;s up to the hiring manager to decide).</p>
<p><strong>2. Health risks with using a shared office phone</strong></p>
<p><em>Are there any known health issues with being forced to use a workplace phone that 6-8 different people use daily for work and personal calls?</em></p>
<p><em>I need to use the phone to do my work. But my employer has cut back on allowing desk to have a phone. I&#8217;m concerned about whether there are health issues with this practice. Could I contract a communicable disease this way? I do recall many years ago when I worked in the telecom industry that a former boss said something to me one day that day about how germs live in the mouthpiece of the phone and she believed that was a health concern of no minor consequence. I am very concerned about this as I work with a group of people with varying degrees of cleanliness!</em></p>
<p>I have no idea, although I&#8217;m sure you could Google it and find out &#8212; but keep in mind that you come in contact with all kinds of germy things every day, like money, shopping carts, public bathrooms, and more. But since you&#8217;re stuck in this situation and it&#8217;s making you uneasy, why not carry disinfecting wipes and wipe down the phone before using it each time?</p>
<p><strong>3. &#8220;Reliable transportation&#8221; when you don&#8217;t own a car</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m applying to a job that requires &#8220;reliable transportation&#8221; and occasional travel. I don&#8217;t own or want to own a car. If I got the job, however, I could theoretically rent a ZipCar when necessary. That&#8217;s could get expensive quickly, though! Is it too tacky to ask about potential rental reimbursements in the interview/negotiations process, since they&#8217;re looking for someone with &#8220;reliable transportation&#8221; in the first place? Is this something that can potentially be bargained over if they really like me, or does it fall more into the range of &#8220;why the heck did you even apply to this job?&#8221;</em></p>
<p>They&#8217;re telling you up-front that it requires reliable transportation, and you&#8217;re saying that you&#8217;d want them to pay for you to be obtain the transportation that they require you to already have. You could certainly go ahead and try it, but I think they&#8217;re likely to be irked unless you&#8217;re a really, really phenomenal candidate who they just can&#8217;t allow themselves to pass up. And even then, asking for reimbursement (beyond mileage for travel, which you&#8217;d normally get anyway) is pretty over the top in this context.</p>
<p><strong>4. Remaining eligible for re-hire after an unreasonable manager blew up at me</strong></p>
<p><em>This winter, I picked up a part-time seasonal job in addition to my full-time day job. When I was hired, my manager and I agreed to a very specific schedule. However, one of the shifts we had originally agreed to was no longer needed and he wanted me to work a different shift instead. Even thought this new shift was very inconvenient, I agreed to do it, confirming a very specific schedule via email (including dates and times for every single shift I would work for the rest of the season).</em></p>
<p><em>However, these shifts kept getting longer and he also scheduled me for additional days I was unable to work. When I talked to him about this, telling him I am only available for the dates and times that we agreed to via email, he blew a gasket. He was angry and used unprofessional language. He also said that if I didn&#8217;t work those shifts, he would make me ineligible for rehire. He was so mad he demanded that I leave. Later, he called me to tell me he was taking me off the schedule for the rest of the reason.</em></p>
<p><em>While I have no desire to ever work for this manager again, the company is a large one and I would like to be eligible to apply for jobs in different departments. They have no performance-based reason to make me ineligible for rehire. How would you recommend I approach this situation?</em></p>
<p>Contact the company&#8217;s HR department, explain what happened (professionally and without malice), and ask how you can ensure that you&#8217;re eligible for re-hire in the future.</p>
<p><strong>5. Are creative job titles silly?</strong></p>
<p><em>I recently read some articles about employees creating their own job title and encouraging people to start doing that for themselves. For example, instead of &#8220;customer service representative,&#8221; one could call themselves &#8220;colonel of service.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>Personally, I can see doing this on your LinkedIn profile under your headline (I&#8217;ve done that for myself), but I&#8217;m not sure how I feel about changing my resume. What do you think? Is this innovative or silly?</em></p>
<p>Silly. Your title is supposed to quickly convey to other people what you do, with as much clarity as possible. Resist the temptation.</p>
<p><strong>6. Telling future employers about a raise I would have received if I&#8217;d stayed in my old job</strong></p>
<p><em>I recently decided to leave my current employment to move with my fiance to her graduate program. I helped hire my replacement, and in the process I learned that he will be paid considerably more than me and receive a job title more appropriate to the position. This was inconsiderate of my boss, since I have asked for these things in the past but been denied, partly because my boss and HR both knew that I would be moving on eventually. While I understand why they wouldn&#8217;t feel it&#8217;s a good allocation of funds at this point, I&#8217;m worried that it will hurt me in salary negotiations. I work in IT and am paid well at the bottom end of the pay scale (below the bottom end, in fact). My job was not initially IT, but my employer decided they needed me there instead of in my original position but kept my job description and salary the same.</em></p>
<p><em>My boss told me that even though I wouldn&#8217;t receive a raise to match my successor&#8217;s salary, I should say that I would have been eligible for that raise this summer had I stayed, and that he would mention it in my reference. Will that help? Will future employers care what I would have been paid, or is it all about my actual ending salary?</em></p>
<p>You can say it, but generally it&#8217;s not going to have a huge impact; when you&#8217;re dealing with companies that care about salary history, it&#8217;s more about your actual ending salary. However, you&#8217;re better off sharing <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2009/11/how-to-handle-requests-for-salary.html">not your salary history</a> anyway, when you can avoid it. If you can&#8217;t, consider building a case for why you deserve more money anyway (like I talk about <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2011/05/pay-increases-when-changing-jobs-or-how-i-doubled-my-salary-in-one-career-move.html  ">here</a>).</p>
<p><strong>7. Will recruiters tell my employer I&#8217;m looking?</strong></p>
<p><em>I work in a mid-sized city and I am thinking of leaving my job. Due to LinkedIn, I can see that in some cases, recruiters at the major employers I am looking at have worked at my company in the past or have worked with current employees of my company. Therefore, they have connections with recruiters and management of my company. As a result, I am hesitant to submit my resume to these companies or contact the recruiter for more information without risking my manager finding out. What do you think? Is there an un-said rule not to contact the current employer?</em></p>
<p>Generally, yes, and recruiters have incentive to follow that rule because they want to place candidates and they want other candidates to be willing to work with them in the future. They don&#8217;t want to get a reputation for screwing people over like that. That doesn&#8217;t mean there&#8217;s zero risk, but it&#8217;s fairly low.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/fast-answer-friday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-27.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>123</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>can you ask to meet future coworkers before accepting a new job?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/can-you-ask-to-meet-coworkers-before-accepting-a-new-job.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/can-you-ask-to-meet-coworkers-before-accepting-a-new-job.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 18:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advice about your coworkers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interviewing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5708</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: Is it appropriate to ask to get to know future coworkers before accepting a new job? I have a second interview coming up shortly with the president of the company. During my initial interview, the panel of nine interviewers w­­ere all very nice and welcoming, except for one person … the person [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>Is it appropriate to ask to get to know future coworkers before accepting a new job?</em></p>
<p><em>I have a second interview coming up shortly with the president of the company. During my initial interview, the panel of nine interviewers w­­ere all very nice and welcoming, except for one person … the person who I would be directly working with. She never once smiled and even gave an answer to one of my questions that I interpreted as a &#8220;back-door&#8221; comment in regards to my lack of experience (I am younger than this person with a higher degree).</em></p>
<p><em>I currently work part-time for a similar company where my coworkers and I work wonderfully together. Although the financial gain of being employed full-time would be highly beneficial, I am scared to leave a great and collaborative working environment for a possibly hostile one. If I am offered the position, is it out of line to ask if I could have lunch/coffee with my future coworkers in the department before accepting the position to see if my initial impression was correct? I understand that people rarely get to pick their coworkers, but the monetary gain of working full-time is not worth me giving up my current collaborate working environment for a hostile one.</em></p>
<p>It&#8217;s actually surprising to me how uncommon of a request this is. Considering how much of an impact your coworkers will have on your quality of life, you&#8217;d think more people would want to do this.</p>
<p>That said, it <em>is</em> a fairly unusual request, particularly outside of senior level positions. That doesn&#8217;t mean you can&#8217;t ask it, though &#8212; you can. But because it&#8217;s unusual, you want to pay attention to how you word it. I&#8217;d say something like, &#8220;I&#8217;m really excited about this position. Before I formally accept, would it be possible to talk with others in the department to get a sense of how everyone works together? I&#8217;d love to have coffee with the people I&#8217;d be working closest with, or even just come in to talk with them, if possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>I wouldn&#8217;t necessarily ask for lunch &#8212; that&#8217;s more of an imposition than some people would be happy about. (My own personal biases are creeping in here, but I&#8217;m not the only one who has them.)</p>
<p>Keep in mind, though, that even the most collegial lunch in the world won&#8217;t offer any guarantees against bad coworkers. You could love them, and then they could all leave over the next year and be replaced by horrible, incompetent people. Or they could be lovely to everyone in the beginning and horrid after that. There&#8217;s no way to guard against that &#8212; other than by making sure that you&#8217;re ending up somewhere that manages well, hires well, and fires when they need to. (Which maybe gives us the answer to why more people don&#8217;t ask to meet the coworkers &#8212; ultimately what matters is the quality of management.)</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also worth noting that a coworker who didn&#8217;t smile in your interview isn&#8217;t necessarily going to be a bad coworker. Some people are more serious than others, but are still great coworkers (defined not by warmness but by doing their jobs well, being helpful when needed, and otherwise staying out of your way). Yes, if she made a comment about your lack of experience, she might be indicating some skepticism about you, but that&#8217;s also the kind of thing that makes sense to bring up in an interview &#8212; you&#8217;re there to talk about fit and experience, after all.</p>
<p>Anyway, I do think it&#8217;s okay to ask for the meeting if it&#8217;s important to you &#8230; but keep in mind all the caveats above.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/can-you-ask-to-meet-coworkers-before-accepting-a-new-job.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>74</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>can you have blue hair at a job interview?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/can-you-have-blue-hair-at-a-job-interview.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/can-you-have-blue-hair-at-a-job-interview.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 16:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[job searching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5706</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I&#8217;m in the middle of applying for a job at a very large company, where I would do a fair amount of client-facing work. It&#8217;s a big deal for me. I&#8217;ve been a huge fan of this company for years. I haven&#8217;t even submitted my application yet, so I don&#8217;t know that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m in the middle of applying for a job at a very large company, where I would do a fair amount of client-facing work. It&#8217;s a big deal for me. I&#8217;ve been a huge fan of this company for years.</em></p>
<p><em>I haven&#8217;t even submitted my application yet, so I don&#8217;t know that I&#8217;ll get an interview, but I do feel that I&#8217;m a strong candidate. I also know that if they do like me, it will be a pretty quick hiring process right now. They&#8217;re hiring a bunch of people for this position, the next starting date is May, and they&#8217;re making it clear on the site that if you&#8217;re applying right now, you should expect to start in May if you&#8217;re successful.</em></p>
<p><em>At the same time&#8230; I&#8217;m getting married very soon. Next week, in fact. And I&#8217;ve been planning for my &#8220;something blue&#8221; to be my hair. (Right now it&#8217;s pink, and my current job doesn&#8217;t mind at all, even when I go to conferences &#8212; hooray for tech startups.) I would be happy to dye it to a natural color after the blue, but doing that and actually having it look natural would probably require a couple weeks of fade time. So I would almost certainly be going to interviews with blue hair.</em></p>
<p><em>As I said, it&#8217;s not certain I&#8217;ll even get an interview, but I will probably have a similar problem the next time I look for a job too (it&#8217;s actually been joked about at my current work that they&#8217;ll know I&#8217;m looking elsewhere if my hair turns brown). Should I mention it in the interview, like &#8220;My current workplace is very casual/it went blue for an event, and I&#8217;d be happy to dye it to something &#8216;normal&#8217; if I&#8217;m offered this job&#8221;? For the job I&#8217;m applying for now, a lot of the other applicants will be straight out of college (or still in it), so I expect they see some stuff like this, but &#8230; I don&#8217;t want to rely on that.</em></p>
<p><em>I also don&#8217;t want to dye it natural colors for my wedding just on the off-chance, and I don&#8217;t want to spook my current workplace. I&#8217;m not irreplaceable there, but my leaving would definitely be a big blow, so I really don&#8217;t want them to know I&#8217;m even looking.</em></p>
<p>Blue hair is going to be a deal-breaker in a lot of industries, and not an issue in others. So you really, really need to know your own industry on this. In the design or fashion world, for instance, it might be totally fine. In banking, no.</p>
<p>And you might be surprised by where it&#8217;s not okay. I spent many years working in advocacy nonprofits, and candidates often assumed that because we worked on &#8220;cool&#8221; issues, we&#8217;d be okay with non-mainstream appearances (blue hair, mohawks, facial piercings, long hair on men.). But we categorically were not &#8212; those things were banned on our staff, because we wanted the public&#8217;s focus (and reporters&#8217; and legislators&#8217; focus) to be on our message, not on the messenger. And even though you might think that it would only matter for positions that dealt with the public, it mattered for everyone. We didn&#8217;t want a reporter to be in our office one day, see a blue-haired I.T. person walk by, and include that detail in their story, because it played into perceptions that our issue was outside the mainstream, while we were working to mainstream the issue with grandparents, clergy, and conservative legislators.</p>
<p>On the other hand, there are businesses that you might expect to be more conservative about appearance that are actually more relaxed about it &#8230; but you can&#8217;t always tell from the outside. (And simply having a lot of recently graduated applicants doesn&#8217;t mean anything either way.)</p>
<p>So you really, really need to know your industry, and what&#8217;s generally accepted. And if your industry doesn&#8217;t embrace non-mainstream looks, and you want a particular job in it, then yeah, you probably need to adjust your hair to accommodate that.</p>
<p>You certainly shouldn&#8217;t alter your plans for your hair for your wedding though. But if you&#8217;re interviewing for a job before it&#8217;s had a chance to return to a natural color, and you&#8217;re not in a field known to be friendly to non-mainstream looks (again, fashion and design are the best known for this; some parts of tech too, but few others), then I&#8217;d address it up-front. Because otherwise you risk getting rejected when you otherwise wouldn&#8217;t.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/can-you-have-blue-hair-at-a-job-interview.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>212</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>after I resigned, my boss asked me to drive 1,000 miles at my own expense</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/after-i-resigned-my-boss-asked-me-to-drive-1000-miles-at-my-own-expense.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/after-i-resigned-my-boss-asked-me-to-drive-1000-miles-at-my-own-expense.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 14:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[resigning]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5704</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I put my notice in a few weeks ago. We have a slow season come May. Knowing my boss&#8217; history of being overdramatic, I offered to work until May to give her some extra time to find a replacement, as she has to attend a few conferences taking her away from the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I put my notice in a few weeks ago. We have a slow season come May. Knowing my boss&#8217; history of being overdramatic, I offered to work until May to give her some extra time to find a replacement, as she has to attend a few conferences taking her away from the office.</em></p>
<p><em>I was trying my best to be gracious with my exit and was willing to train my replacement. We are a small company (3 employees <em>total, </em>including my boss, who is the owner). However, I run all aspects of her business for her, so she wouldn&#8217;t know how to train my replacement.</em></p>
<p><em>I work in a remote office in Georgia, and she is in Michigan. Now she&#8217;s saying I have to drive all the company property to her office and spend a week in that city training my replacement all at my own expense.</em></p>
<p><em>I am financially unable to do that and think that is completely unreasonable. I already packed everything up and offered to ship it via our company FedEx account. I of course planned to return everything, but not on my own dime. We even have an office in Georgia that she won&#8217;t let me return the property to.</em></p>
<p><em>I now want to cut my time here and just walk away now. It&#8217;s been three weeks since I&#8217;ve given notice. I refuse to go to the headquarters at my own expense to train my replacement. Is that acceptable?</em></p>
<p>What?!  She&#8217;s being ridiculous.</p>
<p>Out of curiosity, is she the type who tried to get you to do things on your own dime previously, or is this twist just a petulant reaction to you leaving?</p>
<p>In any case, she can <em>ask</em> for whatever she wants, and you can decline to give it. Certainly it&#8217;s not normal to expect someone to do what she&#8217;s asking, so you should have no qualms about saying no.</p>
<p>However, I would not walk away now. You gave notice for May, which means she&#8217;s planning to have another month-plus for your transition, and if you cut that short without warning, you&#8217;ll be stooping to &#8212; well, not to her level, but you&#8217;ll be ceding some high ground.</p>
<p>Instead, say something like this, &#8220;I&#8217;m not able to come to Michigan in my final weeks, nor am I able to personally pay for any transition expenses. I&#8217;d be glad to ship things via our FedEx account or return things to the Georgia office. Please let me know what you&#8217;d prefer.&#8221;</p>
<p>If she becomes hostile or continues to be irrational, then say this: &#8220;Jane, asking an employee to spend their own money on work expenses like these is extremely unusual, and I want to be very clear that it&#8217;s off the table. But more importantly, I gave you a good deal of extra notice because I value our relationship and wanted to make things as easy as possible on you. But you&#8217;re pushing me to do something that I&#8217;ve already made it clear I&#8217;m not willing to do, and something that isn&#8217;t reasonable to expect of me. I&#8217;d like to stay here through May and help you transition. But if it&#8217;s going to be contentious, it will be better for both of us if I were to leave sooner.&#8221;</p>
<p>If she calms down, great. If she doesn&#8217;t, then you say, &#8220;Given this situation, it would be better for both of us if I give a standard two weeks, instead of a longer notice period, so my last day will be ___ (two weeks from now). Please let me know where you&#8217;d like me to send these items.&#8221;</p>
<p>If she doesn&#8217;t tell you where to send them, then you make that call yourself and send them to one of the two offices.</p>
<p>But you should give two weeks if you&#8217;re going to leave earlier than your original exit date &#8212; because otherwise you undo a large chunk of the usefulness of early notice periods (which are about transitioning work) &#8230; and allow her to tell future reference checkers that you essentially walked off the job.</p>
<p>The only exception to this is if she becomes outright abusive, at which point you could say, &#8220;I’d like to work the remaining two weeks and I don’t want to leave you in the lurch. However, I need to be treated professionally during that time. I had planned to use the next two weeks to put my projects in order, write up documentation to leave behind, and so forth, but I do have a bottom line as far as respectful treatment. If we can’t work together without the hostility, then I will need to leave now.&#8221;</p>
<p>Good luck, and congratulations on moving away from this.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/after-i-resigned-my-boss-asked-me-to-drive-1000-miles-at-my-own-expense.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>105</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>terse answer Thursday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/terse-answer-thursday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-27.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/terse-answer-thursday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-27.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 04:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5702</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s terse answer Thursday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. How soon is too soon to reject a candidate? I have a question about hiring timelines. Sometimes we screen a candidate, and know pretty much immediately that the person won&#8217;t be a good fit. But I feel like it [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s terse answer Thursday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. How soon is too soon to reject a candidate?</strong></p>
<p><em>I have a question about hiring timelines. Sometimes we screen a candidate, and know pretty much immediately that the person won&#8217;t be a good fit. But I feel like it might be discouraging to be on the other end of such a situation (to interview and be declined the same day). Right now, I&#8217;ve been waiting a day or two before passing on a candidate in these cases. Does this seem like an acceptable timeline, or should I be sucking it up and letting a candidate know right away that they haven&#8217;t made the cut?</em></p>
<p>I usually wait a week, because I agree &#8212; many people find it insulting to be rejected so quickly after an interview. The reality is that very few candidates require days of consideration before you decide they&#8217;re a no &#8212; the people who make it to the end-stages often do, but early on in the process, you often know as soon as the phone interview is completed (or during it) that you won&#8217;t be moving the person forward. I&#8217;d love to be fully transparent and tell them that immediately, but too many people feel slighted or argue the decision or just feel dejected (like &#8220;I&#8217;m so awful that they didn&#8217;t even have to think about it&#8221;). So I wait a week, which seems like a perfectly reasonable amount of time.</p>
<p>(And I know that some people will object to hearing that and think I should tell them faster, but a week is not an unreasonable amount of time to hear back &#8212; and plenty faster than many places.)</p>
<p><strong>2. CEO gave my personal cell phone number to clients without my permission</strong></p>
<p><em>I’m a production coordination trainee at a small company. I’ve been working for them for a little over 1 year, and although I’m still a trainee under the contract, I have business card and email signature with &#8220;Project Manager&#8221; as the job title which I’m forced to use. Besides that, I also do sales related jobs such as communicating with some clients, submitting quotes/invoices and getting new jobs because actual account executive for those clients is also the company CEO and he can’t do everything.</em></p>
<p><em>The CEO gave my personal cell phone number to clients without my permission. He told me afterwards and said I should be prepared to receive calls anytime. His email to the client listed my cellphone number and noted that they should contact me directly on my cell especially after 5 pm (our office operates 8-5). I have direct number at my desk during the day, and I’m not allowed to work overtime without prior permission from my supervisors. Is it ok for a company / boss to provide an employee’s personal phone number without her permission? I have a feeling this is not illegal and only an ethical issue, but I’m wondering if there is anything I can do about it. Clients indeed call me on my cell and it is becoming a part of stress I feel from the job.</em></p>
<p>No, that&#8217;s not cool. Legal, but not cool. But if the CEO isn&#8217;t willing to budge, then the message here is that this is a job that requires you to be on call. You&#8217;ll have to decide if you want that job or not.</p>
<p>However, if you&#8217;re non-exempt (and it sounds like you are), you need to be paid for any time spent answering these calls. Start tracking your time, and since you&#8217;re supposed to get advance permission for overtime, ask the CEO how he wants to handle this since you can&#8217;t predict in advance when calls will come in.</p>
<p><strong>3. Forgot to bring copies of my resume to an interview</strong></p>
<p><em>I just had a second round interview today for a position I&#8217;m really interested in. I prepared all night for the interview, and in my rush to get out the door the morning of the interview, I forgot copies of my resume! When the interviewers asked if I had a copy, I said no but I could speak to it and then just proceeded to discuss my experience. Totally my fault, but is this a deal breaker? In my thank you email I sent immediately after, I attached my resume and said please reach out with questions. I&#8217;m so upset I may have lost this opportunity due to this silly mistake!</em></p>
<p>This irks the hell out of me &#8212; at them, not at you. It&#8217;s ridiculous that they came into an interview without copies of your resume, and that they didn&#8217;t offer to find your resume in their system when it became clear you didn&#8217;t have them either. Yes, bringing your resume is a nice thing to do, but it&#8217;s not your responsibility &#8212; it&#8217;s theirs to have it, and they should have reviewed it before the interview anyway. The only way this is okay is if they were pulled into the meeting at the last minute and given no time to prepare.</p>
<p>It shouldn&#8217;t be a deal-breaker, especially since you immediately emailed it to them afterwards.</p>
<p><strong>4. Hiring contact has left the company</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m a retail sales and merchandising professional who wanted to respond to a job posting on a website for a position with a design company. The job description lists an email address/specific contact to send a cover letter and resume to, which I promptly did. Being my investigative self, I looked up the contact on LinkedIn. Her LinkedIn profile states that she ended her tenure with this company in 2013 and lists her occupation as &#8220;Seeking Next Opportunity.&#8221; I would really like to work with this company, but does this mean my application just got sent to oblivion if she no longer works there? Should I contact her via LinkedIn to inquire whether or not I should try to contact someone else about the position?</em></p>
<p>It&#8217;s possibly that someone else is handling her email now that she&#8217;s gone, but you can certainly call the company&#8217;s main number and ask who is now handling the hiring for that position. I would not contact the former employee; she no longer works there and no doubt doesn&#8217;t want to field questions about their hiring process.</p>
<p><strong>5. Where&#8217;s my raise?</strong></p>
<p><em>I started a new job back in December. When negotiating salary, I was told (via email, so I still have it) that it is company policy to provide a small raise along with obtaining licensure. My licensure paperwork came through the end of January, and I have been waiting for something to happen &#8212; but nothing has. The HR manager told me that the paperwork I sent her was what she needed to make the raise happen, but now 4 pay periods have passed with no changes. I contacted payroll to ask how long those changes usually take, and she told me that she has heard nothing about it and that she would be able to make that change instantly. I&#8217;ve emailed and called HR, but she is not responding to me (it has been almost 2 weeks since my last email). Should I try to track her down in person? She is at a different location than me, which is why I haven&#8217;t done it yet, and I am so nervous about coming off as a crazy person. Then again, perhaps I am expecting this to move too fast.</em></p>
<p>Talk to your manager, not HR. Your manager can advocate to push this through more forcefully than you can.</p>
<p><strong>6. Using &#8220;sic&#8221; on a resume</strong></p>
<p><em>I had a friend look over my resume and he was confused with my use of the phrase/grammar shorthand &#8220;sic.&#8221; Two of the companies I have worked for used lowercase letters in their names as a stylistic choice, and my resume reads like this:</em></p>
<p><em>tiny teapots (sic); Anytown, USA; Chocolate Design Engineer</em><br />
<em> Teapots R Us; Anyville, USA; Chocolate Engineer</em></p>
<p><em>I had to look up how to credit a lowercase company, but I want it to be clear that I am not submitting a resume riddled with typos. Is (sic) a dated or confusing term? Is it acceptable in some fields but not others (for instance, academics might recognize it, but it stumped my architect friend)?</em></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been surprised on a few occasions by people who didn&#8217;t know what it meant, so your better bet might be to simply go ahead and capitalize the name. You wouldn&#8217;t do that in an official publication like a newspaper article, but it&#8217;s not a terrible crime to do it on your resume. (Unless you&#8217;re applying for a copyediting job, and then maybe it would be. Fortunately you design chocolate teapots instead.)</p>
<p><strong>7. Applying for a job when I want more than the posted salary</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m interested in applying for a position but the top of the salary range is still $3,500 under what I would like. Should I still apply for the job? Is there any hope of maybe getting them to offer more outside of their top range? (If it helps, the highest salary offered is only $2,500 more than the lowest salary they offer.)</em></p>
<p>Sure, you can try negotiating for more. There&#8217;s no guarantee that you&#8217;ll get it, but it&#8217;s not crazy to try. It would be if what you wanted was significantly above their posted range, but $3,500 isn&#8217;t that much.</p>
<p>But speaking of that, $3,500 a year breaks down to about $218/month after taxes. It&#8217;s not going to make a huge difference in your paycheck.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/terse-answer-thursday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-27.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>165</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>new assistant already missed work her third day on the job</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/new-assistant-already-missed-work-her-third-day-on-the-job.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/new-assistant-already-missed-work-her-third-day-on-the-job.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 17:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[good management]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5700</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I have just hired a part-time administrative assistant that started on Monday. She works for us in the morning and cares for her mother in the afternoon. This morning, I recevied an email from her stating she was unable to come in today because of something she needed to help her mother [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I have just hired a part-time administrative assistant that started on Monday. She works for us in the morning and cares for her mother in the afternoon. This morning, I recevied an email from her stating she was unable to come in today because of something she needed to help her mother with. While I sympathize as I&#8217;m sure caring for an ailing mother is not an easy undertaking, I&#8217;m not at all excited about her calling in after only two days on the job.</em></p>
<p><em>Should I address this with her tomorrow morning when she arrives or wait to see if this is an isolated incident? Also, any suggestions on how I talk to her about this? I need to communicate to her that I need reliable people on my team and right now, I&#8217;m uncertain she is a reliable team member.</em></p>
<p>You should probably talk with her.</p>
<p>While it&#8217;s certainly true that emergencies can come up during your first week on the job, most people are mortified when they do &#8212; because they know that they&#8217;re still proving themselves, that it&#8217;s not a great idea to miss work during your first week, and that an employer is likely to have exactly the worries that you&#8217;re having. So most people in this situation will stress that they&#8217;re mortified, that this is out of character, etc. &#8212; they won&#8217;t sound cavalier or matter-of-fact about it.</p>
<p>The fact that your employee didn&#8217;t handle it that way &#8212; it sounds like her email was pretty matter of fact &#8212; is much more troubling than the fact that she had to take the morning off. After all, you&#8217;d probably be having a much different reaction if she&#8217;d called you rather than emailed, sounded mortified, and assured you this wouldn&#8217;t be a regular thing, right? (You&#8217;d still probably be a little concerned because that&#8217;s human nature when you don&#8217;t yet have a ton of data points on someone, but you probably wouldn&#8217;t be quite as uneasy as you are now.)</p>
<p>So, while you could certainly wait and see if there are other problems, the way she handled this strongly suggests that there are going to be other problems, and so it&#8217;s worth talking with her when she&#8217;s back tomorrow.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d start by asking her if everything is okay, because that&#8217;s a kind thing to do in this context, and then say something like this: &#8220;I realize that sometimes things come up and it&#8217;s just bad timing, but because we so rarely have people miss work in their first week &#8212; their first month, really &#8212; I want to make sure that the scheduling needs of this role are going to work for you going forward. I want to be up-front with you that I generally need the person in your role to be here every day, unless it&#8217;s pre-planned vacation time or a very rare absence that can&#8217;t be planned, such as sickness. We can&#8217;t easily accommodate more than a few unplanned absences per year. And again, I realize that on occasion something will come up, and sometimes it&#8217;ll have the bad timing to do it during someone&#8217;s first week, but since we&#8217;re just starting to work together, I wanted to raise this and make sure it works for you.&#8221;</p>
<p>Make sure to use a kind and sympathetic tone during this conversation. If she&#8217;s truly a conscientious employee who just had bad luck during her first week, you shouldn&#8217;t come down hard on her, and keeping your tone kind can help with that. And if she&#8217;s not really a conscientious employee, using a kind tone isn&#8217;t going to detract from the substance of the message.</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s the thing: If she&#8217;s <em>not</em> an especially conscientious employee and therefore needs to hear this message, it&#8217;s already over. There are going to be more problems with reliability and more problems with work ethic (and maybe other problems too, like quality of work, because they often &#8212; although not always &#8212; go hand in hand).</p>
<p>So why have this conversation at all then? Why not just wait and see if those other problems appear and address it then (by letting her go and hiring someone better)? You could &#8212; that&#8217;s one option. But by addressing it up-front now, you&#8217;re making your expectations clear and ensuring that you won&#8217;t be starting from scratch the next time there&#8217;s a problem. If she&#8217;s not the right employee for you, then you want to end this as soon as possible before you&#8217;ve invested more time in training, etc., and by having this conversation now, you&#8217;re setting the stage for moving quickly in the next few weeks if you continue to see problems. (Plus, it&#8217;s possible that this conversation could lead to her deciding on her own that it&#8217;s not the right fit.)</p>
<p>And if she <em>is</em> a conscientious employee and this was really a legitimate emergency that isn&#8217;t indicative of a problem with her work ethic or reliability, she&#8217;s going to understand why you&#8217;re raising this. (That said, you still might make a point of being particularly kind and welcoming to her the rest of the week so that she doesn&#8217;t feel misunderstood or like she&#8217;s been chastised and sent to the corner, because a conscientious person will be wondering if she&#8217;s just ruined her standing in your eyes. So show her that she hasn&#8217;t.)</p>
<p>If I had to bet money on the most likely outcome, I&#8217;d say this isn&#8217;t going to end well and you should be preparing yourself for that &#8230; but that&#8217;s not a guarantee and it&#8217;s possible that she&#8217;s a conscientious person with one piece of bad luck. This approach accounts for both, but you&#8217;ll know soon enough which you&#8217;re dealing with. Good luck.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/new-assistant-already-missed-work-her-third-day-on-the-job.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>179</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>why is it bad to sound naive when applying for jobs?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/why-is-it-bad-to-sound-naive-when-applying-for-jobs.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/why-is-it-bad-to-sound-naive-when-applying-for-jobs.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 14:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[new grads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5695</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I’ve seen you throw around the word “naïve” several times in your How-Not-Tos for cover letters and resumes. I actually find it a really helpful insult when I recognize things that I’ve been doing wrong. But still, being 22, I am kind of professionally naïve. Surely there’s got to be something beneficial [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I’ve seen you throw around the word “naïve” several times in your How-Not-Tos for cover letters and resumes. I actually find it a really helpful insult when I recognize things that I’ve been doing wrong. But still, being 22, I am kind of professionally naïve. Surely there’s got to be something beneficial about showing my sincerity and eagerness in a cover letter, but I also don’t want to sound like an intern.</em></p>
<p><em>Here’s the more pragmatic question: In several of my cover letters I’ve directly addressed that although I’m technically qualified, I understand that I’m not going to be the most experienced. And then I say something like, “what I lack in experience I make up for with an eagerness to learn.” Most recently I said, “If ability is driven by energy, I may still be your most qualified candidate.”</em></p>
<p><em>Good? Bad? Should I fake it till I make it? Or should I beg?</em></p>
<p>Well, first, sincere and eager aren&#8217;t the same thing as naive. Sincere and eager are good things. Most employers want them. Naivete, though, is something different; it&#8217;s the <em>lack of knowledge</em>.</p>
<p>Now, of course when you&#8217;re new to the work world, you&#8217;re starting out with a certain amount of lack of knowledge, and there&#8217;s no way around that.</p>
<p>And some forms of naivete aren&#8217;t bad at all, and can even be kind of charming. For instance, I once hired a recent grad who insisted on calling me &#8220;Ms. Green&#8221; for his first few days before I could get him to stop. He was naive about typical forms of address in most offices and the fact that professional adults generally call each other by their first names (with <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/03/office-insists-we-refer-to-higher-ups-as-ms-or-mr.html">some exceptions</a>), but that was fine. He was inexperienced, it did no harm, and it was easy to smile at.</p>
<p>But the kind of naivete that we usually talk about here &#8212; when it&#8217;s in the context of Don&#8217;t Do That &#8212; is different. Those forms of naivete can signal to an employer that you&#8217;re going to require more hand-holding or be higher-maintenance or just be more of a pain than they&#8217;d ideally like to take on.</p>
<p>I figured it would be useful to talk specifics, so I searched for past posts where I warned someone that a behavior would seem problematically naive. Here are a few of them:</p>
<p>* In <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/05/why-would-a-company-freeze-a-hiring-process.html">this case</a>, a reader wanted to call a company that had frozen their hiring and try to personally convince their CFO to restart the hiring for the position he wanted. I told him he&#8217;d come across as naive (and overstepping and presumptuous). Being naive about something like this isn&#8217;t likely to get dismissed with an indulgent smile; it&#8217;s likely to make the company think that you have such a lack of understanding of professional norms that you&#8217;re likely to continually alienate coworkers and clients.</p>
<p>* In <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/05/short-answer-saturday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-7.html">this case</a>, a reader wanted to ask for a raise after only two months on the job because she regretted not negotiating initially. I told her that she would look naive and like she didn&#8217;t understand how business works (and that her employer would be annoyed that she didn’t think through the salary before accepting it). Being naive about something like this is a problem because the person&#8217;s lack of understanding of business conventions is directly causing a problem for the company: Now they have someone asking for something totally unrealistic, thinking it&#8217;s realistic to get it, and probably being dissatisfied when they can&#8217;t. As a manager, not only is that a pain in the ass to deal with, but it also makes you wonder what other unreasonable expectations the person has that you&#8217;re going to need to fend off too.</p>
<p>* In the <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-mother-says-i-should-call-employers-daily-for-an-interview.html">recent letter</a> from someone whose mother was telling her to call employers daily to ask for an interview, I said that doing that would come across as naive at best and and rude at worst. In this case, &#8220;naive&#8221; wasn&#8217;t horribly damning (although &#8220;rude&#8221; was), but the point was that she wasn&#8217;t going to portray herself in a way that would be helpful. You don&#8217;t want to take an action where the best that could be said of you is that you seem naive. When you&#8217;re trying to convince an employer to hire you, you want to seem attractive to them. Standing out by displaying a total lack of understanding of how hiring works isn&#8217;t going to be appealing. It&#8217;s going to be a negative, not a plus.</p>
<p>Now, as for your question about language in your cover letter, there&#8217;s nothing wrong with &#8220;what I lack in experience I make up for with an eagerness to learn.&#8221; You&#8217;re going to need to back it up with more compelling specifics, but there&#8217;s nothing problematic about that statement. And it&#8217;s not naive &#8212; it&#8217;s eager, but like I said above, those are two different things, and eagerness is good.</p>
<p>And your second sentence &#8212; &#8220;If ability is driven by energy, I may still be your most qualified candidate&#8221; &#8212; isn&#8217;t too bad either. I don&#8217;t love it, because I dislike anything where an applicant claims that they&#8217;re the most qualified candidate for the job (since <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2011/11/stop-telling-me-youre-the-best-candidate-for-the-job.html">they can&#8217;t possibly know</a>), but it&#8217;s a reasonably engaging way of saying something about your energy and enthusiasm.</p>
<p>Neither of those really sounds naive; they sound eager, and that&#8217;s a good thing. They&#8217;re very different from the examples of problematic naivete above.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/why-is-it-bad-to-sound-naive-when-applying-for-jobs.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>red flags on your resume are turning employers off</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/red-flags-on-your-resume-are-turning-employers-off.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/red-flags-on-your-resume-are-turning-employers-off.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 13:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[resumes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5698</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As you&#8217;re probably well aware, most employers spend only seconds skimming your resume before making a quick decision about whether to reject you or consider you further, so it&#8217;s essential that your resume doesn&#8217;t contain the red flags that will turn them off during that short initial scan. Over at U.S. News &#38; World Report today, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/03/27/8-red-flags-employers-see-on-your-resume"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2095" alt="featured-on-usn" src="http://www.askamanager.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/featured-on-usn1.jpg" width="90" height="60" /></a>As you&#8217;re probably well aware, most employers spend only seconds skimming your resume before making a quick decision about whether to reject you or consider you further, so it&#8217;s essential that your resume doesn&#8217;t contain the red flags that will turn them off during that short initial scan.</p>
<p>Over at U.S. News &amp; World Report today, I talk about eight red flags that will often put you straight into the &#8220;no&#8221; pile without further consideration, including overly aggrandized self-descriptions, no overarching theme to your career choices, bad writing, and more. You can <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/03/27/8-red-flags-employers-see-on-your-resume">read it here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/red-flags-on-your-resume-are-turning-employers-off.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>87</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Caught between invoices? CBAC can help</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/caught-between-invoices-cbac-can-help.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/caught-between-invoices-cbac-can-help.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 13:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[sponsors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5696</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[And now a break to talk about a sponsor… I want to tell you about CBAC, because I recently talked to their founder and was pretty intrigued. CBAC is an invoice financing exchange that provides working capital to small and medium businesses. Here&#8217;s how it works: You&#8217;re a business that needs immediate cash. You have [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><em>And now a break to talk about a sponsor…</em></p>
<p>I want to tell you about CBAC, because I recently talked to their founder and was pretty intrigued.</p>
<p><a href="https://cbacfunding.com">CBAC</a> is an invoice financing exchange that provides working capital to small and medium businesses. Here&#8217;s how it works:</p>
<p>You&#8217;re a business that needs immediate cash. You have invoices out for services or goods that you&#8217;ve provided, but it can take two months or more &#8212; sometimes much more &#8212; to get those invoices paid and receive the cash. Meanwhile, you want to pay employees, pay your own bills, or expand &#8212; but you&#8217;re sitting around waiting for your clients to pay you. Rather than having to wait month after month, CBAC lets you cash in on the cheap cost of money in today&#8217;s market. They&#8217;ll take your outstanding invoices and provide you with the up-front cash you&#8217;re owed.</p>
<p>Businesses just complete a short application and then can upload their unpaid invoices. CBAC&#8217;s financing partners will then compete against each other to provide the business with the best pricing for their accounts receivables &#8212; so if CBAC themselves can&#8217;t provide you with the money you need at the rate you want, they&#8217;ll find a company that can. Businesses have the chance to review bids before accepting any, and can negotiate terms directly with the invoice buyer, creating immediate working capital.</p>
<p>This system &#8212; called invoice factoring &#8212; is a way for small and medium companies to stay in business or expand without being thwarted while you wait for clients to pay their bills.</p>
<p>If you own or operate a small or medium business, check out whether CBAC might be right for you. A good place to start with is the <a href="https://cbacfunding.com/tools/calculator">invoice factoring calculator</a>, which will help you figure out both the cost of factoring and the growth you can achieve utilizing a factoring line of credit.</p>
<p><em>Disclosure: This post was sponsored by CBAC. All thoughts and opinions are my own.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/caught-between-invoices-cbac-can-help.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>wee answer Wednesday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/wee-answer-wednesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-29.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/wee-answer-wednesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-29.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 04:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5693</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s wee answer Wednesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Do I have to provide my employer with a copy of the reference I gave a former coworker? My ex-coworker is in the process of looking for a new job, and she put my name as a reference without [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s wee answer Wednesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Do I have to provide my employer with a copy of the reference I gave a former coworker?</strong></p>
<p><em>My ex-coworker is in the process of looking for a new job, and she put my name as a reference without asking me. However, unaware that she told the hiring company that I was her supervisor, which I am not, I decided to help her and provide a reference. The company sent me a form in an email to fill out, which I did and emailed it back to them. I did not lie; I stated that I was her coworker, which was an option on the form.</em></p>
<p><em>The hiring company then called my company and spoke with her supervisor. My supervisor is now questioning me and asking me for a copy of the reference that I gave to the ex-coworker. Am I obligated to provide the reference I give for my ex-coworker to my supervisor? I don&#8217;t have an issue sharing the reference with my manager, but because I think it was a personal reference, I feel I am not obligated to share this information.</em></p>
<p>It wasn&#8217;t a personal reference, even if you look at it that way; it was a professional reference because you were a coworker, or at least I can pretty much guarantee you that the reference-checker sees it that way.</p>
<p>Your employer is entitled to want to see a copy of what you provided, since as long as you&#8217;re employed by your company, you&#8217;re representing them to some extent when you give references for their former employees. But even if that weren&#8217;t the case, taking a stand on this is unlikely to go well for you. At best, it will negatively impact your standing with your manager long-term, and at worst it could be insubordination. Do you really want to take on that battle for a former coworker who tried to get you to lie on her behalf?</p>
<p><strong>2. Cutting hours for chronically absent employees</strong></p>
<p><em>I have a manager who wants to make it a policy that if an employee is chronically absent, their hours will be reduced. Is this legal? Wouldn’t you have to give them warnings first?</em></p>
<p>There&#8217;s no law in the U.S. that requires that employees be warned about disciplinary action before it occurs &#8212; whether it&#8217;s cutting their hours or firing them. As long as the manager is talking about non-exempt employees (rather than exempt employees, who must be paid the same amount each week in which they do any work, regardless of how many hours they work), there&#8217;s no legal issue here. And it&#8217;s understandable that she might want to schedule them less often, if they&#8217;re not reliably at work.</p>
<p><strong>3. Withdrew from a hiring process but now I want to get back in</strong></p>
<p><em>I had an interview and was told I would hear from them by week&#8217;s end or beginning of the new week. I had a change of heart (or so I thought) over the weekend and considered staying with what I have been doing. I emailed the interviewer and told him this. He emailed me back and was very nice and wished me luck and thanked me for letting him know.</em></p>
<p><em>Now, I have had another change of heart and regret my emailing him. Is it acceptable to call him or email him to let him know I would still like to be considered?</em></p>
<p>No. You&#8217;ll look really flaky, and they won&#8217;t be able to trust that you won&#8217;t change your mind again. You really want to be sure before you withdraw from a hiring process, because it&#8217;s hard to reverse.</p>
<p><strong>4. Listing multiple temp assignments on a resume</strong></p>
<p><em>Since I was laid off back in 2009, I’ve worked many temp assignments. Now I’m having a hard time finding permanent work because it looks like I’ve bounced around a lot. How can I make my resume look more appealing so I can finally land a permanent position?</em></p>
<p>Rather than listing them all as separate jobs, list them all under one heading &#8212; Contract Work, Temp Work, or whatever is appropriate.</p>
<p><strong>5. Changing fields when my resume doesn&#8217;t show my qualifications</strong></p>
<p><em>I am looking to change the field I currently work in. I have the education in the field I want to pursue and extensive experience in the field I currently work in. I currently work as a paramedic and I want to move into health/preventive education and wellness programs. I have an MPH in this field. The problem is my resume doesn’t speak for my true qualifications for the new career move. I obviously don’t want to falsify my resume, but how do I make changes that won’t have a recruiter or HR department just toss it in the trash?</em></p>
<p>Why doesn&#8217;t your resume speak to your true qualifications? That&#8217;s the problem. It needs to.</p>
<p>If it can&#8217;t because these qualifications aren&#8217;t anything you can objectively demonstrate, well, you can&#8217;t really expect an hiring manager to pick you over someone who IS demonstrably qualified. You can try to write a really compelling cover letter, but it&#8217;s hard to change fields in this economy because employers don&#8217;t have incentive to pick less qualified candidates when they&#8217;re flooded with qualified ones.</p>
<p>That said, having an MPH and experience working with a paramedic sounds like a pretty good background for moving into health and wellness education. You might find it useful to talk to people in the field you want to move into about how you could play up the qualifications that you do bring.</p>
<p><strong>6. What should you include on a reference list?</strong></p>
<p><em>A library application is asking for my references up front. When I send the names, what else do I include besides name and contact information? I was going to separate them according to type, manager and professional colleague. Do I include job titles? All of the references are managers, but only one is my manager.</em></p>
<p>Names, contact info, job title when you worked together, and a short explanation of your relationship to them (one sentence or less). Unless the employer has specified otherwise, they&#8217;re going to be more interested in people who have managed you than people who haven&#8217;t.</p>
<p><strong>7. Not allowed to keep employee handbook after leaving company</strong></p>
<p><em>My company just rolled out a fancy employee policy book that looks like it cost some money to produce. Of course it has that section that requires you to sign and return a page that confirms you received it, read it, and will comply. But here&#8217;s the kicker. It states that when I leave the job, whether I quit or they fire me, I have to return all company property, &#8220;including this Staff Member Handbook. Otherwise the company may take action to recoup any replacement costs and/or seek the return of company property through appropriate legal recourse.&#8221; It&#8217;s got a lot of pages so photocopying would be kind of a pain.</em></p>
<p><em>In my opinion, I think that anything I sign my name to, I am entitled to a copy of. But my manager doesn&#8217;t see it that way. Is this legal? I&#8217;ve seen employers try to dissuade workers from copying employee personnel reviews as well.</em></p>
<p>Yes, it&#8217;s legal. While you should have a copy of any contract you sign, employee handbooks generally aren&#8217;t considered contracts (and most contain a disclaimer to that effect). Documents where you sign to acknowledge some fact (like the receipt of a handbook) aren&#8217;t obligational or contractual; they&#8217;re more akin to signing a sign-in sheet at a meeting, which you wouldn&#8217;t be entitled to a copy of either. And companies often do consider their handbooks to contain proprietary information about their operations.</p>
<p>But if you think there are particular policies that you might want to reference once you&#8217;re no longer employed there, photocopy those and keep them at home. Otherwise, this is not a battle worth waging.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/wee-answer-wednesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-29.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>my employer might drop our health insurance &#8212; what can I do?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-employer-might-drop-our-health-insurance-what-can-i-do.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-employer-might-drop-our-health-insurance-what-can-i-do.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[workplace practices]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5691</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: Yesterday, I overheard a conversation between the owner of the company and our accountant where they discussed dropping the company&#8217;s health insurance plan. (Note &#8212; we were in an open area, they were being loud and speaking openly, and I said hi when I came into the area to alert them that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>Yesterday, I overheard a conversation between the owner of the company and our accountant where they discussed dropping the company&#8217;s health insurance plan. (Note &#8212; we were in an open area, they were being loud and speaking openly, and I said hi when I came into the area to alert them that I was there, so I wasn&#8217;t snooping!)</em></p>
<p><em>Apparently, rates are being increased again, and they are leaning towards just dropping the plan altogether. If past experience with the way the owner handles things like this is indicative of future behavior, it is likely that she&#8217;ll tell us just a few days before the change, and offer little or no compensation to make up for it. It&#8217;s upsetting on a lot of levels &#8212; when we negotiate raises, the owner is always making a big deal about how our health insurance is part of our compensation and how she&#8217;s such a generous person to offer it to us, so I am going to feel like this is a pay cut if this happens, and of course, like everyone, I have basic healthcare needs and want to make sure I am protected.</em></p>
<p><em>If it does happen, what is the best way to try to negotiate additional money so I can pay for my own insurance? I am searching for another job for other reasons, but as the process may take a while, I am concerned about losing healthcare in the meantime. Another issue is that if she really does not tell us until a few days before, as she has in the past with changes like this, do I have any obligation to warn my coworkers or confront the boss earlier so it&#8217;s in the open? I am generally healthy, but I worry about a few coworkers who have some minor health issues that might bankrupt them if they lose insurance coverage, a few who are parents of young kids, one who is a cancer survivor who needs yearly checks, etc. I am sure many of us would appreciate the chance to get one more physical in or one more prescription filled before we lose coverage.</em></p>
<p>Why not ask directly, since it&#8217;s clear that you were right there when they were discussing it?</p>
<p>Yes, it&#8217;s not polite to eavesdrop or comment on conversations that you weren&#8217;t a part of, but sometimes you can&#8217;t help overhearing things, and sometimes those things are alarming enough that it wouldn&#8217;t make sense to pretend you didn&#8217;t hear. After all, if what you&#8217;d overheard was &#8220;today is Jane&#8217;s last day,&#8221; and you were Jane, you&#8217;d probably ask about that, right? (Actually, some people wouldn&#8217;t even ask about that, but they should.)</p>
<p>Say something like this to her: &#8220;When I was in the room with you and Bob yesterday, I couldn&#8217;t help overhearing that we might drop our insurance plan altogether. I don&#8217;t mean to intrude on a private conversation, but since that would have such a significant impact, I wanted to check with you and see if that&#8217;s something you&#8217;re considering, especially since it&#8217;s the kind of thing that it would help to have as much advance notice of as possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>No matter what her answer &#8212; whether she says yes or no or that she&#8217;s not sure, or whether she doesn&#8217;t answer you at all, and even if she bristles at you asking &#8212; you should then follow up by, &#8220;If things do go in that direction, I&#8217;d like to ask that we get as much notice as possible, so that we can use the coverage while we have it.&#8221; She may be clueless enough that you actually need to point that out to her.</p>
<p>Depending on how the conversation goes and what kind of rapport you have with her, you can also point out that insurance is a requirement for many people when deciding whether or not to accept a job, that it was part of the benefits package that you signed up for when you were hired, and that eliminating it is likely to cause significant hardship and morale problems for people on staff, as well as make it hard to hire good people in the future. You could also suggest that people might strongly prefer to simply pay an additional portion of the premiums themselves rather than lose the coverage altogether.</p>
<p>And if your company does end up dropping the insurance coverage, you can certainly try to negotiate for additional money so that you can purchase your own, pointing out again that insurance was part of the benefits package that you signed up for when you were hired, and that it factored into your initial salary negotiations. You might not get it, but you can and should make the case for it &#8230; and if you don&#8217;t get it (or even if you do), then you can decide whether you still want to stay under these new terms.</p>
<p>Given the way the U.S. health insurance system is structured, an employer deciding to drop their coverage is a Big Deal Big Thing to do to employees, particularly when they have employees who took their jobs there with the understanding that insurance was part of the package. I hope you don&#8217;t have to deal with it &#8212; and if it does happen, I hope your boss hears loud and clear that it&#8217;s unacceptable, in the form of people going elsewhere and telling her why.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-employer-might-drop-our-health-insurance-what-can-i-do.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>61</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>is it okay to apply makeup in the bathroom at work?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/is-it-okay-to-apply-makeup-in-the-bathroom-at-work.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/is-it-okay-to-apply-makeup-in-the-bathroom-at-work.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 17:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[workplace practices]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5690</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I work at a large university in a building of about 300 people. There are two floors and I know almost everyone on my floor by face, if not by name. After a long winter, I&#8217;ve recently started biking to work. I bring my makeup with me and put it on in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I work at a large university in a building of about 300 people. There are two floors and I know almost everyone on my floor by face, if not by name.</em></p>
<p><em>After a long winter, I&#8217;ve recently started biking to work. I bring my makeup with me and put it on in the women&#8217;s bathroom about 10 minutes before official working hours start. It only takes me 2 or 3 minutes; this is not a fashion level routine, just some foundation, mascara, and eyeliner. Is that weird? Should I get a makeup mirror for my cube? So far no one&#8217;s said anything and all my coworkers in my office know I&#8217;m biking to work (and are encouraging and positive about it).</em></p>
<p>It would be weirder to apply it in your cube, so don&#8217;t do that. Your cube is more of an open space than the bathroom is.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think what you&#8217;re doing is any big deal, particularly since people know you bike to work. It&#8217;s not ideal &#8212; foundation, mascara, and eyeliner is a bigger production than a quick swipe of lipstick, and it&#8217;s more grooming than you usually expect to see in an office bathroom &#8212; but it&#8217;s not a big deal. Certainly not a big enough deal for you to stop biking to work.</p>
<p>As a side note, years ago, I worked with someone who carried a full makeup case to work &#8212; one of those big metal boxes with shelves and compartments on the inside &#8212; and every afternoon after lunch, she&#8217;d stand in front of the bathroom mirror and do a full makeup reapplication with foundation, powder, eye makeup, lip liner, different brushes, etc. That&#8217;s something I&#8217;d say not to do, because it made her look so preoccupied with her appearance at work that it was hard to take her seriously; her priorities seemed off-kilter.</p>
<p>But that&#8217;s very different than what you&#8217;re doing, so I think you&#8217;re fine.</p>
<p>Anyone want to disagree? Or share their own workplace grooming habits?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/is-it-okay-to-apply-makeup-in-the-bathroom-at-work.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>212</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>tiny answer Tuesday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/tiny-answer-tuesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-26.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/tiny-answer-tuesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-26.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 15:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5685</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s tiny answer Tuesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Company offered me a job, then called me back to meet with the owner I&#8217;ve been searching for a job and think I&#8217;ve finally found the one that I want and luckily it seems as though they want me [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s tiny answer Tuesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Company offered me a job, then called me back to meet with the owner</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve been searching for a job and think I&#8217;ve finally found the one that I want and luckily it seems as though they want me too &#8230; I think. I have had a phone interview and an in-person interview over the past several weeks and then Friday they called and made a verbal offer. They said they would send over the written offer today or tomorrow (Monday/Tuesday). Today, the person with whom I&#8217;ve been interviewing asked me to come in for an interview with the owner. I was caught off guard but offered up my availability. I&#8217;m scheduled to meet the owner later this week. I haven&#8217;t received the written offer yet. Does that mean they&#8217;re re-thinking their decision? What should I expect from meeting with the owner, whom I met once briefly last week, and should I bring up the verbal offer with him?</em></p>
<p>They should have been clearer with you when they called to ask you to meet with the owner! Since they weren&#8217;t, ideally on that call you would have said, &#8220;Just to clarify, we&#8217;d talked on Friday about you sending over a formal offer. Is that on hold pending this meeting?&#8221; Since you that easy window to ask has closed, at this point I would just go to the next meeting and not ask about it (although it&#8217;s still your prerogative to call them now and ask) &#8212; but either way, assume that there&#8217;s no offer yet, since it sounds hazy enough that you shouldn&#8217;t rely on it until it&#8217;s formalized. Certainly in your meeting with the owner, if it doesn&#8217;t become clear what&#8217;s going on, before the meeting ends you can ask about it. I&#8217;d can say something like, &#8220;Can you tell me your timeline for next steps? When I spoke with Jane on Friday, she had offered me the position &#8212; but I&#8217;m less clear now where things stand in your process.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>2. Company removed my name from my work after I stopped working there</strong></p>
<p><em>I wrote a bunch of blog posts for a digital marketing agency&#8217;s corporate blog while I worked there, and now that I have left, they took my name off of all of the content I contributed. I&#8217;m sure they legally own the content, but is it even worth reaching out to them to ask about it? I ask because I work in online marketing and writing relevant blog content is important for my portfolio. It&#8217;s probably not worth it, just bummed to have spent the time on writing posts (10+) and not getting any credit.</em></p>
<p>Sure, you can ask. They do indeed own the content since you produced it as part of your work for them (and in fact they could have chosen not to byline it with your name even while you were employed there), but there&#8217;s no harm in asking them. They can say no (and really, a company that removes your byline when you leave probably has some reason for doing it that isn&#8217;t going to be reversed by you asking them), but it&#8217;s certainly no inappropriate to say something like, &#8220;Hey, I&#8217;d love to show this work in my portfolio. Is there any way to return my byline to it?&#8221;</p>
<p>Keep in mind, though, that even if they say no, you can still include that work in your portfolio because you did indeed produce it.</p>
<p><strong>3. Withdrawing from a hiring process when your interviewer knows your current manager</strong></p>
<p><em>I just walked out of a second interview for a position and decided that the chemistry just isn&#8217;t right and that I want to withdraw my candidacy. Normally I would handle this in the post-meeting thank-you email so that they can quickly move on to other candidates (&#8220;thank you for taking the time to meet with me, but the position isn&#8217;t right for me at this time,&#8221; etc), but there&#8217;s a thing. I work fairly frequently with the hiring company in my current capacity. Hell, the hiring manager and my boss are on a first name basis. When I submitted my resume, I did write &#8220;resume submitted in confidence, please don&#8217;t contact current employer at this time,&#8221; and of course I only spoke good things about my current employer, but I&#8217;m a little nervous now that I know for sure I don&#8217;t want the position.</em></p>
<p><em>Should I email them now with my withdrawal or wait and hope they sensed what I did and reject me? If I email them my withdrawal, should I reiterate my need for discretion, or not mention it and hope they&#8217;ll be discreet (and bite my fingernails for a few weeks)? As background, the hiring company is a very small one, with no HR department, and my second interview was with the head of the company.</em></p>
<p>Well, if they&#8217;re going to be indiscreet, they&#8217;re probably going to do it whether you withdraw or not. So I would proceed however you normally would, and not worry that a withdrawal email is going to send them into a fit of pique that will cause them to tell your boss you applied. Just make sure your email is particularly gracious and doesn&#8217;t sound like the decision is because of some failing on their part. If you want to be extra safe, you could even say that your withdrawal is because you&#8217;ve decided to stay in your current role, thus mitigating any potential &#8220;Jane is job searching&#8221; gossip that might be passed on.</p>
<p><strong>4. Boss interrupted me in a meeting</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m in a job that demands the most of my resources. I&#8217;m a pretty good thinker, but I never planned to end up in business analysis, and I&#8217;m surrounded by people who have majored in this stuff and gobble it up. It&#8217;s challenging, to say the least &#8212; and just like people who speak English as a second language, I&#8217;m often out to sea when they&#8217;re all running ahead. I&#8217;m afraid I&#8217;m being seen as less competent than I&#8217;d like to be. Last week in a meeting, when a particularly tricky analysis was being discussed and it just, just didn&#8217;t make sense to me (and thinking of it over the weekend, it still doesn&#8217;t, and I&#8217;m wondering if maybe I&#8217;m right!), I started to voice a train of thought &#8212; paused &#8212; and right in the middle of it my normally polite boss just picked up and changed the subject. Also, the supervisor has said in meetings, &#8220;what Jane is trying to say&#8230;&#8221; and I&#8217;m not the go-to person for answers. But one-on-one I&#8217;m fine! It&#8217;s scary, and it&#8217;s frustrating.</em></p>
<p><em>How do you privately address a boss who interrupted you in a meeting and it&#8217;s still burning you up??</em></p>
<p>Hmmm. I think the issue here is less about talking to your boss about interrupting you and more about figuring out the bigger picture here. Is this the right role for you, and the right company? If you&#8217;re struggling and not following along in meetings, and your boss has stopped waiting for you to work through your thoughts and you feel less competent than others, these might be signals about overall fit. That means that being irked at your boss is a side issue; the bigger one is what all this stuff is telling you about your long-term success in this role.</p>
<p>If you have good rapport with your boss, it might be worth talking with her about what you&#8217;ve noticed and saying that you&#8217;re trying to figure out what feedback to take away from these instances. Don&#8217;t do this if you&#8217;re not prepared for hear fairly critical feedback, because you might &#8230; but on the other hand, you might hear that you&#8217;re doing fine overall and these thing are minor in the overall scheme of things, and that could give you more peace of mind.</p>
<p><strong>5. Job postings on job boards that aren&#8217;t on the company&#8217;s own website</strong></p>
<p><em>Sometimes I come across interesting job postings on external job sites (like Monster), but when I go to that company&#8217;s own careers webpage, the position is not listed. The external site prompts users to apply through their own system instead of pointing to the company&#8217;s website to apply. Is something like this worth pursuing? Or is something sketchy/unreliable about it? Any idea of what&#8217;s going on here?</em></p>
<p>It often means that the position is no longer open, but the external job sites haven&#8217;t removed it. However, sometimes it means that the company didn&#8217;t post the position on their own site and is relying solely on external sites to advertise it. This could be because they don&#8217;t post any jobs on their site (some places don&#8217;t) or because they&#8217;re not publicizing the site internally yet (because someone doesn&#8217;t know they&#8217;re leaving yet, for example). It&#8217;s hard to know from the outside which it is, unfortunately.</p>
<p><strong>6. Addressing spiritual requirements in a cover letter</strong></p>
<p><em>If a job description (for a religious higher ed institution) lists &#8220;Spiritual Requirements,&#8221; do I need to address these in my cover letter? I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m exactly the religious person they are looking for (although I do think I&#8217;m a good fit for the actual position, which has nothing to do with religion), but would rather apply and see if I get to the interview stage before addressing it (where I would be honest about my personal religious views if they asked). Does this seem like a bad idea?</em></p>
<p>Nope. You&#8217;re under no obligation to address any particular requirement in your cover letter, unless they specifically tell you to.</p>
<p><strong>7. Books for new managers</strong></p>
<p><em>I start a new IT job in 2 weeks where I will be managing a small team of technical people. I&#8217;ve managed project teams and technical teams, but direct people management will be new to me. I&#8217;m so excited and really want to be a success. I&#8217;m engaging with an HR leadership coach. I also wanted to do some reading on my own. I&#8217;ve heard good things about &#8220;First Break All the Rules.&#8221; Are there others you or your readers would recommend?</em></p>
<p>Well, there&#8217;s <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/my-book">mine</a> &#8212; which, uh, is awesome. It&#8217;s geared toward nonprofit managers, but 95% of what&#8217;s in there applies to managers in every field, and I wish I could make it required reading.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/tiny-answer-tuesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-26.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>54</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>what to do when you lose out on a promotion</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/what-to-do-when-you-lose-out-on-a-promotion.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/what-to-do-when-you-lose-out-on-a-promotion.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 14:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[work habits]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5684</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I recently applied for an internal promotion to be manager of the small team I serve. I was unsuccessful. Two questions. First, I was &#8220;let down easy&#8221;&#8211;the hiring manager said things like &#8220;it was close&#8221; and &#8220;we want to keep you.&#8221; But isn&#8217;t being turned down for the role essentially a repudiation [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I recently applied for an internal promotion to be manager of the small team I serve. I was unsuccessful. Two questions. First, I was &#8220;let down easy&#8221;&#8211;the hiring manager said things like &#8220;it was close&#8221; and &#8220;we want to keep you.&#8221; But isn&#8217;t being turned down for the role essentially a repudiation of me? If they really wanted to keep me, I feel like they would have considered offering me some incentive to remain. I am reading it as a clear sign that I should move on.</em></p>
<p><em>That notwithstanding, how do I establish rapport with the new manager, an external candidate who I was in competition with and lost out to? Do I specifically acknowledge that I applied for his role but that now I am ready to be a great team member, colleague, and partner? The truth is that I might have a hard time being an enthusiastic team member now that I&#8217;ve been rejected for this particular advancement.</em></p>
<p>You can read <a href="http://quickbase.intuit.com/blog/2013/03/26/what-to-do-when-you-lose-out-on-a-promotion/">my answer to this question at the The Fast Track blog by Intuit QuickBase today</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/what-to-do-when-you-lose-out-on-a-promotion.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>41</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>how flexible should you be when scheduling an interview?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/how-flexible-should-you-be-when-scheduling-an-interview.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/how-flexible-should-you-be-when-scheduling-an-interview.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 03:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[job searching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5686</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: This has been nagging me for a while now and I just wanted an expert opinion on the situation or how I could have handled it better. So, I applied for a summer internship at a very small up-and-coming magazine and got called back for an interview. At the interview, I was [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>This has been nagging me for a while now and I just wanted an expert opinion on the situation or how I could have handled it better. So, I applied for a summer internship at a very small up-and-coming magazine and got called back for an interview. At the interview, I was told I was being seriously considered and to look out for a follow-up. Well, I did and got nothing for over a month.</em></p>
<p><em>So I emailed, inquiring about how the selection process was coming along. The person in charge apologized for not getting back, said they were very busy, and said on Saturday to come in on the following Tuesday. I agreed. She said she would get back to me soon to give me directions, as it was a new location. Well, she didn&#8217;t give me the directions until THURSDAY and asked me to come in on that Friday. I told her I unfortunately had plans that day (I did, I had a dentist appointment) and asked to reschedule. She never replied.</em></p>
<p><em>This person is kind of a&#8221; who&#8217;s who&#8221; in the industry I want to work in. Should I have pushed harder? Was I too inflexible? Was I wrong for not cancelling my plans and going to the office on that Friday? I just felt like I was being stringed along and not really wanted.</em></p>
<p>Hell, no, you weren&#8217;t wrong. It&#8217;s <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2010/02/combatting-unhealthy-power-dynamics.html">not unreasonable</a> to be unavailable on a day&#8217;s notice, and it&#8217;s not unreasonable to expect a reply when you ask about other open time slots. And it&#8217;s certainly not unreasonable not to cancel an prior appointment, especially when your interviewer had already shown she was willing to renege on scheduled meetings (without even bothering to tell you).</p>
<p>However, what&#8217;s reasonable doesn&#8217;t always mesh well with how employers operate during hiring.</p>
<p>There are an awful lot of employers that operate the way this one did &#8212; alluding to dates that they&#8217;ll get in touch with you by and then not doing it, setting tentative interview times and then not following up with until long afterwards (while you&#8217;re meanwhile holding that time open and wondering what&#8217;s going on), stalling for weeks and then asking you to come in the next day, never responding to your replies to their scheduling emails, and so forth.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s rude &#8212; and incredibly so when you&#8217;re holding time on your calendar for them, and possibly even arranging to take off work.</p>
<p>But despite how rude it is, a <em>lot</em> of employers operate like this. Including even some that you might like to work for. And that means that you need to make your decisions with that in mind.</p>
<p>If you have options and you&#8217;re willing to risk that this is a rude/disorganized employer who won&#8217;t bother getting back to you when you ask for an alternate interview time, then I strongly urge you to continue to operate like a normal, reasonable person &#8212; saying &#8220;no, I have a conflict at that time, but could you do it Tuesday instead?&#8221; and assuming you will receive a reply back. (And figuring that if you don&#8217;t, you&#8217;ll be glad to have screened out a rude, disorganized employer.)</p>
<p>But if you don&#8217;t have options and aren&#8217;t willing to take that risk, well &#8230; the less flexible you are, the higher your risk of ending up in a situation like this one. Should you have to cancel a dentist appointment for an interview on a day&#8217;s notice? Absolutely not. But might you choose to anyway, knowing that some employers behave like this? You&#8217;ve got to make that call yourself, based on your own situation.</p>
<p>In job searching, how much you should put up with and how much you should bend to accommodate an employer comes down to how many options you have. So I&#8217;d start by being realistic about that, and then deciding what you are and aren&#8217;t willing to do from there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/how-flexible-should-you-be-when-scheduling-an-interview.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>mini answer Monday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/mini-answer-monday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-16.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/mini-answer-monday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-16.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 19:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5677</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s mini answer Monday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Coworker&#8217;s loud calls are distracting I work for a F100 company and I was recently promoted from a union to a management position on a new team. Since the promotion, I was moved to a new office floor that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s mini answer Monday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Coworker&#8217;s loud calls are distracting</strong></p>
<p><em>I work for a F100 company and I was recently promoted from a union to a management position on a new team. Since the promotion, I was moved to a new office floor that is somewhat vacant. There are about 5 union employees and the rest of us are management on varying levels. Everything is great, I really like the position, growth opportunities and I still have a huge window overlooking the park!</em></p>
<p><em>My dilemma is one of the managers (who was sitting over here before me) who sits in the back talks extremely loudly. We do not have doors that we can close, so I am stuck listening to her all day. Sometimes I put my headphones on and listen to jazz, but even then she can still be heard. I dread having to listen to the conference calls that are on speaker phone and every detail of her work that she is discussing. Everyone else manages to talk softly and discreetly. Since she is on the other side of the office and I can still hear her, she must be talking pretty loud. I assume no one has brought this to her attention since there are very few people over here. As I type, she has got on another call and she is ridiculously loud.</em></p>
<p><em>I have heard her speak to other people and she can be very brash and almost rude and condescending. How do I politely bring this to her attention without confrontation? I want to specifically address her volume and the fact that every call is on speaker. My work is important too and I need some concentration. My boss is in another state so I can&#8217;t (and wouldn&#8217;t) rely on him to fix this. I&#8217;m not &#8220;scurd&#8221; as they say, I just want to put an end to this and retain an otherwise pleasant office atmosphere.</em></p>
<p>&#8220;Jane, I hate to ask, but I wonder if you could keep your voice down when you&#8217;re on the phone? I&#8217;m finding that it really carries and make it hard to focus on times.&#8221; Or, &#8220;Jane, could you avoid speaker phone when you&#8217;re on calls? It makes it hard for me to concentrate.&#8221; You can probably only ask one of these for now, so pick it carefully.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m assuming she&#8217;s a peer, by the way. If she&#8217;s significantly above you in the hierarchy, you might need to just suck it up or find someone else to talk to her.</p>
<p><strong>2. Adding a spouse or friends on LinkedIn</strong></p>
<p><em>Is it appropriate to add your spouse on LinkedIn if you have no major professional ties? What about friends?</em></p>
<p>Sure, that&#8217;s fine. Lots of people add social contacts on LinkedIn and don&#8217;t confine their networks only to people they&#8217;ve worked with or know from a professional setting. (Part of the value of LinkedIn, after all, is gaining access to your circle&#8217;s network &#8212; something that doesn&#8217;t require you to know them in a professional context.)</p>
<p><strong>3. Interviewing with the CEO</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m super nervous about my upcoming second round interview. I&#8217;m interviewing for a junior position on a communications team. I&#8217;m meeting with a panel for the second round that includes the CEO of the organization. I&#8217;ve never had an interview with the highest ranking person at an org before&#8211;my question is, what will he be looking for? I assume they wouldn&#8217;t waste a CEO&#8217;s time with asking behavioral interview questions. What do you think he will be looking for ? More examples of my experience?</em></p>
<p>It could be a completely typical interview, with behavioral questions, etc., or &#8212; somewhat more likely &#8212; he might just want to talk more informally with you. I&#8217;d prepare as if it&#8217;s going to be the former because most people don&#8217;t do well at that type of interview without preparation, but don&#8217;t be thrown off it&#8217;s the latter.</p>
<p><strong>4. Interviewer asked what my husband thought of him</strong></p>
<p><em>I was at an interview, and the main interviewer knew my husband from a previous job. He asked me what my husband thought of him. The more I think about it, the weirder it seems. What are you thoughts?</em></p>
<p>Yes, that&#8217;s a weird question. He might have been joking, or he might have just been a weird and maybe awkward guy. Who knows?</p>
<p><strong>5. Employer thinks I&#8217;m over-stating how difficult my work is</strong></p>
<p><em>Ten years ago, I was hired at a church because they were starting a communications dept. and I had some Quark experience. I&#8217;m self taught on Photoshop. I&#8217;ve improved tremendously over the years with my design work. It&#8217;s solid and competent &#8212; for our demographic &#8212; but not inspired. A true graphic artist who I respect has judged my work to be quite on par with our church&#8217;s needs, for most things.</em></p>
<p><em>One of our pastors has decided that all three of us need to be cross trained. I was shocked yesterday when he told me that &#8220;due to my insecurities, I&#8217;ve over dramatized how difficult my job is.&#8221; Yes, I am insecure, yet I&#8217;ve been honest about the complexity for people who have never used these programs. I&#8217;m discouraged and distressed to hear this, especially after all these years. But worst of all, is that my word has no value to them. What is the best way to deal with this low opinion they have of me? How do I convince them that insecurity doesn&#8217;t equal liar? And why is it so hard to believe that people who have never done this kind of work might, possibly, find it a touch difficult?</em></p>
<p>Well, first, people are notorious for thinking that graphic design doesn&#8217;t involve as much work as it really does, so that comes with the territory.</p>
<p>But it doesn&#8217;t sound like anyone is accusing you of lying &#8212; just of perhaps being overly dramatic or overly anxious about the work that your job involves. Yes, it&#8217;s easy to be insulted by something like that, but it&#8217;s not going to be particularly helpful to you to take that stance. It&#8217;s not crazy to want some degree of cross-training in a small department, so that if you&#8217;re out some day and they need something changed in a document before you&#8217;re back, someone is capable of at least basic updates. I&#8217;d just look at it from that viewpoint and give up on trying to convince them that they&#8217;re wrong, since I suspect that will be fruitless &#8212; and frustrating.</p>
<p><strong>6. Sent home for being in a bad mood</strong></p>
<p><em>A friend of mine who lives in North Carolina just told me that his sister that works for a company on a commisson basis was told not to come in for a week because on this particular day she was in a bad mood because the windshield of her car was smashed. Is this legal?</em></p>
<p>Yes. If her position is <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/exempt-and-non-exempt">exempt</a>, she needs to be paid her full salary for every week in which she does any work, but if they sent her home for the full week &#8212; or if she&#8217;s non-exempt &#8212; they can absolutely suspend her without pay for a week. I&#8217;m assuming that if was at the point that she was sent home for it, that bad mood must have been pretty disruptive &#8212; that&#8217;s generally not a good idea at work.</p>
<p><strong>7. Will a master&#8217;s hurt my chances of getting an internship?</strong></p>
<p><em>I am finishing up my first year of grad school (it&#8217;s a 2-year program), and I am now applying to internships for the summer, when I will be on break. My field is communications/journalism/PR, and I am finding that a lot of people in my industry, even those at the top, don&#8217;t seem to hold advanced degrees. As a matter of fact, I was often warned in undergrad that in my field, experience is valued a lot more that a master&#8217;s degree. So my question is, do you think a master&#8217;s degree can hurt my chances of getting an internship for the summer? I am already having trouble even finding internships to apply for that accept grad students. Will I seem overqualified, un-experienced, or (at the risk of sounding narcissistic), I have even heard that some employers are intimidated by candidates with master&#8217;s degrees. I would love to know your thoughts!</em></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever met a professional adult who was intimidated by someone with a master&#8217;s, so I&#8217;d drop that worry &#8212; or you risk coming across as thinking that it counts for more than it does. In most fields, most employers value work experience far more than graduate degrees (with the usual exceptions, like academia), and that&#8217;s certainly true in journalism, where what matters most is your ability to write and your published clips. (In fact, had you written to me earlier, I would have advised you to <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2011/12/thinking-about-grad-school-think-again.html">skip the graduate program</a> and start writing. Much less cost to you, and a bigger pay-off.)</p>
<p>Anyway &#8230;being in a masters program, or having a masters, may or may not harm your chances of getting an internship. Some internships are specifically designed for undergraduate students, and those obviously won&#8217;t be a good fit. But your school should help you find internships that you&#8217;d be a good candidate for; that should be part of what your program does for you, and if they don&#8217;t, I&#8217;d think really hard about what exactly you&#8217;re getting out of the program &#8212; it should be helping you become more marketable, not less, right?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/mini-answer-monday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-16.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>119</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>my mother says I should call employers daily for an interview</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-mother-says-i-should-call-employers-daily-for-an-interview.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-mother-says-i-should-call-employers-daily-for-an-interview.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[job search: following up]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5676</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I am at my second semester of graduate school. In order to get an internship for next semester, I&#8217;ve been really working 24/7 for the past month. However, I still haven&#8217;t heard anything from employers yet and of course feel frustrated, as the deadline for join my school&#8217;s internship program is in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I am at my second semester of graduate school. In order to get an internship for next semester, I&#8217;ve been really working 24/7 for the past month. However, I still haven&#8217;t heard anything from employers yet and of course feel frustrated, as the deadline for join my school&#8217;s internship program is in three weeks.</em></p>
<p><em>My mother, who is staying with me now, has strong opinions and thinks I should call employers much more often than I am doing now. (I normally only call them before submitting the application to ask for more details and when the time they promised to come back to me has passed.) However, my mother believes that employers are rather busy and don&#8217;t have so much time to go through every resume, and since I have a not-that-outstanding resume, I should call them more often. Maybe if the person has so much to do and doesn&#8217;t want to bother with boring recruitment, they will just pick the one who always calls them. Therefore, I should lobby by phone more often (&#8220;every day&#8221; is what she thinks is a decent frequency).</em></p>
<p><em>I don&#8217;t think my mother knows so much about the job market, but I do think it makes sense that all applicants are somewhat similarly qualified with promising cover letters, so maybe it is one way to stand out, as it could impress HR more than a plain letter. What do you think? What would be a nice frequency to call up the companies, and what should I say? (Especially if I really am going to call every day, I wonder what to say.) Is it a good idea to be more private and ask the person about their own positions or background on the phone? Or will this backfire on me if the company gets irritated or annoyed?</em></p>
<p>You are hereby forbidden to take advice from your mother on anything job-related.</p>
<ul>
<li>The correct frequency for calling to check on your application: zero</li>
<li>The correct frequency for calling before you submit an application: zero</li>
<li>The correct frequency for taking advice to annoy hiring managers with <em>daily</em> (!) phone calls: zero</li>
<li>The correct frequently for calling employers and asking about their own backgrounds, when they haven&#8217;t even expressed interest in interviewing you: zero</li>
</ul>
<p>The vast, vast majority of employers do not want to receive phone calls from applicants. If they&#8217;re interested in interviewing you, they will contact you. If you call, you will annoy them. If you call more than once, you will <em>really</em> annoy them and risk having your application thrown out or at least marked as &#8220;pushy/annoying.&#8221; And if you call daily, you will be told to stop and will probably never get a job there, ever.</p>
<p>After all, most employers get hundreds of applications for every open position. Imagine if all those people called them, even just once. (To say nothing of every day.) By demanding their attention, you&#8217;re going to come across as naive at best and and rude at worst.</p>
<p>They know you&#8217;re interested. The act of applying conveyed that to them. They will get in touch if they want to talk to you. But you can&#8217;t force your way in the door, and they are not going to be impressed by you continually knocking on it.</p>
<p>Now, yes, there <em>are</em> some employers who are so disorganized that calling them can be enough to get them to look at your application when they otherwise would not have. But these employers are the minority, so while there&#8217;s the chance that you <em>could</em> hit on the random luck to help yourself with one of them, you will harm yourself with everyone else (and everyone else is in the vast majority). So the overwhelming odds are that this behavior will hurt your chances. (Plus, those disorganized employers who respond to random phone calls? You don&#8217;t want to work for them. They&#8217;re disorganized and chaotic and don&#8217;t know how to hire.)</p>
<p>If you want to stand out, you stand by being a highly qualified candidate with a compelling cover letter and a resume that shows a track record of achievement. <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/12/if-youre-not-getting-interviews-read-this.html">That&#8217;s it</a>.</p>
<p>I know that it&#8217;s tempting to want to find some other way of standing out, especially when you feel you have a &#8220;not that outstanding resume.&#8221; But employers are looking for <strong>the most qualified candidate who&#8217;s the best fit</strong>. They&#8217;re not looking for the loudest.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-mother-says-i-should-call-employers-daily-for-an-interview.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>116</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>what managers learn that workers don&#8217;t know</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/what-managers-learn-that-workers-dont-know.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/what-managers-learn-that-workers-dont-know.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 15:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advice about your boss]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5678</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Have you ever noticed that often when people get promoted to management, their perspective on workplaces issues changes? I&#8217;m pretty sure this is because as a manager, you see things that you might never have been exposed to as a regular employee, and you come to view workplace questions through a different lens than the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/03/25/what-new-managers-learn-that-employees-dont-know"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2095" alt="featured-on-usn" src="http://www.askamanager.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/featured-on-usn1.jpg" width="90" height="60" /></a>Have you ever noticed that often when people get promoted to management, their perspective on workplaces issues changes?</p>
<p>I&#8217;m pretty sure this is because as a manager, you see things that you might never have been exposed to as a regular employee, and you come to view workplace questions through a different lens than the one you used previously. As a result, managers’ stance on common workplace issues often ends up changing – often to their own surprise.</p>
<p>Over at U.S. News &amp; World Report today, I talk about some of the most common ways that your perspective might change after becoming a manager &#8212; including your views on turnover, bonuses, priorities, and more. You can <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/03/25/what-new-managers-learn-that-employees-dont-know">read it here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/what-managers-learn-that-workers-dont-know.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>my boss is dragging her feet on hiring my replacement</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-boss-is-dragging-her-feet-on-hiring-my-replacement.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-boss-is-dragging-her-feet-on-hiring-my-replacement.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advice about your boss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resigning]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5675</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: Earlier this week, I told my boss I would be leaving/moving to the state my fiance lives in at the end of our season in May. She knows we&#8217;re getting married, and I&#8217;m a terrible liar, so despite planning to wait until mid-April to tell her (in my field, 6 weeks or [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>Earlier this week, I told my boss I would be leaving/moving to the state my fiance lives in at the end of our season in May. She knows we&#8217;re getting married, and I&#8217;m a terrible liar, so despite planning to wait until mid-April to tell her (in my field, 6 weeks or so is standard for giving notice), I couldn&#8217;t avoid telling her when she asked. Then she freaked out about plans for next season now being off-track because she had thought, that since I hadn&#8217;t said anything sooner, she&#8217;d &#8220;have me&#8221; for another season, etc, etc. I&#8217;m not worried about being let go earlier or treated poorly, but what I am worried about is what came out next: that she might not hire someone until July or August.</em></p>
<p><em>This is why I wasn&#8217;t going to tell her until mid-April, because her habit is to resist believing change is coming and to procrastinate on hiring a new person. (The woman before me gave her notice at about this same point and left in May and I wasn&#8217;t hired until July, and what had piled up was kind of a mess when I started; similar story the time before that.) I would LOVE to have the opportunity to help train the new person, rather than just leave how-to&#8217;s and my phone number. In addition, my boss has a lot more on her plate now than when I started (and we don&#8217;t have an intern now either), so there&#8217;s no way she&#8217;ll have time to keep the day-to-day stuff of my job running in the perhaps months between my departure and a new person&#8217;s arrival, not to mention her time spent getting the new person acclimated to our programs.</em></p>
<p><em>Is there anything I can do or say to help get the hiring process moving? I know at some point it&#8217;s out of my control, but I think she&#8217;s stuck in the &#8220;OMG WHAT AM I GOING TO DO!?!?!&#8221; phase. I&#8217;m already updating my job description so that won&#8217;t be what she&#8217;s waiting on. My fiance doesn&#8217;t understand why I care so much about trying to help her out because she hasn&#8217;t been a good boss but I&#8217;d like to leave this neat and tidy, and a months-long lag time between employees seems messy.</em></p>
<p>Honestly, it&#8217;s not your problem. And even if it were (which it&#8217;s not), you just don&#8217;t have the authority or control over the situation to make it work the way you want it to work.</p>
<p>Of course you&#8217;re right that it&#8217;s ridiculous and irresponsible to stall on hiring someone when if she moved faster, she could have a shorter vacancy, less work piling up, and maybe time for you to train the person. But this isn&#8217;t about what&#8217;s sensible or obvious; it&#8217;s about what your boss is willing to do. And you can&#8217;t control that. Moreover, you don&#8217;t need to. Because, again, it&#8217;s not your problem.</p>
<p>Your obligation is solely to give as much notice as you&#8217;re comfortable giving, to leave your realm as orderly as possible, and to leave behind as much documentation as you can for the next person.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s it. Your obligation is not to somehow push your boss into acting differently than she seems inclined to act. And it&#8217;s not to protect her from the consequences of her own actions.</p>
<p>Now, you can certainly point out to her what&#8217;s in the best interests of the organization and your eventual replacement. That means that you can say something like, &#8220;If the new person starts by May, I can help train them before I leave. To do that, I think we&#8217;d need to start advertising this week or next, with the goals of conducting interviews by X. If you&#8217;d like, I can update the job description and help with the initial resume screening so that we&#8217;re able to keep the process moving relatively quickly.&#8221;</p>
<p>But from there, it&#8217;s up to her. She&#8217;ll either act or she won&#8217;t. And it&#8217;s not your problem if she doesn&#8217;t, not any more than it&#8217;s your problem if she, say, doesn&#8217;t turn in a report to her own manager on time. This is not your job. It is hers, and you need to let her do it the way she sees fit &#8212; even if that way is terrible.</p>
<p>I totally understand feeling some personal responsibility for ensuring that your role is handled well, even after you&#8217;re gone &#8212; that&#8217;s common in conscientious people. But the reality is that what you can and should do is limited, because you are leaving. Get your area in good order and leave extensive documentation, then move on with a clear conscience. There&#8217;s no feasible way to do anything else.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-boss-is-dragging-her-feet-on-hiring-my-replacement.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>we&#8217;re winners!</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/5680.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/5680.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 02:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5680</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thanks to everyone in voted in the Bloggies &#8212; Ask a Manager won in the category of Best Topical Blog, which is awesome. (And which surely couldn&#8217;t have happened without posts like this and this. And this.)]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>Thanks to everyone in voted in the <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es">Bloggies</a> &#8212; Ask a Manager won in the category of Best Topical Blog, which is awesome. (And which surely couldn&#8217;t have happened without posts like <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/08/my-former-coworker-wants-my-company-to-sponsor-her-party.html">this</a> and <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/06/my-company-has-hired-a-pushy-dietician-who-wont-leave-me-alone.html">this</a>. And <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/09/our-employee-wont-stop-hugging-people.html">this</a>.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/5680.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>short answer Sunday &#8212; 6 short answers to 6 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-sunday-6-short-answers-to-6-short-questions-11.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-sunday-6-short-answers-to-6-short-questions-11.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 13:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5668</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s short answer Sunday &#8212; six short answers to six short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Negotiating maternity leave and salary at the same time I am excited about a recent interview. However, if it results in a job offer, I am worried about asking for too much in negotiations. I am 7 months pregnant [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s short answer Sunday &#8212; six short answers to six short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Negotiating maternity leave and salary at the same time</strong></p>
<p><em>I am excited about a recent interview. However, if it results in a job offer, I am worried about asking for too much in negotiations. I am 7 months pregnant and will need to negotiate a maternity leave. I understand taking leave shortly after starting is not ideal and I hope to negotiate a short leave 3-4 weeks, then reduced hours for an additional 2-3 weeks. First, does this sound reasonable? Or should I have different expectations of what will be agreed to since I will only be at the position about 10 weeks?</em></p>
<p><em>Second, when we discussed salary, we were $15k apart. I based my asking salary on industry data, but it was national data and not region-specific. I feel that the salary they said they were planning for the position is still on the low side, even taking our geographic area into consideration. I would be comfortable (but not ideal) taking $10k less than my asking salary but don&#8217;t want to sell myself short. My main question is&#8230; can I negotiate a higher salary AND a maternity leave? I feel like I should only be asking for one. Is asking for too much a turn-off to an employer? I have had three professional jobs and have only negotiated salary.</em></p>
<p>No, you can do that. Maternity leave is really a separate thing from salary negotiations (and what you&#8217;re planning to ask for there is more than reasonable; they&#8217;ll probably be relieved you&#8217;re not asking for more).</p>
<p><strong>2. Declining to extend an internship</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve been an intern at a nonprofit wildlife hospital since last June. I&#8217;ve loved the experience and my end date has been extended several times. Recently, I&#8217;ve been asked to stay another nine months and this time I don&#8217;t think I can accept, as I don&#8217;t feel as though I have anything more to learn and they&#8217;ve already made it clear they cannot afford to hire me as a member of their full-time staff. How do I go about declining the internship without offending anyone? We work in a very intimate environment where the lines between friendship and professionalism tend to blur, but I do need a good recommendation from them before I leave, thus I can&#8217;t afford to hurt anyone&#8217;s feelings with my answer.</em></p>
<p>Do not worry At All about this. It&#8217;s perfectly normal to leave jobs and decline offers to extend internships. They&#8217;re not going to be offended. You can simply say that you need to find full-time work, but that you&#8217;ve loved the experience and hope to stay in touch.</p>
<p><strong>3. What did this interview question mean?</strong></p>
<p><em>I have a question about a question I was asked in an interview. The position is for a mid-career, non-management position, and I would be hired as the most junior position on a team. During the first interview, they asked me about my &#8220;strategic management&#8221; style. I was floored because this position will not supervise others. I fumbled my way through a response where I talked about how I handle projects (and gave a specific example). I know my answer was adequate enough to not kick me out of the interviewing process, but I am unsure of what they were looking for. I am just anxious that the next round of interviews may ask similar questions. What kind of information do you think they were looking for?</em></p>
<p>I have no idea &#8212; that&#8217;s a bizarre question to ask anyone, let alone someone not managing people. (I really have no idea what &#8220;strategic management style&#8221; even means.) But if you ever get asked questions in the future that you&#8217;re not sure how to interpret, it&#8217;s totally fine to ask for clarification. Just say something like, &#8220;Could you tell me a little more about what you&#8217;re looking for there?&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>4. Do the rules change when you&#8217;re headhunted?</strong></p>
<p><em>I was headhunted by a firm two months ago. I told them politely that I was happy with my current job but thanks anyway. They’ve reached out again today, asking if I’d reconsider because they’re being very particular and are really interested in the background I have. They’ve piqued my interest a bit more this time, but I’ve never been headhunted before. In these kind of situations, is it ok to ask upfront about salary expectations and bring up that I’m currently on manager track at my current role and wouldn’t move unless this opportunity (which isn’t a manger role) had similar opportunities? I normally wouldn’t bring this up so early during a regular job search but seeing as they approached me, do the rules change?</em></p>
<p>Yep. It&#8217;s totally fine to say, &#8220;I&#8217;m interested in talking more, but I want to be up-front with you that I wouldn&#8217;t make a move unless the opportunity was really the right one. I don&#8217;t want to waste your time, so can I ask you about the salary range and the growth potential in the role?&#8221;</p>
<p>If they turn it around and ask you what salary you&#8217;d be looking for, you can say, &#8220;Since I&#8217;m not actively looking, I haven&#8217;t given that enough thought. But if you can give me a sense of your ballpark, I can tell you if it makes sense for us to keep talking.&#8221; They still might not, because some companies don&#8217;t, but that would be ridiculous since they&#8217;re pursuing you.</p>
<p><strong>5. Asking to connect with an interviewer on LinkedIn</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m curious what you think of candidates requesting to connect with HR managers on LinkedIn. I am the HR person for a small company and have been doing a lot of hiring recently thus I have been doing a TON of phone interviews with candidates. I find it awkward to phone interview someone and then receive a request to connect and I tend to ignore these requests, regardless of if I liked the candidate or not. If we hire them then, sure, I&#8217;ll connect but I tend to be more selective with who I connect with. What are your thoughts, both for the candidates sending them and the HR managers receiving them?</em></p>
<p>I think it&#8217;s fine for candidates to do, because some HR people and hiring managers are happy to connect with them. Others, however, aren&#8217;t &#8212; feeling that they don&#8217;t know them well enough. (I&#8217;m in the last category myself, and ignore connection requests from most candidates I interview.) So while I don’t think it’s inappropriate to request the connection, I think it&#8217;s fine for you to ignore it if you&#8217;d prefer to.</p>
<p><strong>6. Employer said they were about to check my references and then disappeared</strong></p>
<p><em>I applied for an out-of-state job and had a phone interview and a subsequent in-person interview. I sent a thank you e-mail the next day after the in-person interview and my interviewer quickly responded that it was great to meet me and they would be in contact soon. A few days later the interviewer emailed me to tell me they would be contacting my references the next day. Great news! I contacted all my references to tell them to expect a call.</em></p>
<p><em>But nothing happened! All my references contacted me saying they never heard from my interviewer. It&#8217;s now been about 3 weeks since they said they would contact my references and I haven&#8217;t heard a word. I tried sending an &#8220;update on your timeline&#8221; email, but again, no response. Even if they had run a credit, background, social media, etc. check, I would have been in the clear. What do you think could have happened? I understand not getting the job, but it just seems odd to say you&#8217;re going to contact references and not do so and then completely stop communicating.</em></p>
<p>Could be anything &#8212; they went with another candidate, the hiring process stalled for some reason, your interviewer quit or got fired, she&#8217;s been out sick, something higher priority came up &#8230; or something else. There&#8217;s no way to know. Your best move here is to mentally move on, and let it be a pleasant surprise if they resurface later.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-sunday-6-short-answers-to-6-short-questions-11.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>58</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>short answer Saturday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-saturday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-30.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-saturday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-30.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5663</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s short answer Saturday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Contacting companies in the area I&#8217;ll be moving to in a year My husband and I are in the unique position of knowing that we are relocating for his job in one year. I have begun researching companies in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s short answer Saturday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Contacting companies in the area I&#8217;ll be moving to in a year</strong></p>
<p><em>My husband and I are in the unique position of knowing that we are relocating for his job in one year. I have begun researching companies in my field in the new area and am enthusiastic about all the prospects.</em></p>
<p><em>How should I go about communicating with these companies? Is it wise to reach out with an introduction rather than a formal application because it&#8217;s so far in advance? Or should I continue monitoring their job postings? In that case, what if a job is posted six months from now and I have to explain that I wouldn&#8217;t be able to move for another half of a year?</em></p>
<p>It depends. If you&#8217;re very junior, reaching out to companies now probably isn&#8217;t going to do you much good because they&#8217;re probably just not going to care that much (although you should still try to start building your network in that area). But if you&#8217;re more senior or have a very in-demand skill, it could absolutely be helpful to start making contacts and building relationships now.</p>
<p><strong>2. Asking for a raise when my manager doesn&#8217;t have the authority to approve it</strong></p>
<p><em>I have been working for my employer for three years. I like the company, and for the past 18months I have been doing a managers post but been paid a normal worker&#8217;s salary (as per the conditions of the post advert).</em></p>
<p><em>For a while, this was fine, but I now need more financial stability and I feel this is the right time to ask as I have completed my probation period, and I frequently receive positive feedback on my work from managers and external agencies. But how can I ask for a raise when it&#8217;s not within my manager&#8217;s or his manager&#8217;s control? I know they would both support me with this. But I the impression these decisions are made by our head office by someone I have hardly ever spoken to. It&#8217;s likely I will have to do it via email and I just don&#8217;t really know what to say.</em></p>
<p>You still go through your manager. It&#8217;s up to your manager to make a case on your behalf to whoever the decision-maker is above him.</p>
<p><strong>3. Having mutual friends contact a hiring manager on my behalf</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m interested in a position in which the hiring manager and I have two mutual friends. Is it too much to have both of them contact her on my behalf?</em></p>
<p>No, that&#8217;s fine to do, but make sure that it doesn&#8217;t come across like <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2011/05/bombarding-an-employer-with-unsolicited-recommendations-can-backfire.html">this</a>. You should also apply on your own meanwhile &#8212; and then your mutual friends&#8217; recommendations can be a supplement to that.</p>
<p><strong>4. Getting in touch with a company without using their online application system</strong></p>
<p><em>If I know there&#8217;s a specific company I want to work for, is there an appropriate way to get in touch with HR directly through linkedin? I feel that sending my application into their system through the Taleo site will just end up in my application in a black hole of other applications.</em></p>
<p>HR will just direct you to apply through their normal channels. However, if you can track down the hiring manager in charge of the area you want to work in (because &#8212; in case you are someone who doesn&#8217;t know this &#8211; <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/06/fired-vs-laid-off-and-the-difference-between-a-hiring-manager-and-hr.html">a hiring manager is different from HR</a>, very different), you can try sending your application directly to them, with a compelling cover letter. (You should still apply the regular way too, though, and you should note in your letter that you did &#8212; because you don&#8217;t want to look like you don&#8217;t follow directions.)</p>
<p>Plus, if you&#8217;re set on this company in particular, you should direct a whole bunch of networking efforts to people who work there.</p>
<p><strong>5. Should I reapply for a job after a phone interview gone bad?</strong></p>
<p><em>I recently submitted my resume to a firm and received a phone call from them since they wanted some additional information. I got nervous and said some things I did not mean, which made it look like I was not that interested in the job and may not be able to work full-time, when in fact I most definitely would work full-time if offered the position. The HR manager said she would send me an email by the end of this week if she wanted to set up an interview. It is Friday and I have not received an email. I want to clarify/redeem myself and therefore want to add my availability and strong interest in my cover letter and hence resubmit my resume. Should I just submit my resume again or should I withdraw the old one and then send the new resume (since I have the option of withdrawing it on their site)?</em></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t resubmit an application; that&#8217;s going to seem weird since you&#8217;ve already had contact with them about this very job. If anything, send a follow-up email to the HR manager clarifying whatever it is that you want to clarify. But don&#8217;t withdraw or resubmit anything.</p>
<p><strong>6. Who do I follow up with when I interviewed with multiple people?</strong></p>
<p><em>When you have an interview with several people at one company, how do you determine the &#8220;person of contact&#8221; when following up? I recently had an interview with a partner in the firm and also the events manager, and then I had a second interview with the same partner and a different associate. It&#8217;s been two weeks since they said they had planned to make a decision, but I&#8217;m not sure which of the three to follow up with. It&#8217;s a small place, so there isn&#8217;t much of an HR department either. I was contacted for the interview by an executive assistant.</em></p>
<p>Follow up with the partner, since you&#8217;ve talked with him twice and he&#8217;s probably the decision-maker. In general, the decision-maker is the one to check in with. If it&#8217;s truly unclear (not the case here), then go with the person you had the most rapport with.</p>
<p><strong>7. Why is this offer taking so long?</strong></p>
<p><em>I’ve been looking to move away from my current company and have interviewed with a multinational for a position that has much better future projections. The whole process was dealt with through a specialist recruiter for the sector I work in (linguistics). I received a verbal offer via the recruiter, which I verbally accepted, subject to seeing the specific terms (mainly bonus structure that the recruiter was unable to give me clear information about). That was two and a half weeks ago. Since then, I’ve been given various excuses as to why the contract (or even a written offer) has not been prepared and sent to me: namely, administrative delay and the HR manager on holiday.</em></p>
<p><em>My only point of contact is the recruiter – I have no direct contact with HR at the company. I really don’t know what to make of it. On the one hand, I think that they have no logical reason to be stalling or wavering on their offer; on the other, I just can’t see why they have not been able to send me some kind of document in the last 18 days. Is this normal? Am I being played? It’s starting to put me off the whole idea of the company as I see it as exemplary of how they operate.</em></p>
<p>Believe it or not, this isn&#8217;t that unusual. It takes some large companies a <em>really</em> long time to put together formal offers. And if the HR manager has been on vacation, that could absolutely hold things up. Ask the recruiter for a sense of the likely timeline, and meanwhile, keep up your job search. I don&#8217;t say that to alarm you &#8212; again, this isn&#8217;t that unusual &#8212; but just because you should always keep up your job search until you have a formal, written offer that you&#8217;ve accepted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-saturday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-30.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>should you attach writing samples, transcripts, and other extra items when applying for a job?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-attach-writing-samples-transcripts-and-other-extra-items-when-applying-for-a-job.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-attach-writing-samples-transcripts-and-other-extra-items-when-applying-for-a-job.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[job searching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5672</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I woke up with either a cold or allergies, but I&#8217;ve never had allergies before so I&#8217;m starting to think it is in fact a dreadful cold. I am quite literally a mouth-breather right now. In any case&#8230; A reader writes: When applying for a job, should I provide supplemental materials such as sample writings, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>I woke up with either a cold or allergies, but I&#8217;ve never had allergies before so I&#8217;m starting to think it is in fact a dreadful cold. I am quite literally a mouth-breather right now.</p>
<p>In any case&#8230;</p>
<p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>When applying for a job, should I provide supplemental materials such as sample writings, projects done, and/or transcripts when they are not asked for in the job description? I want to include one of my writing samples in the application, as the job I&#8217;m applying for asked for proficient written communication skills, but I&#8217;m afraid sometimes HR gets annoyed by extra materials. </em></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t provide stuff that isn&#8217;t asked for. They don&#8217;t want it at this stage, or they would have asked for it. (They know that they can request it when they&#8217;re ready for it, believe me.)</p>
<p>You can demonstrate strong writing in your cover letter. And as for transcripts, most sane people don&#8217;t care about them &#8212; and the ones who do will tell you. To the rest of us, it&#8217;ll just come across as a little naive and a little strange to offer them unsolicited.</p>
<p>A cover letter, a resume, and that&#8217;s it, unless they specifically ask for more.</p>
<p>That means, of course, that those two items need to be awesome. So please <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/12/if-youre-not-getting-interviews-read-this.html">make them so</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-attach-writing-samples-transcripts-and-other-extra-items-when-applying-for-a-job.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>64</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
