<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ask a Manager</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.askamanager.org/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.askamanager.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 15:11:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5</generator>
		<item>
		<title>after I resigned, my boss asked me to drive 1,000 miles at my own expense</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/after-i-resigned-my-boss-asked-me-to-drive-1000-miles-at-my-own-expense.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/after-i-resigned-my-boss-asked-me-to-drive-1000-miles-at-my-own-expense.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 14:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[resigning]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5704</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I put my notice in a few weeks ago. We have a slow season come May. Knowing my boss&#8217; history of being overdramatic, I offered to work until May to give her some extra time to find a replacement, as she has to attend a few conferences taking her away from the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I put my notice in a few weeks ago. We have a slow season come May. Knowing my boss&#8217; history of being overdramatic, I offered to work until May to give her some extra time to find a replacement, as she has to attend a few conferences taking her away from the office.</em></p>
<p><em>I was trying my best to be gracious with my exit and was willing to train my replacement. We are a small company (3 employees <em>total, </em>including my boss, who is the owner). However, I run all aspects of her business for her, so she wouldn&#8217;t know how to train my replacement.</em></p>
<p><em>I work in a remote office in Georgia, and she is in Michigan. Now she&#8217;s saying I have to drive all the company property to her office and spend a week in that city training my replacement all at my own expense.</em></p>
<p><em>I am financially unable to do that and think that is completely unreasonable. I already packed everything up and offered to ship it via our company FedEx account. I of course planned to return everything, but not on my own dime. We even have an office in Georgia that she won&#8217;t let me return the property to.</em></p>
<p><em>I now want to cut my time here and just walk away now. It&#8217;s been three weeks since I&#8217;ve given notice. I refuse to go to the headquarters at my own expense to train my replacement. Is that acceptable?</em></p>
<p>What?!  She&#8217;s being ridiculous.</p>
<p>Out of curiosity, is she the type who tried to get you to do things on your own dime previously, or is this twist just a petulant reaction to you leaving?</p>
<p>In any case, she can <em>ask</em> for whatever she wants, and you can decline to give it. Certainly it&#8217;s not normal to expect someone to do what she&#8217;s asking, so you should have no qualms about saying no.</p>
<p>However, I would not walk away now. You gave notice for May, which means she&#8217;s planning to have another month-plus for your transition, and if you cut that short without warning, you&#8217;ll be stooping to &#8212; well, not to her level, but you&#8217;ll be ceding some high ground.</p>
<p>Instead, say something like this, &#8220;I&#8217;m not able to come to Michigan in my final weeks, nor am I able to personally pay for any transition expenses. I&#8217;d be glad to ship things via our FedEx account or return things to the Georgia office. Please let me know what you&#8217;d prefer.&#8221;</p>
<p>If she becomes hostile or continues to be irrational, then say this: &#8220;Jane, asking an employee to spend their own money on work expenses like these is extremely unusual, and I want to be very clear that it&#8217;s off the table. But more importantly, I gave you a good deal of extra notice because I value our relationship and wanted to make things as easy as possible on you. But you&#8217;re pushing me to do something that I&#8217;ve already made it clear I&#8217;m not willing to do, and something that isn&#8217;t reasonable to expect of me. I&#8217;d like to stay here through May and help you transition. But if it&#8217;s going to be contentious, it will be better for both of us if I were to leave sooner.&#8221;</p>
<p>If she calms down, great. If she doesn&#8217;t, then you say, &#8220;Given this situation, it would be better for both of us if I give a standard two weeks, instead of a longer notice period, so my last day will be ___ (two weeks from now). Please let me know where you&#8217;d like me to send these items.&#8221;</p>
<p>If she doesn&#8217;t tell you where to send them, then you make that call yourself and send them to one of the two offices.</p>
<p>But you should give two weeks if you&#8217;re going to leave earlier than your original exit date &#8212; because otherwise you undo a large chunk of the usefulness of early notice periods (which are about transitioning work) &#8230; and allow her to tell future reference checkers that you essentially walked off the job.</p>
<p>The only exception to this is if she becomes outright abusive, at which point you could say, &#8220;I’d like to work the remaining two weeks and I don’t want to leave you in the lurch. However, I need to be treated professionally during that time. I had planned to use the next two weeks to put my projects in order, write up documentation to leave behind, and so forth, but I do have a bottom line as far as respectful treatment. If we can’t work together without the hostility, then I will need to leave now.&#8221;</p>
<p>Good luck, and congratulations on moving away from this.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/after-i-resigned-my-boss-asked-me-to-drive-1000-miles-at-my-own-expense.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>terse answer Thursday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/terse-answer-thursday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-27.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/terse-answer-thursday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-27.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 04:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5702</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s terse answer Thursday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. How soon is too soon to reject a candidate? I have a question about hiring timelines. Sometimes we screen a candidate, and know pretty much immediately that the person won&#8217;t be a good fit. But I feel like it [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s terse answer Thursday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. How soon is too soon to reject a candidate?</strong></p>
<p><em>I have a question about hiring timelines. Sometimes we screen a candidate, and know pretty much immediately that the person won&#8217;t be a good fit. But I feel like it might be discouraging to be on the other end of such a situation (to interview and be declined the same day). Right now, I&#8217;ve been waiting a day or two before passing on a candidate in these cases. Does this seem like an acceptable timeline, or should I be sucking it up and letting a candidate know right away that they haven&#8217;t made the cut?</em></p>
<p>I usually wait a week, because I agree &#8212; many people find it insulting to be rejected so quickly after an interview. The reality is that very few candidates require days of consideration before you decide they&#8217;re a no &#8212; the people who make it to the end-stages often do, but early on in the process, you often know as soon as the phone interview is completed (or during it) that you won&#8217;t be moving the person forward. I&#8217;d love to be fully transparent and tell them that immediately, but too many people feel slighted or argue the decision or just feel dejected (like &#8220;I&#8217;m so awful that they didn&#8217;t even have to think about it&#8221;). So I wait a week, which seems like a perfectly reasonable amount of time.</p>
<p>(And I know that some people will object to hearing that and think I should tell them faster, but a week is not an unreasonable amount of time to hear back &#8212; and plenty faster than many places.)</p>
<p><strong>2. CEO gave my personal cell phone number to clients without my permission</strong></p>
<p><em>I’m a production coordination trainee at a small company. I’ve been working for them for a little over 1 year, and although I’m still a trainee under the contract, I have business card and email signature with &#8220;Project Manager&#8221; as the job title which I’m forced to use. Besides that, I also do sales related jobs such as communicating with some clients, submitting quotes/invoices and getting new jobs because actual account executive for those clients is also the company CEO and he can’t do everything.</em></p>
<p><em>The CEO gave my personal cell phone number to clients without my permission. He told me afterwards and said I should be prepared to receive calls anytime. His email to the client listed my cellphone number and noted that they should contact me directly on my cell especially after 5 pm (our office operates 8-5). I have direct number at my desk during the day, and I’m not allowed to work overtime without prior permission from my supervisors. Is it ok for a company / boss to provide an employee’s personal phone number without her permission? I have a feeling this is not illegal and only an ethical issue, but I’m wondering if there is anything I can do about it. Clients indeed call me on my cell and it is becoming a part of stress I feel from the job.</em></p>
<p>No, that&#8217;s not cool. Legal, but not cool. But if the CEO isn&#8217;t willing to budge, then the message here is that this is a job that requires you to be on call. You&#8217;ll have to decide if you want that job or not.</p>
<p>However, if you&#8217;re non-exempt (and it sounds like you are), you need to be paid for any time spent answering these calls. Start tracking your time, and since you&#8217;re supposed to get advance permission for overtime, ask the CEO how he wants to handle this since you can&#8217;t predict in advance when calls will come in.</p>
<p><strong>3. Forgot to bring copies of my resume to an interview</strong></p>
<p><em>I just had a second round interview today for a position I&#8217;m really interested in. I prepared all night for the interview, and in my rush to get out the door the morning of the interview, I forgot copies of my resume! When the interviewers asked if I had a copy, I said no but I could speak to it and then just proceeded to discuss my experience. Totally my fault, but is this a deal breaker? In my thank you email I sent immediately after, I attached my resume and said please reach out with questions. I&#8217;m so upset I may have lost this opportunity due to this silly mistake!</em></p>
<p>This irks the hell out of me &#8212; at them, not at you. It&#8217;s ridiculous that they came into an interview without copies of your resume, and that they didn&#8217;t offer to find your resume in their system when it became clear you didn&#8217;t have them either. Yes, bringing your resume is a nice thing to do, but it&#8217;s not your responsibility &#8212; it&#8217;s theirs to have it, and they should have reviewed it before the interview anyway. The only way this is okay is if they were pulled into the meeting at the last minute and given no time to prepare.</p>
<p>It shouldn&#8217;t be a deal-breaker, especially since you immediately emailed it to them afterwards.</p>
<p><strong>4. Hiring contact has left the company</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m a retail sales and merchandising professional who wanted to respond to a job posting on a website for a position with a design company. The job description lists an email address/specific contact to send a cover letter and resume to, which I promptly did. Being my investigative self, I looked up the contact on LinkedIn. Her LinkedIn profile states that she ended her tenure with this company in 2013 and lists her occupation as &#8220;Seeking Next Opportunity.&#8221; I would really like to work with this company, but does this mean my application just got sent to oblivion if she no longer works there? Should I contact her via LinkedIn to inquire whether or not I should try to contact someone else about the position?</em></p>
<p>It&#8217;s possibly that someone else is handling her email now that she&#8217;s gone, but you can certainly call the company&#8217;s main number and ask who is now handling the hiring for that position. I would not contact the former employee; she no longer works there and no doubt doesn&#8217;t want to field questions about their hiring process.</p>
<p><strong>5. Where&#8217;s my raise?</strong></p>
<p><em>I started a new job back in December. When negotiating salary, I was told (via email, so I still have it) that it is company policy to provide a small raise along with obtaining licensure. My licensure paperwork came through the end of January, and I have been waiting for something to happen &#8212; but nothing has. The HR manager told me that the paperwork I sent her was what she needed to make the raise happen, but now 4 pay periods have passed with no changes. I contacted payroll to ask how long those changes usually take, and she told me that she has heard nothing about it and that she would be able to make that change instantly. I&#8217;ve emailed and called HR, but she is not responding to me (it has been almost 2 weeks since my last email). Should I try to track her down in person? She is at a different location than me, which is why I haven&#8217;t done it yet, and I am so nervous about coming off as a crazy person. Then again, perhaps I am expecting this to move too fast.</em></p>
<p>Talk to your manager, not HR. Your manager can advocate to push this through more forcefully than you can.</p>
<p><strong>6. Using &#8220;sic&#8221; on a resume</strong></p>
<p><em>I had a friend look over my resume and he was confused with my use of the phrase/grammar shorthand &#8220;sic.&#8221; Two of the companies I have worked for used lowercase letters in their names as a stylistic choice, and my resume reads like this:</em></p>
<p><em>tiny teapots (sic); Anytown, USA; Chocolate Design Engineer</em><br />
<em> Teapots R Us; Anyville, USA; Chocolate Engineer</em></p>
<p><em>I had to look up how to credit a lowercase company, but I want it to be clear that I am not submitting a resume riddled with typos. Is (sic) a dated or confusing term? Is it acceptable in some fields but not others (for instance, academics might recognize it, but it stumped my architect friend)?</em></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been surprised on a few occasions by people who didn&#8217;t know what it meant, so your better bet might be to simply go ahead and capitalize the name. You wouldn&#8217;t do that in an official publication like a newspaper article, but it&#8217;s not a terrible crime to do it on your resume. (Unless you&#8217;re applying for a copyediting job, and then maybe it would be. Fortunately you design chocolate teapots instead.)</p>
<p><strong>7. Applying for a job when I want more than the posted salary</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m interested in applying for a position but the top of the salary range is still $3,500 under what I would like. Should I still apply for the job? Is there any hope of maybe getting them to offer more outside of their top range? (If it helps, the highest salary offered is only $2,500 more than the lowest salary they offer.)</em></p>
<p>Sure, you can try negotiating for more. There&#8217;s no guarantee that you&#8217;ll get it, but it&#8217;s not crazy to try. It would be if what you wanted was significantly above their posted range, but $3,500 isn&#8217;t that much.</p>
<p>But speaking of that, $3,500 a year breaks down to about $218/month after taxes. It&#8217;s not going to make a huge difference in your paycheck.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/terse-answer-thursday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-27.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>91</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>new assistant already missed work her third day on the job</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/new-assistant-already-missed-work-her-third-day-on-the-job.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/new-assistant-already-missed-work-her-third-day-on-the-job.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 17:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[good management]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5700</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I have just hired a part-time administrative assistant that started on Monday. She works for us in the morning and cares for her mother in the afternoon. This morning, I recevied an email from her stating she was unable to come in today because of something she needed to help her mother [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I have just hired a part-time administrative assistant that started on Monday. She works for us in the morning and cares for her mother in the afternoon. This morning, I recevied an email from her stating she was unable to come in today because of something she needed to help her mother with. While I sympathize as I&#8217;m sure caring for an ailing mother is not an easy undertaking, I&#8217;m not at all excited about her calling in after only two days on the job.</em></p>
<p><em>Should I address this with her tomorrow morning when she arrives or wait to see if this is an isolated incident? Also, any suggestions on how I talk to her about this? I need to communicate to her that I need reliable people on my team and right now, I&#8217;m uncertain she is a reliable team member.</em></p>
<p>You should probably talk with her.</p>
<p>While it&#8217;s certainly true that emergencies can come up during your first week on the job, most people are mortified when they do &#8212; because they know that they&#8217;re still proving themselves, that it&#8217;s not a great idea to miss work during your first week, and that an employer is likely to have exactly the worries that you&#8217;re having. So most people in this situation will stress that they&#8217;re mortified, that this is out of character, etc. &#8212; they won&#8217;t sound cavalier or matter-of-fact about it.</p>
<p>The fact that your employee didn&#8217;t handle it that way &#8212; it sounds like her email was pretty matter of fact &#8212; is much more troubling than the fact that she had to take the morning off. After all, you&#8217;d probably be having a much different reaction if she&#8217;d called you rather than emailed, sounded mortified, and assured you this wouldn&#8217;t be a regular thing, right? (You&#8217;d still probably be a little concerned because that&#8217;s human nature when you don&#8217;t yet have a ton of data points on someone, but you probably wouldn&#8217;t be quite as uneasy as you are now.)</p>
<p>So, while you could certainly wait and see if there are other problems, the way she handled this strongly suggests that there are going to be other problems, and so it&#8217;s worth talking with her when she&#8217;s back tomorrow.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d start by asking her if everything is okay, because that&#8217;s a kind thing to do in this context, and then say something like this: &#8220;I realize that sometimes things come up and it&#8217;s just bad timing, but because we so rarely have people miss work in their first week &#8212; their first month, really &#8212; I want to make sure that the scheduling needs of this role are going to work for you going forward. I want to be up-front with you that I generally need the person in your role to be here every day, unless it&#8217;s pre-planned vacation time or a very rare absence that can&#8217;t be planned, such as sickness. We can&#8217;t easily accommodate more than a few unplanned absences per year. And again, I realize that on occasion something will come up, and sometimes it&#8217;ll have the bad timing to do it during someone&#8217;s first week, but since we&#8217;re just starting to work together, I wanted to raise this and make sure it works for you.&#8221;</p>
<p>Make sure to use a kind and sympathetic tone during this conversation. If she&#8217;s truly a conscientious employee who just had bad luck during her first week, you shouldn&#8217;t come down hard on her, and keeping your tone kind can help with that. And if she&#8217;s not really a conscientious employee, using a kind tone isn&#8217;t going to detract from the substance of the message.</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s the thing: If she&#8217;s <em>not</em> an especially conscientious employee and therefore needs to hear this message, it&#8217;s already over. There are going to be more problems with reliability and more problems with work ethic (and maybe other problems too, like quality of work, because they often &#8212; although not always &#8212; go hand in hand).</p>
<p>So why have this conversation at all then? Why not just wait and see if those other problems appear and address it then (by letting her go and hiring someone better)? You could &#8212; that&#8217;s one option. But by addressing it up-front now, you&#8217;re making your expectations clear and ensuring that you won&#8217;t be starting from scratch the next time there&#8217;s a problem. If she&#8217;s not the right employee for you, then you want to end this as soon as possible before you&#8217;ve invested more time in training, etc., and by having this conversation now, you&#8217;re setting the stage for moving quickly in the next few weeks if you continue to see problems. (Plus, it&#8217;s possible that this conversation could lead to her deciding on her own that it&#8217;s not the right fit.)</p>
<p>And if she <em>is</em> a conscientious employee and this was really a legitimate emergency that isn&#8217;t indicative of a problem with her work ethic or reliability, she&#8217;s going to understand why you&#8217;re raising this. (That said, you still might make a point of being particularly kind and welcoming to her the rest of the week so that she doesn&#8217;t feel misunderstood or like she&#8217;s been chastised and sent to the corner, because a conscientious person will be wondering if she&#8217;s just ruined her standing in your eyes. So show her that she hasn&#8217;t.)</p>
<p>If I had to bet money on the most likely outcome, I&#8217;d say this isn&#8217;t going to end well and you should be preparing yourself for that &#8230; but that&#8217;s not a guarantee and it&#8217;s possible that she&#8217;s a conscientious person with one piece of bad luck. This approach accounts for both, but you&#8217;ll know soon enough which you&#8217;re dealing with. Good luck.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/new-assistant-already-missed-work-her-third-day-on-the-job.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>162</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>why is it bad to sound naive when applying for jobs?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/why-is-it-bad-to-sound-naive-when-applying-for-jobs.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/why-is-it-bad-to-sound-naive-when-applying-for-jobs.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 14:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[new grads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5695</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I’ve seen you throw around the word “naïve” several times in your How-Not-Tos for cover letters and resumes. I actually find it a really helpful insult when I recognize things that I’ve been doing wrong. But still, being 22, I am kind of professionally naïve. Surely there’s got to be something beneficial [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I’ve seen you throw around the word “naïve” several times in your How-Not-Tos for cover letters and resumes. I actually find it a really helpful insult when I recognize things that I’ve been doing wrong. But still, being 22, I am kind of professionally naïve. Surely there’s got to be something beneficial about showing my sincerity and eagerness in a cover letter, but I also don’t want to sound like an intern.</em></p>
<p><em>Here’s the more pragmatic question: In several of my cover letters I’ve directly addressed that although I’m technically qualified, I understand that I’m not going to be the most experienced. And then I say something like, “what I lack in experience I make up for with an eagerness to learn.” Most recently I said, “If ability is driven by energy, I may still be your most qualified candidate.”</em></p>
<p><em>Good? Bad? Should I fake it till I make it? Or should I beg?</em></p>
<p>Well, first, sincere and eager aren&#8217;t the same thing as naive. Sincere and eager are good things. Most employers want them. Naivete, though, is something different; it&#8217;s the <em>lack of knowledge</em>.</p>
<p>Now, of course when you&#8217;re new to the work world, you&#8217;re starting out with a certain amount of lack of knowledge, and there&#8217;s no way around that.</p>
<p>And some forms of naivete aren&#8217;t bad at all, and can even be kind of charming. For instance, I once hired a recent grad who insisted on calling me &#8220;Ms. Green&#8221; for his first few days before I could get him to stop. He was naive about typical forms of address in most offices and the fact that professional adults generally call each other by their first names (with <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/03/office-insists-we-refer-to-higher-ups-as-ms-or-mr.html">some exceptions</a>), but that was fine. He was inexperienced, it did no harm, and it was easy to smile at.</p>
<p>But the kind of naivete that we usually talk about here &#8212; when it&#8217;s in the context of Don&#8217;t Do That &#8212; is different. Those forms of naivete can signal to an employer that you&#8217;re going to require more hand-holding or be higher-maintenance or just be more of a pain than they&#8217;d ideally like to take on.</p>
<p>I figured it would be useful to talk specifics, so I searched for past posts where I warned someone that a behavior would seem problematically naive. Here are a few of them:</p>
<p>* In <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/05/why-would-a-company-freeze-a-hiring-process.html">this case</a>, a reader wanted to call a company that had frozen their hiring and try to personally convince their CFO to restart the hiring for the position he wanted. I told him he&#8217;d come across as naive (and overstepping and presumptuous). Being naive about something like this isn&#8217;t likely to get dismissed with an indulgent smile; it&#8217;s likely to make the company think that you have such a lack of understanding of professional norms that you&#8217;re likely to continually alienate coworkers and clients.</p>
<p>* In <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/05/short-answer-saturday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-7.html">this case</a>, a reader wanted to ask for a raise after only two months on the job because she regretted not negotiating initially. I told her that she would look naive and like she didn&#8217;t understand how business works (and that her employer would be annoyed that she didn’t think through the salary before accepting it). Being naive about something like this is a problem because the person&#8217;s lack of understanding of business conventions is directly causing a problem for the company: Now they have someone asking for something totally unrealistic, thinking it&#8217;s realistic to get it, and probably being dissatisfied when they can&#8217;t. As a manager, not only is that a pain in the ass to deal with, but it also makes you wonder what other unreasonable expectations the person has that you&#8217;re going to need to fend off too.</p>
<p>* In the <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-mother-says-i-should-call-employers-daily-for-an-interview.html">recent letter</a> from someone whose mother was telling her to call employers daily to ask for an interview, I said that doing that would come across as naive at best and and rude at worst. In this case, &#8220;naive&#8221; wasn&#8217;t horribly damning (although &#8220;rude&#8221; was), but the point was that she wasn&#8217;t going to portray herself in a way that would be helpful. You don&#8217;t want to take an action where the best that could be said of you is that you seem naive. When you&#8217;re trying to convince an employer to hire you, you want to seem attractive to them. Standing out by displaying a total lack of understanding of how hiring works isn&#8217;t going to be appealing. It&#8217;s going to be a negative, not a plus.</p>
<p>Now, as for your question about language in your cover letter, there&#8217;s nothing wrong with &#8220;what I lack in experience I make up for with an eagerness to learn.&#8221; You&#8217;re going to need to back it up with more compelling specifics, but there&#8217;s nothing problematic about that statement. And it&#8217;s not naive &#8212; it&#8217;s eager, but like I said above, those are two different things, and eagerness is good.</p>
<p>And your second sentence &#8212; &#8220;If ability is driven by energy, I may still be your most qualified candidate&#8221; &#8212; isn&#8217;t too bad either. I don&#8217;t love it, because I dislike anything where an applicant claims that they&#8217;re the most qualified candidate for the job (since <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2011/11/stop-telling-me-youre-the-best-candidate-for-the-job.html">they can&#8217;t possibly know</a>), but it&#8217;s a reasonably engaging way of saying something about your energy and enthusiasm.</p>
<p>Neither of those really sounds naive; they sound eager, and that&#8217;s a good thing. They&#8217;re very different from the examples of problematic naivete above.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/why-is-it-bad-to-sound-naive-when-applying-for-jobs.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>red flags on your resume are turning employers off</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/red-flags-on-your-resume-are-turning-employers-off.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/red-flags-on-your-resume-are-turning-employers-off.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 13:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[resumes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5698</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As you&#8217;re probably well aware, most employers spend only seconds skimming your resume before making a quick decision about whether to reject you or consider you further, so it&#8217;s essential that your resume doesn&#8217;t contain the red flags that will turn them off during that short initial scan. Over at U.S. News &#38; World Report today, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/03/27/8-red-flags-employers-see-on-your-resume"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2095" alt="featured-on-usn" src="http://www.askamanager.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/featured-on-usn1.jpg" width="90" height="60" /></a>As you&#8217;re probably well aware, most employers spend only seconds skimming your resume before making a quick decision about whether to reject you or consider you further, so it&#8217;s essential that your resume doesn&#8217;t contain the red flags that will turn them off during that short initial scan.</p>
<p>Over at U.S. News &amp; World Report today, I talk about eight red flags that will often put you straight into the &#8220;no&#8221; pile without further consideration, including overly aggrandized self-descriptions, no overarching theme to your career choices, bad writing, and more. You can <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/03/27/8-red-flags-employers-see-on-your-resume">read it here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/red-flags-on-your-resume-are-turning-employers-off.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>85</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Caught between invoices? CBAC can help</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/caught-between-invoices-cbac-can-help.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/caught-between-invoices-cbac-can-help.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 13:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[sponsors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5696</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[And now a break to talk about a sponsor… I want to tell you about CBAC, because I recently talked to their founder and was pretty intrigued. CBAC is an invoice financing exchange that provides working capital to small and medium businesses. Here&#8217;s how it works: You&#8217;re a business that needs immediate cash. You have [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><em>And now a break to talk about a sponsor…</em></p>
<p>I want to tell you about CBAC, because I recently talked to their founder and was pretty intrigued.</p>
<p><a href="https://cbacfunding.com">CBAC</a> is an invoice financing exchange that provides working capital to small and medium businesses. Here&#8217;s how it works:</p>
<p>You&#8217;re a business that needs immediate cash. You have invoices out for services or goods that you&#8217;ve provided, but it can take two months or more &#8212; sometimes much more &#8212; to get those invoices paid and receive the cash. Meanwhile, you want to pay employees, pay your own bills, or expand &#8212; but you&#8217;re sitting around waiting for your clients to pay you. Rather than having to wait month after month, CBAC lets you cash in on the cheap cost of money in today&#8217;s market. They&#8217;ll take your outstanding invoices and provide you with the up-front cash you&#8217;re owed.</p>
<p>Businesses just complete a short application and then can upload their unpaid invoices. CBAC&#8217;s financing partners will then compete against each other to provide the business with the best pricing for their accounts receivables &#8212; so if CBAC themselves can&#8217;t provide you with the money you need at the rate you want, they&#8217;ll find a company that can. Businesses have the chance to review bids before accepting any, and can negotiate terms directly with the invoice buyer, creating immediate working capital.</p>
<p>This system &#8212; called invoice factoring &#8212; is a way for small and medium companies to stay in business or expand without being thwarted while you wait for clients to pay their bills.</p>
<p>If you own or operate a small or medium business, check out whether CBAC might be right for you. A good place to start with is the <a href="https://cbacfunding.com/tools/calculator">invoice factoring calculator</a>, which will help you figure out both the cost of factoring and the growth you can achieve utilizing a factoring line of credit.</p>
<p><em>Disclosure: This post was sponsored by CBAC. All thoughts and opinions are my own.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/caught-between-invoices-cbac-can-help.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>wee answer Wednesday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/wee-answer-wednesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-29.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/wee-answer-wednesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-29.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 04:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5693</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s wee answer Wednesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Do I have to provide my employer with a copy of the reference I gave a former coworker? My ex-coworker is in the process of looking for a new job, and she put my name as a reference without [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s wee answer Wednesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Do I have to provide my employer with a copy of the reference I gave a former coworker?</strong></p>
<p><em>My ex-coworker is in the process of looking for a new job, and she put my name as a reference without asking me. However, unaware that she told the hiring company that I was her supervisor, which I am not, I decided to help her and provide a reference. The company sent me a form in an email to fill out, which I did and emailed it back to them. I did not lie; I stated that I was her coworker, which was an option on the form.</em></p>
<p><em>The hiring company then called my company and spoke with her supervisor. My supervisor is now questioning me and asking me for a copy of the reference that I gave to the ex-coworker. Am I obligated to provide the reference I give for my ex-coworker to my supervisor? I don&#8217;t have an issue sharing the reference with my manager, but because I think it was a personal reference, I feel I am not obligated to share this information.</em></p>
<p>It wasn&#8217;t a personal reference, even if you look at it that way; it was a professional reference because you were a coworker, or at least I can pretty much guarantee you that the reference-checker sees it that way.</p>
<p>Your employer is entitled to want to see a copy of what you provided, since as long as you&#8217;re employed by your company, you&#8217;re representing them to some extent when you give references for their former employees. But even if that weren&#8217;t the case, taking a stand on this is unlikely to go well for you. At best, it will negatively impact your standing with your manager long-term, and at worst it could be insubordination. Do you really want to take on that battle for a former coworker who tried to get you to lie on her behalf?</p>
<p><strong>2. Cutting hours for chronically absent employees</strong></p>
<p><em>I have a manager who wants to make it a policy that if an employee is chronically absent, their hours will be reduced. Is this legal? Wouldn’t you have to give them warnings first?</em></p>
<p>There&#8217;s no law in the U.S. that requires that employees be warned about disciplinary action before it occurs &#8212; whether it&#8217;s cutting their hours or firing them. As long as the manager is talking about non-exempt employees (rather than exempt employees, who must be paid the same amount each week in which they do any work, regardless of how many hours they work), there&#8217;s no legal issue here. And it&#8217;s understandable that she might want to schedule them less often, if they&#8217;re not reliably at work.</p>
<p><strong>3. Withdrew from a hiring process but now I want to get back in</strong></p>
<p><em>I had an interview and was told I would hear from them by week&#8217;s end or beginning of the new week. I had a change of heart (or so I thought) over the weekend and considered staying with what I have been doing. I emailed the interviewer and told him this. He emailed me back and was very nice and wished me luck and thanked me for letting him know.</em></p>
<p><em>Now, I have had another change of heart and regret my emailing him. Is it acceptable to call him or email him to let him know I would still like to be considered?</em></p>
<p>No. You&#8217;ll look really flaky, and they won&#8217;t be able to trust that you won&#8217;t change your mind again. You really want to be sure before you withdraw from a hiring process, because it&#8217;s hard to reverse.</p>
<p><strong>4. Listing multiple temp assignments on a resume</strong></p>
<p><em>Since I was laid off back in 2009, I’ve worked many temp assignments. Now I’m having a hard time finding permanent work because it looks like I’ve bounced around a lot. How can I make my resume look more appealing so I can finally land a permanent position?</em></p>
<p>Rather than listing them all as separate jobs, list them all under one heading &#8212; Contract Work, Temp Work, or whatever is appropriate.</p>
<p><strong>5. Changing fields when my resume doesn&#8217;t show my qualifications</strong></p>
<p><em>I am looking to change the field I currently work in. I have the education in the field I want to pursue and extensive experience in the field I currently work in. I currently work as a paramedic and I want to move into health/preventive education and wellness programs. I have an MPH in this field. The problem is my resume doesn’t speak for my true qualifications for the new career move. I obviously don’t want to falsify my resume, but how do I make changes that won’t have a recruiter or HR department just toss it in the trash?</em></p>
<p>Why doesn&#8217;t your resume speak to your true qualifications? That&#8217;s the problem. It needs to.</p>
<p>If it can&#8217;t because these qualifications aren&#8217;t anything you can objectively demonstrate, well, you can&#8217;t really expect an hiring manager to pick you over someone who IS demonstrably qualified. You can try to write a really compelling cover letter, but it&#8217;s hard to change fields in this economy because employers don&#8217;t have incentive to pick less qualified candidates when they&#8217;re flooded with qualified ones.</p>
<p>That said, having an MPH and experience working with a paramedic sounds like a pretty good background for moving into health and wellness education. You might find it useful to talk to people in the field you want to move into about how you could play up the qualifications that you do bring.</p>
<p><strong>6. What should you include on a reference list?</strong></p>
<p><em>A library application is asking for my references up front. When I send the names, what else do I include besides name and contact information? I was going to separate them according to type, manager and professional colleague. Do I include job titles? All of the references are managers, but only one is my manager.</em></p>
<p>Names, contact info, job title when you worked together, and a short explanation of your relationship to them (one sentence or less). Unless the employer has specified otherwise, they&#8217;re going to be more interested in people who have managed you than people who haven&#8217;t.</p>
<p><strong>7. Not allowed to keep employee handbook after leaving company</strong></p>
<p><em>My company just rolled out a fancy employee policy book that looks like it cost some money to produce. Of course it has that section that requires you to sign and return a page that confirms you received it, read it, and will comply. But here&#8217;s the kicker. It states that when I leave the job, whether I quit or they fire me, I have to return all company property, &#8220;including this Staff Member Handbook. Otherwise the company may take action to recoup any replacement costs and/or seek the return of company property through appropriate legal recourse.&#8221; It&#8217;s got a lot of pages so photocopying would be kind of a pain.</em></p>
<p><em>In my opinion, I think that anything I sign my name to, I am entitled to a copy of. But my manager doesn&#8217;t see it that way. Is this legal? I&#8217;ve seen employers try to dissuade workers from copying employee personnel reviews as well.</em></p>
<p>Yes, it&#8217;s legal. While you should have a copy of any contract you sign, employee handbooks generally aren&#8217;t considered contracts (and most contain a disclaimer to that effect). Documents where you sign to acknowledge some fact (like the receipt of a handbook) aren&#8217;t obligational or contractual; they&#8217;re more akin to signing a sign-in sheet at a meeting, which you wouldn&#8217;t be entitled to a copy of either. And companies often do consider their handbooks to contain proprietary information about their operations.</p>
<p>But if you think there are particular policies that you might want to reference once you&#8217;re no longer employed there, photocopy those and keep them at home. Otherwise, this is not a battle worth waging.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/wee-answer-wednesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-29.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>47</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>my employer might drop our health insurance &#8212; what can I do?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-employer-might-drop-our-health-insurance-what-can-i-do.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-employer-might-drop-our-health-insurance-what-can-i-do.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[workplace practices]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5691</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: Yesterday, I overheard a conversation between the owner of the company and our accountant where they discussed dropping the company&#8217;s health insurance plan. (Note &#8212; we were in an open area, they were being loud and speaking openly, and I said hi when I came into the area to alert them that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>Yesterday, I overheard a conversation between the owner of the company and our accountant where they discussed dropping the company&#8217;s health insurance plan. (Note &#8212; we were in an open area, they were being loud and speaking openly, and I said hi when I came into the area to alert them that I was there, so I wasn&#8217;t snooping!)</em></p>
<p><em>Apparently, rates are being increased again, and they are leaning towards just dropping the plan altogether. If past experience with the way the owner handles things like this is indicative of future behavior, it is likely that she&#8217;ll tell us just a few days before the change, and offer little or no compensation to make up for it. It&#8217;s upsetting on a lot of levels &#8212; when we negotiate raises, the owner is always making a big deal about how our health insurance is part of our compensation and how she&#8217;s such a generous person to offer it to us, so I am going to feel like this is a pay cut if this happens, and of course, like everyone, I have basic healthcare needs and want to make sure I am protected.</em></p>
<p><em>If it does happen, what is the best way to try to negotiate additional money so I can pay for my own insurance? I am searching for another job for other reasons, but as the process may take a while, I am concerned about losing healthcare in the meantime. Another issue is that if she really does not tell us until a few days before, as she has in the past with changes like this, do I have any obligation to warn my coworkers or confront the boss earlier so it&#8217;s in the open? I am generally healthy, but I worry about a few coworkers who have some minor health issues that might bankrupt them if they lose insurance coverage, a few who are parents of young kids, one who is a cancer survivor who needs yearly checks, etc. I am sure many of us would appreciate the chance to get one more physical in or one more prescription filled before we lose coverage.</em></p>
<p>Why not ask directly, since it&#8217;s clear that you were right there when they were discussing it?</p>
<p>Yes, it&#8217;s not polite to eavesdrop or comment on conversations that you weren&#8217;t a part of, but sometimes you can&#8217;t help overhearing things, and sometimes those things are alarming enough that it wouldn&#8217;t make sense to pretend you didn&#8217;t hear. After all, if what you&#8217;d overheard was &#8220;today is Jane&#8217;s last day,&#8221; and you were Jane, you&#8217;d probably ask about that, right? (Actually, some people wouldn&#8217;t even ask about that, but they should.)</p>
<p>Say something like this to her: &#8220;When I was in the room with you and Bob yesterday, I couldn&#8217;t help overhearing that we might drop our insurance plan altogether. I don&#8217;t mean to intrude on a private conversation, but since that would have such a significant impact, I wanted to check with you and see if that&#8217;s something you&#8217;re considering, especially since it&#8217;s the kind of thing that it would help to have as much advance notice of as possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>No matter what her answer &#8212; whether she says yes or no or that she&#8217;s not sure, or whether she doesn&#8217;t answer you at all, and even if she bristles at you asking &#8212; you should then follow up by, &#8220;If things do go in that direction, I&#8217;d like to ask that we get as much notice as possible, so that we can use the coverage while we have it.&#8221; She may be clueless enough that you actually need to point that out to her.</p>
<p>Depending on how the conversation goes and what kind of rapport you have with her, you can also point out that insurance is a requirement for many people when deciding whether or not to accept a job, that it was part of the benefits package that you signed up for when you were hired, and that eliminating it is likely to cause significant hardship and morale problems for people on staff, as well as make it hard to hire good people in the future. You could also suggest that people might strongly prefer to simply pay an additional portion of the premiums themselves rather than lose the coverage altogether.</p>
<p>And if your company does end up dropping the insurance coverage, you can certainly try to negotiate for additional money so that you can purchase your own, pointing out again that insurance was part of the benefits package that you signed up for when you were hired, and that it factored into your initial salary negotiations. You might not get it, but you can and should make the case for it &#8230; and if you don&#8217;t get it (or even if you do), then you can decide whether you still want to stay under these new terms.</p>
<p>Given the way the U.S. health insurance system is structured, an employer deciding to drop their coverage is a Big Deal Big Thing to do to employees, particularly when they have employees who took their jobs there with the understanding that insurance was part of the package. I hope you don&#8217;t have to deal with it &#8212; and if it does happen, I hope your boss hears loud and clear that it&#8217;s unacceptable, in the form of people going elsewhere and telling her why.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-employer-might-drop-our-health-insurance-what-can-i-do.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>58</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>is it okay to apply makeup in the bathroom at work?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/is-it-okay-to-apply-makeup-in-the-bathroom-at-work.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/is-it-okay-to-apply-makeup-in-the-bathroom-at-work.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 17:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[workplace practices]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5690</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I work at a large university in a building of about 300 people. There are two floors and I know almost everyone on my floor by face, if not by name. After a long winter, I&#8217;ve recently started biking to work. I bring my makeup with me and put it on in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I work at a large university in a building of about 300 people. There are two floors and I know almost everyone on my floor by face, if not by name.</em></p>
<p><em>After a long winter, I&#8217;ve recently started biking to work. I bring my makeup with me and put it on in the women&#8217;s bathroom about 10 minutes before official working hours start. It only takes me 2 or 3 minutes; this is not a fashion level routine, just some foundation, mascara, and eyeliner. Is that weird? Should I get a makeup mirror for my cube? So far no one&#8217;s said anything and all my coworkers in my office know I&#8217;m biking to work (and are encouraging and positive about it).</em></p>
<p>It would be weirder to apply it in your cube, so don&#8217;t do that. Your cube is more of an open space than the bathroom is.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think what you&#8217;re doing is any big deal, particularly since people know you bike to work. It&#8217;s not ideal &#8212; foundation, mascara, and eyeliner is a bigger production than a quick swipe of lipstick, and it&#8217;s more grooming than you usually expect to see in an office bathroom &#8212; but it&#8217;s not a big deal. Certainly not a big enough deal for you to stop biking to work.</p>
<p>As a side note, years ago, I worked with someone who carried a full makeup case to work &#8212; one of those big metal boxes with shelves and compartments on the inside &#8212; and every afternoon after lunch, she&#8217;d stand in front of the bathroom mirror and do a full makeup reapplication with foundation, powder, eye makeup, lip liner, different brushes, etc. That&#8217;s something I&#8217;d say not to do, because it made her look so preoccupied with her appearance at work that it was hard to take her seriously; her priorities seemed off-kilter.</p>
<p>But that&#8217;s very different than what you&#8217;re doing, so I think you&#8217;re fine.</p>
<p>Anyone want to disagree? Or share their own workplace grooming habits?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/is-it-okay-to-apply-makeup-in-the-bathroom-at-work.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>212</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>tiny answer Tuesday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/tiny-answer-tuesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-26.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/tiny-answer-tuesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-26.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 15:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5685</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s tiny answer Tuesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Company offered me a job, then called me back to meet with the owner I&#8217;ve been searching for a job and think I&#8217;ve finally found the one that I want and luckily it seems as though they want me [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s tiny answer Tuesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Company offered me a job, then called me back to meet with the owner</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve been searching for a job and think I&#8217;ve finally found the one that I want and luckily it seems as though they want me too &#8230; I think. I have had a phone interview and an in-person interview over the past several weeks and then Friday they called and made a verbal offer. They said they would send over the written offer today or tomorrow (Monday/Tuesday). Today, the person with whom I&#8217;ve been interviewing asked me to come in for an interview with the owner. I was caught off guard but offered up my availability. I&#8217;m scheduled to meet the owner later this week. I haven&#8217;t received the written offer yet. Does that mean they&#8217;re re-thinking their decision? What should I expect from meeting with the owner, whom I met once briefly last week, and should I bring up the verbal offer with him?</em></p>
<p>They should have been clearer with you when they called to ask you to meet with the owner! Since they weren&#8217;t, ideally on that call you would have said, &#8220;Just to clarify, we&#8217;d talked on Friday about you sending over a formal offer. Is that on hold pending this meeting?&#8221; Since you that easy window to ask has closed, at this point I would just go to the next meeting and not ask about it (although it&#8217;s still your prerogative to call them now and ask) &#8212; but either way, assume that there&#8217;s no offer yet, since it sounds hazy enough that you shouldn&#8217;t rely on it until it&#8217;s formalized. Certainly in your meeting with the owner, if it doesn&#8217;t become clear what&#8217;s going on, before the meeting ends you can ask about it. I&#8217;d can say something like, &#8220;Can you tell me your timeline for next steps? When I spoke with Jane on Friday, she had offered me the position &#8212; but I&#8217;m less clear now where things stand in your process.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>2. Company removed my name from my work after I stopped working there</strong></p>
<p><em>I wrote a bunch of blog posts for a digital marketing agency&#8217;s corporate blog while I worked there, and now that I have left, they took my name off of all of the content I contributed. I&#8217;m sure they legally own the content, but is it even worth reaching out to them to ask about it? I ask because I work in online marketing and writing relevant blog content is important for my portfolio. It&#8217;s probably not worth it, just bummed to have spent the time on writing posts (10+) and not getting any credit.</em></p>
<p>Sure, you can ask. They do indeed own the content since you produced it as part of your work for them (and in fact they could have chosen not to byline it with your name even while you were employed there), but there&#8217;s no harm in asking them. They can say no (and really, a company that removes your byline when you leave probably has some reason for doing it that isn&#8217;t going to be reversed by you asking them), but it&#8217;s certainly no inappropriate to say something like, &#8220;Hey, I&#8217;d love to show this work in my portfolio. Is there any way to return my byline to it?&#8221;</p>
<p>Keep in mind, though, that even if they say no, you can still include that work in your portfolio because you did indeed produce it.</p>
<p><strong>3. Withdrawing from a hiring process when your interviewer knows your current manager</strong></p>
<p><em>I just walked out of a second interview for a position and decided that the chemistry just isn&#8217;t right and that I want to withdraw my candidacy. Normally I would handle this in the post-meeting thank-you email so that they can quickly move on to other candidates (&#8220;thank you for taking the time to meet with me, but the position isn&#8217;t right for me at this time,&#8221; etc), but there&#8217;s a thing. I work fairly frequently with the hiring company in my current capacity. Hell, the hiring manager and my boss are on a first name basis. When I submitted my resume, I did write &#8220;resume submitted in confidence, please don&#8217;t contact current employer at this time,&#8221; and of course I only spoke good things about my current employer, but I&#8217;m a little nervous now that I know for sure I don&#8217;t want the position.</em></p>
<p><em>Should I email them now with my withdrawal or wait and hope they sensed what I did and reject me? If I email them my withdrawal, should I reiterate my need for discretion, or not mention it and hope they&#8217;ll be discreet (and bite my fingernails for a few weeks)? As background, the hiring company is a very small one, with no HR department, and my second interview was with the head of the company.</em></p>
<p>Well, if they&#8217;re going to be indiscreet, they&#8217;re probably going to do it whether you withdraw or not. So I would proceed however you normally would, and not worry that a withdrawal email is going to send them into a fit of pique that will cause them to tell your boss you applied. Just make sure your email is particularly gracious and doesn&#8217;t sound like the decision is because of some failing on their part. If you want to be extra safe, you could even say that your withdrawal is because you&#8217;ve decided to stay in your current role, thus mitigating any potential &#8220;Jane is job searching&#8221; gossip that might be passed on.</p>
<p><strong>4. Boss interrupted me in a meeting</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m in a job that demands the most of my resources. I&#8217;m a pretty good thinker, but I never planned to end up in business analysis, and I&#8217;m surrounded by people who have majored in this stuff and gobble it up. It&#8217;s challenging, to say the least &#8212; and just like people who speak English as a second language, I&#8217;m often out to sea when they&#8217;re all running ahead. I&#8217;m afraid I&#8217;m being seen as less competent than I&#8217;d like to be. Last week in a meeting, when a particularly tricky analysis was being discussed and it just, just didn&#8217;t make sense to me (and thinking of it over the weekend, it still doesn&#8217;t, and I&#8217;m wondering if maybe I&#8217;m right!), I started to voice a train of thought &#8212; paused &#8212; and right in the middle of it my normally polite boss just picked up and changed the subject. Also, the supervisor has said in meetings, &#8220;what Jane is trying to say&#8230;&#8221; and I&#8217;m not the go-to person for answers. But one-on-one I&#8217;m fine! It&#8217;s scary, and it&#8217;s frustrating.</em></p>
<p><em>How do you privately address a boss who interrupted you in a meeting and it&#8217;s still burning you up??</em></p>
<p>Hmmm. I think the issue here is less about talking to your boss about interrupting you and more about figuring out the bigger picture here. Is this the right role for you, and the right company? If you&#8217;re struggling and not following along in meetings, and your boss has stopped waiting for you to work through your thoughts and you feel less competent than others, these might be signals about overall fit. That means that being irked at your boss is a side issue; the bigger one is what all this stuff is telling you about your long-term success in this role.</p>
<p>If you have good rapport with your boss, it might be worth talking with her about what you&#8217;ve noticed and saying that you&#8217;re trying to figure out what feedback to take away from these instances. Don&#8217;t do this if you&#8217;re not prepared for hear fairly critical feedback, because you might &#8230; but on the other hand, you might hear that you&#8217;re doing fine overall and these thing are minor in the overall scheme of things, and that could give you more peace of mind.</p>
<p><strong>5. Job postings on job boards that aren&#8217;t on the company&#8217;s own website</strong></p>
<p><em>Sometimes I come across interesting job postings on external job sites (like Monster), but when I go to that company&#8217;s own careers webpage, the position is not listed. The external site prompts users to apply through their own system instead of pointing to the company&#8217;s website to apply. Is something like this worth pursuing? Or is something sketchy/unreliable about it? Any idea of what&#8217;s going on here?</em></p>
<p>It often means that the position is no longer open, but the external job sites haven&#8217;t removed it. However, sometimes it means that the company didn&#8217;t post the position on their own site and is relying solely on external sites to advertise it. This could be because they don&#8217;t post any jobs on their site (some places don&#8217;t) or because they&#8217;re not publicizing the site internally yet (because someone doesn&#8217;t know they&#8217;re leaving yet, for example). It&#8217;s hard to know from the outside which it is, unfortunately.</p>
<p><strong>6. Addressing spiritual requirements in a cover letter</strong></p>
<p><em>If a job description (for a religious higher ed institution) lists &#8220;Spiritual Requirements,&#8221; do I need to address these in my cover letter? I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m exactly the religious person they are looking for (although I do think I&#8217;m a good fit for the actual position, which has nothing to do with religion), but would rather apply and see if I get to the interview stage before addressing it (where I would be honest about my personal religious views if they asked). Does this seem like a bad idea?</em></p>
<p>Nope. You&#8217;re under no obligation to address any particular requirement in your cover letter, unless they specifically tell you to.</p>
<p><strong>7. Books for new managers</strong></p>
<p><em>I start a new IT job in 2 weeks where I will be managing a small team of technical people. I&#8217;ve managed project teams and technical teams, but direct people management will be new to me. I&#8217;m so excited and really want to be a success. I&#8217;m engaging with an HR leadership coach. I also wanted to do some reading on my own. I&#8217;ve heard good things about &#8220;First Break All the Rules.&#8221; Are there others you or your readers would recommend?</em></p>
<p>Well, there&#8217;s <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/my-book">mine</a> &#8212; which, uh, is awesome. It&#8217;s geared toward nonprofit managers, but 95% of what&#8217;s in there applies to managers in every field, and I wish I could make it required reading.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/tiny-answer-tuesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-26.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>54</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>what to do when you lose out on a promotion</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/what-to-do-when-you-lose-out-on-a-promotion.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/what-to-do-when-you-lose-out-on-a-promotion.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 14:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[work habits]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5684</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I recently applied for an internal promotion to be manager of the small team I serve. I was unsuccessful. Two questions. First, I was &#8220;let down easy&#8221;&#8211;the hiring manager said things like &#8220;it was close&#8221; and &#8220;we want to keep you.&#8221; But isn&#8217;t being turned down for the role essentially a repudiation [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I recently applied for an internal promotion to be manager of the small team I serve. I was unsuccessful. Two questions. First, I was &#8220;let down easy&#8221;&#8211;the hiring manager said things like &#8220;it was close&#8221; and &#8220;we want to keep you.&#8221; But isn&#8217;t being turned down for the role essentially a repudiation of me? If they really wanted to keep me, I feel like they would have considered offering me some incentive to remain. I am reading it as a clear sign that I should move on.</em></p>
<p><em>That notwithstanding, how do I establish rapport with the new manager, an external candidate who I was in competition with and lost out to? Do I specifically acknowledge that I applied for his role but that now I am ready to be a great team member, colleague, and partner? The truth is that I might have a hard time being an enthusiastic team member now that I&#8217;ve been rejected for this particular advancement.</em></p>
<p>You can read <a href="http://quickbase.intuit.com/blog/2013/03/26/what-to-do-when-you-lose-out-on-a-promotion/">my answer to this question at the The Fast Track blog by Intuit QuickBase today</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/what-to-do-when-you-lose-out-on-a-promotion.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>41</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>how flexible should you be when scheduling an interview?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/how-flexible-should-you-be-when-scheduling-an-interview.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/how-flexible-should-you-be-when-scheduling-an-interview.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 03:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[job searching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5686</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: This has been nagging me for a while now and I just wanted an expert opinion on the situation or how I could have handled it better. So, I applied for a summer internship at a very small up-and-coming magazine and got called back for an interview. At the interview, I was [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>This has been nagging me for a while now and I just wanted an expert opinion on the situation or how I could have handled it better. So, I applied for a summer internship at a very small up-and-coming magazine and got called back for an interview. At the interview, I was told I was being seriously considered and to look out for a follow-up. Well, I did and got nothing for over a month.</em></p>
<p><em>So I emailed, inquiring about how the selection process was coming along. The person in charge apologized for not getting back, said they were very busy, and said on Saturday to come in on the following Tuesday. I agreed. She said she would get back to me soon to give me directions, as it was a new location. Well, she didn&#8217;t give me the directions until THURSDAY and asked me to come in on that Friday. I told her I unfortunately had plans that day (I did, I had a dentist appointment) and asked to reschedule. She never replied.</em></p>
<p><em>This person is kind of a&#8221; who&#8217;s who&#8221; in the industry I want to work in. Should I have pushed harder? Was I too inflexible? Was I wrong for not cancelling my plans and going to the office on that Friday? I just felt like I was being stringed along and not really wanted.</em></p>
<p>Hell, no, you weren&#8217;t wrong. It&#8217;s <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2010/02/combatting-unhealthy-power-dynamics.html">not unreasonable</a> to be unavailable on a day&#8217;s notice, and it&#8217;s not unreasonable to expect a reply when you ask about other open time slots. And it&#8217;s certainly not unreasonable not to cancel an prior appointment, especially when your interviewer had already shown she was willing to renege on scheduled meetings (without even bothering to tell you).</p>
<p>However, what&#8217;s reasonable doesn&#8217;t always mesh well with how employers operate during hiring.</p>
<p>There are an awful lot of employers that operate the way this one did &#8212; alluding to dates that they&#8217;ll get in touch with you by and then not doing it, setting tentative interview times and then not following up with until long afterwards (while you&#8217;re meanwhile holding that time open and wondering what&#8217;s going on), stalling for weeks and then asking you to come in the next day, never responding to your replies to their scheduling emails, and so forth.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s rude &#8212; and incredibly so when you&#8217;re holding time on your calendar for them, and possibly even arranging to take off work.</p>
<p>But despite how rude it is, a <em>lot</em> of employers operate like this. Including even some that you might like to work for. And that means that you need to make your decisions with that in mind.</p>
<p>If you have options and you&#8217;re willing to risk that this is a rude/disorganized employer who won&#8217;t bother getting back to you when you ask for an alternate interview time, then I strongly urge you to continue to operate like a normal, reasonable person &#8212; saying &#8220;no, I have a conflict at that time, but could you do it Tuesday instead?&#8221; and assuming you will receive a reply back. (And figuring that if you don&#8217;t, you&#8217;ll be glad to have screened out a rude, disorganized employer.)</p>
<p>But if you don&#8217;t have options and aren&#8217;t willing to take that risk, well &#8230; the less flexible you are, the higher your risk of ending up in a situation like this one. Should you have to cancel a dentist appointment for an interview on a day&#8217;s notice? Absolutely not. But might you choose to anyway, knowing that some employers behave like this? You&#8217;ve got to make that call yourself, based on your own situation.</p>
<p>In job searching, how much you should put up with and how much you should bend to accommodate an employer comes down to how many options you have. So I&#8217;d start by being realistic about that, and then deciding what you are and aren&#8217;t willing to do from there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/how-flexible-should-you-be-when-scheduling-an-interview.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>mini answer Monday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/mini-answer-monday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-16.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/mini-answer-monday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-16.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 19:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5677</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s mini answer Monday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Coworker&#8217;s loud calls are distracting I work for a F100 company and I was recently promoted from a union to a management position on a new team. Since the promotion, I was moved to a new office floor that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s mini answer Monday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Coworker&#8217;s loud calls are distracting</strong></p>
<p><em>I work for a F100 company and I was recently promoted from a union to a management position on a new team. Since the promotion, I was moved to a new office floor that is somewhat vacant. There are about 5 union employees and the rest of us are management on varying levels. Everything is great, I really like the position, growth opportunities and I still have a huge window overlooking the park!</em></p>
<p><em>My dilemma is one of the managers (who was sitting over here before me) who sits in the back talks extremely loudly. We do not have doors that we can close, so I am stuck listening to her all day. Sometimes I put my headphones on and listen to jazz, but even then she can still be heard. I dread having to listen to the conference calls that are on speaker phone and every detail of her work that she is discussing. Everyone else manages to talk softly and discreetly. Since she is on the other side of the office and I can still hear her, she must be talking pretty loud. I assume no one has brought this to her attention since there are very few people over here. As I type, she has got on another call and she is ridiculously loud.</em></p>
<p><em>I have heard her speak to other people and she can be very brash and almost rude and condescending. How do I politely bring this to her attention without confrontation? I want to specifically address her volume and the fact that every call is on speaker. My work is important too and I need some concentration. My boss is in another state so I can&#8217;t (and wouldn&#8217;t) rely on him to fix this. I&#8217;m not &#8220;scurd&#8221; as they say, I just want to put an end to this and retain an otherwise pleasant office atmosphere.</em></p>
<p>&#8220;Jane, I hate to ask, but I wonder if you could keep your voice down when you&#8217;re on the phone? I&#8217;m finding that it really carries and make it hard to focus on times.&#8221; Or, &#8220;Jane, could you avoid speaker phone when you&#8217;re on calls? It makes it hard for me to concentrate.&#8221; You can probably only ask one of these for now, so pick it carefully.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m assuming she&#8217;s a peer, by the way. If she&#8217;s significantly above you in the hierarchy, you might need to just suck it up or find someone else to talk to her.</p>
<p><strong>2. Adding a spouse or friends on LinkedIn</strong></p>
<p><em>Is it appropriate to add your spouse on LinkedIn if you have no major professional ties? What about friends?</em></p>
<p>Sure, that&#8217;s fine. Lots of people add social contacts on LinkedIn and don&#8217;t confine their networks only to people they&#8217;ve worked with or know from a professional setting. (Part of the value of LinkedIn, after all, is gaining access to your circle&#8217;s network &#8212; something that doesn&#8217;t require you to know them in a professional context.)</p>
<p><strong>3. Interviewing with the CEO</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m super nervous about my upcoming second round interview. I&#8217;m interviewing for a junior position on a communications team. I&#8217;m meeting with a panel for the second round that includes the CEO of the organization. I&#8217;ve never had an interview with the highest ranking person at an org before&#8211;my question is, what will he be looking for? I assume they wouldn&#8217;t waste a CEO&#8217;s time with asking behavioral interview questions. What do you think he will be looking for ? More examples of my experience?</em></p>
<p>It could be a completely typical interview, with behavioral questions, etc., or &#8212; somewhat more likely &#8212; he might just want to talk more informally with you. I&#8217;d prepare as if it&#8217;s going to be the former because most people don&#8217;t do well at that type of interview without preparation, but don&#8217;t be thrown off it&#8217;s the latter.</p>
<p><strong>4. Interviewer asked what my husband thought of him</strong></p>
<p><em>I was at an interview, and the main interviewer knew my husband from a previous job. He asked me what my husband thought of him. The more I think about it, the weirder it seems. What are you thoughts?</em></p>
<p>Yes, that&#8217;s a weird question. He might have been joking, or he might have just been a weird and maybe awkward guy. Who knows?</p>
<p><strong>5. Employer thinks I&#8217;m over-stating how difficult my work is</strong></p>
<p><em>Ten years ago, I was hired at a church because they were starting a communications dept. and I had some Quark experience. I&#8217;m self taught on Photoshop. I&#8217;ve improved tremendously over the years with my design work. It&#8217;s solid and competent &#8212; for our demographic &#8212; but not inspired. A true graphic artist who I respect has judged my work to be quite on par with our church&#8217;s needs, for most things.</em></p>
<p><em>One of our pastors has decided that all three of us need to be cross trained. I was shocked yesterday when he told me that &#8220;due to my insecurities, I&#8217;ve over dramatized how difficult my job is.&#8221; Yes, I am insecure, yet I&#8217;ve been honest about the complexity for people who have never used these programs. I&#8217;m discouraged and distressed to hear this, especially after all these years. But worst of all, is that my word has no value to them. What is the best way to deal with this low opinion they have of me? How do I convince them that insecurity doesn&#8217;t equal liar? And why is it so hard to believe that people who have never done this kind of work might, possibly, find it a touch difficult?</em></p>
<p>Well, first, people are notorious for thinking that graphic design doesn&#8217;t involve as much work as it really does, so that comes with the territory.</p>
<p>But it doesn&#8217;t sound like anyone is accusing you of lying &#8212; just of perhaps being overly dramatic or overly anxious about the work that your job involves. Yes, it&#8217;s easy to be insulted by something like that, but it&#8217;s not going to be particularly helpful to you to take that stance. It&#8217;s not crazy to want some degree of cross-training in a small department, so that if you&#8217;re out some day and they need something changed in a document before you&#8217;re back, someone is capable of at least basic updates. I&#8217;d just look at it from that viewpoint and give up on trying to convince them that they&#8217;re wrong, since I suspect that will be fruitless &#8212; and frustrating.</p>
<p><strong>6. Sent home for being in a bad mood</strong></p>
<p><em>A friend of mine who lives in North Carolina just told me that his sister that works for a company on a commisson basis was told not to come in for a week because on this particular day she was in a bad mood because the windshield of her car was smashed. Is this legal?</em></p>
<p>Yes. If her position is <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/exempt-and-non-exempt">exempt</a>, she needs to be paid her full salary for every week in which she does any work, but if they sent her home for the full week &#8212; or if she&#8217;s non-exempt &#8212; they can absolutely suspend her without pay for a week. I&#8217;m assuming that if was at the point that she was sent home for it, that bad mood must have been pretty disruptive &#8212; that&#8217;s generally not a good idea at work.</p>
<p><strong>7. Will a master&#8217;s hurt my chances of getting an internship?</strong></p>
<p><em>I am finishing up my first year of grad school (it&#8217;s a 2-year program), and I am now applying to internships for the summer, when I will be on break. My field is communications/journalism/PR, and I am finding that a lot of people in my industry, even those at the top, don&#8217;t seem to hold advanced degrees. As a matter of fact, I was often warned in undergrad that in my field, experience is valued a lot more that a master&#8217;s degree. So my question is, do you think a master&#8217;s degree can hurt my chances of getting an internship for the summer? I am already having trouble even finding internships to apply for that accept grad students. Will I seem overqualified, un-experienced, or (at the risk of sounding narcissistic), I have even heard that some employers are intimidated by candidates with master&#8217;s degrees. I would love to know your thoughts!</em></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever met a professional adult who was intimidated by someone with a master&#8217;s, so I&#8217;d drop that worry &#8212; or you risk coming across as thinking that it counts for more than it does. In most fields, most employers value work experience far more than graduate degrees (with the usual exceptions, like academia), and that&#8217;s certainly true in journalism, where what matters most is your ability to write and your published clips. (In fact, had you written to me earlier, I would have advised you to <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2011/12/thinking-about-grad-school-think-again.html">skip the graduate program</a> and start writing. Much less cost to you, and a bigger pay-off.)</p>
<p>Anyway &#8230;being in a masters program, or having a masters, may or may not harm your chances of getting an internship. Some internships are specifically designed for undergraduate students, and those obviously won&#8217;t be a good fit. But your school should help you find internships that you&#8217;d be a good candidate for; that should be part of what your program does for you, and if they don&#8217;t, I&#8217;d think really hard about what exactly you&#8217;re getting out of the program &#8212; it should be helping you become more marketable, not less, right?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/mini-answer-monday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-16.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>117</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>my mother says I should call employers daily for an interview</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-mother-says-i-should-call-employers-daily-for-an-interview.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-mother-says-i-should-call-employers-daily-for-an-interview.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[job search: following up]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5676</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I am at my second semester of graduate school. In order to get an internship for next semester, I&#8217;ve been really working 24/7 for the past month. However, I still haven&#8217;t heard anything from employers yet and of course feel frustrated, as the deadline for join my school&#8217;s internship program is in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I am at my second semester of graduate school. In order to get an internship for next semester, I&#8217;ve been really working 24/7 for the past month. However, I still haven&#8217;t heard anything from employers yet and of course feel frustrated, as the deadline for join my school&#8217;s internship program is in three weeks.</em></p>
<p><em>My mother, who is staying with me now, has strong opinions and thinks I should call employers much more often than I am doing now. (I normally only call them before submitting the application to ask for more details and when the time they promised to come back to me has passed.) However, my mother believes that employers are rather busy and don&#8217;t have so much time to go through every resume, and since I have a not-that-outstanding resume, I should call them more often. Maybe if the person has so much to do and doesn&#8217;t want to bother with boring recruitment, they will just pick the one who always calls them. Therefore, I should lobby by phone more often (&#8220;every day&#8221; is what she thinks is a decent frequency).</em></p>
<p><em>I don&#8217;t think my mother knows so much about the job market, but I do think it makes sense that all applicants are somewhat similarly qualified with promising cover letters, so maybe it is one way to stand out, as it could impress HR more than a plain letter. What do you think? What would be a nice frequency to call up the companies, and what should I say? (Especially if I really am going to call every day, I wonder what to say.) Is it a good idea to be more private and ask the person about their own positions or background on the phone? Or will this backfire on me if the company gets irritated or annoyed?</em></p>
<p>You are hereby forbidden to take advice from your mother on anything job-related.</p>
<ul>
<li>The correct frequency for calling to check on your application: zero</li>
<li>The correct frequency for calling before you submit an application: zero</li>
<li>The correct frequency for taking advice to annoy hiring managers with <em>daily</em> (!) phone calls: zero</li>
<li>The correct frequently for calling employers and asking about their own backgrounds, when they haven&#8217;t even expressed interest in interviewing you: zero</li>
</ul>
<p>The vast, vast majority of employers do not want to receive phone calls from applicants. If they&#8217;re interested in interviewing you, they will contact you. If you call, you will annoy them. If you call more than once, you will <em>really</em> annoy them and risk having your application thrown out or at least marked as &#8220;pushy/annoying.&#8221; And if you call daily, you will be told to stop and will probably never get a job there, ever.</p>
<p>After all, most employers get hundreds of applications for every open position. Imagine if all those people called them, even just once. (To say nothing of every day.) By demanding their attention, you&#8217;re going to come across as naive at best and and rude at worst.</p>
<p>They know you&#8217;re interested. The act of applying conveyed that to them. They will get in touch if they want to talk to you. But you can&#8217;t force your way in the door, and they are not going to be impressed by you continually knocking on it.</p>
<p>Now, yes, there <em>are</em> some employers who are so disorganized that calling them can be enough to get them to look at your application when they otherwise would not have. But these employers are the minority, so while there&#8217;s the chance that you <em>could</em> hit on the random luck to help yourself with one of them, you will harm yourself with everyone else (and everyone else is in the vast majority). So the overwhelming odds are that this behavior will hurt your chances. (Plus, those disorganized employers who respond to random phone calls? You don&#8217;t want to work for them. They&#8217;re disorganized and chaotic and don&#8217;t know how to hire.)</p>
<p>If you want to stand out, you stand by being a highly qualified candidate with a compelling cover letter and a resume that shows a track record of achievement. <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/12/if-youre-not-getting-interviews-read-this.html">That&#8217;s it</a>.</p>
<p>I know that it&#8217;s tempting to want to find some other way of standing out, especially when you feel you have a &#8220;not that outstanding resume.&#8221; But employers are looking for <strong>the most qualified candidate who&#8217;s the best fit</strong>. They&#8217;re not looking for the loudest.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-mother-says-i-should-call-employers-daily-for-an-interview.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>115</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>what managers learn that workers don&#8217;t know</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/what-managers-learn-that-workers-dont-know.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/what-managers-learn-that-workers-dont-know.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 15:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advice about your boss]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5678</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Have you ever noticed that often when people get promoted to management, their perspective on workplaces issues changes? I&#8217;m pretty sure this is because as a manager, you see things that you might never have been exposed to as a regular employee, and you come to view workplace questions through a different lens than the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/03/25/what-new-managers-learn-that-employees-dont-know"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2095" alt="featured-on-usn" src="http://www.askamanager.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/featured-on-usn1.jpg" width="90" height="60" /></a>Have you ever noticed that often when people get promoted to management, their perspective on workplaces issues changes?</p>
<p>I&#8217;m pretty sure this is because as a manager, you see things that you might never have been exposed to as a regular employee, and you come to view workplace questions through a different lens than the one you used previously. As a result, managers’ stance on common workplace issues often ends up changing – often to their own surprise.</p>
<p>Over at U.S. News &amp; World Report today, I talk about some of the most common ways that your perspective might change after becoming a manager &#8212; including your views on turnover, bonuses, priorities, and more. You can <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/03/25/what-new-managers-learn-that-employees-dont-know">read it here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/what-managers-learn-that-workers-dont-know.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>my boss is dragging her feet on hiring my replacement</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-boss-is-dragging-her-feet-on-hiring-my-replacement.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-boss-is-dragging-her-feet-on-hiring-my-replacement.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advice about your boss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resigning]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5675</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: Earlier this week, I told my boss I would be leaving/moving to the state my fiance lives in at the end of our season in May. She knows we&#8217;re getting married, and I&#8217;m a terrible liar, so despite planning to wait until mid-April to tell her (in my field, 6 weeks or [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>Earlier this week, I told my boss I would be leaving/moving to the state my fiance lives in at the end of our season in May. She knows we&#8217;re getting married, and I&#8217;m a terrible liar, so despite planning to wait until mid-April to tell her (in my field, 6 weeks or so is standard for giving notice), I couldn&#8217;t avoid telling her when she asked. Then she freaked out about plans for next season now being off-track because she had thought, that since I hadn&#8217;t said anything sooner, she&#8217;d &#8220;have me&#8221; for another season, etc, etc. I&#8217;m not worried about being let go earlier or treated poorly, but what I am worried about is what came out next: that she might not hire someone until July or August.</em></p>
<p><em>This is why I wasn&#8217;t going to tell her until mid-April, because her habit is to resist believing change is coming and to procrastinate on hiring a new person. (The woman before me gave her notice at about this same point and left in May and I wasn&#8217;t hired until July, and what had piled up was kind of a mess when I started; similar story the time before that.) I would LOVE to have the opportunity to help train the new person, rather than just leave how-to&#8217;s and my phone number. In addition, my boss has a lot more on her plate now than when I started (and we don&#8217;t have an intern now either), so there&#8217;s no way she&#8217;ll have time to keep the day-to-day stuff of my job running in the perhaps months between my departure and a new person&#8217;s arrival, not to mention her time spent getting the new person acclimated to our programs.</em></p>
<p><em>Is there anything I can do or say to help get the hiring process moving? I know at some point it&#8217;s out of my control, but I think she&#8217;s stuck in the &#8220;OMG WHAT AM I GOING TO DO!?!?!&#8221; phase. I&#8217;m already updating my job description so that won&#8217;t be what she&#8217;s waiting on. My fiance doesn&#8217;t understand why I care so much about trying to help her out because she hasn&#8217;t been a good boss but I&#8217;d like to leave this neat and tidy, and a months-long lag time between employees seems messy.</em></p>
<p>Honestly, it&#8217;s not your problem. And even if it were (which it&#8217;s not), you just don&#8217;t have the authority or control over the situation to make it work the way you want it to work.</p>
<p>Of course you&#8217;re right that it&#8217;s ridiculous and irresponsible to stall on hiring someone when if she moved faster, she could have a shorter vacancy, less work piling up, and maybe time for you to train the person. But this isn&#8217;t about what&#8217;s sensible or obvious; it&#8217;s about what your boss is willing to do. And you can&#8217;t control that. Moreover, you don&#8217;t need to. Because, again, it&#8217;s not your problem.</p>
<p>Your obligation is solely to give as much notice as you&#8217;re comfortable giving, to leave your realm as orderly as possible, and to leave behind as much documentation as you can for the next person.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s it. Your obligation is not to somehow push your boss into acting differently than she seems inclined to act. And it&#8217;s not to protect her from the consequences of her own actions.</p>
<p>Now, you can certainly point out to her what&#8217;s in the best interests of the organization and your eventual replacement. That means that you can say something like, &#8220;If the new person starts by May, I can help train them before I leave. To do that, I think we&#8217;d need to start advertising this week or next, with the goals of conducting interviews by X. If you&#8217;d like, I can update the job description and help with the initial resume screening so that we&#8217;re able to keep the process moving relatively quickly.&#8221;</p>
<p>But from there, it&#8217;s up to her. She&#8217;ll either act or she won&#8217;t. And it&#8217;s not your problem if she doesn&#8217;t, not any more than it&#8217;s your problem if she, say, doesn&#8217;t turn in a report to her own manager on time. This is not your job. It is hers, and you need to let her do it the way she sees fit &#8212; even if that way is terrible.</p>
<p>I totally understand feeling some personal responsibility for ensuring that your role is handled well, even after you&#8217;re gone &#8212; that&#8217;s common in conscientious people. But the reality is that what you can and should do is limited, because you are leaving. Get your area in good order and leave extensive documentation, then move on with a clear conscience. There&#8217;s no feasible way to do anything else.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-boss-is-dragging-her-feet-on-hiring-my-replacement.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>we&#8217;re winners!</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/5680.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/5680.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 02:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5680</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thanks to everyone in voted in the Bloggies &#8212; Ask a Manager won in the category of Best Topical Blog, which is awesome. (And which surely couldn&#8217;t have happened without posts like this and this. And this.)]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>Thanks to everyone in voted in the <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es">Bloggies</a> &#8212; Ask a Manager won in the category of Best Topical Blog, which is awesome. (And which surely couldn&#8217;t have happened without posts like <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/08/my-former-coworker-wants-my-company-to-sponsor-her-party.html">this</a> and <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/06/my-company-has-hired-a-pushy-dietician-who-wont-leave-me-alone.html">this</a>. And <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/09/our-employee-wont-stop-hugging-people.html">this</a>.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/5680.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>short answer Sunday &#8212; 6 short answers to 6 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-sunday-6-short-answers-to-6-short-questions-11.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-sunday-6-short-answers-to-6-short-questions-11.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 13:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5668</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s short answer Sunday &#8212; six short answers to six short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Negotiating maternity leave and salary at the same time I am excited about a recent interview. However, if it results in a job offer, I am worried about asking for too much in negotiations. I am 7 months pregnant [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s short answer Sunday &#8212; six short answers to six short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Negotiating maternity leave and salary at the same time</strong></p>
<p><em>I am excited about a recent interview. However, if it results in a job offer, I am worried about asking for too much in negotiations. I am 7 months pregnant and will need to negotiate a maternity leave. I understand taking leave shortly after starting is not ideal and I hope to negotiate a short leave 3-4 weeks, then reduced hours for an additional 2-3 weeks. First, does this sound reasonable? Or should I have different expectations of what will be agreed to since I will only be at the position about 10 weeks?</em></p>
<p><em>Second, when we discussed salary, we were $15k apart. I based my asking salary on industry data, but it was national data and not region-specific. I feel that the salary they said they were planning for the position is still on the low side, even taking our geographic area into consideration. I would be comfortable (but not ideal) taking $10k less than my asking salary but don&#8217;t want to sell myself short. My main question is&#8230; can I negotiate a higher salary AND a maternity leave? I feel like I should only be asking for one. Is asking for too much a turn-off to an employer? I have had three professional jobs and have only negotiated salary.</em></p>
<p>No, you can do that. Maternity leave is really a separate thing from salary negotiations (and what you&#8217;re planning to ask for there is more than reasonable; they&#8217;ll probably be relieved you&#8217;re not asking for more).</p>
<p><strong>2. Declining to extend an internship</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve been an intern at a nonprofit wildlife hospital since last June. I&#8217;ve loved the experience and my end date has been extended several times. Recently, I&#8217;ve been asked to stay another nine months and this time I don&#8217;t think I can accept, as I don&#8217;t feel as though I have anything more to learn and they&#8217;ve already made it clear they cannot afford to hire me as a member of their full-time staff. How do I go about declining the internship without offending anyone? We work in a very intimate environment where the lines between friendship and professionalism tend to blur, but I do need a good recommendation from them before I leave, thus I can&#8217;t afford to hurt anyone&#8217;s feelings with my answer.</em></p>
<p>Do not worry At All about this. It&#8217;s perfectly normal to leave jobs and decline offers to extend internships. They&#8217;re not going to be offended. You can simply say that you need to find full-time work, but that you&#8217;ve loved the experience and hope to stay in touch.</p>
<p><strong>3. What did this interview question mean?</strong></p>
<p><em>I have a question about a question I was asked in an interview. The position is for a mid-career, non-management position, and I would be hired as the most junior position on a team. During the first interview, they asked me about my &#8220;strategic management&#8221; style. I was floored because this position will not supervise others. I fumbled my way through a response where I talked about how I handle projects (and gave a specific example). I know my answer was adequate enough to not kick me out of the interviewing process, but I am unsure of what they were looking for. I am just anxious that the next round of interviews may ask similar questions. What kind of information do you think they were looking for?</em></p>
<p>I have no idea &#8212; that&#8217;s a bizarre question to ask anyone, let alone someone not managing people. (I really have no idea what &#8220;strategic management style&#8221; even means.) But if you ever get asked questions in the future that you&#8217;re not sure how to interpret, it&#8217;s totally fine to ask for clarification. Just say something like, &#8220;Could you tell me a little more about what you&#8217;re looking for there?&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>4. Do the rules change when you&#8217;re headhunted?</strong></p>
<p><em>I was headhunted by a firm two months ago. I told them politely that I was happy with my current job but thanks anyway. They’ve reached out again today, asking if I’d reconsider because they’re being very particular and are really interested in the background I have. They’ve piqued my interest a bit more this time, but I’ve never been headhunted before. In these kind of situations, is it ok to ask upfront about salary expectations and bring up that I’m currently on manager track at my current role and wouldn’t move unless this opportunity (which isn’t a manger role) had similar opportunities? I normally wouldn’t bring this up so early during a regular job search but seeing as they approached me, do the rules change?</em></p>
<p>Yep. It&#8217;s totally fine to say, &#8220;I&#8217;m interested in talking more, but I want to be up-front with you that I wouldn&#8217;t make a move unless the opportunity was really the right one. I don&#8217;t want to waste your time, so can I ask you about the salary range and the growth potential in the role?&#8221;</p>
<p>If they turn it around and ask you what salary you&#8217;d be looking for, you can say, &#8220;Since I&#8217;m not actively looking, I haven&#8217;t given that enough thought. But if you can give me a sense of your ballpark, I can tell you if it makes sense for us to keep talking.&#8221; They still might not, because some companies don&#8217;t, but that would be ridiculous since they&#8217;re pursuing you.</p>
<p><strong>5. Asking to connect with an interviewer on LinkedIn</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m curious what you think of candidates requesting to connect with HR managers on LinkedIn. I am the HR person for a small company and have been doing a lot of hiring recently thus I have been doing a TON of phone interviews with candidates. I find it awkward to phone interview someone and then receive a request to connect and I tend to ignore these requests, regardless of if I liked the candidate or not. If we hire them then, sure, I&#8217;ll connect but I tend to be more selective with who I connect with. What are your thoughts, both for the candidates sending them and the HR managers receiving them?</em></p>
<p>I think it&#8217;s fine for candidates to do, because some HR people and hiring managers are happy to connect with them. Others, however, aren&#8217;t &#8212; feeling that they don&#8217;t know them well enough. (I&#8217;m in the last category myself, and ignore connection requests from most candidates I interview.) So while I don’t think it’s inappropriate to request the connection, I think it&#8217;s fine for you to ignore it if you&#8217;d prefer to.</p>
<p><strong>6. Employer said they were about to check my references and then disappeared</strong></p>
<p><em>I applied for an out-of-state job and had a phone interview and a subsequent in-person interview. I sent a thank you e-mail the next day after the in-person interview and my interviewer quickly responded that it was great to meet me and they would be in contact soon. A few days later the interviewer emailed me to tell me they would be contacting my references the next day. Great news! I contacted all my references to tell them to expect a call.</em></p>
<p><em>But nothing happened! All my references contacted me saying they never heard from my interviewer. It&#8217;s now been about 3 weeks since they said they would contact my references and I haven&#8217;t heard a word. I tried sending an &#8220;update on your timeline&#8221; email, but again, no response. Even if they had run a credit, background, social media, etc. check, I would have been in the clear. What do you think could have happened? I understand not getting the job, but it just seems odd to say you&#8217;re going to contact references and not do so and then completely stop communicating.</em></p>
<p>Could be anything &#8212; they went with another candidate, the hiring process stalled for some reason, your interviewer quit or got fired, she&#8217;s been out sick, something higher priority came up &#8230; or something else. There&#8217;s no way to know. Your best move here is to mentally move on, and let it be a pleasant surprise if they resurface later.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-sunday-6-short-answers-to-6-short-questions-11.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>58</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>short answer Saturday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-saturday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-30.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-saturday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-30.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5663</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s short answer Saturday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Contacting companies in the area I&#8217;ll be moving to in a year My husband and I are in the unique position of knowing that we are relocating for his job in one year. I have begun researching companies in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s short answer Saturday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Contacting companies in the area I&#8217;ll be moving to in a year</strong></p>
<p><em>My husband and I are in the unique position of knowing that we are relocating for his job in one year. I have begun researching companies in my field in the new area and am enthusiastic about all the prospects.</em></p>
<p><em>How should I go about communicating with these companies? Is it wise to reach out with an introduction rather than a formal application because it&#8217;s so far in advance? Or should I continue monitoring their job postings? In that case, what if a job is posted six months from now and I have to explain that I wouldn&#8217;t be able to move for another half of a year?</em></p>
<p>It depends. If you&#8217;re very junior, reaching out to companies now probably isn&#8217;t going to do you much good because they&#8217;re probably just not going to care that much (although you should still try to start building your network in that area). But if you&#8217;re more senior or have a very in-demand skill, it could absolutely be helpful to start making contacts and building relationships now.</p>
<p><strong>2. Asking for a raise when my manager doesn&#8217;t have the authority to approve it</strong></p>
<p><em>I have been working for my employer for three years. I like the company, and for the past 18months I have been doing a managers post but been paid a normal worker&#8217;s salary (as per the conditions of the post advert).</em></p>
<p><em>For a while, this was fine, but I now need more financial stability and I feel this is the right time to ask as I have completed my probation period, and I frequently receive positive feedback on my work from managers and external agencies. But how can I ask for a raise when it&#8217;s not within my manager&#8217;s or his manager&#8217;s control? I know they would both support me with this. But I the impression these decisions are made by our head office by someone I have hardly ever spoken to. It&#8217;s likely I will have to do it via email and I just don&#8217;t really know what to say.</em></p>
<p>You still go through your manager. It&#8217;s up to your manager to make a case on your behalf to whoever the decision-maker is above him.</p>
<p><strong>3. Having mutual friends contact a hiring manager on my behalf</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m interested in a position in which the hiring manager and I have two mutual friends. Is it too much to have both of them contact her on my behalf?</em></p>
<p>No, that&#8217;s fine to do, but make sure that it doesn&#8217;t come across like <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2011/05/bombarding-an-employer-with-unsolicited-recommendations-can-backfire.html">this</a>. You should also apply on your own meanwhile &#8212; and then your mutual friends&#8217; recommendations can be a supplement to that.</p>
<p><strong>4. Getting in touch with a company without using their online application system</strong></p>
<p><em>If I know there&#8217;s a specific company I want to work for, is there an appropriate way to get in touch with HR directly through linkedin? I feel that sending my application into their system through the Taleo site will just end up in my application in a black hole of other applications.</em></p>
<p>HR will just direct you to apply through their normal channels. However, if you can track down the hiring manager in charge of the area you want to work in (because &#8212; in case you are someone who doesn&#8217;t know this &#8211; <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/06/fired-vs-laid-off-and-the-difference-between-a-hiring-manager-and-hr.html">a hiring manager is different from HR</a>, very different), you can try sending your application directly to them, with a compelling cover letter. (You should still apply the regular way too, though, and you should note in your letter that you did &#8212; because you don&#8217;t want to look like you don&#8217;t follow directions.)</p>
<p>Plus, if you&#8217;re set on this company in particular, you should direct a whole bunch of networking efforts to people who work there.</p>
<p><strong>5. Should I reapply for a job after a phone interview gone bad?</strong></p>
<p><em>I recently submitted my resume to a firm and received a phone call from them since they wanted some additional information. I got nervous and said some things I did not mean, which made it look like I was not that interested in the job and may not be able to work full-time, when in fact I most definitely would work full-time if offered the position. The HR manager said she would send me an email by the end of this week if she wanted to set up an interview. It is Friday and I have not received an email. I want to clarify/redeem myself and therefore want to add my availability and strong interest in my cover letter and hence resubmit my resume. Should I just submit my resume again or should I withdraw the old one and then send the new resume (since I have the option of withdrawing it on their site)?</em></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t resubmit an application; that&#8217;s going to seem weird since you&#8217;ve already had contact with them about this very job. If anything, send a follow-up email to the HR manager clarifying whatever it is that you want to clarify. But don&#8217;t withdraw or resubmit anything.</p>
<p><strong>6. Who do I follow up with when I interviewed with multiple people?</strong></p>
<p><em>When you have an interview with several people at one company, how do you determine the &#8220;person of contact&#8221; when following up? I recently had an interview with a partner in the firm and also the events manager, and then I had a second interview with the same partner and a different associate. It&#8217;s been two weeks since they said they had planned to make a decision, but I&#8217;m not sure which of the three to follow up with. It&#8217;s a small place, so there isn&#8217;t much of an HR department either. I was contacted for the interview by an executive assistant.</em></p>
<p>Follow up with the partner, since you&#8217;ve talked with him twice and he&#8217;s probably the decision-maker. In general, the decision-maker is the one to check in with. If it&#8217;s truly unclear (not the case here), then go with the person you had the most rapport with.</p>
<p><strong>7. Why is this offer taking so long?</strong></p>
<p><em>I’ve been looking to move away from my current company and have interviewed with a multinational for a position that has much better future projections. The whole process was dealt with through a specialist recruiter for the sector I work in (linguistics). I received a verbal offer via the recruiter, which I verbally accepted, subject to seeing the specific terms (mainly bonus structure that the recruiter was unable to give me clear information about). That was two and a half weeks ago. Since then, I’ve been given various excuses as to why the contract (or even a written offer) has not been prepared and sent to me: namely, administrative delay and the HR manager on holiday.</em></p>
<p><em>My only point of contact is the recruiter – I have no direct contact with HR at the company. I really don’t know what to make of it. On the one hand, I think that they have no logical reason to be stalling or wavering on their offer; on the other, I just can’t see why they have not been able to send me some kind of document in the last 18 days. Is this normal? Am I being played? It’s starting to put me off the whole idea of the company as I see it as exemplary of how they operate.</em></p>
<p>Believe it or not, this isn&#8217;t that unusual. It takes some large companies a <em>really</em> long time to put together formal offers. And if the HR manager has been on vacation, that could absolutely hold things up. Ask the recruiter for a sense of the likely timeline, and meanwhile, keep up your job search. I don&#8217;t say that to alarm you &#8212; again, this isn&#8217;t that unusual &#8212; but just because you should always keep up your job search until you have a formal, written offer that you&#8217;ve accepted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-saturday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-30.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>should you attach writing samples, transcripts, and other extra items when applying for a job?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-attach-writing-samples-transcripts-and-other-extra-items-when-applying-for-a-job.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-attach-writing-samples-transcripts-and-other-extra-items-when-applying-for-a-job.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[job searching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5672</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I woke up with either a cold or allergies, but I&#8217;ve never had allergies before so I&#8217;m starting to think it is in fact a dreadful cold. I am quite literally a mouth-breather right now. In any case&#8230; A reader writes: When applying for a job, should I provide supplemental materials such as sample writings, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>I woke up with either a cold or allergies, but I&#8217;ve never had allergies before so I&#8217;m starting to think it is in fact a dreadful cold. I am quite literally a mouth-breather right now.</p>
<p>In any case&#8230;</p>
<p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>When applying for a job, should I provide supplemental materials such as sample writings, projects done, and/or transcripts when they are not asked for in the job description? I want to include one of my writing samples in the application, as the job I&#8217;m applying for asked for proficient written communication skills, but I&#8217;m afraid sometimes HR gets annoyed by extra materials. </em></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t provide stuff that isn&#8217;t asked for. They don&#8217;t want it at this stage, or they would have asked for it. (They know that they can request it when they&#8217;re ready for it, believe me.)</p>
<p>You can demonstrate strong writing in your cover letter. And as for transcripts, most sane people don&#8217;t care about them &#8212; and the ones who do will tell you. To the rest of us, it&#8217;ll just come across as a little naive and a little strange to offer them unsolicited.</p>
<p>A cover letter, a resume, and that&#8217;s it, unless they specifically ask for more.</p>
<p>That means, of course, that those two items need to be awesome. So please <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/12/if-youre-not-getting-interviews-read-this.html">make them so</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-attach-writing-samples-transcripts-and-other-extra-items-when-applying-for-a-job.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>64</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>my interviewers want my boyfriend and me to have dinner with their wives</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-interviewers-want-my-boyfriend-and-me-to-have-dinner-with-their-wives.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-interviewers-want-my-boyfriend-and-me-to-have-dinner-with-their-wives.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[interviewing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5671</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I just got called in for my third interview for a political financial compliance firm. The first interview was over coffee at a Starbucks, and they drove to my location to make it easier for me to make the interview during my lunch break (I have a job and they know it). [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I just got called in for my third interview for a political financial compliance firm. The first interview was over coffee at a Starbucks, and they drove to my location to make it easier for me to make the interview during my lunch break (I have a job and they know it). The second was at their office yesterday and I met the team. It&#8217;s a small firm with less than 10 people. And then they just called me moments ago to request that I come in for a third interview.</em></p>
<p><em>Now is where things get confusing for me. The interview is going to be over dinner next week with the two head guys and their wives, and they would like me to bring my significant other (boyfriend) so they can see how we fit in with them. I am so completely adrift in ignorance as to how this goes, it isn&#8217;t even funny. They told me it is down to me and one other person and they need to decide who they will choose. I also have no idea how much this job even pays at this point. I have until Tuesday or Wednesday next week to figure out what they&#8217;re really looking for during this interview and how I can do an awesome job and impress them with my amazingness. There is literally no information on this problem on the internet at all. Please help me?</em></p>
<p>Ick.</p>
<p>Sorry, that&#8217;s just my personal reaction. Plenty of people love this stuff. Are you one of them? That&#8217;s worth thinking about, because saying that they want to see how you and your boyfriend fit in with them and their wives is telling you something huge about the culture there. Do some serious contemplation about whether that&#8217;s a culture you want.</p>
<p>Moreover, make sure you&#8217;re thinking about whether you want this job, aside from the dinner request. I might be reading too much into it, but I get a vibe from your letter that you&#8217;re waiting to see if you&#8217;re selected by them, but haven&#8217;t thought much yet about whether <em>you</em> want to select <em>them</em>. This is stuff is a two-way street, and it&#8217;s crucial to think beyond &#8220;I want to get the offer&#8221; &#8212; because the way people end up in jobs where they&#8217;re miserable is often by focusing just on getting hired and not thinking rigorously about what happens after that.</p>
<p>I realize I just went on a tangent that might not apply to you at all, but there&#8217;s a lot of &#8220;I want to impress them&#8221; in your letter and not a mention of &#8220;I&#8217;d really love to do this work,&#8221; so I thought it worth mentioning. If it doesn&#8217;t apply to you, ignore me and consider it a PSA for everyone else.</p>
<p>In any case &#8230; Assuming you&#8217;re still interested, what they&#8217;re going to be looking for during the dinner is probably what kind of rapport you have with the group, as well as how you handle yourself in businessy social situations, which maybe the job will put you in a lot. (If it won&#8217;t put you in those situations, then this is weirder.)</p>
<p>Dress nicely, be warm and charming, and hope that your boyfriend can do the same. Follow some of the tips in <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-interviewer-wants-to-meet-over-lunch-and-im-freaking-out.html">this post</a>. Don&#8217;t get drunk.   Ask the wives about themselves, and be sincerely interested.</p>
<p>And let&#8217;s hope your boyfriend is down for this. If I were a significant other expected to go on someone else&#8217;s job interview, I would not be happy. But then I&#8217;m a curmudgeon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-interviewers-want-my-boyfriend-and-me-to-have-dinner-with-their-wives.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>226</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>fast answer Friday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/fast-answer-friday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-26.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/fast-answer-friday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-26.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 04:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5662</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s fast answer Friday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Could this GPA requirement be negotiable? I have read several of your postings about job requirements and how often a person does not need to be a 100% perfect fit. My fiancé is being transferred to another city and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s fast answer Friday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Could this GPA requirement be negotiable?</strong></p>
<p><em>I have read several of your postings about job requirements and how often a person does not need to be a 100% perfect fit. My fiancé is being transferred to another city and I found an internal job with my company that I would really like to apply to, but the job description said in bold letters &#8220;candidates must have a minimum GPA of 3.2.&#8221; I have a 3.0 and could easily explain this. I double majored in college and I was just bad at one major no matter how hard I tried. By the time I was ready to give up on that second major, I was too close to finishing it and my GPA wouldn&#8217;t have changed.</em></p>
<p><em>This is one of those situations where since it was emphasized in bold I was wondering if that was an indicator of &#8220;if you don&#8217;t have this, don&#8217;t bother applying.&#8221; I would hate to apply and then be known as the guy who can&#8217;t read and follow directions. My fiancé says that may be flexible, but my dad says not to waste my and their time. Another note, I have taken college courses since then and have made the dean&#8217;s list so i was wondering if that might help. What do you think?</em></p>
<p>Go ahead and apply. Because you&#8217;re an internal candidate and therefore a known quantity, you might have more leeway than someone they don&#8217;t know at all. Sure, they might not waive the requirement, but they&#8217;re not going to think less of you for trying. Believe me, people apply for jobs all the time that they&#8217;re nowhere near qualified for &#8212; recruiters and hiring managers are used to it and generally save their incredulousness for much more egregious cases.</p>
<p><strong>2. Should I wait for my boss to retire?</strong></p>
<p><em>I have worked for my current company for 3.5 years. I was hired in at a lower salary than I desired, but in the interview it was made to seem that there was a lot of room for growth, as my boss is in her 60&#8242;s and said she was on the 5-year plan to leave and put me in her role.</em></p>
<p><em>The company has had furloughs and no raises for 5 years. Last year, I approached my boss with multiple sources of proof that I was underpaid compared to market rates/national average and tried to negotiate a raise. I received a promotion and very small pay increase that was nowhere close to what I should be making for an even higher job position. My boss told me it was a very generous increase and that my job was not as difficult as the same job at other companies.</em></p>
<p><em>Everyone keeps telling me to run from this job as fast as I can and that my boss doesn&#8217;t appreciate me. My boss recently told me that she probably still has another 5 years to go, so my hopes of taking over her role in the next year or two are gone. Is it worth it to stay underpaid for a future position that is pretty much guaranteed to you?</em></p>
<p>Is it really guaranteed to you though? This company has already misled you about that timeline once.</p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t the only opportunity for growth out there for you &#8212; there are tons of others. Don&#8217;t lock yourself into this one. Take a look at what else is out there and see if you find something you like better. You&#8217;re not obligated to take another offer if you get one, but it seems silly not to even look at your options. You might find something you like a lot better, or you might find that you&#8217;re actually be paid about the going rate for your skills in your geographic area (since national averages don&#8217;t really tell you much, as we covered <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-be-earning-more-money.html">here</a>). Either way, you&#8217;ll have a better sense of your options than you do right now.</p>
<p><strong>3. How long will Ask a Manager be around?</strong></p>
<p><em>I love your blog, but how long are these answers accessible for? I.e., 3 years down the road, when making a HR decision regarding someone or something, I may want to re-read, as a guideline, some suggestions you posted here – will I find it? Or could be that you moved onto a new career and closed the blog and access to all the postings? And does it work differently whether one is in the U.S. or Canada?</em></p>
<p>It&#8217;ll be on the Internet as long as I pay the hosting fees to keep it here, which I can&#8217;t imagine I&#8217;d stop doing any time soon. I&#8217;ve actually never thought about what will happen to the site if I stop writing it at some point, but I assume I&#8217;d keep the archives around for a fairly long period of time, unless I&#8217;m sadly destitute and need to spend the hosting fees on burritos. But assume it&#8217;ll be here in, say, 2016. But 2026? Who knows &#8212; maybe by then the Internet will be passe and everything will be done on mimeographed newsletters again.</p>
<p>But unless Canada starts censoring your access to the Internet like North Korea, it will not work any differently there than it does here.</p>
<p><strong>4. Should I put work in my portfolio if I&#8217;m on bad terms with the client?</strong></p>
<p><em>Should I put work in my portfolio if I&#8217;m not on good terms with the client? I am a graphic designer and I want to use some work I did for my portfolio. When I billed my client for this work, he responded first with silence, and later with threats. He ultimately paid 60% of the bill and I refused to work for him again.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m worried that if I use the work I did for him in my portfolio, hiring managers might try to talk to him and he will say bad things about me and my work ethic. We live in a small province and it&#8217;s not inconcievable that someone might know him already and make a call. I&#8217;d like to use this work because it demonstrates a specific skill that I need more examples of in my portfolio.</em></p>
<p>I&#8217;d probably use it, because it&#8217;s your work and it demonstrates something you want to demonstrate. There&#8217;s a risk that someone might call him without asking you about it first, yes, but it&#8217;s a relatively small risk compared to the value of being able to demonstrate skills that you can&#8217;t otherwise show in your portfolio. (If that weren&#8217;t the case &#8212; if you had other samples that would do just as well &#8212; I&#8217;d say to leave it out, but it doesn&#8217;t sound like that&#8217;s the case.)</p>
<p><strong>5. Dealing with sleep disorders at work</strong></p>
<p><em>I was recently diagnosed with both obstructive sleep apnea and periodic limb movement disorder (basically, I kick my legs in my sleep). The meds that I was prescribed for the PLMD carry a side effect of possibly falling asleep without warning while carrying out everyday tasks, which is also a very real possibility with OSA. How much detail do I need to go into about my diagnosis and med regimen with my employer?</em></p>
<p><em>I am a union employee covered by a contract, so there&#8217;s a very real possibility that I am covered by additional protections, but I thought that this might be an interesting question to answer given the prevalence of OSA.</em></p>
<p>You don&#8217;t need to go into detail at all; you just need to let them know what they might notice at work and what accommodations you might need. (You don&#8217;t even need to do that if you don&#8217;t want any accommodations, but it sounds like it would be a good idea to do it so they don&#8217;t think you&#8217;re just sleeping on the job.) Your employer might ask you further questions, but they can&#8217;t do so unless they&#8217;re related to your job requirements and necessary for the operation of the business.</p>
<p>(By the way, it&#8217;s worth noting that this may or may not be covered under the ADA; I wasn&#8217;t able to find a ruling specific to these disorders, and so it would likely depend on whether your specific manifestations met the law&#8217;s standard of an impairment that &#8220;substantially limits major life activities such as seeing, hearing, speaking, walking, breathing, performing manual tasks, learning, caring for oneself, and working.&#8221; Either way, though, it seems like it would be wise to talk with your employer so they aren&#8217;t alarmed if you do fall asleep without warning.)</p>
<p><strong>6. Can my boss cut my hours just because she doesn&#8217;t like me?</strong></p>
<p><em>I am currently working a part-time job that is usually between 20-30 hours a week. It is a franchise located in many states. I recently found out my boss does not like me. Is it legal for her to start giving me 1 to 2 days a week?</em></p>
<p>Yes. Your employer can cut your hours or even fire you for any reason at all, as long as it&#8217;s not based on your race, religion, sex, national origin, or other protected class.</p>
<p><strong>7. Coworker keeps asking me to dinner</strong></p>
<p><em>How can I delicately decline a co-worker keeps asking me to dinner? I have said no many times. I think the other person wants a romantic relationship, but I don&#8217;t fish off the company pier.</em></p>
<p>You can&#8217;t do it delicately at this point; your repeated no&#8217;s were an attempt to do it delicately, and your coworker hasn&#8217;t picked up on the hint. So it&#8217;s time to be more direct: &#8220;I&#8217;m not interested in a relationship outside of work. Please don&#8217;t keep asking me.&#8221;</p>
<p>If you can&#8217;t bring yourself to use wording that blunt, you can try, &#8220;I don&#8217;t socialize with coworkers&#8221; (if the person hasn&#8217;t already seen evidence to the contrary) or &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry, but I&#8217;m not interested in getting together outside of work.&#8221; But if that doesn&#8217;t work, then you&#8217;re going to have to go with the blunter option.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/fast-answer-friday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-26.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>156</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>can I write to my wife&#8217;s boss and ask him to promote her?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/can-i-write-to-my-wifes-boss-and-ask-him-to-promote-her.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/can-i-write-to-my-wifes-boss-and-ask-him-to-promote-her.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[spouses & significant others]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5666</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: Thank you very much for being a sounding board. My wife has been working at her current position for over five years in an A/R and HR capacity. However, she isn&#8217;t trained in this, and she has a master&#8217;s degree in an unrelated field that is actually the primary focus of the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>Thank you very much for being a sounding board. My wife has been working at her current position for over five years in an A/R and HR capacity. However, she isn&#8217;t trained in this, and she has a master&#8217;s degree in an unrelated field that is actually the primary focus of the company. Because she is hard working and competent, however, her boss refuses to see her as a fit for positions within the company that she is actually trained in. She has stated her desire to move into this other arena, but so far it has fallen on deaf ears. I&#8217;m afraid that as an owner/manager, he sees her as a cog that is keeping the wheels turning, and that&#8217;s all he really cares about, especially since her position has seen a lot of turnover in the past.</em></p>
<p><em>As her husband, I want to see her happy, and she is not. She is incredibly intelligent and very gifted, and it bothers me greatly that she isn&#8217;t working in the arena that she is trained for. At this late stage, I would like to write a letter to her boss on her behalf, but I don&#8217;t want to jeopardize her job. Is this a bad idea? I just want to help if I can, but I don&#8217;t want to make the situation worse for her either.</em></p>
<p>Oh no, no, no, no. Do not do this.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s very sweet that you want to help your wife, and of course you&#8217;re frustrated to see her unhappy, and maybe you&#8217;re additionally frustrated if you feel that she&#8217;s not doing or saying the things that could improve the situation. But reaching out to her employer yourself will not help, and it will absolutely hurt.</p>
<p>You will make your wife look like she can&#8217;t handle her own career. She is a professional adult, and these are her battles to fight (if indeed it even needs to be fought at all; she may simply need to change jobs). There&#8217;s just no possible scenario where it would be appropriate for you to ask her employer for anything on her behalf (aside from time off if she&#8217;s in the hospital and unable to call them herself), let alone a change in job responsibilities.</p>
<p>If you reach out on her behalf, you&#8217;ll be effectively ruining her reputation at this company, as well as with anyone they speak with about her in the future. This is a story that would get told and re-told, believe me, and she will forever be the person whose husband asked her boss to give her more interesting job duties.</p>
<p>And there&#8217;s no way she&#8217;ll get what she wants from this company after this. No sane manager is going to respect her or see her as someone they want to retain once this happens. Employers deal with employees, not their spouses, parents, or children. Their relationship is with her, not her family.</p>
<p>But what you <em>can</em> to is to support your wife in handling this on her own. Talk through options with her, point her to sources of advice if she wants them, encourage her to explore other jobs if she&#8217;s not finding what she wants at her current one, and generally be a supportive sounding board.</p>
<p>And frankly, it&#8217;s also probably worth thinking through why you think that you&#8217;d be a more effective advocate for your wife than she would be for herself, to the point that you&#8217;re seriously considering interfering in her professional dealings. Do you not trust her to speak up for herself effectively? Do you see her as less capable than you? It&#8217;s not crazy to think that you might be better at this kind of thing than she is &#8212; that happens in couples &#8212; but you can&#8217;t respond to that by infantilizing her. You&#8217;ve got to find a different approach there.</p>
<p>Those are all constructive things to think about and talk about. But she needs to handle her own career, and you need to stay far, far away from her boss!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/can-i-write-to-my-wifes-boss-and-ask-him-to-promote-her.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>142</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>frustrated that I&#8217;m having trouble turning my internship into a job</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/frustrated-that-im-having-trouble-turning-my-internship-into-a-job.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/frustrated-that-im-having-trouble-turning-my-internship-into-a-job.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 14:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[internships]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5665</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I am beginning to feel very frustrated with the nonprofit organization that I have been interning for the past six months. My internship is supposed to end this Friday and the organization does not allow for internships to last more than six months. This January, I was told about a new part-time [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I am beginning to feel very frustrated with the nonprofit organization that I have been interning for the past six months.</em></p>
<p><em>My internship is supposed to end this Friday and the organization does not allow for internships to last more than six months. This January, I was told about a new part-time position opening up in the department I&#8217;ve been working in and was highly encouraged by the acting director to apply. The idea of hiring someone was thrown around a couple times in December, so I was really excited for the prospect of turning the internship into a job! The acting director gave me the job posting before it was made available to the public, which was extremely kind of her to give me the heads up. I was told that the organization has rules on promoting from inside and that the department needs to follow protocol to interview others outside of the organization.</em></p>
<p><em>The posting was finally made available sometime middle-to-end of February. I had followed up with the acting director a couple days after the submission of my application to see if she had gotten my resume and cover letter through email, because I figured I didn&#8217;t want to pester her in person. She came to me in person and reassured that I would get an interview soon. Finally, I received an email of my interview schedule the second week of March. I had the interview last Wednesday and everything went smoothly and was told that I will hear back latest by on Tuesday of this week.</em></p>
<p><em>I work there from Wednesday to Friday. Yesterday (Wednesday), I went into the office with the intention of asking about the hiring decision. As usual, everyone in the department was swamped with work (and so was I), so I didn&#8217;t have the chance to ask. The department is obviously understaffed, and they really need my help. I am continuously given the most tedious and silliest grunt work without pay. I didn&#8217;t mind it so much until recently because of the long time it took for them to interview me.</em></p>
<p><em>I don&#8217;t understand why they can&#8217;t make the hiring decision sooner. What frustrates me even more is that they had hired an paid intern for a more specific program in the department two weeks ago (I&#8217;m more of the general department intern). Now that there&#8217;s a paid intern, I feel like I am being undervalued for the amount of work I do and effort I put in. And often times, my supervisor gives me very short notice to complete projects because she was given a very short time by the people who she&#8217;s working with.</em></p>
<p><em>I don&#8217;t know if their intentions are. Do they think it&#8217;s okay to wait until the end of my internship, which is this week, to hire me? The job description stated that the position is temporary, lasting from February to June. February is over, and March is soon to be, too. I feel overwhelmed with the amount of work I&#8217;ve put in in the last six months and I am still unpaid! I understand everyone&#8217;s very busy with their work, but does it take that long to make this hiring decision? How should I handle this situation?</em></p>
<p>The problem here is that you&#8217;re assuming that they should make a hiring decision along your timeline, rather than on theirs, and that&#8217;s not how hiring works.</p>
<p>There are all sorts of things that can make hiring <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2011/09/21/why-is-it-taking-so-long-to-hear-back-after-your-job-interview">take a long time</a>: assuring that the funding for the position will be available, resolving questions about whether the funding should go to this position or somewhere else, dealing with higher priorities that come up, interviewing candidates and checking references, waiting for decision-makers to be in town, and much more. (And wouldn&#8217;t you rather have them wait until they&#8217;re confident the position is fully funded than to hire you and lay you off in two months?)</p>
<p>The timeline for filling the position is going to be determined by what makes sense on their side, and how it fits in with other work they need to juggle. It&#8217;s not going to be determined by when you&#8217;d like it to be done. It might take far longer than what you were originally told; that&#8217;s normal. It might stall; that&#8217;s normal. It might get pushed aside because other things are more important to them right now; that&#8217;s also normal.</p>
<p>Moreover, it sounds like you&#8217;re thinking that the job is yours if only they&#8217;d hurry up and offer it to you, but there&#8217;s no guarantee that they&#8217;re going to hire you at the end of this. You were one of a group of candidates who was interviewed. It&#8217;s possible that the job will go to someone else.</p>
<p>You are sounding as if you feel oddly entitled to something that you&#8217;re not really entitled to. That has the potential to make you unhappy in a couple of different ways: If you really believe that you&#8217;re entitled to this stuff, you will be frustrated and unhappy when others don&#8217;t give it to you. And if it shows in your attitude at work, it will impact your reputation (and maybe their interest in hiring you).</p>
<p>I understand that you&#8217;re feeling resentful because you&#8217;ve been working all this time unpaid, but &#8230;. you agreed to that when you took the internship. They&#8217;re under no obligation to hire you, they haven&#8217;t made any promises to hire you, and you knew you were signing up for an unpaid role when you took the job. It&#8217;s not reasonable to be resentful that they haven&#8217;t converted you to a paid position. It&#8217;s not reasonable to be resentful when people don&#8217;t give you something they never promised you.</p>
<p>As for what you can do, go talk to the person in charge of hiring. Say that with your internship ending tomorrow, you&#8217;d love to get a sense of their timeline for making a decision, and whether you&#8217;re a finalist for the job or not. But that&#8217;s all you can do &#8212; you can&#8217;t push them to move any faster, and you can&#8217;t even reasonably <em>expect</em> them to move any faster.</p>
<p>Hopefully, you haven&#8217;t been counting on this position coming through and you&#8217;ve been conducting an active job search over the past few months. If you haven&#8217;t been, start that immediately and move on mentally from the idea of this position. If you end up getting it, it will be a pleasant surprise. If you don&#8217;t, you&#8217;ll be focused on a job search elsewhere anyway.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/frustrated-that-im-having-trouble-turning-my-internship-into-a-job.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>83</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>terse answer Thursday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/terse-answer-thursday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-26.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/terse-answer-thursday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-26.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 04:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5660</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s terse answer Thursday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. My new job just reposted an ad for my position I recently got a new job and have been working there for a week. It&#8217;s a copywriting position, and I was hired to replace another recent hire whose work [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s terse answer Thursday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. My new job just reposted an ad for my position</strong></p>
<p><em>I recently got a new job and have been working there for a week. It&#8217;s a copywriting position, and I was hired to replace another recent hire whose work was not up to par. This company puts new employees on a 90-day probationary/trial period to start and then evaluates their work and determines whether to offer them full employment.</em></p>
<p><em>After a week on the job, I feel reasonably confident that things are going well. I&#8217;ve always had strong writing skills, and my superiors have told me directly that I&#8217;m doing a good job and am picking up on things quickly. Yesterday, however, I happened to notice that the listing for this job had been reposted online that same day. It&#8217;s the exact same ad that I answered to get an interview and this job. What does/could this mean? Should I be worried?</em></p>
<p>Speculating won&#8217;t do you any good, because it could be something as innocuous as someone in HR automatically refreshing the ad by mistake. Rather than worrying without really knowing, ask your manager. Say, &#8220;I couldn&#8217;t help but notice that the ad for my position was reposted today, and it made me a little anxious.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>2. Explaining flushing at work (no, not that kind)</strong></p>
<p><em>I’m trying to figure out the best way to handle a situation that I know will come up at my new job. I’m on a medicine right now – a necessary one, can’t be substituted – that has a side effect of causing fairly severe intermittent (so it comes and goes) flushing on my face and neck. And I have really pale skin, so it’s quite obvious. I’m concerned that it will be perceived as me being nervous or shy, and that will have a negative effect on my reputation and relationships at work. The flushing occurs in a whole variety of situations that are both high and low pressure.</em></p>
<p><em>I’m working on my ability to control this through mental tricks and maybe I&#8217;ll try out biofeedback, but I think there’s a limit to how much I can really control this, given that it’s happening due to the medicine. If someone were to ask me about it, I think I’d be fine with saying something casually like, “oh, thanks for checking, I’m on a great preventative medicine for headaches that has that unfortunate side effect – but I’ll take fewer headaches any day!” What I don’t know is how to handle people who just watch me and make assumptions. Maybe I can’t do anything about that, and they’ll just think what they think. I’d like there to be something I can do, though! I’d really appreciate any suggestions.</em></p>
<p>Can you feel when it&#8217;s happening? If so, I&#8217;d just say something in the moment: &#8220;I think I feel myself flushing &#8212; don&#8217;t be alarmed; I&#8217;m on a headache medicine that causes that sometimes.&#8221; If you can&#8217;t tell when it&#8217;s happening, then why not just mention something to your new manager after you start? You could say something like, &#8220;By the way, I&#8217;m taking a headache medicine that&#8217;s been causing me to flush at random times. I don&#8217;t want you to think it&#8217;s a stress reaction, so I wanted to warn you ahead of time.&#8221; Your manager can then correct anyone who might comment on it.</p>
<p>To be clear, you don&#8217;t have to do this &#8212; but because it&#8217;s bothering you, it might give you peace of mind to say something.</p>
<p><strong>3. Why can&#8217;t I get promoted?</strong></p>
<p><em>I have been passed over for a promotion twice in the six years of working in the same department, and three times for positions outside of my department. I have gotten my MBA, taken additional training, and am in the process of planning an event for a staff of 50. No one has any complaints about my work to my knowledge, and I was one of the top two for a promotion out of 250 applicants. I did ask the hiring manager what it was that I could do to improve myself for the future and he said &#8220;nothing, it was just one of those things.&#8221; Any suggestions?</em></p>
<p>You might need to go somewhere else to get a higher-level job. Your company isn&#8217;t necessarily sending you a signal that they don&#8217;t plan to promote you (it&#8217;s possible that there were simply better candidates each time), but (a) they should sure as hell be giving you some feedback on how to better position yourself at this point, and (b) after six years there, there&#8217;s no reason not to be looking at all your options if you&#8217;d like to move up.</p>
<p><strong>4. Can HR share candidates&#8217; information with a competing candidate?</strong></p>
<p><em>Is it ethical for a person in HR to divulge a candidate&#8217;s information to a competing candidate, specifically give that person your LinkdIn information? This recently happened to me.</em></p>
<p><em>I interviewed for a position and found out it was awarded to someone else on the inside when that person, who I didn&#8217;t know from Adam, went on my LinkdIn profile announcing she had the job. There was no way she could&#8217;ve known who I was or that I had also interviewed for the job unless someone on the inside gave her my information (unless she somehow was able to sneak a peek at the competition). Why would someone do this? I am very disheartened and feel my privacy was invaded. Am I overreacting? I mean, this doesn&#8217;t seem ethical to me at all.</em></p>
<p>Are you sure that&#8217;s what happened? An internal candidate posting gloating messages on external job candidates&#8217; LinkedIn pages seems pretty out there, and I wonder if there&#8217;s some more innocent interpretation. In any case, though, I&#8217;d just let it go and not be terribly disheartened &#8212; there&#8217;s no real privacy violation if she works for the company where you applied (since you have to assume when you apply to a company that anyone who works there could become privy to it); it&#8217;s just bizarre and not worth stewing over.</p>
<p><strong>5. I&#8217;m being made to sit in a painful chair</strong></p>
<p><em>I am a full-time employee for a very large national company. That company holds a government contract that I work on. Recently the government agency we are contracted with had new chairs brought in for our entire office, though no ergonomic study was done beforehand that I am aware of. At over 6’6”, I am a very large parson and my shoulder blades literally rest on the top of this hard plastic and mesh chair back. The lumbar support is also not adjustable so it does not feel right. This causes both lower back and shoulder pain that I have never experienced before. The day after I was forced to sit in these chairs I woke up with continued back and shoulder pain even though it had been 12 hours after I had last sat in the chairs.</em></p>
<p><em>After talking to my manager, they told me I had no other option but to get a doctor’s note. I made the next available appointment and went. They accepted my note and I got a new chair that, while not perfect, was 100% better than my current chair. But after only a week, I was told that I and anyone else who had a different chair due to a doctor’s note would have to give up their chair because the government contractor didn’t like that the chairs weren’t all the same. I was told that I would need another doctor’s note with more exact specifications or I would not be able to get a different chair. I feel that even if I bring in a note with the exact make and model of chair I need, I will still be sitting in these painful chairs for the rest of my time at this contract. My manager, I, and even my doctor don’t know what to do. What would you suggest as a next course of action for something like this?</em></p>
<p>Go back and get the more specific note that they&#8217;re asking for. Yes, it&#8217;s a pain in the ass, and yes, it&#8217;s ridiculous that they&#8217;re micromanaging what chairs you sit in, and yes, it&#8217;s even more ridiculous that they&#8217;re requiring this extra documentation, but they are. So get it, and hopefully put an end to it.</p>
<p><strong>6. Termination if company ceases to exist</strong></p>
<p><em>After two years of active job searching (unemployed), I have finally landed a job offer. Love the company&#8217;s culture (small company in terms of staff, but moderate size in terms of capitalization).</em></p>
<p><em>However, I am a little unsure of how to interpret the following paragraph in the offer letter: &#8220;Your employment with the company will be as a regular employee, subject to your successful completion of a six-month probation period, at which point your salary will be reviewed. However, should the company cease to exist, for whatever reason at any time, your employment may then terminate on simple notice as per the company’s policy.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>So, as I understand this, any possible future termination would be swift, with no notice or severance package, regardless of the amount of time employed with them? I can&#8217;t imagine a 15 or 20-year employee being treated in this way. I know that in Canada, an employer must at least pay vacation pay if not taken at the time of termination. Is there any way that I can protect myself from being booted out should the company &#8220;cease to exist&#8221;? Can I try to negotiate this clause in some way (doubt it)?</em></p>
<p>I can&#8217;t advise on what protections might be available to you in Canada or about anything related to Canada for that matter, but it&#8217;s pretty normal that if a company ceases to exist, it might not be paying severance. I&#8217;d point out, though, that this language isn&#8217;t saying that you&#8217;d have no notice; it&#8217;s saying that you&#8217;d have notice per the company&#8217;s policy &#8212; so to find out how much notice that is, you&#8217;d want to look at the relevant policy.</p>
<p>Overall, though, this doesn&#8217;t alarm me too much. It&#8217;s what would happen in lots of cases; they&#8217;re just telling you in advance. (Maybe because Canada requires it? Who knows what goes on up there.)</p>
<p><strong>7. I put the wrong phone number on my resume</strong></p>
<p><em>I recently realised I made an ridiculous mistake on my resume &#8212; my phone number had the wrong area code. In Toronto, where I live, there are two area codes and I inadvertently switched them &#8212; the last 7 digits were correct though. I know how important it is to have my resume perfect and am furious at myself for the mistake. However, in all of my cover letters (in the body of the email application) my phone number is correct. Would employers who were potentially trying to contact me have given up/passed upon reaching the wrong number, or would they have contacted me by email instead?</em></p>
<p><em>Do you think I should re-send emails for potential applications to inform of the mistake? Or will this look worse for pointing out a glaring mistake?</em></p>
<p>Some employers contact people by phone and some by email, so there&#8217;s really no way to know if someone has tried to reach you and given up. I&#8217;d err on the side of a follow-up email with a correction. It&#8217;s not ideal, but it&#8217;s better than letting the mistake go unfixed and possibly missing phone calls. (I should note, though, that even a follow-up may not fix the problem, because it won&#8217;t be attached to your resume itself &#8212; but it&#8217;s your best bet.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/terse-answer-thursday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-26.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>123</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>restaurant wants waitresses to sign non-compete agreements</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/restaurant-wants-waitresses-to-sign-non-compete-agreements.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/restaurant-wants-waitresses-to-sign-non-compete-agreements.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 19:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[law + order]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5658</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: My granddaughter has just received a new contract of employment. She works part time as a waitress in a local pub/restaurant. I am concerned about a clause in it that reads: &#8220;You agree that in the event of termination of your employment, you will not have any involvement with any other licensed [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>My granddaughter has just received a new contract of employment. She works part time as a waitress in a local pub/restaurant. I am concerned about a clause in it that reads: &#8220;You agree that in the event of termination of your employment, you will not have any involvement with any other licensed premises within a three-mile radius for a minimum of two years.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>Can this be enforced on her? She is looking to work part-time in another restaurant nearer to our home and only 2 miles from where she is now working.</em></p>
<p>Where on earth is your granddaughter working that a restaurant is using contracts with employees, let along bothering with a non-compete clause?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s very rare in the U.S. for employees to have contracts at all, and even rarer for waitresses.</p>
<p>In any case, the non-compete clause probably isn&#8217;t enforceable, because courts generally rule that the employer must show that the restriction is reasonable and necessary to protect them against unfair competition. That&#8217;s unlikely to apply to a waitress. Additionally, if she was already working there when she was asked to sign this contract &#8211; as opposed to the contract being presented as something she needed to sign before she can be hired &#8212; then most courts will invalidate the agreement because there was no &#8220;consideration&#8221; to her for signing it (meaning some payment or other benefit to her).</p>
<p>Your granddaughter should ask her manager why they&#8217;re asking this of her, and why they&#8217;d object to her waitressing somewhere else in the future. And if the manager holds firm, then she&#8217;ll need to decide whether she wants to take a stand, or just sign it with the intent of ignoring it and assuming it&#8217;s unenforceable.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/restaurant-wants-waitresses-to-sign-non-compete-agreements.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>73</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>my mentor might get demoted or fired &#8212; and I might be offered her job</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-mentor-might-get-demoted-or-fired-and-i-might-be-offered-her-job.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-mentor-might-get-demoted-or-fired-and-i-might-be-offered-her-job.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 16:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advice about your boss]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5655</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I&#8217;ve been working for the same company for about 3.5 years now, but a year and a half ago I was promoted to a more interesting, more lucrative position. This job is still at the assistant level, but I&#8217;ve been fortunate enough to be working under a woman who has been very [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve been working for the same company for about 3.5 years now, but a year and a half ago I was promoted to a more interesting, more lucrative position. This job is still at the assistant level, but I&#8217;ve been fortunate enough to be working under a woman who has been very kind, generous, and helpful. She has really been more of a mentor than a boss. She has given me opportunities to try things that were above my pay grade, and I&#8217;m proud to say that I&#8217;ve really flourished in the role. I get things done well, on time, and under budget.</em></p>
<p><em>But then I had a meeting with the executives about a week ago. My mentor and I have contracts that are up for renewal at the end of the month, and they told me in this meeting that they&#8217;re so impressed with how I&#8217;ve grown in the position (and they said they&#8217;re concerned about my mentor&#8217;s performance) that they&#8217;re seriously considering giving me her job and only hiring her back at part-time &#8230; or possibly not at all.</em></p>
<p><em>So &#8230; do I mention this to my mentor? She is my friend and my confidante, but since everything said in this meeting was vague and nothing official was offered, I feel uneasy saying anything at all. Plus what if the execs change their minds? They said they were going to have a meeting with my mentor, but it&#8217;s been over a week and nothing has been scheduled.</em></p>
<p><em>WHAT DO I DO?! Do I warn her? Do I sit tight? And if they offer me the job, do I take it? It would be a huge step up for my career, but I don&#8217;t want to burn a bridge with my mentor.</em></p>
<p>They put you in a tough position by sharing their thoughts with you before they&#8217;ve made any decisions. And if they end up keeping her after all, you&#8217;ll now know things you probably shouldn&#8217;t really know about your boss (the performance problems and how close she came to losing her job). Plus, they&#8217;ve risked you getting your hopes up about getting promoted, which really isn&#8217;t a smart thing for them to do in case it falls through &#8230; unless they&#8217;re actually already planning on all of this and only presented it as a &#8220;maybe&#8221; to you to test the waters and gauge your interest.</p>
<p>In any case &#8230; It doesn&#8217;t sound like you have permission to share what you were told with your mentor. It sounds like you were told in confidence and you&#8217;re expected to keep it private. That doesn&#8217;t mean that you&#8217;re bound by that, of course; you could still decide to tell her. But you&#8217;d need to be aware that you&#8217;d be breaking a confidence and possibly harming your own prospects with your employer, because if they find out you shared this with her, they&#8217;re likely to question your ability to be discreet with information in the future (which is usually a huge strike against someone when they&#8217;re being considered for a management role, now or in the future). And you might think that it&#8217;s unlikely that it will get back to them, but if your manager feels compelled to talk to them about what she learns from you, you probably won&#8217;t be able to contain it.</p>
<p>So whether or not to tell comes down in part to whether you value your relationship with your mentor over your own career prospects with this company, and in part to how seriously you take confidences that are shared with you in the expectation that you&#8217;ll keep them to yourself.</p>
<p>If it sounds like I&#8217;m pushing you toward the path of not sharing it &#8230; I am. That&#8217;s because part of having a job is handling sensitive information discreetly and not sharing things that it&#8217;s clear the people who sign your paychecks didn&#8217;t mean for you to share, even <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2009/07/should-i-warn-my-friend-hes-about-to-be.html">when it&#8217;s hard</a>.</p>
<p>As for whether to take the job if it&#8217;s offered to you, would you accept it if you didn&#8217;t feel it was being taken &#8220;from&#8221; your mentor? If so, a good mentor wouldn&#8217;t want you to turn it down. She might feel weird about it, but she wouldn&#8217;t expect you to say no simply as an act of solidarity with her. And if she did, then she&#8217;s not much of a mentor.</p>
<p>(Also, keep in mind that you&#8217;re not taking the job from her; she&#8217;s being removed from the job because of performance concerns. You&#8217;re not lobbying to steal her job away; you&#8217;re a bystander.)</p>
<p>But that&#8217;s just an abstract argument. If despite this you&#8217;d feel like a traitor or won&#8217;t be able to sleep soundly at night if you accept the job, then it&#8217;s your prerogative to decide that it&#8217;s not for you. You&#8217;re allowed to turn down a promotion, although doing it can sometimes limit you in undesirable ways in your present company. But you&#8217;re still allowed to.</p>
<p>(However, keep in mind that turning the job down might not preserve your mentor&#8217;s job; it might mean that your company brings in someone else instead.)</p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t an easy situation. As you sort through it, keep in mind that the business conventions governing these situations are different than social/friendship conventions, but remember too that it&#8217;s fine to make the decision based on what you can live with.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-mentor-might-get-demoted-or-fired-and-i-might-be-offered-her-job.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>are you cut out to be a manager?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/are-you-cut-out-to-be-a-manager.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/are-you-cut-out-to-be-a-manager.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 15:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[good management]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5654</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;re thinking about taking on a management role, before you make the move, make sure you’ve thought through what it really takes to be a manager. Parts of the job are painfully hard, and it&#8217;s not for everyone. Over at U.S. News &#38; World Report today, I talk about some key questions you should [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/03/20/are-you-cut-out-to-be-a-boss"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2095" alt="featured-on-usn" src="http://www.askamanager.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/featured-on-usn1.jpg" width="90" height="60" /></a>If you&#8217;re thinking about taking on a management role, before you make the move, make sure you’ve thought through what it really takes to be a manager. Parts of the job are painfully hard, and it&#8217;s not for everyone.</p>
<p>Over at U.S. News &amp; World Report today, I talk about some key questions you should ask yourself before signing up to manage, including whether you&#8217;re comfortable hiring and managing people smarter than you, whether you know how to get things done without resorting to fear tactics, whether you deliver difficult criticism, and more. You can <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/03/20/are-you-cut-out-to-be-a-boss">read it here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/are-you-cut-out-to-be-a-manager.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>55</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>wee answer Wednesday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/wee-answer-wednesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-28.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/wee-answer-wednesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-28.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 04:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5652</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s wee answer Wednesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. I&#8217;m quitting, but my employer wants me to stay on to finish a project I&#8217;ve been reading your blog for about two years. Your advice helped me land my current position, and guided me through finding a new position which [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s wee answer Wednesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. I&#8217;m quitting, but my employer wants me to stay on to finish a project</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve been reading your blog for about two years. Your advice helped me land my current position, and guided me through finding a new position which I officially accepted last week. I turned in my two weeks notice on Wednesday, and on Thursday my boss asked me to stay on to finish my current project (through June 30). I spoke with my boss and HR in a meeting on Friday where they said they&#8217;d like to break down my current salaried pay into an hourly figure and pay me as an hourly, part-time employee. I told them I&#8217;d feel more comfortable terminating my employment and becoming a contractor, creating objectives and being paid a lump sum for finishing the project.</em></p>
<p><em>I should note that I&#8217;m leaving because my boss is a complete jerk. He became my boss midway through this project and I&#8217;ve been miserable ever since. He&#8217;s very much a &#8220;my way or the highway&#8221; and take credit for everyone else&#8217;s work-type of leader. I don&#8217;t want to continue to be under his constant control. I would love to see this project through &#8212; but how do I get my old employer to see that letting me become a contractor is the way to go? I can do everything I was doing from home, in the evenings or weekends. My new job is 4 10-hour days, so, yes, I could come in on Fridays but I don&#8217;t want to. My boss has already said how appreciative he is of me staying on board to wrap this up &#8212; I want to but not on their terms. Any advice?</em></p>
<p>Frankly, I&#8217;d urge you to seriously consider <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/08/my-boss-wants-me-to-do-contract-work-after-i-move-to-a-new-job.html">not doing it at all</a>. You need to have all your focus on your new job, and not deal with the distractions (and apparently serious hassles) of the old. You&#8217;re finally getting away from your horrible boss &#8212; why drag out the relationship instead of having a clean break?</p>
<p>But if you still want to do it, then just lay out the terms that you&#8217;re willing to do it on: You&#8217;ll do it as a contractor, working from home. If they refuse, then walk away. They can&#8217;t make you do it, and whatever desire you have to see out your project is going to fade dramatically after a week or two at your new job, believe me.</p>
<p><strong>2. Interviewer asked me to call her, but I can&#8217;t reach her</strong></p>
<p><em>Two days ago, I had a phone interview that apparently went very well. The woman I interviewed with stated she would get back to me in about a week about the next steps in the hiring process. Later that day, I sent her a thank you email and expressed my continued interest in the position. She emailed back right away and stated she had a great time talking to me and wanting to schedule an in-person interview. Her instructions stated to call her when I had a moment to schedule an in-person interview. Instantly, I called her and had to leave a voicemail. I thought I would hear back from her in a business day, but I have not. I do not want to bug her with numerous phone calls and emails (especially, since her instructions ask that I call her). How long would you suggest I wait to contact her again and in what form?</em></p>
<p>Wait two business days from your last call and call again. It&#8217;s also fine to send a response to her email letting her know that you weren&#8217;t able to reach her and asking her to call whenever it&#8217;s most convenient for her (just as you&#8217;d probably do with any other business contact &#8212; no need to treat this one more gingerly just because it&#8217;s for an interview).</p>
<p><strong>3. When you don&#8217;t know a candidate&#8217;s sex ahead of time</strong></p>
<p><em>I have a issue that&#8217;s arisen a few times in the past few weeks. I&#8217;m working in HR/hiring right now, and the company I&#8217;m working for is going through a rapid expansion &#8212; tons of interviews and new hires happening. There have been a handful of candidates invited for interviews where we can&#8217;t tell the gender of the person beforehand through email/resume screens. It&#8217;s not a major problem &#8212; it&#8217;s just disconcerting to the interviewers when they were expecting a male voice and instead hear a female. This mostly has happened with gender-neutral or &#8220;unique&#8221; names. What are your thoughts on this? I don&#8217;t want to presume to assign a sex to a person, but I also want to prep my coworkers adequately!</em></p>
<p>I&#8217;d say to let your coworkers deal with it and not worry about prepping them. First, there&#8217;s really no way that you can (I mean, I suppose you could try Googling the person to see if there&#8217;s something out there that would tell you, but &#8230; is it really worth the trouble?), and second, it really shouldn&#8217;t matter. I suppose that if it&#8217;s a gender-neutral name, you could note for the interviewer that you&#8217;re not sure if the candidate is a man or a woman, but it raises the question of why people need to know. I do know that you&#8217;re not saying that it&#8217;s important info, but just that it can be a little weird to hear a very different voice than what you were expecting. But your colleagues should be able to take the mild surprise of realizing they got it wrong and should be able to recover immediately. (If they can&#8217;t, though, that&#8217;s a different issue.)</p>
<p><strong>4. Taking time off to study for a professional exam</strong></p>
<p><em>It&#8217;s been a month now since I was &#8220;let go&#8221; from a temp assignment. I went through my ups and downs and tried looking for work again. I started looking at the bigger picture of the career goals I want to achieve and have formulated a plan. The first step is taking a professional exam. I also finally feel like I&#8217;m in a position to relax and take the time off from the stress of looking for work.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve learned the hard way that multitasking isn&#8217;t my strong suit. So I want ot take time off from working to study for the exam. I&#8217;m just wondering, how would this look to future employers? That while I wasn&#8217;t working I was studying for an exam? Is it something that&#8217;s not looked down upon?</em></p>
<p>It depends on how intensive studying for that particular exam is known to be. If it&#8217;s something like the CPA exam or the bar, then you can probably get away with saying that. If it&#8217;s less intensive, employers are more likely to wonder why you needed so much time off for something that most people do while they&#8217;re working.</p>
<p><strong>5. Quoting from a job ad in your cover letter</strong></p>
<p><em>In a cover letter, is it okay to quote from the posting of the position I&#8217;m applying to? I don&#8217;t want to come across as unoriginal or, worse, as plagiarizing, but if they use a particular wording that really does describe me or the work I do, can I go ahead and use it? Or is it going to be a big strike against me?</em></p>
<p>I&#8217;d do it only very sparingly, if at all. You&#8217;re generally better off describing yourself in your own words &#8230; at very clearly acknowledging that you&#8217;re quoting them (for instance, &#8220;you wrote that you&#8217;re looking for someone maniacally obsessed with clowns, and I&#8217;m exactly that&#8221;).</p>
<p><strong>6. Asking for a raise when the company is being sold</strong></p>
<p><em>I work at a very small company (about 20 people, including freelancers). The owner has been working in this industry for many many years and is well over retirement age. Myself and many of the coworkers have picked up on subtle clues from her (guiding people on &#8220;tours&#8221; of the office–we never have people from outside come here–and her introducing us to them but not them to us) and have found other information on the internet to confirm that the business is up for sale. People have found out that &#8220;due process&#8221; ends today, and the closing could be any time within the next month. The owner has not directly told anyone about this information.</em></p>
<p><em>My question is about when I should be asking for a raise. I am coming up on the 2-year anniversary of my start date (June). I believe the work I have done and the accomplishments I have achieved merit a raise. However, I don&#8217;t know when I should ask for it. Should I be asking for it now? I am hesitant to do it now because it may seem odd that I didn&#8217;t wait the 2.5 months until June. But I&#8217;m worried that if I don&#8217;t do it now, the new owners will see it as me trying to take advantage of the situation. or they could think &#8220;well if the old owner hasn&#8217;t given her a raise, why should we?&#8221; I also think that if I wait, they won&#8217;t know anything about my work and accomplishments and will say no because I have not proven myself to them yet. Is it customary for new owners to discuss previous work with the old owner to decide on issues like this?</em></p>
<p>Go ahead and ask now. The worst that can happen is that you&#8217;ll be told no.</p>
<p>Be prepared for the fact that she may be less inclined to give you a raise now because retaining good employees isn&#8217;t going to be her problem for much longer, but again, you lose nothing by asking.</p>
<p>Whether she&#8217;ll advise new owners on this kind of thing as part of the handover very much depends on the situation, but in general new owners like to make their own decisions on this type of thing.</p>
<p><strong>7. Getting online marketing jobs without online marketing experience</strong></p>
<p>I<em>n recent years, social and digital marketing has become a key component of many job requirements in public relations. My problem is that I have worked for organizations that actively refused to enhance their digital footprint. I kept up on trends by reading the books and attending the professional development sessions. I&#8217;m preparing to apply for a job that I&#8217;d be perfect for, but I don&#8217;t have any direct social or digital marketing experience they want. How do I address this in my resume and cover letter?</em></p>
<p>You might think you&#8217;d be perfect for these jobs, but &#8212; well, <em>they&#8217;re</em> less likely to think you&#8217;re perfect since you don&#8217;t have actual experience doing the work. And when you&#8217;re up against well-qualified candidates who do have the experience, employers won&#8217;t have much incentive to hire you. I&#8217;d try to get that experience first &#8212; volunteer for a few organizations who want help in this area and start building up a portfolio of work and accomplishments that you can point to.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/wee-answer-wednesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-28.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>108</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>my coworker&#8217;s husband hangs out in our office every afternoon &#8212; and cuddles with her</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/coworkers-husband-hangs-out-in-our-office-every-afternoon.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/coworkers-husband-hangs-out-in-our-office-every-afternoon.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advice about your coworkers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5650</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: My coworker&#8217;s husband comes in every day between 3:30 and 4:30, depending on when he gets out of work, and sits in our open concept, 468 square foot, 6-person office until my coworker is ready to leave around 5. They do not ride into work together. Sometimes he stands beside her hugging [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>My coworker&#8217;s husband comes in every day between 3:30 and 4:30, depending on when he gets out of work, and sits in our open concept, 468 square foot, 6-person office until my coworker is ready to leave around 5. They do not ride into work together.</em></p>
<p><em>Sometimes he stands beside her hugging her while she works, and they are always whispering to each other. My desk faces them and it’s distracting to me. Am I wrong or is this inappropriate, and if so how can I ask my coworker or my boss to reduce this visitation?</em></p>
<p>Eeuwww. Yes, it&#8217;s totally inappropriate.</p>
<p>Honestly, it would be a little weird to have this guy in your office for this long every afternoon even if he were just sitting quietly in a corner, keeping to himself. But the whispering and the extended hugging? And she&#8217;s supposed to be <em>working</em> while he snuggles with her? It&#8217;s not professional and it&#8217;s not considerate of others. (Or of basic decorum, for that matter. And it&#8217;s making my skin crawl a little.)</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t imagine why your boss is okay with your coworker being distracted that way or with the rest of you dealing with the distraction they pose. Does she know it&#8217;s happening with this frequency?</p>
<p>In any case, if you&#8217;re up for it, you could certainly say something to your coworker, her husband, or her boss, although how it goes over with the first two will depend entirely on how reasonable each is, and how it goes over with your boss will depend on how savvy she is about handling stuff like this.</p>
<p>To the coworker: &#8220;Do you think Frank could sit over there (somewhere far from the rest of you) when he meets you here, or even wait downstairs some of the time? I end up getting distracted when he comes in and talks to you every afternoon, and I&#8217;ve noticed it makes it harder for me to focus.&#8221;</p>
<p>To the husband: &#8220;Hey, Frank, could you wait over there? It&#8217;s pretty distracting to have you canoodling with Jane while we&#8217;re working. Thanks.&#8221; (I actually prefer this option to saying something to the coworker, since the husband is the one committing the actions you object to &#8230; although ultimately your coworker is the one responsible for not allowing visitors to interfere with the rest of you.)</p>
<p>To your boss: &#8220;For the last few months, Jane&#8217;s husband has been meeting her at work every afternoon and spending up to 90 minutes hanging out in her space while he waits for her to be ready to leave at 5. It&#8217;s pretty distracting, because he stands there whispering and hugging her while the rest of us are working. I feel awkward saying anything to them because I don&#8217;t want to strain my relationship with Jane, but it really is distracting and making it hard to focus. I wouldn&#8217;t care if it were occasional, but it&#8217;s every day. Could you maybe ask her to have him wait for her somewhere else so it&#8217;s not interfering with our work?&#8221;</p>
<p>If you doubt that speaking to your coworker or her husband will have any effect and so you know you&#8217;ll end up needing to say something to your manager next, it might be better to just skip that and jump straight to your manager &#8212; since otherwise it&#8217;s going to be quite clear to your coworker who instigated the manager&#8217;s intervention.</p>
<p>If that intervention comes, of course. Some managers are laissez-faire to the point of neglect, and if you&#8217;ve got one of those, then you might end up just needing to live with an hour-plus of inappropriate cuddling and whispering every day. My sympathies if so.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/coworkers-husband-hangs-out-in-our-office-every-afternoon.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>190</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>how can I be a great reference for a former coworker?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/how-can-i-be-a-great-reference-for-a-former-coworker.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/how-can-i-be-a-great-reference-for-a-former-coworker.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[references]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5643</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: A former coworker reached out to me via LinkedIn recently to ask if I&#8217;d be willing to serve as a reference for him during his job search. He is leaving the company where I used to work in a role that was semi-managerial. He was a great coworker and valuable member of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>A former coworker reached out to me via LinkedIn recently to ask if I&#8217;d be willing to serve as a reference for him during his job search. He is leaving the company where I used to work in a role that was semi-managerial. He was a great coworker and valuable member of our team, so I agreed, but I&#8217;m not sure what I need to do to be prepared to give him the reference he deserves.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve never been asked to serve as a reference before, so I honestly don&#8217;t know what I just agreed to and what the most professional way to approach this is. Most of the advice I&#8217;ve seen is regarding people for whom you <a title="What to Do When You Can’t Give a Positive Reference" href="http://quickbase.intuit.com/blog/2011/10/05/what-to-do-when-you-cant-give-a-positive-reference/" target="_blank">don&#8217;t feel comfortable giving a good reference</a>. Any tips you could provide on what to be sure to mention or avoid and how to stay within the boundaries of professional (rather than personal) comments would be great.</em></p>
<p>You can read my answer to this question at the <a href="http://quickbase.intuit.com/blog/2013/03/19/reader-question-how-to-be-a-great-reference/">The Fast Track blog by Intuit QuickBase</a> today.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/how-can-i-be-a-great-reference-for-a-former-coworker.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>tiny answer Tuesday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/tiny-answer-tuesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-25.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/tiny-answer-tuesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-25.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 04:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5648</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s tiny answer Tuesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Interviewer asked me to send him all my contacts I just interviewed at a start-up where 3 people liked me and the CEO said he would like to give me a shot for 90 days and see where things [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s tiny answer Tuesday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Interviewer asked me to send him all my contacts</strong></p>
<p><em>I just interviewed at a start-up where 3 people liked me and the CEO said he would like to give me a shot for 90 days and see where things go. I then interviewed with a sales director, on a different day. He had a different interviewing style &#8212; grilled me and asked me to send him ALL my contacts on Monday. He wasn&#8217;t even sure why they were interviewing me! (They were not ready to open that division.) I thought this was strange and emailed a friend who has been in healthcare sales for 20+ years. She thought it was strange.</em></p>
<p><em>Sunday night, I sent an email stating I was very interested, but those contacts were my clients and I didn&#8217;t feel comfortable handing them over without an offer (some were big time names, of big time hospitals). 30 minutes later, I got a &#8220;thank you but we are looking for someone with a different skill set&#8221; email.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s the contacts they were really after or if I offended them? The email was not harsh. Is it appropriate and expected to hand this over? I worked on these for years and they span 15 states (where this company would eventually expand to).</em></p>
<p>No, no employer should expect you to hand over your contacts before you&#8217;re working there. This may or may not be the reason you didn&#8217;t get the job, but I doubt they put you through all those interviews just as a ploy to access your contacts. In any case, don&#8217;t second-guess your decision &#8212; you were in the right, and the interviewer who asked was in the wrong.</p>
<p><strong>2. Is it too late to negotiate salary when I&#8217;ve already accepted the offer?</strong></p>
<p><em>I accepted an offer for an insurance position and I lowballed my salary requirement in an effort not to price myself out of the position. They of course offered me the position at my requested amount. I had a sinking feeling I could have asked for more, but accepted the position. Now that I&#8217;ve been there a week, I know i deserve more! Is it too late to negotiate salary?</em></p>
<p>Yes. The time to negotiate salary is before you accepted the offer. At this point, you&#8217;ve already agreed to their offer and are working there. Imagine, after all, if they came back to you now and said they&#8217;d decided they want to pay you less than you earlier agreed to &#8212; you&#8217;d be rightfully irked. Same thing here. You made an agreement, and you&#8217;re expected to honor it, at least until you&#8217;ve been there long enough to credibly ask for a raise (which for most people is about a year). This is the problem with lowballing yourself in order &#8220;not to price yourself out of the position.&#8221; You commit to taking the salary you&#8217;ve asked for, lowball or not.</p>
<p><strong>3. My new cubicle is right by the bathroom, and I can hear everything</strong></p>
<p><em>Our department just moved to a newly remodeled floor with the restrooms located within the area. I sit outside the handicapped restroom, and the men are using it instead of going around to their larger restroom. Unfortunately, I can hear them urinating and other bodily functions. Then they leave the door open after they use the restroom. There is no exhaust fan in the bathroom to ventilate it and/or mask the sounds. It makes me sick to listen to this everyday, all day. What do I do about this situation? The cube I am in is probably only 5 ft from the bathroom door. What should I do? Wear noise-cancelling headphone and place air fresheners on the upper edge of my cube?</em></p>
<p>Explain the problem to your manager and ask if you can move. If you can&#8217;t, then yes, noise-canceling headphones are going to be your friends. (If you&#8217;re wondering whether you can ask people not to use that bathroom, no, you probably cannot. I mean, you could &#8212; but in most offices people are going to think it&#8217;s a bit of a prima donna request, unfortunately.)</p>
<p><strong>4. I cried in a job interview</strong></p>
<p><em>I had a job interview today and one of the questions asked was &#8220;Pick a stressful time in your life and explain how you coped with it.&#8221; I was doing great in the interview, until this. It reminded me of recent issues and I began to cry. I felt so dumb! The interviewer gave me a Kleenex and apologized for bringing up memories, and after a minute of crying, I picked myself up and answered the question. After that, I was fine and answered all remaining questions with no problems. When I apologized again, the interviewer said that she knows exactly how it feels and shouldn&#8217;t be embarrassed. Even though she told me that, do you think that I am not going to get the job because of this?</em></p>
<p>There&#8217;s no way to know. She might have genuinely not cared, or she might be worried that you&#8217;re more thin-skinned than would be ideal for their office. All you can really do is be patient and wait and see what happens &#8212; and remind yourself that people don&#8217;t get job offers for all kinds of reasons, you might have not gotten it even without the crying, and some mistakes are unavoidable, and don&#8217;t beat yourself up about it too much.</p>
<p><strong>5. Can I reapply if I applied too early?</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m trying to get an internship at the company of my dreams this summer, and after reading some of your blog archives I sent them a really personalized cover letter that was much more true to my own voice and passions than what I had been sending out before that. The thing is that I got a little overzealous, and I was so eager to get on their radar that I sent them my info in early January while they were probably looking for spring semester interns. They usually take applications for summer interns in March and April, and on somewhat of a rolling basis. They&#8217;re pretty low-key on the timeframe for this kind of stuff (when they announce they&#8217;re looking for new interns, they do it via tweet!). I assume my resume is lost somewhere in their email cyberspace now because I sent it at the wrong time and it wasn&#8217;t useful to them at that point. Maybe they set it aside for summer but I doubt it.</em></p>
<p><em>Should I send my information again when they ask for summer intern applicants? Or will that just look like an annoying repeat if by some chance they DO still have my info from January? There&#8217;s a new addition to my resume since then that might make them see me as a stronger candidate. If I do reapply should I acknowledge that I already applied earlier so they at least know I respect their time and am not trying to spam them into hiring me?</em></p>
<p>Yes, that&#8217;s basically a whole new hiring round, like a company advertising again for a regular, non-intern position. It&#8217;s fine to reapply when they announce their summer internships &#8212; and for that matter, it&#8217;s fine to reapply when they finally announce their spring internships too. For the latter, just include a note saying that you had applied in January but later realized they weren&#8217;t hiring for spring yet at that point.</p>
<p><strong>6. Can you be treated as both exempt and non-exempt?</strong></p>
<p><em>My husband is an attorney, and he&#8217;s been working a long-term temporary job. He has never been told if he is classified as exempt or non-exempt. His contract with his employer indicates that he is to be paid on a salaried basis of $X per year. However, his manager docks his pay if he is not in the office during the times the office is open. For example, on a day that he had to leave an hour before the office closed, he came in an hour early and skipped his lunch. She still docked him an hour&#8217;s pay, even though he&#8217;d worked two hours extra. Because of the nature of his work, she has also suggested that he come in on weekends to get things done. He does this. On average, he works 10+ hours a week outside of the hours his office is actually open. But not only does he not get paid any extra, his manager docks his pay if he needs to leave the office an hour early, or if he needs to come in a little late (between treacherous winter roads, a death in the family, and a major illness, he&#8217;s needed to be out a handful of hours in the past year).</em></p>
<p><em>I feel that his manager is trying to have it both ways &#8212; she expects him to work extra hours to get the job done, as if he&#8217;s exempt, but she docks his pay if he isn&#8217;t in the office during certain hours, as if he&#8217;s non-exempt. He&#8217;s put his heart and soul into this job, bringing work home, going in on the weekends, waking up insanely early to make it into the office before anyone else gets there, and staying later than anyone else. I feel like, if he&#8217;s non-exempt, his manager needs to manage his workload so he doesn&#8217;t need to work more than the hours he&#8217;s paid for, and if he&#8217;s exempt, she shouldn&#8217;t dock his pay when he needs a little flexibility in his schedule. Any thoughts on how to handle this?</em></p>
<p>You&#8217;re right that she&#8217;s trying to have it both ways, and the law doesn&#8217;t allow it. By docking his pay for hours he misses, she&#8217;s treating him as <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/exempt-and-non-exempt">non-exempt</a>, which means that they law requires her to meet the other requirements for non-exempt workers, meaning that he must be paid overtime in weeks where he works over 40 hours, and that she probably owes him back wages for the times when she didn&#8217;t do that.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/02/20/how-to-assert-your-legal-rights-at-work">advice on how he can raise this with her</a> &#8230; although he&#8217;ll almost certainly sour the relationship if he demands back wages, legally entitled or not, so he might want to settle on just getting it straightened out going forward.</p>
<p><strong>7. Employer won&#8217;t tell me much about the job they&#8217;ve hired me for</strong></p>
<p><em>I got hired on the spot at a childcare center as a lead teacher. I told the manager that I&#8217;ve only been a assistant teacher, and most of my experience is assisting the teacher in the room! The manager said that&#8217;s okay, but that I will be by myself with 7-10 2-year-olds and I will be their lead teacher. She didn&#8217;t tell me what my job duties are exactly just I&#8217;ll be in the room by myself with the kids. She said that if I had questions, to speak up and call her. I did call her, and when she answered, she told me not to call her because she is too busy, but that she will let me know the job duties right before I enter the room. I feel I may have to quit because I&#8217;m not sure if I can handle it. Please help!</em></p>
<p>Um, yeah, that&#8217;s ridiculous. You&#8217;re not under any obligation to accept a job you don&#8217;t want or feel prepared for, or one where the hiring manager won&#8217;t answer questions or even tell you what your responsibilities will be. You can certainly tell her that you need to know more before you can accept the job. If you have any doubts, it&#8217;s probably better to do this now rather than waiting for your first day, since being left alone in charge of children when you&#8217;re not sure you&#8217;re equipped for it isn&#8217;t a good situation for you or the kids to be in.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/tiny-answer-tuesday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-25.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>247</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>recruiter said the position had been filled &#8212; but was it true?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/recruiter-said-the-position-had-been-filled-but-was-it-true.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/recruiter-said-the-position-had-been-filled-but-was-it-true.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 20:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[external recruiters]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5645</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: My husband and I are both in the same specialized field and have very similar education/degrees, skills and experience. He recently applied to a position that read like it was made for him, with the bonus that it was located in the area where he grew up and to which we wanted [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>My husband and I are both in the same specialized field and have very similar education/degrees, skills and experience. He recently applied to a position that read like it was made for him, with the bonus that it was located in the area where he grew up and to which we wanted to move. This was a very rare combination and he tried really hard to get this job. After several phone interviews with recruiters and a hiring manager, he was getting great feedback and they seemed to really like him as a candidate. The recruiter called him on a Wednesday and said he was doing really well, and that the company would like to set up another interview with another key manager the next week. We were really happy about this, but the next Monday he received an email from the recruiter that said they filled the position with another candidate. We were disappointed but moved on.</em></p>
<p><em>A couple of weeks later, he received an email from a second person at the same recruiting agency, saying that she had an open position for which he should apply. It was the exact same job. He was annoyed and wanted to sent a nasty reply (he has been frustrated and cynical after job-hunting for many years), but I cajoled him into sending a pleasant but &#8220;confused&#8221; response that he had already gone through the interview process for that position, and he had been told that it had been filled. The second recruiter said she would look into it, but she never got back to him. He emailed her to say that he was no longer interested in the opportunity, and suggested that she contact me, since I have also been looking for employment.</em></p>
<p><em>I heard back from the first recruiter the next day, and she conducted an initial interview over the phone. At the end of the conversation, I told her that I understood this position had already been filled. She told me that it had not. I decided not to say anything about my husband because it seemed awkward at the time. After about a week, she emailed me to say that the position had been filled, and my contact ended there.</em></p>
<p><em>I suppose it&#8217;s possible that they had indeed made a job offer to someone and that fell through, but the whole experience struck me as being weird. My husband had a similar experience a few years ago where he made it through the final interview process but was told they chose another candidate &#8212; but then saw the same, unique position re-advertised a few weeks later. Is this common, or were they just trying to let him down easy?</em></p>
<p>Who knows. There&#8217;s rarely any point in trying to speculate on stuff like this, since there are so many possible explanations.</p>
<p>Maybe they had indeed offered the job to someone but that fell through, or maybe it was a miscommunication between the recruiter and the employer, or maybe it was just disorganization on the recruiter&#8217;s side, or maybe the recruiter meant to convey &#8220;they&#8217;re interested in going with someone else, although they don&#8217;t yet know who&#8221; but it got conveyed as &#8220;they did go with someone else,&#8221; or maybe the recruiter did indeed lie to your husband and said it was filled when it wasn&#8217;t. (But honestly, that last one is pretty unlikely, since recruiters have plenty of experience rejecting candidates; it&#8217;s not like they&#8217;re so uncomfortable with it that they have to lie to get out of being direct.)</p>
<p>Hell, it&#8217;s also possible that the recruiter was right when she told your husband the position had been filled, and it was all the subsequent communications that were wrong. (The second recruiter at the agency might not have realized the job had been filled when she contacted him and then you.)</p>
<p>The best thing you can do when dealing with recruiters &#8212; and when dealing with employers directly, too &#8212; is not to bother to try to read too much into any of this. It doesn&#8217;t really matter, after all. They&#8217;ve declined to proceed with you, and that&#8217;s really the relevant information; trying to read into what might have happened beyond that is generally a waste of energy, because unless someone tells you directly, you really can&#8217;t know. And don&#8217;t really need to, even though it&#8217;s tempting to try to do a post mortum on it all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/recruiter-said-the-position-had-been-filled-but-was-it-true.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>ask the readers: how should I follow up with a teary employee?</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/ask-the-readers-how-should-i-follow-up-with-a-teary-employee.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/ask-the-readers-how-should-i-follow-up-with-a-teary-employee.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 18:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[good management]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5623</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s the second of our &#8220;ask the readers&#8221; questions today. This reader writes: I am a male in a mostly female organization. However, I find myself in a middle management position with about 10 reports. Today when I was making rounds to check in on people, one of my reports appeared sad. I asked if [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>Here&#8217;s the second of our &#8220;ask the readers&#8221; questions today. This reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I am a male in a mostly female organization. However, I find myself in a middle management position with about 10 reports. Today when I was making rounds to check in on people, one of my reports appeared sad. I asked if everything was alright and at that point I could see she was on the verge of tears. I knew if I asked anything more she would have started to cry, embarrassing her in front of five other coworkers who sit in her office space. I assumed the issue was not work-related and I excused myself.</em></p>
<p><em>I have a good rapport with her, but I do not know if I should ask her now if she would like to talk about it in my office or let her handle it? Maybe it&#8217;s as easy as finding out if it&#8217;s work or home related before pressing the conversation forward.</em></p>
<p>Readers, what say you?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/ask-the-readers-how-should-i-follow-up-with-a-teary-employee.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>128</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>ask the readers: how to overcome job search anxiety</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/ask-the-readers-how-to-overcome-job-search-anxiety.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/ask-the-readers-how-to-overcome-job-search-anxiety.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 15:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[job searching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5619</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m traveling today, so I&#8217;m throwing two questions out to readers to help with. Here&#8217;s the first one, from a reader who writes: I have job anxiety. I graduated from college last May and as such I am relatively new to the job field. But I&#8217;ve had experience as an administrative assistant and marketing intern. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>I&#8217;m traveling today, so I&#8217;m throwing two questions out to readers to help with. Here&#8217;s the first one, from a reader who writes:</p>
<p><em>I have job anxiety. </em></p>
<p><em>I graduated from college last May and as such I am relatively new to the job field. But I&#8217;ve had experience as an administrative assistant and marketing intern. </em></p>
<p><em>When I see a job advertisement, I get so intimidated by the job description because it always requires experience in terms of years that I don&#8217;t have. Even if the experience is within my qualifications and I do receive an offer, I constantly worry about if I can do a good job. If I don&#8217;t do it competently enough, will they fire me? If they give me something to do in the job description that I don&#8217;t know how to do (i.e. spreadsheets, expense reports), will they allow me to learn or show me how to do it? Can I meet their expectations? </em></p>
<p><em>Those are some of the thoughts I have and I lose the courage to continue with the job process. If it was a minimum wage job, I wouldn&#8217;t even have a problem with anxiety like that. But with a professional job, I am scared to an anxious degree. I know that I can&#8217;t be the only one who has a problem with this. What is this exactly and what can I do to get over it? Is this something that is fairly common with recent grads? Thank you for your help.</em></p>
<p>What advice do you have for this new grad?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/ask-the-readers-how-to-overcome-job-search-anxiety.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>67</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 sticky job searching conundrums and how to solve them</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/5-sticky-job-searching-conundrums-and-how-to-solve-them.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/5-sticky-job-searching-conundrums-and-how-to-solve-them.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 14:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[job searching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5633</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Job searching is rife with sticky situations that job seekers often aren&#8217;t sure how to handle. For instance: You get a job offer but you’re waiting to hear back from another employer about a job you’d rather take. Can you stall the first employer while you wait to hear from the second? A prospective employer [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p><a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/03/18/how-to-solve-the-5-stickiest-job-searching-conundrums"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2077" alt="featured-on-usn" src="http://www.askamanager.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/featured-on-usn.jpg" width="90" height="60" /></a>Job searching is rife with sticky situations that job seekers often aren&#8217;t sure how to handle. For instance:</p>
<ul>
<li>You get a job offer but you’re waiting to hear back from another employer about a job you’d rather take. Can you stall the first employer while you wait to hear from the second?</li>
<li>A prospective employer asks if they can contact your current manager for a reference, but your manager doesn’t know you’re looking for another job.</li>
<li>You exaggerated your salary history on your job application, and now an employer is asking you to verify the numbers.</li>
<li>You need to schedule an interview, but you’re currently employed and can’t get away during the workday.</li>
<li>You have an interview after work, but if you come to work wearing a suit, your whole office will know you’re interviewing.</li>
</ul>
<p>Over at U.S. News &amp; World Report today, I talk about how to navigate these and come out safely on the other side. (Well, with one exception.) You can <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2013/03/18/how-to-solve-the-5-stickiest-job-searching-conundrums">read it here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/5-sticky-job-searching-conundrums-and-how-to-solve-them.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>mini answer Monday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/mini-answer-monday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-15.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/mini-answer-monday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-15.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 09:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5640</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s mini answer Monday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. When should you let your employer know you&#8217;re looking for a new job? When is the best time to tell your current employer that you are looking for/about to get a new job elsewhere? I&#8217;ve heard of various scenarios&#8211;letting [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s mini answer Monday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. When should you let your employer know you&#8217;re looking for a new job?</strong></p>
<p><em>When is the best time to tell your current employer that you are looking for/about to get a new job elsewhere? I&#8217;ve heard of various scenarios&#8211;letting them know early that you are &#8220;just looking,&#8221; in which case they might feel compelled (and have the time) to promote you or give you a raise. Or letting them know that you are actually in the midst of interviewing, which could give them more incentive to try to retain you. Or only tell them once you have a hard offer from another company so they have clear numbers to work with in case they want to counter offer.</em></p>
<p><em>In all scenarios, the individual is ready and willing to leave; it&#8217;s not a ploy to stay and get more money.</em></p>
<p>This depends 100% of how your employer handles the knowledge that someone is planning to leave but hasn&#8217;t given official notice yet, and how they handle generous notice periods (of longer than two weeks). If your manager has a track record of handling these things well &#8212; of being appreciative of the long notice or informal heads-up &#8212; rather than penalizing people or even pushing them out the door earlier than they wanted to go, then great &#8212; you know how they operate, and it&#8217;s reasonably safe for you to be candid. But if, on the other hand, your manager has a track record of not handling it well (firing people, pushing them out early, denying you raises, bonuses, or good projects that you&#8217;d otherwise get for the remainder of your employment), then let that be your guide &#8212; meaning give only two notice (or give more, but be prepared for the consequences). In other words, there&#8217;s no blanket rule here; you need to know your employer/manager and act accordingly.</p>
<p>All that said, however, if your goal in telling them is because you hope they&#8217;ll give you a raise or promotion, that&#8217;s not the way to do it. If you want those things, you should make a case for them independently of mentioning your job search. If you can&#8217;t get them that way and it takes a threat of leaving to get them, you need to stick with your plan to leave. Somewhere that only acts when you have one foot out the door isn&#8217;t a great place to work. (And taking a counteroffer is usually a bad idea for all the reasons discussed <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2012/03/26/why-you-shouldnt-take-a-counteroffer">here</a>.)</p>
<p><strong>2. Job ads that ask you to describe how interesting you are</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m having trouble with job ads that ask to describe how interesting you are. I don&#8217;t find myself very interesting. This isn&#8217;t a self esteem issue. I don&#8217;t have any interesting hobbies like skydiving or founding a burlesque troop. Or even any exotic pets like a ferret or lemur. What should I do?</em></p>
<p>I&#8217;d love to know what industry you&#8217;re in that you&#8217;re encountering a lot of these requests; it&#8217;s an odd one. In any case, if you described why you&#8217;re obsessed with ___ (fill in the type of work you do), where that comes from, and how it manifests in your life, even outside of work, I&#8217;d find that pretty damn interesting if I were hiring for a job. But then that&#8217;s the kind of thing I want to know all the time anyway &#8212; not what your hobbies or pets are.</p>
<p>These ads are telling you something about their culture, and it might not be something you like.</p>
<p><strong>3. How to back out of a job offer you&#8217;ve already accepted</strong></p>
<p><em>My department recently restructured, and I was put into a role that was far less &#8220;important&#8221; than my previous position, though title and salary didn&#8217;t change. I went from managing a team and reporting directly in to an EVP to having one direct report and reporting to someone who has more or less the same experience as I do. Based on that, I started looking and secured an offer from another company, which I accepted (in writing).</em></p>
<p><em>Well, as it turns out, that was a terrible decision. The area I was put into, which I considered a demotion, is undergoing a large expansion, and the boss I am currently reporting to is leaving the company; the reporting situation was simply so I could be trained.</em></p>
<p><em>Hindsight is 20/20; obviously I should have communicated my concerns when the move happened. But now I&#8217;m in the awkward position of having to un-accept the offer. I haven&#8217;t received any compensation from the new company, and I only accepted earlier this week. There&#8217;s no specific language in my acceptance that reads exactly like a contract, though it clearly states I am accepting the offer. Does the other company have any recourse (other, obviously, than never hiring me again &#8212; I&#8217;m accepting that the bridge is probably a charred mess) against me? Do a lot of people accept and then rescind acceptance of offers?</em></p>
<p>No, they have no legal recourse against if you if you&#8217;re not breaking a contract (and just accepting the offer letter isn&#8217;t a contact, just like it doesn&#8217;t prevent them from pulling the offer or firing you on week two). You will burn the bridge, and you will probably harm your reputation with people who hear about it, but there aren&#8217;t any legal repercussions.</p>
<p>You asked if if a lot of people accept offers and then back out, and the answer is no. Most people have a story about someone who did it to their company &#8212; but it tends to be a notorious story about That Awful Bob Who Backed Out After We&#8217;d Already Turned Loose Our Other Candidates and Set Up His Computer. You will be Awful Bob at that company, so prepare yourself for that! (And talk to your employer the next time you&#8217;re unhappy about a restructure!)</p>
<p><strong>4. Explaining in a cover letter that you&#8217;re switching fields</strong></p>
<p><em>I recently decided that I need a career change in my life and was wondering if that is something worth mentioning in your cover letter. All of my experience lands in one field graphic design, but I also managed teams and provided customer service. I&#8217;m now looking into a recruitment position. Should I mention in my cover letter that I&#8217;m changing careers?</em></p>
<p>God, yes. Otherwise they&#8217;ll have no idea why you&#8217;re applying for a position that doesn&#8217;t relate to the work they see on your resume. In fact, not only do you need to mention it, you need to make the case for why you&#8217;ll be good at it and why your experience translates to the new field. Don&#8217;t expect them to make that case on their own &#8212; you&#8217;re going to need to figure it out and be compelling about it. (You should also be prepared for the fact that it&#8217;s hard to change fields in this job market, because employers generally have tons of qualified candidates who <em>have</em> worked in the field, and not much incentive to take a chance on someone switching careers. So you&#8217;ve really got to be compelling.)</p>
<p><strong>5. Is this salary too low?</strong></p>
<p><em>Via grapevine networking through a family member, I&#8217;ve been alerted to a job opening for a receptionist+ position at a small (less than 30 employees) company. As the &#8220;+&#8221; entails all of the marketing experience (3+ years) I bring to the table, they have added to the position responsibilities, but are still looking to pay close to what they originally conceived for the post &#8212; a full $17,000 less than what my last position paid, and still $10,000 less than the first role listed on my resume.</em></p>
<p><em>I know this is impossible to gauge, but just how low is too low? I live in a very expensive city, have high student loan bills, and chose my apartment based on my salary and budgeting of my last few positions&#8217; salaries.</em></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know. You&#8217;d need to look at what similar work pays for people with your experience in your particular geographic area. That&#8217;s what market rate is based on, not your last salary, your student loans, or your rent.</p>
<p><strong>6. Dealing with a board of directors that oversteps their role</strong></p>
<p><em>Have you or could you do a post about dealing with a dysfunctional board? My husband has been the executive director for two nonprofits, and his major issues have always been with the board. For example: board members who use their positions to promote their personal projects at official events; members who micromanage the staff when it&#8217;s the ED&#8217;s responsibility; members who backtrack on policies they&#8217;ve implemented to suit their current needs; members responding to disgruntled former chair instead of ignoring him.</em></p>
<p><em>You say that reputation is so important, and I worry that husband will have a reputation for not being able to work well with boards. He gets great results with his staff, receives recognition by industry experts, and is effective in his job (increased revenue, reduced expenses, removed problem employees, etc.). Instead of recognizing his efforts, his current board has started to micromanage his staff to the point that two key staff members want to quit and he is looking for another job. Any guidance that you can provide?</em></p>
<p>Boardsource.org and blueavocado.org both have good advice on dealing with boards, including on the appropriate role of the board (big-picture oversight and managing the ED) versus the appropriate role of the ED (managing the staff and the day-to-day operations of the organization). When you&#8217;ve got a board committed to doing the ED&#8217;s role rather than their own &#8212; and when they&#8217;re resistant to learning about best practices for boards and adjusting their behavior &#8212; it&#8217;s nearly always a nightmare for the ED (and often for the organization). Personally, I&#8217;d get the hell out of there and go somewhere that would let me do my job &#8230; which your husband probably needs to more carefully screen for in the future, really asking questions about how the board, ED, and staff interact, and doing some diligent research into the experiences of past EDs in the organization.</p>
<p><strong>7. Managing bad apples</strong></p>
<p><em>I manage 12 people, two of whom are bad apples. These two have a negative attitude and try to influence others to be negative. How can I stop this?</em></p>
<p>Um, manage them? Set standards for what is and isn&#8217;t appropriate behavior and consequences for not meeting that bar. Warn them that they&#8217;re in danger of losing their jobs if they don&#8217;t improve in areas A, B, and C, set a short period of time to evaluate whether they&#8217;ve moved to where you need them to be (meaning weeks, not months), and <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2011/01/how-to-fire-an-employee-with-a-bad-attitude.html">replace them</a> if they haven&#8217;t.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/mini-answer-monday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-15.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>76</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>short answer Sunday &#8212; 6 short answers to 6 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-sunday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-34.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-sunday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-34.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5641</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s short answer Sunday &#8212; six short answers to six short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Applying for a job with a store I stole from two years ago I stole from a store when I was 16. I took about $20 worth of items, and my sister took more than $100. It was a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s short answer Sunday &#8212; six short answers to six short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Applying for a job with a store I stole from two years ago</strong></p>
<p><em>I stole from a store when I was 16. I took about $20 worth of items, and my sister took more than $100. It was a class B misdemeanor and I went to juvenile center. I was a minor and my case was dismissed. I&#8217;m 18 and I have an interview at that store for a job. Should I bring it up or not say anything? I didn&#8217;t put in on the application because I was a minor, I didn&#8217;t go to jail, and it was wiped clean from my record when i became an adult.</em></p>
<p>In general, because it was erased from your record, there&#8217;s no need to bring this up when you&#8217;re applying for jobs. But the same store that you stole from? I would not apply with that store. If you bring it up, they&#8217;re unlikely to hire you &#8230; and if you don&#8217;t bring it up and start working there, and someone there remembers you from two years ago, it&#8217;s going to be Uncomfortable. Why not try to get a job with other stores instead?</p>
<p><strong>2. Mentioning a spouse&#8217;s job when it might be relevant to yours</strong></p>
<p><em>My husband is applying for a position as an engineer within an event space. The job description requires interaction between his potential position and event planners that would be clients of the space. Ordinarily (obviously, perhaps?), engineers don&#8217;t have much familiarity with the events industry, but as I am an event planner myself, and even a client of this venue, he has a bit of inside knowledge of the industry and what event planners would be looking for. We both agree that this would be an asset to his candidacy and his position, if he got the job, but neither of us can figure out how to word it. Is it appropriate to include this information in a cover letter? Is there a good way to word it?</em></p>
<p>Normally I&#8217;d say that info about a spouse never belongs in a cover letter (unless it&#8217;s &#8220;I&#8217;m relocating on April 1 because my spouse has accepted a job in your city&#8221;), but I could actually see mentioning this. I&#8217;d say something like, &#8220;Because my wife is an event planner, I know a fair bit about the industry and &#8212; unlike many engineers &#8212; actually enjoy talking about ___.&#8221; (Fill that in with something event-planning-related that&#8217;s likely to be relevant to him if he were doing the job &#8212; &#8220;the relative merits of various caterers,&#8221; &#8220;floral decor,&#8221; or whatever makes sense.) It&#8217;s fine if this sounds wry or semi-funny; that&#8217;s actually a plus if he can pull that off.</p>
<p><strong>3. Using a reference from a short-term job</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m starting to look for a new job and have a question about references. The jobs I&#8217;m looking at are in the school system, so I want to use a reference from my last job in a similar position at a school in a different district. The problem is that I only worked there for a few months last year. My position wasn&#8217;t carried over into the fall school year, even though my supervisors were happy with my work. My supervisor has said she&#8217;d be happy to be a reference for me, but is a few months a year ago too short a time, too long ago to work as a good reference? If I don&#8217;t use her, I&#8217;m limited to either having all my references from my current position, or using references from unrelated jobs or an unpaid practicum that was also a year ago, but lasted for the entire school year.</em></p>
<p>Yeah, it&#8217;s not ideal. I&#8217;d want to know why your contract wasn&#8217;t renewed (and if you don&#8217;t know for sure, you should try to find out) before you decide whether or not to use it.</p>
<p><strong>4. Why are my lazy coworkers still here?</strong></p>
<p><em>I work in a somewhat small office with six employees and one manager. I have worked here for two year and have survived multiple managers (most of whom have provided special treatment and overlooked things such as other employees&#8217; drug use). Last summer, I was extremely happy to find out that our company was hiring a new manager and after meeting with him it was clear that he does not put up with BS. However, lately he seems to be siding with the people who complain the most. Of the six employees, three continually get away with everything from not showing up for work, lying, not doing their jobs, and causing drama. While I make a point not to go and complain to my boss (for fear of being labeled as a problem child), these three constantly run down to his office and complain about everything. I have had them complain about me creating “tension” in the office and therefore they don’t get their work done. However, when I asked how I caused tension, they said I have been ignoring them and I close my door all the time. I do make a point to close my door when they are standing in the hall talking for over an hour sometimes to focus on my work. I say hello and goodbye every morning and I am polite when I am forced to work with them; yet I do make a point to stay away from them for fear of being affiliated with their lazy work ethic. I cordially explained to the three that I focus better with the door closed and that they are welcome to come in any time, but I made it clear that I was not going to start going out and BSing for over an hour with them to make them feel comfortable. I have never once been reprimanded by my boss for lack of being cordial, mostly because I deal with several supervisors and consultants who all like dealing with me and appreciate my work ethic. I have even been promoted and have joined several big corporate outings.</em></p>
<p><em>While I love my actual job and the experience I am getting as well as pay, I can’t stand dealing with the constant complaints and drama these three add. They are so lazy that when one fails to do a job it gets shoved onto me, or when they screw up I get nipped for it and told to watch it better next time. I am constantly having to pick up their slack and the few times I have mentioned it to my boss he defends these people. I am told to work with these people (I have no authority over them) yet when their work is lacking and mistakes happen I get nailed for it. I don&#8217;t understand why my boss has not fired them and found other employees and I am starting to doubt that he even cares whether these people do their jobs. When is it time to give up a great job due to horrible coworkers?</em></p>
<p>Now. And it&#8217;s not because of your horrible coworkers, but rather because of your inept managers who have shown they&#8217;re not going to do their job and manage these people.</p>
<p><strong>5. How do I stand out when 24 candidates are being interviewed?</strong></p>
<p><em>I have an interview coming up for a job I really, really want. Like, it&#8217;s a perfect fit. I know I am qualified for the job because I got called for an interview! Here&#8217;s my concern, they are interviewing 24 people for the position! What are some ways to stick out in the interview (and make sure the interviewing panel remembers me) without any gimmicks? I figure I have nothing to lose because it is going to be a competitive pool, but I don&#8217;t want to appear ridiculous.</em></p>
<p>You stand out by being a highly qualified candidate who has done <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/how-to-guide">a ton of preparation for the interview</a>. That&#8217;s it &#8212; there&#8217;s no other way to do it.</p>
<p>Interviewing 24 candidates in a first round is insane, by the way.</p>
<p><strong>6. New manager is asking me to bring in materials from my old job</strong></p>
<p><em>I am just making a move to a new job with a better salary and a nice position. The thing is that my new manager asked me to bring some work-related materials such as excel sheets and various templates from my previous employer. It&#8217;s my first time to switch jobs and I don&#8217;t know if this is a normal practice. I don&#8217;t want to do this as I perceive this to be completely unethical. On the other hand, the job is well paying and definitely a strong move in my career. How can I handle this situation in a way that doesn&#8217;t affect the relationship with my new manager?</em></p>
<p>Say this: &#8220;My agreement with my previous employer prevents me from sharing those materials.&#8221; If pushed, repeat it again. If still pushed, say, &#8220;I&#8217;m uncomfortable being asked to share these materials, when I know my previous employer would have strong objections to me doing it.&#8221; And then stand firm.</p>
<p>This response is completely normal, and any manager who won&#8217;t accept that is seriously bad news.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-sunday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-34.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>64</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>short answer Saturday &#8212; 7 short answers to 7 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-saturday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-29.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-saturday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-29.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5635</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s short answer Saturday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. When your interviewers are stiff and not conversational I have a friend who had an interview this morning for an assistant position (she&#8217;s been out of college for a year). I had her read your blog to prepare and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s short answer Saturday &#8212; seven short answers to seven short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. When your interviewers are stiff and not conversational</strong></p>
<p><em>I have a friend who had an interview this morning for an assistant position (she&#8217;s been out of college for a year). I had her read your blog to prepare and I helped her as well. After her interview, she called me and told me that she thought it went ok. Her biggest concern was that the two men interviewing her did not give much feedback or really attempt to make the conversation conversational, if that makes sense. My gut instinct told me it is a sign of an inexperienced interviewer because I have only had 1 interview out of dozens like that. I guess I&#8217;m wondering if it&#8217;s more a reflection on them or does the interviewee need to try harder to keep the conversation flowing? And how do you handle an interview when it feels like you&#8217;re talking to the wall?</em></p>
<p>It could be inexperienced interviewers, but it could also just be their personal style. Some people are fairly formal in interview situations, and not everyone gives feedback on the spot (or ever). If you&#8217;re a candidate in that situation, the best thing to do is not to take it personally; if you start feeling it&#8217;s a reflection on you, you can get anxious and lose focus. Just treat it like a normal interview, since for them, it may be.</p>
<p><strong>2. Pre-planned vacation when interviewing with a tiny office</strong></p>
<p><em>I have read through your archives regarding interviews and waiting until an offer has been made to mention a <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2008/06/pre-planned-vacation-when-job-hunting.html">pre-planned vacation</a>. I agree with this approach as it doesn&#8217;t seem appropriate to bring up days I&#8217;d want off during an interview.</em></p>
<p><em>I recently interviewed for a position with a large company with offices nationwide. However, I&#8217;d be working in a very small satellite office that covers a small part of the country. When I say small satellite office, I mean the smallest you can get: my potential future boss and whomever is hired to be his assistant.</em></p>
<p><em>I have a vacation planned in about 6.5 weeks that will require me to miss 6 days of work. I already have plane tickets and have paid deposits on rentals. This vacation cannot be rescheduled because its purpose is for me to run a marathon for which I&#8217;ve been training for months. I don&#8217;t want to shorten the vacation because of my non-refundable plane tickets and rental deposits. Should I email my potential employer and let him know of these plans, or wait until I am offered the position? Normally I would wait until an offer has been made but I feel this situation is different due to the size of the office. I&#8217;m afraid if I wait he will feel duped and I don&#8217;t want to tick off my one-and-only coworker before I even start working. My interview was Monday and he said he hopes to make a decision by the end of this week.</em></p>
<p>Nope, just like always, wait until you have an offer and then negotiate it then as part of your overall negotiation. Employers don&#8217;t want to get into the specifics of what days candidates will need off; they want to wait until they&#8217;ve determined who they&#8217;d like to hire, and deal with it then.</p>
<p><strong>3. Should I leave if I get demoted?</strong></p>
<p><em>My company is going through an organizational change which will result in the elimination of my job. The company has been very vocal about wanting to keep all employees, and has offered three alternatives: a promotion with enough positions for 10% of the people with my job title, a demotion with loss of some PTO benefits and salary, or a lateral transfer to an entirely different job type. Although there is no formal interview process, I sent a cover letter style email to my bosses regarding my interest in the promotion, and have since met with all three of them to discuss the changes in the company. Although they&#8217;ve assured me that they like my work and my attitude, they&#8217;ve also emphasized that I&#8217;m competing against 100 other people. I&#8217;ve been in this industry for 5 years, but in this particular company for less than 2. Many of my colleagues have more than 10+ years of experience and are 5+ years older than I am. I&#8217;m confident in my abilities, but not confident that I&#8217;ll be chosen.</em></p>
<p><em>My question is whether or not I should stay with this company if I don&#8217;t receive the promotion. I would likely be placed in the lower paying job with less PTO and incentives, and would also lose my job title and many of my responsibilities. I&#8217;m worried that I will be stuck in a position I find unfulfilling and if I do choose to leave in the future, this demotion will impact my resume. I could take a severance package, but I&#8217;m also worried that I would be placing a time limit on myself to find a new career. I&#8217;ve never been in this position before, and I would appreciate any advice you may have!</em></p>
<p>It&#8217;s easier to find a new job when you&#8217;re still employed, so if you don&#8217;t want to stay in the position you end up in, you can always stay in it while embarking on a job search and leave when you find something else. (In fact, you should probably start looking now so that you get a head start on your search. You can always curtail it if you get the promotion or otherwise decide not to leave.) If you leave quickly enough after the demotion, if indeed it happens, you can simply leave it off your resume.</p>
<p><strong>4. Listing seasonal work on your resume</strong></p>
<p><em>I saw you say that it&#8217;s bad form to leave months off resumes because it looks like you&#8217;re trying to hide rapid job-hopping. Does that apply to jobs that are very specifically seasonal? I&#8217;m in the education/youth org sphere and I have a few jobs on my resume listed as &#8220;Summer ____&#8221; because they were positions akin to a summer camp counselor that didn&#8217;t say so in the title. My thinking is that it provides a more accurate impression of my time there, it looks neater, and people in schools or other youth organizations are familiar with that type of job since many teachers and other professionals spend their summers that way. Someone who works in recruiting told me he liked that way of phrasing it, but I wanted a second opinion, or thoughts on whether it should be altered for certain jobs (maybe it&#8217;s more appropriate, for example, for my upcoming search for a summer job, since it signifies I&#8217;m experienced with the kind of position I&#8217;m applying for, than if I were to apply for an office-based position in a youth org that does similar work year-round).</em></p>
<p>Yes, &#8220;summer 2012&#8243; or whatever is totally fine and normal.</p>
<p><strong>5. Negotiating with a J.D. but not much experience</strong></p>
<p><em>I graduated in May of 2012 with a J.D., and have been searching for jobs since then. I am applying to jobs that are J.D. required/preferred, but not necessarily &#8220;traditional&#8221; law firm jobs. A lot of these jobs ask for so many years of experience (which I don&#8217;t have as a new grad) or will substitute having a J.D. for the required number of years. They list the salary as either a range or as negotiable.</em></p>
<p><em>I am wondering how, as a new grad, I can negotiate for a salary and come across as deserving of that salary, especially as a new graduate with minimal years of experience.</em></p>
<p>You&#8217;d negotiate the same way anyone else does, by making a case for why you deserve more than what they&#8217;re offering. That said, without much work experience, you don&#8217;t have a lot of negotiating power / standing to justify more, so you want to be aware of that so that you don&#8217;t come across as out of touch about your current market value. Good luck!</p>
<p><strong>6. Getting a job with a vendor my company just rejected</strong></p>
<p><em>I would appreciate your advice on how to get a job with a vendor my company just rejected. Currently I work in sourcing for a large manufacturing company and have responsibility for vetting potential vendors. Recently I came across a really exciting startup company who could really provide a boost to our business. I spent several months reviewing their company, analyzing their business model, and realized this was a truly remarkable company with a great management team. I also presented my recommendation to several senior leaders and received very positive feedback about this partnership. Right before closing terms on the contract, we got a huge surprise, though. My company was no longer interested in the deal due to a sudden strategy shift.</em></p>
<p><em>The problem is I like the vendor more than my current company. How do I approach them to let them know I would be interested in joining them even though my company turned them down? I know I have a lot to offer them from my background and experience, plus I know their business and industry very well. Should I just ask them to keep me in mind for future openings? Or offer to do some moonlighting? I am worried about a potential conflict of interest with my current employer. I only know a few people at the company, including the founder. Any advice you can offer would be greatly appreciated.</em></p>
<p>Tell the founder you&#8217;re interested. Say something like, &#8220;I got to know so much about your company over the last few months and am impressed. If you&#8217;re ever looking for someone to do X, I&#8217;d love to talk with you.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>7. Convincing my manager that I need to quit due to health issues</strong></p>
<p><em>I started working at a salon as a receptionist (part-time) to have a little extra spending money. My husband makes enough to cover our living expenses, but my extra income allows us to travel occasionally and not worry about money. Overall, I&#8217;m alright with my job; it&#8217;s not the best job I&#8217;ve ever had, but it&#8217;s not the worst either. However, in the six months I&#8217;ve worked at the salon I have had severe bronchitis four times. After an extreme lifestyle search with my doctor (I&#8217;m a nonsmoker, and have never had bronchitis before six months ago), he believes working at the hair salon could be what is causing my bronchitis. He said he would be more than happy to speak with my boss about it and has strongly encouraged me to resign.</em></p>
<p><em>How do I quit without burning the bridge at the salon? How do you professionally explain that you have to quit because the environment is making you ill? I&#8217;ve broached the topic with the owner several times before and she laughed and thought I was joking because &#8220;that doesn&#8217;t happen to anybody.&#8221; I&#8217;ve tried being direct and she has just blown me off. This sounds horrible, but she really has been a good boss to me other than this issue. Basically, as long as I go with her flow, I am golden in her eyes. Should I just write this off as a bridge that must be burned?</em></p>
<p>You don&#8217;t need to justify quitting for health reasons, and you definitely don&#8217;t need your doctor to talk to them. Just say something like, &#8220;My doctor has believes something about the salon is causing bronchitis in me, and has strongly urged me to resign. I feel I need to take his advice, so X will be my last day.&#8221;</p>
<p>If your manager mocks you or tells you you&#8217;re wrong, it doesn&#8217;t matter. Just stay pleasant and say, &#8220;This is the decision I&#8217;ve made. I really appreciate the chance to work here, and I&#8217;m sorry I couldn&#8217;t stay longer.&#8221;</p>
<p>No sane manager would consider this a bridge burned. If she does, then she&#8217;s irrational enough that something else was likely to burn it anyway. But by staying pleasant but firm, you might be able to avoid that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-saturday-7-short-answers-to-7-short-questions-29.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>my boss leads a clique that gossips about other staff &#8212; and now wants to have a &#8220;drunk sleepover&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-boss-leads-a-clique-that-gossips-about-other-staff-and-now-wants-to-have-a-drunk-sleepover.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-boss-leads-a-clique-that-gossips-about-other-staff-and-now-wants-to-have-a-drunk-sleepover.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 18:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advice about your boss]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5617</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Would you do me a favor?  Voting in the Bloggie Awards closes this weekend, so if you haven&#8217;t yet voted for Ask a Manager, would you please take a second to do it now? (I&#8217;m nominated in the Best Topical Blog category). Thank you &#8212; I really appreciate it! Now, here&#8217;s a crazy one to end [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>Would you do me a favor?  Voting in the Bloggie Awards closes this weekend, so if you haven&#8217;t yet voted for Ask a Manager, would you please <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es/#topical">take a second to do it now</a>? (I&#8217;m nominated in the Best Topical Blog category). Thank you &#8212; I really appreciate it!</p>
<p>Now, here&#8217;s a crazy one to end the week. A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I work for the government in a small office where there is one director, nine educational specialists (of which I am one), five support staff, and four specialists who share our office space but actually report to a different department. I originally applied for a specialist position, and while I did not get the job, they hired me as support staff because they wanted me at the organization and I had the necessary skills. After one month, the person they hired for the specialist position quit, and I was asked to apply again. This time, I was selected!</em></p>
<p><em>The director of our organization was promoted just before I was hired. Previously, she had been a specialist for many years, and the other specialists are some of her very best friends. I like her and the other specialists and I have enjoyed my job a lot so far. However, last week I was invited out for dinner and drinks, which is where my problems began. I really did not want to spend my Friday night “at work” (because for me, this dinner was going to cause me a lot of anxiety and make me work at socializing all night long), but I decided to go and try to build relationships.</em></p>
<p><em>At the dinner were my boss and six of the nine specialists. They have all worked together for over three years and have made their “girls nights” a tradition, so no spouses are allowed. I assumed the other three specialists were not there because of schedule conflicts, but I found out during the course of the night that two of them are not invited because they are male and these dinners are only for ladies, and the other female specialist is not invited because they don’t get along. They also do not seem to like the male specialists very much.</em></p>
<p><em>I was hoping to be able to learn a little bit about my colleagues and boss’s hobbies and families, but instead they spent the entire evening venting and gossiping about the employees that weren’t there. I assumed that there would be SOME “shop talk,” but I felt very uncomfortable because our boss was joining in (and unlike the rest of them, I haven’t been friends with her since before she was a supervisor) and because I didn’t have anything to contribute to the conversation. I really don’t like gossip, I don’t like negativity, and I happen to like the support staff and specialists who weren’t there. By the end of the night, my previous boss and current colleague had shared details about my family that I had mistakenly thought were from private conversations between us, I knew the scores that the people who weren’t there had received on their annual performance reviews, and I had basically been warned “what happens in Vegas stays in Vegas!”</em></p>
<p><em>They want to have a “drunk sleepover” in a few months which everyone is excited about. These are academic professionals ranging in age from 35-60 (I am in my 20s, but I used to be a teacher so this is not my first professional job) and I had assumed they would behave more professionally. I have zero interest in going out with them again, but I know that will put me on the “outside” with the rest of the office and they will probably spend their next dinner gossiping about my performance reviews. I also feel that now I can’t go to my boss with any problems because it will be spread around to everyone in the office, and I am a rather private person.</em></p>
<p><em>Can you offer any advice? I do enjoy the actual work I do, and of course in our economy I am grateful to have a job, especially since my husband was just laid off!</em></p>
<p>What the hell?!</p>
<p>This is so wildly beyond the bounds of any acceptable behavior for managers that I don&#8217;t even know where to begin. A manager holding &#8220;women-only&#8221; dinners?! And not inviting someone because she doesn&#8217;t like her?!  And badmouthing other employees? And sharing their performance evaluation scores?!</p>
<p>And &#8230; and &#8230; I can barely even type the words. A drunk sleepover?</p>
<p>Is this some sort of job apprentice program for teenagers and your boss is a 16-year-old girl? Because otherwise, this is ludicrous.</p>
<p>You don&#8217;t want to continue to join them outside work &#8212; for exclusionary dinners, drunken sleepovers, or anything else &#8212; and so you shouldn&#8217;t. Yes, that may mean that you join the list of people discussed at those dinners, but you&#8217;re better off just resigning yourself to that than feeling obligated to join them. So they&#8217;ll talk about you. So be it. Avoid giving them fodder to discuss, and decide you don&#8217;t care about the rest of it. It sounds like you&#8217;ll have plenty of company on the list of outsiders, so it shouldn&#8217;t be too lonely of a place.</p>
<p>And meanwhile &#8230; is this where you want to stay long-term? It&#8217;s perfectly legitimate to decide that you&#8217;re just glad to have a job and you enjoy the actual work you do, and if that&#8217;s the case, then just keep your head down and focus on that. But you might also consider at some point &#8212; down the road, if not right now &#8212; whether you wouldn&#8217;t rather go somewhere where your boss acts like a grown-up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-boss-leads-a-clique-that-gossips-about-other-staff-and-now-wants-to-have-a-drunk-sleepover.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>120</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>my interviewer wants to meet over lunch, and I&#8217;m freaking out!</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-interviewer-wants-to-meet-over-lunch-and-im-freaking-out.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-interviewer-wants-to-meet-over-lunch-and-im-freaking-out.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[interviewing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5616</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A reader writes: I have been networking to try and find a job as an attorney or two years! Finally, one of my contacts has been able to get me an interview with one of the most prestigious law firms in Utah. At first I thought this would give me an inside track on getting [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>A reader writes:</p>
<p><em>I have been networking to try and find a job as an attorney or two years! Finally, one of my contacts has been able to get me an interview with one of the most prestigious law firms in Utah. At first I thought this would give me an inside track on getting the job offer, then the interviewer asked to do the interview during lunch. This has caused a lot of anxiety. Is this a serious interview or is he just doing a favor for my contact? Is this such a hassle that he can&#8217;t take time during his normal work hours to do it? What if he asks me where I want to eat? What type of place should I choose? What if he takes me to McDonalds? How should I deal with the check (I assume he&#8217;s buying)? You can see the thoughts I have been having. What do you think?</em></p>
<p>You are freaking yourself out unnecessarily, to the point that you&#8217;re not going to be able to eat without instantly vomiting on this poor guy. Take a deep breath!</p>
<p>First, no, I would not assume that a lunch interview means that it&#8217;s not a serious interview or that it&#8217;s such a hassle that he can&#8217;t take the time to do it during his normal work hours. Some people just operate this way &#8212; if there&#8217;s a candidate they&#8217;re interested in talking to, sometimes their default is to meet over lunch or coffee, particularly if they don&#8217;t interview a lot of people as part of their normal job. It&#8217;s not uncommon.</p>
<p>If he&#8217;s like most lunch interviewers, he will probably suggest a place to eat. But if instead he asks you, just suggest a mid-priced place near his office. While some people do hold interviews in more casual restaurants (although usually more along the lines of a Chipotle rather than a McDonald&#8217;s), the more common option is to do it in a sit-down restaurant with service at your table, so if you&#8217;re put on the spot, you should suggest a place like that.</p>
<p>Assume that he is picking up the check. This is a business expense for his company. This is always the case with any lunch interview, but you can be extra confident that it&#8217;s the case with &#8220;one of the most prestigious law firms&#8221; in your state. Seriously. They&#8217;re buying.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s see, some other things that you should keep in mind:</p>
<p>* If you&#8217;re concerned about what&#8217;s appropriate to order, take your cues from him. If he orders an appetizer, entree, and dessert, do something roughly the same. If he orders water and an appetizer and no entree, restrain the price of your own meal accordingly. Either way, don&#8217;t be the only one ordering dessert.</p>
<p>* Don&#8217;t order alcohol.</p>
<p>* Don&#8217;t order anything that&#8217;s really messy to eat, like barbecue or tacos, or anything that you know from experience gets stuck in your teeth, like spinach.</p>
<p>* If you know where you&#8217;re eating in advance, look at its menu online ahead of time, so that you can decide what to order in advance, rather than spending a lot of time deciding when you&#8217;re there.</p>
<p>* Be unfailingly polite to the wait staff. (You should always do this, of course, but in case for some reason you don&#8217;t, now is the time to start.)</p>
<p>This probably won&#8217;t be the last lunch interview you encounter in life. Don&#8217;t agonize over it, and prepare as you would for a normal interview, and you&#8217;ll be fine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/my-interviewer-wants-to-meet-over-lunch-and-im-freaking-out.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>133</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>fast answer Friday &#8212; 6 short answers to 6 short questions</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-saturday-6-short-answers-to-6-short-questions-13.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-saturday-6-short-answers-to-6-short-questions-13.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 04:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[short answers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5631</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s fast answer Friday &#8212; six short answers to six short questions. Here we go&#8230; 1. Sending a handwritten thank-you to follow up on your emailed thank-you I’m a recent grad who’s been going through a battery of interviews lately. Usually, I’m the type of girl to send a handwritten note afterward to follow up, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>It&#8217;s fast answer Friday &#8212; six short answers to six short questions. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Sending a handwritten thank-you to follow up on your emailed thank-you</strong></p>
<p><em>I’m a recent grad who’s been going through a battery of interviews lately. Usually, I’m the type of girl to send a handwritten note afterward to follow up, but the companies I’ve been interviewing with all have short time frames for making hiring decisions so I’ve been following up with emails instead. I would still like to send handwritten notes though, but I don’t want to come off as redundant. Do you have any content advice for a post-email thank-you note so that I don’t end up repeating what I’ve already said?</em></p>
<p>It should be blank, because you shouldn&#8217;t send it. Sending two thank-you notes for the same interview is going to come across as overkill. It&#8217;s too much. Sending them by email is fine to begin with, and there&#8217;s no need for another. At this point, your job is to sit tight and wait to hear back. (And good luck.)</p>
<p><strong>2. Asking to telecommute to an unpaid internship</strong></p>
<p><em>If an internship is unpaid, is it ok to ask if you can telecommute? I think this is a reasonable request, but I have found that many managers I asked to do this were either perplexed or slightly offended that I asked. I don’t want to pretend that I don’t live in the real world and that I don’t have bills to pay, because I do, and I would like hiring managers to recognize that. I want the experience, but I have eat. What is the best way to articulate this request?</em></p>
<p>Well, a lot of them aren&#8217;t going to be amenable to it, as you&#8217;re discovering. Many internships are designed to be based in the organization&#8217;s office because they involve interaction with other people, going to meetings, being available for ad hoc conversations, and other work that&#8217;s more easily done in-person. Moreover, with very entry-level work where part of the point is to provide feedback and development, managers usually find it easier to have a face-to-face relationship. So you can ask, but realize that a lot of them will say no &#8212; so make sure you do it at the very beginning of your conversation with any employer, because if you wait until the end of the hiring process, many are going to be irritated that you didn&#8217;t bring it up earlier (so that they didn&#8217;t invest further time in the hiring process if it&#8217;s a deal-breaker for them).</p>
<p><strong>3. I&#8217;m being told to donate my time to our CEO&#8217;s second organization</strong></p>
<p><em>I am the assistant to the CEO of a large nonprofit. As such, I not only help my boss, but also help out where ever needed. He recently started another nonprofit that is completely separate from the agency I am employed with. They keep different accounts, have different staff, and are a completely separate entity. I am not an employee of theirs, and their employees are not listed on our payroll.</em></p>
<p><em>Saying that, my boss who heads both organizations often asks me and a few other staff members to help out with things for this organization. They currently rent a space in our building. I love helping out, but the work is interfering with the already large work load I have. They are basically getting free labor for our agency staff, and aren&#8217;t reimbursing for any hours that we put in. Our accounting department and our independent auditor have discussed billing for our time, but there haven&#8217;t been any action made to remedy the situation.</em></p>
<p><em>I want to approach my boss about the extra workload and how I am confused about how these separate agency fits into our own (we provide completely different services). Any suggestions? Or should I just suck it up and do the work hoping the problem will eventually fix itself?</em></p>
<p>Talk to your boss. Tell him that the work for the second organization is interfering with your ability to put your own organization first. Tell him that you&#8217;re uneasy about essentially volunteering your services for the other organization during time that you&#8217;re being paid by Organization 1, and that you&#8217;re not comfortable continuing to do it, at least not without a formal arrangement where Organization 2 is billed for your time.</p>
<p>You can also go back to your accounting department and push them to handle this, since &#8230; well, since they should. And out of curiosity, does your nonprofit&#8217;s board know that the CEO is diverting the organization&#8217;s resources to his own separate organization? If not, they probably won&#8217;t be pleased to hear it.</p>
<p><strong>4. Is it normal for contractors not to get feedback or performance reviews?</strong></p>
<p><em>I have been a government contractor working on-site for a large national institution for over 2 years. I like my job, but am becoming increasingly frustrated by that lack of feedback I receive from my manager. There are no performance reviews performed by my actual manager, who is a contractor from a different contracting company. I have the same position as eight other people and am losing my motivation to do a good job.</em></p>
<p><em>My superviser will casually say that I am doing a good job and thanks me for my work on various projects from time to time. He has even said that they couldn&#8217;t afford to lose me. The contract company I work for has almost no idea what I actually do all day and rarely communicates with me. They do an annual performance review where they basically check in with me for 10 minutes and give me a small raise, which I believe is given at the same rate to all of their other employees. I&#8217;m sure if there were a problem that was relayed to them from my supervisor I would hear about it, but positive feedback is never really relayed. I feel I am not being rewarded, financially or verbally, for doing work that is in some cases better than others who have my job. I watch one of them play video games for most of the day and ignore emails, while I work late to make sure my clients are happy. But we are treated the same.</em></p>
<p><em>This may be a fault, but I recognize that I do better and stay motivated by positive feedback. Is it normal for contractors not to recieve feedback or have a performance review with their on-site supervisor? What can I do to ask for a raise when the people who grant it don&#8217;t know what I do or how well I do it, really?</em></p>
<p>Yes, it&#8217;s pretty normal. In fact, it&#8217;s a widespread problem even among non-contractor employees and their managers &#8230; but among contractors, it&#8217;s often considered not even a problem, but rather par for the course with contracting.</p>
<p>You can certainly make a case for a raise by pointing to your achievements, just like you&#8217;d make a case for a raise normally &#8230; but realize that in the environment you&#8217;re working in, they may find it more efficient to treat you all as a group, without much individualized attention.</p>
<p><strong>5. Negotiating when a company has just been acquired</strong></p>
<p><em>I recently interviewed for a job with a start up. I was told that there would be no equity/stocks or options as my compensation, only the basics salary, med, 401. I agreed. My final interview is next week.</em></p>
<p><em>The company got acquired yesterday. They are eager to hire me. However, as I see it, we are now part of a larger org and my duties will increase and my initial negotiation had been with a start-up but that has changed. This situation is new to me and I would like to know what I can negotiate to get the best package due to this changed situation. Can you please advise?</em></p>
<p>Yeah, it&#8217;s a different situation now. But it doesn&#8217;t sound like you&#8217;d already discussed salary, only benefits, and being acquired doesn&#8217;t mean that they&#8217;ll necessarily be offering equity now (in fact, it might be less likely). In any case, if they make you an offer, you can certainly ask about the changed landscape in light of the situation, and you then proceed with your negotiations accordingly. You&#8217;re not locked into anything yet.</p>
<p><strong>6. Putting church community outreach work on your resume</strong></p>
<p><em>I was just asked to help out with a community outreach committee at my church. My dream job would be to do community programming in the museum field, so it&#8217;s something that I want to do. I&#8217;m wondering if I do end up helping with community programming at the church (something I have done in the past), would it be OK to add to a resume? The community outreach is more in the way of helping people and events, not pushing the bible down their throats (ew).</em></p>
<p>Sure, you can absolutely put that on your resume. In general, assume that volunteer work can always go on a resume. Just be specific about exactly what you did, since volunteer work is often described in a vague way that doesn&#8217;t really convey what the person actually did.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/short-answer-saturday-6-short-answers-to-6-short-questions-13.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>96</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>update on the reference for the brilliant but abusive former manager</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/update-on-the-reference-from-the-brilliant-but-abusive-former-manager.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/update-on-the-reference-from-the-brilliant-but-abusive-former-manager.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 19:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[updates]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5629</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Remember the letter-writer last month who was wondering how and whether to give a reference for a brilliant but abusive former manager? Here&#8217;s here update. I called my colleague on the phone and told him that I had both some positive and negative things to say, and asked that it stay off the record. He [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>Remember the letter-writer last month who was wondering how and whether to give a reference for a <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2013/02/giving-a-reference-for-a-brilliant-but-abusive-former-manager.html">brilliant but abusive former manager</a>? Here&#8217;s here update.</p>
<p><em>I called my colleague on the phone and told him that I had both some positive and negative things to say, and asked that it stay off the record. He was totally cool about it, so I laid out basically what I wrote in my post: I think she could have great vision for the institution, but that she was sometimes hard to work with as she could be very sharp with her reports. I suggested that her skill set (grant writing, visioning, tech planning, etc) would potentially be really useful, but that her personnel management was weaker.</em></p>
<p><em>My colleague listened carefully and said that the position had actually been explicitly designed to have the director position be someone who could schmooze with the bigwigs, write grants, and provide vision and that his position would be actually be the one managing the employees. Great! Except he was concerned that all her &#8220;sharpness&#8221; would fall on him as the only report to her! I told him that I actually managed to have a really good working relationship with her and thought that it might not be as problematic if she only had one report to work with.</em></p>
<p><em>Anyway, it gave him some food for thought. I tried my best to be honest about the potential drawbacks and also be positive about the potential advantages. Some people in the comments suggested that she doesn&#8217;t deserve any kind of management job, but others commented on the possibility of putting her in a position where her strengths could be capitalized on and weaknesses minimized. My position is that I certainly don&#8217;t want to scuttle anyone&#8217;s career, but I also don&#8217;t want her damaging future institutions or employees.</em></p>
<p><em>It may be that if she&#8217;s hired they could simply be honest about what they heard? e.g. &#8220;We heard from various references that you have a history of anger management issues and while we think you&#8217;re great and want to offer you the job we need you to understand that that kind of behavior won&#8217;t be tolerated here. ABC are the consequences for such behavior.&#8221; I haven&#8217;t heard of that happening, but who knows.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/update-on-the-reference-from-the-brilliant-but-abusive-former-manager.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>should you be earning more money? these 3 people want to know.</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-be-earning-more-money.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-be-earning-more-money.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 16:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[salary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5622</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I figured I&#8217;d bundle three somewhat-related salary-related questions into one post. Here we go&#8230; 1. Should my promotion come with a higher raise? Today I accepted a promotion at work after waiting for the formal offer/salary for almost two weeks. The salary is about $5,000 less than I wanted (and I was aiming for $15,000 [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>I figured I&#8217;d bundle three somewhat-related salary-related questions into one post. Here we go&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>1. Should my promotion come with a higher raise?</strong></p>
<p><em>Today I accepted a promotion at work after waiting for the formal offer/salary for almost two weeks. The salary is about $5,000 less than I wanted (and I was aiming for $15,000 less than online pay scales state).</em></p>
<p><em>The thing is, it&#8217;s a decent raise from my current wage: 20%. It is also my first management position. However, I do bring skills that no one else in the company has and have produced work over the past year for which they would normally pay a consultant twice my wage. Am I being greedy in wanting more?</em></p>
<p><em>I feel foolish because I didn&#8217;t negotiate: the director who called me phrased it as though it was a great salary and I should be happy. I was stressed after waiting to find out the salary for so long (they told me right after my interview that they planned to offer me the job and they advertised for my current position a week ago). I felt like I had no choice but to accept.</em></p>
<p><em>They built this role up to sound very high-profile (significant responsibility nationally) and so I expected a salary closer to those I see online. Have I just accepted a much lower wage than this role would normally receive?</em></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know. But it&#8217;s your first management position, so you represent a risk and you&#8217;re guaranteed to need to learn on the job, and so it probably makes sense for them to pay you less than they&#8217;d be paying a more experienced and tested candidate.</p>
<p>As for salaries you see online &#8230; are you talking about salaries that you see in job listings, or salary websites like salary.com? Salary websites, unfortunately, aren&#8217;t going to give you very accurate information; they generally don’t account for the fact that job titles frequently represent wildly different scopes of responsibility, or vary significantly by type of company or geography. (You can get a far <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2011/05/09/how-to-determine-what-salary-to-ask-for">more accurate idea</a> by simply bouncing figures off of other people in your field, checking with professional organizations in your industry, or talking with recruiters.)</p>
<p>But what&#8217;s <em>most</em> useful is knowing what salary <em>you</em> can command on the market &#8212; you, with your particular set of skills, experience, and ability to market yourself. That&#8217;s very different from what knowing what a huge swatch of people all performing vaguely similar duties with very different skill levels at wildly different companies around the country can command.</p>
<p><strong>2. MBA working as executive assistant, disappointed in raise</strong></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve been an executive assistant at a large and prosperous firm for about a year now. Although being an EA wasn&#8217;t my original plan, when I graduated from my MBA program and spent many months applying like a madwoman and interviewing to no avail, I decided to take this job because of the security and great benefits.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve ended up loving my job and excelling at it. I frequently have to ask if there is any more help I could offer because I finish my regular tasks quickly. I received shining evaluations from the two executives I work under, and was called in to talk about my &#8220;raise&#8221; at the end of this year. It was $1,000. I was disappointed because I have received nothing but praise since starting here, and was hired at nearly $10,000 less than what I initially asked for. I figured that after a year of proving myself, they would at least try to meet me in the middle. Now I know that I should have advocated for myself more, but I was in shock at the time and unsure how to react.</em></p>
<p><em>I&#8217;ve researched and even after my &#8220;raise,&#8221; my salary is significantly lower than even the low range of EA salaries listed on websites such as glassdoor.com. I have an MBA and finance/accounting experience, and now make even less than I did before I received my graduate degree. I am frustrated because I love my job, my firm, my coworkers and the company culture and don&#8217;t want to leave, but I also feel like I have sealed my fate by accepting what I was initially given and then this small cost of living raise. It&#8217;s now several months later and I feel it would be awkward to bring it up now. I don&#8217;t want to settle for less than I deserve, but I also don&#8217;t want to leave. Is it too late?</em></p>
<p>Well, again, websites like glassdoor or salary.com aren&#8217;t going to give you very accurate information. See #1 above. But you could probably get more reliable information by talking with recruiters or people with similar jobs at similarly sized companies in your area.</p>
<p>However, what you definitely <em>don&#8217;t</em> want to do is to base your raise request on having an MBA or on what you made before your graduate degree. It needs to be based on the value you bring to the company. Simply having an graduate degree doesn&#8217;t generally warrant a higher salary in most fields, particularly in a role that doesn&#8217;t require one; salary is about the value of the work you&#8217;re doing to the company. Are you using the MBA in significant ways in your role? If not, then you can&#8217;t reasonably expect that it will factor in to what you&#8217;re paid. (Although if you <em>are</em> using it in significant ways, and if that&#8217;s not something generally expected of the person in your role, then it can become part of your case.)</p>
<p>Keep in mind, too, that depending on what percentage it is of your total salary, $1,000 might not be such a paltry raise. The average raise nationally is 3%. I don&#8217;t know what you earn, but if you&#8217;re earning close to the national average income of $43,000, 3% is $1,290, or pretty close to what you got. Of course, if you&#8217;re not an average performer, you deserve more &#8212; but it might be useful to know that it&#8217;s not the shocking insult that it might have seemed at first.</p>
<p>In any case &#8230; It&#8217;s not too late to go back and say that you think you&#8217;ve earned a larger raise. Here&#8217;s some advice on how to <a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/blogs/outside-voices-careers/2011/04/11/10-tips-for-negotiating-a-raise">make that case</a>. Just make sure that you base it on your value to the company in your current role and what you&#8217;ve achieved there.</p>
<p><strong>3</strong><strong>. Boss doesn&#8217;t care if people leave over money</strong></p>
<p><em>I have worked in the accounts department of a property management company for 5 years. There are approximately 45 employees. I am happy in my job, most of my coworkers are great, the hours are flexible, and it&#8217;s close to home.</em></p>
<p><em>My boss is the owner of the business and is very tight when it comes to paying anyone what he should or what they are actually worth. Four years ago, I spoke to him about a raise and questioned whether he does performance reviews because I had been there over a year and nothing had been mentioned. Prior to speaking to the boss, I asked a coworker about the procedure for a review and pay raise, etc. and they told me not to bother, because &#8220;the boss doesn&#8217;t give raises.&#8221; I was really surprised, but I didn&#8217;t let it stop me from asking for one anyway. So, when I spoke to the boss and stated my case as to why I deserved a raise, he confirmed he doesn&#8217;t do annual reviews, but would consider my request for a raise. A month went by before he told me he had decided to give me the raise, but it was a very small one.</em></p>
<p><em>Since then, I haven&#8217;t approached him about another raise, but I know I certainly deserve one! Mind you, the company has had quite a few employees leave because they have asked for more money and the boss has knocked them back. He thinks everyone is dispensible, so he doesn&#8217;t care if they leave. So, recently, I have been thinking perhaps I should state my case again, but instead of asking in person, should I put it in writing? I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s going to be worth my while even though I know he doesn&#8217;t pay me what he should. I feel stuck inbetween a rock and a hard place &#8212; I don&#8217;t want to leave my job but I am finding it hard to earn so little. It also makes me feel unappreciated too. I&#8217;m not afraid to ask him for a raise in person but I feel like it would be a waste of time. What do you think my next step should be?</em></p>
<p>There&#8217;s no advantage to putting in writing over asking in person. In fact, asking in person is usually the better route, since it allows for an actual conversation.</p>
<p>But, you know, you&#8217;ve been there five years. If your boss won&#8217;t give you the salary you want, it would make more sense to either move on or accept that you&#8217;re staying for reasons of your own (whether it&#8217;s liking the work, your coworkers, the flexibility, or whatever). This is what your employer pays for the work you do and it&#8217;s up to you whether to accept it or not accept it, but it&#8217;s not really fair (or good for your own state of mind) to accept it and then complain that he&#8217;s cheap and not paying people what they&#8217;re worth.</p>
<p>So either you want to stay under these terms, or you don&#8217;t. But trying to have it both ways is going to frustrate you endlessly, and probably won&#8217;t get you what you want.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/should-you-be-earning-more-money.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>update on the networking group with the high-pressure sales tactics</title>
		<link>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/update-on-the-networking-group-with-the-high-pressure-sales-tactics.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/update-on-the-networking-group-with-the-high-pressure-sales-tactics.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ask a Manager</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[updates]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.askamanager.org/?p=5613</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Remember the reader whose new networking group used high-pressure sales tactics, including requiring members to promote and buy from other members&#8217; businesses and pushing members to get friends to attend their meetings? Here&#8217;s her update. You were right &#8211; SCAM! I joined this so-called &#8220;networking group&#8221; in mid-October and by early February, members started dropping. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p><p>Remember the reader whose <a href="http://www.askamanager.org/2012/11/my-new-networking-group-uses-high-pressure-sales-tactics.html">new networking group used high-pressure sales tactics</a>, including requiring members to promote and buy from other members&#8217; businesses and pushing members to get friends to attend their meetings? Here&#8217;s her update.</p>
<p><em>You were right &#8211; SCAM! </em></p>
<p><em>I joined this so-called &#8220;networking group&#8221; in mid-October and by early February, members started dropping. In November, we were at 9 people, and although another chapter in our city kept claiming they had 4 or 5 new applications per week (yeah, right), our growth seemed to stagnate. </em><em>When we were at 5 remaining members, we met with our chapter&#8217;s coordinator (a paid position, working for this company) and expressed our concerns. She tried to rev us all up about re-launching the chapter, etc., which frankly seemed like a lot of work for little return. </em></p>
<p><em>We questioned her pretty intensely about the future of the chapter and the promises made to all of us when we paid our membership fees, including whether some of us could transfer our membership to the other, supposedly more-successful chapter. She finally got angry and told us that none of us could transfer to the other chapter without paying the membership fee again and that none of us were getting our money back for any reason, &#8220;because that&#8217;s just not how the company works.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>I spoke to my boss and offered to pay back my membership fee; she said that wasn&#8217;t necessary, just find something else that works better. Since I left the group, I have spoken to several other current and former members, and learned a lot about this company and its &#8220;founder and CEO&#8221; &#8212; none of it good, but we did seem to do some bonding during these information-sharing sessions! </em></p>
<p><em>It was a good decision to leave, I just wish I had researched it more before I joined &#8212; lesson learned. I&#8217;m spending more time with the community and volunteer groups I like and with whom I have interests in common &#8212; people who already know me and trust me, and are likely to send business my way when they remember I&#8217;m around.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.askamanager.org/2013/03/update-on-the-networking-group-with-the-high-pressure-sales-tactics.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
