<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Cowardly Feminist</title>
	<atom:link href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com</link>
	<description>Pop Culture and Modern Woman&#039;s Battle with the F-Word (Feminism)</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 01:04:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Oh damn, I forgot about my blog.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6589#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6589#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 01:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I am a busy bee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6589</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Man, I guess I took an unplanned, unannounced blogging break this week, which is more or less the same thing as saying I slacked off on posting. Sorry y’all. My husband has been out of town again for work. Whenever &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6589">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Man, I guess I took an unplanned, unannounced blogging break this week, which is more or less the same thing as saying I slacked off on posting. Sorry y’all.</p>
<p>My husband has been out of town again for work. Whenever this happens and I know he’ll be gone for more than a day or two, I always think the same thing – <strong>I Am Going To Get Shit Done</strong>. It’ll be great, no timetable, interruption, or consideration of anyone else’s schedule. I will be a bundle of smug productivity. And I was. I busted my butt on non-blog writing and various other projects &#8211; productive was my middle name. But the smug part, as always, dissipated at about the 48 hour mark. Two days in is usually when I realize I’ve only spoken face to face with the dogs, and possibly the mail man. I start to miss my other half, and just like that, I go from happily Doing Stuff to <i>hey this sucks</i>.</p>
<p>My husband works long hours, so a lot of times I only see him once during the day. Sometimes he’s out the door at 4:30 in the morning, and other times he doesn’t get home until midnight. But, at some point during the day, we usually have the opportunity to hang out and chit chat. So I get antsy after 48 hours of just me, myself, and I. I like having my man around to bullshit with, and let’s face it, the dogs don’t laugh at my jokes.</p>
<p>What makes matters worse is that my husband was in Austin this week. As in Texas. As in <i>my beloved</i> <i>home</i>. So not only am I stuck flying solo, I’m getting updates about how beautiful the hill country is, favorite restaurants, and basically all the stuff I pine for, especially right now, because springtime in Texas is fantastic. Take this morning, for example. The phone rang around nine, and when I picked up my husband said this:<i><br />
</i></p>
<p><i>I fucking LOVE Austin! It’s 75 degrees, with just a touch of humidity, it’s perfect outside! Okay, I’ve gotta run.<br />
</i></p>
<p>Then he hung up on me. Yes, babe, I know it’s awesome. Don’t get me wrong, I’m thrilled he loves my home state as much as me, but that doesn’t stop me from being just a <i>little</i> bitter he’s there and I’m not. In a few short hours I pick up him up from the airport, and I’m certain he will taunt me with more tales of Texas in late March. Sigh.</p>
<p>Anyway, sorry for the slackerly-ness folks. Back on track next week. I think.</p>
<p>Enjoy the weekend!</p>
<!--post 6589; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6589</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speculation time!</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6566#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6566#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 23:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Glass]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6566</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So this morning I read an io9 article, What will human cultures be like in 100 years? This is my favorite sort of speculation game. We really have no clue what we’ll be like in a century, but it sure &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6566">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So this morning I read an io9 article, <a href="http://io9.com/what-will-human-cultures-be-like-in-100-years-453934475" target="_blank"><i>What will human cultures be like in 100 years?</i> </a>This is my favorite sort of speculation game. We really have no clue what we’ll be like in a century, but it sure is fun to think about (or depressing depending on your outlook towards humanity). Unfortunately, the what if game resulted in me wasting half the day reading about bipedal robots, which subsequently led me to the new <i>Transformers </i>movie. Who goes to see those? And how in the hell did Mark Walberg get roped into the franchise? Actually, I might consider seeing a non-Shia<em> Transformers</em>.</p>
<p>Clearly, I need some sort of shock collar that automatically zaps me every time I get distracted for longer than five minutes on the internet.</p>
<p>Anyway, my dad and I were just talking about <a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/18/google-glass-backlash/" target="_blank">Google Glass</a>, which turned into a conversation about evolution. My dad thinks we’ll eventually evolve to have necks that swoop down, which makes sense considering how much time we spent bent over our tablets, phones, iPods, and whatever (although technology like Glass might prevent that from happening, since we can once again look forward). Several years ago in a physical anthropology seminar, the professor spent a class discussing how, very rapidly, we’ve become a culture in which bipedalism is not the ideal human form because we spend too much time sitting on our asses. Obviously, it’s impossible to know how we’ll evolve, but it&#8217;s entertaining to imagine our future generations as swoop-necked beings with legs bent and splayed from eons of sitting on our behinds. Given the new form, pants would be impossible, so really quite a few of us are already ahead of the curve. Hell yes.</p>
<p>What I liked most about the io9 article was the discussion of what will become of old people. The author likens senior citizens to teenagers in that they have tons of time and not a lot of cash. I would never, ever want to be a teen again, but the idea of having more time, less responsibility, and none of the hormonal angst, doesn’t sound half bad.</p>
<p>I actually ponder what will become of us when we’re old frequently, although it’s hard for me to not envision a <i>Welcome to the Monkey House </i>future. While I may not be around in 100 years, there is a good possibility I’ll still be here in seventy. Seven. Zero. That’s a long freaking time. So, I avidly read any literature that comes my way regarding the science of aging. I know a lot of people dislike the idea of tampering with nature, but I do hope scientists find a way to combat aging (and not for vanity reasons, thank you very much. Well, mostly not for vanity). I’d rather not spend the last 40 years of my life with creaky knees and hip problems, and I&#8217;m banking on someone figuring out an economically feasible way to make that happen. If we&#8217;re extended longevity, then let&#8217;s make sure the quality is good too.</p>
<p>But if we do figure out a way to finally halt our cells from aging, then what? What do we do with all the extra people? It’s a legitimate concern, especially considering many of us will be the elderly folks in question decades down the road. Perhaps by that time we’ll have figured out a plan for long-term space colonization. We are, after all, talking about fifty to seventy years, so it’s entirely possible. The way I figure it, either they’ll start shuttling us old folks off to space, or, the planet will be such a toxic wasteland that the youth will be the ones in space, leaving the fogies on planet Earth. Since I already live in the pollution-infested badlands of LA County, I’m not too bothered by that scenario, it can’t be all that different.</p>
<p>Anyway, if this is old age, then bring it. They look like they’re having a blast.<br />
<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/_8Y5ze4YrTs" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<!--post 6566; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6566</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Just listen, doc.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6537#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6537#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 16:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender gap in healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laurie Edwards]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6537</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sunday I came down with some sort of stomach bug, or had a touch a food poisoning, or something. Whatever it was, it was no bueno, and as a result yesterday was not very productive. But today? Dude, there is &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6537">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sunday I came down with some sort of stomach bug, or had a touch a food poisoning, or something. Whatever it was, it was no bueno, and as a result yesterday was not very productive. But today? Dude, there is nothing like waking up to find you are no longer ill &#8211; it totally makes you feel kick ass, even though what you’re really feeling is normal.</p>
<p>Anyway, I did actually write a post yesterday. However, when I read it this morning I thought, <i>why does this sound so…ranty and shouty</i>? And long, it was ridiculously long. The topic is important though, so I decided to do a (less angry) rewrite.</p>
<p>Over the weekend I read the NY Times online article <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/17/opinion/sunday/women-and-the-treatment-of-pain.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=0" target="_blank"><i>The Gender Gap in Pain</i></a> , by Laurie Edwards. She discussed the relationship between biological and gender differences of males and females, as how they affect drug dosing and treatment in the healthcare system. Biologically, men and women respond differently to various drugs. Obviously we have very different body types, which means we don&#8217;t always metabolize drugs in the same way. Edwards also points out that women are more prone than men to have chronic pain and autoimmune diseases (three times more likely, as a matter of fact). In spite of this, complaints of pain from women are more likely to be dismissed by health care professionals. She writes:</p>
<p><i>This is a serious problem, because pain is subjective and self-reported, and diagnosis and treatment depend on the assumption that the person reporting symptoms is beyond doubt. </i></p>
<p><i>The oft-cited study “The Girl Who Cried Pain: A Bias Against Women in the Treatment of Pain” found that women were less likely to receive aggressive treatment when diagnosed, and were more likely to have their pain characterized as “emotional,” “psychogenic” and therefore “not real.” </i></p>
<p><i>Instead of appropriate care for physical pain, this can lead to treatment for mental health issues that might not even exist.</i></p>
<p>I not only agree with Edwards, but I would further add that healthcare professionals don&#8217;t just dismiss complaints of women involving pain. They have a frightening tendency to assume any physical ailment is emotionally related.</p>
<p>I was fortunate enough to get through my teens, early, and mid 20s without ever being sick (aside from the self-inflicted, too much partying kind). I had health insurance, but never used it. In my late 20s I began having problems, which eventually I found out were related to my blood sugar. In between that final diagnosis and my first visit, was a string of doctors that refused to listen to me. I cannot tell you how many physicians tried to prescribe me anti-anxiety drugs for my symptoms. And it’s important to note they were all general practitioners. The frustrating part was that I knew my symptoms were physical, and they insisted it was ‘in my head’, without ever ordering any tests to asses my physical health. I had one doctor accuse me of having an eating disorder. Another absolutely insisted what I was describing was an anxiety attack, even though I patiently explained over and over to him that I was not having any anxiety issues. He went so far as to say that perhaps it was something stemming from my childhood, and had the audacity to ask if I was sexually abused. I was appalled, to put it mildly, and needless to say never visited him again. Traversing the healthcare system was new to me, and it wasn’t until, out of complete frustration, I threw a freaking hissy fit that I finally received a referral to an endocrinologist. In a very short period of time, he determined that my problems were indeed physical.</p>
<p>My point is this – depression and anxiety are serious issues, and as such physicians must look out for warning signs, therefore I completely understand why I was asked about my mental health. In fact, questions relating to emotions are standard on a new patient health questionnaire. What I can’t understand is why a half dozen doctors would refuse to consider my complaints were due to a genuine physical issue, and not psychosomatic. To be honest, I came to a point where I began to question myself. Is this in my head? Are they right? When I was finally diagnosed, I felt relieved, but also angry it took so long to get there.</p>
<p>The gender gap problem in health care is greater than just pain &#8211; it encompasses all diagnoses. It’s also important to note that this happens to men too. My dad visited a dozen doctors over the course of several years, some of which flat out told him the symptoms he described were in his head. What he actually had was a tumor, a large one, and it was releasing toxins into his system. Thankfully, someone finally <i>listened </i>to him, sent him to a specialist, and it was removed. He lived, but what if that final doctor had dismissed his complaints too?  Who knows what the outcome would have been?</p>
<p>I think it&#8217;s safe to say the healthcare system as a whole is a mess. But the gender gap and this widespread phenomenon of physicians dismissing any complaint that isn&#8217;t easily diagnosable are both important issues that needs to be addressed sooner rather than later. How do we go about doing it? I’m not sure, but perhaps getting the word out is a good first step. Healthcare, like anything else, is a business. Doctors certainly treat it that way, and so should we. If you are unhappy with the service your healthcare professional is providing,<em> be vocal about it.</em></p>
<!--post 6537; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6537</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>I don’t know what made me think of crabs. Also, vote.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6509#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6509#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 23:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bloggie Awards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crabs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grasshoppers are scary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6509</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So this morning I got up, dealt with the dogs, and then made coffee because I once again forgot to set it up the night before. While waiting for the caffeine to happen I crawled back in bed. For no &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6509">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So this morning I got up, dealt with the dogs, and then made coffee because I once again forgot to set it up the night before. While waiting for the caffeine to happen I crawled back in bed. For no discernable reason I started thinking about the following event from my childhood:</p>
<p>We were in Rockport, which is a little coastal town in Texas. I don’t remember why, but my dad brought my sister and I early, and our mom was to drive in a day or two later. Anyway, my dad decided to take us crabbing. We must have spent a couple of hours on the dock, laughing at my dad as he tried to chase down a crab that got away, and in general having a blast. After we filled our bucket, my dad carted us back to the little place where we stayed, and set about getting everything ready to boil the crabs. As soon as he dropped the first one in the pot, my little sister started screaming bloody murder.<b><i><br />
</i></b></p>
<p><strong><i>“NOOOOOOO! MY CRAAAAAAABS!! MY CRAAAAAAAAABS!!”</i></strong><b><i><br />
</i></b></p>
<p>Honestly, you would have thought he dropped in a puppy from the fit she pitched. I guess Monkey Girl assumed we were catching the crabs to keep, not to eat, and she was upset that my dad planned to callously murder her new pets. My poor pops, I can still vividly recall the look on his face, which pretty much said <i>oh crap what have I done?</i></p>
<p>Needless to say, we did not eat the crabs, and if I recall correctly she made my dad take them back to the water. By that time they were all dead, I’m sure, but he did it anyway.</p>
<div id="attachment_6512" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 203px"><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/big-hair.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class="size-full wp-image-6512" alt="big hair" src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/big-hair.jpg" width="193" height="261" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My mom looks nothing like John Stamos but her hair resembled his, only longer and fluffier on the bottom. And no, mom, you are not allowed to be mad at me, it&#8217;s an accurate description. Plus, it was the 80s, everyone had bad hair. I had crunchy bangs with Sun In, for crying out loud.</p></div>
<p>The next day my mom drove in – she opened the door and before anyone could say a word she was blabbering away frantically, a mile a minute, about a monster in her car. It was the 80s, and she had big hair, which was completely blown askew. She told my dad some huge thing flew in her car fifty miles back, and that she barreled down the highway going a hundred miles an hour in the hopes a cop would pull her over (so said cop could  save her from the monster). My dad finally got her to calm down, and went to go check out whatever it was in the car that tried to kill my mom.</p>
<p>It was a grasshopper.</p>
<p>I haven’t thought about the trip in years, and I really have no idea why it sprung to mind this morning, but thinking about it made me laugh, which is really hard to do before coffee.</p>
<p>On a completely unrelated note – If we&#8217;re peeps on facebook you can stop reading because you already heard this spiel, but, Sunday is the last day to vote in the Bloggies. I am up for Best Topical and Weblog of the Year, and don’t forget to vote for my bloggy buddies, Bondo of <a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">Movie Review Warehouse</a> is up for Best Entertainment, and Greg of <a href="http://dogsondrugs.com/" target="_blank">Dogs on Drugs</a> is up for Best Writing. You can vote <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>Make it happen, y’all. Happy Friday!</p>
<!--post 6509; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6509</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Round and round we go.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6487#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6487#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 03:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big life decisions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biological clock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child-free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female/male communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6487</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[First, let me say that I know I’ve already written about our decision not to have kids a half dozen times. Second, I was actually going to post about something else today, but for the past five minutes the kid &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6487">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First, let me say that I know I’ve already written about our decision not to have kids a half dozen times. Second, I was actually going to post about something else today, but for the past five minutes the kid next door has been screaming <b>I HATE YOU</b> at the top of his lungs, making it impossible for me to concentrate on my other topic. I always expect him to be hoarse, but the screeching seems to have no ill effect on his vocal cords.</p>
<p>Anyway.</p>
<p>Going back to the first thought, if you think I’ve written about whether or not to have children repeatedly, then try to imagine how many times I’ve discussed it with my husband. The answer is thousands. Tens of thousands, even.</p>
<p>I have never, ever wanted kids, I’m just not a maternal person. However, in the past two years my biological clock finally started ticking. In spite of this, I still don’t really want children. Many of my reasons are very personal, and so I’ve never gone into detail when writing. Suffice it to say kids probably aren&#8217;t in the cards for me. But, that doesn’t mean I don’t get that gooey squishy innit-so-cute feeling whenever I set eyes on a baby. I get that way about puppies and kittens too, always have. I have <em>not</em> always felt that way about babies. In fact, I used to think babies were sort of weird looking. They have such big heads, and they’re so marshmallow-y &#8211; it’s a little disconcerting. Now I get it. I may not want it, but I totally get it. They are irresistible little buggers.</p>
<p>I’m in my mid-30s, and the time to have kids is rapidly diminishing for us. My husband is not remotely interested, and when I actually think about what all goes in to having kids, neither am I. But there is this nagging suspicion in the back of my mind that worries we will regret this decision one day. Also, most of the couples we know have at least one, if not multiple children. Keep this in mind.</p>
<p>I consider myself to be a logical woman, but that does not mean I don’t engage in some stereotypical female behavior. For example, without fail, every time my husband relays a story of one of his coworkers talking to him about being a father, the first thing I ask him is, “Do you feel like you’re missing out?”</p>
<p>His answer never changes, because he is quite happy as a twosome, but when he discusses his father friends, I always wonder if he’s trying to tell me something. Of course, guys don’t do that, but since women tend to think that way we assume guys do too. Since most of our acquaintances have children, it seems the topic comes up every week or two, which means each time I mentally dissect the conversation and wonder if there is some hidden meaning to what my husband says. You&#8217;d think I would have leaned by now.</p>
<p>So, over the weekend, we were having breakfast at our favorite restaurant. Across from us was a couple with a set of twins that looked to be about 18 months, and a newborn. <i>Holy crap,</i> I said to my husband, <i>that is a lot of small persons</i>. I guess that reminded him of a conversation he had with a friend the previous night about being a dad. The gist of it was, he loves his kid, but kids consume every bit of your free time and therefore he and his wife were going to stick to just the one.</p>
<p>And so began another round of the ‘are we making a mistake’ game. Only this time, my husband held his hands up, and said with confusion, “We have had this conversation so many times, are you changing your mind?” I responded with an I don’t know, followed by a no, followed by my husband staring at me like I finally fell off the deep end.</p>
<p>The truth of the matter is that if my husband had turned to me and said, ‘yes, I want to have kids’, I probably would have passed out. I know this, and yet, I still flip flop back and forth about how I might feel in the future about the decision we have made today. What’s worse, even though I know having this conversation over and over again is driving both of us crazy, I’m pretty sure we’re going to have it again before the month of March is over. I hadn’t given much thought about why I feel the need to repeat the same discussion with my husband until today. Perhaps I’m looking for validation, who knows?</p>
<p>The decision to have children is monumental, but so is the decision not to. Clearly I am a little conflicted. I wish I wasn&#8217;t. Give me something definitive, whether it&#8217;s my old child-free way of thinking, or a new parent-minded mentality. This merry go round of mostly decided but not quite is a crummy ride.</p>
<p>PS – Just as I finished typing this, the kid across the way started up with a fresh round of I HATE YOU. He never grows tired of it.</p>
<!--post 6487; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6487</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Casting couch</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6470#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6470#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 16:12:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sweded Pacific Rim]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6470</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday I had my book club meeting. This month&#8217;s book was, for me, a tedious read, and no one else in the group cared for it either. After we discussed the details that annoyed us most, we sort of ran &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6470">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I had my book club meeting. This month&#8217;s book was, for me, a tedious read, and no one else in the group cared for it either. After we discussed the details that annoyed us most, we sort of ran out of things to say. It’s always a bit of a dull discussion when the selection is either universally loved or hated, much better when we have a mixed bag of likes and dislikes. Anyway, one of the members said that, in her old book club, when they ran out of things to talk about they resorted to casting the characters.</p>
<p>So of course I came home and spent an inordinate amount of time last night casting some of my favorite faceless bloggers. I thought my casting job was pretty good, but then I realized posting it could potentially get me into trouble.</p>
<p><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Not-Alanis.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-6471" alt="Not Alanis" src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Not-Alanis.jpg" width="300" height="181" /></a></p>
<p>Someone once told me I looked like Alanis Morissette, and I swear to god I still think that person is an asshole. Not only do I bear no resemblance to her, other than dark hair and eyes, her voice is like nails on a chalkboard to me. Worse, really. Her voice makes me feel like Malcolm McDowell in the scene from <i>A Clockwork Orange</i> where they force his eyes open for aversion therapy. Yes indeedy, her screechy songs are enough to send me running for the hills, which made me take the comparison as a personal affront. And so, you see why I opted to not post my casting list. Because even though I may have excellent reasons for choosing so and so to play the part of your life, that particular actor might be your own personal clockwork orange.</p>
<p>Since it appears this post is about nothing, I leave you with this (I love these guys)…</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/fRAqvsD1uxw" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<!--post 6470; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6470</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Things are going to start happening to me now.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6441#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6441#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 22:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lazy neighbors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telephone book]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6441</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Longtime readers may remember the series of alters I made around the telephone book my neighbors left outside their front door forever, because they couldn’t be bothered to throw it away. I think we got to Day 17 before my &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6441">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Longtime readers may remember the series of alters I made around the<a title="Good sister/bad sister" href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=2777#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed" target="_blank"> telephone book</a> my neighbors left outside their front door<em> forever,</em> because they couldn’t be bothered to throw it away. I think we got to Day 17 before my husband finally tired of my antics and tossed it himself.</p>
<div id="attachment_6455" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/telephone-twinsies-2013.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6455" alt="" src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/telephone-twinsies-2013-300x300.jpg" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">telephone book twinsies</p></div>
<p>So this year, the telephone books showed up over three weeks ago, and the girls downstairs are muy simpatico with the other people across the hall. Neither pair can bring themselves to get rid of the unwanted books. My husband keeps threatening to throw them away, but I asked him not to, because I planned to make another alter, I’ve just been too lazy (which is pretty pathetic, since I&#8217;ve had 22 days to do it).</p>
<p>And then, today we received <em>another</em> telephone book. I never looked at the first one, but I think it was the white pages, and this one is the yellow, or something like that. Anyway, there are now four phone books hanging out downstairs. If I were a betting woman, I’d say they’ll all sit and collect dust for<em> at least</em> another three weeks, which gives me plenty of time to come up with a sufficient offering to appease the Telephone Book Gods.</p>
<div id="attachment_6442" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/telephone-friends.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class=" wp-image-6442 " alt="" src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/telephone-friends-764x1024.jpg" width="584" height="782" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">BFFs 4-eva!</p></div>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/kOTDn2A7hcY" height="315" width="420" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe><br />
Maybe they forgot how important it is to get your name in print&#8230;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<!--post 6441; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6441</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>XX</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6421#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6421#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 21:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[International Women's Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women's health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women's rights]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6421</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I’ve known all week that I was going to write a post about International Women’s Day, because, you know, I’m a woman, and this is the Cowardly Feminist, and blah blah etc. So this morning I sat down in front &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6421">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve known all week that I was going to write a post about International Women’s Day, because, you know, I’m a woman, and this is the Cowardly Feminist, and blah blah etc. So this morning I sat down in front of my computer with a Big Ass cup of coffee, and wrote out a post with all sorts of facts and figures. I had to set it aside before giving it a final once over, because I realized I was about to be late for a doctor appointment, specifically, my annual women’s exam (sheer coincidence it was scheduled for today).</p>
<p>While sitting in the waiting room, I watched several women sign in, and then pay their copayment with a credit card. That, to me, was far more interesting than any amount of facts I could give you. Because really, we already know about women&#8217;s suffrage and equal opportunity employment. What we should be focusing on, is to not take what we have for granted. Like access to women’s health care. We don’t even have that across the board in the United States, much less the rest of the world. And what about the credit cards used to pay? For many of us, particularly those born and raised in a time where women already had, on the books anyway, equal rights and the ability to contribute economically, socially, and politically, we don’t think about something as simple as a credit card. And yet, the ability for a woman to obtain credit in her own name is relatively new. The Equal Credit Opportunity Act wasn’t passed until 1974. <i>Nineteen seventy-four. </i>Less than 40 years ago, that Amex you whipped out over the weekend to pay for dinner would not have been available to you.</p>
<p>But, this isn&#8217;t<em> American</em> Women&#8217;s Day, it&#8217;s <em>International</em> Women&#8217;s Day, so let&#8217;s broaden the scope.</p>
<p>Here’s the deal, I dislike when someone judges me in a negative manner for the simple fact that I’m an American female. Likewise, I am not a person that feels my way is the only way &#8211; I truly believe we should be careful about judging another culture based on what is considered normal for us. The last thing I want is to homogenize the planet.</p>
<p>There are women in the world for whom a romantic love-based marriage is not only a foreign concept, but a stupid and illogical one. There are also women who not only can’t imagine the life of a Western woman,<strong> they don’t want it</strong>. That’s absolutely fine with me. What isn’t fine, and here is the reason International Women’s Day is so very important, is that there are women being denied basic human rights all across the globe. Women (and children) are forced into prostitution every day. It happens all over the world, <i>and it happens in this country</i>. Women are being kidnapped and smuggled into China, a country with a highly skewed proportion of men to women, where they are sold as brides. And, in many countries worldwide, there simply aren’t laws in place to protect women from abuse.</p>
<p>I guess what I’m saying is this – pretty much every damn day on the calendar is marked to acknowledge and celebrate something, and often that something is asinine, like Margarita Day, or National Stapler Day, or whatever. But today? Today is important, because there are many women in the world that lack basic care and not just women’s, but human rights.</p>
<p>Happy Friday y’all. You can find out more about International Women’s Day <a href="http://www.internationalwomensday.com/default.asp" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<!--post 6421; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6421</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Um, you might want to rethink that location.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6386#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6386#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communal dog toilet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public display of affection]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6386</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday around 5 in the afternoon I was walking my dog. Nearby is an intersection with a strip of trees and grass favored by pretty much every pooch on the block. So I headed in that direction, and rounded the &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6386">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday around 5 in the afternoon I was walking my dog. Nearby is an intersection with a strip of trees and grass favored by pretty much every pooch on the block. So I headed in that direction, and rounded the corner to find two people lying on the ground, arms and legs intertwined, having a very serious make out session on the grass. I am talking all sorts of groping and tongue, her purse was flung haphazardly to the side, and there was some&#8230;undulating. Now, this particular intersection gets fairly busy around rush hour, so I looked up to see every person waiting at the stop light was staring at the couple. It was quite the show.</p>
<p>Obviously, that was where my dog decided she absolutely had to do her business. It was Lil Stinko, which meant it took <em><b>forever</b></em>. So there I stood, trying to look at something other than the massive display of horniness in front of me, next to which was my tiny, constipated dog, who kept giving them nervous sideways glances. Good times.</p>
<p>I couldn’t blame Stinky though, because that little area is her spot. And for that matter, it’s also Spazzy’s spot. Really, it’s the spot for every damn dog in the neighborhood. Which got me to thinking, exactly how many dogs have used that particular patch of grass this week? Or even today? At that point I began to examine the ground around them. I always have a wad of cleanup baggies in my pocket, but not everyone is so considerate. And sure enough, without even trying very hard, I spotted a couple of poos perilously close to the make out couple, who, by the way, had yet to come up for air.</p>
<p>I cannot tell you how much this bothered me, and therefore I briefly considered nudging one of them with my toe, &#8220;<i>Hey there, just so you know, you guys are gettin&#8217; down on ground that’s probably been shat upon by at least fifty dogs this week. I know they cut the grass and all, but still, it’s contaminated. You are lying in a communal dog toilet!&#8221;<br />
</i></p>
<p>I decided against it. If they didn’t care about the fact that cars were lined up watching them, a little poo was probably not a concern. Interestingly, they did not appear to be in high school. I mean, I couldn’t guess their exact ages, because their faces were practically embedded in one another, but still, definitely not teenagers.</p>
<p>You know, I&#8217;m not bothered by a little PDA. You want to make out in public? Okay, be my guest. Show the world you are passionate about your lover and blah blah blah. But for the love of all that is good, find a semi-clean, poo-free place to do it in.</p>
<!--post 6386; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6386</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Little goody two shoes.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6355#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6355#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 01:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bruce Campbell is awesome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evil Dead remake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[straw that broke the camel's back syndrome]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6355</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today I read a blurb on io9 about the Evil Dead remake. Sadly, Bruce Campbell does not star in it, which is a freaking travesty (I was going to say it&#8217;s a grave mistake, but decided it was too terrible &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6355">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today I read a blurb on io9 about the <i>Evil Dead</i> remake. Sadly, Bruce Campbell does not star in it, which is a freaking travesty (I was going to say it&#8217;s a grave mistake, but decided it was too terrible of a pun&#8230;apparently I just couldn&#8217;t help myself though, oh well). Anyway, it made me think about this dude I dated a bazillion years ago. I broke up with him over the <em>Evil Dead</em> movies.</p>
<p>We were <del>bickering</del> having a conversation about something and I pointed to him and said, “I’m <em>Bad</em> Ash. You’re <em>Good</em> Ash.” He stared blankly at me in response, so thinking perhaps he needed a bit of a memory jog, I began to do the <a href="http://youtu.be/BTsES7PYMK4" target="_blank">little goody two shoes dance</a>. As it turned out, he didn&#8217;t get my reference because had never seen <i>Evil Dead</i> or <i>Army of Darkness</i>. I was floored, but also excited, because we were about to have a Bruce Campbell-a-thon.</p>
<p>What actually ended up happening is that we didn’t make it through the first movie, let alone the trilogy, since he repeatedly felt the need to say the movie was stupid. All I could think was,<em> no shit</em>. Of course it’s stupid, and campy, and downright awful. But it’s a classic, for Pete’s sake. It’s Bruce Campbell at his very best, which is to say it’s Bruce Campbell playing Bruce Campbell (I love the guy, but homeboy has one trick and he sticks to it). It isn’t a serious movie, you’re supposed to laugh, dammit. So somewhere around the umpteenth time he rolled his eyes, I shut it off, which was fine because by that point I had other things on my mind. Like, <i>what in the hell am I doing with this guy?</i></p>
<p>Shortly after that, I ditched him. Obviously, there was more to my decision than Bruce Campbell. But for whatever reason, that was what triggered me to say, hey, I don’t really like this guy, and we are not a good fit for one another.</p>
<p>It isn&#8217;t like I&#8217;m the first person to break up with someone over something trivial. A friend once told me he dumped a girl with a deviated septum because he couldn&#8217;t stand the sound of her voice. Another girlfriend of mine cast off an ex because she hated his tighty-whities. It might sound shallow to part ways over something so silly, but nine times out of ten, that inconsequential thing we suddenly decided we could no longer tolerate really stood for some insurmountable obstacle in the relationship.</p>
<p>The funny thing about that is, we are usually aware of those complications from the start, but choose to overlook them, or perhaps think they’ll change (or we&#8217;ll change). Maybe at first it seemed exciting, in a two wrongs make a right sort of way. Then, somewhere down the line we realize whatever it is will always remain the same, and that two wrongs make a mess. We turn our focus to something small and nit-picky, and end up making a mountain out of a molehill instead of acknowledging the issues from the start. It&#8217;s ridiculous.</p>
<p>I don’t think this phenomenon is limited to relationships either, it works in all other aspects of life too. Like employment. Perhaps you took a job that, at the end of the day, wasn’t really what you wanted. But the economy is shitty, the company offers great benefits, and the pay is pretty damn good. And yet, you find yourself obsessing over little things, like the fact that someone stole your double ended highlighter, or that the person in the office next to you eats smelly egg sandwiches from her desk everyday, or your supervisor’s halitosis. The next thing you know, you’re wigging out in a Monday meeting and your coworkers are staring at you with gaping mouths. Is the highlighter what’s really bothering you? Of course not, but it’s a tangible thing to focus on, and much easier than examining why you don’t find your current employment fulfilling.</p>
<p>That does happen to other people, right?</p>
<!--post 6355; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6355</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
