<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Cowardly Feminist</title>
	<atom:link href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com</link>
	<description>Pop Culture and Modern Woman&#039;s Battle with the F-Word (Feminism)</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 01:31:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Cocktail dedication time!</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6670#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6670#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 01:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cocktail Hour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cocktails]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Happy hour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6670</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today’s happy hour cocktail is for Holly. If you aren’t reading her blog, you should be, because she’s pretty bad ass. She lives on a farm with chickens, rabbits, other assorted animals, and a husband. Holly is also a master &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6670">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today’s happy hour cocktail is for <a href="http://ahollywithfollies.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">Holly</a>. If you aren’t reading her blog, you should be, because she’s pretty bad ass. She lives on a farm with chickens, rabbits, other assorted animals, and a husband. Holly is also a master at fixing stuff. Real stuff, like furnaces and back hoes and thingymagigs.</p>
<p>Anyway, for whatever reason, it seems anything with a motor is fritzing out on her lately, and I think she needs a drink. So this one’s for you.</p>
<div id="attachment_6671" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/holly-folly-tea.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6671" alt="I would suggest doing whatever hammering that needs to be done before having a cocktail. " src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/holly-folly-tea-300x224.jpg" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I would suggest doing whatever hammering that needs to be done before having a cocktail.</p></div>
<p><strong>Holly Folly’s Tea</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>2 oz Kentucky bourbon</li>
<li>1 oz peach schnapps</li>
<li>pineapple juice</li>
<li>lime</li>
<li>bitters</li>
</ul>
<p>In a tall, ice-filled glass, pour bourbon and schnapps, then add one dash of bitters and a squeeze of lime. Top with pineapple juice, and feel free to stir with a wrench.</p>
<p>Happy Friday y&#8217;all! Don&#8217;t drink and drive, and don&#8217;t drink while fixing machinery either. I don&#8217;t want anyone losing a finger this weekend.</p>
<!--post 6670; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6670</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A picture is forever.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6637#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6637#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Spags]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexting PSA]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6637</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Well hello there ladies and gentlemen. Before we get started, I keep meaning to tell you guys that, for some reason, I can’t respond to comments. Word Press is being a fussy bitch right now, and I haven’t had the &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6637">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well hello there ladies and gentlemen. Before we get started, I keep meaning to tell you guys that, for some reason, I can’t respond to comments. Word Press is being a fussy bitch right now, and I haven’t had the time to sit down and figure out the problem.</p>
<p>Okay.</p>
<p>I’m sure by now most of you have already seen and/or read about the PSA by Candian-based Children of the Streets, aimed at warning teenage girls to stop sending sexually explicit photos of themselves. If you haven’t watched it already, here it is:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Avm7nr1kZhg" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Commentary on the PSA has popped up everywhere, from <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/sexting-psa-children-of-the-street_n_2964001.html?utm_hp_ref=women&amp;ir=Women" target="_blank">HuffPo</a> to <a href="http://jezebel.com/5992359/new-online-safety-psa-warns-girls-to-not-share-sexy-pics" target="_blank">Jezebel</a> to <a href="http://guyism.com/humor/new-psa-tells-girls-no-sexting-photos.html" target="_blank">Guyism</a>. I’m not sure how I feel about it. Let’s ignore my personal opinion that public service announcements don’t do much to deter behavior. What is important, I suppose, is to get the message out and raise awareness. One of the things I read regarding the PSA is that it places the responsibility on females to ensure photos of themselves don’t end up on the internet for the entire world to see, by telling them not to share explicit photos in the first place. It’s sound advice, but Jezebel questioned why the blame should be on girls rather than the boys that share the photos.</p>
<p>Obviously when something like this occurs with minors, it needs to be taken seriously, and the point of the PSA was to try and prevent it from happening at all. But, perhaps we should add to that message. The argument is often made that when a female takes a nude photo of herself and sends it to someone, she does so with the knowledge that it could become public and therefore can blame no one but herself. Fair enough, but let&#8217;s not shame these young women for making a mistake. Chances are, the girl is embarrassed, adding blame to the mix won&#8217;t help.</p>
<p>Making mistakes is part of youth, the problem is that mistakes nowadays often become public. And it isn’t limited to kids, adults engage in this sort of behavior all the time. Nude cell phone photos of various celebrities are leaked with such regularity that no one cares anymore. Most of the instances I recall off the top of my head were of females. Now, perhaps this is pessimistic of me to say, but it is also true &#8211; guys are going to look at naked photos of women. And they will forward said photos to each other, especially young guys. So spreading the word to young women to look out for themselves is important, because if they don&#8217;t, then who will?</p>
<p>I have to say I liked Chris Spags of Guyism&#8217;s take on the PSA -</p>
<p><em>&#8220;The sooner we all have naked pictures of each other in messy bedrooms through poorly Windexed mirrors, the sooner we can move forward as a society and truly accept each other as equals. Please, don’t applaud my courage and creativity.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>My interpretation of that is, this is the world we live in now, let&#8217;s make the best of it.</p>
<!--post 6637; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6637</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Useful lessons from my dad.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6612#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6612#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 23:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fatherly advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanks dad]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6612</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last night, I read a post by the lovely Heather of Creative Devolution. Among other things, she talked about wearing an inflatable unicorn horn on her head (don’t ask, just swing by her blog). This made me think of my &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6612">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night, I read a post by the lovely Heather of <a href="http://www.creativedevolution.com/" target="_blank">Creative Devolution.</a> Among other things, she talked about wearing an inflatable unicorn horn on her head (don’t ask, just swing by her blog). This made me think of my dad, which might sound weird, but if you knew him would totally make sense. Athough I’ve never known him to wear a unicorn horn on his head, it is exactly the type of thing he would do. For no reason at all. Because that’s how he rolls.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/imgres?q=glitter+balls+headband&amp;um=1&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=N&amp;complete=0&amp;biw=1093&amp;bih=437&amp;tbm=isch&amp;tbnid=FsZ-7Z6HyQ8-oM:&amp;imgrefurl=http://www.ebay.com.au/itm/Silver-Glitter-Balls-HEADBAND-Head-Boppers-Antennae-Costume-Hat-Headpiece-/221172830734&amp;docid=gZq7IY7Dx35yBM&amp;imgurl=http://i.ebayimg.com/00/s/NDUwWDM5OA%253D%253D/%2524(KGrHqRHJCYE9!Hb,N,OBP,WuIsGcw~~60_35.JPG&amp;w=265&amp;h=300&amp;ei=_ShSUb2DJaS7igKTwYDoDg&amp;zoom=1&amp;iact=rc&amp;dur=172&amp;page=1&amp;tbnh=150&amp;tbnw=132&amp;start=0&amp;ndsp=16&amp;ved=1t:429,r:0,s:0,i:84&amp;tx=102&amp;ty=78" target="_blank"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-6616" alt="boingers" src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/boingers.jpg" width="265" height="300" /></a>When we were kids, my mom had this habit of writing out really long grocery lists on itty-bitty pieces of paper. She could fit fifty items on the back of a business card, and the script would be so tiny you practically needed a magnifying glass to read it. I have no idea why she wouldn&#8217;t use a regular piece of paper, maybe she was trying to save trees or something. Anyway, she once handed him a long list she wrote out on a post it, which he promptly stuck to his forehead, and then went to the store and randomly asked people if they could read his list. He would also occasionally mow the front lawn while wearing one of those headbands that had a pair of red glittery balls on springs. I don’t really know what they’re called but my sister and I referred to them as boingers. As in, <i>Daddy put the boingers on to mow the lawn!</i> Followed by a lot of tee hee-ing, because he would do it, and my mom would be mortified. I’m sure the neighbors were either entertained or appalled, depending on who you asked, not that my dad cared. If we had an inflatable unicorn horn, I’m pretty sure he would have worn that too (but not with the glitter balls, because that would be too weird).</p>
<p>When I was very young I found his antics hilarious. During my preteen and teenage years, I pretended I didn’t know him when he hammed it up, which is probably par for the course at that age. But, even though I was completely embarrassed, it taught me some important things. First, who the hell cares what other people think? Second, you can’t take yourself too seriously. And lastly, mundane tasks are much less sucky when you try to entertain yourself (or your kids) while carrying them out.</p>
<p>I don’t really know if those lessons were intentional, but I certainly try to adhere to them.</p>
<p>Now let me tell you another lesson my dad taught me – whoever lives on the top floor wins.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a direct quote that stems from a story about an apartment he had in his twenties. Apparently, the guy below was a bit of a dick. Without going into the whole tale, their beef culminated one night with my dad turning his speakers up as high as they would go, placing them facedown on the floor, and then jumping up and down while wearing boots.</p>
<p>So.</p>
<p>Last night I was unable to sleep. Did I have insomnia? No, what I had was very loud neighbors. I can only guess from the loud cackling and slamming of doors that copious amounts of alcohol were involved in whatever they were doing. I don’t expect the building to be lights out at 10:00pm, but woo-hooing it up at midnight on a weekday is a little excessive. I crank up a white noise machine to blot out the sounds of neighbors coming and going, so if I can here them word for word, it’s because they are being really fucking loud. As the night wore on I became infuriated. Do I go downstairs and ask them to be quiet? I decided against it, because I’ve already explained to them once that I can’t hear anything if they’re in the living room or office, but in the bedroom we hear it all. Clearly, they don&#8217;t care.</p>
<p>When my husband’s alarm went off at 5:30 this morning, my first thought was <i>I am soooo tired</i>. Then I jumped out of the bed and landed with a thud on the floor. After repeating that a few times, I began to open and shut the door to the closets and bedroom. By that point, my husband walked in and asked me what I was doing.</p>
<p><i>Following my dad’s advice, that’s what I’m doing</i>.</p>
<p>After properly caffeinating myself, I felt kind of bad. First off, if they were drinking, then my banging around was for naught, because they were probably passed the hell out. But really, I should have found a more mature way to deal with the problem, so shame on me.</p>
<p>Or maybe I should have put my boots on and done jumping jacks.</p>
<!--post 6612; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6612</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fingers and toes are crossed, Monkey Girl.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6599#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6599#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 23:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[milestones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sisters]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6599</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There have been a few birthdays that were a big deal to me, 18 and 21 were milestones, and 30 gave me a bit of a freak out. But other than that I don’t care a whole lot about gaining &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6599">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There have been a few birthdays that were a big deal to me, 18 and 21 were milestones, and 30 gave me a bit of a freak out. But other than that I don’t care a whole lot about gaining another year under my belt. That isn’t to say I don’t care about aging, because I do, otherwise why would I dutifully moisturize every night? My concerns about growing older, however, are mostly related to things like finding my first grey hair or scanning my face for fine lines. Sure, I care about the effects, but who gives a shit about the actual number? It does no good to say you don’t want to turn 35, or 40, or 50, or whatever upcoming number sounds scary. After all, if you don’t have that birthday, then you’re dead.</p>
<p>But that is on <strong>my </strong>birthday. My little sister’s birthday, which is right around the corner, is a totally different story.  For some reason, her growing older trips me out. Me turning 35? Not that big of a deal. Her turning 30? <i>Holy shit when did that happen?</i> It’s a weird thing, because her age definitely bothers me more than my own. Perhaps it’s the knowledge that, while she may be my baby sister, she isn’t a kid. And if she isn’t, then I’m sure as hell not one. Of course I know that, but never it is more crystal clear than when my younger sister turns another year older.</p>
<p>This year the cold, clammy fingers of time wrapped me tighter in its grip a little earlier than usual, because today is the first day of my sister’s candidacy exam. My little sister. Embarking on one of the final fiery hoola hoops academia makes you jump through to put those important letters after your name. In the not too far off future, the family will have to address her as <strong>Dr. Monkey Girl.</strong> Man, does that make me feel old.</p>
<p>Anyway, I have been thinking about my sister all day, because I know she’s totally freaking out right now, and rightfully so. And, to top it all off, her husband takes his exams in a couple of weeks. So they are living in a house of pressure, anxiety, and sleep deprivation, bless their hearts.  I spoke to her yesterday to wish her luck, and unless she needs me to talk her off a ledge during the week, I probably won’t talk to her again until she’s completed the exam. However, in the event she stops by my blog in an effort to distract herself at some point during the week, a few words to Monkey Girl…</p>
<p>You can do this, little sister. You are one of the brightest, most prepared women I’ve ever known. And I’m not just saying that because we’re related. Really. You knew what you wanted to do in life since you were a little girl, and you went out there, kicked ass, and did it. You know how many people can say that? Not many, that’s for sure.</p>
<p>I know this week is tough and stressful. But, it will all be over soon, and when it is, <i>you will party down.</i></p>
<!--post 6599; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6599</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oh damn, I forgot about my blog.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6589#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6589#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 01:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I am a busy bee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6589</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Man, I guess I took an unplanned, unannounced blogging break this week, which is more or less the same thing as saying I slacked off on posting. Sorry y’all. My husband has been out of town again for work. Whenever &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6589">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Man, I guess I took an unplanned, unannounced blogging break this week, which is more or less the same thing as saying I slacked off on posting. Sorry y’all.</p>
<p>My husband has been out of town again for work. Whenever this happens and I know he’ll be gone for more than a day or two, I always think the same thing – <strong>I Am Going To Get Shit Done</strong>. It’ll be great, no timetable, interruption, or consideration of anyone else’s schedule. I will be a bundle of smug productivity. And I was. I busted my butt on non-blog writing and various other projects &#8211; productive was my middle name. But the smug part, as always, dissipated at about the 48 hour mark. Two days in is usually when I realize I’ve only spoken face to face with the dogs, and possibly the mail man. I start to miss my other half, and just like that, I go from happily Doing Stuff to <i>hey this sucks</i>.</p>
<p>My husband works long hours, so a lot of times I only see him once during the day. Sometimes he’s out the door at 4:30 in the morning, and other times he doesn’t get home until midnight. But, at some point during the day, we usually have the opportunity to hang out and chit chat. So I get antsy after 48 hours of just me, myself, and I. I like having my man around to bullshit with, and let’s face it, the dogs don’t laugh at my jokes.</p>
<p>What makes matters worse is that my husband was in Austin this week. As in Texas. As in <i>my beloved</i> <i>home</i>. So not only am I stuck flying solo, I’m getting updates about how beautiful the hill country is, favorite restaurants, and basically all the stuff I pine for, especially right now, because springtime in Texas is fantastic. Take this morning, for example. The phone rang around nine, and when I picked up my husband said this:<i><br />
</i></p>
<p><i>I fucking LOVE Austin! It’s 75 degrees, with just a touch of humidity, it’s perfect outside! Okay, I’ve gotta run.<br />
</i></p>
<p>Then he hung up on me. Yes, babe, I know it’s awesome. Don’t get me wrong, I’m thrilled he loves my home state as much as me, but that doesn’t stop me from being just a <i>little</i> bitter he’s there and I’m not. In a few short hours I pick up him up from the airport, and I’m certain he will taunt me with more tales of Texas in late March. Sigh.</p>
<p>Anyway, sorry for the slackerly-ness folks. Back on track next week. I think.</p>
<p>Enjoy the weekend!</p>
<!--post 6589; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6589</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speculation time!</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6566#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6566#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 23:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Glass]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6566</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So this morning I read an io9 article, What will human cultures be like in 100 years? This is my favorite sort of speculation game. We really have no clue what we’ll be like in a century, but it sure &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6566">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So this morning I read an io9 article, <a href="http://io9.com/what-will-human-cultures-be-like-in-100-years-453934475" target="_blank"><i>What will human cultures be like in 100 years?</i> </a>This is my favorite sort of speculation game. We really have no clue what we’ll be like in a century, but it sure is fun to think about (or depressing depending on your outlook towards humanity). Unfortunately, the what if game resulted in me wasting half the day reading about bipedal robots, which subsequently led me to the new <i>Transformers </i>movie. Who goes to see those? And how in the hell did Mark Walberg get roped into the franchise? Actually, I might consider seeing a non-Shia<em> Transformers</em>.</p>
<p>Clearly, I need some sort of shock collar that automatically zaps me every time I get distracted for longer than five minutes on the internet.</p>
<p>Anyway, my dad and I were just talking about <a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/18/google-glass-backlash/" target="_blank">Google Glass</a>, which turned into a conversation about evolution. My dad thinks we’ll eventually evolve to have necks that swoop down, which makes sense considering how much time we spent bent over our tablets, phones, iPods, and whatever (although technology like Glass might prevent that from happening, since we can once again look forward). Several years ago in a physical anthropology seminar, the professor spent a class discussing how, very rapidly, we’ve become a culture in which bipedalism is not the ideal human form because we spend too much time sitting on our asses. Obviously, it’s impossible to know how we’ll evolve, but it&#8217;s entertaining to imagine our future generations as swoop-necked beings with legs bent and splayed from eons of sitting on our behinds. Given the new form, pants would be impossible, so really quite a few of us are already ahead of the curve. Hell yes.</p>
<p>What I liked most about the io9 article was the discussion of what will become of old people. The author likens senior citizens to teenagers in that they have tons of time and not a lot of cash. I would never, ever want to be a teen again, but the idea of having more time, less responsibility, and none of the hormonal angst, doesn’t sound half bad.</p>
<p>I actually ponder what will become of us when we’re old frequently, although it’s hard for me to not envision a <i>Welcome to the Monkey House </i>future. While I may not be around in 100 years, there is a good possibility I’ll still be here in seventy. Seven. Zero. That’s a long freaking time. So, I avidly read any literature that comes my way regarding the science of aging. I know a lot of people dislike the idea of tampering with nature, but I do hope scientists find a way to combat aging (and not for vanity reasons, thank you very much. Well, mostly not for vanity). I’d rather not spend the last 40 years of my life with creaky knees and hip problems, and I&#8217;m banking on someone figuring out an economically feasible way to make that happen. If we&#8217;re extended longevity, then let&#8217;s make sure the quality is good too.</p>
<p>But if we do figure out a way to finally halt our cells from aging, then what? What do we do with all the extra people? It’s a legitimate concern, especially considering many of us will be the elderly folks in question decades down the road. Perhaps by that time we’ll have figured out a plan for long-term space colonization. We are, after all, talking about fifty to seventy years, so it’s entirely possible. The way I figure it, either they’ll start shuttling us old folks off to space, or, the planet will be such a toxic wasteland that the youth will be the ones in space, leaving the fogies on planet Earth. Since I already live in the pollution-infested badlands of LA County, I’m not too bothered by that scenario, it can’t be all that different.</p>
<p>Anyway, if this is old age, then bring it. They look like they’re having a blast.<br />
<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/_8Y5ze4YrTs" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<!--post 6566; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6566</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Just listen, doc.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6537#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6537#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 16:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender gap in healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laurie Edwards]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6537</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sunday I came down with some sort of stomach bug, or had a touch a food poisoning, or something. Whatever it was, it was no bueno, and as a result yesterday was not very productive. But today? Dude, there is &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6537">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sunday I came down with some sort of stomach bug, or had a touch a food poisoning, or something. Whatever it was, it was no bueno, and as a result yesterday was not very productive. But today? Dude, there is nothing like waking up to find you are no longer ill &#8211; it totally makes you feel kick ass, even though what you’re really feeling is normal.</p>
<p>Anyway, I did actually write a post yesterday. However, when I read it this morning I thought, <i>why does this sound so…ranty and shouty</i>? And long, it was ridiculously long. The topic is important though, so I decided to do a (less angry) rewrite.</p>
<p>Over the weekend I read the NY Times online article <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/17/opinion/sunday/women-and-the-treatment-of-pain.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=0" target="_blank"><i>The Gender Gap in Pain</i></a> , by Laurie Edwards. She discussed the relationship between biological and gender differences of males and females, as how they affect drug dosing and treatment in the healthcare system. Biologically, men and women respond differently to various drugs. Obviously we have very different body types, which means we don&#8217;t always metabolize drugs in the same way. Edwards also points out that women are more prone than men to have chronic pain and autoimmune diseases (three times more likely, as a matter of fact). In spite of this, complaints of pain from women are more likely to be dismissed by health care professionals. She writes:</p>
<p><i>This is a serious problem, because pain is subjective and self-reported, and diagnosis and treatment depend on the assumption that the person reporting symptoms is beyond doubt. </i></p>
<p><i>The oft-cited study “The Girl Who Cried Pain: A Bias Against Women in the Treatment of Pain” found that women were less likely to receive aggressive treatment when diagnosed, and were more likely to have their pain characterized as “emotional,” “psychogenic” and therefore “not real.” </i></p>
<p><i>Instead of appropriate care for physical pain, this can lead to treatment for mental health issues that might not even exist.</i></p>
<p>I not only agree with Edwards, but I would further add that healthcare professionals don&#8217;t just dismiss complaints of women involving pain. They have a frightening tendency to assume any physical ailment is emotionally related.</p>
<p>I was fortunate enough to get through my teens, early, and mid 20s without ever being sick (aside from the self-inflicted, too much partying kind). I had health insurance, but never used it. In my late 20s I began having problems, which eventually I found out were related to my blood sugar. In between that final diagnosis and my first visit, was a string of doctors that refused to listen to me. I cannot tell you how many physicians tried to prescribe me anti-anxiety drugs for my symptoms. And it’s important to note they were all general practitioners. The frustrating part was that I knew my symptoms were physical, and they insisted it was ‘in my head’, without ever ordering any tests to asses my physical health. I had one doctor accuse me of having an eating disorder. Another absolutely insisted what I was describing was an anxiety attack, even though I patiently explained over and over to him that I was not having any anxiety issues. He went so far as to say that perhaps it was something stemming from my childhood, and had the audacity to ask if I was sexually abused. I was appalled, to put it mildly, and needless to say never visited him again. Traversing the healthcare system was new to me, and it wasn’t until, out of complete frustration, I threw a freaking hissy fit that I finally received a referral to an endocrinologist. In a very short period of time, he determined that my problems were indeed physical.</p>
<p>My point is this – depression and anxiety are serious issues, and as such physicians must look out for warning signs, therefore I completely understand why I was asked about my mental health. In fact, questions relating to emotions are standard on a new patient health questionnaire. What I can’t understand is why a half dozen doctors would refuse to consider my complaints were due to a genuine physical issue, and not psychosomatic. To be honest, I came to a point where I began to question myself. Is this in my head? Are they right? When I was finally diagnosed, I felt relieved, but also angry it took so long to get there.</p>
<p>The gender gap problem in health care is greater than just pain &#8211; it encompasses all diagnoses. It’s also important to note that this happens to men too. My dad visited a dozen doctors over the course of several years, some of which flat out told him the symptoms he described were in his head. What he actually had was a tumor, a large one, and it was releasing toxins into his system. Thankfully, someone finally <i>listened </i>to him, sent him to a specialist, and it was removed. He lived, but what if that final doctor had dismissed his complaints too?  Who knows what the outcome would have been?</p>
<p>I think it&#8217;s safe to say the healthcare system as a whole is a mess. But the gender gap and this widespread phenomenon of physicians dismissing any complaint that isn&#8217;t easily diagnosable are both important issues that needs to be addressed sooner rather than later. How do we go about doing it? I’m not sure, but perhaps getting the word out is a good first step. Healthcare, like anything else, is a business. Doctors certainly treat it that way, and so should we. If you are unhappy with the service your healthcare professional is providing,<em> be vocal about it.</em></p>
<!--post 6537; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6537</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>I don’t know what made me think of crabs. Also, vote.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6509#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6509#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 23:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bloggie Awards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crabs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grasshoppers are scary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6509</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So this morning I got up, dealt with the dogs, and then made coffee because I once again forgot to set it up the night before. While waiting for the caffeine to happen I crawled back in bed. For no &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6509">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So this morning I got up, dealt with the dogs, and then made coffee because I once again forgot to set it up the night before. While waiting for the caffeine to happen I crawled back in bed. For no discernable reason I started thinking about the following event from my childhood:</p>
<p>We were in Rockport, which is a little coastal town in Texas. I don’t remember why, but my dad brought my sister and I early, and our mom was to drive in a day or two later. Anyway, my dad decided to take us crabbing. We must have spent a couple of hours on the dock, laughing at my dad as he tried to chase down a crab that got away, and in general having a blast. After we filled our bucket, my dad carted us back to the little place where we stayed, and set about getting everything ready to boil the crabs. As soon as he dropped the first one in the pot, my little sister started screaming bloody murder.<b><i><br />
</i></b></p>
<p><strong><i>“NOOOOOOO! MY CRAAAAAAABS!! MY CRAAAAAAAAABS!!”</i></strong><b><i><br />
</i></b></p>
<p>Honestly, you would have thought he dropped in a puppy from the fit she pitched. I guess Monkey Girl assumed we were catching the crabs to keep, not to eat, and she was upset that my dad planned to callously murder her new pets. My poor pops, I can still vividly recall the look on his face, which pretty much said <i>oh crap what have I done?</i></p>
<p>Needless to say, we did not eat the crabs, and if I recall correctly she made my dad take them back to the water. By that time they were all dead, I’m sure, but he did it anyway.</p>
<div id="attachment_6512" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 203px"><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/big-hair.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class="size-full wp-image-6512" alt="big hair" src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/big-hair.jpg" width="193" height="261" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My mom looks nothing like John Stamos but her hair resembled his, only longer and fluffier on the bottom. And no, mom, you are not allowed to be mad at me, it&#8217;s an accurate description. Plus, it was the 80s, everyone had bad hair. I had crunchy bangs with Sun In, for crying out loud.</p></div>
<p>The next day my mom drove in – she opened the door and before anyone could say a word she was blabbering away frantically, a mile a minute, about a monster in her car. It was the 80s, and she had big hair, which was completely blown askew. She told my dad some huge thing flew in her car fifty miles back, and that she barreled down the highway going a hundred miles an hour in the hopes a cop would pull her over (so said cop could  save her from the monster). My dad finally got her to calm down, and went to go check out whatever it was in the car that tried to kill my mom.</p>
<p>It was a grasshopper.</p>
<p>I haven’t thought about the trip in years, and I really have no idea why it sprung to mind this morning, but thinking about it made me laugh, which is really hard to do before coffee.</p>
<p>On a completely unrelated note – If we&#8217;re peeps on facebook you can stop reading because you already heard this spiel, but, Sunday is the last day to vote in the Bloggies. I am up for Best Topical and Weblog of the Year, and don’t forget to vote for my bloggy buddies, Bondo of <a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">Movie Review Warehouse</a> is up for Best Entertainment, and Greg of <a href="http://dogsondrugs.com/" target="_blank">Dogs on Drugs</a> is up for Best Writing. You can vote <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>Make it happen, y’all. Happy Friday!</p>
<!--post 6509; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6509</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Round and round we go.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6487#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6487#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 03:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big life decisions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biological clock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child-free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female/male communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6487</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[First, let me say that I know I’ve already written about our decision not to have kids a half dozen times. Second, I was actually going to post about something else today, but for the past five minutes the kid &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6487">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First, let me say that I know I’ve already written about our decision not to have kids a half dozen times. Second, I was actually going to post about something else today, but for the past five minutes the kid next door has been screaming <b>I HATE YOU</b> at the top of his lungs, making it impossible for me to concentrate on my other topic. I always expect him to be hoarse, but the screeching seems to have no ill effect on his vocal cords.</p>
<p>Anyway.</p>
<p>Going back to the first thought, if you think I’ve written about whether or not to have children repeatedly, then try to imagine how many times I’ve discussed it with my husband. The answer is thousands. Tens of thousands, even.</p>
<p>I have never, ever wanted kids, I’m just not a maternal person. However, in the past two years my biological clock finally started ticking. In spite of this, I still don’t really want children. Many of my reasons are very personal, and so I’ve never gone into detail when writing. Suffice it to say kids probably aren&#8217;t in the cards for me. But, that doesn’t mean I don’t get that gooey squishy innit-so-cute feeling whenever I set eyes on a baby. I get that way about puppies and kittens too, always have. I have <em>not</em> always felt that way about babies. In fact, I used to think babies were sort of weird looking. They have such big heads, and they’re so marshmallow-y &#8211; it’s a little disconcerting. Now I get it. I may not want it, but I totally get it. They are irresistible little buggers.</p>
<p>I’m in my mid-30s, and the time to have kids is rapidly diminishing for us. My husband is not remotely interested, and when I actually think about what all goes in to having kids, neither am I. But there is this nagging suspicion in the back of my mind that worries we will regret this decision one day. Also, most of the couples we know have at least one, if not multiple children. Keep this in mind.</p>
<p>I consider myself to be a logical woman, but that does not mean I don’t engage in some stereotypical female behavior. For example, without fail, every time my husband relays a story of one of his coworkers talking to him about being a father, the first thing I ask him is, “Do you feel like you’re missing out?”</p>
<p>His answer never changes, because he is quite happy as a twosome, but when he discusses his father friends, I always wonder if he’s trying to tell me something. Of course, guys don’t do that, but since women tend to think that way we assume guys do too. Since most of our acquaintances have children, it seems the topic comes up every week or two, which means each time I mentally dissect the conversation and wonder if there is some hidden meaning to what my husband says. You&#8217;d think I would have leaned by now.</p>
<p>So, over the weekend, we were having breakfast at our favorite restaurant. Across from us was a couple with a set of twins that looked to be about 18 months, and a newborn. <i>Holy crap,</i> I said to my husband, <i>that is a lot of small persons</i>. I guess that reminded him of a conversation he had with a friend the previous night about being a dad. The gist of it was, he loves his kid, but kids consume every bit of your free time and therefore he and his wife were going to stick to just the one.</p>
<p>And so began another round of the ‘are we making a mistake’ game. Only this time, my husband held his hands up, and said with confusion, “We have had this conversation so many times, are you changing your mind?” I responded with an I don’t know, followed by a no, followed by my husband staring at me like I finally fell off the deep end.</p>
<p>The truth of the matter is that if my husband had turned to me and said, ‘yes, I want to have kids’, I probably would have passed out. I know this, and yet, I still flip flop back and forth about how I might feel in the future about the decision we have made today. What’s worse, even though I know having this conversation over and over again is driving both of us crazy, I’m pretty sure we’re going to have it again before the month of March is over. I hadn’t given much thought about why I feel the need to repeat the same discussion with my husband until today. Perhaps I’m looking for validation, who knows?</p>
<p>The decision to have children is monumental, but so is the decision not to. Clearly I am a little conflicted. I wish I wasn&#8217;t. Give me something definitive, whether it&#8217;s my old child-free way of thinking, or a new parent-minded mentality. This merry go round of mostly decided but not quite is a crummy ride.</p>
<p>PS – Just as I finished typing this, the kid across the way started up with a fresh round of I HATE YOU. He never grows tired of it.</p>
<!--post 6487; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6487</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Casting couch</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6470#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6470#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 16:12:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sweded Pacific Rim]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6470</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday I had my book club meeting. This month&#8217;s book was, for me, a tedious read, and no one else in the group cared for it either. After we discussed the details that annoyed us most, we sort of ran &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6470">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I had my book club meeting. This month&#8217;s book was, for me, a tedious read, and no one else in the group cared for it either. After we discussed the details that annoyed us most, we sort of ran out of things to say. It’s always a bit of a dull discussion when the selection is either universally loved or hated, much better when we have a mixed bag of likes and dislikes. Anyway, one of the members said that, in her old book club, when they ran out of things to talk about they resorted to casting the characters.</p>
<p>So of course I came home and spent an inordinate amount of time last night casting some of my favorite faceless bloggers. I thought my casting job was pretty good, but then I realized posting it could potentially get me into trouble.</p>
<p><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Not-Alanis.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-6471" alt="Not Alanis" src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Not-Alanis.jpg" width="300" height="181" /></a></p>
<p>Someone once told me I looked like Alanis Morissette, and I swear to god I still think that person is an asshole. Not only do I bear no resemblance to her, other than dark hair and eyes, her voice is like nails on a chalkboard to me. Worse, really. Her voice makes me feel like Malcolm McDowell in the scene from <i>A Clockwork Orange</i> where they force his eyes open for aversion therapy. Yes indeedy, her screechy songs are enough to send me running for the hills, which made me take the comparison as a personal affront. And so, you see why I opted to not post my casting list. Because even though I may have excellent reasons for choosing so and so to play the part of your life, that particular actor might be your own personal clockwork orange.</p>
<p>Since it appears this post is about nothing, I leave you with this (I love these guys)…</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/fRAqvsD1uxw" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<!--post 6470; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6470</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
