<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Cowardly Feminist</title>
	<atom:link href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com</link>
	<description>Pop Culture and Modern Woman&#039;s Battle with the F-Word (Feminism)</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 21:12:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Sexy Monkey</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6825#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6825#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 21:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duck face is very unbecoming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[survival of the fittest]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6825</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Duuuuuude. I am swamped right now and my blog has fallen by the wayside, again. Actually, I&#8217;ve been half-assed working on this post for a few days, but every time I add something to it, it seems a little less &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6825">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><!--[if gte mso 9]><xml><br />
<w:WordDocument><br />
<w:View>Normal</w:View><br />
<w:Zoom>0</w:Zoom><br />
<w:PunctuationKerning/><br />
<w:ValidateAgainstSchemas/><br />
<w:SaveIfXMLInvalid>false</w:SaveIfXMLInvalid><br />
<w:IgnoreMixedContent>false</w:IgnoreMixedContent><br />
<w:AlwaysShowPlaceholderText>false</w:AlwaysShowPlaceholderText><br />
<w:Compatibility><br />
<w:BreakWrappedTables/><br />
<w:SnapToGridInCell/><br />
<w:WrapTextWithPunct/><br />
<w:UseAsianBreakRules/><br />
<w:DontGrowAutofit/><br />
</w:Compatibility><br />
<w:BrowserLevel>MicrosoftInternetExplorer4</w:BrowserLevel><br />
</w:WordDocument><br />
</xml><![endif]--></p>
<p><!--[if gte mso 9]><xml><br />
<w:LatentStyles DefLockedState="false" LatentStyleCount="156"><br />
</w:LatentStyles><br />
</xml><![endif]--><!--[if !mso]><object classid="clsid:38481807-CA0E-42D2-BF39-B33AF135CC4D" id=ieooui></object></p>
<style>
st1\:*{behavior:url(#ieooui) }
</style>
<p><![endif]--><!--[if gte mso 10]></p>
<style>
 /* Style Definitions */
 table.MsoNormalTable
	{mso-style-name:"Table Normal";
	mso-tstyle-rowband-size:0;
	mso-tstyle-colband-size:0;
	mso-style-noshow:yes;
	mso-style-parent:"";
	mso-padding-alt:0in 5.4pt 0in 5.4pt;
	mso-para-margin:0in;
	mso-para-margin-bottom:.0001pt;
	mso-pagination:widow-orphan;
	font-size:10.0pt;
	font-family:"Times New Roman";
	mso-ansi-language:#0400;
	mso-fareast-language:#0400;
	mso-bidi-language:#0400;}
</style>
<p><![endif]--></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Duuuuuude. I am swamped right now and my blog has fallen by the wayside, again. Actually, I&#8217;ve been half-assed working on this post for a few days, but every time I add something to it, it seems a little less coherent. But hey, who needs articulate logic, right?</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">So, no logic for you today. Or me. And that&#8217;s okay.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">I&#8217;ve read a smattering of articles and blog posts lately about our cultural obsession with all things &#8216;hot&#8217;. Prior to this blog, I coauthored another with a colleague on hotness (the actual concept of it, NOT how to be hot or any such nonsense). Part of me wishes we had kept up with it, because it’s a highly relevant topic, and one I don’t touch upon all that often here.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Hotness is a weird thing. Number one, it’s cultural, and even within cultures there are regional differences. Take a trip to a major US city on the East Coast, West Coast, and Midwest, and you’ll find the herd of hotties is a little different in each place. But you know what’s also weird about hot? Females tend to think certain behaviors, expressions, and appearances are attractive to men, while men don’t actually think they’re hot. Take duck face, for example. I don’t know who specifically decided that odd, pursed lip look was sexually enticing, but I haven’t come across a guy that doesn’t find it strange. And yet, young women (and not so young) persist in posting selfies with said duck face. Because they think it’s hot. Go ahead and type duck face into google image search, there are so many priceless pics I couldn&#8217;t decide on one to post as an example.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Anyway.</p>
<div id="attachment_6845" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 394px"><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/oompa-loompa.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class=" wp-image-6845 " alt="I dunno, maybe it's hot to Gene Wilder." src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/oompa-loompa.jpg" width="384" height="384" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I dunno, maybe it&#8217;s hot to Gene Wilder.</p></div>
<p class="MsoNormal">Also on the list of things chicks do in the name of hotness that most guys don’t understand – oompa loompa orange fake tan, sky high heels when the wearer can’t actually function in them, and caterpillar-like false eyelashes.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">There is, however, a tried and true hot tactic I think we can all agree on that women do, and men seem to respond to, which is wearing scanty clothing. Now, respond can mean different things, some men might mentally drool (some might physically do it too), while others might be intimidated. But they respond, to be sure. For Pete&#8217;s sake, I look when I see a chick with revealing clothing, why <em>wouldn’t</em> a guy?</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Which brings me to a conversation I had with Monkey Girl the other day.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">She was telling me how she has become conservative in her manner of dress, and I agreed that over the years I have too. Not, like, Quaker conservative or anything, but at some point you reach an age where you realize certain clothing choices are best left to 18-year-old girls. Now, this is not a post about how females shouldn’t dress slutty and blah blah blah. Dress in whatever manner suits you and won&#8217;t cause health problems (which means no jeggings y&#8217;all, the hoo needs at least a little breathing room). Plus I would be a big ass hypocrite if I tried to tell anyone to tone it down. Both my sister and I went through a period in our early to mid 20s of wearing clothing more revealing than we would dream of donning today.</p>
<div id="attachment_6840" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 180px"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Navel"><img class="size-full wp-image-6840" alt="navel gazing" src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/navel-gazing.jpg" width="170" height="255" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Best not to bend over in these jeans.</p></div>
<p class="MsoNormal">Remember the early aughts, when cropped belly shirts and super low-rise pants were all the rage? Oh yeah, I rocked that look like nobody’s business. Even worse, I had a rather large collection of those shirts that weren’t really shirts, but draped pieces of fabric that hung over your boobs and tied at the neck and back, requiring loads of double-sided sticky tape to ensure you weren’t charged with indecent exposure. At the time, I thought it looked hot, but not slutty. I reasoned that, a) I didn’t have big boobs, so I could get away with wearing stuff like that, and b) I wore those shirts with jeans, not short skirts. My theory was, even though my top was little more than a handkerchief, my bottom was covered (but just barely, those jeans were ridiculously low), so it was okay.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Um, sure.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Anyhow, during this conversation, Monkey Girl wondered how much clothing/cosmetic choices/etc are related to cultural norms, and how much has do to with being in prime childbearing years. You know, showing your wares to attract a mate. At first this theory made sense, like peacocks feathers and birds puffing out their chests and whatnot. But then I got to thinking – in the animal world, it’s mostly males that strut their stuff to entice females. Off the top of my head, the only female example I can think of is monkeys showing their behinds to advertise their goods (and that right there is really all the proof you need that we evolved from primates. Go to a club this weekend and check out all the booty flaunting). I&#8217;m sure there are others, but I&#8217;m too lazy to google it.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">So, I guess my point is that the duck face and burnt sienna tan look is going to die a quick death sometime soon, because, you know, survival of the fittest and all.</p>
<!--post 6825; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6825</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hot Mess</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6815#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6815#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 21:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[procrastination]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6815</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Things I’ve lost today: My keys (twice) Cell phone (which I found by using one of those websites that will call your phone. It was underneath a pile of mail) Tennis shoes (for some reason I set them on the &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6815">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><!--[if gte mso 9]><xml><br />
<w:WordDocument><br />
<w:View>Normal</w:View><br />
<w:Zoom>0</w:Zoom><br />
<w:PunctuationKerning/><br />
<w:ValidateAgainstSchemas/><br />
<w:SaveIfXMLInvalid>false</w:SaveIfXMLInvalid><br />
<w:IgnoreMixedContent>false</w:IgnoreMixedContent><br />
<w:AlwaysShowPlaceholderText>false</w:AlwaysShowPlaceholderText><br />
<w:Compatibility><br />
<w:BreakWrappedTables/><br />
<w:SnapToGridInCell/><br />
<w:WrapTextWithPunct/><br />
<w:UseAsianBreakRules/><br />
<w:DontGrowAutofit/><br />
</w:Compatibility><br />
<w:BrowserLevel>MicrosoftInternetExplorer4</w:BrowserLevel><br />
</w:WordDocument><br />
</xml><![endif]--></p>
<p><!--[if gte mso 9]><xml><br />
<w:LatentStyles DefLockedState="false" LatentStyleCount="156"><br />
</w:LatentStyles><br />
</xml><![endif]--><!--[if gte mso 10]></p>
<style>
 /* Style Definitions */
 table.MsoNormalTable
	{mso-style-name:"Table Normal";
	mso-tstyle-rowband-size:0;
	mso-tstyle-colband-size:0;
	mso-style-noshow:yes;
	mso-style-parent:"";
	mso-padding-alt:0in 5.4pt 0in 5.4pt;
	mso-para-margin:0in;
	mso-para-margin-bottom:.0001pt;
	mso-pagination:widow-orphan;
	font-size:10.0pt;
	font-family:"Times New Roman";
	mso-ansi-language:#0400;
	mso-fareast-language:#0400;
	mso-bidi-language:#0400;}
</style>
<p><![endif]--></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Things I’ve lost today:</p>
<ul style="margin-top: 0in;" type="disc">
<li class="MsoNormal" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; tab-stops: list .5in;">My keys (twice)</li>
<li class="MsoNormal" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; tab-stops: list .5in;">Cell phone (which I found by using one of those websites that will call your phone. It was underneath a pile of mail)</li>
<li class="MsoNormal" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; tab-stops: list .5in;">Tennis shoes (for some reason I set them on the bathroom counter &#8211; I passed them a half dozen times during my search, but never noticed because I was looking at the floor. I have no idea what made me put them on the counter, which, if you think about it, is kind of gross)</li>
<li class="MsoNormal" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; tab-stops: list .5in;">Laundry basket, with laundry in it (I completely forgot that I set it on the balcony this morning)</li>
<li class="MsoNormal" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; tab-stops: list .5in;">My mind, which I have yet to find. Is there a website for that too?</li>
</ul>
<p class="MsoNormal">You would think my muddle-headedness would have happened on Monday. Not so much.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Anyway.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">A few months back my computer had a meltdown. I managed to fix it, enough to make it work anyway, but it hasn’t been the same since. Lately it has been freezing up or randomly shutting down with alarming regularity, and so I’ve finally accepted that I need to suck it up and get a new laptop. I do not, however, want one. I’m all for change, but when you use a tool daily, you get used to it. I like my little Dell, it suits me.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Since I’m about to trade in my little buddy for a newer, shinier piece of equipment, I have been going through all the extraneous bullshit stored on it to figure out what I actually need. What a freaking disaster. The favorites tab on IE alone is enough to make your head spin, and the list is equally long of bookmarked pages on Firefox. And don’t even get me started on my feeds. Add to that the mess in my inbox…where did these 300+ unread emails come from? And why didn’t I just delete them, if they were so unimportant?</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">I don&#8217;t actually have a point today, other than to poll you guys on laptops. I am not going to do another Dell, since this one crapped out after only three years. On principal I&#8217;ve avoided getting a Mac, but since I went ahead and drank the Kool-Aid and got an iphone last year, I figured, what the hell? But if anyone has something else they absolutely love, I&#8217;m all ears.</p>
<!--post 6815; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6815</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is happening?</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6794#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6794#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Audrie Pott case]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rape culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steubenville rape trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stop blaming the victim]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6794</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Maybe a better question is why is it still happening? I’m talking about the recent smattering of headlines like Steubenville, and the one in Saratoga that broke today. My heart goes out to these girls. I haven’t written about this &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6794">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><!--[if gte mso 9]><xml><br />
 <w:WordDocument><br />
  <w:View>Normal</w:View><br />
  <w:Zoom>0</w:Zoom><br />
  <w:PunctuationKerning/><br />
  <w:ValidateAgainstSchemas/><br />
  <w:SaveIfXMLInvalid>false</w:SaveIfXMLInvalid><br />
  <w:IgnoreMixedContent>false</w:IgnoreMixedContent><br />
  <w:AlwaysShowPlaceholderText>false</w:AlwaysShowPlaceholderText><br />
  <w:Compatibility><br />
   <w:BreakWrappedTables/><br />
   <w:SnapToGridInCell/><br />
   <w:WrapTextWithPunct/><br />
   <w:UseAsianBreakRules/><br />
   <w:DontGrowAutofit/><br />
  </w:Compatibility><br />
  <w:BrowserLevel>MicrosoftInternetExplorer4</w:BrowserLevel><br />
 </w:WordDocument><br />
</xml><![endif]--></p>
<p><!--[if gte mso 9]><xml><br />
 <w:LatentStyles DefLockedState="false" LatentStyleCount="156"><br />
 </w:LatentStyles><br />
</xml><![endif]--><!--[if !mso]><object classid="clsid:38481807-CA0E-42D2-BF39-B33AF135CC4D" id=ieooui></object></p>
<style>
st1\:*{behavior:url(#ieooui) }
</style>
<p><![endif]--><!--[if gte mso 10]></p>
<style>
 /* Style Definitions */
 table.MsoNormalTable
	{mso-style-name:"Table Normal";
	mso-tstyle-rowband-size:0;
	mso-tstyle-colband-size:0;
	mso-style-noshow:yes;
	mso-style-parent:"";
	mso-padding-alt:0in 5.4pt 0in 5.4pt;
	mso-para-margin:0in;
	mso-para-margin-bottom:.0001pt;
	mso-pagination:widow-orphan;
	font-size:10.0pt;
	font-family:"Times New Roman";
	mso-ansi-language:#0400;
	mso-fareast-language:#0400;
	mso-bidi-language:#0400;}
</style>
<p><![endif]--></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Maybe a better question is why is it still happening? I’m talking about the recent smattering of headlines like Steubenville, and the one in Saratoga that broke today. My heart goes out to these girls. I haven’t written about this yet because, quite frankly, I find the topic nauseating. However, I shouldn’t shy away from something so tragic just because it’s hard.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">It saddens me to say I’ve known two people that were victims of rape, in similar circumstances as the ones mentioned above. Young, stupid and overly trusting, each of them got obliterated at a party and were sexually assaulted. Not one of them reported it to the police, and do you know why? Because they were wasted when it happened, and blamed themselves. In both of those instances, other partygoers sided with the rapists in an attempt to coerce the victim into staying silent (notice, by the way, I said rapists plural, meaning multiple guys assaulted the girls). In one of those cases it wasn’t only the male friends of the rapists willing to back up their buddies, there were females involved too. One memorable quote was, “Look, you were so drunk anyone could have had you.”</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">So what?</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Someone inebriated to the point of not being able to fend off an unwanted advance doesn’t deserve to be raped. Yet that’s the attitude so many people have. And yes, I said so many, because I think this problem is far more wide spread than we would like to believe.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">I am one person, and I am writing about two people I knew in my late teens and early twenties. Two separate instances of sexual assault, neither of which was reported. So you have to ask yourself, exactly how many girls has this happened to? How many never told a soul? How many told their close girlfriends? How many had the nerve to tell their folks, or boyfriend, much less the police?</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">This problem is not a new one. I think the reason we are hearing about it more is social media and technology. Everyone has a camera on their phone. I cannot even begin to understand why anyone would want to document such a horrible act. I suppose the only upside is that in the Steubenville case those trophy photos and text messages helped convict the rapists. It saddens me that they were tried as juveniles, I find it unthinkable that the young men involved will be free and clear of their crime when they turn 21. A teenager knows it isn’t okay to sexually assault someone. It doesn’t matter if the person is drunk, or wearing revealing clothing, it is never okay to violate someone. Ever.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">A part of me finds it difficult to believe that, here we are, in 2013, and we are still blaming the victims of sexual assault. I don’t know what will happen to the boys charged with assaulting Audrie Pott, but I do know the defense attempted to shred the character of the young victim in the Steubenville rape trial. That, of course, is a large part of what keeps so many females from reporting sexual assault in cases where alcohol is involved. It’s a given the other party will claim she knew what she was doing or “was asking for it”.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">I don’t have any answers. I wish I did. Something, anything to explain why an alarming number of young men think it’s okay to violate a woman too drunk to know what’s happening. Or purposefully put a roofie in a sorority girl’s drink with the sole purpose of dragging her off somewhere to rape. Give me an explanation as to why other girls would stand by the side of a rapist and taunt the victim. How could you possibly pour salt on a wound like that?</p>
<!--post 6794; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6794</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Burn baby burn. Aka – Bra Rant.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6778#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6778#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bras are useless]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waiting for the boobs that never came]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6778</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I read a little piece of good news today. According to a French study that took place over the course of fifteen years, bras are useless. Now, before I go on, let me say two things. Yes, this post is &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6778">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I read a little piece of good news today. <a href="http://www.connexionfrance.com/Bra-support-damage-professor-Rouillon-back-pain-nipple-14626-view-article.html" target="_blank">According to a French study</a> that took place over the course of fifteen years, bras are useless. Now, before I go on, let me say two things. Yes, this post is about bras, so dude readers feel free to tune out on this one.</p>
<p>Secondly, for my busty readers who immediately said, <i>well I need one</i>, I don’t know what to say. I can’t even begin to relate. In my teens and early twenties, <i>I really</i> <em>wanted</em> to relate. I think a lot of petite girls go through that phase of wanting bigger boobs. The thing is, as a preteen, I assumed mine were going to show up. My mom has more boobage than she knows what to do with, so I figured I had nothing to worry about. What didn’t occur to me was that I totally take after my dad’s side of the family, and let’s face it, my dad does not have boobs &#8211; I was doomed. Luckily I realized big bazongas weren’t going to make or break me in life, and I went on my merry way.</p>
<p>But enough about boobs, let’s get back to the topic at hand, bras.</p>
<p>Here’s a blurb that basically sums up the very short article about the study –</p>
<p><i>Breasts would gain more tone and support themselves if no bra was used. Using a bra meant “supporting tissues will not grow and even they will wither and the breast will gradually degrade”.<br />
</i></p>
<p>So if the whole reason we’re supposed to wear them is to counteract gravity, and it isn’t working, then what’s the point? Count me in. I only wear one for propriety’s sake anyway. The reality of the situation is that you could slap some of those nipple sticker thingies on me and no one would be the wiser.</p>
<p>Bra buying is like torture for me. Jeans? Swimsuits? Give me those any day of the week. I’d rather try on bikinis than brassieres. They are uncomfortable and never, ever fit the way they’re supposed to, dammit. And before someone helpfully suggests I go to a fancy shop and get fitted, because that will solve my problem, let me stop you. It won’t. <i>I’ve tried</i>. I am one of those people that has to have clothes altered to fit correctly. Everything is too long, or gapes, or something &#8211; nothing off the rack ever works. That, however, is kind of hard to do with bras. I know this because I’ve tried to have them altered, and it is always unsuccessful, which is all the more frustrating because then I’ve wasted money on something unwearable. I am aware there are places that make custom made bras, but a little research will tell you they usually cater to people on the opposite end of the cup spectrum from me. Plus, those suckers are ridiculously expensive.</p>
<p>And please, don’t even get me started with the three inches of padding present in practically all smaller than C cup bras. Seriously, you could smack someone wearing one of those in the boobies with a baseball bat and they&#8217;d never know, the bat would probably bounce. It’s like wearing a pair of tiny helmets on my chest. And really, I’ve been with my husband for eight years, <i>he knows I don’t have those extra three inches. </i>So do I. Wearing something like that makes me feel all conspicuous and shit.<i><br />
</i></p>
<p>Non-padded options typically don’t work for me either, they just never fit quite right &#8211; the straps are too long or too short, or it’s some lacy number that won’t work under a t-shirt. I guess I could wear a sports bra, but for Pete’s sake, they’re so utilitarian and ugly looking. If I must wear a contraption over my boobs, I’d prefer it to be pretty.</p>
<p>But today, after years and years of never finding the right bra, I finally have the answer. <i>I don’t freaking need one! </i>So I’m going to strip all the wires from my bras, sell them as scrap metal, and then burn the whole damn collection. Not because I’m trying to relive some 60s feminist, anti-Miss America Pageant movement<i>, but because I’ve been lied to</i>.</p>
<p>Peace.</p>
<p>Oh, and PS – The guy that conducted the study did say he wasn’t recommending women who have been wearing bras for decades to shuck those suckers off. Sorry.</p>
<p>PPS – The <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/11/women-bras-study-france-false-necessity_n_3062114.html?utm_hp_ref=women&amp;ir=Women" target="_blank">HuffPo version of the article</a> had someone talking about running sans bra. She didn’t seem to mind, but I would imagine that to be uncomfortable for most women.</p>
<!--post 6778; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6778</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diorama!</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6761#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6761#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 03:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diorama fun]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6761</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the weekend we made a trip to the Natural History Museum for a photo project my husband is working on &#8211; I haven’t visited a natural history museum since I was a kid. We got there shortly after they &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6761">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the weekend we made a trip to the Natural History Museum for a photo project my husband is working on &#8211; I haven’t visited a natural history museum since I was a kid. We got there shortly after they opened with hopes of avoiding the crowds, but there were already a significant amount of families there.</p>
<p>We had been there for less than five minutes when, while waiting for my husband to fiddle with his camera gear, I watched a small child uproot one of the large metal pipes placed in front of all the displays in order to keep kids from, I dunno, pressing their little noses against the glass, or something. His parents weren’t paying any attention when it happened, not that I’m saying anything bad about his folks, I fully understand children are capable of taking out an entire toy store in the five seconds it takes a parent to locate their wallet &#8211; those little buggers are quick like that.</p>
<div id="attachment_6762" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 247px"><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/pipe.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6762" alt="It's a dark photo, but as you can see, that's a pretty damn big piece of metal for a small person to lift. He must eat his veggies." src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/pipe-237x300.jpg" width="237" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">It&#8217;s a dark photo, but you get the idea &#8211; that&#8217;s a pretty damn big piece of metal for a tiny person to lift. He must eat his veggies.</p></div>
<p>Anyway, I was pretty impressed when this three-year-old kid pulled a big ass metal pipe from the floor. For a split second I thought he was a mini-superman, but apparently not, because he dropped it. The pipe didn’t actually land on him, but the clatter was incredibly loud and echo-y, so of course he started screaming bloody murder. It scared the bejesus out of his parents too. They scooped him up and immediately checked for injuries &#8211; then they got angry, like the pipe just uprooted itself and attacked their child.</p>
<p>It made for an interesting way to start the day. I think we might have been the only two adults not toting a small kid around. There were a lot of frazzled looking parents trying to corral chilluns, and those whose kids weren’t fussy balls of energy dutifully read from each placard. While waiting for my husband I entertained myself by watching the kids’ expressions. It was interesting, a lot of them were full of questions, but some looked bored out of their skulls, and a few were frightened by the displays, bless their little hearts.</p>
<p>Anyway, it’s diorama time:</p>
<p><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/deer-2-0111.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-6766" alt="deer 2 011" src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/deer-2-0111.jpg" width="1024" height="683" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/sexy.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-6767" alt="sexy" src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/sexy.jpg" width="1024" height="683" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_6768" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/pelican-013.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class="size-full wp-image-6768" alt="Where is this guy from? Chucky Cheese?" src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/pelican-013.jpg" width="1024" height="683" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Where is this guy from? Chucky Cheese?</p></div>
<!--post 6761; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6761</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Filler time.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6711#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6711#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 19:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communication crutches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female/male communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[verbal fillers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6711</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This morning I read an io9 article on the use of verbal filler. The gist of it is that we all use filler, such as like, um, you know, I mean, etc., and that it exists in some form in &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6711">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This morning I read an io9 article on the use of <a href="http://io9.com/every-language-needs-its-like-filler-words-466993943" target="_blank">verbal filler</a>. The gist of it is that we all use filler, such as like, um, you know, I mean, etc., and that it exists in some form in every language. The point of the article was that filler words are necessary, and signal all sorts of things in communication. The monosyllable equivalent to um, for example, exists in most languages, and it indicates the speaker is not finished with their thought. I use it in informal writing too, as do any number of bloggers, often to indicate sarcasm in a sentence. I don’t think I have to tell you guys about my propensity for filler. I toss it out like candy. Anyway, the article got me to thinking, not just about verbal fillers, but other forms of communication crutches as well.</p>
<p>You know who doesn’t use filler? My dad. The only time he does is when you tell him a story he has no response to, in which case he’ll say ‘huh’. Other than that, he’s a straight shooter when it comes to communication. Same with my grandparents. In fact, the first time I brought my not-then husband home to meet my family, I made sure to explain to him beforehand that, 1) everyone speaks much slower than he’s used to, and 2) just because there’s a pause in the conversation doesn’t mean they are done speaking. I’ve witnessed people unintentionally interrupt my dad on numerous occasions. They weren’t purposefully doing it, but without an ‘um’ or ‘so’ in there to signify his thought was incomplete, they just assumed he finished speaking.</p>
<p>My mom, on the other hand, is not a direct communicator, even though she and my dad are close to the same age. Like me, she has a more roundabout way of speaking, and while she doesn’t necessarily use fillers like I do, she does have verbal crutches, most notably when she’s asking for something. I once took a class on male/female communication, and we spent a lot of time on the female inability to make a direct request. Women have a tendency, even in situations where they are in control, to pose demands in the form of a question and with verbal qualifiers, i.e. “Do you think you could possibly get those spreadsheets to me by the end of the day?&#8221; Instead of, <em>I need those spreadsheets by the end of the day.</em></p>
<p>Or, ladies, how many times have you said something like this to your partner, “When you have a chance could take out the trash?” What you <em>really</em> mean is, take out the trash now. And yet, we place more words at the beginning of the demand than the demand itself contains. We do this, of course, so as not to seem confrontational.</p>
<p>Obviously there are men that engage in verbal filler as much or more than women, and women that don’t use it at all. I will admit though, in spite of knowing all this, I have been guilty of stereotyping people based on their communication habits. For example, a few days ago my husband and I were talking about another man we know that uses ‘um’ liberally, and my impression is that he is unsure of himself. Is that really the case? Maybe. Then again, I don&#8217;t know him well, so maybe my perception based on his use of &#8216;um&#8217; is incorrect.</p>
<p>Conversely, in professional situations when a female speaks bluntly, I am always a little taken aback. I used to work with a woman that was very direct. It took me weeks to realize she wasn’t bitchy, she was succinct. I came to appreciate her style of communicating, especially during meetings, because she said what she had to in a minimal amount of time, and I always knew exactly where I stood with her.</p>
<p>Strangely, although I might initially find a direct female a little jarring in face to face professional situations, I prefer it in written communication. One of my female superiors at work would pepper her email communication to me with smiley faces. As in, I need that COBRA report stat <img src='http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':-)' class='wp-smiley' /> . I know the smiley faces were meant as balm on her demands, and that she did it out of politeness.</p>
<p>Still, it did not keep me from thinking, F*@K <img src='http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif' alt=':-(' class='wp-smiley' /> .</p>
<!--post 6711; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6711</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sometimes I get things wrong. Really wrong.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6688#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6688#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 22:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brain snafu]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6688</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[About seven years ago, I received an email from someone I’ve known since I was eight. We lived down the street from each other, and had classes together from third grade through high school. As teens we lost touch. Actually, &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6688">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>About seven years ago, I received an email from someone I’ve known since I was eight. We lived down the street from each other, and had classes together from third grade through high school. As teens we lost touch. Actually, I only managed to ever keep in contact with one childhood friend, Brad, and we speak from time to time. Anyway, I asked her if she still spoke with anyone from school, and she responded with a brief synopsis of several girls’ lives. One of which was a one sentence tidbit about our friend Jenny. She wrote, ‘Jenny Jackson (now Walter) moved to Minnesota for college and still lives there’.</p>
<p>I don’t remember what she said about anyone else, because all I could think was, <i>woweewowowowaza</i>! Man, Jenny had sexual reassignment surgery? I had no idea! I spent an inordinate amount of time recalling my childhood friend &#8211; sleep overs, lunchtime at school, and parties. Not once did I ever think Jenny wanted to be a man. She did have a rather deep, throaty voice, but otherwise she was exactly like all the other girls in school. I wondered whether she always knew she wanted to be male, or was it something she figured out later? In a word, it was fascinating. And, of course, I called my parents to tell them the news. They were equally astounded. Really? Little Jenny had a sex change operation? When did that happen? Why did she choose the name Walter?</p>
<p>I wondered the same thing.</p>
<p>The next day I ceased thinking about the whole Jenny/Walter thing and went about my life. A few weeks later, my old friend Brad called out of the blue. Immediately after exchanging pleasantries, I asked him if he knew Jenny was a dude.</p>
<p>Brad: WHAT?!?! What are you talking about?</p>
<p>Me (relaying the story I heard): Blah blah blah</p>
<p>Brad: Really? We were pretty close. I knew a few of the guys she dated…tell me <i>exactly </i>what the email said.</p>
<p>Me: She wrote Jenny Jackson, now Walter, moved to Minnesota for college and still lives there, or something like that.</p>
<p>Brad: (silence for an uncomfortable amount of time) Um, are you sure she didn’t mean Jenny got married, and her last name is now Walter?</p>
<p>Me: *crickets*</p>
<p>Man I am an idiot. <strong>Of course that’s what she meant</strong>.</p>
<p>Occasionally I grossly misinterpret something, and usually at the time it makes absolute sense to me. When I discover my error, typically via embarrassing situation, I am always dumbfounded at my fuck up. Where did I come up with that? Sure, I could try and defend myself. Had my old classmate written Walter<strong><i>s</i></strong>, with an<strong><i> S</i></strong>, I would have gotten it was a surname, but she wrote Walter, that’s a first name, dammit. Can I explain how I took it from just a name to a different sex? Um, no, other than to say my synapses don’t always fire correctly.</p>
<p>I haven’t thought about that story in a while, but it sprung to mind yesterday when I completely misinterpreted something another blogger wrote. Not in a sexual reassignment way or anything, but still. So, I thought I’d share what I hope was the biggest misunderstanding I will ever have. Somehow I doubt it though. To this day, whenever I do something particularly dumb, my dad will cackle like crazy and say, <i>remember when you thought Jenny had a sex change?</i></p>
<p>I will never live that one down.</p>
<p>Oh, and here’s the real kicker. When I responded to my old classmate’s email, I wrote something to the effect of, <i>Wow, I’m shocked to hear about Jenny, I never would have guessed</i>. My old friend had no way of knowing I thought Jenny was a Walter, so I&#8217;m sure she read that and thought &#8211; What. A. Bitch. Because in her mind, I more or less said I never guessed someone would have married Jenny. And since they kept in touch, she probably told her.</p>
<p>*Sigh*</p>
<p>I can’t imagine Jenny will be very happy to see me in a few years at the 20 year reunion.</p>
<!--post 6688; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6688</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Busted.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6678#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6678#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 23:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[procrastination]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6678</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s Monday. I had a wonderfully pleasant weekend hanging out with my husband, almost all fun and no work, the sort we’re usually too busy to have. The effects of my lazy weekend, however, linger on today. Clearly I haven’t &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6678">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s Monday.</p>
<p>I had a wonderfully pleasant weekend hanging out with my husband, almost all fun and no work, the sort we’re usually too busy to have. The effects of my lazy weekend, however, linger on today. Clearly I haven’t given a single thought to my blog, since by the time this posts it will be evening. And forget about the rest of my writing. A few half-hearted sentences and some lame pondering of changing a character’s name (come to think of it, I never made a decision on that one). I did manage to run a ton of errands this morning. But all the other items on my To Do list still sit there, woefully sad and lonely, without a check mark to show they were completed.</p>
<p>And you know something? I can’t even tell you what happened to the rest of my day. All I know is this: at about four in the afternoon, I burst out laughing at an article in The Awl, <a href="http://www.theawl.com/2013/03/what-writing-programs-ought-to-teach-you-when-they-teach-you-about-writing?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheAwl+%28The+Awl%29" target="_blank">What Writing Programs Ought To Teach You When They Teach You About Writing. </a></p>
<p>Point six in the article was about ‘concentration class’, the gist of which is that writers, and really this applies to pretty much everyone I know, regardless of occupation, waste a ridiculous amount of time on streaming video, social media, and the internet in general. It ends like this:</p>
<p><i>“C&#8217;mon. Stop wasting time. You could die tomorrow, but most likely you will die unfulfilled when you&#8217;re really old. And your grandkid will say, &#8220;&#8216;Great, Grandma, Where Did You Stand On &#8216;Leaning In&#8217;?&#8221; And you will just have a stroke.”<br />
</i></p>
<p>I totally have a half-written post regarding Lean In that was very likely unfinished because I spent too much time watching &#8220;Shit Southern Women Say&#8221; on You Tube. I feel like I just got caught red-handed – as though the author personally called me out. And you know what? I’ll never finish the post, because I’ve grown sick and tired of the topic. That actually happens to me a lot. Something comes up, it’s important, newsworthy, women’s issue-y, and I start writing. Then, perhaps I stop to look up something, or find the link to the original article I read, and the next thing you know I’ve read everything there is to read on the subject, plus all the comments and silly internet arguments between readers, and by that time I’ve overdosed on information and no longer care.</p>
<p>Then I walk the dogs. Or call my sister. Or start writing another post on something completely unrelated and irrelevant, like beer pong. I don’t think I ever published the beer pong post either. Huh.</p>
<p>Soooo, what were we talking about? Oh, right, distractions. Tomorrow I’m leaving my phone behind and taking my laptop to a location without wi-fi, and preferably people, otherwise I’ll end up inventing details for their lives instead of my characters, and I am going to concentrate on writing. I’ll let y’all know how it goes.</p>
<!--post 6678; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6678</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cocktail dedication time!</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6670#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6670#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 01:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cocktail Hour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cocktails]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Happy hour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6670</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today’s happy hour cocktail is for Holly. If you aren’t reading her blog, you should be, because she’s pretty bad ass. She lives on a farm with chickens, rabbits, other assorted animals, and a husband. Holly is also a master &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6670">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today’s happy hour cocktail is for <a href="http://ahollywithfollies.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">Holly</a>. If you aren’t reading her blog, you should be, because she’s pretty bad ass. She lives on a farm with chickens, rabbits, other assorted animals, and a husband. Holly is also a master at fixing stuff. Real stuff, like furnaces and back hoes and thingymagigs.</p>
<p>Anyway, for whatever reason, it seems anything with a motor is fritzing out on her lately, and I think she needs a drink. So this one’s for you.</p>
<div id="attachment_6671" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/holly-folly-tea.jpg#utm_source=feed&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6671" alt="I would suggest doing whatever hammering that needs to be done before having a cocktail. " src="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/holly-folly-tea-300x224.jpg" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I would suggest doing whatever hammering that needs to be done before having a cocktail.</p></div>
<p><strong>Holly Folly’s Tea</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>2 oz Kentucky bourbon</li>
<li>1 oz peach schnapps</li>
<li>pineapple juice</li>
<li>lime</li>
<li>bitters</li>
</ul>
<p>In a tall, ice-filled glass, pour bourbon and schnapps, then add one dash of bitters and a squeeze of lime. Top with pineapple juice, and feel free to stir with a wrench.</p>
<p>Happy Friday y&#8217;all! Don&#8217;t drink and drive, and don&#8217;t drink while fixing machinery either. I don&#8217;t want anyone losing a finger this weekend.</p>
<!--post 6670; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6670</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A picture is forever.</title>
		<link>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6637#utm_source=feed&#038;utm_medium=feed&#038;utm_campaign=feed</link>
		<comments>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6637#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VV</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Oh My]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Spags]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexting PSA]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6637</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Well hello there ladies and gentlemen. Before we get started, I keep meaning to tell you guys that, for some reason, I can’t respond to comments. Word Press is being a fussy bitch right now, and I haven’t had the &#8230; <a href="http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?p=6637">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well hello there ladies and gentlemen. Before we get started, I keep meaning to tell you guys that, for some reason, I can’t respond to comments. Word Press is being a fussy bitch right now, and I haven’t had the time to sit down and figure out the problem.</p>
<p>Okay.</p>
<p>I’m sure by now most of you have already seen and/or read about the PSA by Candian-based Children of the Streets, aimed at warning teenage girls to stop sending sexually explicit photos of themselves. If you haven’t watched it already, here it is:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Avm7nr1kZhg" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Commentary on the PSA has popped up everywhere, from <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/sexting-psa-children-of-the-street_n_2964001.html?utm_hp_ref=women&amp;ir=Women" target="_blank">HuffPo</a> to <a href="http://jezebel.com/5992359/new-online-safety-psa-warns-girls-to-not-share-sexy-pics" target="_blank">Jezebel</a> to <a href="http://guyism.com/humor/new-psa-tells-girls-no-sexting-photos.html" target="_blank">Guyism</a>. I’m not sure how I feel about it. Let’s ignore my personal opinion that public service announcements don’t do much to deter behavior. What is important, I suppose, is to get the message out and raise awareness. One of the things I read regarding the PSA is that it places the responsibility on females to ensure photos of themselves don’t end up on the internet for the entire world to see, by telling them not to share explicit photos in the first place. It’s sound advice, but Jezebel questioned why the blame should be on girls rather than the boys that share the photos.</p>
<p>Obviously when something like this occurs with minors, it needs to be taken seriously, and the point of the PSA was to try and prevent it from happening at all. But, perhaps we should add to that message. The argument is often made that when a female takes a nude photo of herself and sends it to someone, she does so with the knowledge that it could become public and therefore can blame no one but herself. Fair enough, but let&#8217;s not shame these young women for making a mistake. Chances are, the girl is embarrassed, adding blame to the mix won&#8217;t help.</p>
<p>Making mistakes is part of youth, the problem is that mistakes nowadays often become public. And it isn’t limited to kids, adults engage in this sort of behavior all the time. Nude cell phone photos of various celebrities are leaked with such regularity that no one cares anymore. Most of the instances I recall off the top of my head were of females. Now, perhaps this is pessimistic of me to say, but it is also true &#8211; guys are going to look at naked photos of women. And they will forward said photos to each other, especially young guys. So spreading the word to young women to look out for themselves is important, because if they don&#8217;t, then who will?</p>
<p>I have to say I liked Chris Spags of Guyism&#8217;s take on the PSA -</p>
<p><em>&#8220;The sooner we all have naked pictures of each other in messy bedrooms through poorly Windexed mirrors, the sooner we can move forward as a society and truly accept each other as equals. Please, don’t applaud my courage and creativity.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>My interpretation of that is, this is the world we live in now, let&#8217;s make the best of it.</p>
<!--post 6637; d_t_p == false; dprv_e=, dprv_a_e=-->]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cowardlyfeminist.com/?feed=rss2&#038;p=6637</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
