<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB">
  <title>Tom Morris</title>
  <link href="http://tommorris.org" rel="alternate" title="Ferocity" type="text/html" />
  <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/"/>
  <id>http://tommorris.org/posts.xml</id>
  <author>
    <name>Tom Morris</name>
    <uri>http://tommorris.org/</uri>
  </author>
  <updated>2013-04-17T07:44:40Z</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>New Zealand is on the brink of making same-sex ...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8212" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>New Zealand is on the brink of <a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/dominion-post/news/8558572/Gay-couples-counting-down-to-full-equality">making same-sex marriage legal</a>. Go Kiwis!</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-17T07:44:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-17T07:44:39Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8212</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8212" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How &quot;love the sinner, hate the sin&quot; works in reality</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8211" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p><img src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/529442_453362054742738_2042195844_n.jpg" /></p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-16T15:23:43Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T15:23:43Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8211</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8211" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/article</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I’ve found something more annoying than small c...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8210" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>I’ve found something more annoying than small children screaming in my ears on the train: drunken “blokey” lads having some “banter”. It’s all “proper geezers” and “slags” and girls they’ve “bonked”.</p>

<p>Nobody actually speaks like that in reality, right? It’s basically idiots impersonating some media-created mockney twat gestalt.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-14T19:54:15Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-14T19:54:15Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8210</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8210" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Two arguments about Mrs Thatcher</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8209" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>I’ve been watching the back-and-forth regarding Thatcher’s legacy on the social media silo sites. And friends of mine have made a few really bad arguments to try and defend Margaret Thatcher from the charges laid against her.</p>

<p><strong>It’s the economy.</strong></p>

<p>The first argument people say is something along the lines of: <em>Yes, Thatcher was a nasty piece of work. But what she did was essential because the economy was up shit creek and she needed to fix it otherwise Britain would have collapsed economically.</em></p>

<p>I hate to sound like a broken record but… Section 28. No economic circumstance can justify the phrase “homosexuality as pretended family relationship”. Plenty of the things Thatcher did which her critics hate her for most have nothing to do with the economy. Her opposition to the anti-apartheid movement: what great moral leadership there.</p>

<p><strong>Ah, but she was elected fair and square, repeatedly. She must have been doing something right.</strong></p>

<p>Sorry, that’s not a valid argument. There are people out there who undoubtedly think The Cheeky Girls have made more of a contribution to Western culture than Mozart. Just because a bunch of people agree with something doesn’t mean it is right. An appeal to popular opinion ignores the actual point under discussion, namely <em>whether people are justified in holding the opinions they do</em>, whether they are morally right or not, whether the opinions are in the best interests of the country (etc.).</p>

<p>It is perfectly legitimate to criticise a politician because they do things you don’t like. The democratic process isn’t a magic wand: sometimes we elect people who do bad things. That doesn’t mean the bad things are somehow good. Hitler won an election at one point. That the country voted for a politician who gave us Section 28 doesn’t mean that Section 28 was somehow acceptable. (Feel free to fill in your least favourite Thatcher policy in place.)</p>

<p>The “well, she was democratically elected, therefore you can’t say anything bad about her” argument sets a pretty low bar. No, she wasn’t a dictator. She’s an improvement on Kim Jong-Il. That’s a fairly low bar to meet. Saying Thatcher was alright because she was a democratically elected leader rather than a dictator is a bit like going to a dinner party and saying “well, the meal wasn’t too bad, it wasn’t a bloody turd on a plate”. I have slightly higher expectations of prime ministers of democracies (which, you know, we all take irrational pride in being for some reason) than “slightly better than a totalitarian dictator”.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-14T11:11:34Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-14T11:11:34Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8209</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8209" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/article</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Wondering what the anarchist would do if I nick...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8207" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Wondering what the anarchist would do if I nicked their iPhone…</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-13T22:53:31Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T22:53:31Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8207</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8207" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I’m on the train with some of the anti-Thatcher...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8206" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>I’m on the train with some of the anti-Thatcher protesters. Idealistic young anarchists discussing the failure of standing in the rain drinking cans of beer as an activism technique, and the failure of other anarchists to give a shit about feminism and minorities.</p>

<p>Saw one guy being dragged off in handcuffs in the station.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-13T22:28:26Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T22:28:26Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8206</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8206" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lots of Transport Police at Charing Cross. Not ...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8205" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Lots of Transport Police at Charing Cross. Not sure if it is for run-of-the-mill pissheads and Saturday night revellers or something more.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-13T21:40:36Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T21:40:36Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8205</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8205" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>There’s a talk about “geeks and professionalism...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8204" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>There’s a talk about “geeks and professionalism” at a conference called ‘Devs Love Bacon’. (Except us vegetarians, obvs.)</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-13T09:53:10Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T09:53:10Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8204</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8204" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>“Everyone in this room is now a gender-queer pa...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8203" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>“Everyone in this room is now a gender-queer panda” (<a href="http://twitter.com/mia_out">@mia_out</a>)</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-13T09:47:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T09:47:38Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8203</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8203" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>At GLAM-WIKI, @mia_out just lumped Wikipedians ...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8202" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>At GLAM-WIKI, <a href="http://twitter.com/mia_out">@mia_out</a> just lumped Wikipedians in with the government and the Daily Mail… oh god, we’ve become The Man.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-13T09:38:53Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T09:38:53Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8202</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8202" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Am somewhat amused that the discussions about #...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8201" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Am somewhat amused that the discussions about <a href="https://uk.wikimedia.org/wiki/GLAM-WIKI_2013">#glamwiki</a> are happening almost exclusively on Twitter’s silo. Because we <em>love</em> open… right?</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-12T12:21:59Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T12:21:59Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8201</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8201" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CV tip: if you claim to have “attention to deta...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8200" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>CV tip: if you claim to have “attention to detail”, check to make sure there are no grammar issues <em>in the sentence</em> where you proclaim your attention to detail. True story.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-12T07:59:24Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T07:59:24Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8200</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8200" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What concerns me far more than whether Thatcher...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8199" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>What concerns me far more than whether Thatcher has a state funeral is that government’s have discretion over whether to provide one or not. We could do something radical like <em>pass a law</em> that says whether or not ex-prime-ministers get a state funeral or not. Then it wouldn’t be up to fate, fortune and partisan political hacks to decide.</p>

<p>You know, equal and consistent treatment under the law. What a radical idea.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-11T12:34:43Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T12:34:43Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8199</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8199" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mobile internet is getting faster, but not much better</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8198" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Over the years, the experience of using the internet from a mobile device has been getting worse rather than better.</p>

<p>I started using mobile internet years ago, just on the cusp of the introduction of 3G. For a long time, I was accessing the Internet through GPRS. And GPRS worked pretty damn well. The experience of connecting was painful in some ways, but once connected, it worked wonderfully.</p>

<p>One simple example: if you went through a train tunnel, often the reconnection would be almost immediate after exiting the tunnel. You’d be back online within a few seconds, pretty much as soon as you had a few bars of signal.</p>

<p>These days, I use the ‘personal wifi hotspot’ on Android. Which is a great idea, but upon exiting a railway tunnel, it can often take up to a minute or two to reconnect to the Internet. Sometimes, the only way I get a connection involves manual intervention (switching the ‘Data network mode’ setting on Android to off and then on again).</p>

<p>I can hear the complaints already. “Yeah, but it’s so much faster!”</p>

<p>And I don’t care.</p>

<p>Speed is pretty much irrelevant. It’s like money. Once you have enough of it, you don’t really need to give a shit. It’s only when you don’t have enough that it is really a concern. I usually have enough speed to do the sort of tasks I need to do: editing Wikipedia, checking my email, checking code in or out of version control (the fact that I can check into Git and then later push it up to the server helps; and <code>git svn</code> is a lifesaver).</p>

<p>I don’t do much more than that… because of usage limitations. My mobile provider, O2, has a 1Gb limit on usage per month. So, you can make my connection as fast as you like—GPRS, 3G, HSDPA, 4G—all it means is that I can more quickly reach the monthly cap. If you put a relatively low monthly cap on the amount of miles one is allowed to do, upgrading the speed of one’s car isn’t going to make much of a difference.</p>

<p>I’m sure when 4G comes trotting along, Wikipedia will load a smidgen faster. I’m still not going to be watching iPlayer on the train because even if it is <strong>OMG SUPER BLOW YOUR SOCKS OFF FASTER THAN A SPEEDING BULLET</strong> like the advertising tells me, watching half an hour of telly will use up quarter of my damn data plan for the month.</p>

<p>I’d post this, but first I need to manually tell my phone to reconnect to the fucking Internet… because god forbid I should be able to use the service I pay for in that barren wasteland of connectivity, south London.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-11T07:39:36Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T07:39:36Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8198</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8198" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/article</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>According to The Economist, only 8% of benefit ...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8197" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>According to The Economist, <a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/blighty/2013/04/benefit-cuts">only 8% of benefit claimants have three or more children</a>. I say this, because we wouldn’t judge everybody who is on benefits on the basis of one case, would we? Oh, wait…</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-09T07:23:18Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-09T07:23:18Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8197</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8197" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Who is Margaret Thatcher? Apparently, some peop...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8196" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p><a href="http://whoismargaretthatcher.tumblr.com/">Who is Margaret Thatcher?</a> Apparently, some people don’t know. And their first response to not knowing is to jump on to Twitter and let the world know that they don’t know. I ♥ human stupidity.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-09T07:14:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-09T07:14:55Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8196</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8196" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Thatcher is dead. Two words: Section 28.

I sha...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8195" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Thatcher is dead. Two words: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Section_28">Section 28</a>.</p>

<p>I shall shed no tears tonight.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-08T13:18:30Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-08T13:18:30Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8195</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8195" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Just been photomapping Old Compton Street. Lond...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8194" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Just been photomapping Old Compton Street. London changes so quickly…</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-07T17:26:20Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-07T17:26:20Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8194</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8194" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The HTML5 Test has a blog post on Blink.</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8193" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>The HTML5 Test has a <a href="http://blog.html5test.com/post/47128015347/thoughts-on-blink">blog post on Blink</a>.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-06T14:46:27Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-06T14:46:27Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8193</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8193" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Andrew Ray has an argument for why new develope...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8192" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p><a href="http://delvarworld.github.io/blog/2013/03/16/just-use-sublime-text/">Andrew Ray</a> has an argument for why new developers shouldn’t use Vim. I have a very compelling reason to use Vim: because mice suck. Mice may let you point to places on the screen easier… I quite like having a working wrist though.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-04-06T13:54:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-06T13:54:12Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8192</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8192" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
</feed>
