<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB">
  <title>Tom Morris</title>
  <link href="http://tommorris.org" rel="alternate" title="Ferocity" type="text/html" />
  <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/"/>
  <id>http://tommorris.org/posts.xml</id>
  <author>
    <name>Tom Morris</name>
    <uri>http://tommorris.org/</uri>
  </author>
  <updated>2013-03-26T09:42:12Z</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>I had the same problem as this guy with the Git...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8161" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>I had the <a href="http://victorquinn.com/blog/2011/12/22/solved-zsh-git-tab-completion-painfully-slow/">same problem as this guy</a> with the Git tab-completion zsh plugin being very slow. <a href="https://github.com/bobthecow/git-flow-completion/wiki/Update-Zsh-git-completion-module">Here</a> is the solution. And it works for me.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-26T09:42:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T09:42:12Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8161</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8161" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My afternoon chatting with a man who thinks I shouldn&#x27;t be able to get married</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8160" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>I spent this afternoon talking to a man who doesn’t think gay people actually exist, but does think we should also not be able to get married.</p>

<p>For some reason, London’s anti gay marriage folk decided to stage a rally in Trafalgar Square today. And for some reason I’m not quite able to remember, I went along. I had a shit journey into town, and tried hard to prepare myself for the protest with a heady cocktail of loud drum’n’bass, a standard skin-thickening preparation for these sorts of things.</p>

<p>I turned up, ready to listen. Firm in my identity. Calm. Unflappable.</p>

<p>And then it came into view. Hundreds of people who didn’t want me to be able to get married. A few little beacons in the crowd with rainbow pride flags, but mostly people with signs proclaiming that marriage was between one man and one woman.</p>

<p>I wandered around and took a few photos. Eventually, I started talking to an elderly man who had been appointed a steward for the protest. He told me he was there to “defend traditional marriage”.</p>

<p>I had previously seen a gay couple show their distaste for the views on display by dropping their trousers and waving their naked behinds at the protesters. I decided that perhaps a more Socratic approach may be appropriate when discussing my rights with the gentleman.</p>

<p>In an attempt at journalistic neutrality, I didn’t tell him that I was gay. I simply wished to hear what his position was, preferably without being battered over the head with accusations about how I’m a terrible, horrible sinner who deserves to burn in hell.</p>

<p>And I learned a great deal. Gay marriage is apparently a plot to destroy Western civilisation. The plotters? Marxist intellectuals from the Frankfurt School. It was all a plot to undermine Western society. And to destroy our birth rate so that “the Muslims” would outbreed us.</p>

<p>Quite how the Conservative Party somehow got wrapped up in this Marxist-Islamist plot, I am not too sure.</p>

<p>The nice man then went on to explain that gay marriage would destroy the family and leave children in a perilous state. I asked him how this would happen but he seemed unable to give me a plausible causal chain from Elton John to apocalypse.</p>

<p>I tried to nudge him by pointing out that if one opposes same-sex parenting, that was already legal and that whether gay people can become parents is a distinct question from whether they can get married. He seemed uninterested in the distinction. He seemed to think that somehow the Marxist/Islamist forces who want to destroy Western civilisation would be kept at bay so long as gay parents could not get legal recognition.</p>

<p>He also told me only a tiny number of people in civil partnerships had kids, around 5,000 or so couples. I wondered whether he saw any particular incompatibility between the claim that gay marriage would destroy civilisation and the claim that it would affect only a tiny portion of the population. He didn’t seem to be interested in answering.</p>

<p>I then pointed out to him that I know plenty of straight couples who aren’t particularly interested in having children, but they can still get married. He then told me that this was tragic because hordes of Muslim immigrants would outbreed us, leaving us a minority in our own country. I tried to nudge him to see how gay marriage was any part of this. I mean, sure, if the heteros aren’t able to do their thing to keep the side up against the invading hordes, that’s sort of their problem, isn’t it? And weren’t all us filthy Sodomites rather blameless in this particular part of the decline and fall of Western civilisation given our rather inherent inability to pump out babies on demand?</p>

<p>He was having none of it. “I don’t believe in gay people.” Oh? “What am I then?”, I felt like asking, but declined. He went on to say that there is no “gene” for being gay, and therefore there are no such thing as gay people. We’re all abused as children, neglected by our families, have terrible relationship issues as teenagers, then somehow get magically addicted to shagging other blokes. And we can be cured if we just ask Jesus for help. His wife gave me a nice leaflet that told me all about Jesus. He then went on to tell me that Jesus does in fact hate queers, contrary to all the people who bang on about how Jesus loves everybody. I asked him whether his view is that gay people are essentially like drug addicts. He happily consented to such a description.</p>

<p>One other intriguing part of our conversation was his view on the democratic legitimacy of gay rights. He told me that nobody really supports gay rights, and it is pushed by a sinister cabal of gay rights activists from Stonewall, Peter Tatchell, Ben Sumerskill and “radical lesbians”. He then told me that once gay marriage is on the books, the sinister cabal of gay rights activists would move on to try and lower the age of consent, and schools would attempt to get schoolchildren to “try out” being gay. Sort of a test drive programme but for hot sweaty man-on-man love.</p>

<p>He went on to hint darkly at “ritual abuse”. I didn’t quite catch what he was arguing. Or whether it was even an argument in the sense one might use in a textbook on formal logic.</p>

<p>I managed to remain stoney-faced throughout.</p>

<p>But he went on. He told me about ex-gay people. Men who had decided to fight their same-sex attractions, marry women and have children. And he told me they really, really loved their wives. And they were being persecuted by the state and the medical establishment for their radical, groundbreaking queer-no-more therapies. (I didn’t ask whether the ex-gays preferred Grindr, bars or bath-houses for getting their end away when wifey was away.)</p>

<p>He explained to me that while ex-gay therapists were being persecuted, there were therapists you could see who could make you “more gay”, and hinted that one could go for such therapy in Soho. I’ve seen the bars, the restaurants, the ice cream parlours and the overpriced sandwich shops, but I’ve yet to see the “make me more gay, doc” clinic. I inquired further, and he told me it was a place where they would train you in sadomasochism, kinky sex and other depraved homosexual things. I thought it was probably best not to tell him about the kinky straight people I know. Who knew that sadomasochism made you “more gay”?</p>

<p>I looked back down to the crowd and saw a sign that proclaimed that they were pro-marriage but not homophobic. I told the man that it was very interesting to talk to him, but I was getting cold and needed to go and warm up. I shook his hand and left. I should have asked him for his details so I could send him a card if I get married one day.</p>

<p>Do I feel anger? A little. Do I feel insulted, either intellectually or personally? A bit of both. Really, the overriding emotion is just sadness. They live in a world where they see people like me and see grand multi-generational conspiracy theories to undermine Western civilisation rather than seeing kindness and love and a desire for the same sort of happiness my parents and grandparents had. I just want to give them a cuddle and tell them it’ll get better for them too, and that in a few years time, they won’t remember why they gave a hoot about gay marriage. But that is rather unlikely. I walked slowly back to the bus stop and felt a strange and uncomfortable knot in my stomach on the way home.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-24T18:52:35Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-24T18:52:35Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8160</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8160" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/article</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>It must be so disappointing for the sort of idi...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8159" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>It must be so disappointing for the sort of idiots who voted for Boris Johnson because “OMG ROFLOL LEGEND!!!1!” to find out there have been long-standing <a href="https://soundcloud.com/bloggerheads/boris-johnson-and-darius">serious allegations that he conspired with a man who was later convicted of faking a jewel theft in order to scam an insurance company to have a journalist beaten up</a>.</p>

<p>If only there were some kind of media to tell us about these sort of things when people stand for public office…</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-24T10:33:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-24T10:33:44Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8159</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8159" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We are disposable people</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8158" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>I’m <a href="http://www.thestar.co.uk/news/local/barnsley-teen-burned-to-death-on-his-18th-birthday-1-5521116">so proud of the British justice system</a>. You can douse an 18-year-old disabled gay kid in tanning oil, set light to him and scrawl homophobic insults all over his face and then… go to prison for three-and-a-half years.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>the judge said taunting which led up to Steven’s death had been ‘good-natured horseplay’</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Let me count the number of times I’ve seen bullying dismissed as horseplay. It’s horseplay when the teacher sees it once. It’s bullying when it continues everyday for a child’s whole life. Been there. Seen that. I’ve seen countless ways that authority figures turn a blind eye. Bullying is just horseplay. It builds character. Don’t be so sensitive. Stand up to them yourself (because we don’t give a fuck).</p>

<p>That an 18-year-old disabled kid can be burned to death by a homophobic bully and there are no meaningful consequences from it sends one enormous message: in the justice system, just as in the school playground, there are disposable people. Steven Simpson is considered by the justice system to be a disposable person.</p>

<p>And people tell me homophobia is no longer an issue.</p>

<p>Between this and the Steubenville rape case, I think I have every reason to be cynical and disappointed by humanity.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-23T12:12:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T12:12:45Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8158</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8158" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/article</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I know, guys, let’s spend a few more days telli...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8157" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>I know, guys, let’s spend a few more days telling Adria Richards how she “ought” to have reacted. Or we could just keep on <a href="http://cl.ly/image/1m2D1D271L1u">threatening to rape and murder her</a> and <a href="http://cl.ly/image/0Y1V3t0o373q">making racist jokes on her Facebook</a>. Keep on being classy, Internet.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-23T11:21:05Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T11:21:05Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8157</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8157" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Whenever anyone suggests that there ought to be...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8156" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Whenever anyone suggests that there ought to be a gay President of the United States, some wag will say “yeah, but who will be the First Lady?”</p>

<p>Her wife, obviously.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-23T08:13:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T08:13:17Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8156</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8156" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>There is a campaign to ask the Daily Mail to sa...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8155" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>There is a <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/greenslade/2013/mar/22/richard-littlejohn-transgender">campaign to ask the Daily Mail to sack Richard Littlejohn</a> over the death of the transgender teacher Lucy Meadows. Whatever the outcome, just remember that Richard Littlejohn has the punishment of waking up everyday in the body of Richard Littlejohn, which is a fitting punishment for such an odious little man.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-23T07:27:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T07:27:45Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8155</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8155" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Some bastard coughed all over me on the train h...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8154" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Some bastard coughed all over me on the train home yesterday. I now have a cold.</p>

<p>British railways: spreading disease since the 1830s.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-21T06:37:36Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T06:37:36Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8154</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8154" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sevenoaks Railway Station</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8153" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="h-card checkin">
  <div class="p-name">Sevenoaks Railway Station</div>
  <div><span class="description"></span> <i>in</i>
  <span><a href="http://openstreetmap.org/browse/node/502562806" class="geo" title="51.27713;0.18291">Mount Harry Road, Sevenoaks CP, Sevenoaks</a></span></div>
</div>

<p>I hate commuting.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-20T06:52:04Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T06:52:04Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8153</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8153" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>There’s an article in today’s Metro about Asper...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8152" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>There’s an article in today’s <cite>Metro</cite> about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asperger_syndrome">Asperger syndrome</a> called called something like “My son is Wikipedia with a pulse”.</p>

<p>Contrary to popular opinion, not all of us wikidorks are on the autistic spectrum.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-19T09:14:30Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-19T09:14:30Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8152</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8152" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Salvation Army and workfare</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8151" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Apparently, the Salvation Army have been <a href="https://johnnyvoid.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/the-true-face-of-salvation-army/">harassing anti-workfare protesters</a>.</p>

<p>I didn’t actually know that the Salvation Army are part of the Workfare programme. This concerns me greatly. Once you get over the nastiness of forcing people to work with the threat of removing their benefits, being forced to work <em>for the Salvation Army</em> is extremely concerning.</p>

<p>The Salvation Army is a Christian organisation. Non-Christians may have very good reason to not wish to support an organisation that pushes a religious message that may be incompatible with their own religious views. I would certainly never wish to work for the Salvation Army given they oppose equal rights for LGBT people (by opposing same-sex marriage, and in the past having opposed the repeal of Section 28).</p>

<p>If the ultra-religious were being forced to go and work in abortion clinics by the Workfare programme, we’d never hear the end of it, but it is apparently fine to force non-Christians, LGBT people and others to go and work for an organisation that pushes a fundamentalist and anti-gay brand of Christianity.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-18T21:18:18Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T21:18:18Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8151</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8151" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/article</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Github is down, apparently. Distributed version...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8150" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Github is down, apparently. Distributed version control systems with centralized dependencies are inherently hilarious.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-18T17:02:27Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-18T17:02:27Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8150</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8150" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Merchant Venturers Building</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8149" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="h-card checkin">
  <div class="p-name">Merchant Venturers Building</div>
  <div><span class="description"></span> <i>in</i>
  <span><a href="http://openstreetmap.org/browse/way/41180592" class="geo" title="51.45573;-2.60276">Park Row, Spike Island, Bristol</a></span></div>
</div>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-17T16:21:31Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T16:21:31Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8149</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8149" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Won a telescope at env[:hack] for writing some ...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8148" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Won a telescope at <a href="http://envhack.com/">env[:hack]</a> for writing some hacky code to check government geo-data against OpenStreetMap. Specifically data about canals, but it’ll eventually be reusable for other stuff. We can use it for data quality validation and adding new stuff to OpenStreetMap.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-17T16:13:35Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-17T16:13:35Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8148</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8148" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>College Green, Bristol</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8147" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="h-card checkin">
  <div class="p-name">College Green</div>
  <div><span class="description"></span> <i>in</i>
  <span><a href="http://openstreetmap.org/browse/way/83705630" class="geo" title="51.45266;-2.60044">College Green, Spike Island, Bristol</a></span></div>
</div>

<p>Sleeping in a council office with a bunch of geeks.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-16T22:46:43Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T22:46:43Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8147</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8147" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scaladocs now have SVG type hierarchy diagrams....</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8146" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Scaladocs now have <a href="http://cl.ly/image/3A0n3h2u3T1X">SVG type hierarchy diagrams</a>. This is pretty cool. Scala is a big improvement on Java if only because Scaladocs are so much more enjoyable to read than Javadocs.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-16T06:50:47Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-16T06:50:47Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8146</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8146" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Some indieweb reading matter: Tantek on silos v...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8145" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Some indieweb reading matter: <a href="http://tantek.com/2013/073/b1/silos-vs-open-social-web">Tantek</a> on silos vs. an open social web. And a response from <a href="http://benwerd.com/2013/03/14/silos-the-open-web-and-selfdogfooding/">Ben Werdmuller</a>. I have nothing interesting to add, so go read.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-15T07:11:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-15T07:11:55Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8145</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8145" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cybe is a rather strange-looking attempt at sol...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8144" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p><a href="http://www.cybe.com/">Cybe</a> is a rather strange-looking attempt at solving the same sort of problems that the decentralised social networking services and <a href="http://indiewebcamp.com">indie web</a> community are trying to do.</p>

<p>As I said, it looks kind of kooky and odd, almost like “Microsoft Bob in the Cloud”. But I feel like I ought to share it in case other people’s intuitions about these things are different.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-14T13:19:56Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T13:19:56Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8144</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8144" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>“Oh, they are shutting down Google Reader. Bett...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8143" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>“Oh, they are shutting down Google Reader. Better go complain about it on G+”, said nobody.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-14T08:20:37Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T08:20:37Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8143</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8143" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Google are closing Reader, despite it being rid...</title>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:base="http://tommorris.org/posts/8142" xml:space="preserve">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Google are <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.co.uk/2013/03/a-second-spring-of-cleaning.html">closing Reader</a>, despite it being ridiculously bloody useful.</p>

      </div>
    </content>
    <published>2013-03-14T06:54:18Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-14T06:54:18Z</updated>
    <id>http://tommorris.org/posts/8142</id>
    <link href="http://tommorris.org/posts/8142" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <object-type xmlns="http://activitystrea.ms/spec/1.0/">http://activitystrea.ms/schema/1.0/note</object-type>
  </entry>
</feed>
