<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Getting Stamped</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.gettingstamped.com</link>
	<description>Figuring out life one stamp at a time...</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 03:58:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Fremont Street: The Heart of Las Vegas</title>
		<link>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/fremont-street-the-heart-of-las-vegas/</link>
		<comments>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/fremont-street-the-heart-of-las-vegas/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 03:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Guest Poster</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Posts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.gettingstamped.com/?p=3095</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When most people imagine Las Vegas, what comes to mind is the Strip: the stretch of road lined with some of the largest dramatic hotels and resorts in the world. What few people realize is The Strip is located outside <a class="more-link" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/fremont-street-the-heart-of-las-vegas/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSCN3253.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-3099" alt="DSCN3253" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSCN3253-e1364269003943-300x277.jpg" width="300" height="277" /></a>When most people imagine Las Vegas, what comes to mind is the Strip: the stretch of road lined with some of the largest dramatic hotels and resorts in the world. What few people realize is The Strip is located outside of Las Vegas city limits and was not always the center of Las Vegas’ gambling industry.</p>
<p dir="ltr">That distinction belongs to Fremont Street, once the heart of Las Vegas. Today, visitors venture to downtown Las Vegas and Fremont Street to visit the Fremont Street Experience, a high-tech light and music show projected on screens above the pedestrian mall below. In the past though, Fremont Street was known as Glitter Gulch and formed the backbone of everything we consider “Las Vegas.”</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">“Next Stop: Las Vegas!”</h2>
<p dir="ltr">In 1905, Las Vegas was nothing more than a dry and dusty desert town. Settlers from the east made their way to Nevada in hopes of finding inexpensive land. Many arrived in Vegas via the Union Pacific Railroad. The Train Depot marked the end (or beginning) of Fremont Street, and the first place visitors saw when they arrived via train.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As more people arrived in Las Vegas to take advantage of the cheap land, businesses popped up along Fremont Street including everything from drugstores to gambling parlors. Gambling was outlawed in 1909, but it wasn’t hard to find a game of chance somewhere in city limits.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Between 1905 and 1931, Las Vegas grew and modern conveniences were introduced. 1907 saw the first telephone installed at the Train Depot. In 1925, Fremont Street was the first street in Vegas to be paved.</p>
<p dir="ltr">However, the real “Glitter Gulch” wasn’t born until construction began on the nearby Hoover Dam.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSCN3257.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-large wp-image-3098" alt="DSCN3257" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSCN3257-e1364269301490-1024x667.jpg" width="1024" height="667" /></a></p>
<h2 dir="ltr">No Gambling Allowed</h2>
<p dir="ltr">Construction on the Hoover Dam began in 1931, and drew more than 10,000 workers and their families to sleepy Las Vegas. In an attempt to keep the town of McKeersville, which housed many of the workers, safe and family friendly, gambling and other “sordid” activities like drinking were banned. To avoid the restrictions of the work town, workers would travel into Las Vegas. The city, sensing an opportunity, granted six establishments licenses to allow gambling. One of those establishments was the Northern Club located at 15 East Fremont Street.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Over the next decade, additional casinos and clubs opened on Fremont Street. Their flashing neon signs earned the street the name Glitter Gulch. “Vegas Vic,” the enormous neon cowboy who waves to visitors on the street below was installed at the Pioneer Club in 1947 and served as a symbol of Las Vegas for decades.</p>
<p dir="ltr">In fact, the bustling, brightly lit street was the primary image most people had of Las Vegas before the Strip grew and the “Welcome to Fabulous Las Vegas Nevada” was installed. Glitter Gulch appeared in movies and on television well into the early 1990s – when the Fremont Experience was born.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">The Fremont Street Experience</h2>
<p dir="ltr">As the Strip grew, both in size and popularity, the casinos and hotels along Fremont Street saw a downturn in the number of tourists coming downtown. Visitors needed a reason to head downtown and <a href="http://thingstodo.expedia.com/las-vegas-nevada-activities/">find things to do in Las Vegas</a>. In 1994, construction on the Fremont Street Experience began. The new attraction was designed to entice tourists away from the high-rise hotels and resorts along Las Vegas Boulevard, and bring them downtown.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSCN3255.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-large wp-image-3097" alt="DSCN3255" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSCN3255-1024x768.jpg" width="1024" height="768" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr">The Fremont Experience officially opened in 1995. By some estimates, more than 60 percent of the visitors to the downtown area are drawn by the attraction, which benefits the casinos and hotels along the original street, including the Golden Nugget and the Golden Gate Hotel and Casino, two of the oldest gaming sites in the city.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Fremont Street is also a repository of Las Vegas history, thanks to the collection of vintage signs from now-defunct properties dotting the street. Neon pieces like the original lamp from the Aladdin Casino join Vegas Vic and other legendary signs to offer a visual history of the city.</p>
<p>Today, visitors enjoy the LED light show on the canopy covering the street or zip-line several stories above the crowd, but Fremont Street wasn’t always a hub of activity. This short stretch of road is the true heart of Vegas and the birthplace of America’s playground.</p>
<p><em><em>~ The above is a guest post ~ </em></em>About the Author:  Historian Carey Carmichael is working on a fictionalized account of life in Las Vegas in the 1920s and ‘30s.</p>
<p><em><em><em>For more info on our guest posts see our <a title="Guest Post Details" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/guest-post-details/">Guest Post Details</a> ~</em></em></em></p>
<div id="fcbk_share"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/fremont-street-the-heart-of-las-vegas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Winter training in Lanzarote</title>
		<link>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/winter-training-in-lanzarote/</link>
		<comments>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/winter-training-in-lanzarote/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 03:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Guest Poster</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Posts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.gettingstamped.com/?p=3090</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As a keen triathlete and all-round fitness fan, I find the winters long, hard and boring. Unfortunately, like most others, I’m not good enough to be a professional athlete but that doesn’t mean I don’t take my fitness regime and <a class="more-link" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/winter-training-in-lanzarote/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">As a keen triathlete and all-round fitness fan, I find the winters long, hard and boring. Unfortunately, like most others, I’m not good enough to be a professional athlete but that doesn’t mean I don’t take my fitness regime and training seriously – seriously enough, anyway, to decide to look for an ideal winter training venue.</p>
<p dir="ltr">In short, I found it in Lanzarote.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/lanzarote.bmp"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-3092" alt="lanzarote" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/lanzarote.bmp" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr">This Canary Island has gradually developed over the last 20 years as one of the winter training venues of choice for professional athletes – and particularly endurance athletes. In their preparation for the London Olympics, the Yorkshire Brownlee brothers came here – whilst the neighbouring bigger island of Tenerife provided winter training for Bradley Wiggins during the winter of 2012-13 as he readied himself for his Tour de France Yellow Jersey – and Olympic gold medal.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So it was this that spurred me on for some winter training in late December-early January, with a lot of road work on my bike, some running and (indoor only…!) swimming.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Lanzarote makes for the ideal venue for winter training. I stayed at the excellent <a href="http://www.jet2holidays.com/hotel-search/ficus-apartments">Ficus apartments</a> and flights here were cheap to buy.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Many keen cyclists base themselves at the “La Santa” (literally meaning the health) sports complex in the north end of the island, but I was keen not to let cycling envelop my whole holiday – and I was keen to do some quieter bike touring and hill-waking, so found my location ideal. I took my own road bike with me – but if you prefer, there are a number of companies offering good quality bike hire as the island really becomes a mecca for cycle training in the off season due to its dry climate and warm, but not too hot, days.</p>
<p dir="ltr">If you’re looking for some great winter training opportunities in warm weather and out of the rain – you’ll quickly see why so many of the top athletes make a beeline for Lanzarote.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><em><strong>~</strong> <strong>The above is a guest post from www.jet2holidays.com ~</strong> <em>For more info on our guest posts see our <a title="Guest Post Details" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/guest-post-details/">Guest Post Details</a> ~</em></em></em></p>
<div id="fcbk_share"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/winter-training-in-lanzarote/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top Destination Wedding Locations</title>
		<link>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/top-destination-wedding-locations/</link>
		<comments>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/top-destination-wedding-locations/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 03:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Guest Poster</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Posts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.gettingstamped.com/?p=3085</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[At this time of year, love is definitely in the air and whether you’ve only just got engaged or you’ve been planning your big day for a while, we’ve got some ideas for you. In times gone by couples got <a class="more-link" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/top-destination-wedding-locations/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">At this time of year, love is definitely in the air and whether you’ve only just got engaged or you’ve been planning your big day for a while, we’ve got some ideas for you. In times gone by couples got married locally, usually in the parish church, but recent trends show couples are looking further afield. Locations today include everything from tree houses, to shark tanks, to airplane hangars. Destination weddings account for 20% of the wedding business. So here are some of the best, and weirdest, destination wedding locations.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Do it Viking style!</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">For an ultra-cool wedding, head to Finland’s Lainio Snow Village. Roughly 125 miles north of the Arctic Circle, prospective newlyweds can choose from a wooden chapel or the famous Ice Chapel to say their vows. Transport is provided by reindeer or huskies and you can spend your first night as a married couple in the Lainio Snow Rooms, snuggled under a reindeer skin duvet!</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Get a little exotic!</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">India is the perfect choice for an opulent, luxurious big day. Wedding packages offer mountains of lush flowers and venues include rustic churches or forest glades surrounded by wildlife. The Bandhavgarh National Park is the ultimate Indian wedding location as your guests will be dazzled by the 10th century temples and the park’s 50 tigers.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Feel the magic!</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">If you’ve got children attending your wedding, or you’re just a big kid at heart, why not get married at Disney World? Hundreds of couples have married in the world famous Wedding Pavilion and it’s not unusual for the wedding party to wear Disney character costumes. It’s also the perfect place to begin your honeymoon as Disney World boasts many luxury hotels.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Read all about it!</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Enjoy reading the Sunday papers? Or did you and your beau bond over a shared love of current affairs? Couples can pay homage to their love of everything newsworthy by getting married in the Editor’s office at the Daily Mirror in Canary Wharf. If London is your destination of choice you can also get married on the London Eye and soak up the view of the United Kingdom’s capital city.</p>
<p dir="ltr">If these destinations sound nice but all you want is a dream location with perfect weather and a little less of the ‘wackiness’, then maybe look into some of the more established wedding destinations, such as Sharm el Sheikh. <a href="http://www.beatthebrochure.com/holidays/egypt/default.asp">Egypt vacations</a> for wedding purposes are affordable and with regular flights available you will have plenty of guests willing to make that trip!</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/Hr6vjta27pHsbSPWBKQ3PYc63nYn_kHXYw6KQ4dcERAdUpn4Sj2jwTxobsNvn4N6x3FtcuPp9fSDyNoYaZvHNQ4hQbli-sJs_crZUDuzuQT59RH-CdjgjO9qb8v_1NCg_aM" width="500px;" height="443px;" /></p>
<p>Destination weddings make a great story for the grandkids!</p>
<p><em><em>~ The above is a guest post from www.BeattheBrocure.com ~ <em>For more info on our guest posts see our <a title="Guest Post Details" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/guest-post-details/">Guest Post Details</a> ~</em></em></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="fcbk_share"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/top-destination-wedding-locations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet a Traveler- Interview with Over Yonderlust</title>
		<link>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/meet-a-traveler-interview-with-over-yonderlust/</link>
		<comments>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/meet-a-traveler-interview-with-over-yonderlust/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 16:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Hannah</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Meet a Traveler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.gettingstamped.com/?p=2910</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Meet Shaun &#38; Erica from Over Yonderlust The who are you ?&#8217;s 1. Who are you and where do you hail from? We are Shaun and Erica Kuschel and hail from Austin, Texas (the greatest city in TEXAS!). Shaun is <a class="more-link" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/meet-a-traveler-interview-with-over-yonderlust/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Meet Shaun &amp; Erica from Over Yonderlust</h1>
<p><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Silly.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-2912" alt="Silly" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Silly.jpg" width="612" height="612" /></a></p>
<h1>The who are you ?&#8217;s</h1>
<p>1. Who are you and where do you hail from? We are Shaun and Erica Kuschel and hail from Austin, Texas (the greatest city in TEXAS!). Shaun is originally from Mesa, Arizona and I grew up in El Paso, Texas before moving to Austin.</p>
<p>2. How did you meet your partner in crime? How long have you known each other? Haha! One little known fact about us is that we met when we were 15 years old at church and have been together off and on for the past 15 years. To relay the whole thing would require a short novel so I hope you don&#8217;t mind the Reader&#8217;s Digest version.</p>
<p>3. What jobs did you kick to the curb in order to travel? Both of us worked for Blizzard Entertainment (think World of Warcraft) for a few years. I quit to pursue my photography career and Shaun was at it up until 3 days before we left. It was a hard thing for him to give up.</p>
<p>4. Explain your website name, where did it come from/how did you come up with it? I actually had a group brainstorm with all my friends on Facebook and my very awesome friend Cameron came up with it. In the south we say &#8220;over yonder&#8221; to denote something in the distance and then we fused &#8220;yonder&#8221; with &#8220;wanderlust&#8217; to create Over Yonderlust.</p>
<h1>The fun ?&#8217;s</h1>
<p>1. What&#8217;s the most under-estimated country &amp; why? Colombia. People are still afraid of it for some reason. The crime is under control and it has some of the most amazing people in the world. Besides Japan, it is one of our favorite countries.</p>
<p>2. What&#8217;s your biggest travel mishap? The time that Shaun rushed into a bar in Mexico and asked to use the bathroom due to a raging case of TD. I guess the looked horrible because the bartender told me she was calling the cops (thinking that Shaun was using drugs) and we were kicked out of the bar.</p>
<p>3. What luxuries did you forgoe in order to save for your travels? The hardest thing was working at a video game company and whenever the end of year bonuses would come flooding in, everyone would spend it on new TVs, new gaming systems, and tech in general. There were several years where we had no common ground because we didn&#8217;t own the same things.</p>
<p>4. What country has the best $1usd menu? What can one expect to get for $1usd? Bolivia! We ate at this one burger stand &#8211; I kid you not &#8211; 10 days in a row. For $1 you got a hamburger with an egg, hotdogs, salsa, and fries. You can&#8217;t beat that. AND THEY WERE GOOD.</p>
<h1>Quick &amp; Dirty (1-2 word answers)</h1>
<p>1. Favorite beach Tulum, Mexico</p>
<p>2. #1 must have travel items Bandana</p>
<p>3. Zip-off pants or no zip-off pants No.</p>
<p>4. Favorite beer Fireman&#8217;s 4</p>
<p>5. Favorite ice-cream flavor Pistachio</p>
<p>6. How many stamps in your passport? 48</p>
<p><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Madmen.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2911" alt="Madmen" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Madmen.jpg" width="612" height="612" /></a></p>
<p>Website link: http://overyonderlust.com</p>
<p>Facebook link: http://facebook.com/overyonderlust</p>
<p>Twitter link: http://twitter.com/overyonderlust</p>
<div id="fcbk_share"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/25/meet-a-traveler-interview-with-over-yonderlust/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Last Stop Munich!</title>
		<link>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/22/last-stop-munich/</link>
		<comments>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/22/last-stop-munich/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 02:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Adam</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Our Trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pre-Trip]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.gettingstamped.com/?p=2996</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think we decided (at least tentatively) on our ending point for our RTW trip. Munich! When we first started to plan our RTW trip we kinda pushed Europe to the back burner because we felt like it was going <a class="more-link" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/22/last-stop-munich/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think we decided (at least tentatively) on our ending point for <a title="Our Route" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/our-trip/our-rout/">our RTW trip</a>. Munich!</p>
<div id="attachment_3068" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 810px"><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Munich-Flag.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3068" alt="~ Flag of Munich ~" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Munich-Flag.jpg" width="800" height="480" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">~ Flag of Munich ~</p></div>
<p>When we first started to plan our RTW trip we kinda pushed Europe to the back burner because we felt like it was going to be too expensive . As of late I have really started to get excited about the time at the end of our trip where we will wander through a few countries trying to end trip in Munich. Also when talking with friends about our trip it never fails, they always ask &#8220;when are you going to Europe&#8221; or &#8220;I want to meet you in Germany&#8221; or &#8220;we should go to Oktoberfest with you,&#8221; after enough asking it started to sound like a good idea.</p>
<p>There are a bunch of reasons the Munich makes for a good last stop, but one of the most important for me is the Beer! If we time it right, and we have enough money left I would love to be in one of the beer capitals of the world during the hop harvesting season. Oktoberfest in Munich is by no means a secret anymore, but I do still want to check it out, along with a bunch of smaller more authentic festivals.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/photo18.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-3069" alt="photo(18)" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/photo18-1024x764.jpg" width="1024" height="764" /></a></p>
<p>The month of September 2014 is about the time Hannah&#8217;s year of leave will be up, and along with the beer season the weather should be quite nice. We will find out soon if they will let her take off for a year or more, fingers crossed they give us 2 years!</p>
<p>Hopefully we will be successfully cheap in the rest of the world, and have enough cash left to make it to Germany, and if we are lucky we can even splurge a little to ease the pains of going home. I think a few nights in a posh resort like <a title="Hotel Kempinski" href="http://www.kempinski.com/en/munich/hotel-vier-jahreszeiten/" target="_blank">Hotel Kempinski</a>, along with some amazing beer should cap off a 15 month world tour quite nicely!</p>
<p>Money factors into our end game, as well we should have sufficient <a title="Flying around the world for FREE!" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/01/27/flying-around-the-world-for-free/">airline points to make it back home</a>. Munich being a large enough airport, we will have about 30k points left in out American Airlines miles which should get is to Chicago. Also taxes and fees seem to be less that other European cities when cashing points, bonus!</p>
<p>Ok, so what do you think of our plan? We need some good insider ideas that will make Munich, our last stop, a memorable one! If you have ever been please posts in the comments!</p>
<div id="fcbk_share"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/22/last-stop-munich/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond The Big Smoke</title>
		<link>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/22/beyond-the-big-smoke/</link>
		<comments>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/22/beyond-the-big-smoke/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 01:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Guest Poster</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Posts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.gettingstamped.com/?p=3055</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Beyond the Big Smoke: Day Trip to Add to your Visit While a trip to the Big Smoke can, in itself, be enough to keep you occupied for a weekend, it&#8217;s always interesting to know what other attractions are available <a class="more-link" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/22/beyond-the-big-smoke/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr" id="internal-source-marker_0.952156769527508"><strong>Beyond the Big Smoke: Day Trip to Add to your Visit</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">While a trip to the Big Smoke can, in itself, be enough to keep you occupied for a weekend, it&#8217;s always interesting to know what other attractions are available in the area, should a day trip beyond the city limits be on the cards.</p>
<p dir="ltr">London is a gateway to many other areas in the south, which can be reached via rail and road links with ease. Even if you don&#8217;t fancy bringing a car into the capital, rail networks can be highly recommended and affordable transport links.</p>
<p dir="ltr">During your stay in the city, make sure you choose reasonably priced accommodation to keep the costs down so that you have more money to actually enjoy yourself. Visit <a title="Travelodge.co.uk" href="https://www.travelodge.co.uk/hotels/book/london-hotels" target="_blank">https://www.travelodge.co.uk/hotels/book/london-hotels</a> for plenty of centrally located choices that won&#8217;t break the bank. From here, draw up an itinerary of sights and attractions you&#8217;d like to see within the city and, if you have a free day, consider one of these trips as well.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Warner Bros. Studio Tour, Leavesden</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Located just on the outskirts of North London, near to Watford, the new Warner Bros. Studio Tour is an absolute must for all Harry Potter fans. Suitable for people of all ages, you can enjoy a behind the scenes look at all things Hogwarts. Whether you&#8217;re Gryffindor through and through or you&#8217;d always preferred the dark side of Slytherin, this studio tour is a must. Separate the muggles from the mudbloods and see the magic come to life with Warner Bros. Be sure to book yourself a time slot before you leave because tickets aren&#8217;t sold on the door.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/WB_London.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3047" alt="WB_London" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/WB_London.jpg" width="788" height="412" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr">From the city, head to London Euston and hop on a train to Watford Junction. There&#8217;s a dedicated shuttle bus that will take you to Leavesden too, so no excuse for getting lost on the way!</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre, Great Missenden</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Nestled in this quaint village of Buckinghamshire, where Roald Dahl lived for 36 years, this fantastic award-winning museum is a perfect day out for all the family. Whether you&#8217;re into your whizzpops and whizzbangs or your everlasting gobstoppers, paying tribute to this incredible children&#8217;s author is an absolute must.</p>
<p dir="ltr">May this inspiring museum help to plant seeds of imagination into your children&#8217;s minds – who knows what stories will be told in the future.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Located an hour from London, just north of High Wycombe, it can easily be done in a day, with the help of a little frobscottle to keep your thirst quenched.</p>
<p><strong>Thorpe Park, Chertsey</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">As one of the most thrilling theme parks in the UK, Thorpe Park is an absolute must at some point – preferably before your personal risk assessment kicks in and you decide to keep your feet on terra firma. With plenty of jaw-dropping rides providing thrills aplenty and adrenaline-fuelled twists and turns, it&#8217;s a daredevil&#8217;s haven.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Likewise, little adventurers will love the myriad of child-friendly rides available – as long as they can tear their parents away from Stealth, Colossus and the Saw Ride, that is!</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/tp-london.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-3048" alt="tp-london" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/tp-london-1024x586.jpg" width="1024" height="586" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr">Start your journey today! With so many day trips available within a couple of hours traveling time, you can be sure to make the most out of your visit to the capital.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><em>~ The above is a guest post from www.travelodge.co.uk ~ <em>For more info on our guest posts see our <a title="Guest Post Details" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/guest-post-details/">Guest Post Details</a> ~</em></em></em></p>
<div id="fcbk_share"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/22/beyond-the-big-smoke/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>To TBEX or Not to TBEX?</title>
		<link>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/21/to-tbex-or-not-to-tbex/</link>
		<comments>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/21/to-tbex-or-not-to-tbex/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 01:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Adam</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Pre-Trip]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.gettingstamped.com/?p=3004</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In June we are off to Toronto to rub elbows with the travel blogging industry! Being a relatively young blog, we debated for a little bit whether we should attend this year&#8217;s North American TBEX, but after some encouragement from <a class="more-link" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/21/to-tbex-or-not-to-tbex/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In June we are off to Toronto to rub elbows with the travel blogging industry!</p>
<p>Being a relatively young blog, we debated for a little bit whether we should attend this year&#8217;s North American TBEX, but after some encouragement from fellow bloggers we decided to go!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/tbex.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3024" alt="tbex" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/tbex.jpg" width="600" height="300" /></a></p>
<h1>New kids on the block (or Blog!)</h1>
<p>Our blog has only been alive for about 6 months, so what do we have to offer potential tourism boards and other advertisers? Well a lot, we think. The advantages we have are that our flights are already paid for, so we will not be asking for a large investment of a comped flight. Another thing we have going for us is that our dates are specify, yet not set in stone. We have found our greatest success in requesting freebies is when we request specific dates. On our trip we are going to 30+ countries, so we have a ton of people to pitch. So hopefully our trip will be worth our while, and we can make a bunch of new relationships.</p>
<h1>Getting to Toronto</h1>
<p>Luckily Milwaukee isn&#8217;t terribly far from Toronto, so we have the option to drive or fly. The drive is about 9 hours and we have some friends along the way where we could break up the drive. Option 2: Fly, recently <a title="WestJet" href="http://www.flighthub.com/airlines/westjet" target="_blank">WestJet</a> started to offer some new cheap flights for us. Flying would give us a lot more time at the convention, but there is something appealing about a good old fashioned road trip! Decisions, decisions&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/MKE-TRO.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3023" alt="MKE-TRO" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/MKE-TRO.jpg" width="990" height="591" /></a></p>
<p>How ever we chose to get there we will definitely be staying in a hostel for the social aspect (and the cost too!). The city and conference will be filled with a bunch of awesome, like minded people that we are excited to meet!</p>
<p>Super excited! If anyone else plans to attend we would love to split a ride or a room,  or at least for a happy hour to swap travel stories!!!</p>
<div id="fcbk_share"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/21/to-tbex-or-not-to-tbex/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>99 Days!</title>
		<link>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/21/99-days/</link>
		<comments>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/21/99-days/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Adam</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Pre-Trip]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.gettingstamped.com/?p=3017</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Double Digit Day! OMG!!! Can&#8217;t believe we are in double digits already. I remember first looking at our countdown until we leave, and it reading over 365. Back then it felt like forever, like it was never going to come, <a class="more-link" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/21/99-days/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Double Digit Day!</h1>
<p>OMG!!! Can&#8217;t believe we are in double digits already. I remember first looking at our countdown until we leave, and it reading over 365. Back then it felt like forever, like it was never going to come, but now its almost scary how fast its coming!</p>
<div id="attachment_1561" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/DSC_0163.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-1561" alt="Aaahhhhhhh! There is so much to do before we leave!!!!!!!!!" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/DSC_0163-1024x678.jpg" width="1024" height="678" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Aaahhhhhhh! There is so much to do before we leave!!!!!!!!!</p></div>
<h1>I got 99 Problems&#8230;</h1>
<p>There is at least 99 things to do before we leave, and no matter how many things we tick off we find something else to do! Sure 99 days sounds like a long time, but when we look at a calendar March is just about gone, and April is extremely busy with work trips, plus we have almost every weekend booked. May is when we need to get everything finalized, cause there is not a single day open weekend in June, then we leave! Sorry for the mini freakout everyone, but stuff is starting get real (I guess in a good, but stressful way).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/99.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3019" alt="99" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/99.jpg" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="fcbk_share"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/21/99-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Dollar Menu &#8211; Tulum, Mexico</title>
		<link>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/19/the-dollar-menu-tulum-mexico/</link>
		<comments>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/19/the-dollar-menu-tulum-mexico/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 14:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Adam</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Dollar Menu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.gettingstamped.com/?p=2485</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every town we visit we like to round up everything we found for about a $1USD or under, to give you an idea of the cost to travel. Accommodation in Tulum is not super cheap with most hostels starting at <a class="more-link" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/19/the-dollar-menu-tulum-mexico/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every town we visit we like to round up everything we found for about a $1USD or under, to give you an idea of the cost to travel. Accommodation in Tulum is not super cheap with most hostels starting at nearly $20 for a dorm bed, so luckily the food is cheap and <em><strong>good!</strong></em></p>
<p>Prices are listed in Mexican Pesos</p>
<p>Current conversions (At time of this article):$1USD = 12.7 Pesos, 1 Euro = 16.8 Pesos, 1 GBP = 19.3 Pesos</p>
<h1>Street Eats</h1>
<ul>
<li>$13 &#8211; Giant Quesadillas with Chicken/Beef/Chorizo</li>
<li>$7 &#8211; Sopas</li>
<li>$4 &#8211; Anything from the &#8216;Pan Man&#8217; (the guys selling bakery on their bikes)</li>
<li>$12 &#8211; 1.5L Water</li>
<li>$10 &#8211; Coke/ +$1 for Diet</li>
<li>$2 &#8211; Banana</li>
<li>$10 &#8211; 1/2 Kilo of Tortillas</li>
<li>$8  &#8211; Beef Tacos</li>
<li>$10 &#8211; Hot Horchata with Rice (Breakfast Food)</li>
<li>$10 &#8211; Ice Cream (1/2 cup serving)</li>
<li>$12 &#8211; Hand made fresh fruit popsicles (Super good)</li>
<li>$10 &#8211; Chicken Tamales</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<dl class="wp-caption alignleft" id="attachment_2612" style="width: 310px;">
<dt class="wp-caption-dt"><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSCN1117.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2612" alt="Street Tamales!" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSCN1117-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></dt>
<dd class="wp-caption-dd">Street Tamales!</dd>
</dl>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_2608" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSCN1111.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2608" alt="Street Tacos, just be sure when you tell the cook you want 3, they know you really only want 3, not 3 each! Oops" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSCN1111-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Street Tacos, just be sure when you tell the cook you want 3, they know you really only want 3, not 3 each! Oops</p></div>
<h1>Local&#8217;s Restaurants</h1>
<ul>
<li>$18 1 liter of fresh fruit smoothie</li>
<li>$8 Tacos</li>
<li>$7 Empanadas</li>
<li>$7 Tostadas</li>
</ul>
<div id="attachment_2628" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSCN1209.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2628" alt="Smoothie, add your own rum!" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSCN1209-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Smoothie, add your own rum!</p></div>
<div id="attachment_2605" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSCN0841.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2605" alt="Tacos al Pastor" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSCN0841-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Tacos al Pastor</p></div>
<h1>Drinks</h1>
<ul>
<li>$8-$15 &#8211; Single beer purchased in a super market, or convenience store</li>
<li>$20-$45 &#8211; Single beer at a bar</li>
<li>$40 &#8211; 200ml bottle of name brand liquor to mix your own drinks</li>
<li>$40-$75 most mixed drinks at a bar (generally over $60 unless happy hour)</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/20130216_2017421.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2448" alt="Mexico beer 8" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/20130216_2017421-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<h1>Transportation</h1>
<p>We ended up spending more in this category than we normally would because <a title="Limping across 6 continents" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/2012/11/01/limping-across-6-continents/" target="_blank">Adam&#8217;s knee is still recovering</a>! The town is very walkable, the beach however is about 7km from the center so bikes or taxis are the way to go. Below is a list of some common destinations via taxi &amp; collectivo (collective taxi vans).</p>
<p>Taxi:</p>
<ul>
<li>City Center to the beach -  $50 each way (add $10-20 on the way back)</li>
<li>Trip with in the Tulum Pueblo (town) &#8211; $20-30 each way</li>
<li>City Center to The Ruins &#8211; $60-70 each way</li>
<li>City Center to Casa Cenote &#8211; $120 each way (You can usually arrange for pick up and pay on your return trip)</li>
</ul>
<p>Collectivo: Best for longer trips, if traveling as a group taxis might be the same or cheaper, and definitely quicker</p>
<ul>
<li>City Center to Ruins &#8211; $25 per person each way</li>
<li>City Center to Akumal &#8211; $30 per person each way</li>
<li>Trips with in town &#8211; $10 per person each way</li>
</ul>
<h1> Not on the cheap!</h1>
<ul>
<li>$130-$160 &#8211; Sunscreen (Make sure to bring your own from home!)</li>
<li>$40 &#8211; Beers on the beach (Nearly Double restaurants in town)</li>
<li>$35 &#8211; 3 pack of Pens (Yes pens, the writing impliment) &#8211; No one in the town has ever has a pen they are too expensive</li>
<li>$25 &#8211; Paper Notebook Office &amp; School Supplies very high priced (so if you plan to take a Spanish class don&#8217;t forget this stuff like we did)</li>
<li>$40-$50 &#8211; Pack of cigarettes (Cheaper than home)</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSC_0188.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2449" alt="Mexico Beer 3" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DSC_0188-198x300.jpg" width="198" height="300" /></a></p>
<div id="fcbk_share"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/19/the-dollar-menu-tulum-mexico/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Romantic Trip for Two to New York</title>
		<link>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/18/a-romantic-trip-for-two-to-new-york/</link>
		<comments>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/18/a-romantic-trip-for-two-to-new-york/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 02:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Guest Poster</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[NYC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.gettingstamped.com/?p=2950</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[New York City is one of the most romantic places in the world. Some might think an exotic beach is the epitome of romance, but there are many romantic aspects of this city. This brings to mind the scene in <a class="more-link" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/18/a-romantic-trip-for-two-to-new-york/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New York City is one of the most romantic places in the world. Some might think an exotic beach is the epitome of romance, but there are many romantic aspects of this city. This brings to mind the scene in &#8220;Sleepless in Seattle&#8221; when Tom Hanks&#8217;s and Meg Ryan&#8217;s characters met at the top of the Empire State Building at sunset. It doesn&#8217;t get much more romantic than that.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NYC-HB1-e1363648532994.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-2952" alt="NYC HB1" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NYC-HB1-e1363648532994.jpg" width="296" height="454" /></a>The Empire State Building is a very romantic start to a weekend in New York. Go up as high as possible and view the city at sunset before a romantic dinner at some cosy little cafe or bistro. It might be good to go back to the hotel after dinner to take advantage of the alone time it affords.</p>
<p>There are many luxurious and romantic hotels from which to choose, but if this is a budget weekend, the check out HostelBookers as they have a great range of <a title="Cheap Hostels in the centre of New York" href="http://www.hostelbookers.com/hostels/usa/new-york-city/" target="_blank">cheap hostels in the centre of New York</a>. If seeing NYC is the objective, the accommodation does not have to cost an arm and a leg, but it should be pleasant for a romantic weekend.</p>
<p>At some point, a walk across the Brooklyn Bridge may be fun. It only takes 15 minutes or so, and it is a New York City icon. Unfortunately, the River Cafe is closed because of storm damage, or that would be the destination. Walk back across and cab it down to Little Italy. Almost anything there is romantic, but try Onieal&#8217;s, site of &#8220;Scout&#8221; on &#8220;Sex in the City.&#8221; Reservations are necessary at just about restaurant in New York.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NYC-HB2-e1363648628931.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2954" alt="NYC HB2" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NYC-HB2-e1363648628931.jpg" width="606" height="454" /></a><br />
Always a romantic notion, a carriage ride through Central Park is leisurely and relaxing. Visitors can see the park from a good perspective, and this saves energy for walking around the city. If the ride ends up near 5th Avenue and 57th Street, walk by Tiffany&#8217;s and window-shop like Holly Golightly in &#8220;Breakfast at Tiffany&#8217;s.&#8221; A girl can dream.</p>
<p>Consider a ferry ride to the Statue of Liberty, a must see for first-time visitors to New York City. Many visitors return to let their children experience it as they did years before. The ferry ride is windy and romantic&#8211;couples can cling to each other for warmth. It is also a nice view of The Battery and the south end of Manhattan. The statue is open Thursday through Sunday.</p>
<p>Way back up on the north side of Manhattan, the Metropolitan Museum is a visitor magnet, and rightly so. The Impressionist wing on the second floor is certainly romantic, and there is a special exhibit of Monet&#8217;s lilies. All parts of the museum are accessible with admission, of course, so find out what is romantic to you.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NYC-HB3-e1363648590413.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2953" alt="NYC HB3" src="http://www.gettingstamped.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NYC-HB3-e1363648590413.jpg" width="560" height="418" /></a><br />
Many visitors want to be kissed in Times Square as a nod to the famous &#8220;Life Magazine&#8221; picture of the sailor kissing the girl in white on V-J Day. That was on August 14, 1945, and over 60 years later, we still re-enact it. Now that is romantic!</p>
<p>The best way to have a romantic trip to New York City is to make your own romantic memories. Feeding each other fresh strawberries dipped in chocolate from Godiva or just walking along a beautiful stretch of Central Park together can be as romantic as anything else. Have a champagne toast to each other at a romantic little cafe like The Place in Greenwich Village. There is nothing like a gourmet dinner and champagne to cap off a romantic trip to the big city.</p>
<p><em><em>~ The above is a guest post from HostelBookers.com &#8211; <em>For more info on our guest posts see our <a title="Guest Post Details" href="http://www.gettingstamped.com/guest-post-details/">Guest Post Details</a> ~</em><br />
</em></em></p>
<div id="fcbk_share"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.gettingstamped.com/2013/03/18/a-romantic-trip-for-two-to-new-york/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
