<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>y Travel Blog</title>
	
	<link>http://www.ytravelblog.com</link>
	<description>Travel more. Create better memories</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 13:35:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
<!-- podcast_generator="Blubrry PowerPress/4.0.7" -->
	<itunes:summary>y Travel Cafe podcast highlighting global travel, destinations, budget travel, couples travel family travel, travel stories, travel tips, backpacking, and working holidays. Caz and Craig have been living and working around the world since 1997.
 They have lived in Dublin, Ireland; London, UK; Bangkok, Thailand; and Raleigh, NC, USA and multiple places in Australia where they are from. They have travelled through 35 countries independently solo, as a couple, and now as a family. They love to share all they have learned through their popular blog and now through y Travel Cafe podcast.
This podcast will feature travel tips and will have a Friday Five show talking about 5 things related to a travel topic; Sunday Sessions which will feature chats with other travellers and those in the industry and Questions from our fans, which we will answer through the podcast.</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:author>Caz Makepeace</itunes:author>
	<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/powerpress/Podcastimage_copy-782-965.jpg" />
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>Caz Makepeace</itunes:name>
		<itunes:email>admin@ytravelblog.com</itunes:email>
	</itunes:owner>
	<managingEditor>admin@ytravelblog.com (Caz Makepeace)</managingEditor>
	<copyright>y Travel blog</copyright>
	<itunes:subtitle>y Travel Cafe podcast highlighting global travel, destinations, budget travel, couples travel family travel, travel stories, travel tips, backpacking, and working holidays. Caz and Craig have been living and working around the world since 1997. They have </itunes:subtitle>
	<itunes:keywords>independent travel,travel blog,couples travel,budget travel,travel destinations,travel tips,travel,world travel,travel podcast,family travel,backpacking</itunes:keywords>
	<image>
		<title>y Travel Blog</title>
		<url>http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/powerpress/Podcastimage_copy-782-965.jpg</url>
		<link>http://www.ytravelblog.com</link>
	</image>
	<itunes:category text="Society &amp; Culture">
		<itunes:category text="Places &amp; Travel" />
	</itunes:category>
		<rawvoice:rating>TV-G</rawvoice:rating>
		<rawvoice:location>Global</rawvoice:location>
		<rawvoice:frequency>Weekly</rawvoice:frequency>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Ytravelblog" /><feedburner:info uri="ytravelblog" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><media:copyright>y Travel blog</media:copyright><media:thumbnail url="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/powerpress/Podcastimage_copy-782-965.jpg" /><media:keywords>independent travel,travel blog,couples travel,budget travel,travel destinations,travel tips,travel,world travel,travel podcast,family travel,backpacking</media:keywords><media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Society &amp; Culture/Places &amp; Travel</media:category><item>
		<title>How to Save Money on Travel – 52 Ideas</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~3/5YopbmoPWNw/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-save-money-on-travel/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Craig</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to Save Money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ytravelblog.com/?p=29027</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>How to save money whilst traveling is one of the most common questions we get asked. It&#8217;s a great question. Luckily for us, and you, we have some suggestions. Like us, most people we know include travel high on their priority list each year, as they want to get away from life&#8217;s routines and create [...]</p><p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-save-money-on-travel/">How to Save Money on Travel &#8211; 52 Ideas</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-save-money-on-travel/how-to-save-money-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-29122"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-29122" alt="How to Save Money" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/How-to-save-money.jpg" width="600" height="800" /></a></p>
<p><em><strong>How to save money</strong></em> whilst traveling is one of the most common questions we get asked.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a great question. Luckily for us, and you, we have some suggestions.</p>
<p>Like us, most people we know include travel high on their priority list each year, as they want to get away from life&#8217;s routines and create precious memories. But most people don&#8217;t have money trees growing in their back yards &#8211; if you do, what&#8217;s your address??</p>
<p>The other common question that comes up a lot is <em><strong>how do we get out of debt</strong> </em>so we can travel more? Unfortunately we&#8217;ve been there too, and it&#8217;s not a nice place to be. Thanks to our friend Jeremy Branham that challenge was <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/5-tips-to-get-out-of-debt-so-you-can-travel-more/" target="_blank"><strong>discussed here</strong></a> with some great insights.</p>
<p>Whilst increased competition between airlines and the ever growing accommodation options has helped lower travel costs, more and more people are finding themselves with less disposable income to play with each year.</p>
<h3>Where&#8217;s the fun in that?</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We have a motto &#8211; <strong><em>Travel more. Create better memories -</em></strong><em> </em>it&#8217;s something we are very passionate about and have been following that travel motto for the past 15 years, first solo, then <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/tips-for-couples-travel/" target="_blank"><strong>as a couple</strong></a>, and now as a <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/25-tips-for-travel-with-kids/" target="_blank"><strong>traveling family</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Some people honestly think we are millionaires being able to travel as much as we do, if only.</p>
<p>But it&#8217;s mostly been about making smart choices, having different priorities, and using certain strategies to save money as we go.</p>
<p>As they say, a dollar saved is a dollar earned and it&#8217;s better off in your pocket than theirs. Every little bit counts. Why pay more when you don&#8217;t have to!</p>
<p>The 52 ideas I&#8217;m about to share will be obvious to some of you, but if you&#8217;re new to travel and new to our site, I&#8217;m sure you will appreciate the heads up on a few strategies to help you save a dollar on the road.</p>
<h2>How to Save Money on Travel:</h2>
<h3>1. Use the Free Days</h3>
<p>Such a simple tip I know but simple is always good. Visit museums or tourist sites on <strong>free days</strong> or when they are discounted. Before you go anywhere, make sure you look on their website to find out if they offer free visiting hours or discounts.</p>
<h3>2. Talk to the Locals</h3>
<p>This is how we travel. We love getting insider tips from locals. It can go a long way to good advice, a friendship and even<strong> a discount</strong>. A good ice-breaker is to ask for directions or advice (“Where’s a good restaurant?”).</p>
<h3>3. Spend More Time in Fewer Places</h3>
<p>We LOVE slow travel. Instead of racing from one end of a country to another, or tearing through 6 countries in 6 weeks, get to know a region well. Undertaking too many flights, bus trips, train journeys and driving long distances can really eat into your budget. So slow down, take more in, and discover all the cool free stuff.</p>
<div id="attachment_29108" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 810px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-save-money-on-travel/how-to-save-money/" rel="attachment wp-att-29108"><img class="size-full wp-image-29108" alt="How to Save money" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/How-to-Save-Money.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">We spent 2 weeks discovering Cape Town, South Africa</p></div>
<h3>4. Be Flexible with Your Flight Dates</h3>
<p>If possible, give yourself the best chance to capture any of the <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/cheap-international-flights/" target="_blank"><strong>cheap flights</strong></a> when the prices fluctuate by searching a couple of days, or even weeks, either side of your preferred departure date. A few booking engines we like using include:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.kayak.com/flights" target="_blank"><strong>Kayak</strong></a><strong> </strong>– Compares hundreds of sites at once.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.vayama.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Vayama</strong></a> &#8211; specialises in cheap international flights.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.skyscanner.com.au/?utm_medium=affiliate&amp;utm_campaign=3887010_UK+Skyscanner+468+x+60_10641624&amp;utm_source=CJ_UK" target="_blank"><strong>Skyscanner</strong> – </a>Provides instant comparison on flight prices for over 670,000 routes.</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.airtreks.com/" target="_blank">Air Treks</a> </strong>- Around the world flight ticket experts.</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.airfarewatchdog.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Airfarewatchdog</a></strong> – Keeps track of deals and alerts you of price drops.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.airasia.com/au/en/home.page" target="_blank"><strong>Air Asia</strong></a> &#8211; Great for short flights within Asia, but to read why we will never fly long-haul as a family with them again click <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/the-good-and-bad-of-air-asia-x/" target="_blank"><strong>here</strong></a>.</li>
</ul>
<h3>5. Adjust Your Times for Flying</h3>
<p>Flying at unpopular hours, such as the red-eye or early in the AM increases your chance of getting discounted flights.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<h3>6. Fly on a Midweek Day</h3>
<p>Tuesdays and Wednesdays are usually the cheapest times, and try and avoid holiday periods.</p>
<h3>7. Go Directly to the Airline Website</h3>
<p>Once you have looked at all the flight search websites and found the cheapest price, as a LAST resort go direct to that airlines own website. Many of the airlines have lower fares that you can only get when you book online at their site, or buy an e-ticket.</p>
<h3>8. Join a Frequent Flyer Program</h3>
<p>Earn points towards cheaper fares, upgrades, and free companion tickets. It may take a while to accumulate points, but they CAN pay off big time. I once used my points to fly round trip from the United States to South Africa.</p>
<h3>9. Use Your Age</h3>
<p>Ask about student discounts at<strong> <a href="http://www.statravel.com?wt.mc_id=CJ_statravel_110209" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">STA Travel.</a> </strong>(if only to be young again!)</p>
<h3>10. Stay More Than 1 Night</h3>
<p>Many hotels, hostels and certainly apartments provide their best deals when you stay over more than one night. A few sites we like to search on include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/click?id=FOzBzQoz428&amp;offerid=120349.10000002&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Hotwire </a></strong>- For last minute deals. e.g. We got a 4 star hotel in the heart of the French Quarter in New Orleans for $50.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.tkqlhce.com/click-3887010-10784648" target="_blank"><strong>Hotels.com</strong></a> – has over 20,000 last minute deals each week.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.agoda.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Agoda </strong></a>- Great for deals in Asia.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.stayz.com.au/" target="_blank"><strong>Stayz </strong></a>(apartments).</li>
<li><a href="http://www.tkqlhce.com/click-3887010-10392970" target="_blank"><strong>Priceline</strong></a> – Bid low on last-minute hotels. Check their pricebreaker deals.</li>
<li>and <a href="http://www.lastminute.com.au/" target="_blank"><strong>Last Minute</strong></a><strong>. </strong></li>
</ul>
<h3>11. Call the Hotel Directly</h3>
<p>A last minute phone call directly to a hotel, or hostel, asking about cheap rooms can prove fruitful. They don’t like having empty rooms so will discount.</p>
<h3>12. Stay over Sunday</h3>
<p>Many hotels receive Friday-Saturday night bookings from leisure travelers and Monday-Friday bookings from business travelers, so there can be a void on Sunday nights and again they may discount.</p>
<h3>13. Sign Up for e-Mail Notifications</h3>
<p>The best <strong>airfare and hotel sales</strong> can go largely unannounced. Sign up for your favourite travel brands e-Newsletters. Special promotion codes can save you money and you can also be notified of last minute deals in this way.</p>
<h3>14. Follow on Social Media</h3>
<p>Go and “like” your favorite travel sites on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog" target="_blank"><strong>facebook</strong> </a>and “follow” them on <strong><a href="http://twitter.com/ytravelblog" target="_blank">twitter.</a></strong> It’s getting more common for travel companies to release hot deals directly through their social media channels.</p>
<h3>15. e-Newsletter Deals</h3>
<p>We are subscribed to a few e-newsletter’s that produce a list of current deals available on the net for any given time period.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.travelzoo.com/top20/" target="_blank">Travel Zoo</a>- </strong>Subscribe to their weekly FREE newsletter of their Top 20 deals<strong> &#8211; </strong>editions for different countries.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.dealbase.com/#" target="_blank"><strong>Deal Base</strong></a> – Sign up for there free deal alerts. They have deals of unadvertised sales and offers you won’t find anywhere else.</li>
</ul>
<h3>16. Rent an Apartment</h3>
<p>Apartments are the BOMB for families or those looking for extra living space and a kitchen so you  can save on food. We haven&#8217;t personally used this site yet, but check out <strong><a href="http://www.airbnb.com/">AirBnB </a></strong>as a way to get low-cost vacation rentals and sublets from locals in <em>180 countries</em>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.homeaway.com.au/" target="_blank"><strong>Homeaway</strong> </a>has a large selection of apartments, and a good one we like to use in Australia is <a href="http://www.stayz.com.au/" target="_blank"><strong>Stayz.</strong></a></p>
<h3>17. Use Hotel Reward Programs</h3>
<p>Many brands have them and you can get perks like free nights or room upgrades. The <strong><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/hotels-com-welcome-rewards/" target="_blank">Hotels.com welcome rewards program</a> </strong>gives you one free night for every 10 booked through them.</p>
<div id="attachment_29109" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-save-money-on-travel/how-to-save-money-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-29109"><img class="size-full wp-image-29109" alt="Enjoying the benefits of Hilton Honors Rewards program in Phuket" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/How-to-save-money-2.jpg" width="600" height="800" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Enjoying the benefits of Hilton Honors Rewards program in Phuket</p></div>
<h3>18. Check for Family Deals<strong> </strong></h3>
<p>Always ask about discounted rates, free meals for children, and an upgrade at check in – they can only say no.</p>
<h3>19. Use Coupons</h3>
<p>Do your research to find travel discounts and coupons for the areas you are visiting. Check out the brochure shelf in the lobby of your hotel.<strong>Visit the local tourist information offices</strong> for free maps and ideas.</p>
<p>Use the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Tourist booklets and brochures.</li>
<li>Back of supermarket receipts.</li>
<li>Websites (local tourist boards and businesses and coupon sites).</li>
</ul>
<h3>20. Use Credit Card Reward Points</h3>
<p>Check the program and benefits for your particular credit card, you might be able to use your points for accommodation costs and frequent flyer points. We currently have an AMEX card that gives us three Qantas points for every dollar spent.</p>
<h3>21. Stay in Hostels and Guesthouses</h3>
<p>A great option for <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-find-budget-accommodation/" target="_blank"><strong>budget accommodation</strong></a> but they are not for everyone, and we have written a post about our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-tips/tips-for-backpackers-hostels" target="_blank"><strong>tips for staying in hostels. </strong></a>Hostels are usually well located allowing you to walk and save on transport.</p>
<ul>
<li>In Australia consider a <a href="http://www3.yha.com.au/membership/yha-membership/" target="_blank"><strong>YHA Membership</strong> </a>and get 10% discounts.</li>
<li>Search hostels worldwide at <a href="http://hostelzoo.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Hostel Zoo</strong></a> &#8211; a free hostel comparison site.<br />
<strong> </strong></li>
</ul>
<div id="attachment_29110" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-save-money-on-travel/img_6583-4/" rel="attachment wp-att-29110"><img class="size-full wp-image-29110" alt="How to save money" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_6583.jpg" width="640" height="427" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Views from YHA Sydney The Rocks</p></div>
<h3><strong>22. Couch Surf</strong></h3>
<p>A great way to meet locals for a drink, a tour, and accommodation is by <a href="http://www.couchsurfing.org" target="_blank"><strong>Couchsurfing</strong></a>. It connects travelers with local people in various cities that offer members a place to sleep.</p>
<h3>23. WWOOF</h3>
<p>WWOOF or WWOOFING stands for World Wide Opportunities on Organic Farms. It is a world wide network of organisations and they link volunteers with organic farmers<b>. </b>In return for volunteer help, WWOOF hosts offer food, accommodation and opportunities to learn about organic lifestyles. Learn more <a href="http://www.wwoof.org/" target="_blank"><strong>here.</strong></a></p>
<h3><strong>24. House Sitting</strong></h3>
<p>Make yourself at home with a spot of <a href="www.ytravelblog.com/house-sitting" target="_blank"><strong>house-sitting</strong></a>. House sitters provide their pet and house sitting services for free in exchange for the privilege of accommodation in the owner’s home.</p>
<h3>25. Do a <strong>Home Exchange</strong></h3>
<p>The <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/holiday-home-exchange/" target="_blank"><strong>home exchange strategy</strong></a> is possibly best for families or retired people who are looking to base themselves in another country or state for an agreed period of time. Just like the name suggests, you stay in their house whilst they stay in yours.</p>
<h3>26. VRBO – Vacation Rentals By Owner</h3>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-3887010-10697640" target="_blank">Vacation Rentals By Owner</a></strong> was founded by owners who self-manage their second homes. Vacation rentals can sometimes offer more value, space and privacy to hotels. VRBO provide an online space for homeowners to advertise their vacation properties &#8211; <strong>130,000+ rentals in over 100 countries worldwide</strong>.</p>
<h3>27. Go Camping</h3>
<p>Camp in a National Park, a caravan park, or on the beach. You’ve got to be prepared for roughing it a little, but hey camping is probably your cheapest option. We have also camped cheaply in the grounds of hostels, and for free in out-of-town family and friends backyards.</p>
<div id="attachment_29111" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 590px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-save-money-on-travel/rsz_185963498303-580x343/" rel="attachment wp-att-29111"><img class="size-full wp-image-29111" alt="How to save money" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/rsz_185963498303-580x343.jpg" width="580" height="343" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Camping in Rocky Mountain National Park, Colorado</p></div>
<h3>28. Sleep While Traveling</h3>
<p>When travelling by plane, train, or bus, try and time it so you are traveling at night. That way, you don’t have to pay for a night’s accommodation.</p>
<h3>29. Attend Time Share Presentations</h3>
<p>Not our favourite strategy &#8211; these can be aggressive sale pitches of 90 minutes or more, but just say no at the end and thank you for the free accommodation for your troubles. Over the years we have had free accommodation in Turkey, Daytona Beach, Orlando, and Key West.</p>
<h3>30. Walk as Much as You Can Walk.</h3>
<p>Get active and see things at a slower pace &#8211; walking is FREE. You can experience more just by wandering around a city and getting lost, talking with locals, and people watching. Explore local markets, wander and take photos, or even hike to the top of a hill for an awesome view.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-save-money-on-travel/bg-7412/" rel="attachment wp-att-29114"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-29114" alt="how to save money" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/BG-7412.jpg" width="480" height="640" /></a></p>
<h3>31. Rent a Bike</h3>
<p>Cheap price, more comfy than a bus, slightly faster pace than walking..</p>
<h3>32. Travel Like the Locals</h3>
<p>Use <strong>public transport</strong> where possible. You get great knowledge and insight by hanging with the locals, it costs you less, and is a more authentic travelling experience. We have done this extensively in Africa and Asia.</p>
<h3>33. Share Transport Costs</h3>
<p>When you do travel by other means, try and share a car with another traveller. Also, sharing a Taxi, mini-van, and tours etc are all more cost-effective when there’s a group of travelers to split the costs.</p>
<h3>34. Eat out for Breakfast, Lunch or Brunch</h3>
<p>Try and avoid dinner as restaurants raise prices. OR, have brunch instead of 3 meals a day. Many restaurants offer lunch specials where items on the dinner menu are offered for a fraction of the cost you’d pay in the evening.</p>
<h3><strong>35. Eat Away from the Tourist Streets</strong></h3>
<p>Just go one street or one block over and it will usually be <strong>much cheaper and more authentic! </strong></p>
<h3>36. Have Picnics and BBQ&#8217;s</h3>
<p>Purchase food in a local grocery store or a market and arrange a picnic in one of the city’s parks with great views. We&#8217;ve had picnics in Sydney&#8217;s Royal Botanic Gardens, New York&#8217;s Central Park, and BBQ&#8217;s world wide.</p>
<h3>37. Self-Cater Where You Can</h3>
<p>We make self-contained accommodation with kitchen facilities a priority. Purchasing your own supplies and cooking-in can save you big bucks &#8211; unless you are in Asia where eating out is incredibly cheap.</p>
<p>And take your own food on flights, buses and trains where practical.</p>
<h3>38. Have Breakfast Included</h3>
<p>When booking a hotel or hostel look for one with breakfast included.</p>
<h3>39. Eat Street Food</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/the-real-reason-you-should-eat-street-food/" target="_blank"><strong>The real reason you should eat street food</strong></a> is because it’s cheap, you help the locals, and it&#8217;s safe  &#8211; you can see what is actually being cooked and is cooked fresh right in front of you. Pay attention to where the locals eat and what is popular.</p>
<div id="attachment_28215" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 810px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/places-to-escape-the-bangkok-madness/index-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-28215"><img class="size-full wp-image-28215" alt="How to save money" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/index1.jpg" width="800" height="800" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Cheap street food in Thailand</p></div>
<h3>40. Drink in Before Going Out</h3>
<p>Just like eating, purchase your alcohol from a store. Then, take advantage of any happy hours and don’t drink expensive import stuff – give the local stuff a go.</p>
<h3>41. Leave your ATM Card at Home</h3>
<p>When out partying or out for dinner, only take a certain amount of cash, once it&#8217;s gone it&#8217;s gone. Your pocket, and your head, will thank you in the morning.</p>
<h3>42. Bargain &#8211; it&#8217;s expected in many countries</h3>
<p>But don&#8217;t over bargain. 50 cents is nothing to you, but may mean a days worth of meals to the person you are haggling with.</p>
<h3>43. Pre-Paid Travel Money Cards</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/prepaid-travel-money-cards/" target="_blank"><strong>Using pre-paid travel money cards</strong></a><strong> </strong>can save you on transaction fees and currency conversion rates (you can lock in a conversion rate) and is a safe and convenient way to carry your money.</p>
<h3>44. Shopping</h3>
<p>Shop for souvenirs, clothes and food where the locals shop. Look for weekend markets and outlet stores.</p>
<h3>45. Laundry</h3>
<p>Wash as much of your laundry as you can by yourself by hand, instead of pumping money through laundromats or using expensive hotel laundry services. Better still, stay in apartments that have washing machines included.</p>
<h3>46. Free Phone Calls</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.vonagemobile.com/apps/vonage-mobile-app.php" target="_blank"><strong>Vonage Moblie has an app</strong></a> that allows for free talk, text, and photo sharing worldwide, available on iPhone and Android.</p>
<p>If you have access to the internet here are two great options:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.skype.com/apps/tracking/commissionjunction.php?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww%2Eskype%2Ecom%2Fgo%2Fgetconnected%3Fcm%5Fmmc%3Daffiliate%2D%5F%2Dcommission%5Fjunction%2D%5F%2Dbanner%2D%5F%2Dskype%5Fkey%5Ffeatures_pid=%zp" target="_blank">Skype</a></strong> is an internet based phone service that lets you call other skype users around the world for <strong>FREE. </strong>Just get a web cam.<strong><br />
</strong></li>
<li>If you are on <a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/109859598166821255303/posts" target="_blank"><strong>Google+</strong></a> use hangouts to video call for free.</li>
</ul>
<h3>47. Internet Access</h3>
<p>When booking accommodation one of the first things we look for is <strong>free WiFi</strong>. In cities and towns seek out free wifi spots at cafes, libraries and hot spots.</p>
<p>If using an internet cafe access can be painfully slow, and if you are paying by the minute it can get expensive. If you have a laptop, pre-write out all your email responses before hand.</p>
<h3>48. How Strong is Your Currency?</h3>
<p>Think about traveling to countries where your currency is stronger and you will get more bang-for-your-buck. For us as Australian&#8217;s Asia, the Pacific Islands, New Zealand, South Africa and currently the USA offers good value!</p>
<h3>49. Compare Car Hire Prices</h3>
<p>We use sites that search all the major car hire companies around the world checking which supplier is offering the best prices for the date you need it. Two sites we use include <a href="http://www.traveljigsaw.com.au/" target="_blank"><strong>Travel Jigsaw</strong></a> and <a href="http://www.vroomvroomvroom.com.au/" target="_blank"><strong>VrommVroomVroom.</strong></a></p>
<h3>50. Improve the Efficiency of Your Car</h3>
<p>When <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/" target="_blank"><strong>taking road trips</strong></a><strong> </strong>make sure your car is operating efficiently and is fully serviced. Some tips:</p>
<ul>
<li>Check the pressure of your car tires.</li>
<li>Drive slower.</li>
<li>Use the right oil to increase mile usage.</li>
<li>Watch your luggage – the heavier the car the more fuel you’ll use.</li>
<li>Pack inside your car not on top.</li>
</ul>
<p>For the ultimate road trip planning guide click <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/" target="_blank"><strong>here.</strong></a></p>
<div id="attachment_28861" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 810px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/seal-rocks-3-013/" rel="attachment wp-att-28861"><img class="size-full wp-image-28861" alt="How to save money" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Seal-Rocks-3-013.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Family road trip in Australia</p></div>
<h3>51. Stay Local<strong><br />
</strong></h3>
<p>Travelling doesn&#8217;t have to involve long flights and extensive road trips. A great way to <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/how-to-travel-more/" target="_blank"><strong>bring more travel into your life</strong></a> is by exploring new areas in your local region. Climb a new mountan, visit a new cafe or market, go kayaking in a nearby river, take a day trip to a new town.</p>
<h3>52. Do the FREE Stuff</h3>
<p>Many things to see and do are absolutely free:</p>
<ul>
<li>See a street fair, concert, or cultural event.</li>
<li>Catch a magnificent sunset or sunrise</li>
<li>Take a walk or bike ride.</li>
<li>Play in the park.</li>
<li>Free movie screenings in local cafes and hostels</li>
<li>Swim at the beach or lake.</li>
<li>Climb a mountain.</li>
<li>Visit a market.</li>
</ul>
<p>Hit the street with your feet and get lost in a city or town. It&#8217;s amazing what you&#8217;ll discover around every corner.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-save-money-on-travel/thailand-beaches-402-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-29115"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-29115" alt="thailand-beaches-402" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/thailand-beaches-402.jpg" width="600" height="775" /></a></p>
<h2>Your Turn</h2>
<h3>What tips do you have on how to save money?</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-save-money-on-travel/">How to Save Money on Travel &#8211; 52 Ideas</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~4/5YopbmoPWNw" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-save-money-on-travel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-save-money-on-travel/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Everything is Figureoutable</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~3/TkgleZjGIZE/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ytravelblog.com/everything-is-figureoutable/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Caz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Experiences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Experiences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B-School]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experiences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiring quotes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ytravelblog.com/?p=28854</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Hands up if there is something you really want to do with your life, but you haven’t done it because you can’t figure out the hows? My hand is raised too. &#160; It doesn’t matter how powerful the urge is, the “How am I going to make this work” roadblock can send us cowering in [...]</p><p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/everything-is-figureoutable/">Everything is Figureoutable</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hands up if there is something you really want to do with your life, but you haven’t done it because you can’t figure out the hows?</p>
<h3>My hand is raised too.</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It doesn’t matter how powerful the urge is, the <em>“How am I going to make this work”</em> roadblock can send us cowering in the trenches and waving goodbye to that life we just knew we would love.</p>
<p>Sounds pretty ridiculous right?</p>
<p>I’m not one to get bogged down in details; I&#8217;m more of a big picture person, which serves me well when working to make my dreams come to life.</p>
<p>I see the ultimate goal and go for it because I know:</p>
<h2><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28957" alt="Marie Forleo quote" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Marie-Forleo-quote.jpg" width="600" height="900" /></h2>
<p><a href="http://rhhbschool.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Marie Forleo</strong></a> introduced me to this phrase recently and I realised I’ve been following this advice all my life. (If you don’t know her she is an amazing marketer who runs <a href="http://rhhbschool.com/" target="_blank"><strong>B-School</strong></a>, this fantastic course I have recently joined).</p>
<p>If you spend all your time and energy trying to figure out everything before you even start, you’ll never start.</p>
<p>It’s truly not as easy as it sounds, but it is also even easier.</p>
<p>Hmm. Try and figure that one out?</p>
<h2>The hard part</h2>
<p>It’s not easy because relying on this concept means you have to have a lot of confidence in yourself and faith in your dreams.</p>
<p>That’s the hard part. From an early age society loves to tell us we don’t know it all and to look to the experts before trusting the innate wisdom you hold.</p>
<p>We should be letting our urges and intuition guide us.</p>
<h2>The easy part</h2>
<p>If you have a dream to travel the world, or a desire itching you from deep within, that is your inner knowing telling you to follow and do.</p>
<p>That place of confidence is what you must dive into. Put your faith in the calling and go for it.</p>
<p>Forget all the things that can go wrong, forget the how am I going to make it happen. Just put one foot in front of the other and figure it out as you go along &#8211; the easy part.</p>
<p>Some of you are booking your travel tickets right now. Others need more hand holding and convincing. Sometimes we need to build confidence as we go. Take small steps and hold someone’s hand &#8211; a relatable person who has done what you want to do.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>If they can do it, you can do it.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>This empowering phrase has driven and empowered me to live the life of my choosing.</p>
<p><strong>If someone else can do it why not me?</strong></p>
<p><em>If I can do it so can you. I am no more special than you are; I just figured it out along the way.</em></p>
<p>Sometimes you just gotta throw yourself in the deep end to convince yourself you can.</p>
<h2>Throwing myself in the deep end of travel</h2>
<p>When I first moved to London I was 21. I had not long graduated from University and had never lived on my own. I had some independence and self-confidence, but my parents were mostly looking after my needs.</p>
<p>I travelled first through Indonesia with two girlfriends. Thanks to a badly infected foot, I left early and moved to London. I had no money, no job, no place to stay and a badly infected foot. (You can read about it<a title="Arriving in London Alone and Without Any Money" href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/arriving-in-london-alone-and-without-any-money/" target="_blank"><strong> here</strong></a>).</p>
<p>I cried when there was no one around; I was so scared and lonely. But, out in public, I put on my brave face and said, “You’ve got this.”</p>
<p><strong>One foot after the other.</strong> I figured it out and 15 years later I am still going.</p>
<p>Stop for a minute and think about the inner power you tap into when you arrive in one of the biggest metropolises in the world with nothing but a backpack and a few dollars in your wallet, and then survive.</p>
<h2>What did I rely on?</h2>
<p>I knew I was capable of working. I had a working holiday visa, I also had a degree (yet no experiences), I had hospitality experience, and I knew how to work hard.</p>
<p>I had an acquaintance in London I could phone to see if she could lend me a couch to sleep on. They call it couch-surfing now, back then it was <strong>dossing.</strong> I phoned terrified, but her warm friendly voice soon took those fears away. I stayed with her and soon found my feet. She’s one of my best friends to this day.</p>
<div id="attachment_29020" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 704px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/everything-is-figureoutable/scan0066-l/" rel="attachment wp-att-29020"><img class="size-full wp-image-29020" alt="Teaching in London, 1997" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/scan0066-L.jpg" width="694" height="600" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Teaching in London, 1997</p></div>
<blockquote><p><strong>Everything is figureoutable.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>A couple of years later, I broke up the disastrous relationship I had with my South African boyfriend.  I decided to leave London. But go where? And with what?</p>
<p><strong>What did I rely on?</strong></p>
<p>My brother, who had been traveling for years before me. New York or Dublin? He advised me Dublin would be easier. It was closer to London, he had contacts that could possibly help me find work, it wasn’t as big, and I should enjoy the craic.</p>
<p>So I went. Again in the space where no one was watching I cried. A lot. This time I was an emotional wreck. I had 70 Irish punt in the bank, no friends, no place to stay, and no job.</p>
<p><strong>What did I do?</strong></p>
<p>Relied on my ability to work. I forced myself to walk into bars and ask for work. I had zero confidence, but I knew I had to suck it up and swim. I was tired of sinking.</p>
<p>That evening I started my first shift in one of the busiest bars in Temple Bar. I was crap at serving Guinness—a sin in Ireland. An all in brawl started as I was collecting glasses and I ducked just in time before copping a flying fist to the face.</p>
<p>My manager was a jerk and we had a shouting match. He sent me upstairs to help out in the busy restaurant. I worked my butt off and asked the manager if I could work there instead of the bar. She said yes.</p>
<p>Every evening I walked out with a wallet overflowing with tips. My best friend soon moved over to join me. We found a flat share and made some amazing friends. It was one of the happiest times of my travel life.</p>
<div id="attachment_29021" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 810px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/everything-is-figureoutable/scan0039/" rel="attachment wp-att-29021"><img class="size-full wp-image-29021" alt="Enjoying a pint with my best friend Bec" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/scan0039.jpg" width="800" height="537" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Enjoying a pint with my best friend Bec</p></div>
<blockquote><p>Everything is figureoutable.</p></blockquote>
<h2>How to trust yourself</h2>
<p>Now, I am happy to travel to a destination on a whim. Without knowing anything, without even having much money in the bank. I trust myself.</p>
<p>I know all I have to do is fall back on my skill levels. What do I know? What can I do? Who can I turn to?</p>
<p>I trust I am empowered enough to figure it out.</p>
<h2>Figuring it out to create your ultimate lifestyle</h2>
<p>I now apply this way of thinking to my business. I started not knowing a thing about <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/to-all-new-travel-bloggers/" target="_blank"><strong>travel blogging</strong></a>, writing, social media, or even networking.</p>
<p>Whenever an opportunity arose, which meant us progressing to another level, I said yes and then in my quiet spaces either cried or said, <em>“Shit. I don’t know how to do this.”</em></p>
<p>But, one thing I do know is that <strong>Everything is figureoutable. </strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.beautifulyoubyjulie.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Julie Parker</strong></a>, </strong>a life coach I&#8217;ve recently met through B-School described it beautifully.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28949" alt="inspiring quote" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/inspiring-quote.jpg" width="488" height="600" /></p>
<p>Craig and I have been focused on getting ourselves into mainstream media. We know that it is the next step up for us. But, it is pretty damn scary (not to mention difficult).</p>
<p>Last week we were asked by the producer of 702 ABC radio in Sydney to chat about places to see in Sydney Harbour on their travel segment.</p>
<p><em>“We are looking at the undiscovered places that not many people will know about. Do you think you can do it?”</em> the producer asked over the phone.</p>
<blockquote><p>“Yes, sure.”</p>
<p>&#8220;Can you come in tomorrow?”</p>
<p>“Sure thing.”</p></blockquote>
<p>I had no idea what my schedule was. I just knew I could not say no. As I was saying yes, my mind was shaking,</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“Shit. I don’t know enough. How am I going to talk for 10 minutes? I haven’t been everywhere on the harbour. I think I only know the well-known places. Shit shit shit.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>I was forced to fall back on what I know. I went through old blog posts and realized I actually did know more than I thought about undiscovered places. I had enough material to chat for 10 minutes. What I didn’t know I did a little research on.</p>
<h3>Phew.</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I arrived. I took a deep breath, told myself “You’ve got this, just be yourself.” I chatted live on radio, only stumbled once, and was greeted with a smile and thumbs up when it was over.</p>
<p>(press play to hear the interview- Recording courtesy of &#8220;Mornings with Linda Mottram on <a href="http://abc.net.au/sydney" target="_blank"><strong>702 ABC Sydney</strong></a>&#8220;)</p>

<p>I had fun and I want to do more of it.</p>
<p>I was buzzing because I knew the new realm of confidence I leapt into would bring new opportunities.</p>
<p>When you shove aside the fears and just do what you truly want to do, the Universe will bring you what you want. You don’t need to have it perfect before you start.</p>
<h2>Everything is figureoutable.</h2>
<p>Listen to your heart and leap, the Universe will fly you to the perfect place.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/everything-is-figureoutable/">Everything is Figureoutable</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~4/TkgleZjGIZE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ytravelblog.com/everything-is-figureoutable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://media.blubrry.com/ytravelblogpodcast/media.blubrry.com/mojitomotherpodcast/content.blubrry.com/mojitomotherpodcast/thingstoseesydneyharbour.mp3" length="7308392" type="audio/mpeg" />
			<itunes:keywords>B-School,experiences,inspiration,inspiring quotes</itunes:keywords>
	<itunes:subtitle>Hands up if there is something you really want to do with your life, but you haven’t done it because you can’t figure out the hows? My hand is raised too.   - It doesn’t matter how powerful the urge is, the “How am I going to make this work” roadblo...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Hands up if there is something you really want to do with your life, but you haven’t done it because you can’t figure out the hows?
My hand is raised too.
 

It doesn’t matter how powerful the urge is, the “How am I going to make this work” roadblock can send us cowering in the trenches and waving goodbye to that life we just knew we would love.

Sounds pretty ridiculous right?

I’m not one to get bogged down in details; I'm more of a big picture person, which serves me well when working to make my dreams come to life.

I see the ultimate goal and go for it because I know:

Marie Forleo introduced me to this phrase recently and I realised I’ve been following this advice all my life. (If you don’t know her she is an amazing marketer who runs B-School, this fantastic course I have recently joined).

If you spend all your time and energy trying to figure out everything before you even start, you’ll never start.

It’s truly not as easy as it sounds, but it is also even easier.

Hmm. Try and figure that one out?
The hard part
It’s not easy because relying on this concept means you have to have a lot of confidence in yourself and faith in your dreams.

That’s the hard part. From an early age society loves to tell us we don’t know it all and to look to the experts before trusting the innate wisdom you hold.

We should be letting our urges and intuition guide us.
The easy part
If you have a dream to travel the world, or a desire itching you from deep within, that is your inner knowing telling you to follow and do.

That place of confidence is what you must dive into. Put your faith in the calling and go for it.

Forget all the things that can go wrong, forget the how am I going to make it happen. Just put one foot in front of the other and figure it out as you go along - the easy part.

Some of you are booking your travel tickets right now. Others need more hand holding and convincing. Sometimes we need to build confidence as we go. Take small steps and hold someone’s hand - a relatable person who has done what you want to do.
If they can do it, you can do it.
This empowering phrase has driven and empowered me to live the life of my choosing.

If someone else can do it why not me?

If I can do it so can you. I am no more special than you are; I just figured it out along the way.

Sometimes you just gotta throw yourself in the deep end to convince yourself you can.
Throwing myself in the deep end of travel
When I first moved to London I was 21. I had not long graduated from University and had never lived on my own. I had some independence and self-confidence, but my parents were mostly looking after my needs.

I travelled first through Indonesia with two girlfriends. Thanks to a badly infected foot, I left early and moved to London. I had no money, no job, no place to stay and a badly infected foot. (You can read about it here).

I cried when there was no one around; I was so scared and lonely. But, out in public, I put on my brave face and said, “You’ve got this.”

One foot after the other. I figured it out and 15 years later I am still going.

Stop for a minute and think about the inner power you tap into when you arrive in one of the biggest metropolises in the world with nothing but a backpack and a few dollars in your wallet, and then survive.
What did I rely on?
I knew I was capable of working. I had a working holiday visa, I also had a degree (yet no experiences), I had hospitality experience, and I knew how to work hard.

I had an acquaintance in London I could phone to see if she could lend me a couch to sleep on. They call it couch-surfing now, back then it was dossing. I phoned terrified, but her warm friendly voice soon took those fears away. I stayed with her and soon found my feet. She’s one of my best friends to this day.


Everything is figureoutable.
A couple of years later, I broke up the disastrous relationship I had with my South African boyfriend.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Caz</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>17:24</itunes:duration>
		<rawvoice:embed>&lt;iframe width="320" height="24" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/?powerpress_embed=28854-podcast&amp;amp;powerpress_player=default" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</rawvoice:embed>
	<media:content url="http://media.blubrry.com/ytravelblogpodcast/media.blubrry.com/mojitomotherpodcast/content.blubrry.com/mojitomotherpodcast/thingstoseesydneyharbour.mp3" fileSize="7308392" type="audio/mpeg" /><feedburner:origLink>http://www.ytravelblog.com/everything-is-figureoutable/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>City Guide – Things to Do in Adelaide</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~3/mrahx7RtTKg/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 12:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Craig</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Adelaide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[City Guides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oceania]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[city guides]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ytravelblog.com/?p=28929</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Are you looking for tips on things to do in Adelaide? As part of our city guides series, we interviewed Nicole Smith from Bitten by the Travel Bug who is an Adelaide native. Nicole shares with us her insider tips on the best things to do in Adelaide, plus advice on where to eat, sleep, drink, shop [...]</p><p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/">City Guide &#8211; Things to Do in Adelaide</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/adelaide-austral-hotel-rundle-street-east/" rel="attachment wp-att-28977"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28977" alt="Things to Do in Adelaide" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Adelaide-Austral-Hotel-Rundle-Street-East.jpg" width="730" height="400" /></a></p>
<p>Are you looking for tips on <strong>things to do in Adelaide?</strong></p>
<p>As part of our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/city-guide/" target="_blank"><strong>city guides</strong></a> series, we interviewed Nicole Smith from <a href="http://www.bittenbythetravelbug.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Bitten by the Travel Bug </strong></a>who is an Adelaide native.</p>
<p>Nicole shares with us her <em><strong>insider tips</strong></em> on the best things to do in Adelaide, plus advice on where to eat, sleep, drink, shop and explore.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Why Visit Adelaide?</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Adelaide is often the ‘forgotten’ city of Australia or considered ‘for the old fogies’ because it’s more food and wine country. That said, Adelaide is one of the greenest cities in the world, the <strong>most affordable city in Australia</strong>, and we have a huge passion for sport and the arts.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Adelaide has the best of everything Australia offers within 20-minutes of the city centre – who wouldn’t love that?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Best of all, there’s minimal traffic problems in Adelaide.</p>
<div id="attachment_28982" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 740px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/adelaide-koala/" rel="attachment wp-att-28982"><img class="size-full wp-image-28982" alt="Things to Do in Adelaide" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Adelaide-Koala.jpg" width="730" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">See koala&#8217;s and other Australian wildlife at Cleland Wildlife Park</p></div>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Things to Do in Adelaide</h2>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong>Take in a game of cricket at Adelaide Oval</strong> &#8211; Widely considered the best pitch in the world by players and one of the few places where you can still sit ‘on the hill’ and have a picnic.</li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong>Spend an evening at Henley Beach</strong> &#8211; This has to be my favourite area of Adelaide. Beautiful clean beach that not many tourists frequent (they seem to head to dirty Glenelg), wonderful meals, and a great atmosphere in what is turning out to be quite an artsy neighborhood.</li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong>Take a wine tour</strong> &#8211; We’re mad about our wine and know that ours is the best in Australia – take that Victoria! I recommend either arranging for a short-stay in one of the wine regions – we have 18 to choose from whether you want to be near the water or close to the city – or doing a Wine tour with a reputable company, such as Groovy Grapes.</li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong>Enjoy Hahndorf</strong> &#8211; The oldest Germany community in Australia, Hahndorf hasn’t lost all of it’s old-style architecture or fun, and don’t forget to have a pint at the Hahndorf Inn.</li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong>Meet the locals at Cleland National Park</strong> &#8211; If you want to see some of Australia’s native flora and fauna, head to the Adelaide hills and see kangaroos and koalas up close.</li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong>Explore the River Torrens</strong> &#8211; The river that runs through the heart of the city is small but there is plenty going on. A hub for festivals, paddle boat for some fun, or take the Popeye river cruise.</li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong>Eat Haigh&#8217;s Chocolate</strong> &#8211; Whilst there is a shop in Rundle Mall, visit the <strong><a title="Haigh's Chocolate factory" href="http://www.haighschocolates.com.au/" target="_blank">Haigh&#8217;s factory on Greenhill Road</a></strong> to see chocolates being made and taste samples of this South Australian companies chocolate.</li>
</ul>
<div id="attachment_28992" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 740px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/adelaide-haighs-chocolate-factory-greenhill-road/" rel="attachment wp-att-28992"><img class="size-full wp-image-28992" alt="Things to Do in Adelaide" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Adelaide-Haighs-Chocolate-Factory-Greenhill-Road.jpg" width="730" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Chocolate time at Haigh’s Chocolate factory!</p></div>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong>Mount Lofty</strong> &#8211; For a view across Adelaide this is the place to visit. It’s quite a way out so if you’re happy with something a little closer to town visit Windy Point instead.</li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong>Victor Harbour</strong> &#8211; Horse drawn carriages, fairy penguins and cute markets are found in this coastal town about two-hours out of Adelaide. Especially popular in summer with locals who own beach-side properties.</li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong>Kangaroo Island</strong> &#8211; Made famous by Oprah, Kangaroo Island is a wildlife paradise. Sea-lions, koalas, little penguins and of course a few kangaroos; Kangaroo Island is the perfect place to visit all year round. See a lavender farm, birds of prey display or taste the local produce, there&#8217;s plenty to do on this island.</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Best Neighborhoods to Explore?</h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Hahndorf</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Wander the main street and enjoy a proper German stout at the Hahndorf Inn, enjoy the leather or wood-craft stores, eat some lebkuchen (that is, gingerbread) or other traditional German cakes at the bakery, and enjoy the atmosphere.</p>
<p>If you have time I highly recommend you walk or take the bus one stop out-of-town to the <strong>Beerenberg Farm</strong>. The jams and condiments made by Beerenberg can be found around Australia and internationally, and if it’s strawberry season you can pick your own berries to enjoy.</p>
<h3>Glenelg</h3>
<p>Connected to the city by Adelaide’s trams (and the historic carriages on the weekends), Glenelg is Adelaide’s busiest beach. Personally, I’d choose to visit <b>Henley Beach</b> if you want to escape the crowds and have clean sands, but you can’t go past the restaurants, bars, shopping and nightlife in Glenelg.</p>
<h3>Henley Beach</h3>
<p>Glenelg’s cleaner and quieter cousin, Henley Beach has white sands, volleyball courts, and quality restaurants and cafes – alongside the local fish&amp;chip and yiros/souvlaki stores.</p>
<p>Henley Beach is quite an artsy places with plenty of galleries along Seaview Road popping up and a weekend organic market.</p>
<h3>Rundle Street East<b> </b></h3>
<p>In the city centre, but if you’re looking for boutique stores, a range of pubs and plenty of great places to eat then Rundle Street East is your place to go.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Be sure to check out the laneways as there are more galleries, more restaurants and more shops than just on the main road!</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Where to Eat in Adelaide</h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Restaurants</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong><a title="Lenzerheide restaurant Adelaide" href="http://www.lenzerheide.com.au/index.php" target="_blank">Lenzerheide</a></strong> – celebrating Adelaide’s abundant fresh food and Swiss/Austrian cuisine, the Lenzerheide has taken home a slew of awards, including ‘Best European Restaurant’. Located 10 minutes out of the city the restaurant is easy to get to by public transport or car.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>I highly recommend the potato &amp; leek soup and the chateaubriant (roasted beef tenderloin) at this somewhat pricey, but worth it, restaurant.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong><a title="Alphutte restaurant in Adelaide" href="http://www.alphutte.com.au/" target="_blank">Alphutte</a></strong> – comparable to the Lenzerheide (they were once sister restaurants), Alphutte brings German and Austrian cuisine to Adelaide. Centrally located on the corner of Pultney St and Wakefield St, the prices are quite expensive by Adelaide-standards.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong><a title="Estia Greek Restaurant in Adelaide" href="http://www.estia.com.au/" target="_blank">Estia</a></strong> – If you took my advice and headed to Henley Beach then Estia is the restaurant I’d recommend you dine at. Greek cuisine in Henley Square, tapas or single servings, a laid-back family atmosphere, and the sounds of the beach in the background – do I need to say more?</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>I recommend the Tis Skaras Arnaki (marinated grilled chicken) and loukoumathes (honey puffs) for dessert.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Spats</strong> – blink and you’ll miss it; Spats on King William Road, Hyde Park is fast becoming the locals favourite dinner and late night café and restaurant. Serving Eastern European food, I wasn’t blown away by it but for the prices it’s worth a visit. My tip would be to eat elsewhere and come for drinks and dessert.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><a title="Goodlife Pizza Adelaide" href="http://www.goodlifepizza.com/" target="_blank"><strong>GoodLife Pizza</strong></a> – Hutt Street has plenty of choices but I go for cheap and cheerful Good Life pizza any day of the week. Wood oven fired organic pizza which not only is healthy but tasty – perfecto.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dumpling King</strong> – A student favourite in China town. Cheap, cheerful, and tasty Chinese food on a budget. The dumplings aren’t standout but when you’re paying AU$6 for a plate of 15, I’m not complaining. Top picks are the pork dumplings and the silver thread loaf.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><a title="Joy Discovery Cafe Restaurant" href="http://www.joydiscoverycafe.com.au/" target="_blank"><strong>Joy Discovery Vegetarian Cafe</strong></a> &#8211; A really simple Vegetarian restaurant just off of Rundle Street East on Bent Street (next to American Apparel). Highly recommend one of their curries and some samosas!</li>
</ul>
<div id="attachment_28983" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 740px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/adelaide-chocolate-bean-union-street/" rel="attachment wp-att-28983"><img class="size-full wp-image-28983" alt="Things to Do in Adelaide" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Adelaide-Chocolate-Bean-Union-Street.jpg" width="730" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Welcome to chocolate heaven at the Chocolate Bean Cafe</p></div>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Cafes</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong><a title="Chocolate Bean cafe Adelaide" href="http://www.chocolatebean.com/" target="_blank">Chocolate Bean</a></strong> – have you ever wanted to try chocolate soup? Well this is the place to do it. Located on Union Street, just off of Rundle Street East, they serve great sandwiches and chocolate everything! They’re also vegan and vegetarian friendly.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong><a title="Cibo Espresso cafe in Adelaide and Queensland" href="http://www.ciboespresso.com.au/" target="_blank">Cibo Espresso</a></strong> &#8211; Alright, I’m not much for chains but in Adelaide Cibo does coffee best. Located through the city and metropolitan area and expanding rapidly into Queensland and other Australian states, their coffee knocks all of the competition out of the water.</li>
</ul>
<div id="attachment_8293" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 740px"><a href="http://bittenbythetravelbug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Adelaide-Zambreros-Rundle-Street-East.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-8293" alt="Zambreros Mexican Adelaide" src="http://bittenbythetravelbug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Adelaide-Zambreros-Rundle-Street-East.jpg" width="730" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Grab a late night Mexican feast at Zambreros</p></div>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Late Eats</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong><a title="Vilis Pies and Cakes in Adelaide" href="http://www.vilis.com/vilis-cafe/" target="_blank">Vilis Pies &amp; Bakery</a></strong> &#8211; Vili’s is an Australian icon and it started business in Adelaide. Forget fast food if your hungry at night, Vili’s Café’ which is just outside the city on Manchester St, Mile End is the place to go for a meat pie and frog cake. It’s not just the pies and cakes we love, the owner – Vili Milisits – is an icon around Adelaide who doesn’t let it get to his head by participating in on air pranks (he has his own rap!) and most days you’ll find him manning the fryer in the café.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong><a title="Zambrero" href="http://www.zambrero.com/" target="_blank">Zambreros</a></strong> &#8211; gourmet Mexican food. I&#8217;m talking close to foot-long burritos burritos made in front of you. There are two great things about Zambreros: 1. they&#8217;re open late. 2. They can serve beer and tequila!</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Where to Drink in Adelaide</h2>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong><a title="Coopers Brewery Adelaide" href="http://www.coopers.com.au/" target="_blank">Cooper&#8217;s Brewery</a> &#8211; </strong>Located in Mile End, the brewery offers tours of the enormous factory that makes SA’s favourite beer.</li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong><a title="The Duke of York Hotel Adelaide" href="http://www.dukeofyork.com.au/" target="_blank">The Duke</a> (of York)</strong> &#8211; Cheap pizzas throughout the week, a beer garden out the back and DJ + dance floor upstairs Thursday til Sunday makes it the perfect place to hang and have a good time.</li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong><a title="Zhivago Adelaide" href="http://zhivago.com.au/" target="_blank">Zhivago</a></strong> &#8211; One of Adelaide’s newest and perhaps most edgy club, Zhivago is one of the hottest places to be and perfect for the inner hipster.</li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong><a title="The Austral bar in Adelaide" href="http://www.theaustral.com.au/" target="_blank">The Austral</a></strong> &#8211; if you want a pub, a real pub, with a pub atmosphere, the Austral on Rundle Street East is the place that you need to go. Three areas, a few video games, seating out the front and a bar – what more do you need?</li>
</ul>
<div id="attachment_28984" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 740px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/adelaide-austral-hotel-rundle-street-east-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28984"><img class="size-full wp-image-28984" alt="Things to Do in Adelaide" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Adelaide-Austral-Hotel-Rundle-Street-East1.jpg" width="730" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Austral – a great pub on Rundle Street East</p></div>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong><a title="Boho bar" href="http://www.bohobar.com.au/" target="_blank">Boho Bar</a></strong> &#8211; risqué and circus themed, Boho bar on the bottom of Unley Road is a feast for all of your senses. Come for a meal, drink, or one of their Halloween extravaganzas.</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Where to Stay in Adelaide</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you’re looking for a central location that’s <strong>budget friendly</strong> my top choice would be<strong> <a title="Adelaide Central YHA" href="http://www3.yha.com.au/hostels/sa/adelaide/adelaide-backpackers-hostel/" target="_blank">Adelaide Central YHA</a></strong>. Located in Light Square it’s a two blocks to Rundle Mall – Adelaide’s main shopping strip and there are plenty of bars and restaurants nearby.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you’re after <strong>luxury</strong> in Adelaide then you can’t go past the<strong><a href="http://www.icadelaide.com.au/" target="_blank"> Intercontinental Adelaide</a></strong>. On North Terrace, you are a stone throw away from Adelaide’s main sights – the Torrens River, Rundle Mall, the museums, and even Adelaide Zoo!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you are wanting a beachside getaway be sure to enquire about two properties that <strong><a title="Oaks" href="http://www.oakshotelsresorts.com/glenelg-accommodation/" target="_blank">Oaks</a></strong> have at Glenelg. One is on the water and Marina whilst the other is one street back. Offering larger apartment-style rooms it is a great choice for families looking to stretch out and relax.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If <strong>boutique</strong> is more your style then I’ve heard good things about the <a title="Clarion Hotel Soho Adelaide" href="http://www.clarionhotelsoho.com.au" target="_blank"><strong>Clarion Hotel Soho</strong></a>. Slick, sexy and modern, the Clarion Hotel Soho is perfect boutique hotel for a couple’s getaway.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Markets and Shopping in Adelaide</h2>
<p>My personal favourite type of shopping is through little boutiques and <strong>King William Road, Hyde Park </strong>and <strong>Rundle Street East</strong> take the cake for choices. King William Road can be a little higher priced but check out Wild Child for a great range, though sizes do run small.</p>
<p>Rundle Street has big name bands like Australian designer Lisa Ho and Zimmerman to favourite miss gladys sym choon and alternative chain, Dangerfield. There are also some quirky boutiques in the backstreets including Mid-West Traders.</p>
<div id="attachment_28993" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 740px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/adelaide-shopping-ms-gladys-sim-choo-rundle-street-east-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28993"><img class="size-full wp-image-28993" alt="Things to Do in Adelaide" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Adelaide-Shopping-Ms-Gladys-Sim-Choo-Rundle-Street-East1.jpg" width="730" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Go shopping at Miss Gladys Sym Choon on Rundle Street East</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Adelaide love their markets</strong>, but the one closest to our heart has to be <strong><a title="Adelaide's Central Markets" href="http://www.adelaidecentralmarket.com.au/" target="_blank">Adelaide’s Central Market</a></strong>. Open Monday to Saturday the restaurant is home to fresh produce from across the state, an array of boutique stalls, as well as a camera store and second-hand book seller. If you want a quick, cheap, fresh bite then this is the place to go.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Adelaide also has a <strong><a title="Adelaide Farmers Market" href="http://www.asfm.org.au/" target="_blank">Farmers Market</a></strong> at the Wayville Showgrounds. Farmers from across the state come every Sunday to sell their produce and cut out the middle man, meaning you get great tasting produce and get to support farmers from around the state. There’s everything from fruit &amp; veg to baked goods, bottled cordials and small goods.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If <strong>fashion and design</strong> are more your style then the <strong><a title="Gillies Street Market" href="http://gillesstreetmarket.com.au/" target="_blank">Gillies Street Market</a></strong>, which happens twice a month, will be a winner with you. Find your inner vintage goddess amongst live music and food stalls.</p>
<div id="attachment_8296" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 740px"><a href="http://bittenbythetravelbug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Adelaide-Farmers-Market-Cordial-Tasting.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-8296" alt="Adelaide Farmers Market" src="http://bittenbythetravelbug.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Adelaide-Farmers-Market-Cordial-Tasting.jpg" width="730" height="550" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Taste cordials and lots more at the Adelaide Farmers Market at Wayville Showgrounds</p></div>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Events and Festivals in Adelaide</h2>
<p>January we play host to the <a title="Tour Down Under" href="http://www.tourdownunder.com.au/" target="_blank"><b>Tour Down Under</b></a>. Forgiving all the locals who will done lycra and think they are the next Cadel Williams, Adelaide puts on a good show. Think outdoor parties by the Torrens River, a big parade welcoming the athletes, 7-days of intense racing through the best areas of South Australia, and of course – street parties, the chance for many of the neighborhoods that riders will start/finish in to host a party and celebrate what’s best in that area.</p>
<p>For four weeks during February and March Australia’s largest arts event, the <a title="Adelaide Fringe Festival" href="http://www.adelaidefringe.com.au/" target="_blank"><b>Adelaide Fringe Festival</b></a> comes to town. Similar to the Edinburgh Fringe Festival, Adelaide opens its doors to artists from around the world to share their art forms – cabaret, comedy, circus, dance, film, theatre, puppetry, music, visual art and design.</p>
<div id="attachment_28987" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 740px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/adelaide-fringe-festival-hans/" rel="attachment wp-att-28987"><img class="size-full wp-image-28987" alt="Things to Do in Adelaide" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Adelaide-Fringe-Festival-Hans.jpg" width="730" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Adelaide Fringe Festival is a flurry of dance, cabaret, circus and comedy – favourite show has to go to ‘Hans’</p></div>
<p>The <a title="Clipsal 500" href="http://www.clipsal500.com.au/" target="_blank"><b>Clipsal 500</b></a> is the beginning of a busy March. V8 supercars turn the cities East into a race track. It&#8217;s not just the V8 Supercars that will take to the track as the GT championship is back in 2013, as well as playing host to the Dunlop racing series.</p>
<p><a title="Womadelaide" href="http://www.womadelaide.com.au/" target="_blank"><b>WOMADelaide</b></a>, the dance, music and arts festival is held mid-March. A unique music experience runs over four days in the cities Botanic Park and show cases performances and workshops by the best traditional and contemporary musicians, dancers and DJs.<br />
WOMADelaide also has a very cool ‘Taste the World’ cooking program and environmental discussion forum, and supports a number of charitable causes. Best of for families, all kids 12 and under get free entry into the festival!</p>
<p>If contemporary and traditional isn’t the beat to your drum I highly recommend checking out the <a title="Future Music Festival" href="http://www.futuremusicfestival.com.au/" target="_blank"><b>Future Music Festival</b></a>. A one-day festival from noon til 10pm, Future Music Festival showcases the best of up &amp; coming or the summers top performers. This year features big name performers like The Prodigy, Bloc Party, Dizzee Rascal, Rita Ora, Ellie Goulding, Fun, The Temper Trap and Psy – and that’s not even half the line up!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Adelaide is also home to the <strong><a title="Schutzenfest Adelaide" href="http://schutzenfest.com.au/" target="_blank">Schutzenfest</a></strong> in January – the cities equivalent to a German beer fest; the <strong><a title="Adelaide Festival" href="http://www.adelaidefestival.com.au/2013/index" target="_blank">Adelaide Festival</a></strong> , an arts festival which runs alongside the Fringe Festival in March, and the <strong><a title="Adelaide Cabaret Festival" href="http://www.adelaidecabaret.com/" target="_blank">Adelaide Cabaret Festival</a></strong> in June. There&#8217;s also the <strong><a title="Adelaide Fashion Festival" href="http://adelaidefashionfestival.com.au/" target="_blank">Adelaide Fashion Festival</a></strong> in October for the fashionistas among us!</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Getting Around Adelaide</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you’re in the city centre it’s pretty easy to walk around between the main sites or take the <strong><a title="Adelaide Connector Bus" href="http://www.adelaidecitycouncil.com/community/your-transport-options/free-connector-bus/" target="_blank">free connector bus</a>.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you’re heading to <strong>Glenelg</strong>, from one side of the city to the other, King William Road, or the Entertainment Centre, I recommend you take the <strong><a title="Adelaide Metro Tram" href="http://www.adelaidemetro.com.au/routes/Tram" target="_blank">tram</a></strong>. It’s one route so easy to get on or off, and if you’re travelling through the city its free!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I’d recommend visitors use buses to get around but to make your own decision check out the <strong><a title="Adelaide Metro website" href="http://www.adelaidemetro.com.au/" target="_blank">Adelaide Metro website</a> </strong>or visit the Adelaide Metro store on the corner of Currie Street and King William Street in the city to plan your journeys.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Finding WiFi in Adelaide</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Adelaide isn’t the most WiFi friendly city. I’d say that all hotels and hostels will have WiFi, and many cafes will but it won’t be the best quality.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you’re having connection problems I’d check out China Town and Grote Street as there is quite a few Internet cafes, otherwise check out <a title="Internode hotspots Adelaide" href="https://hotspot.internode.on.net/coverage/index.php" target="_blank">I<strong>nternodes Hot Spot</strong></a> locations for cafes that offer free WiFi.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Best Time of Year to Visit Adelaide</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Little tip from a local – <strong>visit between January and March</strong>. Not only will you get the best weather but this is when Adelaide really shines and proves that it can compete with Melbourne and Sydney.</p>
<div id="attachment_28988" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 740px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/adelaide-henley-square-beach/" rel="attachment wp-att-28988"><img class="size-full wp-image-28988" alt="Things to Do in Adelaide" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Adelaide-Henley-Square-Beach.jpg" width="730" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Henley Beach is stunning in the summer time!</p></div>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Getting There and Away?</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Adelaide is a big city and serviced by all Australian airlines (Qantas, Virgin Australia, Jetstar), including many regional ones.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Getting from the airport to the city is easy. It’s about AU$15-20 for a taxi or there are <strong><a title="Airport jet bus service Adelaide" href="http://www.adelaidemetro.com.au/Timetables-Maps/Special-Services/JetBus-Airport-Service" target="_blank">airport JetBus</a> </strong>services from the city and many surrounding suburbs.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you prefer the scenic route, Adelaide is the heart of many of the overland train journeys offered by <strong><a title="Great Southern Rail" href="http://www.greatsouthernrail.com.au/site/home.jsp" target="_blank">Great Southern Rail</a>.</strong> Take the Ghan from Adelaide to Darwin, via. Alice Springs; The Indian Pacific from Sydney to Perth, via Adelaide; the Overland from Melbourne to Adelaide; or the Southern Spirit from Adelaide to Brisbane, via. Melbourne.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Trains get into the station at Mile End, and though only minutes from the city I recommend you take a taxi or catch a public bus from Richmond Road.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you prefer taking the bus then they arrive at the Adelaide Central Bus Station. Two choices of operators are <strong><a title="Greyhound Australia" href="http://www.greyhound.com.au/" target="_blank">Greyhound Australia</a></strong> and <strong><a title="FireFly bus service" href="http://www.fireflyexpress.com.au/FFNew/Index.asp" target="_blank">Firefly</a>.</strong></p>
<h2>Best &#8220;insiders&#8221; Tip</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you want a view of the city, a great place for a picnic or somewhere to go ice blocking (yes, you sit on a rug on a huge piece of ice and hurtle down a hill!) then I recommend visiting <strong>Light&#8217;s Point</strong>.</p>
<div id="attachment_28989" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 740px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/adelaide-lights-point-city-landscape/" rel="attachment wp-att-28989"><img class="size-full wp-image-28989" alt="Things to Do in Adelaide" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Adelaide-Lights-Point-City-Landscape.jpg" width="730" height="550" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Enjoy the view over Adelaide from Light’s Point</p></div>
<div id="attachment_28990" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 740px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/adelaide-river-torrens-adelaide-uni/" rel="attachment wp-att-28990"><img class="size-full wp-image-28990" alt="Things to Do in Adelaide" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Adelaide-River-Torrens-Adelaide-Uni.jpg" width="730" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Take a walk along the River Torrens or find a quiet spot for a picnic</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">I love Adelaide because ________?</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Adelaide has the beaches people travel to Sydney for, the arts &amp; culture of Melbourne, plenty of great food, but the laid back attitude of a small city/country town, which makes Adelaide a brilliant blend of everything I want in a city.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>BIO</strong></p>
<p>Nicole Smith is an Adelaide born girl behind travel blog, <strong><a title="solo female travel, adventure, culture, and luxury - Bitten by the Travel Bug" href="http://www.bittenbythetravelbug.com" target="_blank">Bitten by the Travel Bug</a></strong> where she documents her solo journey around the world in search of adventure, culture and just a little bit of luxury. When she&#8217;s not writing on the blog you can find her on in 140-characters-or-less <strong><a title="NicoleTravelBug on Twitter" href="http://www.twitter.com/nicoletravelbug" target="_blank">Twitter</a></strong> or on <strong><a title="Bitten by the Travel Bug on Facebook" href="http://www.facebook.com/bittenbythetravelbug" target="_blank">Facebook</a>.</strong></p></blockquote>
<h3>What do you suggest for things to do in Adelaide?</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/">City Guide &#8211; Things to Do in Adelaide</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~4/mrahx7RtTKg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-adelaide/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Travel Podcast – Life As An Overland Tour Guide</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~3/-tji_Ho4LR4/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-podcast-life-as-an-overland-tour-guide/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Caz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Experiences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiring interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overland adventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel podcast]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ytravelblog.com/?p=28425</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>For our travel podcast interview series this week we are chatting with Natalie and David from Infinite Adventures. David and Natalie have found a way to create a lifestyle of travel based upon their passions and experience. They met as tour leaders on the overland trucks in Africa and used that experience to create their [...]</p><p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-podcast-life-as-an-overland-tour-guide/">Travel Podcast &#8211; Life As An Overland Tour Guide</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For our <strong>travel podcast</strong> interview series this week we are chatting with Natalie and David from Infinite Adventures.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.infiniteadv.com"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28735" alt="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Infinite-Adventures.jpg" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Infinite-Adventures.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>David and Natalie have found a way to create a lifestyle of travel based upon their passions and experience.</p>
<p>They met as tour leaders on the overland trucks in Africa and used that experience to create their own overland adventure company in North America using a very unique vehicle, a <strong>converted school bus.</strong></p>
<p>I love hearing stories like these two. It really shows just how infinite the opportunities are to create that travel lifestyle you have always dreamed about.</p>
<p>Listen to the podcast to hear:</p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>How you can fund your travels through working</li>
<li>The best way to start travelling</li>
<li>How you can create your own passionate travel lifestyle</li>
<li>Why small group guided tours can be the adventure you always wanted</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Click play now</p>

<h3>Now it&#8217;s your turn to share:</h3>
<p>tell us in the comments below.</p>
<p>1. What inspired you the most about hearing David and Natalie&#8217;s story<br />
2. Did it spark any ideas for you as to how you can create your travel lifestyle?</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-podcast-life-as-an-overland-tour-guide/">Travel Podcast &#8211; Life As An Overland Tour Guide</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~4/-tji_Ho4LR4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-podcast-life-as-an-overland-tour-guide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://media.blubrry.com/ytravelblogpodcast/media.blubrry.com/mojitomotherpodcast/content.blubrry.com/mojitomotherpodcast/infiniteadventures.mp3" length="22544384" type="audio/mpeg" />
			<itunes:keywords>inspiring interviews,overland adventures,travel podcast</itunes:keywords>
	<itunes:subtitle>For our travel podcast interview series this week we are chatting with Natalie and David from Infinite Adventures. - David and Natalie have found a way to create a lifestyle of travel based upon their passions and experience. - </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>For our travel podcast interview series this week we are chatting with Natalie and David from Infinite Adventures.



David and Natalie have found a way to create a lifestyle of travel based upon their passions and experience.

They met as tour leaders on the overland trucks in Africa and used that experience to create their own overland adventure company in North America using a very unique vehicle, a converted school bus.

I love hearing stories like these two. It really shows just how infinite the opportunities are to create that travel lifestyle you have always dreamed about.

Listen to the podcast to hear:


	How you can fund your travels through working
	The best way to start travelling
	How you can create your own passionate travel lifestyle
	Why small group guided tours can be the adventure you always wanted


Click play now


Now it's your turn to share:
tell us in the comments below.

1. What inspired you the most about hearing David and Natalie's story
2. Did it spark any ideas for you as to how you can create your travel lifestyle?</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Caz</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>23:29</itunes:duration>
		<rawvoice:embed>&lt;iframe width="320" height="24" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/?powerpress_embed=28425-podcast&amp;amp;powerpress_player=default" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</rawvoice:embed>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-podcast-life-as-an-overland-tour-guide/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Road Trips – The Ultimate Planning Guide</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~3/wDLKBK2Vw_E/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 10:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Craig</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[road trips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ytravelblog.com/?p=28701</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>If you are new to our site, you will soon realise we are big fans of taking road trips. As a travelling family we can&#8217;t rate them highly enough as a memorable travel experience. They are just so practical and cost effective. We have taken many road trips over the years in locations such as [...]</p><p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/">Road Trips &#8211; The Ultimate Planning Guide</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/sugarloaf-lighthouse-seal-rocks2-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28860"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28860" alt="Road Trips" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Sugarloaf-lighthouse-seal-rocks21.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>If you are new to our site, you will soon realise we are big fans of taking <strong>road trips</strong>.</p>
<p>As a <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/25-tips-for-travel-with-kids/" target="_blank"><strong>travelling family</strong></a><strong> </strong>we can&#8217;t rate them highly enough as a memorable travel experience. They are just so practical and cost effective.</p>
<p>We have taken many road trips over the years in locations such as Europe, South Africa, Northern Thailand, California, <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/east-coast-road-tripping-highlights-usa/" target="_blank"><strong>east coast USA</strong></a> and <strong><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/sydney-to-brisbane-road-trip/" target="_blank">up and down the Australian coastline.</a></strong></p>
<p>We love the freedom of hitting the open road, being able to SLOW travel and have the flexibility to do what we want, when we want.</p>
<p>You can set your own travel hours and destinations, you don&#8217;t have to carry around your luggage by hand, and instead of flying from point A to point B and missing everything in between</p>
<blockquote><p>the journey becomes just as memorable as the destination.</p></blockquote>
<p>Ready to get planning that road trip of yours?</p>
<h2>Planning Road Trips &#8211; Questions to Ask</h2>
<p>Here are the initial questions to ask yourself:</p>
<ul>
<li>What sort of experience are you looking for?</li>
<li>Who is going?</li>
<li>What type of car are you driving?</li>
<li>Are you wanting a warm climate or a wintry destination for a change?</li>
<li>When are you available to go and for how long?</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/seal-rocks-3-013/" rel="attachment wp-att-28861"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28861" alt="Road Trips" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Seal-Rocks-3-013.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></a>Are you after a beach break? Seal Rocks, NSW, Australia</p>
<h2>Budget Planning</h2>
<p>Figuring out how much money you have to spend on your road trip is vital in determining where you are going to go and for how long?</p>
<p>Think about what your total budget might be, and then break it down into the major segments of the trip. How much are you willing and able to spend on these necessities:</p>
<ul>
<li>Accommodation</li>
<li>Fuel</li>
<li>Food</li>
<li>Activities</li>
<li>Shopping / Entertainment</li>
<li>Travel Insurance</li>
</ul>
<p>Once you know what you are comfortable spending on a daily basis, divide that dollar amount into your total budget available and that will give you a rough idea of the amount of days you can travel for.</p>
<p>Research the costs for the following:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Accommodation &#8211; </strong>We like to start by using sites such as: <a href="http://hotels.com.au/" target="_blank"><strong>Hotels.com</strong></a>, <a href="http://www.expedia.com.au/" target="_blank"><strong>Expedia</strong></a>, <a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/click?id=FOzBzQoz428&amp;offerid=120349.10000002&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0" target="_blank"><strong>Hotwire</strong></a>, <a href="http://hostelzoo.com" target="_blank"><strong>Hostel Zoo</strong></a> (hostels), <a href="http://www.stayz.com.au/" target="_blank"><strong>Stayz </strong></a>(apartments) and <a href="http://www.lastminute.com.au/" target="_blank"><strong>Last Minute</strong></a><strong>. </strong>For more tips on how to find cheap accommodation <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/how-to-find-budget-accommodation/" target="_blank"><strong>click here.</strong></a></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Fuel</strong> &#8211; You will need to work out mileage getting there and back and also factor in driving when at your travel destination. <a href="http://www.roadmapaustralia.com.au/index.php" target="_blank"><strong>Road Map Australia</strong></a> estimates fuel costs for various distances.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Food &#8211; </strong>Will you be cooking in an apartment or campsite? Will you be eating out? You will need to factor in costs for every meal including snacks. If you are cooking at home think in terms of your usual shopping budget, if eating out factor in $10-$20 per person per meal. $5-$10 for kids.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Activities &#8211; </strong>Decide what you want to do and what the cost will be for each activity at your chosen destination. Try to fit in as many free things as you can. Cater to all interests.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Equipment</strong> &#8211; Consider any extra costs you may have in providing equipment for your trip. You may have to buy camping equipment, clothes etc. Factor in the cost of a vehicle service and possible maintenance.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now you have your rough costs you are in a better position on deciding where to go and for how long.</p>
<p><strong>You can then answer these questions:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>How much money will you need for your desired destination?</li>
<li>How much do you have in savings now?</li>
<li>How much do you need to put away each week?</li>
<li>Where is that money going to come from?</li>
</ul>
<h2>Choosing the Right Destination</h2>
<p>Depending on your budget and the type of experiences you want to have, consider this:</p>
<ul>
<li>Make a list of places you want to go and why?</li>
<li>What type of holiday will it provide?</li>
<li>What activities can you do?</li>
<li>Types of accommodation options?</li>
</ul>
<p>Go through the list with whoever you are road tripping with, discuss pros and cons of each destination and vote.</p>
<p>Number them in preference. (Don’t completely cancel a destination out because you may have to change when you consider factors such as budget and availability).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/coffs-harbour-127/" rel="attachment wp-att-28862"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28862" alt="Road trips" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Coffs-Harbour-127.jpg" width="730" height="530" /></a>How about a trip to the mountains? Dorrigo National Park, Australia</p>
<h2>Preparing Your Car</h2>
<p>Safety, like insurance, is probably one of the most boring travel topics. But, it is truly the most important.</p>
<p>Unless our car is brand new, we always make sure we have put it in for a service before we go on a road trip. It’s a hassle and may cost money, but it is better to pay for the prevention rather than the cure.</p>
<p>Here are some <strong><em>pre-road trip safety tips</em></strong> if you want to perform them yourself:</p>
<ul>
<li>Check brake pads, break lights, headlights and blinkers.</li>
<li>Check car tires (check the tread and pressure to be safe and improve gas mileage).</li>
<li>Check your windscreen wiper blades.</li>
<li>Top up the water level.</li>
<li>Check your engine coolant level and top up.</li>
<li>Fill the windscreen washer fluid.</li>
<li>Check your oil level and change if needed.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Get some sort of <strong>roadside assistance</strong> (in Australia we have NRMA). I cannot tell you how many times we have used them in the past. It&#8217;s good peace of mind.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Check that your insurance and registration is up to date, as well as your drivers license.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Emergency Kit</h3>
<p>Always good to have in the car for peace of mind:</p>
<ul>
<li>A spare tire and tools to change it with</li>
<li>A torch</li>
<li>Warm blankets</li>
<li>Water</li>
<li>A fully charged phone</li>
<li>Hazard triangle</li>
</ul>
<p>Bucket List Destination: Great Ocean Road, Victoria, Australia        creidt:</p>
<h2>Pre-Departure Tips</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s a good idea to have your basic route planned on maps / navigation system. It&#8217;s fun for everyone to follow along and have a general understanding of the places you&#8217;ll be visiting.</p>
<p>Helpful tips:</p>
<ul>
<li>Plan for your stops along the way and organize any accommodation</li>
<li>Book your accommodation.</li>
<li>Have your vehicle serviced and check for safety.</li>
<li>Buy all needed equipment</li>
<li>Create road trip rules to ensure everyone gets along</li>
<li>Have your toll road e-tickets / coins ready</li>
<li>Have a last minute checklist of things that need to be done the day before or day of departure (this has saved me many times from forgetting important things)</li>
<li>Double check your maps or navigation system is ready to go.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Preparing Your Home</h2>
<p>There are obvious and not so obvious things to take care of before leaving your home.</p>
<ul>
<li>Schedule payment of all your bills</li>
<li>Stop your mail or have a trusted source collect it for you.</li>
<li>Clean out your fridge and cupboard of anything that may go off.</li>
<li>Arrange for the care of any pets.</li>
<li>Put your phone on soft ring so it can’t be heard ringing out.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Leave a set of keys with someone trusted. You just never know what might happen while you are gone and who might need to access your house to help you.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Let your bank know that you will be on a road trip and for how long. This may help prevent them from shutting down your credit card if they see charges coming through from different places.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/1d5993f73dd87e178e7261e53c66a74f-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28873"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28873" alt="Road Trips" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/1d5993f73dd87e178e7261e53c66a74f1.jpg" width="550" height="836" /></a>Bucket List Destination: Redwood National Park, California                      credit: <a href="http://fineartamerica.com/featured/avenue-of-the-giants-benjamin-yeager.html" target="_blank">fineartAmerica</a></p>
<h2>Packing Tips</h2>
<p>Try not to stress too much in regards to packing. Remember, you can almost certainly buy anything later on the road.</p>
<p>Once packed go through it again and cut it down by a third. Keep doing that until you really do have just the essentials. Take less and wash more.</p>
<p><strong>Other Tips:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong></strong>Know the weather of the destination you are visiting as this will help reduce over-packing. Planning your travel through one season or climate always works best.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Know the activities you will be doing so you can pack appropriately. You don’t want to turn up to your abseiling adventure without your sneakers.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Know the types of accommodation you will be staying at. If you are camping you are going to need to pack a lot more equipment. If you are staying in hotels you won’t need to take things like towels, hair dryers or linen.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Pack so that the items you may need are easily accessible while on the road.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pack Children’s Entertainment</h3>
<ul>
<li>Favourite toys</li>
<li>Favourite teddy for sleeping</li>
<li>Games</li>
<li>Colouring books / pencils / markers</li>
<li>Reading books</li>
<li>iPods / iPads / other elctronics</li>
</ul>
<h3>Parental Entertainment</h3>
<ul>
<li>Movies</li>
<li>Music</li>
<li>DVD player/iPad/iPod/laptop</li>
<li>Headphones</li>
<li>Spare batteries</li>
<li>Camera</li>
<li>Chargers for all electronics</li>
</ul>
<h3>Food and Drink Supplies</h3>
<ul>
<li>Have separate containers for cold food, dry food</li>
<li>Water bottles</li>
<li>Non-gooey, non-sticky snacks</li>
<li>Trail mix, fruit, crackers, sandwiches in zip lock bags</li>
<li>Spare containers / zip lock bags for leftover food</li>
</ul>
<h3>Smart Clothing Choices</h3>
<ul>
<li>Slip on / off shoes</li>
<li>Spare change of clothes handy for the car especially for kiddies</li>
<li>Comfortable, loose-fitting clothes to wear</li>
<li>swim wear</li>
<li>Rain gear</li>
</ul>
<h3>Baby Supplies at the Ready</h3>
<ul>
<li>Nappy bag full of nappies (diapers), formula, prepared bottles, food.</li>
<li>Baby wipes</li>
<li>Blankets</li>
<li>Toys</li>
<li>Plenty of dummies (pacifire) close at hand (they’ll throw them).</li>
</ul>
<h3>Incidentals</h3>
<ul>
<li>Paper towels</li>
<li>Hand sanitizer</li>
<li>Garbage bags</li>
<li>Vomit bag</li>
<li>Spare toilet paper</li>
</ul>
<h3>First Aid Kit</h3>
<p>A list of items to consider:</p>
<ul>
<li>adhesive dressings</li>
<li>sterile gauze bandages</li>
<li>tape</li>
<li>topical antiseptic</li>
<li>wound cleanser</li>
<li>a thermometer</li>
<li>eye drops</li>
<li>insect repellent</li>
<li>insect bite treatment</li>
<li>scissors</li>
<li>tweezers</li>
<li>safety pins</li>
<li>basic painkillers</li>
<li>sunscreen</li>
<li>antibiotics</li>
<li>disinfectant</li>
<li>calamine lotion</li>
<li>antihistamine tablets</li>
<li>band aids</li>
<li>cotton swabs</li>
<li>latex gloves</li>
<li>Any other personal medications</li>
<li>rehydration solutions</li>
<li>sunscreen</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are travelling overseas you may also want to include:</p>
<ul>
<li>syringes</li>
<li>water purification tablet</li>
<li>doctor’s letter / certificate for personal medication</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/seal-rocks-537-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-28863"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28863" alt="Road Trips" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Seal-Rocks-5371.jpg" width="600" height="600" /></a>Remember &#8211; Pack light.</p>
<h2>How to Cut Costs on the Road</h2>
<h3>Improve the Efficiency of Your Car</h3>
<p>An easy way to save costs of fuel on your road trip is to ensure your car is fully serviced and is optimised for efficiency.</p>
<ul>
<li>Check the pressure of your car tires</li>
<li>Drive slower</li>
<li>Use the right oil to increase mile usage</li>
<li>Watch your luggage – the heavier the car the more fuel you’ll use</li>
<li>Pack inside your car not on top</li>
<li>Use Google maps / in-car GPS to stay out of traffic jams</li>
</ul>
<h3>Use Coupons</h3>
<p>Do your research to find travel discounts and coupons for the areas you are visiting. <strong>Visit the local tourist information offices</strong> for free maps and ideas.</p>
<p>Use the following to help:</p>
<ul>
<li>Tourist booklets and brochures.</li>
<li>Back of supermarket receipts.</li>
<li>Websites (local tourist boards and businesses and coupon sites).</li>
<li>Member sites such as <a href="http://www.mynrma.com.au/travel.htm" target="_blank"><strong>NRMA</strong> </a>or <a href="http://www.racv.com.au/wps/wcm/connect/Internet/primary/travel" target="_blank"><strong>RACV</strong></a> in Australia and <a href="http://carolinas.aaa.com/AAA-Travel/Pages/Travel.aspx" target="_blank"><strong>AAA</strong></a> in the States.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Spend More Time in Fewer Places</h3>
<p>Don’t try to go too crazy and see everything. That’s a sure recipe for burnout and budget blowout.</p>
<p>Choose to spend more time in fewer places so you can save on fuel and snatch more accommodation bargains, like stay 5 nights get one free.</p>
<h3>Look for Accommodation Deals</h3>
<p>Accommodation is one of your biggest holiday expenses. Be wise about where you choose to stay – essentially it is only a bed to sleep in as you will be so busy exploring.</p>
<ul>
<li>Consider apartments, home rentals and hostel stays.</li>
<li>Camping will always be your cheapest option.</li>
<li>Staying longer in one place usually means cheaper price.</li>
<li>Search for accommodation deals that offer perks like free nights, free breakfast, free wireless or even tours.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Supply and Cook Your Own Food</h3>
<p>Constantly eating out can kill your budget and leave less for you to spend on the real memory making activities.</p>
<p>The best way to do this is:</p>
<ul>
<li>Take a packed / picnic lunch out with you for the day</li>
<li>Have pre-filled bottles of water from the tap</li>
<li>Buy all your snacks at the supermarket.</li>
<li>Camp and cook over the campfire (Try these <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/campfire-cooking-recipes-tips-cooking-open-fire/" target="_blank">campfire cooking recipes</a>)</li>
<li>Rent apartments and suites with kitchenettes.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Do the FREE Stuff &#8211; Make Nature Your Friend</h3>
<p>Do as many activities as you can outdoors, most of which will be free or cheap and will give you happy, carefree memories.</p>
<ul>
<li>Pack your own equipment to use like tennis rackets, snorkels, surf boards, beach games, bikes</li>
<li>Enjoy coastal path walks</li>
<li>Go bushwalking and hiking in national parks</li>
<li>Spend the day at beaches</li>
<li>Do self-guided city walks and tours</li>
<li>Relax around your campsite</li>
<li>Get a national parks pass</li>
<li>Attend museums or tourist sites on free days or when they are discounted.</li>
<li>Walk as much as you can. Stay in accommodation that allows for this to save on driving.</li>
<li>DIY hikes</li>
<li>Explore local markets</li>
<li>Walking around town taking photos</li>
<li>Bike riding</li>
<li>Climb a local mountain with views of a city or coastline</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/coffs-harbour-115/" rel="attachment wp-att-28859"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28859" alt="Road Trips" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Coffs-Harbour-115.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a>Visit a National Park</p>
<h2>Hitting the Road</h2>
<p>Now that all the planning is out of the way, all that is left for you to do is pack the car and drive away.</p>
<p>Put your hands in the air and give a celebratory cheer. The hard yards are over and you can relax and enjoy your road trip.</p>
<p><strong>Some last minute tips:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Get a good night’s sleep the evening before departure.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Fill the car up with gas and your purse with cash. You don’t want to get caught in the middle of nowhere with neither.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>All electronics are charged and spare batteries packed</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Share the driving with some one</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Take frequent breaks. Get out and stretch the legs, grab some lunch, and have a coffee every two hours. Remember this slogan&#8230;<strong><em>Stop &#8211; Revive &#8211; Survive.</em></strong></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Stick to the road rules and don’t drink and drive ever.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>If it is wet or low light put your headlights on.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>If you are driving in rural areas be very careful of wildlifre. Drive slowly if you see any around, honk your horn and flash your lights.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Don’t let your fuel level get down into the red zone, always keep it topped up.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Let the navigator (your co-pilot) take control of directions, DJ’ing and any phone stuff!</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/port-macquarie-207/" rel="attachment wp-att-28864"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28864" alt="Road trips" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Port-Macquarie-207.jpg" width="800" height="480" /></a>Take frequent breaks &#8211; Port Macquarie, Australia</p>
<figure></figure>
<h2>The Ultimate Checklist</h2>
<p>Has all this information overwhelmed you?</p>
<p>Here is a road trip packing list that will make sure you include everything you need:</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.kidspot.com.au/villagevoices/a-family-road-trip-packing-list/road-trip-packinglist_476x580_a-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-17194"><img title="Village Voices: road trip packing checklist" alt="road trip packing checklist" src="http://cdn.blogs.kidspot.com.au/villagevoices/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/road-trip-packinglist_476x580_a.jpg" width="476" height="580" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://d33y93cfm0wb4z.cloudfront.net/Lana/Village_Voices/road-trip-packinglist.jpg" target="_blank"><strong>Click here to print</strong></a></p>
<h2>Don’t Forget</h2>
<p>Good conversation<br />
Patience<br />
Laughter<br />
Adventurous spirit</p>
<h2>You Tell Us</h2>
<h3>What is your best tip for successful road trips?</h3>
<h3>Where is your favourite road trip destination?</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/">Road Trips &#8211; The Ultimate Planning Guide</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~4/wDLKBK2Vw_E" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.ytravelblog.com/road-trips-planning-guide/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>If You Get Irritated by Children on Your Travels</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~3/8h4i-59_c6c/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ytravelblog.com/if-you-get-irritated-by-children-on-your-travels/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 01:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Caz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Experiences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experiences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ytravelblog.com/?p=27409</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>To those who get irritated by children on your travels. I get irritated by you more. Well not all, just the ones who are vocalize their annoyance at children in a rude and condescending way. (N.B: I&#8217;m talking about children who are probably under 6, because after that age they should no how to behave [...]</p><p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/if-you-get-irritated-by-children-on-your-travels/">If You Get Irritated by Children on Your Travels</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To those who get irritated by children on your travels.</p>
<p>I get irritated by you more.</p>
<p>Well not all, just the ones who are vocalize their annoyance at children in a rude and condescending way. (<strong>N.B</strong>: I&#8217;m talking about children who are probably under 6, because after that age they should no how to behave and fair enough you can get irritated by them if they are menaces.)</p>
<p>I often see and hear comments like:</p>
<blockquote><p>Children on planes should be banned. They shouldn’t be allowed in restaurants. They are all ruining our peace and quiet. Stay at home with them or give them to your parents to mind when you travel.</p></blockquote>
<p>I get it. I really really do.</p>
<p>My children have completely destroyed my peace and quiet since the day they were born.</p>
<p>I know how tough it is.</p>
<p>But it doesn’t stop me from wanting to tear your eyes out when I hear your comments. I sympathize, but at the same time I think how could you?</p>
<p>How could you be so mean? They are children.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/if-you-get-irritated-by-children-on-your-travels/craig-thailand-023/" rel="attachment wp-att-28795"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28795" alt="Craig Thailand 023" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Craig-Thailand-023.jpg" width="600" height="800" /></a><strong>Look out &#8211; here they come!</strong></p>
<p>You know there was a time in my life when I wasn’t a mother &#8211; feels like another life ago, even though it was only five years.</p>
<p>In my former life as a non-parent I’d experienced at least a hundred flights and ten solid years of international travel, and I don’t ever remember being that disturbed by children.</p>
<p>That is not to say they weren’t crying and screaming and being gigantic pains in the arse, like they can be, it’s just I chose never to hold it against them.</p>
<p>And now that I am a mother, I am so protective of ALL children.</p>
<p>One of your biggest worries as a parent is how your children will <em><strong>go nuts</strong></em> in public and disturb the peace of others.</p>
<blockquote><p>They can’t help it. They can’t control themselves. They are babies.</p></blockquote>
<p>The panic sets in your heart and makes anxiety an unwelcome friend. Do I keep them at home and stop living just so they don’t cry and disturb those around me?</p>
<p>I’ve been lucky with my children; they choose to go rank more in private spaces than public ones, so I know when people complain it is usually not about my child, but I sure as hell take it personally.</p>
<p>Because when you become a mother, that all-encompassing love extends to all babies. Suddenly you become a mother to everyone.</p>
<p>A child walks past and you cup their chin in your hands, and stare into their eyes with honour as you speak.</p>
<blockquote><p>Look at you precious. I will protect you little angel.</p></blockquote>
<p>Because that is what they are. They are pure and innocent and precious. And yes they cry because they don’t know any other way to communicate.</p>
<p>If I was exploring the world for the first time, I’d cry at many of the adults that I came into contact with too.</p>
<p>So when people speak about little children like vermin who inconvenience their lives I feel anger like never before rise from within me.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>How dare you? Do you not understand you are in the presence of angels?</em></p></blockquote>
<p>When my Kalyra was born I was suddenly transported into this world where I knew nothing and she knew everything. She was my teacher and spirit guide. I have honoured children as such ever since.</p>
<p>Raising children is so bloody hard; they wear me down and break my spirit, but that honour  and love I have for them defies all tiredness.</p>
<p>For those who choose to complain about your few hours of disturbed peace, I ask you not to look upon the children with scorn. They are babies. You are only viewing them from the point of view as to how they affect your life.</p>
<p>They’re so much more than that.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/if-you-get-irritated-by-children-on-your-travels/craig-thailand-035/" rel="attachment wp-att-28796"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28796" alt="Craig Thailand 035" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Craig-Thailand-035.jpg" width="600" height="800" /></a><strong>Behaving themselves &#8211; for now!</strong></p>
<p>Craig and I were terrified Savannah was going to scream the whole way home on our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/the-good-and-bad-of-air-asia-x/" target="_blank"><strong>flight from Bangkok to Sydney</strong></a> like she had the previous two nights. We almost cancelled our flight we were so worried.</p>
<p>Most of the angst parents go through is worrying how our baby’s hurts affects others.</p>
<p>That screaming baby you hear is often not screaming because her parents couldn’t be bothered to control her; it is most likely because her parent doesn’t know what else to do.</p>
<p>They have become numb.</p>
<p><strong>I call it the <i>shutting down to protect.</i></strong></p>
<p>You’ve tried everything, yet still they cry. They cry for hours. You don’t know what else to do. They can’t speak; they can’t tell you where it hurts or how to help. You guess for hours and you feel such a failure.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Look how upset my child is and I don’t know what to do.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>You cry silently. You cry from fatigue, from angst, from confusion and utter pain that you, the mother, can’t help your baby.</p>
<p>And then you go numb. It’s a coping mechanism.</p>
<p>As for parents who just sit there and watch their kids run wild and behave unacceptably whilst disturbing the peace, that&#8217;s a different story. At least make an effort to control your children and show courtesy to others. (This post is not really written with these cases in mind, you can get as angry as you like with the adults here- fair play!)</p>
<p>If another child aggressively pushes in front of my girls in the <strong>line up at the playground</strong>, and the parent just watches and says nothing, my blood pressure rises! But I don&#8217;t abuse the child and look at them like dirt beneath my feet.</p>
<p>(You can hear my thoughts on raising respectful and well-mannered children <a href="http://www.mojitomother.com/2013/03/four-simple-playground-rules/" target="_blank"><strong>here</strong></a> and <a href="http://blogs.kidspot.com.au/villagevoices/teaching-our-children-respect-and-manners/" target="_blank"><strong>here</strong></a>)</p>
<p>I believe most parents are doing their best and are considerate of others.</p>
<p>I think back to a flight 4 years ago when we were living in the states. We had an early morning flight with Delta departing Raleigh, North Carolina. Kalyra was about 12 months old then, the plane was packed, it was still dark outside, and it was silent.</p>
<p>Then it happened &#8211; Kalyra just started screaming and crying as the plane started to taxi away from the gate. She didn&#8217;t want to wear the child seat belt and sit on mummy&#8217;s lap, she wanted her own seat. Craig and I did our best to calm her, but sometimes you are helpless. If we could have got up and removed her from the situation (which we do in restaurants), we would have.</p>
<p>I remember not wanting to lock eyes with the other passengers, and could feel their glare burning through us. Those moments are tough. Luckily she calmed down once the plane accelerated for take off and was good for most of the flight, except when landing as it hurts their ears.</p>
<p>You know how upset you get after five minutes of listening to a baby cry. Imagine a mother who has listened to it for 48 hours. Imagine if the mother could not go numb to protect.</p>
<blockquote><p>I know, it&#8217;s not your problem and it&#8217;s still bad for you and the vitriol spills out of your mouth as to why they should not be inflicting that upon others. I so get it. You can’t predict and often you can’t control, but it does not mean mother and child should stop living.</p></blockquote>
<p>When you have done all you can and you can’t help, you detach yourself from the screaming.</p>
<p>You can hear it, but it does not infiltrate your core, if it did it would send you crazy.</p>
<p>And no baby needs a mother who goes crazy.</p>
<p>Aren’t you glad you had a mother who did not go crazy with your endless cries? That is right, you did it once and you pissed off a lot of people. Maybe it&#8217;s just karma. I often think that with my two challenging children who hate sleep. I was exactly the same to my mother.</p>
<p>I cried for months on end. My mother calls me her difficult one, yet the love she has for her baby never leaves her eyes.</p>
<p>That is a powerful love. It says,</p>
<blockquote><p>“<em>Cry and scream for days on end, make me feel like I am going insane and will literally pull my hair out as it feels more enjoyable, but I will still love you; I’d still walk over hot coals for you.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>So when there is nothing else you can do you go numb and you hold your baby, because you know that is all they need. Whatever their unsolvable struggle may be, they know if you hold them, they will feel safe and loved. They will get over the screams and the pain with little damage if they are held.</p>
<p>I remember a childless friend speaking of dinner dates with their friends.</p>
<blockquote><p>“With the first child, they were worried about every noise. They were up dealing with it but now, with the second, the two brothers could be wrestling in the corner and they don’t notice.”</p></blockquote>
<p>It’s the numbing.</p>
<p>I was numbing as we sat in Starbucks waiting for our flight home from Bangkok.</p>
<p>We had two nights of Savannah screaming, we didn’t know what was wrong, but I’m sure it was her teeth. There was nothing else I could do.</p>
<p>All I wanted was coffee to help me.</p>
<p>I sat down and went numb.</p>
<p>I held her.</p>
<p>I couldn’t really hear her, but I was holding her with love.</p>
<p>The two English ladies behind me started scowling and moved place. They looked at me and their eyes spoke viper.</p>
<p>They made it plainly clear how much my crying child had inconvenienced them.</p>
<p>I get it, I really do, but you are being hateful towards a child.</p>
<p>And you are women.</p>
<p>And I am a mother who has just turned numb for five minutes.</p>
<p>I got up and moved outside.</p>
<p>They mumbled something to each other and pointed to me, the scowl permanently imprinting their face. (Hope the wind doesn’t change as your face will stay that way. Sorry your soul already spoke, it is that way.)</p>
<p>I exploded with the words <strong>“Bitches”</strong> to Craig upon return. <strong>Very harsh I know.</strong> I was not proud. I rarely speak about other people like this, but I hadn&#8217;t slept for two days and, as I said at the beginning of this, they failed to honour children at their sake of their own five minutes of peace.</p>
<h3>So what. Get over it.</h3>
<p>You’ll move on in five minutes to peace. So what. You had five minutes you had to listen to a baby cry, and it ruined your Starbucks moment. Hate to have a real problem to moan about. Put it into perspective.</p>
<p>You moan about the baby crying on the plane, in the restaurant, on the street and how it affects YOU. What about the baby? What about the mother who can never move to a quieter place?</p>
<p>Not your problem I know, which is in itself a major problem of Western society.</p>
<p>What I love so much about travelling in Asia is how much they honour children and how they embrace the concept of the <i>village raises the child.</i> We never received any angst from an Asian person about our children, nor did I notice it with any other. Even when my girls had a <strong><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/meltdown-in-the-most-important-temple-in-bangkok/" target="_blank">meltdown in the most important temple in Thailand</a></strong>, their spirits were still honoured and the concern was for them.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/grand-palace-bangkok/grand-palace-bangkok-20/" rel="attachment wp-att-26370"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-26370" alt="Grand palace Bangkok" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Grand-palace-Bangkok-20.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a><strong>Post meltdown at the Grand Palace, Bangkok</strong></p>
<p>On the flight home Savannah thankfully slept. Miraculously there were no screams or tears.</p>
<p>But every other child on the flight was crying.</p>
<blockquote><p>“Thank god it is not mine.” I thought</p></blockquote>
<p>I didn’t sleep much because of the cries, but I did not care. I felt for the parents and the distress of the baby. If Savannah wasn’t sleeping peacefully across my lap, I would have got up and asked the parents</p>
<p><i>How can I help? </i><em>Please let me give you a break.</em></p>
<p>Just like the Asians do. <strong>The village raises a child.</strong></p>
<p>I sent those babies a whole lot of love and hugs and then shut down so the screams couldn’t infiltrate me and send me crazy.</p>
<p>That is all you need to do.</p>
<p>And in the process of shutting down, remember that you were once a baby too.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/if-you-get-irritated-by-children-on-your-travels/">If You Get Irritated by Children on Your Travels</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~4/8h4i-59_c6c" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ytravelblog.com/if-you-get-irritated-by-children-on-your-travels/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.ytravelblog.com/if-you-get-irritated-by-children-on-your-travels/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Places to Eat Thai Street Food in Bangkok</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~3/W47rITzX_lo/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Caz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bangkok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Destinations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ytravelblog.com/?p=26741</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Eating Thai street food is one of our favourite things to do in Bangkok. It’s hard not to find a street corner with a row of carts lined up dishing up meals like noodle soup, BBQ pork, fish cakes and delicious curries. Is your mouth watering as much as mine? The good news is that [...]</p><p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/">5 Places to Eat Thai Street Food in Bangkok</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/bangkok-044/" rel="attachment wp-att-28770"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28770" alt="Thai Street Food" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Bangkok-044.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
<p>Eating Thai street food is one of our favourite <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-bangkok/" target="_blank"><strong>things to do in Bangkok</strong></a>.</p>
<p>It’s hard not to find a street corner with a row of carts lined up dishing up meals like noodle soup, BBQ pork, fish cakes and delicious curries.</p>
<p>Is your mouth watering as much as mine?</p>
<p>The good news is that <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/the-real-reason-you-should-eat-street-food/" target="_blank"><strong>eating street food</strong></a> has many benefits to you as a traveller  &#8211; it&#8217;s generally safe (you can see what&#8217;s being cooked and it&#8217;s fresh), you get to interact with the locals, It’s authentic, delicious and the best way to give back to the local economy.</p>
<p>Eating <strong>Thai street food</strong> in Bangkok is incredibly cheap, as is the street food in all of Thailand. A bag of fish cakes will set you back 20 baht (less than a $1) and a noodle soup around 60 baht ($2).</p>
<h2>How do you know where to eat street food in Bangkok?</h2>
<p>Craig and I really believe the best place to eat street food is the street you are on. Go to the areas that are thriving with locals—always a sign that the food rocks.</p>
<p>Just know a few of your fave dishes in Thai, so you can order the right thing. Have it written down in Thai language if you can. If all else fails use your eyes to choose and then point and smile.</p>
<p>I know most of you are eager to really eat at the BEST places for street food in Bangkok. There has to be a list somewhere right?</p>
<p>Well according to our guide Tim, from Absolutely Fantastic Holidays, there is. Tim is a Bangkok local and shared with us what is widely considered throughout the Bangkok community to be the</p>
<h2>5 Places to Eat Street Food in Bangkok</h2>
<h3>1. Chinatown</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>OMG, if you love authentic street food you will love visiting <a href="www.ytravelblog.com/chinatown-bangkok-thailand" target="_blank"><strong>Chinatown in Bangkok</strong></a>. There are hundreds of street stalls, markets, carts and restaurants. Night time is when <strong>Yaowarat</strong>, as Chinatown is also known as, will rock your taste buds.</p>
<p>We can really understand why this comes in at Number 1. According to Jim Thompson, who took us on a <a title="Chinatown Bangkok – A Bangkok dragon walking tour" href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/chinatown-bangkok-thailand/" target="_blank"><strong>walking tour of Yaowarat</strong></a> last year, Chinatown is the place where street food first began in Thailand over 200 years ago when Bangkok was the major trading hub of South East Asia.</p>
<div id="attachment_28723" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/thai-street-food-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28723"><img class="size-full wp-image-28723" alt="Thai Street Food" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Thai-Street-Food.jpg" width="600" height="863" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dumplings</p></div>
<p>Just look for the ad hoc stalls, the plastic tables and chairs, feast out on delicious food and wash it all down with a Singa beer.</p>
<p>We lived a short walk from the outskirts of Chinatown and loved wandering down for our evening meal of Thai noodles with gravy. At 20 baht how can you say no?</p>
<div id="attachment_28724" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 720px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/thai-street-food-2-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28724"><img class="size-full wp-image-28724" alt="Thai Street Food" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Thai-Street-Food-2.jpg" width="710" height="473" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">oyster omellete &#8211; Chinatown special</p></div>
<h3>2. Silom Road</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This is the only area on the list we have not experienced recently, although we did venture to this area of Bangkok whilst living in the city in 2002.</p>
<p>Being the central business district of Bangkok there are a lot of people, hungry people wanting a quick meal in between office hours. That means you&#8217;ll find a lot of street food options.</p>
<p>Soi Convent and Soi 20 is where you probably most want to go to gorge on cheap Thai food.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/thai-street-food-1-of-1-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28774"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28774" alt="Thai Street Food" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Thai-street-food-1-of-11.jpg" width="4752" height="3168" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/5699261474_fd12aa213d_b/" rel="attachment wp-att-28759"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28759" alt="Thai Street Food" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/5699261474_fd12aa213d_b.jpg" width="800" height="578" /></a>credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/monojussi/5699261474/" target="_blank">monojussi</a></p>
<h3>3. Soi Rambuttri</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This is one of our favourite streets in Bangkok. It is one of the few places you can escape the madness of Bangkok. When we lived in Bangkok this street was known as Dog Shit Alley, because of the number of dogs that paraded up and down the rat infested street. We loved eating and drinking here. It was cool before it was the hipster-cool it is now. It has had a major uplift and is now a pretty Bangkok oasis.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/3386087013_49a5487316_b/" rel="attachment wp-att-28769"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28769" alt="Thai Street Food" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/3386087013_49a5487316_b.jpg" width="600" height="905" /></a>credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/robertdinwiddie/3386087013/" target="_blank">zealous</a></p>
<p>We were surprised Soi Rambuttri made the list as it seems such a small area, but Tim assures us the food there is known to be first class. It’s also really cheap.  We didn’t eat there this time, except for Kalyra who gorged herself on a cheap banana pancake with chocolate &#8211; one of our fave 2am treats after a night in the Alley.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/picmonkey-collage-70/" rel="attachment wp-att-28740"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28740" alt="Thai Street Food" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/PicMonkey-Collage5.jpg" width="800" height="800" /></a></p>
<h3>4. Banglamphu</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When we explained why we didn’t understand how Soi Rambutri and Banglamphu were both on the list &#8211; as Dog Shit Alley is in Banglampoo &#8211; Tim explained that the street food is a little different.</p>
<p>Banglamphu is the area around the river, near the Golden Palace that comprises the backpacking travel area of Khao San Road and So Rambutrri.</p>
<p>If you want the really great street food, then walk to the end of Khao San Road, turn right past the police station opposite the Wat and Soi Rambuttri and lining the streets will be many many street stalls and carts. Also the streets adjacent to Khao San.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/4351329903_c21992cc06_b/" rel="attachment wp-att-28765"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28765" alt="Thai Street Food" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/4351329903_c21992cc06_b.jpg" width="800" height="560" /></a>credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/franklinheijnen/4351329903/" target="_blank">amsfrank</a></p>
<p>We can absolutely affirm that this is a great place to eat street food in Bangkok. This was where we ate dinner most nights when we lived in Bangkok, we loved to feast on fish cakes and noodle soup.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/8481562077_0212119c54_b/" rel="attachment wp-att-28766"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28766" alt="Thai Street Food" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/8481562077_0212119c54_b.jpg" width="800" height="534" /></a>credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/franklinheijnen/8481562077/" target="_blank">amsfrank</a></p>
<h3>5. Soi 38 Sukumvhit</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We don’t feel we had the normal Soi 38 street food experience. We were excited to feast on this street as we had heard so much about it, but only felt disappointed upon arrival.</p>
<p>There were only a few carts lining the street, we envisioned much more, and the selection didn’t seem all that great. Mind you, we did have a very whiny 5 year old at the time so probably were not really focused. We ended up jumping in a small stall just to have some peace.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/3004461369_6e3e244bb5_b/" rel="attachment wp-att-28761"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28761" alt="Thai Street Food" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/3004461369_6e3e244bb5_b.jpg" width="600" height="900" /></a>credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/faithmonsoon/3004461369/" target="_blank">faithmonsoon</a></p>
<p>The Tom Yum Goong we ordered was one of the worst we have ever had. Maybe because we are so used to Bangkok street food, we weren’t that wowed by Soi 38. Many people are though, so I would go and see for yourself.</p>
<div id="attachment_28760" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 810px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/cooking-class-121/" rel="attachment wp-att-28760"><img class="size-full wp-image-28760" alt="Thai Street Food" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-121.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Tom Yum Goong</p></div>
<h2>Your Turn:</h2>
<h3>Where do you think is the best place to eat street food in Bangkok?</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/">5 Places to Eat Thai Street Food in Bangkok</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~4/W47rITzX_lo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-street-food/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Sunday Spotlight – What to Do in Dublin</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~3/JcB9UWQHzqk/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ytravelblog.com/what-to-do-in-dublin/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 01:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Craig</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Destinations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dublin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sunday Spotlight]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ytravelblog.com/?p=28646</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Every Sunday we are shining the spotlight on a different city by sharing travel tips and stories written by other blogs around the web. This weeks spotlight is &#8220;What to do in Dublin&#8221;. We hope these blog posts will inform and inspire you to go travel and take that trip to Dublin. What to Do [...]</p><p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/what-to-do-in-dublin/">Sunday Spotlight &#8211; What to Do in Dublin</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every Sunday we are shining the spotlight on a different city by sharing travel tips and stories written by other blogs around the web.</p>
<p>This weeks spotlight is &#8220;<strong>What to do in Dublin&#8221;.</strong></p>
<p>We hope these blog posts will inform and inspire you to go travel and take that trip to Dublin.</p>
<h2>What to Do in Dublin</h2>
<h3>Dublin on a Budget.</h3>
<p>Janice from Solo Traveler discovers that there is much more to Dublin than literature, politics and James Joyce. For starters there is discovering the best pub to have a pint of Guinness. She also shares great insider tips from her facebook community.</p>
<p>Read more here &#8211;&gt; <a href="http://solotravelerblog.com/dublin-on-a-budget-but-first/" target="_blank"><strong>Dublin on a Budget</strong></a></p>
<div id="attachment_28657" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 404px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/what-to-do-in-dublin/james-joyce/" rel="attachment wp-att-28657"><img class="size-full wp-image-28657" alt="What to Do in Dublin" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/James-Joyce.jpg" width="394" height="700" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">James Joyce                                   credit: <a href="http://solotravelerblog.com/dublin-on-a-budget-but-first/" target="_blank">solotraveler</a></p></div>
<h3>7 Great Things to Do in Dublin</h3>
<p>Ryan from Pause the Moment is constantly learning new things to see and do in Dublin, and in this post he shares seven of his favorite destinations if you don&#8217;t know where to start.</p>
<p>Read more here &#8211;&gt; <a href="http://www.pausethemoment.com/7-great-things-to-see-and-do-while-in-dublin/" target="_blank"><strong>7 Great Things to Do in Dublin</strong></a></p>
<div id="attachment_28660" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 580px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/what-to-do-in-dublin/img_1747-570x427/" rel="attachment wp-att-28660"><img class="size-full wp-image-28660" alt="What to Do in Dublin" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1747-570x427.jpg" width="570" height="427" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">River Liffey                        credit: <a href="http://www.pausethemoment.com/7-great-things-to-see-and-do-while-in-dublin/" target="_blank">PauseTheMoment</a></p></div>
<h3>A Backpacker&#8217;s Guide to Dublin</h3>
<p>Brendan from Brendan&#8217;s Adventures describes Dublin as having all the makings of a great travel destination that shouldn&#8217;t be missed. In this comprehensive guide he offers advice on where to eat, sleep and explore.</p>
<p>Read more here &#8211;&gt; <a href="http://www.brendansadventures.com/travel-guides/western-europe-travel-guides/a-backpackers-guide-to-dublin/" target="_blank"><strong> A Backpacker&#8217;s Guide to Dublin</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/what-to-do-in-dublin/dublin-12-xl/" rel="attachment wp-att-28663"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28663" alt="What to Do in Dublin" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Dublin-12-XL.jpg" width="1024" height="683" /></a>credit: <a href="http://www.brendansadventures.com/travel-guides/western-europe-travel-guides/a-backpackers-guide-to-dublin/" target="_blank">Brendan&#8217;s Adventres</a></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">A Walk in the Rain through Dublin Castle</h3>
<p>Raining in Dublin?? Never! Jeremy of Budget Travel Adventures was in Dublin on a typical gray and misty day, but that didn&#8217;t stop him from discovering the grounds of Dublin Castle and learning about some Irish history.</p>
<p>Read more here &#8211;&gt; <a href="http://www.budgettraveladventures.com/traveldestinations/europe/ireland/dublin-castle-walk-in-the-rain/" target="_blank"><strong>A Walk in the Rain through Dublin Castle</strong></a></p>
<div id="attachment_28666" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/what-to-do-in-dublin/dublin-castle-in-the-rain-m/" rel="attachment wp-att-28666"><img class="size-full wp-image-28666" alt="What to Do in Dublin" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Dublin-Castle-in-the-rain-M.jpg" width="600" height="398" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dublin Castle                   Credit: <a href="http://www.budgettraveladventures.com/traveldestinations/europe/ireland/dublin-castle-walk-in-the-rain/" target="_blank">BudgetTravelAdventures</a></p></div>
<h3>What NOT to Do in Dublin</h3>
<p>Eva from Matador Network talks about the Do&#8217;s and Don&#8217;ts when visiting Dublin and alternatives you can experience. For example, don&#8217;t expect to drink all night in the pubs, but do continue on at people&#8217;s homes.</p>
<p>Read more here &#8211;&gt; <a href="http://matadornetwork.com/trips/what-not-to-do-in-dublin/" target="_blank"><strong>What NOT to Do in Dublin</strong></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/what-to-do-in-dublin/20110404-dublin1/" rel="attachment wp-att-28668"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28668" alt="What to Do in Dublin" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/20110404-dublin1.jpg" width="600" height="400" /></a>credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/theperplexingparadox/" target="_blank">Natalie</a></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;">15 Things to Do for Free in Dublin</h3>
<p>Looking for free things to do in Dublin? Rebecca from Hostelworld created this useful list of attractions for you to check out in the city from entertainment to museums and more.</p>
<p>Read more here &#8211;&gt; <a href="http://www.hostelworld.com/travel-features/157/15-things-to-do-for-free-in-dublin" target="_blank"><strong>15 Things to Do for Free in Dublin</strong></a></p>
<h3>Rating Dublin&#8217;s Popular Tourist Attractions</h3>
<p>Anil Polat from FoXnoMad gives his impressions of some of Dublin&#8217;s top tourist attractions including the Guinness Storehouse, The Temple Bar, Trinity College and Kilmainham Gaol.</p>
<p>Read more here &#8211;&gt; <a href="http://foxnomad.com/2010/02/09/rating-dublin%E2%80%99s-popular-tourist-attractions/" target="_blank"><strong>Rating Dublin&#8217;s Popular Attractions</strong></a></p>
<div id="attachment_28674" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/what-to-do-in-dublin/temple-bar-dublin/" rel="attachment wp-att-28674"><img class="size-full wp-image-28674" alt="What to Do in Dublin" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/temple-bar-dublin.jpg" width="500" height="334" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Temple Bar                    credit: <a href="http://foxnomad.com/2010/02/09/rating-dublin%E2%80%99s-popular-tourist-attractions/" target="_blank">Foxnomad</a></p></div>
<h3>10 of the Best Dublin Pubs and Bars</h3>
<p>We spent a year living in Dublin in 2003, and one of our highlights was exploring all the amazing pubs in and around the city. In this post we share 10 of our favorite pubs to have a pint.</p>
<p>Read more here &#8211;&gt; <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/10-best-dublin-pubs-and-bars/" target="_blank"><strong>10 of the Best Dublin Pubs and Bars</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/what-to-do-in-dublin/scan0059-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28671"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28671" alt="What to Do in Dublin" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/scan0059.jpg" width="1186" height="800" /></a></p>
<h3>Dublin through a Once Locals Eye&#8217;s</h3>
<p>As mentioned, we lived in Dublin back in 2003 and in this post we share our insider tips on things to do not only in the city, but also interesting days trips. We share tips on how to eat Irish style, sporting moments to experience, and why to take literary pub crawl.</p>
<p>Read more here &#8211;&gt; <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-dublin-ireland/" target="_blank"><strong>Dublin through a Once Locals Eye&#8217;s</strong></a></p>
<h2>Your Turn</h2>
<p>If you have a blog post on Dublin share the link in the comments.</p>
<p>OR, if you have a travel tip for Dublin please share that too!</p>
<p><strong>P.S.</strong> Next weeks Sunday Spotlight will be on <strong>San Francisco</strong>&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/what-to-do-in-dublin/">Sunday Spotlight &#8211; What to Do in Dublin</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~4/JcB9UWQHzqk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ytravelblog.com/what-to-do-in-dublin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.ytravelblog.com/what-to-do-in-dublin/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Travel Pinspiration – 8 Photos of California</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~3/yo5CzXgiD8g/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 23:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Craig</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[California]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Destinations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Pinspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel pinspiration]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ytravelblog.com/?p=28602</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This weeks segment of Travel Pinspiration follows the theme of “California”. Our motto here on the blog and in life is: Travel More. Create better memories. And one of the best ways to inspire more travel is through photographs. #TravelPinspiration is when we share amazing photos discovered via our Pinterest Boards to hopefully give you [...]</p><p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/">Travel Pinspiration &#8211; 8 Photos of California</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This weeks segment of <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/tag/travel-pinspiration-2/" target="_blank"><strong>Travel Pinspiration</strong></a> follows the theme of<strong> “California”.</strong> <strong></strong></p>
<p>Our motto here on the blog and in life is: <em>Travel More. Create better memories. </em>And one of the best ways to inspire more travel is through photographs.</p>
<p><strong>#TravelPinspiration</strong> is when we share amazing photos discovered via our <a href="http://pinterest.com/ytravelblog/" target="_blank"><strong>Pinterest Boards</strong></a><strong> </strong>to hopefully give you the inspiration to go travel and visit these places.</p>
<blockquote><p>It happens every Saturday. And each week is a different theme!</p></blockquote>
<p>In this post we share 8<strong> beautiful photos of California. </strong>Check them out and then share your own thoughts in the comments section down the bottom.</p>
<h2>Huntington Beach</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/e840731d934ebd53415347e6572f5d7c-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28624"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28624" alt="Travel Pinspiration California" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/e840731d934ebd53415347e6572f5d7c1.jpg" width="550" height="732" /></a>Credit: <a href="http://www.jetsetter.com/trips/california/huntington-beach/429/shorebreak-hotel" target="_blank">jetsetter</a></p>
<h2>Golden Gate Bridge, San Francisco</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/3deedfebe41f6b761c6e86d5935fbbd4/" rel="attachment wp-att-28629"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28629" alt="Travel Pinspiration California" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/3deedfebe41f6b761c6e86d5935fbbd4.jpg" width="550" height="825" /></a>credit: <a href="http://500px.com/photo/3716133" target="_blank">500px</a></p>
<h2>Venice Beach</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/4cc2d9f5aa3e82bcdd4f90c58bb91159/" rel="attachment wp-att-28605"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28605" alt="Travel Pinspiration California" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/4cc2d9f5aa3e82bcdd4f90c58bb91159.jpg" width="550" height="732" /></a> Credit: <a href="http://www.pbase.com/rubinphoto/image/113803974" target="_blank">pbase.com</a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Napa Valley</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/6ea88a760bc683c17bd7d67d850de3e5/" rel="attachment wp-att-28611"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28611" alt="Travel Pinspiration California" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/6ea88a760bc683c17bd7d67d850de3e5.jpg" width="427" height="640" /></a>Credit: <a href="http://www.mostbeautifulpages.com/2013/01/napa-valley-in-california.html" target="_blank">mostbeautifulpages</a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Winter in Yosemite National Park</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/17de12f8cfc568616c91156578879b02-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28640"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28640" alt="Travel Pinspiration California" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/17de12f8cfc568616c91156578879b021.jpg" width="400" height="600" /></a>credit: <a href="http://www.lik.com/thework/mountains/wintertower.html" target="_blank">lik.com</a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Mc Way Creek Falls, Big Sur</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/c57a4f74640c61325d12c70ab1de107e/" rel="attachment wp-att-28613"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28613" alt="Travel Pinspiration California" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/c57a4f74640c61325d12c70ab1de107e.jpg" width="399" height="600" /></a>Credit: <a href="http://www.wildnatureimages.com/Julia%20Pfeiffer%20Burns%20SP%201.htm" target="_blank">wildnatureimages</a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Disneyland</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/6917c8810214fcf4acb1fa2853697bb5/" rel="attachment wp-att-28614"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28614" alt="Travel Pinspiration" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/6917c8810214fcf4acb1fa2853697bb5.jpg" width="550" height="827" /></a>Credit: <a href="http://www.davewilsonphotography.com/2011/02/15/partners-walt-disney-world-florida/" target="_blank">DaveWilsonPhotography</a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">&#8220;Avenue of the Giants&#8221; &#8211; Redwood National Park</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/1d5993f73dd87e178e7261e53c66a74f/" rel="attachment wp-att-28630"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28630" alt="Travel Pinspiration California" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/1d5993f73dd87e178e7261e53c66a74f.jpg" width="550" height="836" /></a>credit: <a href="http://fineartamerica.com/featured/avenue-of-the-giants-benjamin-yeager.html" target="_blank">fineartamerica</a></p>
<h2>Need Travel Tips on California?</h2>
<p>Check out our guides on <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/san-francisco-travel-tips-from-travelers/" target="_blank"><strong>San Francisco</strong></a> and<a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/los-angeles-travel-tips/" target="_blank"><strong> Los Angeles</strong></a></p>
<h2>Join the Conversation</h2>
<p>In the comments section below tell me:</p>
<p><strong>What is the one place in California you want to visit?</strong></p>
<p><strong>If you have already visited, what is your best tip?</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/">Travel Pinspiration &#8211; 8 Photos of California</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~4/yo5CzXgiD8g" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.ytravelblog.com/travel-pinspiration-california/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Thai Cooking Class with Pat in Phuket</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~3/BX_zBE2S890/</link>
		<comments>http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 22:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Caz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Experiences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phuket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Experiences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thai cooking class]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ytravelblog.com/?p=27022</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I love Asian food, especially Thai, but when it comes to cooking it in my own home, I&#8217;m often left confused. Mostly by the ingredients. Why kaffir lime, won&#8217;t normal lime do? Egg noodles or rice noodles? What sort of eggplant? And what are these peas in the curry? After a morning spent at a [...]</p><p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/">Thai Cooking Class with Pat in Phuket</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-033/" rel="attachment wp-att-28553"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28553" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-033.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a></p>
<p>I love Asian food, especially Thai, but when it comes to cooking it in my own home, I&#8217;m often left confused.</p>
<p>Mostly by the ingredients. Why kaffir lime, won&#8217;t normal lime do? Egg noodles or rice noodles? What sort of eggplant? And what are these peas in the curry?</p>
<p>After a morning spent at a <strong>Thai cooking class</strong> in <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/things-to-do-in-phuket/" target="_blank"><strong>Phuket</strong></a> with Pat, I feel more confident in my ability to create a delicious Thai meal.</p>
<p>Pat is a local Thai chef who has no interest in having her own restaurant, she feels helping tourists learn how to cook Thai food from her own home is far more enjoyable.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/thai-cooking-class-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28556"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28556" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Thai-Cooking-Class.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a></p>
<p>She spent 3 years perfecting the art of Thai cooking at the <strong>&#8220;Green Cafe&#8221;</strong> on the infamous Melrose Street in LA. However, she says most of her learning came from growing up as a child in her family kitchen. It made me squirm to know I was not (yet) passing down any culinary magic to my children.</p>
<blockquote><p>Pat has been teaching tourists how to cook Thai food for 16 years, hers was the very first Thai cooking school in Phuket.</p></blockquote>
<p>Newspaper and magazine articles lining the walls of her kitchen tell the story of her success and appearances on international TV shows, including an Australian cooking show in 2012.</p>
<p>I relaxed into the wok knowing an expert was about to unlock the Thai cooking magic my family desperately craves.</p>
<p>Our first stop was the local markets nearby Pat&#8217;s home in Phuket Town. She quickly moved from stall to stall picking up the fresh fruit and vegetables explaining what they were and how they were used in Thai cooking.</p>
<div id="attachment_28559" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 810px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/thai-cooking-class-1/" rel="attachment wp-att-28559"><img class=" wp-image-28559" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Thai-Cooking-Class-1.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">At the markets</p></div>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/picmonkey-collage-65/" rel="attachment wp-att-28560"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28560" alt="Thai cooking class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/PicMonkey-Collage.jpg" width="800" height="800" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-067/" rel="attachment wp-att-28580"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28580" alt="Thai Cooking class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-067.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a></p>
<p>We hadn&#8217;t even started cooking yet and already I felt I had learned so much and was begging to unravel the mystery to cooking decent food at home. <strong>(Step 1 &#8211; Have a decent local market!)</strong></p>
<p>Maybe Kalyra would no longer complain about my cooking and would relish my Thai dishes as she had been doing the past week in Thailand. Kalyra&#8217;s favourite shows on TV are Masterchef and My Kitchen Rules and she has always loved to help me cook.</p>
<p>She followed Pat and I around the market.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Let me smell&#8221; she grabbed a lemongrass stalk.</p></blockquote>
<p>Mmmm smells good. With each new smell of kaffir lime, holy basil, coriander, and galangal I  recognized of the ingredients that create the distinct aroma and taste of Thai food. It is not as complicated as you think.</p>
<p>When we pulled up at Pat&#8217;s home for the cooking stage of the morning, Kalyra jumped over the car seats</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Are you ready to cook together Mum?&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>We sat under the shade at a table and chair in front of the kitchen sipping an iced lemongrass tea, while Pat prepared for our lesson.</p>
<h3>&#8220;Today there is only us, yesterday we had 8.&#8221;</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Pat doesn’t like to go over this number of students, preferring the more intimate style and ensuring she can give all her students adequate attention.</p>
<p>The open air kitchen is a double sized garage attached to the side of the house. On two benches sit rows of woks and pots on gas burners and two rows behind that are cutting boards, knives and mortar and pestles. ready for food preparation.</p>
<p>The kitchen clean and sparse; the only things present are the tools and ingredients needed for our dishes. <strong>(Step 2: Have an organised kitchen).</strong></p>
<p>The white board at the back lists our menu for the day: spring rolls, green curry, Som tum, tom yung goong and bananas in coconut milk. Some of my all time favourites.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-031/" rel="attachment wp-att-28563"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28563" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-031.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a></p>
<p>Pat tries to tell us that Kalyra is too young for the cooking, but she is yet to understand my willful daughter. She dons the apron and sticks close to my side.</p>
<h3>&#8220;Okay start class.&#8221; a short sharp clap gets us moving to the bench.</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We prepare first for the green curry. Pat explains the different ingredients we use and then we start chopping, slicing and bashing with the mortar and pestle. It&#8217;s not long before the spices of the curry paste hit our noses and we are ready to move to the next dish.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/thai-cooking-class-4/" rel="attachment wp-att-28590"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28590" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Thai-Cooking-Class1.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/picmonkey-collage-66/" rel="attachment wp-att-28567"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28567" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/PicMonkey-Collage1.jpg" width="800" height="800" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_28571" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 810px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-100-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28571"><img class="size-full wp-image-28571" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-1001.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Green Curry</p></div>
<p>There are no quick fixes or packets of convenience in this kitchen; it is all done by hand from the beginning.</p>
<p>Starting with coconut milk. There is something so primal about squeezing the coconut meat with water to create milk. It&#8217;s a long process, but I&#8217;m excited to know every element of the dish comes from a labour of love &#8211; isn’t that what gets the judges handing out tens on these cooking shows?</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-040/" rel="attachment wp-att-28591"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28591" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-040.jpg" width="600" height="900" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_28574" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 810px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-039/" rel="attachment wp-att-28574"><img class=" wp-image-28574" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-039.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Squeezing coconut meat to create coconut milk</p></div>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;You cooked with love and I could taste it. For that I give you a 10&#8243;</p></blockquote>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure I would say I was in love with squeezing coconut milk, it is kind of the long way about it, but I did love learning how coconut milk was made and actually doing it one time. (I am in love with coconut milk though)</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The coconut cream we use at the end for extra richness, not at the beginning otherwise the dish will get too oily. But, you can use a spoonful of the coconut cream instead of oil when your first begin to cook the curry paste&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Maybe I am not a dreadful cook after all, as this is what I have always done, taught to me by my good friend Jintana who gave me cooking lessons in Bangkok in 2003. I remember this tip and not much else.</p>
<p>Kalyra embraces the rolling of the spring rolls, a task easy enough for her to do, although Pat wanted a little more tightness in the rolls and would stop to reroll a couple.</p>
<p>I didn&#8217;t care if the spring roll would fall apart frying in the oil, I was happy for Kalyra to be enthusiastically rolling and learning alongside her.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/picmonkey-collage-69/" rel="attachment wp-att-28593"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28593" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/PicMonkey-Collage4.jpg" width="800" height="800" /></a></p>
<p>Kalyra wore a frown several times when there were tasks she could not do like chopping with the knife and stirring over the hot stove. But she helped me peel the kaffir leaf and grate the mango for the Som Tum. And we both enjoyed the smells of sweet basil wafting up as we peeled and chopped.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-082-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28576"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28576" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-082.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a></p>
<p>The creation of each dish is simple, with few ingredients and little cooking time. Once you understand this, it is not challenging to create a 10 point Thai dish.</p>
<p>Or maybe it’s just because Pat is standing there to guide me with each step.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-122-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-28577"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28577" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-122.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-047/" rel="attachment wp-att-28592"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28592" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-047.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a></p>
<p>After a couple of hours of chopping, grating, mashing and cooking, it is time to sit and eat.</p>
<p>Pat has prepared the dishes on the table inside her home. She busies herself with paper work while we sit and eat as a family. Well try to. Savannah has her exploration boots on, but Pat&#8217;s assistants play with her in between cleaning.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-131/" rel="attachment wp-att-28581"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28581" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-131.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-136/" rel="attachment wp-att-28582"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28582" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-136.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a></p>
<h3>The food tastes good. Authentic. I savour every bite knowing the hard work that went into preparing it.</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/picmonkey-collage-68/" rel="attachment wp-att-28586"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-28586" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/PicMonkey-Collage3.jpg" width="800" height="800" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_28596" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 810px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-134-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-28596"><img class=" wp-image-28596" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-1342.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Tom Yum Goong</p></div>
<div id="attachment_28587" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 810px"><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/cooking-class-137/" rel="attachment wp-att-28587"><img class=" wp-image-28587" alt="Thai Cooking Class" src="http://www.ytravelblog.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cooking-class-137.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Green Curry</p></div>
<p>This was the food we came to Thailand for. My body zinged with each mouthful and the creaminess of the curry rolled around in my tummy and made me coconut happy.</p>
<p>Fresh from the source from market to belly, no tainted, packaged or processed food. I knew what was put into my body was pure energy and was being put to good use, cleansing, restoring and revitalizing.</p>
<p>I felt replete.</p>
<p>The banana in coconut milk added a touch of sweetness to end the meal. Just enough. Not the fullness of a western desert piled high with fat, sugar and calories, but light, healthy polish to the entire Thai meal.</p>
<h2>Where to Find Pat</h2>
<p>To learn more about how you can join Pat in her home in Phuket for a traditional Thai cooking class visit <a href="http://www.phuket.com/thai-cooking/" target="_blank"><strong>her website.</strong></a></p>
<h2>Join the Conversation</h2>
<p>In the comments section down below, tell me:</p>
<p><strong>Which Thai meal would you love to know how to cook?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Disclaimer: We visited Phuket as guests of <a href="http://www.tourismthailand.org/home" target="_blank">Tourism Thailand</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/">Thai Cooking Class with Pat in Phuket</a> 
Thanks so much for subscribing! Don't forget to sign up for our <a href="http://www.ytravelblog.com/about-us-2/y-travel-blog-newsletter">monthly newsletter and free ebook></a> Connect with us on <a href="http://facebook.com/ytravelblog">facebook></a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Ytravelblog/~4/BX_zBE2S890" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.ytravelblog.com/thai-cooking-class/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	<media:credit role="author">Caz Makepeace</media:credit><media:rating>nonadult</media:rating><media:description type="plain">y Travel Cafe podcast highlighting global travel, destinations, budget travel, couples travel family travel, travel stories, travel tips, backpacking, and working holidays. Caz and Craig have been living and working around the world since 1997. They have </media:description></channel>
</rss><!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic (Feed is rejected)
Page Caching using disk: enhanced

 Served from: www.ytravelblog.com @ 2013-03-23 00:36:21 by W3 Total Cache -->
