<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Fox Is Black</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 11:11:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>The Fox Is Black Turns Six Years Old</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/04/01/the-fox-is-black-turns-six-years-old/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/04/01/the-fox-is-black-turns-six-years-old/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 11:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bobby Solomon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Fox Is Black]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=57158</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On April 1, 2007, after a long bout of not understanding what I wanted to do in life, I decided that it might be fun to start a blog. I didn&#8217;t know anything about blogs really, other then I liked reading them. I didn&#8217;t know anything HTML or CSS and I definitely didn&#8217;t know anything [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//six.jpg" alt="The Fox Is Black turns six years old" width="800" height="800" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-57160" /></p>
<p>On April 1, 2007, after a long bout of not understanding what I wanted to do in life, I decided that it might be fun to start a blog. I didn&#8217;t know anything about blogs really, other then I liked reading them. I didn&#8217;t know anything HTML or CSS and I definitely didn&#8217;t know anything about writing a blog. But I was excited to share my thoughts and my ideas and anything else that might come to mind. That enthusiasm now has led me to write nearly every day for six years straight, a feat I never imagined happening.</p>
<p>Now after six years I&#8217;m really trying to improve what the experience of reading The Fox Is Black is. I put a lot of effort in supporting my staff of writers. They all do an amazing job and help to bring an interesting perspective to a number of different topics that I alone could never cover. I put more effort into the pieces I writer and publish, trying to give a unique angle to the topics I find interesting. I&#8217;ve even introduced a set of new features to the site that will hopefully enhance the overall experience.</p>
<p>There are two notable updates: pagination and a footer. Gone is the lazy load scrolling, falling back on the tried and true page-by-page navigation. The footer is something I&#8217;ve wanted to do for a while but never really implemented. Now you have a way to access many of the different categories and features at the site once you hit the bottom. There&#8217;s plenty to dig through, and hopefully you find some time to see for yourself. And overall the site has gotten a brand new code base thanks to my friend <a href="http://look.itst.im/" title="Tim Mather">Tim Mather</a>, who you might know as one of the founders of the app <a href="https://untappd.com/" title="Untappd">Untappd</a>.</p>
<p>Lastly, I just want to say thanks to anyone who&#8217;s reading this. Running a website is hard work, especially when you have a day job like I do. But I&#8217;ve had the experience of meeting and interacting with so many rad people in the world because of this website, and for that I&#8217;m eternally grateful. Thank you so much for reading and supporting The Fox Is Black.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/04/01/the-fox-is-black-turns-six-years-old/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pulp&#8217;s &#8216;This Is Hardcore&#8217; Turns 15</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/04/01/pulps-this-is-hardcore-turns-15/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/04/01/pulps-this-is-hardcore-turns-15/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 09:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Philip Kennedy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56954</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last Saturday Pulp&#8217;s sixth studio album This Is Hardcore turned 15. Released on March 30th 1998, the album was the ambitious follow-up to their 1995 breakthrough, Different Class. The album was eagerly anticipated and on its release it received both critical acclaim and a number one spot in the UK charts. For me, This Is [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Pulp-This-Is-Hardcore.jpg" alt="Pulp - This Is Hardcore" width="850" height="858" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56958" /></p>
<p>Last Saturday <a href="http://www.pulppeople.com/">Pulp&#8217;s</a> sixth studio album <em>This Is Hardcore</em> turned 15. Released on March 30th 1998, the album was the ambitious follow-up to their 1995 breakthrough, <em>Different Class</em>. The album was eagerly anticipated and on its release it received both critical acclaim and a number one spot in the UK charts. </p>
<p>For me, <em>This Is Hardcore</em> might not necessarily be the bands crowning moment, but there&#8217;s so many great things about it that I can&#8217;t help but celebrate it today. So, I invite you to raise a glass and join me in wishing <em>This Is Hardcore</em> a happy fifteenth-birthday. </p>
<p><span id="more-56954"></span><br />
<img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//29_mg1528.jpg" alt="Inside Pulp&#039;s This Is Hardcore" width="1877" height="1000" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-57056" /></p>
<p><big><strong>The Artwork</strong></big><br />
Easily one of the most controversial album covers of the nineties, the artwork for <i>This is Hardcore</i> shows a naked woman draped across a red leather sofa. Photographed by <a href="http://www.horstdiekgerdes.com/">Horst Diekgerdes</a> with art direction from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Saville_%28graphic_designer%29">Peter Saville</a> and American painter <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Currin">John Currin</a>, the artwork plays on the belief that &#8220;all publicity is good publicity&#8221;. </p>
<p>For Pulp&#8217;s front-man Jarvis Cocker, the artwork held more then just shock value, it was a way to make the band be taken more seriously. According to Saville, the title doesn&#8217;t refer to pornography, but rather to the “new, hard, resolute spirit of the band”. Pulp are hardcore, and the artwork creates a paradox where reality and fantasy blur. This crossover echos Cocker&#8217;s frustrations with how fame had changed the world around him and Saville and Currin&#8217;s artwork highlights the dehumanizing nature of pornography, emphasizing one of the album&#8217;s main themes.</p>
<p>To learn more about this artwork I can&#8217;t recommend Hugh Aldersey-Williams&#8217; fantastic piece from <em>New Statesman</em> highly enough. You can read it on the Pulp fansite <a href="http://www.acrylicafternoons.com/hardcore.html">Acrylic Afternoons</a>.</p>
<p><iframe width="800" height="600" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/JXbLyi5wgeg?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><big><strong>The Songs</strong></big><br />
<i>This Is Hardcore</i> is an album filled with great tracks but it&#8217;s the singles &#8216;Help The Aged&#8217; and &#8216;This is Hardcore&#8217; that really steal the show. The latter in particular encapsulates what the band and the album do so well. </p>
<p>&#8216;This Is Hardcore&#8217; is a sordid monument to weary decadence and sinister secrets. It&#8217;s lavish orchestral grandeur and dark unsentimental lyrics mark it out as arguably one of the finest tracks of the 90s. As Twitter user <a href="https://twitter.com/fromdesktildawn">@fromdesktildawn</a> so aptly put it in a piece for <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/music/musicblog/2012/dec/20/pulp-beginners-guide?INTCMP=SRCH">The Guardian</a>, it is &#8220;the Sexual Healing for the indie kids and geeks of this world&#8221;.</p>
<p><iframe width="800" height="600" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/_bZjKC0EaY0?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><big><strong>The Videos</strong></big><br />
In addition to the excellent &#8216;This Is Hardcore&#8217; video by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doug_Nichol">Doug Nichol</a>, the album also brought us the iconic image of Jarvis taking a stair-lift to heaven. The video for &#8216;Help The Aged&#8217; was a career defining moment for film and music video director Garth Jennings and his producer Nick Goldsmith (aka <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hammer_%26_Tongs">Hammer &#038; Tongs</a>). Dark, elegant and beautifully surreal, this video captured the tone of the album perfectly. It also features images and art-direction from John Currin, but more importantly it contains some of Cocker&#8217;s amazing moves!</p>
<p><big><strong>The Music</strong></big><br />
If you wish to listen to the album I&#8217;ve embedded both Rdio and Spotify playlists below. Happy Birthday <em>This Is Hardcore</em>!</p>
<p><center><br />
<iframe width="640" height="370" src="https://rd.io/i/QVSAUyJbSz8/" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:album:65TxXNf79y6E7zBpAdVMZZ" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" width="640" height="auto"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/04/01/pulps-this-is-hardcore-turns-15/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top Five From LAIY: Week Of March 25</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/top-five-from-laiy-week-of-march-25/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/top-five-from-laiy-week-of-march-25/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 22:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>KYLE FITZPATRICK</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles, I'm Yours]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=57005</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Traveller: An Interview With Maya Erdelyi When you think of animation and animators, you don&#8217;t think of cut paper and fine artistry. This is probably because you are not familiar with the work of Maya Erdelyi, an animator who uses cut paper to maker her little films. She is super talented and is one [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Top-Five-From-LAIY25.jpg"><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Top-Five-From-LAIY25.jpg" alt="Top Five From LAIY: Week Of March 25" width="800" height="320" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-57010" /></a></p>
<p><big><a href="http://www.laimyours.com/39876/the-traveller-an-interview-with-maya-erdelyi/">The Traveller: An Interview With Maya Erdelyi</big></a><br />
When you think of animation and animators, you don&#8217;t think of cut paper and fine artistry. This is probably because you are not familiar with the work of Maya Erdelyi, an animator who uses cut paper to maker her little films. She is super talented and is one of those people who is always on the go. We caught up with her in Winter and, funny enough, she&#8217;s already moved on from LA to her next habitat. What a talent!</p>
<p><big><a href="http://www.laimyours.com/39878/a-little-help-from-tylt/">A Little Help From TYLT</big></a><br />
TYLT is a Simi Valley based tech company that makes lots of very useful products to compliment your mobility, i.e. your mobiles when you are mobile. One of their best and most useful products is their PowerPlant, a little on-the-go charger that can resuscitate your device in a pinch. We&#8217;ve used it several time and it is so fast and keeps its charge for a <i>long</i> time. This is a great investment for you mobile workers.</p>
<p><big><a href="http://www.laimyours.com/39973/an-adventure-in-catalina/">An Adventure In Catalina</big></a><br />
Do you guys remember seeing some crazy island-ish Instagram photos from Bobby last weekend? Well, we spent the day in Catalina which is this insane, lush, beautiful island not too far off the coast from Los Angeles. The place is commonly believed to be some sort of weird, cheesy island where OC and Long Beach types go to do nothing but it is actually huge and mostly wild area preserved by the Catalina Island Conservancy, a group who focuses on keeping the island as natural as it has always been. The group invited us out and took us on a crazy fun adventure all around the place. We&#8217;re dying to go back&#8211;and you should definitely check it out, too.</p>
<p><span id="more-57005"></span></p>
<p><big><a href="http://www.laimyours.com/40154/a-drink-at-the-bona-vista-lounge/">A Drink At Bona Vista Lounge</a> &#038; <a href="http://www.laimyours.com/40153/wine-the-angeleno-a-word-with-pallavi-patil-of-vinelust/">Vinelust</big></a><br />
We wanted to share two food items about drinks this week because we couldn&#8217;t figure out which to choose. First, there is this rooftop rotating bar Downtown that is caught in 1984 and it is fantastic albeit expensive and with shitty food and shitty service. It&#8217;s the Bona Vista Lounge and it is a step back in cheese ball time. We also spoke with the CEO of new subscription service Vinelust which helps let you try new wines that are within your palette. If you are a wine person, sign up for this. Moreover, if you sign up between now and April 3, you can use a special LAIY discount code, too.</p>
<p><big><a href="http://www.laimyours.com/40203/commodity-premium-fragrances/">Commodity Premium Fragrances</big></a><br />
Commodity Premium Fragrances are a new scent concept that is hoping to change the game of how we make ourselves smell. By using mail in scent tests, you can try out their wears. This is cool and great but what is even more awesome is their subtle yet bold and beautiful packaging. We&#8217;re obsessed! We almost could care less how they smell because the bottles are so perfect. We love them.</p>
<p>One other thing we wanted to share but <i>barely</i> missed the cut: <a href="http://www.laimyours.com/39877/inside-book-stand-at-the-standard/">Book Stand</a>, a really rad nature and book pop up at The Standard Hollywood. We highly suggest you visit them!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/top-five-from-laiy-week-of-march-25/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Magic Cube by Pixelux Studio</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/the-magic-cube-by-pixelux-studio/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/the-magic-cube-by-pixelux-studio/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bobby Solomon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=57039</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Pixelux Studio, a french motion graphics company, has come up with quite an ambitious but amazing looking project. The Magic Cube is a giant display which is powered by 28 bicycles positioned around the cube. The display changes the more riders you have, eventually hitting a level of pure white if all 28 bikes are [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//magic-cube-pixelux-studio-1.jpg" alt="The Magic Cube by Pixelux Studio" width="900" height="952" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-57042" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.pixelux.tv/" title="Pixelux Studio">Pixelux Studio</a>, a french motion graphics company, has come up with quite an ambitious but amazing looking project. <a href="http://www.pixelux.tv/87046/1075968/home/magic-cube-generative-art" title="The Magic Cube by Pixelux Studio">The Magic Cube</a> is a giant display which is powered by 28 bicycles positioned around the cube. The display changes the more riders you have, eventually hitting a level of pure white if all 28 bikes are rode at their full speed.</p>
<p><span id="more-57039"></span></p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/57856289?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=ffffff" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
<p>The effect is pretty incredible, especially once you consider the scale of the displays. It&#8217;s also pretty great that you have to collaborate with others to get the final effect, the statue of Louis XIV lighting up and a spray of fireworks.</p>
<blockquote><p>Each bicycle supply a digitized signal that is stream to the main application. Everything is done with Touch Designer: Graphics, animation, particle and physics, shading glsl, rendering, programming, light control (dmx), sound modulation (a bridge with Ableton Live). The main challenge was to render generative and 360° seamless graphic texture. Bike&#8217;s data flow is processed individuality and as a group to modulate different generator, creating different levels of graphics, set according the main timeline. A sequence of 240s that drive the rise of the energy until the climax. The cube becomes pure energy, lighting up the statue (Louis XIV) and a burst of fireworks to reward our riders.</p></blockquote>
<p>Anyone seen this in real life?</p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//magic-cube-pixelux-studio-2.jpg" alt="The Magic Cube by Pixelux Studio" width="900" height="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-57041" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//magic-cube-pixelux-studio-3.jpg" alt="The Magic Cube by Pixelux Studio" width="900" height="507" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-57040" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/the-magic-cube-by-pixelux-studio/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Mission Statement Mix by TNGHT</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/the-mission-statement-mix-by-tnght/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/the-mission-statement-mix-by-tnght/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alec Rojas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mixtape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56677</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[TNGHT must be the most important bass and trap outfit out there. One part Glasgow and one part Montreal, the group makes beat making look effortless. Made up of two rising production stars in Hudson Mohawke and Lunice, the group not only is affiliated with the recently-dead-but-now-risen Lil Wayne but also Yeezy and G.O.O.D. Music. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//TNGHT.jpg" alt="The Mission Statement Mix by TNGHT" width="851" height="315" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56912" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//TNGHT1.jpg" alt="TNGHT" width="1318" height="878" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56932" /></p>
<p><a href="http://warp.net/records/tnght">TNGHT</a> must be the most important bass and trap outfit out there. One part Glasgow and one part Montreal, the group makes beat making look effortless. Made up of two rising production stars in<a href="http://hudsonmohawke.com/slowjams-vi"> Hudson Mohawke</a> and <a href="http://thisisluckyme.com/music/lunice/">Lunice</a>, the group not only is affiliated with the recently-dead-but-now-risen Lil Wayne but also Yeezy and G.O.O.D. Music. With spots in the latest Adidas ad and some Adult Swim drops, these dudes are firmly on the map. Last year&#8217;s EP, with all of its weird twists, turns, and absolutely brutal bass lines, sounded like a Southern Crunk Rave. </p>
<p>That&#8217;s a good thing.</p>
<p><span id="more-56677"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F55499783&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;secret_token=s-ANjzd"></iframe></p>
<p>The Mission Statement Mix displays their influences with almost pristine detail. Released on the BBC last year, a week before the EP, it drips fire. The expansive layering of Southern rap is a smooth start but as the BPMs ramp up, their tracks feel just like another step. There are so many great moments to enjoy: a lil&#8217; 2 Chainz, some Master P, and some Dreezy? How about a remix of Mercy? For all the times I can talk about experimental classical and ambient drone, well, let me break the news: I think this mix tape is fine art of the highest quality, an informed look at our own tendencies in dance and urban music.</p>
<p>The playlist below.</p>
<p>1 John Carpenter &#8211; Back to the pod (version 2)<br />
2 SpaceGhostPurrp &#8211; Get Yah Head Bust<br />
3 Dj Zirk &#8211; Lock Em In Da Trunk (Chopped &#038; Screwed Tommy Kruise Remix)<br />
4 Lil Ugly Mane feat. Denzel Curry &#8211; Twistin<br />
5 Jackie Chain feat. Bun B &#038; Big K.R.I.T. &#8211; Parked Outside<br />
6 Lady Bee &#8211; Hard Like A Criminal<br />
7 Dj Squeeky &#038; Tha Family &#8211; Death To You Playa Hata<br />
8 Snoop Dogg feat. Master P &#8211; Snoop World<br />
9 Lunice &#8211; Youngin (Paper)<br />
10 TNGHT &#8211; Bugg&#8217;N<br />
11 2Chainz feat. Drake &#8211; No Lie<br />
12 Lunice &#8211; Believe Dat<br />
13 TNGHT &#8211; Ridin Up<br />
14 Chief Keef feat. Kanye West, Pusha T, Big Sean &#038; Jadakiss &#8211; I Don&#8217;t Like (Remix)<br />
15 TNGHT &#8211; Goooo<br />
16 GOOD Music &#8211; Mercy x Furnace<br />
17 Hudson Mo &#8211; Chimes<br />
18 Sasha Go Hard &#8211; I&#8217;m Hotta<br />
19 Zebra Katz x Boyfriend &#8211; Winter Titty<br />
20 Decibel &#8211; GAP<br />
21 TNGHT &#8211; Bounce Hitum<br />
22 Waka Flocka Flame &#8211; Rooster in my Rari (TNGHT official remix)<br />
23 TNGHT &#8211; Higher Ground<br />
24 Stabber &#8211; Torsion Force<br />
25 S-Type &#8211; Billboard<br />
26 TNGHT &#8211; Go Get Busy<br />
27 Zodiac &#8211; Girlgirlgirl<br />
28 John Carpenter &#8211; Over the Wall</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/the-mission-statement-mix-by-tnght/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Josh Parkin Illustrates Nike&#8217;s Spring/Summer Collection for The Chimp Store</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/josh-parkin-nike-the-chimp-store/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/josh-parkin-nike-the-chimp-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 18:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Andi Teran</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56941</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s always exciting when retail stores eschew flashy photography or expensive commercials in favor of something unique and artist generated to showcase their wares. Such is the case with The Chimp Store, a UK-based menswear boutique that enlisted the talents of Josh Parkin to illustrate Nike&#8217;s upcoming Spring/Summer shoe collection. By putting each shoe in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/josh-parkin-nike-the-chimp-store/josh-parkin-nike-puzzle/" rel="attachment wp-att-56944"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56944" alt="Josh Parkin Nike puzzle" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//josh-parkin-nike-puzzle.jpg" width="800" height="534" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/josh-parkin-nike-the-chimp-store/josh-parkin-nike-chimp-store/" rel="attachment wp-att-56945"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56945" alt="Josh Parkin Nike collection for The Chimp Store" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//josh-parkin-nike-chimp-store.jpg" width="800" height="536" /></a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s always exciting when retail stores eschew flashy photography or expensive commercials in favor of something unique and artist generated to showcase their wares. Such is the case with <a href="http://www.thechimpstore.com">The Chimp Store</a>, a UK-based menswear boutique that enlisted the talents of <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Josh-Parkin-Illustration/282264741824558">Josh Parkin</a> to illustrate <a href="http://www.nike.com/us/en_us/?ref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com%2F">Nike&#8217;</a>s upcoming Spring/Summer shoe collection. By putting each shoe in a fun and/or precarious position—from shark cages and icebergs to a wrecking ball and tow truck scenario—they become characters that tell a story. It&#8217;s delightful to see your favorite styles rendered into a puzzle or stained glass window; in a way, it builds the anticipation of seeing an actual photograph even more. Wouldn&#8217;t it be great if Nike employed artists in the same way, too?</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/josh-parkin-nike-the-chimp-store/josh-parkin-nike-iceberg/" rel="attachment wp-att-56946"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56946" alt="Josh Parkin Nike iceberg shoe" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//josh-parkin-nike-iceberg.jpg" width="800" height="534" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/josh-parkin-nike-the-chimp-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Space Suit of the Week</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/space-suit-of-the-week-127/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/space-suit-of-the-week-127/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 17:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alana Zimmer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Illustration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space Suit of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SPACETIME]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56991</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Illustrator Jay Fleck&#8216;s work is full of childhood ambition: his work illustrates fantasies born while staring at the ceiling on top of bunk bed during summer camp. On a large scale, his work depicts giraffes, whales, rocket ships and other figments of a healthy childhood imagination. The only way I know describe is work is [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//tell-my-wife-that-i-love-her-jay-fleck.jpg" alt="Jay Fleck" width="480" height="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56993" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//blast-off-jay-fleck.jpg" alt="Jay Fleck" width="480" height="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56994" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//panda-express-jay-fleck.jpg" alt="Jay Fleck" width="400" height="500" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56995" /></p>
<p>Illustrator <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/theflecks/sets/72157625377097703/">Jay Fleck</a>&#8216;s work is full of childhood ambition: his work illustrates fantasies born while staring at the ceiling on top of bunk bed during summer camp. On a large scale, his work depicts giraffes, whales, rocket ships and other figments of a healthy childhood imagination. The only way I know describe is work is that he pieces are fun&#8211;some are clever and others are more cheeky, too. All are full of childish fun pared with aspiration and daydreams.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/space-suit-of-the-week-127/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Man Who Met the Moon and Stayed with Her Forever</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/a-man-who-met-the-moon-and-stayed-with-her-forever/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/a-man-who-met-the-moon-and-stayed-with-her-forever/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alex Dent</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56940</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[These are images from Private Moon, an ongoing series created by physician-turned-artist Leonid Tishkov. The series, which has been growing for almost a decade, depicts a glowing crescent moon that wanders the surface of the earth forming relationships with people. In an interview the artist says that the series began as &#8220;this installation with the glowing moon at one of the festivals [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Tishkov_Moon4.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56984" alt="Leonid Tishkov Private Moon" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Tishkov_Moon4.jpg" width="800" height="620" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.designboom.com/art/private-moon-by-leonid-tishkov-travels-the-world/">These are images</a> from <em>Private Moon</em>, an ongoing series created by physician-turned-artist <a href="http://leonid-tishkov.blogspot.it/">Leonid Tishkov</a>. The series, which has been growing for almost a decade, depicts a glowing crescent moon that wanders the surface of the earth forming relationships with people.</p>
<p><span id="more-56940"></span></p>
<p>In <a href="http://leonid-tishkov.blogspot.it/2013/01/el-cuento-de-hadas-de-la-existencia.html">an interview</a> the artist says that the series began as &#8220;this installation with the glowing moon at one of the festivals of contemporary art. I wanted to make a picture of the reality of my favorite artist – Belgian surrealist Rene Magritte. After that I brought the moon to the roof of my studio on a skyscraper on the South of Moscow, where she shone to me personally, and brightened my loneliness.&#8221; So it&#8217;s fitting that Tishkov is not working alone on this series. He is helped by folks across the the globe as he travels with his moon, including help from a very talented photographer <a href="http://www.bendikov.ru/">Boris Bendikov</a>. Tishkov says that he is &#8220;grateful to everyone who walked by my side as I’m carrying the moon around the world.&#8221; And these are just some of the photographs from that orbit.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Tishkov_Moon3.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56985" alt="Leonid Tishkov Private Moon" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Tishkov_Moon3.jpg" width="800" height="596" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Tishkov_Moon2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56986" alt="Leonid Tishkov Private Moon" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Tishkov_Moon2.jpg" width="800" height="601" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Tishkov_Moon.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56987" alt="Leonid Tishkov Private Moon" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Tishkov_Moon.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/29/a-man-who-met-the-moon-and-stayed-with-her-forever/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Illustration Work of Michael Molfetas</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/the-illustration-work-of-michael-molfetas/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/the-illustration-work-of-michael-molfetas/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 18:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Skip Hursh</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Illustration]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56880</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I love coming across new work that puts a unique spin on illustration rooted in abstraction. Brooklyn-based Illustrator Michael Molfetas has a smart and reduced graphic style that has one foot in the Keith Haring school of free-form intuitive linework and the other in character-based idiosyncrasy. Michael&#8217;s characters have a weirdness about them that is [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//michael-molfetas-1.jpg" alt="Michael Molfetas" width="800" height="589" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56881" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//michael-molfetas-2.jpg" alt="Michael Molfetas" width="800" height="455" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56882" /></p>
<p>I love coming across new work that puts a unique spin on illustration rooted in abstraction. Brooklyn-based Illustrator <a href="http://www.michaelmolfetas.com/">Michael Molfetas</a> has a smart and reduced graphic style that has one foot in the Keith Haring school of free-form intuitive linework and the other in character-based idiosyncrasy.</p>
<p><span id="more-56880"></span></p>
<p>Michael&#8217;s characters have a weirdness about them that is certainly in part due to their abstract vibes but also is evocative of contemporary artists with leanings toward comic art like Andy Rementer. I particularly like Michael&#8217;s forays into anthropomorphized shapes, sticking googly eyes on a funky pipe apparatus or a blobby thing that kind of looks like both a pigeon and a water faucet.</p>
<p>Michael has an ongoing project where he&#8217;s <a href="http://appleaday.michaelmolfetas.com/">illustrating an apple every day</a>, with some really creative and varied experiments so far. Check out more of his work <a href="http://www.michaelmolfetas.com/">here</a>.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//michael-molfetas-3.jpg" alt="Michael Molfetas" width="800" height="576" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56883" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//michael-molfetas-4.jpg" alt="Michael Molfetas" width="800" height="574" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56884" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//michael-molfetas-5.jpg" alt="Michael Molfetas" width="800" height="537" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56885" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//michael-molfetas-6.jpg" alt="Michael Molfetas" width="800" height="335" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56886" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//michael-molfetas-7.jpg" alt="Michael Molfetas" width="800" height="350" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56887" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/the-illustration-work-of-michael-molfetas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Doug Johnston Strikes a Cord</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/doug-johnston-strikes-a-cord/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/doug-johnston-strikes-a-cord/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 17:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Andi Teran</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56895</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was walking down a cobblestone street in New York City one night when a strange ghostly sculpture in a shop window caught my eye. I ambled over and stood in front of the glass beholding a giant creature made of cords and a gaping mouth. It was an arresting image, one that humored as [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?attachment_id=56897" rel="attachment wp-att-56897"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56897" alt="Doug Johnston Sash Cord Studies pieces" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//doug-johnston-sash-cord-studies.jpg" width="800" height="517" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?attachment_id=56898" rel="attachment wp-att-56898"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56898" alt="Doug Johnston Sash Cord Studies vessels" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//doug-johnston-sash-cord-bowls.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
<p>I was walking down a cobblestone street in New York City one night when a strange ghostly sculpture in a shop window caught my eye. I ambled over and stood in front of the glass beholding a giant creature made of cords and a gaping mouth. It was an arresting image, one that humored as much as terrified. Later, I found out it was the work of artist <a href="http://www.dougjohnston.net/index.php">Doug Johnston</a>, and this eerily beautiful sculpture barely scratched his polymathic, multi-hyphenate artistic surface.</p>
<p><span id="more-56895"></span></p>
<p>Hailing from Oklahoma by way of West Texas, Johnston works as an artist, designer, architect and musician. Rather than chose a specific genre, he works within them all generating everything from sculpture and installations to fiber art and music made and recorded with a cell phone. Johnston&#8217;s modern nylon and cotton pendant lamps and vessels are truly special—and they&#8217;re for sale. Stitched together on an industrial sewing machine, he weaves cords together in a variety of shapes and sells them, made to order, through his own <a href="http://shop.dougjohnston.net">online shop</a>. Though it doesn&#8217;t appear as if any giant ghosts are currently for sale, there are fantastic woven tote bags, baskets, bowls, and small-scale sculptures to choose from.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?attachment_id=56899" rel="attachment wp-att-56899"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56899" alt="Doug Johnston Two Stools" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//doug-johnston-two-stools.jpg" width="800" height="532" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?attachment_id=56900" rel="attachment wp-att-56900"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56900" alt="Doug Johnston pendant lamps" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//doug-johnston-pendants.jpg" width="800" height="510" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/doug-johnston-strikes-a-cord/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sociopathic Pop Misfits – A Film Review of ‘Spring Breakers’</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/sociopathic-pop-misfits-a-film-review-of-spring-breakers/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/sociopathic-pop-misfits-a-film-review-of-spring-breakers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 16:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Christina Stimpson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Films]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[more]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[more of this]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56858</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What do you get when you mix teenage starlets and pop sensations with America’s most enigmatic independent filmmaker? The answer is Spring Breakers, the neon-blazing, experiential, psychedelic pastiche that is Harmony Korine’s most commercially successful film yet. Comprised as a symphony of character, narrative, and social-political layers, Spring Breakers is a maze through an ultra-fun [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Spring-Breakers-film-by-Harmony-Korine.jpg" alt="Spring Breakers poster by Harmony Korine" width="1350" height="2000" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56859" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Spring-Breakers-film-by-Harmony-Korine.png" alt="Spring Breakers film by Harmony Korine" width="876" height="658" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56861" /></p>
<p>What do you get when you mix teenage starlets and pop sensations with America’s most enigmatic independent filmmaker? The answer is <a href="http://www.springbreakersmovie.com/"><i>Spring Breakers</i></a>, the neon-blazing, experiential, psychedelic pastiche that is Harmony Korine’s most commercially successful film yet. Comprised as a symphony of character, narrative, and social-political layers, <i>Spring Breakers</i> is a maze through an ultra-fun then frenzied trip for four freshmen that will stop at nothing to get to Daytona Beach in time for spring break.</p>
<p><span id="more-56858"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="800" height="450" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/rVvn9T6bqls?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Faith (Selena Gomez), Brit (Ashley Benson), Candy (Vanessa Hudgens) and Cotty (Rachel Korine) each represent a different level of temptation that moves deeper and into more dangerous territory from one to the next. Faith, the most innocent and naïve, wanting simply to party with her friends and escape reality in Daytona, is confronted with the jarring experience of being thrown in jail when the foursome are caught with drugs. Ready to bail them out is Alien, an almost unrecognizable James Franco whose creepy demeanour around the girls is a red flag for Faith to bail on her dream vacation. In <i>Spring Breakers</i>, each girl get lost in their own funnel of danger and limitation. At that point, pegging down the villain becomes as inconsequential as the initial reason of why they came to Daytona in the first place.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Spring-Breakers-film-still-by-Harmony-Korine.jpg" alt="Spring Breakers film still by Harmony Korine" width="1200" height="800" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56862" /></p>
<p><i>Spring Breakers</i> is somewhere between exactly what you think it is and no where near what you thought it would be like. The use of hyper-stylized bright colors and contrast lighting brings a feeling of surrealism to the film, yet it is also exists in a world that is grim, violent and deadly. If you don’t trust Harmony Korine, <i>Spring Breakers</i> may sound like the epicentre of cheesy. But chances are, if you thirst for the Korine touch of ambiguous weirdness (which has previously included vignettes of geriatric trash fornication and skydiving nuns) you’ll understand his vision for <i>Spring Breakers</i>.  As is best with any Korine film, the only expectation worth carrying to the cinema is that of mind-expanding freedom.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/sociopathic-pop-misfits-a-film-review-of-spring-breakers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Film Poster Inspiration: The work of Midnight Marauder</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/film-poster-inspiration-the-work-of-midnight-marauder/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/film-poster-inspiration-the-work-of-midnight-marauder/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 15:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bobby Solomon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Films]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56872</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To aid in the creation of your posters for the Battle Royale Re-Covered Film Poster contest, I though it would be cool to highlight someone who could be potentially be inspirational. He&#8217;s a Los Angeles based artist who goes by the name Midnight Marauder, a prolific creator of self-initiated posters and box art for movies. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//midnight-marauder-death-proof-planet-terror.jpg" alt="Film Poster Inspiration: The work of Midnight Marauder" width="800" height="552" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56874" /></p>
<p>To aid in the creation of your posters for the <a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/category/re-covered-film-posters/" title="Battle Royale Re-Covered Film Poster contest"><em>Battle Royale</em> Re-Covered Film Poster contest</a>, I though it would be cool to highlight someone who could be potentially be inspirational. He&#8217;s a Los Angeles based artist who goes by the name <a href="http://www.midnight-marauder.com/" title="Midnight Marauder">Midnight Marauder</a>, a prolific creator of self-initiated posters and box art for movies. </p>
<p><span id="more-56872"></span></p>
<p>His work often centers around creating Criterion-esque covers for films he enjoys, designing pieces that are beautiful and eye-catching. He has an impeccable way of combining imagery from the film with bold type to make covers that you actually wish existed. The cover for Looper, which you can see below, is a perfect example of this. It&#8217;s the combination of imagery that tells a captivating story that draws you in. You want to know what all those little vignettes mean and how they add up to a cohesive story. Hopefully you&#8217;ll find these inspirational as I have!</p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//midnight-marauder-looper-poster.jpg" alt="Film Poster Inspiration: The work of Midnight Marauder" width="800" height="1132" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56875" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//midnight-marauder-annie-hall-raging-bull.jpg" alt="Film Poster Inspiration: The work of Midnight Marauder" width="800" height="552" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56873" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/film-poster-inspiration-the-work-of-midnight-marauder/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Desktop Wallpaper Project featuring Brock Davis (2/2)</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/the-desktop-wallpaper-project-featuring-brock-davis-22/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/the-desktop-wallpaper-project-featuring-brock-davis-22/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 15:07:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bobby Solomon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Desktop Wallpaper Project]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56916</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Brock Davis 1280&#215;800 1440&#215;900 1680&#215;1050 1920&#215;1200 2560&#215;1440 iPhone iPhone 5 iPad Emo Pineapple. That&#8217;s the actual title for this awesome wallpaper by Brock Davis. Shortly after he sent the wallpaper we featured yesterday he sent this along and I started cracking up. It just amazes me how he&#8217;s able to transform the simplest of things [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//brock-davis-wallpaper-2-blog.jpg" alt="Brock Davis wallpaper - iPhone, iPad, Desktop" width="800" height="500" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56917" /></p>
<h3><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/the-desktop-wallpaper-featuring-brock-davis/">Brock Davis</a></h3>
<aside id="wallpaper" class="group">
<ul>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-2-1280x800.jpg" class="btn_download">1280&#215;800</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-2-1440x900.jpg" class="btn_download">1440&#215;900</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-2-1680x1050.jpg" class="btn_download">1680&#215;1050</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-2-1920x1200.jpg" class="btn_download">1920&#215;1200</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-2-2560x1440.jpg" class="btn_download">2560&#215;1440</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-2-iphone.jpg" class="btn_download">iPhone</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-2-iphone5.jpg" class="btn_download">iPhone 5</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-2-ipad.jpg" class="btn_download">iPad</a></li>
</ul>
</aside>
<p>Emo Pineapple. That&#8217;s the actual title for this awesome wallpaper by <a href="http://www.itistheworldthatmadeyousmall.com/" title="Brock Davis">Brock Davis</a>. Shortly after he sent <a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/the-desktop-wallpaper-project-featuring-brock-davis-12/" title="Brock Davis wallpaper on The Fox Is Black">the wallpaper we featured yesterday</a> he sent this along and I started cracking up. It just amazes me how he&#8217;s able to transform the simplest of things into pieces of observational art. A huge thanks to Brock for making these wallpapers for the site. </p>
<p>Be sure to check back every Wednesday for a new wallpaper!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/the-desktop-wallpaper-project-featuring-brock-davis-22/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aranda\Lasch build crystals, infinite variation, and practice on the edges of architecture</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/arandalasch-build-crystals-infinite-variation-and-practice-on-the-edges-of-architecture/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/arandalasch-build-crystals-infinite-variation-and-practice-on-the-edges-of-architecture/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 14:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alex Dent</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56894</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve spent the last several hours watching two dozen or so videos from the Creators Project, and I regret nothing. The videos are great, highlighting work created by some embarrassingly talented folks. One of the newest videos is focused on the light installation on the San Francisco Bay Bridge that Bobby wrote about last week, and another [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//ArandaLasch_CreatorsProject2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56904" alt="Aranda\Lasch The Creators Project yeasayer" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//ArandaLasch_CreatorsProject2.jpg" width="800" height="553" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//ArandaLasch_CreatorsProject1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56905" alt="Aranda\Lasch The Creators Project yeasayer" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//ArandaLasch_CreatorsProject1.jpg" width="800" height="534" /></a></p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/61825987?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=ffffff" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve spent the last several hours watching two dozen or so videos from the <a href="http://www.thecreatorsproject.com/">Creators Project</a>, and I regret nothing. The videos are great, highlighting work created by some embarrassingly talented folks. One of the newest videos is focused on the <a href="http://vimeo.com/62821199">light installation on the San Francisco Bay Bridge</a> that <a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/18/bay-lights-a-giant-installation-on-san-franciscos-bay-bridge-by-leo-villareal/">Bobby wrote about last week</a>, and another one I particularly like focuses on the work of Aranda\Lasch. </p>
<p>Lead by Benjamin Aranda and Christopher Lasch, the architecture firm has built a body of work along the boundaries of what most would call architecture, spilling over into a kind of computer and fabrication science where the firm experiments with ideas about everything from crystals to infinity. While their <a href="http://www.arandalasch.com/">website</a> is molting into something new, the two are pointing the curious to their <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/arandalasch/">flickr account</a>. There, you can find more pictures (like the ones above) of an excellent project featured in the aforementioned video: a set for the band <a href="http://www.yeasayer.net/">yeasayer</a>. If you&#8217;re unfamiliar with the band, they are <em>bueno</em> and I added one of their songs to the <a href="http://rd.io/x/QR71aTN6XDg/">TFIB March Playlist</a> so you can take a listen.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/28/arandalasch-build-crystals-infinite-variation-and-practice-on-the-edges-of-architecture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tutumu+: Cheerful Pattern-Based Illustrations from Naoko Horiguchi</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/tutumu-cheerful-pattern-based-illustrations-from-naoko-horiguchi/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/tutumu-cheerful-pattern-based-illustrations-from-naoko-horiguchi/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 18:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Philip Kennedy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Illustration]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56493</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This work by Japanese artist Naoko Horiguchi is so bright and cheerful &#8211; I just love it! Horiguchi&#8217;s motto is &#8220;to try out anything&#8221;, and a quick visit to her website proves that she does exactly that. Creating work in collage, inks, acrylics and rubber-stamps, her work is always fun and playful. Personally, I love [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Naoko-Horiguchi-Tutumu-1.png" alt="Naoko Horiguchi - Tutumu" width="800" height="566" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56531" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Naoko-Horiguchi-Tutumu-4.png" alt="Naoko Horiguchi - Tutumu" width="800" height="566" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56534" /></p>
<p>This work by Japanese artist <a href="http://h-mahoroba.net/">Naoko Horiguchi</a> is so bright and cheerful &#8211; I just love it! Horiguchi&#8217;s motto is &#8220;to try out anything&#8221;, and a quick visit to her <a href="http://h-mahoroba.net/">website</a> proves that she does exactly that. Creating work in collage, inks, acrylics and rubber-stamps, her work is always fun and playful.</p>
<p>Personally, I love her pattern-based series <em>tutumu+</em>. &#8220;Tutumu&#8221; is the Japanese word for wrapping and Horiguchi says that these illustrations are printed on A3 kraft paper so they&#8217;re ideal for gift wrapping as well as for hanging on your wall. You can view the full set online <a href="http://h-mahoroba.net/work_3_0.html">here</a>.</p>
<p><span id="more-56493"></span><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Naoko-Horiguchi-Tutumu-3.png" alt="Naoko Horiguchi - Tutumu" width="800" height="566" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56533" /></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//Naoko-Horiguchi-Tutumu-5.png" alt="Naoko Horiguchi - Tutumu" width="800" height="566" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56535" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/tutumu-cheerful-pattern-based-illustrations-from-naoko-horiguchi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Desktop Wallpaper Project featuring Brock Davis (1/2)</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/the-desktop-wallpaper-project-featuring-brock-davis-12/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/the-desktop-wallpaper-project-featuring-brock-davis-12/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 17:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bobby Solomon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Desktop Wallpaper Project]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56846</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Brock Davis 1280&#215;800 1440&#215;900 1680&#215;1050 1920&#215;1200 2560&#215;1440 iPhone iPhone 5 iPad I&#8217;m super excited for our wallpaper today as it features the work of one of the most creative guys out there, Brock Davis. I first noticed Brock&#8217;s work through his first Make Something Cool Everyday project back in 2009, where he turned everyday objects [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//brock-davis-wallpaper-1-blog.jpg" alt="The Desktop Wallpaper Project featuring Brock Davis (1/2)" width="800" height="500" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56847" /></p>
<h3><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/the-desktop-wallpaper-featuring-brock-davis/">Brock Davis</a></h3>
<aside id="wallpaper" class="group">
<ul>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-1-1280x800.jpg" class="btn_download">1280&#215;800</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-1-1440x900.jpg" class="btn_download">1440&#215;900</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-1-1680x1050.jpg" class="btn_download">1680&#215;1050</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-1-1920x1200.jpg" class="btn_download">1920&#215;1200</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-1-2560x1440.jpg" class="btn_download">2560&#215;1440</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-1-iphone.jpg" class="btn_download">iPhone</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-1-iphone5.jpg" class="btn_download">iPhone 5</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thefoxisblack.com/desktop-wallpaper/brock-davis-wallpaper-1-ipad.jpg" class="btn_download">iPad</a></li>
</ul>
</aside>
<p>I&#8217;m super excited for our wallpaper today as it features the work of one of the most creative guys out there, <a href="http://www.itistheworldthatmadeyousmall.com/" title="Brock Davis">Brock Davis</a>. I first noticed Brock&#8217;s work through his first <a href="http://www.itistheworldthatmadeyousmall.com/46341/247088/projects/make-something-cool-every-day-2009">Make Something Cool Everyday project back in 2009</a>, where he turned everyday objects into pieces of art. This <a href="http://behance.vo.llnwd.net/profiles/87066/projects/2131660/870661232393204.jpg">honey bear image</a> is still one of the funniest things I&#8217;ve ever seen before.</p>
<p>Cut to the beginning of January when Jon and I were speaking about <a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/01/07/the-build-up-episode-4/">our favorite Instagrammers on The Build Up</a>, and we mentioned Brock, and how great his Instagram feed is, and how rad it would be if he did a wallpaper. Since the Internet is the smallest place on earth I was introduced to Brock through <a href="http://michaelcinaassociates.com/" title="Michael Cina">Michael Cina</a>, and like magic, he was down to do a wallpaper&#8230; or two. Today&#8217;s wallpaper is honest and hysterical, and I hope you enjoy it. </p>
<p>Be sure to check back every Wednesday for a new wallpaper!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/the-desktop-wallpaper-project-featuring-brock-davis-12/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Rusty Surf Shack: Third Wave Kiosk in Australia</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/a-rusty-surf-shack-third-wave-kiosk-in-australia/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/a-rusty-surf-shack-third-wave-kiosk-in-australia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 15:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alex Dent</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56821</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As the more pale areas of the country are experiencing near-record low temperatures, I&#8217;m pretending it&#8217;s summer all week long. We started the week looking at a warm and modern lake house and yesterday saw iterations on the theme of a pool house. Today we&#8217;re looking at a rusty surf shack. Designed by Tony Hobba Architects, it&#8217;s not just [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//third-wave-kiosk-5.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56835" alt="Tony Hobba Architects Beach Kiosk Australia Architecture" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//third-wave-kiosk-5.jpeg" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
<p>As the more pale areas of the country are experiencing near-record low temperatures, I&#8217;m pretending it&#8217;s summer all week long. We started the week looking at a <a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/25/pretending-its-summer-glen-lake-tower-by-balance-associates-architects/">warm and modern lake house</a> and yesterday saw <a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/26/in-florida-nl-architects-propose-pool-houses-for-a-canadian-entrepreneur/">iterations on the theme of a pool house</a>. Today we&#8217;re looking at a rusty surf shack.</p>
<p><span id="more-56821"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//third-wave-kiosk-1.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56838" alt="Tony Hobba Architects Beach Kiosk Australia Architecture" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//third-wave-kiosk-1.jpeg" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//third-wave-kiosk-3.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56837" alt="Tony Hobba Architects Beach Kiosk Australia Architecture" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//third-wave-kiosk-3.jpeg" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
<p>Designed by <a href="http://hobba.com/">Tony Hobba Architects</a>, it&#8217;s not just a rusty surf shack, but a small building that serves as a gourmet coffee shop, a restroom, and a changing facility for beach goers. On second thought, I&#8217;m not sure if this even qualifies as a surf shack, but I&#8217;m at a loss to figure out what it should be called. Just a rusty concession stand? A metal cabana you can pee in? There are clear disadvantages to my growing up so far inland.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s remarkable about this small project is that it was constructed using left over pleated steel plates that usually are driven below grade to help build sturdy foundations. These particular bits of pleated steel were used in a less conventional but more relevant way durring the 2011 Victorian floods to help control water from the Murray River. And now they make the walls of this small beach kiosk. It&#8217;s a smart solution that utilizes waste as a resource, and a surprisingly sophisticated use of it at that.</p>
<p>These walls will continue to patina as they react to the saline environment of the beach. These walls will also warm in the light of the sun, which will accelerate the deterioration of the structural skin. It&#8217;s almost as if the project was trying desperately to get a tan.</p>
<p><small>Found through <a href="http://inhabitat.com/tony-hobba-architects-third-wave-kiosk-in-australia-is-made-from-recycled-sheet-piling/">Inhabitat</a></small></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/a-rusty-surf-shack-third-wave-kiosk-in-australia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Milk Carton Kids Redefine Contemporary Folk</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/the-milk-carton-kids-redefine-contemporary-folk/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/the-milk-carton-kids-redefine-contemporary-folk/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 15:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Andi Teran</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56819</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Contrary to their title, The Milk Carton Kids are neither a gang of tragic youth rescued from long forgotten cardboard dairy cartons or are they a gang at all. Armed only with acoustic guitars, they&#8217;re a folk music duo from Eagle Rock, California, consisting of  Kenneth Pattengale and Joey Ryan, and their music is swiftly [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/the-milk-carton-kids-redefine-contemporary-folk/milk-carton-kids/" rel="attachment wp-att-56820"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56820" alt="The Milk Carton Kids" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//milk-carton-kids.jpg" width="800" height="601" /></a></p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F78428564&amp;color=000000&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>Contrary to their title, <a href="http://www.themilkcartonkids.com/">The Milk Carton Kids</a> are neither a gang of tragic youth rescued from long forgotten cardboard dairy cartons or are they a gang at all. Armed only with acoustic guitars, they&#8217;re a folk music duo from Eagle Rock, California, consisting of  Kenneth Pattengale and Joey Ryan, and their music is swiftly being hailed as the second coming of contemporary folk. You might want to pipe up and decree that Mumford &amp; Sons own this title or, perhaps, The Lumineers, but I can assure you that in the sternest of definitions of old-school folk (down to their vintage 1950s guitars), The Milk Carton Kids are the realest of deals.</p>
<p>They&#8217;re already being compared to Simon &amp; Garfunkel, due in part to their arrestingly harmonious dual melodies and deft guitar arrangements, but upon further listen they&#8217;re not too shabby at spinning a lyrical yarn either. They also have a Gus van Sant seal of approval with &#8220;Promised Land&#8221;, a somber and beautiful track used in the director&#8217;s film by the same name. And, what&#8217;s more, they&#8217;ve chosen to release their first two albums for free. Nothin&#8217; old-school about that at all. Their new album, <em>The Ash &amp; Clay</em>, is out this week.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/27/the-milk-carton-kids-redefine-contemporary-folk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What are the top 10 things that we should be informed about, in life?</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/26/what-are-the-top-10-things-that-we-should-be-informed-about-in-life/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/26/what-are-the-top-10-things-that-we-should-be-informed-about-in-life/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bobby Solomon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56812</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I came across this thread on Quora about the top 10 things that we should be informed about in life and found the answers of Justin Freeman, pastor of a small evangelical church in southern Missouri, to be quite amazing. I found myself nodding along to everything that Freeman had written, but here are two [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//top-10-life-lessons.jpg" alt="Top 10 Life Lessons" width="800" height="800" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56813" /></p>
<p>I came across <a href="http://www.quora.com/Life/What-are-the-top-10-things-that-we-should-be-informed-about-in-life#ans2267532">this thread on Quora</a> about the top 10 things that we should be informed about in life and found the answers of <a href="http://www.quora.com/Justin-Freeman" title="Justin Freeman">Justin Freeman</a>, pastor of a small evangelical church in southern Missouri, to be quite amazing. I found myself nodding along to everything that Freeman had written, but here are two points that I thought were particularly poignant.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>3. Spend your life with rulebreakers.</strong> Marry them. Befriend them. Work with them. Spend weekends with them. No matter how much power you become possessed of, you&#8217;ll never be able to make someone care—so gather close the caring.</p>
<p><strong>5. Money is expensive.</strong> I mean, it&#8217;s difficult to get your hands on sometimes—and you never know when someone&#8217;s going to pull the floorboards out from under you—so don&#8217;t be stupid with it. Avoid debt on depreciating assets, and never incur debt in order to assuage your vanity (see rule number one). Debt has become normative, but don&#8217;t blithely accept it as a rite of passage into adulthood—debt represents imbalance and, in some sense, often a resignation of control. Student loan debt isn&#8217;t always unavoidable, but it isn&#8217;t a given—my wife and I completed a combined ten years of college with zero debt between us. If you can&#8217;t avoid it, though, make sure that your degree is an investment rather than a liability—I mourn a bit for all of the people going tens of thousands of dollars in debt in pursuit of vague liberal arts degrees with no idea of what they want out of life. If you&#8217;re just dropping tuition dollars for lack of a better idea at the moment, just withdraw and go wander around Europe for a few weeks—I guarantee you&#8217;ll spend less and learn more in the process.
</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/26/what-are-the-top-10-things-that-we-should-be-informed-about-in-life/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Setting the Standard with Fort Standard</title>
		<link>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/26/setting-the-standard-with-fort-standard/</link>
		<comments>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/26/setting-the-standard-with-fort-standard/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 16:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Andi Teran</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?p=56767</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Simple and functional—this is the ethos of design studio Fort Standard. Founded in 2011 by Gregory Buntain and Ian Collings, the company specializes in everything from furniture design and home goods to innovative lighting and  jewelry pieces. They&#8217;re also responsible for store design including the new Steven Alan Home shop in NYC&#8217;s Tribeca neighborhood. I [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?attachment_id=56768" rel="attachment wp-att-56768"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56768" alt="Fort Standard trivets" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//fort-standard-trivets.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?attachment_id=56769" rel="attachment wp-att-56769"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56769" alt="Fort Standard vessels" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//fort-standard-vessels.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
<p>Simple and functional—this is the ethos of design studio <a href="http://fortstandard.com/">Fort Standard</a>. Founded in 2011 by Gregory Buntain and Ian Collings, the company specializes in everything from furniture design and home goods to innovative lighting and  jewelry pieces. They&#8217;re also responsible for store design including the new <a href="http://blog.stevenalan.com/2013/03/14/now-open-steven-alan-home-shop/">Steven Alan Home</a> shop in NYC&#8217;s Tribeca neighborhood.</p>
<p><span id="more-56767"></span></p>
<p>I first encountered Fort Standard&#8217;s work via their <a href="http://fortstandard.com/standard-pendant">Standard Pendant</a>, which I bought at a store in Brooklyn and wear religiously. It&#8217;s a deceivingly simple wooden disk with inlaid brass that seems to pair with every ensemble. I have since become a fan of the geometric stone trivets lined with leather as well as their beautifully made glass wooden vessels, which are perfect for holding various kitchen sundries like coffee beans. Aside from their wide range of home goods (have I mentioned bottle openers, magnets, and candlesticks?), Fort Standard cobbles furniture, too. And their spare stools, side tables, and linear floor lamps are equally as streamlined and arresting.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?attachment_id=56771" rel="attachment wp-att-56771"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56771" alt="Fort Standard bottle opener" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//fort-standard-bottle-opener.jpg" width="800" height="522" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?attachment_id=56770" rel="attachment wp-att-56770"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56770" alt="Fort Standard cage necklace" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//fort-standard-cage-necklace.jpg" width="800" height="522" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/?attachment_id=56777" rel="attachment wp-att-56777"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-56777" alt="Fort Standard elevate table" src="http://www.thefoxisblack.com/blogimages//fort-standard-elevate-table.jpg" width="800" height="1277" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.thefoxisblack.com/2013/03/26/setting-the-standard-with-fort-standard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
