<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Back2Stonewall</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com</link>
	<description>An Unapologetic LGBT News Site - We&#039;re HERE,. We&#039;re Queer, F#@king DEAL With It!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 09:32:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>More With Kylie Minogue And Her Support Of Her Gay Fans</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/kylie-minogue-support-gay-fans.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/kylie-minogue-support-gay-fans.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 02:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kylie Minogue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LOGO TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Now Next Awards]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23826</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For over two decades singer Kylie Minogue has been an inspiration to the gay community and has given her unwavering support of our rights. Tonight she is to be presented with a prestigious award by Scissor Sisters&#8217; Jake Shears to commemorate her contributions to music and her ability to transform her music to translate to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://mp3waxx.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/kylie_minogue-news-article2813-m.jpeg" width="368" height="277" /></p>
<p>For over two decades singer Kylie Minogue has been an <a href="http://www.newnownext.com/kylie-minogue-to-receive-dance-floor-hero-award-at-logo-newnownext-awards/04/2013/">inspiration</a> to the gay community and has given her unwavering support of our rights. Tonight she is to be presented with a prestigious award by Scissor Sisters&#8217; Jake Shears to commemorate her contributions to music and her ability to transform her music to translate to all generations. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/kylie-minogue-newnownext-gay-fans_n_3087012.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>The pop diva, 44, spoke to Willam and Louis Virtel about her “<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Abbey-Road-Sessions-Kylie-Minogue/dp/B0096I9UTE/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1366056508&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=Kylie+Minogue+Abbey+Road" target="_hplink">Abbey Road Sessions</a>” album, which was released last year. She also gave Willam a special tweet thrill.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>In February, it was announced that Minogue <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/06/kylie-minogue-roc-nation-jay-z-label_n_2631861.html" target="_hplink">would join the ranks</a> of Jay-Z, Willow Smith, J. Cole and Rita Ora on the Roc Nation label.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>The Logo NewNowNext Awards 2013 will be air on Logo on April 15 at 10 p.m./9 p.m. central time.</em></strong></p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/kylie-minogue-support-gay-fans.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>MI City Gay Rights Ordinance Thwarted, For Now.</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/mi-city-gay-rights-ordinance-thwarted-now.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/mi-city-gay-rights-ordinance-thwarted-now.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 02:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tim Franco</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23825</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Recently in the city of Royal Oak, MI, the city passed a human rights ordinance that made it illegal for all business within the city to discriminate against LGBT people. The new law was to go into effect March, 2013, but a few business owners and some citizens of Royal Oak decided to start a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Royal-Oak.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-23828" alt="Royal Oak" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Royal-Oak-300x204.jpg" width="300" height="204" /></a>Recently in the city of Royal Oak, MI, the city passed a human rights ordinance that made it illegal for all business within the city to discriminate against LGBT people.</p>
<p>The new law was to go into effect March, 2013, but a few business owners and some citizens of Royal Oak decided to start a petition to block the law from going into effect.</p>
<p>According to <a href="http://www.pridesource.com/article.html?article=59418" target="_blank">Pride Source/Between The Line</a> (a Metro Detroit LGBT publication), it appears that enough petition signatures were turned in at Royal Oak City Hall on April 2, to prevent the new ordinance to go into effect. This petition may force the ordinance to go before the voters in November of this year.</p>
<p>One Royal Oak resident, Fred Birchard, 75, who campaigned against a similar ordinance in 2001, told the <a href="http://www.freep.com/" target="_blank">Detroit Free Press </a> that he turned in 1,200 signatures, almost twice the minimum 746 needed to block the enactment of the ordinance.</p>
<p>If enough of the signatures are validated by the Royal City Clerk, then the city commissioners will take up the ordinance at their April 15 meeting. At that meeting, they will decide whether to drop the ordinance altogether  or vote to place it on the November ballot.</p>
<p>Local residents, such as openly gay city commissioner Jim Rasor and local business owners are not happy that the ordinance has been blocked.</p>
<p>Jim Rasor stated that if the signatures are validated, he has a high level of confidence that the commission will vote to put the ordinance on the ballot in November.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We have a democratic process and if that [a] number of voters thinks it should be put to a vote in November, then so be it,&#8221; said Rasor. &#8220;In listening to Mr. Birchard, he thinks God talks to him directly and that what he thinks God says to him trumps civil Law.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Rasor is also a well know attorney in Royal Oak and is often attained in LGBT discrimination cases because Federal, State and Local laws do not recognize basic rights of LGBT people (perfect example of the importance of ENDA).</p>
<p>Raso states -</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;If someone&#8217;s boss walks into their office and fires them because the boss just found out they are gay, then I have no recourse under current Federal and State law.&#8221; He goes on to say, &#8220;that just feels un-American to me.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Many residents and business owners have their own opinion regarding the blockage of the ordinance -</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I&#8217;m not pleased it was thwarted,&#8221; said Keith Howarth, owner of Noir Leather in Royal Oak. &#8220;I feel it&#8217;s a small minority of the older Royal Oak population and not representative at all of the new Royal Oak population. I think it is ignorant of the people who are thwarting it. It&#8217;s 2013 and we need to understand that there is diversity among us and everyone is welcome in Royal Oak.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;My partner and I were proud as citizens of Royal Oak that the city commissioners had made a wise and just decision,&#8221; said Kate Wade who has lived in Royal Oak with her partner, Eileen Brandeis, for over 25 years. &#8220;We question why when a governing body has made a decision in favor of equality for a minority group it can be challenged by an individual and put to a majority vote.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Royal Oak would have been the 22nd city in Michigan to enact a non-discrimination ordinance. The neighboring city of Ferndale, which has hosted Detroit&#8217;s <a href="http://motorcitypride.org/" target="_blank">Motor City Pride</a> for years until  it was recently moved to Downtown Detroit, passed an ordinance several years ago and Pleasant Ridge, another neighboring city, discussed a similar ordinance at their city council meeting April 9.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I&#8217;m disappointed that residents went the petition route,&#8221; said Dave Coulter, mayor of Ferndale who specifically addressed a frequent objection to non-discrimination ordinances that enactment uses valuable policing resources. &#8220;I spoke before the Royal Oak Commission (when they were considering the ordinance) and shared our experience in Ferndale. There have been very few incidents that involved the police. In fact quite the opposite. Passing the ordinance is one of the reasons that Ferndale has been as successful as we have been because it says to everyone that we are diverse and welcome everyone.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>If the ordinance goes to popular vote in November, it will be up to the business owners and residents to educate the residents of Royal Oak on the importance of a law of this nature.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The challenge to the ordinance represents a small number of voters in Royal Oak. Royal Oak overwhelmingly supports fairness and equality, as the commission did and voters will in November,&#8221; said Jon Hoadley, director of Unity Michigan Coalition, a group that represents six of the largest LGBT organizations in Michigan.</p>
<p>&#8220;I can&#8217;t speak too much (about anti-LGBT sentiments) because <a href="http://www.five15.net/" target="_blank">Five 15</a> does so well with our alternative show,&#8221; said Gary Baglio, owner of Five 15 Store in downtown Royal Oak. &#8220;Our Drag Queen Bingo is so wildly popular that I hope it will help educate people as to why it&#8217;s so important to support this ordinance.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Personally speaking as someone who lives local to Royal Oak and Ferndale, both cities have always been incredibly diverse and extremely accepting of LGBT people. <a href="http://five15.net/" target="_blank">Five 15 bookstore</a> is an amazing LGBT bookstore located in the heart of Royal Oak and is incredibly popular with customers of all kinds. The city of Ferndale has always done what ever they could to help support the fight for LGBT equality. I have every faith that not only will this ordinance get voted to go to a popular vote in November, but the residents of Royal Oak will all stand up and tell their city that they ARE in favor of a non-discrimination act.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/mi-city-gay-rights-ordinance-thwarted-now.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deadly Explosions Rock Boston Marathon, 2 Dead, 26 Injured, Many In Critical Condition &#8211; Video</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/deadly-explosions-rock-boston-marathon-2-dead-26-injured-critical-condition-video.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/deadly-explosions-rock-boston-marathon-2-dead-26-injured-critical-condition-video.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 20:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boston Marathon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Explosion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Horrible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Newton Massacre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patriots Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tcot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terrorism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23820</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Eyewitnesses report &#8220;unspeakable horror&#8221; after two explosions went off near the finish line of the Boston Marathon  at Copley Square on Monday in what could be the first major case of domestic or foreign terrorism since 9/11. So far 2 people are reported dead and over 23 injured, at least 6 critically  according to the Boston Police Department.  [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eyewitnesses report &#8220;unspeakable horror&#8221; after two explosions went off near the finish line of the Boston Marathon  at Copley Square on Monday in what could be the first major case of domestic or foreign terrorism since 9/11.</p>
<p>So far 2 people are reported dead and over 23 injured, at least 6 critically  <a href="https://twitter.com/Boston_Police">according to the Boston Police Department</a>.  Marathon organizers said that bombs caused the two explosions and Boston Police have confirmed the discovery of two more unexploded bombs in the area.</p>
<p>Daniel Lampariello, a college student who was at the finish line, told CBSNews.com that people were trampling each other after the pair of explosions.</p>
<p>&#8220;It sounded like a large firework or M-80,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Competitors and race organizers were crying as they fled the chaos. Bloody spectators were being carried to the medical tent that had been set up to care for fatigued runners.</p>
<p>There were two &#8220;incredibly powerful explosions just seconds apart,&#8221; according to WBZ-TV&#8217;s Lis Hughes.</p>
<p>Law-enforcement sources said at least the first explosion occurred in the lobby of the Fairmont Hotel in Copley Square.</p>
<p>President Obama has been notified of the explosions and he has directed his administration to provide whatever assistance is necessary in the investigation and response.</p>
<p>Law-enforcement sources said at least the first explosion occurred in the lobby of the Fairmont Hotel in Copley Square.</p>
<p>Authorities have a suspect, who is currently being guarded in a Boston hospital with shrapnel wounds and are scouring surveillance video tape from the area looking for more suspects.</p>
<p>The Marathon this year was dedicated to the memory of those lost in the Newtown Massacre.  Relatives of the victims were among those attending the race finish at a VIP area. It was not known of any of the relatives were among the casualties.</p>
<p>Simply horrible.</p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/rfCK3Ar7Yus?rel=0" height="250" width="450" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/deadly-explosions-rock-boston-marathon-2-dead-26-injured-critical-condition-video.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Louis C.K. Implies That Gay Men Are Pedophiles In His Latest HBO Special</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/louis-c-k-implies-pedophiles-gay-men-latest-hbo-special.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/louis-c-k-implies-pedophiles-gay-men-latest-hbo-special.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad gay jokes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GLAAD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Louis CK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offensive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pedophiles]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23810</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Louis C.K.‘s new comedy special, Oh My God, premiered on HBO Saturday night with one joke totally backfiring as C.K using a stereo typical gay effete voice implied that pedophiles are gay . C.K.’s &#8220;humor&#8221; turned to the offensive when describing his New York City apartment building, C.K. reflected on the fountain in the courtyard that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Louis-CK.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23813" alt="Louis CK" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Louis-CK.png" width="300" height="171" /></a></strong></p>
<p><strong>Louis C.K.</strong>‘s new comedy special, <em>Oh My God</em>, premiered on HBO Saturday night with one joke totally backfiring as C.K using a stereo typical gay effete voice implied that pedophiles are gay .</p>
<p>C.K.’s <em>&#8220;humor&#8221;</em> turned to the offensive when describing his New York City apartment building, C.K. reflected on the fountain in the courtyard that features “marble boys pissing”:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>What is it with fountains? Like, all fountain-sculptors are pedophiles, basically. You can’t get a fountain-made without — ‘Can you make me a fountain?’ [Response in stereotypical gay male's, sexually aroused voice:] ‘Yes, I’ll get started right away! Aaaaggh… AAGGGH, yes!!! YES!!! It’s fi-nished!’ And [the commissioned fountain] is just little boys pissing on the face of a Greek god that looks like him a lot? [again in stereotypical gay male's, sexually aroused voice, while mimicking standing under the fountain's boy]: ‘Ahhh, piss on me forever!!!’</em></p></blockquote>
<p>To make matters worse C.K. used the  stereotypical gay male’s voice to the joke preceding this one in which he spilled some water on his shirt while taking a quick swig, mincingly saying: “<em>Oh sh*t. G*d damn it! Idiot. This isn’t a gay voice by the way. It’s NOT! Shut UP!” </em>But it was.</p>
<p>Look. Some things aren&#8217;t funny and just plain wrong and the fact that fact that C.K. himself has advocated for gay marriage, and <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/entertainment/2011/12/louis-c-k-says-gay-community-lost-opportunity-to-address-tracy-morgans-homophobic-comments-in-a-positive-way/" target="_blank">spoken</a> of the need to address homophobia, makes his remarks all the more disturbing.</p>
<p>But to C.K. obviously addressing homophobia stops when making crass unfunny jokes on the stage.  In 2011 when comedian <strong>Tracy Morgan</strong> joked that he would stab his son if he were gay, Louis C.K. was the first to  <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/06/15/louis-ck-defends-tracy-morgan-twitter_n_877373.html#s292385&amp;title=Louis_CK" target="_blank">came to Morgan’s defense</a></p>
<p>These types of jokes are unacceptable and used to to get a laugh from uneducated idiots by lazy comedians.  Just as racial jokes are.   If C.K thinks they are okay perhaps he should go get a real job and  go tell those jokes at work, and then we&#8217;ll see  how long he&#8217;ll last.</p>
<p><em>GLAAD. Hellooooooo</em>?  Where is the outrage over this?  Or is HBO a donor?</p>
<p>You can watch the video clip of C.K.&#8217;s HBO Saturday and the gay pedophilia joke over at <a href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/did-louis-c-k-imply-pedophiles-are-gay-men-in-his-latest-hbo-special/">Mediate.com</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/louis-c-k-implies-pedophiles-gay-men-latest-hbo-special.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>HBO Filming New Gay-Centric Pilot That Resembles Sex In The City</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/hbo-filming-gay-centric-pilot-resembles-sex-city.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/hbo-filming-gay-centric-pilot-resembles-sex-city.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23809</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;ve been feeling like there&#8217;s a lack of comedies centered around the lives of gay men then you may be in luck. In what appears to be a blend of girl power and sex appeal of Girls and Sex In The City, HBO has developed and began filming a pilot in San Francisco depicting the lives [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/rainbow-flag650.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-23811" alt="rainbow-flag650" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/rainbow-flag650-300x150.jpg" width="300" height="150" /></a></p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve been feeling like there&#8217;s a lack of comedies centered around the lives of gay men then you may be in luck. In what appears to be a blend of girl power and sex appeal of Girls and Sex In The City, HBO has developed and began filming a pilot in San Francisco depicting the lives of several gay thirty somethings navigating through their lives with laughter. Here&#8217;s more</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>It&#8217;s an idea so obvious that it&#8217;s shocking it hasn&#8217;t been done before&#8211;a gay version of &#8220;Sex and The City&#8221; set in, of course, San Francisco.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>The comedic pilot was penned for HBO by Michael Lannan, who previously served as a producer on James Franco&#8217;s controversial documentary <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2352488/" target="_hplink">Interior. Leather Bar.</a> and stars Jonathan Groff, best known for playing Jesse St. James in Glee.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>According to Mission Local, the show tells the story of three gay friends&#8211;an artist, a restaurateur and a web game developer&#8211;<a href="http://missionlocal.org/2013/04/hbo-is-in-the-nighborhood/" target="_hplink">navigating the perils and pitfalls</a> of life and love in San Francisco&#8217;s trendy Mission District.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;"><em>Out.com <a href="http://www.out.com/entertainment/popnography/2012/12/21/hbo-gay-series-girls" target="_hplink">reports</a>:</em></strong><br />
<strong style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;"><em>Just like its Girls and Sex and the City predecessors, this untitled project features a group of friends as they try to find footing in a concrete jungle. But these boys are a bit older than their Girls counterparts, so here’s to hoping for less woe-is-me angst and more adult-driven trivialities.</em></strong><br />
<strong style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;"><em> </em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>As always I welcome fresh, new entertaining aspects of the LGBT community being showcased for the masses as we have been lacking in that area. I don&#8217;t even care if the show seems to glorify the stereotypes that are widely believed by society. The more visibility. even when there are vagrant portrayals of inaccurate stereotypes, the more we promote discussion. That is something I will always advocate.</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s the thing, if this is just another shallow superficial gabfest that does nothing to actually show the depth and complexity of the characters, or at the very least show us why they are these stereotypes they&#8217;re portraying then I&#8217;ll pass. I don&#8217;t care if the premise of the show is to be funny and lighthearted causing all kinds of hi-jinx as that is fine by me. But these characters cannot be all about sex and drinking, no matter how pro-sex I am, because in reality no one is that way all the time. Not even those that say they are actually are 24/7. And if these characters are saying and acting like they&#8217;re all about sex and partying, show me <strong><em>why</em></strong> that person acts that way. That&#8217;s how I know I would be able to root for them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/hbo-filming-gay-centric-pilot-resembles-sex-city.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Week In Gay History April 14 &#8211; 20:   DaVinci, The Boys, Abe Lincoln and the Gay Titanic</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/week-gay-history-april-14-20.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/week-gay-history-april-14-20.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 14:12:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Davinci]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lincolm was gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Boys In The Band]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Titanic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[who knew?]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23800</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[April 14 April  14, 1865 &#8211; President Lincoln is shot and mortally wounded by John Wilkes Booth while attending the comedy &#8220;Our American Cousin&#8221; at Ford&#8217;s Theater in Washington, D.C. He passes away the next day. C..A. Tripp&#8217;s book The Intimate World of Abraham Lincoln makes the case that Lincoln had several homosexual relationships throughout [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Gay-Titanic.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23801" alt="Gay Titanic" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Gay-Titanic.png" width="300" height="186" /></a></p>
<h2><strong>April 14</strong></h2>
<p><strong>April  14, 1865</strong> &#8211; President Lincoln is shot and mortally wounded by John Wilkes Booth while attending the comedy &#8220;Our American Cousin&#8221; at Ford&#8217;s Theater in Washington, D.C. He passes away the next day.</p>
<p>C..A. Tripp&#8217;s book <a href="http://erclk.about.com/?zi=15/e5Y" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">The Intimate World of Abraham Lincoln</a> makes the case that Lincoln had several homosexual relationships throughout his life.</p>
<p>Tripp states that Lincoln&#8217;s relationships with women were either invented by biographers (his love of Ann Rutledge) or were desolate botches (his courtship of Mary Owens and his marriage to Mary Todd). Tripp is not the first to argue that Lincoln was secretly gay &#8211; earlier writers have parsed his friendship with Joshua Speed, the young store owner he lived with after moving to Springfield, Ill.</p>
<p><a href="http://query.nytimes.com/gst/fullpage.html?res=9f05e5d61439f93aa35752c0a9639c8b63">Lincoln&#8217;s story becomes interesting when Tripp looks at 1831,</a> when Lincoln was 22, and moved to New Salem, an Illinois frontier town, where he met Billy Greene. Greene coached Lincoln in grammar and shared a narrow bed with him. &#8221;When one turned over the other had to do likewise,&#8221; Greene told Herndon. Bed-sharing was common enough in raw settlements, but Greene also had vivid memories of Lincoln&#8217;s physique: &#8221;His thighs were as perfect as a human being could be.&#8221;</p>
<p>Six years later, Lincoln moved to Springfield, where he met Joshua Speed, who became a close friend; John G. Nicolay and John Hay, two early biographers, called him &#8221;the only &#8212; as he was certainly the last &#8212; intimate friend that Lincoln ever had.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>April 14, 1904</strong> - British actor John Gielgud is born in London. Perhaps the greatest actor to grace a stage in the English-speaking  world, Gielgud never came out publicly. Privately he gave large sums of money to gay rights organizations like Stonewall.</p>
<p><strong>April 14th, 1912</strong> &#8211; The RMS Titanic struck an iceberg just before midnight.  At  11:40 pm ship&#8217;s time. Titanic sideswiped an iceberg and the glancing collision caused <i>Titanic</i>&#8216;s hull plates to buckle inwards along her starboard side and opened five of her sixteen watertight compartments to the sea.  By 2:20 AM, she broke apart and foundered,  taking  over one thousand three hundred people still aboard to their deaths.  Just under two hours after the <i>Titanic</i> foundered, the Cunard liner <a title="RMS Carpathia" href="/wiki/RMS_Carpathia">RMS <i>Carpathia</i></a> arrived on the scene of the sinking, where she brought aboard an estimated 705 survivors.</p>
<p>Were there gay passengers and crew on the Titanic at its time of sinking?  <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B006XNI73U/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B006XNI73U&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=back2stoncom-20">Of course there was.  There was lovers Michael Whitney, Edward Wedding, and Archibald Butts and even the working crew including the rugged Balkan Stoker, the redheaded Royal Purser Felix Jones,  ship’s </a><br />
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B006XNI73U/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B006XNI73U&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=back2stoncom-20">second carpenter Michael Brice and Third Officer Sam Maxwell. </a></p>
<p>You can watch Hugh Brewster, author of <em>‘RMS Titanic: Gilded Lives on a Fatal Voyage’</em> talks about the untold gay stories of the Titanic’s fatal maiden voyage by <a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/2012/04/forget-leo-kate-titanic-untold-gay-story-video.html"><strong>CLICKING HERE.</strong></a></p>
<p><strong>April 14, 1968</strong> &#8211; Mart Crowley&#8217;s play, &#8220;The Boys in the Band&#8221; opens on Broadway in New York. Considered to be a groundbreaking work in American theater, the first truly &#8220;honest&#8221; portrayal of the lives of contemporary homosexuals. It opened in New York on April 14, 1968, at the off-Broadway Theater Four and ran for 1002 performances before being adapted to a successful motion picture. At a time when gay characters were seldom seen in commercial media except as crude stereotypes, although later in history some in the LGBT community would say that is indeed what Crowley&#8217;s play presented</p>
<p>The setup is pure theatrics. A  melange of gay men assemble in the apartment of catholically damaged Michael for   the birthday celebration of Harold a   self-proclaimed <em>&#8220;32-year-old ugly pockmarked Jew fairy.&#8221;</em> These boys were the last ones chosen for P. E., and the first to survive by wits. Tribal unity has the ironic element of verbal onslaughts as Crowley glories in a subculture&#8217;s   artful engagement with its own dialect.</p>
<p>Then came the backlash to the backlash in the early 1990&#8242;s with a revival production by San Francisco&#8217;s Theater Rhino company when fearful of the characters images some LGBT advocates denounced it as <em>Uncle Tomism </em>because they were worried about the LGBT organizations attempts to assimilate the community into straight society ignoring what a groundbreaking piece of LGBT history the play was for the 1960&#8242;.</p>
<p><strong>April 14, 1983 </strong>- In the same year that Great Britain reports its first 17 cases of <a title="AIDS" href="/wiki/AIDS">AIDS</a> the only UK gay magazine, Gay News, stops publication.</p>
<p><strong>April 14, 1985</strong> &#8211; The first Gay Erotic Film Awards is held in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>April 15</strong></h2>
<p><strong>April 15, 1843</strong> - American writer Henry James is born in New York City. His biographer Leon Edel has endorsed a series of articles written by Richard Hall detailing the extent of James love for his brother the Harvard philosopher William James. Of Henry&#8217;s writing, Maugham summed it up<br />
best: &#8220;<em>I don&#8217;t think Henry James knew how ordinary people behave. His characters have neither bowels nor sexual organs.</em> (In his books) people do not go away, they depart, they do not go home but repair to their domiciles.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>April 15, 1894</strong> &#8211; Singer Bessie Smith is born in Chattanooga, Tennessee. In &#8220;Foolish<br />
Man Blues&#8221; Smith sang: &#8220;There&#8217;s two things got me puzzled, there&#8217;s two things I<br />
don&#8217;t understand; That&#8217;s a mannish-actin&#8217; woman, and a skippin, twistin&#8217; woman-actin&#8217; man.&#8221; Strange words for a woman whose best friend was male impersonator Gladys Fergusson and who had been introduced to the world of &#8216;women-lovin&#8217; women&#8217; by blues singer Ma Rainey.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>April 16</strong></h2>
<p><strong>April 16, 1453</strong> &#8211; Leonardo da Vinci is born near Florence, Italy. When he was 24 he was<a href="http://www.bnl.gov/bera/activities/globe/leonardo_da_vinci.htm"> accused of having sex with a 17-year-old youth of &#8220;questionable&#8221; background. </a></p>
<p>Along with three other young men, he was anonymously accused of sodomy, which in Florence was a criminal offense, even though in most cases the authorities looked the other way and the general culture attached little social stigma to homosexuality.</p>
<p>The accusation specifically charged him with a homosexual interaction with one Jacopo Saltarelli, a notorious prostitute. The charges were brought in April, and for a time Leonardo and the other defendants were under the watchful eye of Florence&#8217;s <em>&#8220;Officers of the Night</em>&#8220;&#8211;a kind of renaissance vice squad.</p>
<p>However, the charges were dismissed in June, due to a lack of witnesses and evidence. It is probable that the Medici family brought had something to do with this outcome, as another of the defendants was Lionardo de Tornabuoni, and Lorenzo de Medici&#8217;s mother had been a Tornabuoni.</p>
<p>DaVinci never married or showed any (recorded) interest in women; indeed, he wrote in his notebooks that male-female intercourse disgusted him. His anatomical drawings naturally include the sexual organs of both genders, but those of the male exhibit much more extensive attention. Finally, Leonardo surrounded himself with beautiful young male assistants, such as Salai and Melzi.</p>
<p>This is a bit of gay history that is<a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/entertainment/tv/in-starzs-da-vincis-demons-a-young-leonardo-discovers-some-heat/2013/04/11/2fefa8e6-9e42-11e2-a2db-efc5298a95e1_story.html"> conveniently being <strong><em>straightwashed</em> </strong>out of Starz’new drama series, “Da Vinci’s Demons,”</a> where young and sexy Leonardo (Tom Riley), who also seems to have invented the stubble trimmer and Supercuts along the way to designing  the paraglider and the helicopter. shares the storyline and his bed with high-class Medici mistress Lucrezia Donadi (Laura Haddock) who does more than pose <em>(topless of course)</em> with Leonardo while he’s supposed to spend painting her portrait.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>April 17</h2>
<p><strong>April 17, 1863</strong> - C.V. Cavafy is born in Alexandria, Egypt. During his lifetime Cavafy was considered the poet of Alexandria. Today he is primarily identified with Lawrence Durrell&#8217;s<br />
characterization of him in the Alexandria Quartet.</p>
<p><strong>April 17, 1897</strong> &#8211; <a href="http://www.berkeleydailyplanet.com/issue/2008-12-18/article/31842">Thornton Wilder</a> is born in Madison Wisconsin. Best known as the writer of &#8220;Our Town&#8221;, Wilder suffered &#8220;writer&#8217;s block&#8221; finishing the last act of the play. His close friend, writer Samuel M. Steward helped him through it all as only gone good buddy can help another. <em>*wink wink - nudge nudge*</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>April 18</h2>
<p><strong>April 18, 382, BC</strong> - Phillip of Macedonia is born. Philip II was the military genius who defeated the combined armies of Athens and Thebes, conquering all of Greece. Along the way he availed himself of the 800 young eunuchs that had been brought with the army for his pleasure.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>April 19</h2>
<p><strong>April 19, 1967</strong> &#8211; <strong><em>The Student Homophile League of Columbia University</em> </strong>becomes the first gay group to obtain a campus charter.</p>
<p>The <em>SHL</em> had twelve members who fought with university administrators for a year before the group was officially recognized. Stephen Donaldson, a bisexual identified LGBT rights activist is commemorated by a plaque in the queer lounge that bears his name in one of Columbia&#8217;s residence halls for spearheading the creation of the group.</p>
<p>When the charter was ultimately granted in April 1967 it earned media attention with the <i>New York Times</i> printing a story on the front page, the <i>Columbia Daily Spectator</i> reported that some students believed that the creation of the group was an April Fool&#8217;s Day joke.</p>
<p>The group is still in existence to this day and is now called the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Columbia_Queer_Alliance"><em><b>Columbia Queer Alliance</b></em></a><br />
<strong>April 19, 1982</strong> &#8211; <a href="http://www.goalny.org/Home.html"><em>The Gay Officers Action League, Inc. </em><strong>(GOAL)</strong></a>  is founded by NYPD Sergeant Charles Cochrane and retired Detective Sam Ciccone establishing the first official police fraternal society in the world to represent LGBT people within the criminal justice system.</p>
<p>Cochrane, a 14 year veteran of the NYPD, created shock waves by testifying before a NYC Council hearing in favor of a gay rights bill. Following the testimony of a Patrolmen’s Benevolent Association Vice President, who denounced the bill and declared, &#8220;I didn’t know of any homosexual police officers.&#8221;, Cochrane stunned all present as well as NYC as a whole by his testimony: “<em>I am very proud of being a New York City Police Officer, and I am equally proud of being gay.”</em></p>
<p>In 1987, at the persistent urging of GOAL, the  NYPD began a concerted effort to actively enlist qualified gay candidates. In 2002, GOAL was admitted into COPS, The Committee of Police Societies, an organization consisting of all recognized NYPD religious, ethnic fraternal organizations.</p>
<p>Since its inception, GOAL has evolved not only as a fraternal organization, but also as an<br />
activist organization that represents the interests of its LGBT members in all agencies and branches within the criminal justice system.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>April 20</strong></h2>
<p><strong>April 20, 1492</strong> &#8211;  Renaissance writer and dramatist Pietro Aretino is born in Tuscany. The first well-known writer of his era his works are bawdy and pornographic, at least by the standards of the 15th century.  Aretino was a pioneer of the dirty book.  His book <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2003/aug/23/featuresreviews.guardianreview17"><em>The School of Whoredom</em> </a>is the dialogue between Nanna and her 14-year-old daughter, Pippa, on the tricks of the trade, (remember this is the 1400&#8242;s) it is highly sophisticated, while not only being a satire but also a sex manual.</p>
<p>Aretino is said to have died of a stroke laughing at a dirty joke.</p>
<p>What a way to go.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>The Boys In The Band Movie Trailer (1970)</strong></p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/3Zw4639Ztjs?rel=0" height="315" width="420" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/week-gay-history-april-14-20.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Meningitis Outbreak Leaves Man With Irreparable Brain Damage</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/meningitis-outbreak-leaves-man-irreparable-brain-damage.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/meningitis-outbreak-leaves-man-irreparable-brain-damage.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 00:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brett Shaad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disease prevention and treatment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health scare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meningitis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeHo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White Party]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23794</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the past few months there has been several reports from health professionals warning gay men to be mindful of the spread of the potentially deadly meningitis bacterial virus. Unfortunately the strain has spread and irreparably affected the life of a openly gay man by the name of Brett Shaad in West Hollywood who is [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/tumblr_mdd22wcspD1rzsckyo1_500.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-23798" alt="tumblr_mdd22wcspD1rzsckyo1_500" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/tumblr_mdd22wcspD1rzsckyo1_500-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>Over the past few months there has been several reports from health professionals warning gay men to be mindful of the spread of the potentially deadly meningitis bacterial virus. Unfortunately the strain has spread and irreparably affected the life of a openly gay man by the name of Brett Shaad in West Hollywood who is now brain dead. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/13/brett-shaad-meningitis_n_3076355.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices&amp;ir=Gay%20Voices">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>LOS ANGELES &#8212; A 33-year-old West Hollywood man who felt sickened by bacterial meningitis earlier this week has been declared brain dead amid warnings to sexually active gay men about the deadly strain of illness, officials said.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Brett Shaad was declared brain dead but remained on life support Friday afternoon, said Elizabeth Ashford, a spokeswoman for Shaad&#8217;s family. She declined to release further details.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>[John] Duran, who saw Shaad last weekend, described the openly gay man as being &#8220;robust and healthy&#8221; prior to Monday, when he began to feel sick.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>On Wednesday, he went into the emergency room. By Thursday, he was in a coma.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Earlier Friday, officials warned sexually active gay men to beware of the potentially deadly health threat because Shaad&#8217;s case was detected in Los Angeles County.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Tests were being done to see if the strain of illness is similar to the meningococcal infections that circulated among gay men in New York City and infected 22 people, resulting in seven fatalities, since 2010.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>The illness could be spread by sex and kissing but not by casual contact.</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">We need to be as educated as we possibly can about this outbreak that appears to be affecting gay men. What makes this all the more scary is that the symptoms resemble that of a common flu. It&#8217;s why it is vital for all of us to know about vaccination and prevention. Prevention goes a long way in stopping the spread of this virus and we all need to take it upon ourselves to be safe and protect those that we interact with sexually. </span></p>
<p>What the Center for Disease Control <a href="http://www.cdc.gov/features/meningococcal/">(CDC)</a> urges us all to do in case we suspect we have symptoms or possibly been with someone that has the bacterial strains to get tested immediately and be sure to tell your doctor or health professional why you believe you suspect it may be meningitis by listing your symptoms. Also be sure to be up to date on any and all booster shots for the vaccine.</p>
<p>All the information I&#8217;m providing is a paraphrasing of what we should all be doing just to be safe. This is in no way to incite panic from this story but we all have to be informed of what&#8217;s going on now so that we don&#8217;t see a snowball effect. So please let those around you know to be aware of the precautions they need to take and what symptoms to look out for in order to protect all of us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/meningitis-outbreak-leaves-man-irreparable-brain-damage.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nevada Senate Amends and Passes Gay-Marriage Bill</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nevada-senate-amends-passes-gay-marriage-bill.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nevada-senate-amends-passes-gay-marriage-bill.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 00:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tim Franco</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23795</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[According to lgbtqnation.com, Nevada&#8217;s State Senate has passed a legislative measure that will allow same-sex marriage in the state. This is one of the first steps needed in order to repeal the State&#8217;s constitutional same-sex marriage ban. On a party-line, 3-2 vote, the Senate Committee on Legislative Operations and Elections amended and passed Senate Joint [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Nevada-Marriage-Certificate.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-23796" alt="Nevada Marriage Certificate" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Nevada-Marriage-Certificate-300x199.jpg" width="300" height="199" /></a>According to <a href="http://www.lgbtqnation.com/2013/04/nevada-state-senate-committee-amends-passes-gay-marriage-bill/" target="_blank">lgbtqnation.com</a>, Nevada&#8217;s State Senate has passed a legislative measure that will allow same-sex marriage in the state. This is one of the first steps needed in order to repeal the State&#8217;s constitutional same-sex marriage ban.</p>
<p>On a party-line, 3-2 vote, the Senate Committee on Legislative Operations and Elections amended and passed Senate Joint Resolution 13. It not only repeals the state’s heterosexual definition of marriage, but says Nevada recognizes all marriages regardless of gender.</p>
<p>Laura Martin with Progressive Leadership Alliance of Nevada was quoted -</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;All people in Nevada deserve the freedom to marry&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Since this is a Constitutional Amendment,  this bill has to pass the state&#8217;s Legislature this year and in 2015 in order for it to be brought to the state&#8217;s voters in 2016.</p>
<p>The original proposal sought only to repeal language in the state constitution that defines marriage as between a man and a woman. But a late amendment adopted by the committee Thursday adds that the state “shall recognize marriages and issue marriage licenses, regardless of gender.”</p>
<p>Sen. Tick Segerblom, D-Las Vegas, who introduced the bill said -</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We felt it would be cleaner to both eliminate the current prohibition and make it clear Nevada does not discriminate in any way”</p></blockquote>
<p>The amendment drew opposition from Republican Sen. James Settelmeyer of Minden. Settelmeyer said he gave Segerblom his word that he would vote for the original bill but withdrew his support because of the new wording.</p>
<blockquote><p>“I don’t think the subject of marriage should be in the constitution,” Settelmeyer said. “This is adding something else in, and I can’t support that.”</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nevada-senate-amends-passes-gay-marriage-bill.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEW POLL &#8211; Majority of Americans Support Same-Sex Marriage</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/poll-majority-americans-support-same-sex-marriage.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/poll-majority-americans-support-same-sex-marriage.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 23:45:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tim Franco</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23788</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[According to a recent NBC/Wall Street Journal poll 2 weeks after the Prop. 8 and DOMA cases Supreme Court cases, Americans are 53% in favor of supporting same-sex marriage while 42% of Americans still oppose same-sex marriage. According to NBCnews.com, 53% of respondents who favor same-sex marriage is a 2 point increase from when the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/NBC-WSJ.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-23792" alt="NBC-WSJ" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/NBC-WSJ.jpg" width="300" height="195" /></a>According to a recent NBC/Wall Street Journal poll 2 weeks after the Prop. 8 and DOMA cases Supreme Court cases, Americans are 53% in favor of supporting same-sex marriage while 42% of Americans still oppose same-sex marriage.</p>
<p>According to <a href="http://firstread.nbcnews.com/_news/2013/04/11/17708688-nbcwsj-poll-53-percent-support-gay-marriage" target="_blank">NBCnews.com</a>, 53% of respondents who favor same-sex marriage is a 2 point increase from when the poll was last conducted in December, although the 2 points is within the poll&#8217;s margin of error. The 42% who are opposed is also a 2 point increase from last December.</p>
<p>When broken down by party, the follow results were shown -</p>
<ul>
<li>73% of Democrats and 54% of Independents support same-sex marriage</li>
<li>66% of Republicans oppose same-sex marriage</li>
</ul>
<p>79% of respondents say that they know or work with someone who is gay or lesbian. However, only 15 percent say that knowing or working with someone gay makes them more likely to back same-sex marriage; 4 percent say it makes them less likely to support it, and more than half say it doesn&#8217;t make a difference.</p>
<p>The poll also finds that 63 percent of respondents believe the federal government should recognize same-sex marriages in states where they are legal, and 56 percent think that the question of allowing gay marriage should be left to a federal standard rather than to the states.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/poll-majority-americans-support-same-sex-marriage.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gordon Klingenschmitt: Allowing Openly Gay NFL Players Will Cause Gay Coachs To Recruit Children</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/gordon-klingenschmitt-allowing-openly-gay-nfl-players-gay-coachs-recruit-children.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/gordon-klingenschmitt-allowing-openly-gay-nfl-players-gay-coachs-recruit-children.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 23:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bigots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gordon Klingenschmitt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lunatics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFL]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23787</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Disgraced and dishonorably discharged ex-Navy Chaplain and current lunatic Gordon Klingenschmitt is  sounding the alarm, warning that if NFL players come out as gay, youth coaches will start &#8220;recruiting children into the homosexual lifestyle and punishing Christians because they voice an opposition to that sort of thing in the locker room.&#8221; &#8220;I think the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Crazy-Kleinschmitt.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23789" alt="Crazy Kleinschmitt" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Crazy-Kleinschmitt.png" width="300" height="180" /></a></p>
<p>Disgraced and dishonorably discharged ex-Navy Chaplain and current lunatic Gordon Klingenschmitt is  <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IQqJk3tAebw">sounding the alarm</a>, warning that if NFL players come out as gay, youth coaches will start &#8220;recruiting children into the homosexual lifestyle and punishing Christians because they voice an opposition to that sort of thing in the locker room.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I think the Devil is afoot here,&#8221; <a href="http://youtu.be/l2ILJTH7Yl4">Klingenschmitt warned</a>, saying it &#8220;is a demonic use of the sporting industry&#8221;:</p>
<p>Klingenschmitt mouth may be anti-gay, but his hands and the sound of longing in his voice for the <em>&#8220;young, tough male athlete&#8221;</em> tells a completely different story.</p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/l2ILJTH7Yl4?rel=0" height="250" width="450" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/gordon-klingenschmitt-allowing-openly-gay-nfl-players-gay-coachs-recruit-children.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.428 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-16 09:57:12 -->
