<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Back2Stonewall</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com</link>
	<description>An Unapologetic LGBT News Site - We&#039;re HERE,. We&#039;re Queer, F#@king DEAL With It!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 21:24:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Watch the Live Action Dora the Explorer Movie with Modern Family&#8217;s Ariel Winter And A VERY Hunky Diego</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/watch-live-action-dora-explorer-movie-modern-familys-ariel-winter-hunky-diego.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/watch-live-action-dora-explorer-movie-modern-familys-ariel-winter-hunky-diego.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 21:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GayGeek - All Things Gay and Geeky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[College Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diego]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dora The Explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaygeek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23560</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[CollegeHumor.com has outdone itself with the Live Action Dora the Explorer movie: Dora the Explorer and the Destiny Medallion starring Modern Family&#8217;s Ariel Winter and Adrian Gonzalez as a VERY hunky Diego. Rated PG CollegeHumor&#8217;s Favorite Funny Videos &#160; CollegeHumor&#8217;s Favorite Funny Videos &#160; CollegeHumor&#8217;s Favorite Funny Videos &#160; &#160;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>CollegeHumor.com</em> has outdone itself with the <em><strong>Live Action</strong> </em>Dora the Explorer movie:<strong> Dora the Explorer and the Destiny Medallion</strong> starring Modern Family&#8217;s Ariel Winter and Adrian Gonzalez as a VERY hunky Diego.</p>
<p>Rated PG</p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.collegehumor.com/e/6874662" height="300" width="500" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
<div style="padding: 5px 0; text-align: center; width: 600px;">
<p><a href="http://www.collegehumor.com/videos/most-viewed/this-year">CollegeHumor&#8217;s Favorite Funny Videos</a></p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.collegehumor.com/e/6874663" height="300" width="500" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
<div style="padding: 5px 0; text-align: center; width: 600px;">
<p><a href="http://www.collegehumor.com/videos/most-viewed/this-year">CollegeHumor&#8217;s Favorite Funny Videos</a></p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.collegehumor.com/e/6874664" height="300" width="500" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
<div style="padding: 5px 0; text-align: center; width: 600px;">
<p><a href="http://www.collegehumor.com/videos/most-viewed/this-year">CollegeHumor&#8217;s Favorite Funny Videos</a></p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/watch-live-action-dora-explorer-movie-modern-familys-ariel-winter-hunky-diego.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NOM BUSTED: NOM Thanks The Chicago Bears For Their Support, Chicago Bears Deny Call NOM Liars</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nom-busted-nom-chicago-bears-support-chicago-bears-deny-call-nom-liars.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nom-busted-nom-chicago-bears-support-chicago-bears-deny-call-nom-liars.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 10:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Busted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago Bears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fucking liars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hate Groups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jennifer Roback Morse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[liars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[losers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NOM]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23554</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The National Organization for Marriage and its umbrella organization The Ruth Institute has been busted once again one of their lies yet after they claimed that the NFL football team the Chicago Bears support their anti-gay mission and have donated them items of memorabilia. From the Chicago Tribune: The Chicago Bears and former linebacker Brian Urlacher denied [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Jennifer-Roback-Morse.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23555" alt="Jennifer Roback Morse" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Jennifer-Roback-Morse.png" width="294" height="193" /></a></p>
<p>The <em>National Organization for Marriage</em> and its umbrella organization <em>The Ruth Institute</em> has been busted once again one of their<a href="http://www.chicagotribune.com/sports/football/bears/chi-chicago-bears-same-sex-marriage-20130403,0,4979361.story" target="_blank"> lies</a> yet after they claimed that the NFL football team the Chicago Bears support their anti-gay mission and have donated them items of memorabilia.</p>
<p>From the <i>Chicago Tribune</i>:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>The Chicago Bears and former linebacker Brian Urlacher denied any involvement Wednesday with the Ruth Institute &#8212; an affiliate of the National Organization For Marriage, which opposes same-sex marriage &#8212; after an online promotion for the institute stated a clear involvement of the team. In an advertisement for its June gala at an upcoming conference, the California-based group stated, &#8220;For now, you should know that we have two fabulous raffle items from the Chicago Bears Organization (and a huge THANK YOU to the Bears for supporting our message).&#8221; Below the statement are images of an autographed Urlacher jersey and an autographed black-and-white photo of deceased Hall of Fame running back Walter Payton. &#8220;I sign a lot of stuff for charity and I don&#8217;t always know where it goes,&#8221; Urlacher told the Tribune. &#8220;If I would have known it was for this cause, I wouldn&#8217;t have done it.&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>The Bears home office has released an official statement setting the record straight:</p>
<p><em>&#8220;The two items featured in The Ruth Institute gala invitation were<strong> personal donations</strong> to (President) Dr. Jennifer Roback Morse (pictured above). Neither was a club donation, nor do they represent the team&#8217;s view on any social issues. Any remarks stating otherwise are false.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Morse initially declined comment. But later the website dropped all references to the Chicago Bears at the team&#8217;s request, and Morse issued a statement: &#8220;The Ruth Institute is not working with the Chicago Bears organization or any of its players past or present to promote our upcoming auction. The memorabilia we are auctioning off was acquired by me personally, not through the team or players. We understand that the Chicago Bears organization takes no position on social issues, and we regret any confusion we may have caused on this point.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>Curses, foiled again Witchie Poo!</em></p>
<p>But then again NOM you have to lie.  I mean a signed Adam Corolla or Victoria Jackson item doesn&#8217;t really carry much clout now, does it.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/NOM-Chicago-Bears.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23556" alt="NOM Chicago Bears" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/NOM-Chicago-Bears.png" width="500" height="489" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nom-busted-nom-chicago-bears-support-chicago-bears-deny-call-nom-liars.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jada Pinkett-Smith Says She&#8217;d Support Her Children If They&#8217;re Gay</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/jada-pinkett-support-children-gay.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/jada-pinkett-support-children-gay.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 00:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black and gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civil rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evolution of gay rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gays in hiphop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jada Pinkett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jada Pinkett Smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magic Johnson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents of gay children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[race and homosexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Will Smith]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23546</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Coming off the heels of the story of Magic Johnson, who announced yesterday that he loves and supports his gay son, comes another well known and well liked celebrity discussing that she would have the same reaction as Johnson. Actress, mother of two, and wife of Will Smith, Jada Pinkett-Smith spoke with HuffPostLive today promoting [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://athleanx.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/jada-pinkett-smith-hairstyle.jpg" width="268" height="440" /></p>
<p>Coming off the heels of the story of Magic Johnson, who announced yesterday that he loves and supports his gay son, comes another well known and well liked celebrity discussing that she would have the same reaction as Johnson. Actress, mother of two, and wife of Will Smith, Jada Pinkett-Smith spoke with HuffPostLive today promoting a new film project and also to discuss what she would do if one of her children were gay. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/03/jada-pinkett-smith-support-gay-children_n_3007531.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>Actress and producer Jada Pinkett Smith dropped by Huff Post Live to chat about the new film she produced, &#8220;Free Angela And All Political Prisoners,&#8221; her marriage to Will Smith and raising children in Hollywood.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>When asked how she would respond if either of her children, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/07/08/jaden-smith-photos-2012_n_1644941.html" target="_hplink">Jaden</a> or <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/07/willow-smith-annie-will-smith_n_2637724.html" target="_hplink">Willow</a>, both stars themselves, came out as gay, she answered, &#8220;I would support [them]. For me, I just want my kids to be happy. As long as they&#8217;re happy&#8230; As long as they&#8217;re living the lives that fulfill them, I&#8217;m good.&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Pinkett Smith isn&#8217;t the first celebrity parent to speak out on offering support to gay children &#8212; potential or actual. Magic Johnson&#8217;s gay son, Earvin Johnson III, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/02/earvin-johnson-iii-magic-johnson-gay-son-boyfriend_n_2998117.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices" target="_hplink">was seen with his unidentified boyfriend</a> for the first time on Monday, April 1. Magic and his wife, Earlitha &#8220;Cookie&#8221; Kelly, told TMZ &#8220;[We] love EJ and support him in every way&#8230; We&#8217;re very proud of him.&#8221;</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>It&#8217;s also important to note that Pinkett discussed how older African Americans may still view homosexuality or as she referred to it as &#8220;alternative lifestyle&#8221; as a last resort which she passionately disagrees with. It is hard to decipher if Pinkett herself felt that being gay is a choice which is frustrating both as a blogger and a fan of her work and as a gay man. I hope if ever she is asked about this particular scenario she described in the clip that she clarifies what she meant.</p>
<p>We are seeing more and more celebrities and politicians that are African American speak up and support LGBT rights over the past year. No doubt as the result of President Obama&#8217;s evolution lends support to the theory of &#8220;not wanting to be the first to say it&#8221; is why we&#8217;ve seen this snowball effect in the media. Now more than ever we have seen rappers that were once known for their homophobic slurs in their lyrics speak out for gay rights. It&#8217;s interesting to see how the country has been so passionately interested in the opinion of African Americans on this issue when not too long ago, in any other social issue, the incentive  for answers towards this community may not have been so hard sought after.</p>
<p>While writing this I asked myself the question if I were writing this more because it leads into the discussion of Magic Johnson&#8217;s son, Earvin, coming out or if it is to show further proof that the African American community is not as homophobic as society sometimes depicts. A few theories may surround why this is a common belief, including the fact that as the African American community is seen as the last group in our nation&#8217;s history that has faxed oppression and discrimination (that does still exist). That in turn outrages some when African Americans that are homophobic from the LGBT community should understand the current struggle of the gay civil rights movement.</p>
<p>And unfortunately when a negative opinion is held by one member of a minority group, it is believed by the rest of society that all members of that community have the same beliefs. This is generalization and it is reflected on LGBT and African American community. That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so vital to share stories of this to show that now more than ever we all need to look at each other as individuals and not community that we are associated with as we are more than a category.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/jada-pinkett-support-children-gay.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>GLAAD Conveniently Forgets DOMA and DADT, To Give Bill Clinton &#8220;Advocate for Change&#8221; Award</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/glaad-conveniently-forgets-doma-dadt-award-bill-clinton-advocate-change-award.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/glaad-conveniently-forgets-doma-dadt-award-bill-clinton-advocate-change-award.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 22:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asskissers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill Clinton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GLAAD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GLAAD Sucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OMFG]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23541</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[OH COME ON! As if giving Anderson Cooper the Vito Russo Award and Brett &#8220;Rehearsals are for fags&#8221; Ratner the Ally of the Year Award wasn&#8217;t enough to make you think that someone is spiking GLAAD&#8217;s watercooler with LSD.  Today GLAAD announced today that they will honor Bill Clinton later this month at their Media Awards in Los Angeles. Via [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>OH COME ON!</strong></em></p>
<p>As if giving Anderson Cooper the <em>Vito Russo Award</em> and Brett &#8220;R<em>ehearsals are for fags&#8221;</em> Ratner the <em>Ally of the Year Award</em> wasn&#8217;t enough to make you think that someone is spiking <em>GLAAD&#8217;s</em> watercooler with LSD.  Today <em>GLAAD </em>announced today that they will honor Bill Clinton later this month at their <a href="http://www.glaad.org/mediaawards/losangeles" target="_blank">Media Awards</a> in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>Via press release:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Bill Clinton will receive GLAAD&#8217;s first Advocate for Change Award during the event. In 2011, Clinton advocated for marriage equality in New York, stating that &#8220;for more than a century, our Statue of Liberty has welcomed all kinds of people from all over the world yearning to be free. In the 21st century, I believe New York’s welcome must include marriage equality.” In 2012, he joined the Coalition to Protect North Carolina Families in working against North Carolina&#8217;s proposed Amendment One to ban marriage and civil unions for gay and lesbian couples. Most recently, he called for the Supreme Court to strike down the Defense of Marriage Act in an op-ed for The Washington Post.</em></p>
<p><em> During his administration, Clinton became the first U.S. President to appoint out gay and lesbian people to all levels of government. He appointed more than 150 including James Hormel as America&#8217;s first openly gay ambassador. During the height of the HIV/AIDS crisis, his administration convened the first White House Conference on the epidemic, created the national AIDS Policy Coordinator post, and expanded funding for research.  In 2002, his Clinton Health Access Initiative (CHAI) began as the Clinton HIV/AIDS Initiative to address the HIV/AIDS crisis in the developing world.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Who&#8217;s going to present him the award?  Ken Mehlman?</p>
<p>Really now have they forgotten that Bubba signed DOMA and DADT into law?</p>
<p>Look I know that was a long time ago and he&#8217;s changed and has now jumped on the bandwagon after he threw us under the bus <em>(although he&#8217;s still NEVER apologized for it)  </em>and I&#8217;m kinda okay with Bill now <em>(mostly because of Hillary),</em> but giving him an award?  <em><strong>REALLY?</strong></em></p>
<p>This is just one more example GLAAD&#8217;s  zero accountability and its own lack of sensitivity.  And once again provesits incessant need to ass-kiss and star fuck with celebrities and former presidents whose images need a makeover all for themselves and the almighty dollar and <strong>NOT</strong> for the greater good of the LGBT community.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div data-role="message-shadow"></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/glaad-conveniently-forgets-doma-dadt-award-bill-clinton-advocate-change-award.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NBA Legend Magic Johnson Lovingly Supports His Gay Son</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nba-legend-magic-johnson-lovingly-supports-gay-son.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nba-legend-magic-johnson-lovingly-supports-gay-son.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[activist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coming out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magic Johnson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents of lgbt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proud parent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23535</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Former NBA player for the LA Lakers turned activist Earvin &#8220;Magic&#8221; Johnson recently was asked about his 20 year old son, Earvin (also called EJ3) who was seen out in public with his boyfriend. The response from Magic Johnson is what we all hope our parents would have, complete love and support. Here&#8217;s more: Earvin [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://www.thinkfinity.org/servlet/JiveServlet/showImage/38-4128-2614/Earvin+Johnson+HeadShot.jpg" width="346" height="518" /></p>
<p>Former NBA player for the LA Lakers turned activist Earvin &#8220;Magic&#8221; Johnson recently was asked about his 20 year old son, Earvin (also called EJ3) who was seen out in public with his boyfriend. The response from Magic Johnson is what we all hope our parents would have, complete love and support. Here&#8217;s<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/02/earvin-johnson-iii-magic-johnson-gay-son-boyfriend_n_2998117.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices"> more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>Earvin Johnson III, one of Magic&#8217;s three children, <a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/02/magic-johnson-son-goes-public-with-boyfriend-dad-proud/" target="_hplink">stepped out hand-in-hand with his unidentified boyfriend</a> on Los Angeles&#8217;s Sunset Strip on Monday night, TMZ reports.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Although this is reportedly the first time Earvin, also known as EJ, and his boyfriend have been seen together publicly, there is nothing to suggest that he was not open about his sexuality prior to this.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>EJ is a 20-year-old student at New York University and <a href="http://sports.yahoo.com/blogs/nba-ball-dont-lie/magic-johnson-son-e-j-gay-parents-love-155040567--nba.html" target="_hplink">Magic and his wife, Earlitha &#8220;Cookie&#8221; Kelly, couldn&#8217;t be prouder</a> of him. &#8220;<a href="http://www.towleroad.com/2013/04/earvinjohnson.html" target="_hplink">Cookie and I love EJ and support him</a> in every way,&#8221; Magic told TMZ. &#8220;We&#8217;re very proud of him.&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>When Magic revealed he was HIV-positive in 1991, <a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2009/oct/24/sports/sp-heisler24" target="_hplink">rumors about his sexuality arose</a>. Instead of recoiling from the spotlight and the speculation, the former Los Angeles Lakers player used his celebrity to spread awareness and tolerance.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Back in 2008, Magic opposed California&#8217;s Proposition 8 &#8212; a clause that banned same-sex marriage in the state.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>&#8220;<a href="http://content.usatoday.com/communities/gameon/post/2008/11/782954/1#.UVreJKs6VTF" target="_hplink">Prop 8 singles out one group of Californians</a> to be treated differently &#8212; including members of our family, our friends, and our coworkers,&#8221; he said in a recorded telephone message sent to California voters. &#8220;That is not what California is about. So this Tuesday, vote no on Proposition 8. It is unfair and wrong. Thanks.&#8221;</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>For over two decades Johnson has set out to challenge and defy the stereotypes of HIV. Not only has this man showed a great example of being an involved activist in promoting awareness, prevention and treatment, he is also a devoted and loving father.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nba-legend-magic-johnson-lovingly-supports-gay-son.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ronald Reagan&#8217;s Son Demands Bigots Fight Gay Marriage: &#8216;Where&#8217;s the Moral Outrage?&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/ronald-reagans-son-demands-bigots-fight-gay-marriage-wheres-moral-outrage.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/ronald-reagans-son-demands-bigots-fight-gay-marriage-wheres-moral-outrage.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 23:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bigot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Douchebag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Reagan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ronald Reagan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23531</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Proving that the homophobic douchebag doesn&#8217;t fall far from the tree, Michael Reagan, the former President&#8217;s and murders son, is upset about the recent shift in support for marriage equality and oh so very bitter that his fathers homophobic legacy is dwindling. &#8220;Fox TV, Rush Limbaugh and other talk-show pundits have weighed in, arguing the conservative [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Micheal-Reagen-asshole.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23532" alt="Micheal Reagen asshole" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Micheal-Reagen-asshole.png" width="300" height="184" /></a></p>
<p>Proving that the homophobic douchebag doesn&#8217;t fall far from the tree, Michael Reagan, the former President&#8217;s and murders son, <a href="http://www.irontontribune.com/2013/04/02/churches-time-to-fight-back/" target="_self">is upset about the recent shift in support for marriage equality</a> and oh so very bitter that his fathers homophobic legacy is dwindling.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;Fox TV, Rush Limbaugh and other talk-show pundits have weighed in, arguing the conservative — and moral — position that sanctifying gay marriage with the grace of the U.S. Constitution is not only wrong but a serious threat to the culture of this country.</em></p>
<p><em>But those media outlets often speak to those who are already in the choir. That leaves a lot of other Americans who aren’t hearing anyone preaching the conservative argument on gay marriage.</em></p>
<p><em>I don’t expect the GOP to provide any leadership. Republicans are too busy cat-fighting with each other and making sure their presidential choice will be whooped by Hillary Clinton in 2016.</em></p>
<p><em>And where in the heck are the churches on the issue of legalizing gay marriage?</em></p>
<p><em>Where are the Protestants, Jews and Catholics? Have they lost their tongues? Their hearts and wills? Their institutional you-know-whats?</em></p>
<p><em>Where’s the moral outrage? Why aren’t thousands of our pastors, priests and rabbis shouting from their pulpits? Why aren’t they leading their congregations through the streets in mass protest?</em></p>
<p><em>This fight over Proposition 8 isn’t just about saying it should be legal in the eyes of government for two people of the same sex to get married in California. It’s ultimately about changing the culture of the entire country; it inevitably will lead to teaching our public school kids that gay marriage is a perfectly fine alternative and no different than traditional marriage. There is also a very slippery slope leading to other alternative relationships and the unconstitutionality of any law based on morality. Think about polygamy, bestiality, and perhaps even murder. Churches should be in the vanguard of the fight to defend the culture against legalized gay marriage, not hiding in their pews.&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Just to clarify.  Micheal is the son of Reagan&#8217;s first wife, Jane Wyman from a different marriage. Where is the outrage? Why didn&#8217;t Michael scream and shout when his parents tore asunder their sacred marriage vows?</p>
<p>Mikey must have some serious unresolved issues about daddy loving Ron Jr. more.</p>
<p>But never fear Micheal I am sure you&#8217;ll be playing canasta in hell with Daddy someday.</p>
<div data-role="message-shadow"></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/ronald-reagans-son-demands-bigots-fight-gay-marriage-wheres-moral-outrage.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Michigan GOP Official: Gays &#8216;Will Prey On Our Children!&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/local-michigan-gop-official-gays-must-prey-children.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/local-michigan-gop-official-gays-must-prey-children.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 19:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>John Becker</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anita Bryant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundamentalist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundamentalists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary Helen Sears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michigan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[propaganda]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23523</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Mary Helen Sears, Vice Chair of the First Congressional District of the Republican Party of Michigan, posted a bigoted rant on the website of the Schoolcraft County GOP on Sunday. Sears&#8217;s screed, ominously titled &#8220;End of the GOP?,&#8221; begins as follows: We find ourselves at a precipice, wide and gaping, its darkness, seemingly never-ending. We [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=154447851383988&amp;set=a.154446888050751.1073741828.153725724789534&amp;type=3&amp;permPage=1" rel="attachment wp-att-3250"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-3250" style="margin: 8px;" alt="mary_helen_sears" src="http://www.johnmbecker.com/content/uploads/2013/04/mary_helen_sears.jpg" width="140" height="208" /></a>Mary Helen Sears, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=154447851383988&amp;set=a.154446888050751.1073741828.153725724789534">Vice Chair</a> of the First Congressional District of the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/GOP1stDistrict">Republican Party of Michigan</a>, posted a bigoted <a href="http://schoolcraftrepublican.info/end-of-the-GOP/">rant</a> on the website of the Schoolcraft County GOP on Sunday.</p>
<p>Sears&#8217;s screed, ominously titled &#8220;End of the GOP?,&#8221; begins as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>We find ourselves at a precipice, wide and gaping, its darkness, seemingly never-ending. We have a choice to make. Do we follow the Truth of the Living God, who’s principles and teachings are the foundation of this country or do we follow the dictates of a depraved society and fall headlong, off the cliff, into the abyss below?</p></blockquote>
<p>Sears excoriates the Republican Party for misinterpreting St. Ronald the Great&#8217;s &#8220;big tent idea,&#8221; then launches into a paragraphs-long stream-of-consciousness tirade in which she incorporates everything from Charles Darwin, the Kansas-Nebraska Act, and &#8220;Communist [university] Professors&#8221; to &#8220;Hitler&#8217;s Third Reich, Mussolini&#8217;s Italy and Stalin&#8217;s Russia.&#8221; (Yup, <a href="http://knowyourmeme.com/memes/godwins-law">she went there</a>.)</p>
<p>Then, in the longest section of Sears&#8217;s manifesto devoted to any one particular issue, she attacks Teh Gay.</p>
<blockquote><p>Marriage is a covenant between a man and a woman. It is a reflection of God and his Church. The promise that when this horror show we call life is over, we will once again be reunited with the God of this Universe. <strong>The joining of two men or two women is a perversion of this Covenant and a direct affront to God. Satan uses homosexuality to attack the living space of the Holy Spirit, which is the body of the person.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>&#8220;This horror show we call life?&#8221; What a sad, scary world Ms. Sears must be living in in order for her to describe her life in this manner. This happily married gay man pities her.</p>
<p>Sears continues:</p>
<blockquote><p>Paul says in 1 Corinthians 3:16-17,”Know ye not that ye are the temple of God, and that the Spirit of God dwelleth in you? If any man defile the temple of God, him shall God destroy; for the temple of God is holy, which temple ye are.”</p>
<p>By perverting the Covenant he keeps those who practice it away from God. He knows his time is limited, the more of us he takes to hell with him and the more pain he causes God by destroying His people the better he likes it. God says of homosexuality:</p>
<p>” Thou shalt not lie with mankind, as with womankind: it is abomination.” Leviticus 18:22</p>
<p>“If a man also lie with mankind, as he lieth with a woman, both of them have committed an abomination: they shall surely be put to death; their blood shall be upon them.” Leviticus 20:13</p>
<p>How then can we as Christians stay in a party that adopts Homosexuality into the fabric of the tent. I say we cannot. <strong>Homosexuals make up less than one percent of the total population. They must prey on our children to increase their numbers. Why then, would we, as a party, entertain this perversion? We as a party should be purging this perversion and send them to a party with a much bigger tent.</strong> When we lose track of foundational principles we lose the very essence of our party. By throwing God under the bus we become nothing more than the poor Democrats who have lost their way and by doing so have lost their party. They are nowhere near the party of Andrew Jackson or John Kennedy. They have opened the tent so wide that it no longer provides them a shelter or a solid base upon which to place their platform. I’m sure you all watched when the DNC voted whether to keep God in their party. Three times they voted Him down and someone who knew they would be raked over the coals by their throwing God to the curb, over road the crazed masses and declared the vote for God. Boos were loudly audible. The Democrats Boo’d God! [<strong>emphases mine</strong>]</p></blockquote>
<p>It hardly needs to be said, but for the record, the whole &#8220;gays recruit children&#8221; myth harkens back to the days of Anita Bryant and has been so <a href="http://www.splcenter.org/get-informed/intelligence-report/browse-all-issues/2010/winter/10-myths">thoroughly discredited</a> that there&#8217;s no need for me to devote any space here to that pursuit.</p>
<p>Sears&#8217;s knuckle-dragging homophobic rant shows that her hairstyle isn&#8217;t the only thing about her that&#8217;s stuck in the 1980s. But if you&#8217;re tempted to dismiss Sears as an isolated Northwoods bigot, think again: as of this writing, her blog post has earned 126 &#8220;likes&#8221; on Facebook.</p>
<p>Cross-posted on my blog, <a href="http://www.johnmbecker.com/2013/04/02/local-michigan-gop-official-gays-must-prey-on-our-children/">johnmbecker.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/local-michigan-gop-official-gays-must-prey-children.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is He A Top Or A Bottom?</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/find-bottom.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/find-bottom.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 01:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinions and Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communication in gay relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay conflicts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay couples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay femininity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay interactions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay kiss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay labels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay masculinity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay norms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay perceptions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay Sex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay sex positions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay sex roles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay social apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay stereotypes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grindr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growing up gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hetero-normative behaviors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heteronormative practices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internalized misogyny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masculinity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misogyny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[out of the closet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self hate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self worth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexual preferences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stereotypes of the gay community]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23456</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today while attempting to research for something to blog about I came across this article in the Advocate titled, Six Reasons Why it Sucks to Be a Gay Man, that discussed the different ways that being gay has its downfalls. Never mind the negative tone the name of the article has as it is apparent after reading the first two paragraphs that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter" alt="bitchybottoms" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/bitchybottoms.png" /></p>
<p>Today while attempting to research for something to blog about I came across this article in the Advocate titled, <a href="http://www.advocate.com/commentary/tyler-curry/2013/03/29/op-ed-six-reasons-why-it-sucks-be-gay-man"><em>Six Reasons Why it Sucks to Be a Gay Ma</em><em>n</em><b>, </b></a>that discussed the different ways that being gay has its downfalls. Never mind the negative tone the name of the article has as it is apparent after reading the first two paragraphs that the author was satirically making a point through humor and I can&#8217;t fault him for that.</p>
<p>However there was one particular point on the list that really frustrated me. Maybe frustrate is too strong a word as it&#8217;s not so much that I have hostility towards this point, but rather I question the point itself. It talked about how not knowing a potential partner&#8217;s sexual role early on can pose problems later on in the relationship. The author <a href="http://www.advocate.com/commentary/tyler-curry/2013/03/29/op-ed-six-reasons-why-it-sucks-be-gay-man">implies</a> how it sucks when two gay men get together and are dating only later to find out that they are first in fact bottoms:</p>
<blockquote><p><em><strong>4. “Wait … we are both bottoms?”</strong></em></p>
<p><em><b>It’s the third date and you have been on your best behavior with that gorgeous man across the dinner table.  That means no “sexting,” no more than two cocktails, and nothing below the waist … until now.</b></em></p>
<p><em><b>You think, Finally, this is how dating is supposed to be! You didn’t meet on Grindr or sleep with each other on the first date. You have the same taste in music and even talked about how you both want kids. Everything is perfect!</b></em></p>
<p><em><b>That is, until things finally start heating up and your thighs keep wanting to go in the same direction as his. After a frustrating make-out session and an awkward discussion in the nude, the reality of your preferred position becomes apparent. Even if one of you may be more “versatile” than the other, you are both bottoms.</b></em></p>
<p><em><b>So there went the wedding bells, but it could be worse. At least you have a new shopping pal.</b></em></p></blockquote>
<p>This of course would cause problems in any relationship when you have a preference to a specific sexual role; if you&#8217;re not into it, you just aren&#8217;t. But the first thought I had when I read this point is why would this information be something that you would find out on the third date? When is the right time to ask this question.</p>
<p>And I know that most already know the answers to this question depending on their own experience or belief in common sense but some of us are not as clear on parameters because of inexperience. Or the fact that as the more men you interact with, the sooner you realize that the answer is not as clear cut as you once believed.</p>
<p>Because despite what the media, and sometimes what our own beliefs about the validity in stereotypes of gay men, we know deep down that we are a very diverse group of men so you can&#8217;t just go by appearance. Or how they walk. Or how they talk. Their profession. All of these demographics don&#8217;t automatically tell you this crucial information that will at some point will mean something to both of you.  And despite their popularity, we don&#8217;t always have the convenience of social dating apps like Grindr to blatantly list what are our sexual preferences.</p>
<p>Some may be saying right now, <em>&#8220;all that stuff doesn&#8217;t matter, it&#8217;s all about the connection&#8221;</em>. Well like it or not sex is a component of that connection. Granted, it is not the only connection two people can share with each other or the only way to physically express affections for one another but it is still an important part to intimacy. Remember that as men we react first by what they see, so we also base our future behaviors on what we see in the present and foreseeable future.</p>
<p>You may have sex on the first date or may not have sex for the first six months of dating someone new, but a lot of the attraction may be centered on how you were attracted to him in the first place. So the discussion needs to happen at some point well before you make it to the bedroom one night to take your relationship further. So this will come up at some point.</p>
<p>But the question is of course when. When do approach sex roles in potential partners? So how would you approach the matter if it weren&#8217;t so apparent? Would you bluntly ask? Going up to someone and saying hi, I&#8217;m (insert name) and I&#8217;m wanted to know if you&#8217;re a top or bottom&#8221; probably won&#8217;t go over too smoothly. We can all appreciate a direct inquiry but you&#8217;re more than likely to offend someone with a question that is so intimate and  private.</p>
<p>Would a better way to approach the dilemma be to enact on a series of vague questions to find out the answer? What an icebreaker that could be, if done correctly. There&#8217;s drawback to that as well. A lot of guys do not like these types of long-winded, mull around the bush questions (including myself). After a while they can come off as condescending and suggests that you are too much the inquisitor rather than potential lover.</p>
<p>Maybe the best approach would be a combination of the first two scenarios. But instead of asking them, under no uncertain terms declaring what sexual role you prefer. For instance at some point providing information about your own preferred sexual role (without being vulgar or inappropriate), you suggest how much you love leading your dance partner on the floor and doing a very sensual rumba. And that doesn&#8217;t have to include actually discussing sex itself. But that can be seen as being too forward.</p>
<p>Maybe that approach is too forward as well, suggesting cockiness and that you just assumed what you believe is their sexual role. the whole guessing game and these tactics you employ can be tiresome. Honestly I don&#8217;t think this situation of later on finding out two guys are both bottoms happens that often as natural chemistry will express what each of your roles are. So maybe listening is the true key. Maybe there are subtle indications that can help that we don&#8217;t pay attention to often. Maybe that was what the author was suggesting.</p>
<p>I believe it&#8217;s important to ask why we have such a hard time approaching this topic in the first place. The biggest reason is the result of what the roles themselves imply. Being a top implies masculinity and strength as well as dominance while being the bottom signifies submissive, feminine attributes. One of the problems arises is when we take those sexual roles we assign ourselves outside the bedroom and apply it to everyday life.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s no secret that in the gay community that the bottom is the brunt (no pun intended) of many jokes. And is seen as a negative attribute, especially by those that carry heteronormative practices of misogyny into the gay community. That means they, like chauvinistic men in the rest of society associate anything feminine as being weak.</p>
<p>We can blame it on media, or upbringing as much as we want but the truth is we are responsible for correcting those ill-conceived beliefs into the community. As I&#8217;ve stated <a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/02/reltionshipds.html">before</a>, we have to take accountability for not repeating the mistakes we advocate against. Basically, remember what I said earlier about every guy being different? That&#8217;s the most important thing you can do. And be honest in however you discuss it.</p>
<p>Lastly, don&#8217;t ever question what sexual role he says he prefers and take him at his word. Just the way you would want to not be scrutinized by whatever your preferred sexual role is for you.  If you either don&#8217;t believe or accept that then kindly move on to some other topic or someone else.</p>
<p>I won&#8217;t tell you which method is right or wrong because that is not my job description in this setting  However I will say to always remember how you want to be addressed when this question is asked of you and how you&#8217;d respond accordingly. The chemistry will say more than any line of questioning you can think up and provide you with the answer when necessary. And guys, always do it with respect. Perceive each man, regardless of the position he prefers, is still a man and a human being. Remember and respect that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/find-bottom.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Liberty Counsel&#8217;s &#8216;Fat Matt&#8221; Barber Is In A Tizzy Over SCOTUS: Gays Will Invade Liberty University!</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/liberty-counsels-fat-matt-barber.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/liberty-counsels-fat-matt-barber.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 23:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Douchebag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fat Matt Barber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idiot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liberty University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religious extremist]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23497</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;As soon as DOMA is overturned, the floodgates open. All of those  [state] constitutional amendments are wiped out and schools like Liberty University, for instance, and private organizations with Christian  ownership, we know the homosexual activists already have their gay  married people planning to come and apply to Christian universities so  that they will have [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><em><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Fat-Matt-Barber-Liberty-Counsel.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23498" alt="Fat Matt Barber Liberty Counsel" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Fat-Matt-Barber-Liberty-Counsel.png" width="300" height="185" /></a></em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;As soon as DOMA is overturned, the floodgates open. All of those  [state] constitutional amendments are wiped out and schools like Liberty University, for instance, and private organizations with Christian  ownership, we know the homosexual activists already have their gay  married people planning to come and apply to Christian universities so  that they will have a court challenge.  The persecution is going to run  rampant if gay marriage becomes the law of the land; there is just no  questioning and that is a big part of the motive behind it. If the federal government puts its official stamp of approval on  homosexual behavior and says that it&#8217;s equal to, in every way, natural  heterosexual behavior up to and including marriage, then that officially pits the federal government against those who hold a Judeo-Christian  worldview relative to sexual morality. We automatically become the  modern day racists.&#8221;</em> &#8211; Currently under Federal Investigation Liberty Counsel spokesdouche and ex-failed boxer <em><strong>Fat <a href="http://www.rightwingwatch.org/content/barber-if-doma-struck-down-it-will-be-criminalization-christianity" target="_blank">Matt Barber</a></strong></em></p></blockquote>
<p><strong><em>Riiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiight.</em></strong></p>
<p>Because you know 3rd rate Liberty University in bumfuck Virginia is every LGBT&#8217;s first choice for higher education. <strong>*snort*</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/liberty-counsels-fat-matt-barber.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>HRC Gets Busted, Denies, Then Apologizes for Mistreatment of Trans and Undocumented Activists</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/hrc-discriminates-scotus-hearing-discrimination.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/hrc-discriminates-scotus-hearing-discrimination.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 23:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tim Franco</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay inc.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HRC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HRC Sucks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23457</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[During the protest on the steps of the Supreme Court during the SCOTUS DOMA hearing, members of the LGBT organization GetEQUAL faced some unsettling discrimination. As anyone who has protested or joined a rally for LGBT rights knows, there are always protesters. Usually they are holding signs saying how God hates gays and that all [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/SCOTUS-DOMA.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-23458" alt="SCOTUS DOMA" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/SCOTUS-DOMA-300x224.jpg" width="300" height="224" /></a>During the protest on the steps of the Supreme Court during the SCOTUS DOMA hearing, members of the LGBT organization GetEQUAL faced some unsettling discrimination.</p>
<p>As anyone who has protested or joined a rally for LGBT rights knows, there are always protesters. Usually they are holding signs saying how God hates gays and that all gays are going to hell for being sinners. Well during the DOMA protests, transgender members of GetEQUAL faced discrimination from a group that they thought would be the last group in the world to discriminate, especially against transgender individuals..</p>
<p>According to an independent blog, <a href="http://oblogdeeoblogda.me/2013/03/29/activists-seeing-red-over-hrc-antics-at-scotus-hearings/" target="_blank">O-blog-dee-o-blog-da </a>, members of GetEQUAL were flying a  trans flag outside the Supreme Court building on the DOMA day and placed near the podium.  C.D. Kirven, GetEQUAL board member, was waving that trans flag most prominently when GetEQUAL, who were challenging Westboro Baptist Church, were told to remove their flag by members of the HRC. The HRC&#8217;s reason behind requesting GetEQUAL members to remove their flag was because they said Marriage Equality was not a &#8220;transgender issue&#8221;.</p>
<p>According to another website, <a href="http://www.bilerico.com/2013/03/hrc_and_the_trans_flag_incident.php?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+BilericoProject+(The+Bilerico+Project)" target="_blank">The Bilerico Project</a>, blogger Jerame Davis, who was at the event, reported the following on his blog:</p>
<blockquote><p>Through the bustle and the crowd, I could discern that the HRC staffer was discussing the transgender equality flag the young man was waving. It was clear the staffer wanted him to move or to stop displaying the flag. It was also clear that the young trans man holding the flag was at the edge of his training (and his wits) in dealing with the situation as was the staffer. The HRC staffer moved on just as we got within speaking distance, so we asked the man with the flag what had happened.</p>
<p>He told us that the staffer had been harassing him about his flag and that he wasn&#8217;t going to move. He told us the staffer had stopped on three occasions to ask him to move or stop displaying the flag. He also mentioned that the staffer had denigrated trans issues in some manner, but I know this staffer and I cannot imagine they have any sort of anti-trans animus, so I chalked that up to a misunderstanding.</p></blockquote>
<p>Since I first heard this story reported from a Tumblr post, I have been trying to get clarification on it. When the story first broke on Twitter via the Tumblr post, I found no other supporting information on the net to verify this happened. I spoke to a friend who is a huge supporter of the HRC, and although I feel his opinion was bias, he stated that he would couldn&#8217;t believe for a moment that the HRC would act in this manner.</p>
<p>Based on his reaction combined with my inability, at the time, to find information online to support this story, I decided I would email GetEQUAL and asked for clarification. I sent them an email on Thursday March 28. I mentioned in the email about what I had heard and sent them the Tumblr link I had found the story on. I asked them if any part of this story were true and if it were in fact the Human Rights Campaign that was involved in this. As of today, Sunday March 31, I hadn&#8217;t received a response back. I decided that I would send them a follow up email today asking again for clarification in the story. I told them in today&#8217;s email that I had heard that it could have been two possible organizations named HRC. One being the Human Rights Coalition and the other being of course the Human Rights Campaign. I did some research on the Human Rights Coalition, and from what I found, they are an advocacy group located in Pennsylvania who fights for the right of prisoners, not a group I would expect to be present during the DOMA protests. I have also decided I will be sending an email to the Human Rights Campaign asking for clarification in this story as well. Once I receive a response, if any, from either organization, I&#8217;ll make sure I pass it on to our readers on Back2Stonewall.</p>
<p>As I told GetEQUAL, unity and support of all is the only way we can move forward in our fight for LGBT rights.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>UPDATE</strong></span></p>
<p>I have received an update on this story. Today, Monday April 1, I received a response from the Human Rights Campaign. Yesterday after posting the article above, I decided to send an email to the HRC requesting clarification on the incident I reported about a member requesting a several transgender activists of GetEQUAL to remove their flag and also asking na &#8220;undocumented&#8221; activist was asked to edit his speech to hide part of who he is.</p>
<p>In the email to the HRC, I asked them if it were true that members of their organization were involved in the story reported above. Honestly, I didn&#8217;t even expect a response from the HRC. To my surprise, earlier today I did get an email in response to my email asking about the situation. This is what Jason Lott (Jason.Lott@hrc.org) emailed me the following as the HRC&#8217;s explanation to what had happened:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Thank you for contacting the Human Rights Campaign with your concern about last week’s Supreme Court rallies.</p>
<p>In the midst of a tremendously historic week for our community, two unfortunate incidents at the United for Marriage event at the Supreme Court last week have caused pain in the community.  In one case, a trans activist was asked to remove the trans pride flag from behind the podium, and in another, a queer undocumented speaker was asked to remove reference to his immigration status in his remarks.</p>
<p>HRC joined in a coalition statement on Friday apologizing for these incidents and the individuals involved have personally offered their apologies to those affected.  But to be perfectly clear, HRC regrets the incidents and offers our apologies to those who were hurt by our actions.  We failed to live up to the high standard to which we hold ourselves accountable and we will strive to do better in the future.  Through both our legislative and programmatic work, HRC remains committed to making transgender equality a reality.</p>
<p>Thank you again for taking the time to contact us with your perspective.  If you would like to read more about HRC’s work on transgender issues, please visit <a href="http://www.hrc.org/issues/transgender" target="_blank">http://www.hrc.org/issues/transgender</a>.  And if you have any additional questions or concerns please do not hesitate to contact us.</p>
<p>Respectfully,</p>
<p>The HRC Member Services team&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>I have to be honest and say at first, I was impressed with the speed of their response, that is until I realized that this was basically a &#8220;stock&#8221;, &#8220;PR&#8221; response that they probably sent to everyone who has inquired about this situation.</p>
<p>Lets back this whole situation up a bit. When this situation first happened and the story broke, the HRC signed on to the United For Marriage Coalition in an apology for the mistreatment of Trans and Undocumented Activists. According to <a href="http://thenewcivilrightsmovement.com/united-for-marriage-coalition-apologizes-for-mistreatment-of-trans-and-undocumented-activists-hrc-signs-on-then-denies/politics/2013/03/29/63826">The New Civil Rights Movement</a>, the HRC &#8211; a part of the coalition that also includes the National Gay &amp; Lesbian Task Force, Family Equality Council, GetEQUAL, Marriage Equality USA and the New Organizing Institute &#8211; signed on to a group apology, and then issued a separate statement DENYING that the mistreatment occurred. The statement/apology signed by the coalition stated -</p>
<blockquote><p>“Since the conclusion of the rallies on Wednesday, the coalition has learned about the mistreatment of a few individuals who were attending and speaking at the rallies,” United For Marriage’s statement notes:</p>
<p>In one case, a queer undocumented activist was asked to edit his speech to hide part of who he is. In another case, several activists were asked to lower the trans* pride flag in order to keep out of the scope of TV cameras.</p>
<p>We apologize for having caused harm to the individuals involved. Apologies are being made individually and collectively and we are working to make direct amends.</p></blockquote>
<p>After this statement was released by the Coalition, the HRC decided to backpedal, retracting their apology and actually denying any wrongdoing even happened! The HRC issued a separate statement stating -</p>
<blockquote><p>“It was agreed that featuring American flags at our program was the best way to illustrate this unifying issue which is why when managing the area behind the podium, several people were asked to move who were carrying organizational banners, pride flags or any other flag that was not an American flag. Several people refused and they were allowed to stay. The coalition welcomed the variety of signs and flags that were throughout the plaza that demonstrated the wonderful diversity of our community.</p>
<p>“It is a not true to suggest that any person or organization was told their flag was less important than another – this did not occur and no HRC staff member would ever tolerate such behavior. To be clear, it is the position of the Human Rights Campaign that marriage is an issue that affects everyone in the LGBT community.</p>
<p>“The events at the Court featured lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender speakers as well as LGBT families, religious leaders, Republicans, military spouses and civil rights activists. This has been a historic week and truly demonstrated how all of us – lesbian, gay, bisexual and straight, transgender and cisgender – can unite as one voice to advocate for our constitutional rights.”</p></blockquote>
<p>How can anyone in the LGBT community trust the Human Rights Campaign at this point? In my opinion, they acted like children who were caught red handed getting into trouble. They gave a false apology and then lied to the very people they &#8220;claim&#8221; they are protecting and fighting for. In my opinion, I have lost all respect for the HRC. When I sent them the email last evening requesting clarification, I was hoping they would take the human approach and be honest and truthful. All I received was a stock, public relation answer to placate me. What they didn&#8217;t expect, or simply don&#8217;t care about is that that readers of Back2Stonewall as well as all of the rest of the LGBT community are intelligent individuals that can see right through the HRC&#8217;s lies and public relation B.S.</p>
<p>I sent them a response stating that they answer was not good enough for me or the readers of this blog or the listeners of my podcast. I specifically told them that I wanted to know why they thought they could get away with treating  fellow advocates in this manner and then denying it! I asked them if they have given proper discipline to the HRC members involved.</p>
<p>I am sad to say that I highly doubt I will hear a response at this point. Sadly, the HRC does not value my concern in this situation. This should show the entire LGBT community what type of organization the HRC really is. They are not concerned with the &#8220;everyday&#8221; LGBT advocate like myself. Since I am unable to donate large sums of money, my concern and opinion are worth very little to them. They made it incredibly obvious, in my opinion, that they value their LGBT followers very little since they can lie to us so easily.</p>
<p>I have made a point that I will not longer support the HRC until they come out clean and act like the honest organization and decent human beings as they should act.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/hrc-discriminates-scotus-hearing-discrimination.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.914 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-04 19:24:35 -->
