<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Back2Stonewall</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com</link>
	<description>An Unapologetic LGBT News Site - We&#039;re HERE,. We&#039;re Queer, F#@king DEAL With It!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 09:59:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Louis C.K. Implies That Gay Men Are Pedophiles In His Latest HBO Special</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/louis-c-k-implies-pedophiles-gay-men-latest-hbo-special.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/louis-c-k-implies-pedophiles-gay-men-latest-hbo-special.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad gay jokes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GLAAD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Louis CK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offensive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pedophiles]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23810</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Louis C.K.‘s new comedy special, Oh My God, premiered on HBO Saturday night with one joke totally backfiring as C.K using a stereo typical gay effete voice implied that pedophiles are gay . C.K.’s &#8220;humor&#8221; turned to the offensive when describing his New York City apartment building, C.K. reflected on the fountain in the courtyard that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Louis-CK.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23813" alt="Louis CK" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Louis-CK.png" width="300" height="171" /></a></strong></p>
<p><strong>Louis C.K.</strong>‘s new comedy special, <em>Oh My God</em>, premiered on HBO Saturday night with one joke totally backfiring as C.K using a stereo typical gay effete voice implied that pedophiles are gay .</p>
<p>C.K.’s <em>&#8220;humor&#8221;</em> turned to the offensive when describing his New York City apartment building, C.K. reflected on the fountain in the courtyard that features “marble boys pissing”:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>What is it with fountains? Like, all fountain-sculptors are pedophiles, basically. You can’t get a fountain-made without — ‘Can you make me a fountain?’ [Response in stereotypical gay male's, sexually aroused voice:] ‘Yes, I’ll get started right away! Aaaaggh… AAGGGH, yes!!! YES!!! It’s fi-nished!’ And [the commissioned fountain] is just little boys pissing on the face of a Greek god that looks like him a lot? [again in stereotypical gay male's, sexually aroused voice, while mimicking standing under the fountain's boy]: ‘Ahhh, piss on me forever!!!’</em></p></blockquote>
<p>To make matters worse C.K. used the  stereotypical gay male’s voice to the joke preceding this one in which he spilled some water on his shirt while taking a quick swig, mincingly saying: “<em>Oh sh*t. G*d damn it! Idiot. This isn’t a gay voice by the way. It’s NOT! Shut UP!” </em>But it was.</p>
<p>Look. Some things aren&#8217;t funny and just plain wrong and the fact that fact that C.K. himself has advocated for gay marriage, and <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/entertainment/2011/12/louis-c-k-says-gay-community-lost-opportunity-to-address-tracy-morgans-homophobic-comments-in-a-positive-way/" target="_blank">spoken</a> of the need to address homophobia, makes his remarks all the more disturbing.</p>
<p>But to C.K. obviously addressing homophobia stops when making crass unfunny jokes on the stage.  In 2011 when comedian <strong>Tracy Morgan</strong> joked that he would stab his son if he were gay, Louis C.K. was the first to  <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/06/15/louis-ck-defends-tracy-morgan-twitter_n_877373.html#s292385&amp;title=Louis_CK" target="_blank">came to Morgan’s defense</a></p>
<p>These types of jokes are unacceptable and used to to get a laugh from uneducated idiots by lazy comedians.  Just as racial jokes are.   If C.K thinks they are okay perhaps he should go get a real job and  go tell those jokes at work, and then we&#8217;ll see  how long he&#8217;ll last.</p>
<p><em>GLAAD. Hellooooooo</em>?  Where is the outrage over this?  Or is HBO a donor?</p>
<p>You can watch the video clip of C.K.&#8217;s HBO Saturday and the gay pedophilia joke over at <a href="http://www.mediaite.com/tv/did-louis-c-k-imply-pedophiles-are-gay-men-in-his-latest-hbo-special/">Mediate.com</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/louis-c-k-implies-pedophiles-gay-men-latest-hbo-special.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>HBO Filming New Gay-Centric Pilot That Resembles Sex In The City</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/hbo-filming-gay-centric-pilot-resembles-sex-city.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/hbo-filming-gay-centric-pilot-resembles-sex-city.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23809</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;ve been feeling like there&#8217;s a lack of comedies centered around the lives of gay men then you may be in luck. In what appears to be a blend of girl power and sex appeal of Girls and Sex In The City, HBO has developed and began filming a pilot in San Francisco depicting the lives [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/rainbow-flag650.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-23811" alt="rainbow-flag650" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/rainbow-flag650-300x150.jpg" width="300" height="150" /></a></p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve been feeling like there&#8217;s a lack of comedies centered around the lives of gay men then you may be in luck. In what appears to be a blend of girl power and sex appeal of Girls and Sex In The City, HBO has developed and began filming a pilot in San Francisco depicting the lives of several gay thirty somethings navigating through their lives with laughter. Here&#8217;s more</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>It&#8217;s an idea so obvious that it&#8217;s shocking it hasn&#8217;t been done before&#8211;a gay version of &#8220;Sex and The City&#8221; set in, of course, San Francisco.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>The comedic pilot was penned for HBO by Michael Lannan, who previously served as a producer on James Franco&#8217;s controversial documentary <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2352488/" target="_hplink">Interior. Leather Bar.</a> and stars Jonathan Groff, best known for playing Jesse St. James in Glee.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>According to Mission Local, the show tells the story of three gay friends&#8211;an artist, a restaurateur and a web game developer&#8211;<a href="http://missionlocal.org/2013/04/hbo-is-in-the-nighborhood/" target="_hplink">navigating the perils and pitfalls</a> of life and love in San Francisco&#8217;s trendy Mission District.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;"><em>Out.com <a href="http://www.out.com/entertainment/popnography/2012/12/21/hbo-gay-series-girls" target="_hplink">reports</a>:</em></strong><br />
<strong style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;"><em>Just like its Girls and Sex and the City predecessors, this untitled project features a group of friends as they try to find footing in a concrete jungle. But these boys are a bit older than their Girls counterparts, so here’s to hoping for less woe-is-me angst and more adult-driven trivialities.</em></strong><br />
<strong style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;"><em> </em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>As always I welcome fresh, new entertaining aspects of the LGBT community being showcased for the masses as we have been lacking in that area. I don&#8217;t even care if the show seems to glorify the stereotypes that are widely believed by society. The more visibility. even when there are vagrant portrayals of inaccurate stereotypes, the more we promote discussion. That is something I will always advocate.</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s the thing, if this is just another shallow superficial gabfest that does nothing to actually show the depth and complexity of the characters, or at the very least show us why they are these stereotypes they&#8217;re portraying then I&#8217;ll pass. I don&#8217;t care if the premise of the show is to be funny and lighthearted causing all kinds of hi-jinx as that is fine by me. But these characters cannot be all about sex and drinking, no matter how pro-sex I am, because in reality no one is that way all the time. Not even those that say they are actually are 24/7. And if these characters are saying and acting like they&#8217;re all about sex and partying, show me <strong><em>why</em></strong> that person acts that way. That&#8217;s how I know I would be able to root for them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/hbo-filming-gay-centric-pilot-resembles-sex-city.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Week In Gay History April 14 &#8211; 20:   DaVinci, The Boys, Abe Lincoln and the Gay Titanic</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/week-gay-history-april-14-20.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/week-gay-history-april-14-20.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 14:12:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Davinci]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lincolm was gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Boys In The Band]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Titanic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[who knew?]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23800</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[April 14 April  14, 1865 &#8211; President Lincoln is shot and mortally wounded by John Wilkes Booth while attending the comedy &#8220;Our American Cousin&#8221; at Ford&#8217;s Theater in Washington, D.C. He passes away the next day. C..A. Tripp&#8217;s book The Intimate World of Abraham Lincoln makes the case that Lincoln had several homosexual relationships throughout [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Gay-Titanic.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23801" alt="Gay Titanic" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Gay-Titanic.png" width="300" height="186" /></a></p>
<h2><strong>April 14</strong></h2>
<p><strong>April  14, 1865</strong> &#8211; President Lincoln is shot and mortally wounded by John Wilkes Booth while attending the comedy &#8220;Our American Cousin&#8221; at Ford&#8217;s Theater in Washington, D.C. He passes away the next day.</p>
<p>C..A. Tripp&#8217;s book <a href="http://erclk.about.com/?zi=15/e5Y" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">The Intimate World of Abraham Lincoln</a> makes the case that Lincoln had several homosexual relationships throughout his life.</p>
<p>Tripp states that Lincoln&#8217;s relationships with women were either invented by biographers (his love of Ann Rutledge) or were desolate botches (his courtship of Mary Owens and his marriage to Mary Todd). Tripp is not the first to argue that Lincoln was secretly gay &#8211; earlier writers have parsed his friendship with Joshua Speed, the young store owner he lived with after moving to Springfield, Ill.</p>
<p><a href="http://query.nytimes.com/gst/fullpage.html?res=9f05e5d61439f93aa35752c0a9639c8b63">Lincoln&#8217;s story becomes interesting when Tripp looks at 1831,</a> when Lincoln was 22, and moved to New Salem, an Illinois frontier town, where he met Billy Greene. Greene coached Lincoln in grammar and shared a narrow bed with him. &#8221;When one turned over the other had to do likewise,&#8221; Greene told Herndon. Bed-sharing was common enough in raw settlements, but Greene also had vivid memories of Lincoln&#8217;s physique: &#8221;His thighs were as perfect as a human being could be.&#8221;</p>
<p>Six years later, Lincoln moved to Springfield, where he met Joshua Speed, who became a close friend; John G. Nicolay and John Hay, two early biographers, called him &#8221;the only &#8212; as he was certainly the last &#8212; intimate friend that Lincoln ever had.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>April 14, 1904</strong> - British actor John Gielgud is born in London. Perhaps the greatest actor to grace a stage in the English-speaking  world, Gielgud never came out publicly. Privately he gave large sums of money to gay rights organizations like Stonewall.</p>
<p><strong>April 14th, 1912</strong> &#8211; The RMS Titanic struck an iceberg just before midnight.  At  11:40 pm ship&#8217;s time. Titanic sideswiped an iceberg and the glancing collision caused <i>Titanic</i>&#8216;s hull plates to buckle inwards along her starboard side and opened five of her sixteen watertight compartments to the sea.  By 2:20 AM, she broke apart and foundered,  taking  over one thousand three hundred people still aboard to their deaths.  Just under two hours after the <i>Titanic</i> foundered, the Cunard liner <a title="RMS Carpathia" href="/wiki/RMS_Carpathia">RMS <i>Carpathia</i></a> arrived on the scene of the sinking, where she brought aboard an estimated 705 survivors.</p>
<p>Were there gay passengers and crew on the Titanic at its time of sinking?  <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B006XNI73U/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B006XNI73U&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=back2stoncom-20">Of course there was.  There was lovers Michael Whitney, Edward Wedding, and Archibald Butts and even the working crew including the rugged Balkan Stoker, the redheaded Royal Purser Felix Jones,  ship’s </a><br />
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B006XNI73U/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B006XNI73U&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=back2stoncom-20">second carpenter Michael Brice and Third Officer Sam Maxwell. </a></p>
<p>You can watch Hugh Brewster, author of <em>‘RMS Titanic: Gilded Lives on a Fatal Voyage’</em> talks about the untold gay stories of the Titanic’s fatal maiden voyage by <a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/2012/04/forget-leo-kate-titanic-untold-gay-story-video.html"><strong>CLICKING HERE.</strong></a></p>
<p><strong>April 14, 1968</strong> &#8211; Mart Crowley&#8217;s play, &#8220;The Boys in the Band&#8221; opens on Broadway in New York. Considered to be a groundbreaking work in American theater, the first truly &#8220;honest&#8221; portrayal of the lives of contemporary homosexuals. It opened in New York on April 14, 1968, at the off-Broadway Theater Four and ran for 1002 performances before being adapted to a successful motion picture. At a time when gay characters were seldom seen in commercial media except as crude stereotypes, although later in history some in the LGBT community would say that is indeed what Crowley&#8217;s play presented</p>
<p>The setup is pure theatrics. A  melange of gay men assemble in the apartment of catholically damaged Michael for   the birthday celebration of Harold a   self-proclaimed <em>&#8220;32-year-old ugly pockmarked Jew fairy.&#8221;</em> These boys were the last ones chosen for P. E., and the first to survive by wits. Tribal unity has the ironic element of verbal onslaughts as Crowley glories in a subculture&#8217;s   artful engagement with its own dialect.</p>
<p>Then came the backlash to the backlash in the early 1990&#8242;s with a revival production by San Francisco&#8217;s Theater Rhino company when fearful of the characters images some LGBT advocates denounced it as <em>Uncle Tomism </em>because they were worried about the LGBT organizations attempts to assimilate the community into straight society ignoring what a groundbreaking piece of LGBT history the play was for the 1960&#8242;.</p>
<p><strong>April 14, 1983 </strong>- In the same year that Great Britain reports its first 17 cases of <a title="AIDS" href="/wiki/AIDS">AIDS</a> the only UK gay magazine, Gay News, stops publication.</p>
<p><strong>April 14, 1985</strong> &#8211; The first Gay Erotic Film Awards is held in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>April 15</strong></h2>
<p><strong>April 15, 1843</strong> - American writer Henry James is born in New York City. His biographer Leon Edel has endorsed a series of articles written by Richard Hall detailing the extent of James love for his brother the Harvard philosopher William James. Of Henry&#8217;s writing, Maugham summed it up<br />
best: &#8220;<em>I don&#8217;t think Henry James knew how ordinary people behave. His characters have neither bowels nor sexual organs.</em> (In his books) people do not go away, they depart, they do not go home but repair to their domiciles.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>April 15, 1894</strong> &#8211; Singer Bessie Smith is born in Chattanooga, Tennessee. In &#8220;Foolish<br />
Man Blues&#8221; Smith sang: &#8220;There&#8217;s two things got me puzzled, there&#8217;s two things I<br />
don&#8217;t understand; That&#8217;s a mannish-actin&#8217; woman, and a skippin, twistin&#8217; woman-actin&#8217; man.&#8221; Strange words for a woman whose best friend was male impersonator Gladys Fergusson and who had been introduced to the world of &#8216;women-lovin&#8217; women&#8217; by blues singer Ma Rainey.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>April 16</strong></h2>
<p><strong>April 16, 1453</strong> &#8211; Leonardo da Vinci is born near Florence, Italy. When he was 24 he was<a href="http://www.bnl.gov/bera/activities/globe/leonardo_da_vinci.htm"> accused of having sex with a 17-year-old youth of &#8220;questionable&#8221; background. </a></p>
<p>Along with three other young men, he was anonymously accused of sodomy, which in Florence was a criminal offense, even though in most cases the authorities looked the other way and the general culture attached little social stigma to homosexuality.</p>
<p>The accusation specifically charged him with a homosexual interaction with one Jacopo Saltarelli, a notorious prostitute. The charges were brought in April, and for a time Leonardo and the other defendants were under the watchful eye of Florence&#8217;s <em>&#8220;Officers of the Night</em>&#8220;&#8211;a kind of renaissance vice squad.</p>
<p>However, the charges were dismissed in June, due to a lack of witnesses and evidence. It is probable that the Medici family brought had something to do with this outcome, as another of the defendants was Lionardo de Tornabuoni, and Lorenzo de Medici&#8217;s mother had been a Tornabuoni.</p>
<p>DaVinci never married or showed any (recorded) interest in women; indeed, he wrote in his notebooks that male-female intercourse disgusted him. His anatomical drawings naturally include the sexual organs of both genders, but those of the male exhibit much more extensive attention. Finally, Leonardo surrounded himself with beautiful young male assistants, such as Salai and Melzi.</p>
<p>This is a bit of gay history that is<a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/entertainment/tv/in-starzs-da-vincis-demons-a-young-leonardo-discovers-some-heat/2013/04/11/2fefa8e6-9e42-11e2-a2db-efc5298a95e1_story.html"> conveniently being <strong><em>straightwashed</em> </strong>out of Starz’new drama series, “Da Vinci’s Demons,”</a> where young and sexy Leonardo (Tom Riley), who also seems to have invented the stubble trimmer and Supercuts along the way to designing  the paraglider and the helicopter. shares the storyline and his bed with high-class Medici mistress Lucrezia Donadi (Laura Haddock) who does more than pose <em>(topless of course)</em> with Leonardo while he’s supposed to spend painting her portrait.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>April 17</h2>
<p><strong>April 17, 1863</strong> - C.V. Cavafy is born in Alexandria, Egypt. During his lifetime Cavafy was considered the poet of Alexandria. Today he is primarily identified with Lawrence Durrell&#8217;s<br />
characterization of him in the Alexandria Quartet.</p>
<p><strong>April 17, 1897</strong> &#8211; <a href="http://www.berkeleydailyplanet.com/issue/2008-12-18/article/31842">Thornton Wilder</a> is born in Madison Wisconsin. Best known as the writer of &#8220;Our Town&#8221;, Wilder suffered &#8220;writer&#8217;s block&#8221; finishing the last act of the play. His close friend, writer Samuel M. Steward helped him through it all as only gone good buddy can help another. <em>*wink wink - nudge nudge*</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>April 18</h2>
<p><strong>April 18, 382, BC</strong> - Phillip of Macedonia is born. Philip II was the military genius who defeated the combined armies of Athens and Thebes, conquering all of Greece. Along the way he availed himself of the 800 young eunuchs that had been brought with the army for his pleasure.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>April 19</h2>
<p><strong>April 19, 1967</strong> &#8211; <strong><em>The Student Homophile League of Columbia University</em> </strong>becomes the first gay group to obtain a campus charter.</p>
<p>The <em>SHL</em> had twelve members who fought with university administrators for a year before the group was officially recognized. Stephen Donaldson, a bisexual identified LGBT rights activist is commemorated by a plaque in the queer lounge that bears his name in one of Columbia&#8217;s residence halls for spearheading the creation of the group.</p>
<p>When the charter was ultimately granted in April 1967 it earned media attention with the <i>New York Times</i> printing a story on the front page, the <i>Columbia Daily Spectator</i> reported that some students believed that the creation of the group was an April Fool&#8217;s Day joke.</p>
<p>The group is still in existence to this day and is now called the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Columbia_Queer_Alliance"><em><b>Columbia Queer Alliance</b></em></a><br />
<strong>April 19, 1982</strong> &#8211; <a href="http://www.goalny.org/Home.html"><em>The Gay Officers Action League, Inc. </em><strong>(GOAL)</strong></a>  is founded by NYPD Sergeant Charles Cochrane and retired Detective Sam Ciccone establishing the first official police fraternal society in the world to represent LGBT people within the criminal justice system.</p>
<p>Cochrane, a 14 year veteran of the NYPD, created shock waves by testifying before a NYC Council hearing in favor of a gay rights bill. Following the testimony of a Patrolmen’s Benevolent Association Vice President, who denounced the bill and declared, &#8220;I didn’t know of any homosexual police officers.&#8221;, Cochrane stunned all present as well as NYC as a whole by his testimony: “<em>I am very proud of being a New York City Police Officer, and I am equally proud of being gay.”</em></p>
<p>In 1987, at the persistent urging of GOAL, the  NYPD began a concerted effort to actively enlist qualified gay candidates. In 2002, GOAL was admitted into COPS, The Committee of Police Societies, an organization consisting of all recognized NYPD religious, ethnic fraternal organizations.</p>
<p>Since its inception, GOAL has evolved not only as a fraternal organization, but also as an<br />
activist organization that represents the interests of its LGBT members in all agencies and branches within the criminal justice system.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>April 20</strong></h2>
<p><strong>April 20, 1492</strong> &#8211;  Renaissance writer and dramatist Pietro Aretino is born in Tuscany. The first well-known writer of his era his works are bawdy and pornographic, at least by the standards of the 15th century.  Aretino was a pioneer of the dirty book.  His book <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2003/aug/23/featuresreviews.guardianreview17"><em>The School of Whoredom</em> </a>is the dialogue between Nanna and her 14-year-old daughter, Pippa, on the tricks of the trade, (remember this is the 1400&#8242;s) it is highly sophisticated, while not only being a satire but also a sex manual.</p>
<p>Aretino is said to have died of a stroke laughing at a dirty joke.</p>
<p>What a way to go.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>The Boys In The Band Movie Trailer (1970)</strong></p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/3Zw4639Ztjs?rel=0" height="315" width="420" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/week-gay-history-april-14-20.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Meningitis Outbreak Leaves Man With Irreparable Brain Damage</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/meningitis-outbreak-leaves-man-irreparable-brain-damage.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/meningitis-outbreak-leaves-man-irreparable-brain-damage.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 00:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brett Shaad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disease prevention and treatment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health scare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meningitis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeHo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White Party]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23794</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the past few months there has been several reports from health professionals warning gay men to be mindful of the spread of the potentially deadly meningitis bacterial virus. Unfortunately the strain has spread and irreparably affected the life of a openly gay man by the name of Brett Shaad in West Hollywood who is [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/tumblr_mdd22wcspD1rzsckyo1_500.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-23798" alt="tumblr_mdd22wcspD1rzsckyo1_500" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/tumblr_mdd22wcspD1rzsckyo1_500-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>Over the past few months there has been several reports from health professionals warning gay men to be mindful of the spread of the potentially deadly meningitis bacterial virus. Unfortunately the strain has spread and irreparably affected the life of a openly gay man by the name of Brett Shaad in West Hollywood who is now brain dead. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/13/brett-shaad-meningitis_n_3076355.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices&amp;ir=Gay%20Voices">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>LOS ANGELES &#8212; A 33-year-old West Hollywood man who felt sickened by bacterial meningitis earlier this week has been declared brain dead amid warnings to sexually active gay men about the deadly strain of illness, officials said.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Brett Shaad was declared brain dead but remained on life support Friday afternoon, said Elizabeth Ashford, a spokeswoman for Shaad&#8217;s family. She declined to release further details.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>[John] Duran, who saw Shaad last weekend, described the openly gay man as being &#8220;robust and healthy&#8221; prior to Monday, when he began to feel sick.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>On Wednesday, he went into the emergency room. By Thursday, he was in a coma.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Earlier Friday, officials warned sexually active gay men to beware of the potentially deadly health threat because Shaad&#8217;s case was detected in Los Angeles County.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Tests were being done to see if the strain of illness is similar to the meningococcal infections that circulated among gay men in New York City and infected 22 people, resulting in seven fatalities, since 2010.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>The illness could be spread by sex and kissing but not by casual contact.</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">We need to be as educated as we possibly can about this outbreak that appears to be affecting gay men. What makes this all the more scary is that the symptoms resemble that of a common flu. It&#8217;s why it is vital for all of us to know about vaccination and prevention. Prevention goes a long way in stopping the spread of this virus and we all need to take it upon ourselves to be safe and protect those that we interact with sexually. </span></p>
<p>What the Center for Disease Control <a href="http://www.cdc.gov/features/meningococcal/">(CDC)</a> urges us all to do in case we suspect we have symptoms or possibly been with someone that has the bacterial strains to get tested immediately and be sure to tell your doctor or health professional why you believe you suspect it may be meningitis by listing your symptoms. Also be sure to be up to date on any and all booster shots for the vaccine.</p>
<p>All the information I&#8217;m providing is a paraphrasing of what we should all be doing just to be safe. This is in no way to incite panic from this story but we all have to be informed of what&#8217;s going on now so that we don&#8217;t see a snowball effect. So please let those around you know to be aware of the precautions they need to take and what symptoms to look out for in order to protect all of us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/meningitis-outbreak-leaves-man-irreparable-brain-damage.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nevada Senate Amends and Passes Gay-Marriage Bill</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nevada-senate-amends-passes-gay-marriage-bill.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nevada-senate-amends-passes-gay-marriage-bill.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 00:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tim Franco</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23795</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[According to lgbtqnation.com, Nevada&#8217;s State Senate has passed a legislative measure that will allow same-sex marriage in the state. This is one of the first steps needed in order to repeal the State&#8217;s constitutional same-sex marriage ban. On a party-line, 3-2 vote, the Senate Committee on Legislative Operations and Elections amended and passed Senate Joint [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Nevada-Marriage-Certificate.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-23796" alt="Nevada Marriage Certificate" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Nevada-Marriage-Certificate-300x199.jpg" width="300" height="199" /></a>According to <a href="http://www.lgbtqnation.com/2013/04/nevada-state-senate-committee-amends-passes-gay-marriage-bill/" target="_blank">lgbtqnation.com</a>, Nevada&#8217;s State Senate has passed a legislative measure that will allow same-sex marriage in the state. This is one of the first steps needed in order to repeal the State&#8217;s constitutional same-sex marriage ban.</p>
<p>On a party-line, 3-2 vote, the Senate Committee on Legislative Operations and Elections amended and passed Senate Joint Resolution 13. It not only repeals the state’s heterosexual definition of marriage, but says Nevada recognizes all marriages regardless of gender.</p>
<p>Laura Martin with Progressive Leadership Alliance of Nevada was quoted -</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;All people in Nevada deserve the freedom to marry&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Since this is a Constitutional Amendment,  this bill has to pass the state&#8217;s Legislature this year and in 2015 in order for it to be brought to the state&#8217;s voters in 2016.</p>
<p>The original proposal sought only to repeal language in the state constitution that defines marriage as between a man and a woman. But a late amendment adopted by the committee Thursday adds that the state “shall recognize marriages and issue marriage licenses, regardless of gender.”</p>
<p>Sen. Tick Segerblom, D-Las Vegas, who introduced the bill said -</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We felt it would be cleaner to both eliminate the current prohibition and make it clear Nevada does not discriminate in any way”</p></blockquote>
<p>The amendment drew opposition from Republican Sen. James Settelmeyer of Minden. Settelmeyer said he gave Segerblom his word that he would vote for the original bill but withdrew his support because of the new wording.</p>
<blockquote><p>“I don’t think the subject of marriage should be in the constitution,” Settelmeyer said. “This is adding something else in, and I can’t support that.”</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nevada-senate-amends-passes-gay-marriage-bill.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEW POLL &#8211; Majority of Americans Support Same-Sex Marriage</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/poll-majority-americans-support-same-sex-marriage.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/poll-majority-americans-support-same-sex-marriage.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 23:45:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tim Franco</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23788</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[According to a recent NBC/Wall Street Journal poll 2 weeks after the Prop. 8 and DOMA cases Supreme Court cases, Americans are 53% in favor of supporting same-sex marriage while 42% of Americans still oppose same-sex marriage. According to NBCnews.com, 53% of respondents who favor same-sex marriage is a 2 point increase from when the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/NBC-WSJ.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-23792" alt="NBC-WSJ" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/NBC-WSJ.jpg" width="300" height="195" /></a>According to a recent NBC/Wall Street Journal poll 2 weeks after the Prop. 8 and DOMA cases Supreme Court cases, Americans are 53% in favor of supporting same-sex marriage while 42% of Americans still oppose same-sex marriage.</p>
<p>According to <a href="http://firstread.nbcnews.com/_news/2013/04/11/17708688-nbcwsj-poll-53-percent-support-gay-marriage" target="_blank">NBCnews.com</a>, 53% of respondents who favor same-sex marriage is a 2 point increase from when the poll was last conducted in December, although the 2 points is within the poll&#8217;s margin of error. The 42% who are opposed is also a 2 point increase from last December.</p>
<p>When broken down by party, the follow results were shown -</p>
<ul>
<li>73% of Democrats and 54% of Independents support same-sex marriage</li>
<li>66% of Republicans oppose same-sex marriage</li>
</ul>
<p>79% of respondents say that they know or work with someone who is gay or lesbian. However, only 15 percent say that knowing or working with someone gay makes them more likely to back same-sex marriage; 4 percent say it makes them less likely to support it, and more than half say it doesn&#8217;t make a difference.</p>
<p>The poll also finds that 63 percent of respondents believe the federal government should recognize same-sex marriages in states where they are legal, and 56 percent think that the question of allowing gay marriage should be left to a federal standard rather than to the states.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/poll-majority-americans-support-same-sex-marriage.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gordon Klingenschmitt: Allowing Openly Gay NFL Players Will Cause Gay Coachs To Recruit Children</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/gordon-klingenschmitt-allowing-openly-gay-nfl-players-gay-coachs-recruit-children.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/gordon-klingenschmitt-allowing-openly-gay-nfl-players-gay-coachs-recruit-children.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 23:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bigots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gordon Klingenschmitt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lunatics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFL]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23787</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Disgraced and dishonorably discharged ex-Navy Chaplain and current lunatic Gordon Klingenschmitt is  sounding the alarm, warning that if NFL players come out as gay, youth coaches will start &#8220;recruiting children into the homosexual lifestyle and punishing Christians because they voice an opposition to that sort of thing in the locker room.&#8221; &#8220;I think the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Crazy-Kleinschmitt.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23789" alt="Crazy Kleinschmitt" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Crazy-Kleinschmitt.png" width="300" height="180" /></a></p>
<p>Disgraced and dishonorably discharged ex-Navy Chaplain and current lunatic Gordon Klingenschmitt is  <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IQqJk3tAebw">sounding the alarm</a>, warning that if NFL players come out as gay, youth coaches will start &#8220;recruiting children into the homosexual lifestyle and punishing Christians because they voice an opposition to that sort of thing in the locker room.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I think the Devil is afoot here,&#8221; <a href="http://youtu.be/l2ILJTH7Yl4">Klingenschmitt warned</a>, saying it &#8220;is a demonic use of the sporting industry&#8221;:</p>
<p>Klingenschmitt mouth may be anti-gay, but his hands and the sound of longing in his voice for the <em>&#8220;young, tough male athlete&#8221;</em> tells a completely different story.</p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/l2ILJTH7Yl4?rel=0" height="250" width="450" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/gordon-klingenschmitt-allowing-openly-gay-nfl-players-gay-coachs-recruit-children.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NHL WOOF! &#8211; Retired NHL Detroit Red Wings Hockey Stud Mike Modano</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nhl-woof-mike.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nhl-woof-mike.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 23:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WOOF! - Men, Men, and MORE Men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Modano]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NHL]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23778</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Michael Thomas &#8220;Mike&#8221; Modano, Jr.  is a retired NHL  hockey player, who played primarily for the Minnesota North Stars/Dallas Stars franchise. He is the all-time goal-scoring and points leader amongst American-born players in the NHL, as well as the last active player in the NHL who played for the North Stars when the team was [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mike-Modana-naked-2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23780" alt="Mike Modana naked 2" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mike-Modana-naked-2.png" width="298" height="187" /></a></b></p>
<p><b>Michael Thomas</b> &#8220;<b>Mike</b>&#8221; <b>Modano, Jr.</b>  is a retired NHL <a title="Ice hockey" href="/wiki/Ice_hockey"> hockey</a> player, who played primarily for the <a title="Minnesota North Stars" href="/wiki/Minnesota_North_Stars">Minnesota North Stars</a>/<a title="Dallas Stars" href="/wiki/Dallas_Stars">Dallas Stars</a> franchise. He is the all-time goal-scoring and points leader amongst American-born players in the NHL, as well as the last active player in the NHL who played for the North Stars when the team was in Minnesota.  Modano played his final NHL season with his hometown team, the <a title="Detroit Red Wings" href="/wiki/Detroit_Red_Wings">Detroit Red Wings</a>.</p>
<p>6 ft 3 in and 210 pounds of pure hockey stud.</p>
<p><strong>PUCK ME!</strong></p>
<p><strong>&#8216;WOOF!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mike-Modana-naked-4.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-23781" alt="Mike Modana naked 4" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mike-Modana-naked-4.png" width="345" height="211" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mike-Modana-naked-3.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23782" alt="Mike Modana naked 3" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mike-Modana-naked-3.png" width="456" height="656" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mike-Modana-naked.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23783" alt="Mike Modana naked" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mike-Modana-naked.png" width="408" height="496" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nhl-woof-mike.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>GLAAD Hires Omar Sharif Jr Because All Other LGBT Advocates Already Have Jobs *SNORT*</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/glaad-hires-omar-sharif-jr-lgbt-advocates-jobs-snort.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/glaad-hires-omar-sharif-jr-lgbt-advocates-jobs-snort.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 21:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cash cow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay inc.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GLAAD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[irrelevant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starfuckers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23767</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[GLAAD, the organization formally known as the Gay &#38; Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation has announced that actor  Omar Sharif Jr. will be joining GLAAD&#8217;s staff as National Spokesperson and Strategic Giving Officer. Complementing the work of National Spokesperson Wilson Cruz, Omar will be an essential part of GLAAD&#8217;s Development team, helping to build relationships with donors and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Omar-Shariff-Jr.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23770" alt="Omar Shariff Jr" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Omar-Shariff-Jr.png" width="300" height="188" /></a></strong></p>
<p><strong>GLAAD</strong>, the organization formally known as the<em> Gay &amp; Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation</em> has <a href="http://www.glaad.org/blog/actor-and-advocate-omar-sharif-jr-joins-glaad-staff?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+glaadblog+%28GLAAD+Blog%29">announced that actor  Omar Sharif Jr</a>. will be joining GLAAD&#8217;s staff as National Spokesperson and Strategic Giving Officer.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Complementing the work of National Spokesperson Wilson Cruz, Omar will be an essential part of GLAAD&#8217;s Development team, helping to build relationships with donors and raise vital funds to support GLAAD&#8217;s work to lead the conversation for LGBT equality.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;I’m thrilled to be joining GLAAD in their culture-changing work&#8221; said Omar. &#8220;Having lived and worked in over half a dozen countries, I know the influence and impact that American media has globally &#8211; particularly in the broader Middle East, where it is widely syndicated and consumed. Working with GLAAD, I know that I’ll be helping to effectuate change back home and around the world.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Omar&#8217;s story is one of tremendous courage and one that also reflects the journey travelled by countless Americans who&#8217;ve come to support equality after a friend, family member or colleague comes out as LGBT,&#8221; said GLAAD&#8217;s Dave Montez. &#8220;As an outspoken advocate for equality, Omar brings not only extraordinary skill and expertise to GLAAD, but also an incredible passion for building a better tomorrow for LGBT people everywhere.&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>While I admire Sharif&#8217;s passion for LGBTequality in the Middle East is GLAAD, an organization that&#8217;s main concern is the use of the word &#8220;tranny&#8221; or &#8220;fag&#8221; and on low class sitcom television really a good fit for him helping our brothers and sisters in the Middle East?</p>
<p>And as for GLAAD, there are many other outspoken LGBT advocates that could really use a job and once again this is nothing more than GLAAD being <em>starfuckers </em>and using Sharif  for his  &#8221;name appeal&#8221; to help them suck some money out of uberich A-Gays and corporations to keep their march into irrelevancy going  for the next few years.</p>
<p>Just another day in Gay Inc kiddies, nothing to see here.  Lets move along.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/glaad-hires-omar-sharif-jr-lgbt-advocates-jobs-snort.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>While Mitch McConnell Plays Victim, Ethics Complaint Is Filed Against HIM Over Judd Tape</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/mcconnell-plays-victim-ethics-complaint-filed-judd-tape.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/mcconnell-plays-victim-ethics-complaint-filed-judd-tape.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 13:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ashley Judd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DEM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GOP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kentucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing victim]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23760</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While Senate Minority Leader Mitch McConnell (R-Ky.) has been playing &#8220;victim&#8221; all week and spinning the release of an audio recording from a Feb. 2 meeting between him and his aides debating the use of smear tactics against actress Ashley Judd’s mental  health, views on religion and attitudes about family while she was debating a Kentucky Senate run now the tables have [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mitch-McConnell-cries.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23761" alt="Mitch McConnell cries" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mitch-McConnell-cries.png" width="300" height="185" /></a></p>
<p>While Senate Minority Leader Mitch McConnell (R-Ky.) has been playing <em>&#8220;victim&#8221; </em>all week and spinning the release of an audio recording from a Feb. 2 meeting between him and his aides debating the use of smear tactics against actress Ashley Judd’s mental  health, views on religion and attitudes about family while she was debating a Kentucky Senate run now the tables have tuned and McConnell and his staff may very well be investigated over the incident.</p>
<p><a href="http://thehill.com/blogs/blog-briefing-room/news/292589-mcconnell-asks-fbi-to-investigate-ashley-judd-leak">The Citizens for Responsibility and Ethics in Washington (CREW), </a>a nonprofit government watchdog group, <a href="http://www.citizensforethics.org/legal-filings/entry/crew-fbi-ethics-complaints-mitch-mcconnell-kentucky-misusing-official-staff" target="_blank">has asked the Senate ethics committee and the Federal Bureau of Investigation</a> to probe whether aides and McConnell improperly conducted political opposition research on federal government time and property.</p>
<p>McConnell can be heard on the recording telling his campaign aides they are in “<em>the Whac-A-Mole period of the campaign,”</em> saying to hit anybody who sticks their head up.</p>
<p>One aide can be heard describing Judd as “<em>clearly … emotionally unbalanced.”</em> with the aide leading the strategy meeting stating that Judd “<em>views  [traditional Christianity] as sort of a vestige of patriarchy” and said she is “anti-sort-of-traditional American family.”</em></p>
<p>Senate ethics rules forbid legislative assistants and other Senate employees from participating in political activities on government time.</p>
<p>The FBI is <a href="http://politicalticker.blogs.cnn.com/2013/04/09/breaking-fbi-asked-to-probe-secret-recordings-of-mcconnell-meeting/" target="_blank">currently investigating</a> how the tape of the McConnell was made.  But in the past few days it has come to light that two men Curtis Morrison and Shawn Reilly from the small  progressive Democratic PAC <em>Progress Kentucky</em> recorded and leaked the taped.  But more shockingly is that they  and were exposed by <a href="http://livewire.talkingpointsmemo.com/entry/democratic-official-now-talking-to-fbi-about-progress?ref=fpa">Jacob  Conwa</a>y, a Democratic county official who says that the duo told him about  the recording shortly after they made it.  Said Conway <em>&#8220;I&#8217;m an honest person,&#8221;</em> Conway said. &#8220;<em>If you&#8217;re going to ask me an honest question, I&#8217;m going to give you an honest answer.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>What  Conway did not say is that the current Kentucky Democratic party looks at Morrison and Reilly as annoyances. Said veteran in-state Democratic strategist Jimmy Cauley. “<em>They’re pretty much out there on the fringe of anything I know of as the Kentucky Democratic organization.”</em> , which it turns out is very easy in a state where most of the Democrats are just as conservative as their Republican opponents.  Recently the Democrat-controlled House, voted 82-7 to pass <a href="http://rcnky.com/articles/2013/03/01/state-house-passes-bill-could-undermine-covington-human-rights-ordinance" target="_blank">House Bill 279, dubbed the <em>Religious Freedom Bill</em></a>, that allows Kentucky organizations and individuals <em>carte blanche</em> to ignore anti-LGBT discrimination laws and statutes that they perceive as violations of their religious rights.</p>
<p>Said Melanie Sloan, CREW&#8217;s executive director believes that the FBI should expand its probe. &#8220;<em>McConnell should welcome a review of the tape,&#8221;</em> she says. &#8220;<em>If McConnell thought it was so important for the FBI to investigate, the FBI should investigate everything about the incident. I think that&#8217;s hard to argue against. The tape certainly gives you probable cause to believe something improper occurred. It clearly merits investigation.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>A spokesman for Judd gave the following statement to <a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/ashley-judd-slams-leaked-mitch-mcconnell-tapes-as-politics-of-personal-destruction-2013114" target="_hplink">Us Weekly</a>:</p>
<p><em>&#8220;This is yet another example of the politics of personal destruction that embody Mitch McConnell and are pervasive in Washington, D.C. We expected nothing less from Mitch McConnell and his camp than to take a personal struggle such as depression, which many Americans cope with on a daily basis, and turn it into a laughing matter. Every day it becomes clearer how much we need change in Washington from this kind of rhetoric and actions.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/mcconnell-plays-victim-ethics-complaint-filed-judd-tape.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.326 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-15 08:08:08 -->
