<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Back2Stonewall</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com</link>
	<description>An Unapologetic LGBT News Site - We&#039;re HERE,. We&#039;re Queer, F#@king DEAL With It!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 11:00:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>One Million Mom &#8211; iacs Have A &#8220;Ship Fit&#8221; Over Over Kmart Commercial</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/million-mom-iacs-ship-fit-kmart-commercial.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/million-mom-iacs-ship-fit-kmart-commercial.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 10:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kmart. OMM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shipheads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23888</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So what took them so long? Kmart (Sears Brands, LLC) has a new commercial where the whole ad is based on the slogan &#8220;I shipped my pants.&#8221; This double entendre of the s-word is repeated over and over again. Normally, we do not provide a link since One Million Moms does not want to contribute [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/I-just-shipped-my-bed.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23889" alt="I just shipped my bed" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/I-just-shipped-my-bed.png" width="300" height="185" /></a></p>
<p>So what took them so long?</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Kmart (Sears Brands, LLC) has a new commercial where the whole ad is based on the slogan &#8220;I shipped my pants.&#8221; This double entendre of the s-word is repeated over and over again. Normally, we do not provide a link since One Million Moms does not want to contribute to this filth being spread around even more, but we made an exception this time to show how ridiculous and disgusting this ad really is. Let them know that as a parent and a consumer you are offended. This ad should be pulled off the air immediately. You can also post a comment on Kmart&#8217;s Facebook page by clicking here. (Please keep in mind that not everyone on Facebook will have the same view as you. Having thick skin comes with the territory of taking a stand.)</em></p></blockquote>
<p>An eight-year-old boy was killed by a shrapnel bomb at the Boston Marathon the other day and all these so-called <em>&#8220;loving christians&#8221;</em> can do is find moral outrage over a silly commercial?</p>
<p>One Million Moms, ship for brains.</p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/hL4lSavSepc" height="250" width="450" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/million-mom-iacs-ship-fit-kmart-commercial.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boston Marathon Bombing Suspect Taken Into Custody, Now Dead. Second Suspect On The Run</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/boston-marathon-bombing-suspect-custody-dead-suspect-run.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/boston-marathon-bombing-suspect-custody-dead-suspect-run.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 09:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boston Attacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boston Marathon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BPD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terrorism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23882</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The two Boston Marathon bombers who&#8217;s pictures were realeased by FBI autorities on Thursday armed with explosives and guns — battled law enforcement officers in the Boston suburb of Watertown early Friday morning, unleashing chaos until cops took one of the men into custody and the other fled. The standoff in Watertown, Mass., erupted shortly after the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The two Boston Marathon bombers who&#8217;s pictures were realeased by FBI autorities on Thursday armed with explosives and guns — battled law enforcement officers in the Boston suburb of Watertown early Friday morning, unleashing chaos until cops took one of the men into custody and the other fled.</p>
<p>The standoff in Watertown, Mass., erupted shortly after the fatal shooting of a Massachusetts Institute of Technology  in Cambridge according to BPD.</p>
<p>The suspects approached the MIT officer and shot him in head and then stole the MIT officer&#8217;s cruiser, robbed a nearby 7-11 and carjacked another vehicle, briefly kidnapping the driver, the sources said. At various points, the suspects threw explosives out the window of the moving car.</p>
<p>The events began unfolding with reports of shots fired on the MIT campus at 10:48 p.m. ET, and the situation remained &#8220;active and extremely dangerous&#8221; for hours, according to MIT&#8217;s emergency website. It was later reported that a campus officer had been killed.</p>
<p>A short time later, police received reports of an armed carjacking by two males in the area of Third Street in Cambridge,  “The victim was carjacked at gunpoint by two males and was kept in the car with the suspects for approximately a half hour and was then released at a gas station on Memorial Drive in Cambridge.</p>
<p>Police went in pursuit of the stolen vehicle, following it into Watertown.</p>
<p>Watertown resident Andrew Kitzenberg described the earlier police shoot out outside his house. “They engaged in gunfire for a few minutes,” Kitzenberg told NBC News. “They were  also utilizing bombs, which sounded and looked like grenades, while  engaging in the gunfight. They also had what looked like a  pressure-cooker bomb.”</p>
<p>Kitzenberg said when he looked out the window he saw two people taking cover between a black Mercedes SUV and a sedan, and watched them shooting 70 or 80 yards toward six Watertown police vehicles.</p>
<p>He said the pair took cover behind the Mercedes SUV and were shooting westward toward the police officers. They also had backpacks.</p>
<p>“It was a firefight,” he added. “There was a long exchange of gunfire.”</p>
<div id="vine-inlinePhoto__17819906" data-contentid="17819906"><img class="aligncenter" id="http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/i/MSNBC/Components/Photo/_new/130418-watertown-police-3a.jpg" alt="" src="http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/j/MSNBC/Components/Photo/_new/130418-watertown-police-3a.380;380;7;70;0.jpg" width="380" height="227" />. <!-- end17819906 --></div>
<p>One of the shooters then ran toward the officers, while the other got into the SUV, Kitzenberg recounted.</p>
<p>The person on foot later fell to the ground, but Kitzenberg said he was unable to tell whether he had been tackled or shot.</p>
<p>The other drove the SUV through the line of police cars at the end.</p>
<p>The suspect at large — believed to be the man who physically placed the bags containing the homemade bombs which killed 3 and injured 170 on Monday — was described as &#8220;dressed in a grey hoodie, light skinned male, brown curly hair.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>More to follow&#8230;</em></p>
<p><center><object id="msnbc18ed4a" width="420" height="245" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="FlashVars" value="launch=51592798&amp;width=420&amp;height=245" /><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="wmode" value="transparent" /><param name="src" value="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/32545640" /><param name="flashvars" value="launch=51592798&amp;width=420&amp;height=245" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><param name="pluginspage" value="http://www.adobe.com/shockwave/download/download.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash" /><embed id="msnbc18ed4a" width="420" height="245" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/32545640" FlashVars="launch=51592798&amp;width=420&amp;height=245" allowScriptAccess="always" allowFullScreen="true" wmode="transparent" flashvars="launch=51592798&amp;width=420&amp;height=245" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" pluginspage="http://www.adobe.com/shockwave/download/download.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash" /></object></center><center><a href="http://usnews.nbcnews.com/_news/2013/04/19/17817173-one-boston-marathon-suspect-dead-another-still-on-run-officials-say?lite">Source:  MSNBC</a></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/boston-marathon-bombing-suspect-custody-dead-suspect-run.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tell Me How Good Is Your Gaydar?</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/good-gaydar.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/good-gaydar.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 23:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinions and Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam 4 Adam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[detecting gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flirting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay clothes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay men fating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay social apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GAYDAR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grindr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heteronormative practices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[is he gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OKCupid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[researching gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scruff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sensing sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[understanding gay]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23764</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On a casual warm day like today you&#8217;re probably out and about, walking around enjoying the rays of sunlight that have been absent as a result of the exceptionally long cold winter. Observing all of the regular sites you venue on days like this, you tend to notice someone you haven&#8217;t seen or met before. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://rlv.zcache.com/the_gaydar_game_gay_lesbian_t_shirts-r8dcde99ed2aa4d1791303ae6837dbe92_va6lr_512.jpg" width="307" height="307" /></p>
<p>On a casual warm day like today you&#8217;re probably out and about, walking around enjoying the rays of sunlight that have been absent as a result of the exceptionally long cold winter. Observing all of the regular sites you venue on days like this, you tend to notice someone you haven&#8217;t seen or met before. You notice his stance and the way he walks confidently but relaxed. He has your interests immediately because of how his body moves to show off the physique you find irresistible.</p>
<p>So automatically your senses hone in for more details to take in as much info as you possibly can. You take special notice of the inflection in his voice and how his mouth moves when he speaks to his companions. From the short time that you&#8217;ve been doing all you can to observe without being noticed you pick up on how interactive and engaged into the conversation; he appears to be able to keep the attention of his companions and you notice his beautiful smile and twinkle in his emerald eyes. From what bits of conversation you hear, he loves music and is discussing how he&#8217;d love to see Kylie Minogue in concert this year.</p>
<p>It all goes perfect with his put together attire but appears effortless. As you&#8217;ve finished surveying every bit of info you decide it&#8217;s time to move on with the rest of the day only a short time later, by some luck you&#8217;ve bumped into each other (literally). He reassures you by an earnest pat on the shoulder and a smile. Then as you make eye contact he looks down as he shuffles his feet with an even more incredibly sexy smile and you are smitten.</p>
<p>Caught off guard as you&#8217;ve let the earlier detective work of the day to slip your mind. And to now be presented with a new opportunity to interact by almost walking into each other you both apologize for the harmless confrontation and are reminded of why you were so attracted to this man. You work up the courage to finally ask more about this man so you can ask him out, an almost paralyzing sensation is brought on the fact that you don&#8217;t know if this man plays on the same team you&#8217;re on. Is he gay?</p>
<p>This was a situation that I had recently where I was presented with questions on whether the gut that I was immensely attracted to and was not quite sure if the interaction we had was simple banter or flirting. This guy could have just been a courteous polite straight man. I could have been forward and just asked him out like I wanted to or invoked 20 questions to see if he was gay but would that gesture been rude or was I just being too shy with my own advances?</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve all played this guessing game before and this discussion is not about condemning the practice. At some point every gay man has encountered a situation like this where you&#8217;re attracted to a guy and seems to be everything you&#8217;re looking for, whether that&#8217;s for just a few but worthwhile nights of heated passionate sex or for a loving long term relationship. There&#8217;s attraction and intrigue but you aren&#8217;t completely sure if he&#8217;s gay. It can happen like the scenario described or the some variant or not at all. Just say that your curiosity and attraction wants you to know if it&#8217;s possible. So what do you do? Do you trust your instincts? Do you just ask him if he&#8217;s gay and if you do should you be direct or apply some well-rehearsed wit?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not always as easy when you meet men outside the world of gay social dating apps like Grindr or Scruff (or OKCupid, Adam4Adam, etc.,.). Most of us don&#8217;t reside in gay oases like New York&#8217;s Chelsea or West Hollywood because our world is much bigger than we believe. Remember that I&#8217;m from the south, where nearly everyone greets you with a smile and chivalry is still very much alive. Everyone has a little saunter to their step and sweetness in their voice. So how do we approach this without turning this into an embarrassing situation?</p>
<p>Even with all the debate, our concept as a society of what is masculinity has changed. Of course some in the gay community place this attributes at the highest of hierarchy it isn&#8217;t always so apparent in the rest society. Some would argue that these social constructs on gender roles are much more layered and less rigid than say even ten years ago. It is becoming more and more acceptable for men to be more expressive in their mannerisms that would&#8217;ve been seen as feminine a few years ago. Men can have playful banter and physical contact that are not necessarily due to sports or any other male display of strength. We can&#8217;t always go by what we see.</p>
<p>What other ways can we sense when someone is gay? What do we use to tell in order to make an advance or cool it off. Is it right to just go off of what they look like? Cause unless the verbally confirm or deny their sexuality or are wearing t-shirts that say it you can&#8217;t be certain. Remember that we live in a day and age where a well groomed man in tailored clothes is not an indication of sexual orientation but rather a metropolitan in the know of the latest trends. Maybe a scientific approach would provide more sound methods with better reliability.</p>
<p>There are actually <a href="http://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/2005/05/0510_050510_gayscent_2.html">studies</a> that suggest we are drawn and attracted to others of the same sexual orientation by the pheromones that our bodies release chemically. Researchers are basing this off a theory that gay men respond to the actual sweat from men the same way women do. The findings also revealed that gay men tend to prefer the smell of other gay men rather than straight men. Based on this research, is it possible for us as gay men to actually sense each other by smell?</p>
<p>When we are in the same proximity of another gay men do we release a sent on some unconscious level tells us that our instincts about the guy we are interested in may also be interested in us? I wouldn&#8217;t be surprised if further research suggests that as a result of our pheromones we can decipher who is gay or not, simply by the way they smell. Naturally I&#8217;m not suggesting that every man that smells good means that he&#8217;s gay. But I do think it&#8217;s interesting to examine how our own biological makeup can possibly tell us more things about people our surroundings than we ever believed possible.</p>
<p>Why not as we already have similar research that suggests we can detect who&#8217;s gay by the proportions of the eyes as well as our own <a href="http://nymag.com/news/features/33520/index2.html">hands</a>. Maybe in time more sophisticated approaches will be able to discern as homosexuality as a science has been at best subjective in their findings and at worse grossly inaccurate assumptions that are at times insulting. So maybe we shouldn&#8217;t use those methods in the scenario I experienced. Because we know how unfair it is to assume things as experience has taught us that assumptions are most likely due to what we want to see in an individual rather than who that person is in reality. So if we can&#8217;t always rely on nature or science or even direct approach, what else is left?</p>
<p>Lots of questions with unclear answers is what we are often left with when we truly take a moment to examine our ways of categorization. This discussion was not created to detour anyone from meeting other men in environments where these answers are not as clear cut as we&#8217;d like them. Far from it. But we should question how we base some of our actions on the conclusions we arrive at because they are not always accurate.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s my thing; the concept of having gaydar in and of itself is not necessarily a bad thing or barbaric in how we identify others like us. I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s a bad thing at all as we all have a natural ability to observe characteristics that are similar to us, regardless of sexuality. Problems could arise however when we rely on only those innate measures of deduction that creates issues. So while using all these methods we employ to remember to not those methods be the only thing we use. Sometimes its worth it to let them confirm it for us like the gentlemen in the earlier scenario finally did for me.</p>
<p>Whatever the case, it&#8217;s always important to remember that whatever way a guy presents himself to not just openly assume his sexuality is one way or another. And in whatever way he presents  his sexuality to you or anyone else, accept that. No matter the hunches or years of expertise you have in detecting who&#8217;s gay or not, respect that whatever he says, as you&#8217;d be want to be treated and respected the same way. The whole point of this was to show how much effort, either consciously or unconsciously we observe who among us are like us. Instincts are great but aren&#8217;t always reliable.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/good-gaydar.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Columbus, OH Lesbian Teacher Fired After Partner&#8217;s Name Appears in Mother&#8217;s Obituary</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/columbus-lesbian-teacher-fired-partners-appears-mothers-obituary.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/columbus-lesbian-teacher-fired-partners-appears-mothers-obituary.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 21:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Catholic.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ENDA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inquisition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ohio]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23872</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Bishop Watterson High School a Catholic High in Clintonville, Ohio, (a suburb of Columbus) has fired Carla Hale, a physical education teacher who was outed after an anonymous parent informed them that her partner&#8217;s name which had appeared in her mother&#8217;s obituary. Hale, a physical-education teacher who taught at Watterson for 19 years and never discussed her sexual [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Ohio-Inquisition.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23874" alt="Ohio Inquisition" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Ohio-Inquisition.png" width="300" height="188" /></a></p>
<p>Bishop Watterson High School a Catholic High in Clintonville, Ohio, (a suburb of Columbus) has fired Carla Hale, a physical education teacher who was outed after an anonymous parent informed them that her partner&#8217;s name which had appeared in her mother&#8217;s obituary.</p>
<p>Hale, a physical-education teacher who taught at Watterson for 19 years and never discussed her sexual orientation or her partner with students or fellow teachers.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.dispatch.com/content/stories/local/2013/04/17/backers-rally-for-fired-gay-teacher.html" target="_self">The Columbus Dispatch reports</a>:</p>
<p>According to a contract between the Columbus diocese and the Central Ohio Association of Catholic Educators, teachers can be terminated for “immorality” or “serious unethical conduct.” George Jones, a spokesman for the diocese, had no comment yesterday, saying personnel matters are confidential.</p>
<p>Students and other supporters recently caught wind of the firing, and on Monday, a petition was initiated on change.org to seek Hale’s reinstatement and <a href="http://www.change.org/petitions/diocese-of-columbus-reinstate-faculty-member-carla-hale" target="_self">now has more than 10,000 signatures</a>.</p>
<p><em>&#8220;It’s a disgusting display of hypocrisy by the education system that I was once so proud of,”</em> said Peter Clark of Powell, a 2011 Watterson graduate,  who is now a religious-studies major at the College of Charleston in South Carolina adding that Hale was a compassionate, understanding teacher who was fired for something that <strong><em>“has nothing to do with education.”</em></strong></p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.dispatch.com/content/mediaplayer/embed.html?ooid=lxaGoxYjpCDYAf2E_gKR1BKkJduaBmpt&amp;cmpid=share" height="250" width="450" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/columbus-lesbian-teacher-fired-partners-appears-mothers-obituary.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Obama&#8217;s Emotional Speech After Gun Control Defeat &#8211; Video and Transcript</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/president-obamas-emotional-speech-gun-control-defeat-video-transcript.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/president-obamas-emotional-speech-gun-control-defeat-video-transcript.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 09:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GOP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gun control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NRA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travesty]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23867</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Transcript THE PRESIDENT: A few months ago, in response to too many tragedies — including the shootings of a United States Congresswoman, Gabby Giffords, who’s here today, and the murder of 20 innocent schoolchildren and their teachers –- this country took up the cause of protecting more of our people from gun violence. Families [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/MQGoyQ-TXwo?rel=0" height="250" width="450" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Transcript</strong></p>
<p><strong>THE PRESIDENT:</strong> A few months ago, in response to too many tragedies — including the shootings of a United States Congresswoman, Gabby Giffords, who’s here today, and the murder of 20 innocent schoolchildren and their teachers –- this country took up the cause of protecting more of our people from gun violence.</p>
<p>Families that know unspeakable grief summoned the courage to petition their elected leaders –- not just to honor the memory of their children, but to protect the lives of all our children. And a few minutes ago, a minority in the United States Senate decided it wasn’t worth it. They blocked common-sense gun reforms even while these families looked on from the Senate gallery.</p>
<p>By now, it’s well known that 90 percent of the American people support universal background checks that make it harder for a dangerous person to buy a gun. We’re talking about convicted felons, people convicted of domestic violence, people with a severe mental illness. Ninety percent of Americans support that idea. Most Americans think that’s already the law.</p>
<p>And a few minutes ago, 90 percent of Democrats in the Senate just voted for that idea. But it’s not going to happen because 90 percent of Republicans in the Senate just voted against that idea.</p>
<p>A majority of senators voted “yes” to protecting more of our citizens with smarter background checks. But by this continuing distortion of Senate rules, a minority was able to block it from moving forward.</p>
<p>I’m going to speak plainly and honestly about what’s happened here because the American people are trying to figure out how can something have 90 percent support and yet not happen. We had a Democrat and a Republican -– both gun owners, both fierce defenders of our Second Amendment, with “A” grades from the NRA — come together and worked together to write a common-sense compromise on background checks. And I want to thank Joe Manchin and Pat Toomey for their courage in doing that. That was not easy given their traditional strong support for Second Amendment rights.</p>
<p>As they said, nobody could honestly claim that the package they put together infringed on our Second Amendment rights. All it did was extend the same background check rules that already apply to guns purchased from a dealer to guns purchased at gun shows or over the Internet. So 60 percent of guns are already purchased through a background check system; this would have covered a lot of the guns that are currently outside that system.</p>
<p>Their legislation showed respect for gun owners, and it showed respect for the victims of gun violence. And Gabby Giffords, by the way, is both — she’s a gun owner and a victim of gun violence. She is a Westerner and a moderate. And she supports these background checks.</p>
<p>In fact, even the NRA used to support expanded background checks. The current leader of the NRA used to support these background checks. So while this compromise didn’t contain everything I wanted or everything that these families wanted, it did represent progress. It represented moderation and common sense. That’s why 90 percent of the American people supported it.</p>
<p>But instead of supporting this compromise, the gun lobby and its allies willfully lied about the bill. They claimed that it would create some sort of “big brother” gun registry, even though the bill did the opposite. This legislation, in fact, outlawed any registry. Plain and simple, right there in the text. But that didn’t matter.</p>
<p>And unfortunately, this pattern of spreading untruths about this legislation served a purpose, because those lies upset an intense minority of gun owners, and that in turn intimidated a lot of senators. And I talked to several of these senators over the past few weeks, and they’re all good people. I know all of them were shocked by tragedies like Newtown. And I also understand that they come from states that are strongly pro-gun. And I have consistently said that there are regional differences when it comes to guns, and that both sides have to listen to each other.</p>
<p>But the fact is most of these senators could not offer any good reason why we wouldn’t want to make it harder for criminals and those with severe mental illnesses to buy a gun. There were no coherent arguments as to why we wouldn’t do this. It came down to politics — the worry that that vocal minority of gun owners would come after them in future elections. They worried that the gun lobby would spend a lot of money and paint them as anti-Second Amendment.</p>
<p>And obviously, a lot of Republicans had that fear, but Democrats had that fear, too. And so they caved to the pressure, and they started looking for an excuse — any excuse — to vote “no.”</p>
<p>One common argument I heard was that this legislation wouldn’t prevent all future massacres. And that’s true. As I said from the start, no single piece of legislation can stop every act of violence and evil. We learned that tragically just two days ago. But if action by Congress could have saved one person, one child, a few hundred, a few thousand — if it could have prevented those people from losing their lives to gun violence in the future while preserving our Second Amendment rights, we had an obligation to try.</p>
<p>And this legislation met that test. And too many senators failed theirs.</p>
<p>I’ve heard some say that blocking this step would be a victory. And my question is, a victory for who? A victory for what? All that happened today was the preservation of the loophole that lets dangerous criminals buy guns without a background check. That didn’t make our kids safer. Victory for not doing something that 90 percent of Americans, 80 percent of Republicans, the vast majority of your constituents wanted to get done? It begs the question, who are we here to represent?</p>
<p>I’ve heard folks say that having the families of victims lobby for this legislation was somehow misplaced. “A prop,” somebody called them. “Emotional blackmail,” some outlet said. Are they serious? Do we really think that thousands of families whose lives have been shattered by gun violence don’t have a right to weigh in on this issue? Do we think their emotions, their loss is not relevant to this debate?</p>
<p>So all in all, this was a pretty shameful day for Washington.</p>
<p>But this effort is not over. I want to make it clear to the American people we can still bring about meaningful changes that reduce gun violence, so long as the American people don’t give up on it. Even without Congress, my administration will keep doing everything it can to protect more of our communities. We’re going to address the barriers that prevent states from participating in the existing background check system. We’re going to give law enforcement more information about lost and stolen guns so it can do its job. We’re going to help to put in place emergency plans to protect our children in their schools.</p>
<p>But we can do more if Congress gets its act together. And if this Congress refuses to listen to the American people and pass common-sense gun legislation, then the real impact is going to have to come from the voters.</p>
<p>To all the people who supported this legislation — law enforcement and responsible gun owners, Democrats and Republicans, urban moms, rural hunters, whoever you are — you need to let your representatives in Congress know that you are disappointed, and that if they don’t act this time, you will remember come election time.</p>
<p>To the wide majority of NRA households who supported this legislation, you need to let your leadership and lobbyists in Washington know they didn’t represent your views on this one.</p>
<p>The point is those who care deeply about preventing more and more gun violence will have to be as passionate, and as organized, and as vocal as those who blocked these common-sense steps to help keep our kids safe. Ultimately, you outnumber those who argued the other way. But they’re better organized. They’re better financed. They’ve been at it longer. And they make sure to stay focused on this one issue during election time. And that’s the reason why you can have something that 90 percent of Americans support and you can’t get it through the Senate or the House of Representatives.</p>
<p>So to change Washington, you, the American people, are going to have to sustain some passion about this. And when necessary, you’ve got to send the right people to Washington. And that requires strength, and it requires persistence.</p>
<p>And that’s the one thing that these families should have inspired in all of us. I still don’t know how they have been able to muster up the strength to do what they’ve doing over the last several weeks, last several months.</p>
<p>And I see this as just round one. When Newtown happened, I met with these families and I spoke to the community, and I said, something must be different right now. We’re going to have to change. That’s what the whole country said. Everybody talked about how we were going to change something to make sure this didn’t happen again, just like everybody talked about how we needed to do something after Aurora. Everybody talked about we needed change something after Tucson.</p>
<p>And I’m assuming that the emotions that we’ve all felt since Newtown, the emotions that we’ve all felt since Tucson and Aurora and Chicago — the pain we share with these families and families all across the country who’ve lost a loved one to gun violence — I’m assuming that’s not a temporary thing. I’m assuming our expressions of grief and our commitment to do something different to prevent these things from happening are not empty words.</p>
<p>I believe we’re going to be able to get this done. Sooner or later, we are going to get this right. The memories of these children demand it. And so do the American people.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/president-obamas-emotional-speech-gun-control-defeat-video-transcript.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Zealand Becomes The Next Country To Legalize Marriage Equality</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/zealand-country-legalize-marriage-equality.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/zealand-country-legalize-marriage-equality.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23864</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After what has been a tough week in the news, here&#8217;s a little bright spot to brighten your day from the land down under. News has come that the country of New Zealand had finally approved a measure allowing same sex marriage. Today many citizens of New Zealand are celebrating and rightly so. Here&#8217;s more: WELLINGTON, New [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Gay-Wedding-Rings1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-23865" alt="Gay-Wedding-Rings" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Gay-Wedding-Rings1-300x255.png" width="300" height="255" /></a></p>
<p>After what has been a tough week in the news, here&#8217;s a little bright spot to brighten your day from the land down under. News has come that the country of New Zealand had finally approved a measure allowing same sex marriage. Today many citizens of New Zealand are celebrating and rightly so. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/17/new-zealand-gay-marriage_n_3098762.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>WELLINGTON, New Zealand &#8212; Hundreds of jubilant gay-rights advocates celebrated at New Zealand&#8217;s Parliament on Wednesday as the country became the 13th in the world and the first in the Asia-Pacific region to legalize same-sex marriage.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Lawmakers voted 77 to 44 in favor of the gay-marriage bill on its third and final reading.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>People watching from the public gallery and some lawmakers immediately broke into song after the result was announced, singing the New Zealand love song &#8220;Pokarekare Ana&#8221; in the indigenous Maori language.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>&#8220;For us, we can now feel equal to everyone else,&#8221; said Tania Penafiel Bermudez, a bank teller who said she already considers herself married to partner Sonja Fry but now can get a certificate to prove it. &#8220;This means we can feel safe and fair and right in calling each other wife and wife.&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>In one of several speeches that ended in a standing ovation, bill sponsor Louisa Wall told lawmakers the change was &#8220;our road toward healing.&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>&#8220;In our society, the meaning of marriage is universal – it&#8217;s a declaration of love and commitment to a special person,&#8221; she said. She added that &#8220;nothing could make me more proud to be a New Zealander than passing this bill.&#8221;</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>This makes New Zealand the 13th country approving measures that allow same sex marriage in the world. We congratulate them on their country&#8217;s progress and hope that it further inspires other countries, including the United States, to do the same.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/zealand-country-legalize-marriage-equality.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>April 17, 1965 &#8211; 48 Years Ago Today Frank Kameny Led The First Gay Protest At The White House</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/april-17-1965-gay-history.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/april-17-1965-gay-history.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 20:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[activism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civil rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frank Kameny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[protest]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wolfiedawg.webfactional.com/?p=2236</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In 1957, Dr. Frank Kameny, along with gay rights pioneer Jack Nichols, co-founded the Mattachine Society of Washington, one of the first gay rights organizations in the United States. The Mattachine Society fought for equal treatment of gay employees in the federal government, the repeal of sodomy laws, and the removal of homosexuality as a mental [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;" href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-C64mXi6xIl0/Tar0UqcZlzI/AAAAAAAABu4/DgXyoe7CTBA/s1600/1965+Picket.PNG"><img class="aligncenter" style="border: 0px currentColor;" alt="" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-C64mXi6xIl0/Tar0UqcZlzI/AAAAAAAABu4/DgXyoe7CTBA/s640/1965+Picket.PNG" width="512" height="422" border="0" /></a></div>
<p>In 1957, Dr. Frank Kameny, along with gay rights pioneer Jack Nichols, co-founded the <em>Mattachine Society</em> of Washington, one of the first gay rights organizations in the United States.</p>
<p>The Mattachine Society fought for equal treatment of gay employees in the federal government, the repeal of sodomy laws, and the removal of homosexuality as a mental disorder in the American Psychiatric Association&#8217;s manual of mental disorders.</p>
<p>On this day, 48 years ago,  April 17, 1965, Kameny and Nichols, the Mattachine Society and along with members of the Daughters of Bilitis, launched the first gay and lesbian protest in front of the White House demanding equality.</p>
<p>The Mattachine Society of Washington (MSW), the capital city&#8217;s four-year old militant gay civil rights organization, used public picketing by gays and lesbians to dramatize their demands and demonstrate their determination. Ten MSW members picketed in front of the White House against Cuban and US government repression of homosexuals: Gail Johnson, Dr. Franklin E. Kameny (head of MSW), Gene Kleeberg, Judith Kuch, Paul Kuntzler, Jack Nichols (instigator of the demonstration), Perrin Shaffer, Jon Swanson, Otto Ulrich, Lilli Vincenz (editor of MSW&#8217;s quarterly). Of the first protest, Jack Nichols has written &#8220;Never before had gay people as an organized group paraded openly for our rights.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="color: black; font-family: Times, 'Times New Roman', serif;"><a href="http://www.rainbowhistory.org/Pickets.htm">Nichols recalls:</a></span></p>
<blockquote><p><em>The picket took place during mid-afternoon. It was the Saturday before Easter, and tourists walked the downtown streets. Lige [Clarke], driving the convertible, took me to the White House curb and helped me unload signs. Then he drove off to work the afternoon shift at the Pentagon. Gail arrived at the site on the back seat of Ray&#8217;s motorcycle.</em><em>It was agreed I should lead the picket line. The reason for this was that I was tall and an all-American sort. Also, I suppose, because I&#8217;d conceived the event. Frank Kameny marched behind me and Lilli Vincenz behind him &#8230;</em></p>
<p><em>As we marched, I looked about at our well-dressed little band. Kameny had insisted that we seven men must wear suits and ties, and the women, dresses and heels. New Yorkers later complained that we Washingtonians looked like a convention of undertakers, but given the temper of the times, Kameny&#8217;s insistence was apropos. &#8220;If you&#8217;re asking for equal employment rights,&#8221; he intoned, &#8220;look employable!&#8221; In the staid nation&#8217;s capital, dressing for the occasion was, in spite of New York critics, proper.</em></p>
<p><em>We paraded in a small circle. Behind lampposts stood unknown persons photographing us. Were they government agents? Perrin and Otto wore sunglasses so absolute identification would be difficult should they fall prey to security investigations. We walked for an hour that passed, as I&#8217;d predicted, without incident. A few tourists gawked and there were one or two snickers, more from confusion than from prejudice.</em></p>
<p><em>We&#8217;d hoped for more publicity than we got. Only The Afro-American carried a small item about what we&#8217;d done. But we&#8217;d done it, and that was what mattered. We&#8217;d stood up against the power structure, putting our bodies on the line. Nothing had happened except that we&#8217;d been galvanized, and, to a certain extent, immunized against fear.&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>The Mattachine Society protest was not welcomed by the mainstream gay movement of the time.  More conservative gay leaders felt picketing would draw adverse publicity and greater hostility. <em>(Which sounds very familiar to what we hear today from Gay Inc.)</em></p>
<p>The Mattachine Society&#8217;s protest of the White House, along with the Stonewall Riots are among  the most significant events in LGBT History. But sadly as I look at the pictures and read the picket signs of these our LGBT activist forefathers I realize many of the slogans on these signs could still be carried in protest today 46 years later.</p>
<p>What have we done wrong?</p>
<p>In 2009 I wrote an article for <a href="http://www.citybeat.com/cincinnati/article-18076-reason-to-rally.html">Cincinnati CityBeat</a>  the Queen City&#8217;s alternative newspaper called <em><b>Reason To Rally</b></em> where I offered an explanation of why I believe the momentum of our fight for equality has stalled to a snail&#8217;s pace</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Since then, (the Stonewall riots) the cause for Equality has undertaken many different forms. </em></p>
<p><em>An angry queer in a T-shirt and jeans might have symbolized the gay activism of the 1970s, but the AIDS epidemic of the ’80s caused a significant change in approach.</em></p>
<p><em>By the end of the 90&#8242;s gay advocacy became symbolized by well groomed and overpaid white people sitting on boards, issuing press releases, asking for contributions and hosting fabulous galas instead of multitudes taking to the streets and demanding our rights</em></p>
<p><em>We now donate instead of protest. We sign countless petitions and then sit behind our computers and bitch and moan about our oppression instead of doing something about it ourselves.</em></p>
<p><em>Our cause has been splintered, fragmented and hijacked into piecemeal specific issues such as gay marriage, the repeal of Don’t Ask Don’t Tell and the Defense of Marriage Act instead of what we should be doing: standing together as one and fighting for and demanding federal recognition and protections in toto</em>.</p></blockquote>
<p>We all must become those angry queers, dykes, bisexuals, and trannies in tees shirts once again and we must stand up and stand together and fight the heinous hatred and bigotry that we deal with everyday and let them know that we’ll no longer accept being treated as second-class citizens and let them spread lies and propaganda about us.</p>
<p>Too many years have passed and too many of our LGBT friends have left us without knowing what true equality is.</p>
<p>This is a reminder of exactly how far we have not come. We brag and pat ourselves on the back that a few states have gay marriage.  So fucking what I say.  In 30 states LGBT&#8217;s can still be fired from a job, refused housing, and refused services.  So let me tell you that Lance and Erik can get married in New York and not have federal benefits is no great leap in Equality.  And Gay Inc has spent years and hundreds of million dollars on that issue.</p>
<p>We must ALL stand up and start fighting again.</p>
<p>Not only for us but also for the memory of those who bravely began this fight and are no longer here to see the end of it and left this world wothout being equal.</p>
<p>And of course for Frank Kameny</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/april-17-1965-gay-history.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>EXPOSED! &#8211; Disney and Red Lobster Restaurant Chain Behind Anti-Gay Legislation In Florida</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/exposed-disney-red-lobster-restaurant-chain-anti-gay-legislation-florida.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/exposed-disney-red-lobster-restaurant-chain-anti-gay-legislation-florida.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 10:12:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-worker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23858</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Two dangerous GOP bills racing through the Florida legislature would overturn several of Florida’s strongest local LGBT rights policies and would block future policies statewide.   The bills SB 726 which would eliminate requirements on what kind of benefits businesses must offer their employees prohibits local governments from requiring companies that they do business with to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong></strong></p>
<p>Two dangerous GOP bills<strong> </strong>racing through the Florida legislature would overturn several of Florida’s strongest local LGBT rights policies and would block future policies statewide.   The bills SB 726 which would eliminate requirements on what kind of benefits businesses must offer their employees prohibits local governments from requiring companies that they do business with to have <strong>family leave for domestic partners and would invalidate policies that already exist</strong>.  HB 655 would eliminate equal benefits ordinances (EBO) in the state as well as blocking the pending paid sick time referendum for all workers in that state</p>
<p>Proponents of the so-called pre-emption bills, which includes the Florida Chamber of Commerce, argue that local wage and benefit measures would create a regulatory patchwork unfriendly to business and cost jobs.</p>
<p>And as reported by the <a href="http://www.orlandosentinel.com/news/local/breakingnews/os-local-control-protest-20130416,0,653154.story">Orlando Sentinel </a>and gay advocate and Bilerico journalist Michael Emanuel Rajner <strong><em>sponsors of the bill have admitted that Walt Disney World and Darden Restaurants, owner of the</em> <a id="PLENT000226" title="Red Lobster" href="/topic/economy-business-finance/tourism-leisure-industry/restaurant-catering-industry/red-lobster-PLENT000226.topic">Red Lobster</a> and <a id="PLENT000212" title="Olive Garden" href="/topic/economy-business-finance/tourism-leisure-industry/restaurant-catering-industry/olive-garden-PLENT000212.topic">Olive Garden</a> chains, helped draft the legislation</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/2012/11/papa-johns-refuses-health-insurance.html">This is not the first time that Red Lobster has been caught </a>in attempting anti-worker practices.  Red Lobster was also exposed with Papa John&#8217;s of planning to cut workers hours to get around paying for Obama’s healthcare plan.</p>
<p>And s for Disney.  It looks like its days, aren&#8217;t going to be so gay after this news gets out.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/exposed-disney-red-lobster-restaurant-chain-anti-gay-legislation-florida.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Kids On The Block&#8217;s Jonathan Knight Talks About Being Outed</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/kids-blocks-jonathan-knight-talks-outed.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/kids-blocks-jonathan-knight-talks-outed.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 01:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being outed as gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coming out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay singers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jonathan Knight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT musicians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Kids On The Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NKOTB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perez Hilton]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23856</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you grew up in the 90s as I did, then there&#8217;s no way you could not have heard about the music group New Kids On The Block. And even to this day, mention of the band drives the most mild mannered of housewives to a state of nostalgia and questionable dance moves. As the group evolved [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://images4.fanpop.com/image/photos/17300000/Jonathan-Knight-jonathan-knight-17351392-407-357.jpg" width="285" height="250" /></p>
<p>If you grew up in the 90s as I did, then there&#8217;s no way you could not have heard about the music group New Kids On The Block. And even to this day, mention of the band drives the most mild mannered of housewives to a state of nostalgia and questionable dance moves. As the group evolved and the band members grew up, they were able to have the room to be who they really are and this is especially true for bandmember Jonathan Knight who came out years later.</p>
<p>But it was not of his own will, unfortunately as others decided to voice their own opinions on his sexuality. First by his old girlfriend and teen icon Tiffany. Then by the infamous blogger Perez Hilton that is known for his trolling ways. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/jonathan-knight-nkotb-gay_n_3084799.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>“Perez tried to out me many times and I hate that guy for doing that,&#8221; Knight noted. &#8220;I was already gay and living a gay lifestyle but he wanted me to talk about it. Why? My brother and the rest of the guys don’t go on interviews saying ‘I’m straight&#8217; etc. so why do I need to just because I’m gay?&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>He concluded, &#8220;People like him want me to talk about it to make themselves feel better. They think ‘I’m gay so I want to make sure everybody knows I’m not the only one out there.’ I hate that.”</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>In 2011, Knight broke his silence following the Tiffany gaffe on the official NKOTB blog,<a href="http://www.towleroad.com/2011/01/jonathan-knight.html" target="_hplink"> according to Towleroad</a>.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>He wrote:</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>&#8220;My belief is that you live your life by example, and not by a caption on a magazine! If there ever has been any confusion about my sexuality, then you are someone that doesn’t even know me!</em></strong><strong><em>I love living my life being open and honest, but at this time I choose not to discuss my private life any further! My fellow band members don’t discuss their private lives with their loved ones and I don’t feel that just because I am gay, I should have to discuss mine!”</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>It does not matter whether Knight was living authentically as a gay man and just not speaking about it publicly or completely in the closet the journey of coming out should never be in the hands of anyone else. It&#8217;s disturbing and flat out wrong for Perez or anyone else have a hand in how someone else comes out because it isn&#8217;t anyone else&#8217;s business but yours. No one owes anyone to share that part of their lives if they are not ready to do so. All forms of the media should know that. It&#8217;s all about decency.</p>
<p>I do applaud Knight in embracing the media coverage that came of all this a few years ago and still doing so today. And hope those so called journalist bloggers like Perez learn some decency and stop trying to out people.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em> </em></strong></p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/kids-blocks-jonathan-knight-talks-outed.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NOM Launches International Org Against Gays &#8211; Voulez Vous Hate Homos?</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nom-launching-international-org.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nom-launching-international-org.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 23:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brian Brownshirt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[International Hose of Hate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NOM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paris]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23835</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Jeremy Hooper of As Good As You has exposed The National Organization for Marriage&#8217;s (NOM)  launch of an international organization to promote anti-gay hate. Writes Hooper: We know NOM has moved forward with all of the other plans in those strategy documents (including the &#8220;drive a wedge&#8221; one); this is just a continuation of the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Bryan-Brown-evil1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23852" alt="Bryan Brown evil" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Bryan-Brown-evil1.png" width="298" height="183" /></a></p>
<p>Jeremy Hooper of <em>As Good As You</em> has exposed The National Organization for Marriage&#8217;s (NOM)  launch of an international organization to promote anti-gay hate.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.hrc.org/nomexposed/entry/nom-launching-an-international-organization-for-marriage-france-connections#.UWwIjCsk6zd" target="_self">Writes Hooper:</a></p>
<p>We know NOM has moved forward with all of the other plans in those strategy documents (including the &#8220;drive a wedge&#8221; one); this is just a continuation of the international plan, with France being the first chess move in a larger, planetary onslaught on behalf of inequality. Because it&#8217;s NOM&#8217;s Earth, apparently—we just get discriminated within it.</p>
<p>This should come as a surprise to no one.  With support and money dwindling for NOM and Brian Brown&#8217;s million dollar paycheck, Brown took a  <a href="http://www.goodasyou.org/good_as_you/2013/01/video-brian-brown-thanks-nom-supporters-for-buying-him-a-french-vacation.html" target="_hplink">recent trip to Paris</a>, where he enthusiastically reported on the <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/01/13/world/europe/france-marriage-rights-protest/" target="_hplink">French anti-gay marriage demonstrations</a>.</p>
<p>Hooper goes on to note that internal NOM documents <a href="http://www.hrc.org/nomexposed/entry/must-read#.UWwXENca87s">released</a> last year confirm that NOM has been planning the creation of International Organization for Marriage since at least 2008-09.</p>
<p>And while French &#8216;traditional marriage&#8217; opponents are amping up the violent rhetoric, <a href="http://www.thelocal.fr/page/view/hollande-wants-blood-and-he-will-get-it#.UWwKFb8gqZh" target="_self">promising blood will be spilled over equality</a> and gay bashing is on the rise.  Brian Brown<del>shirt</del> and NOM remain silent on the violence.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Brian-Brown-shirt-Paris.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23853" alt="Brian Brown shirt Paris" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Brian-Brown-shirt-Paris.png" width="450" height="448" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/nom-launching-international-org.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.464 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-19 08:55:46 -->
