<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Back2Stonewall</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com</link>
	<description>An Unapologetic LGBT News Site - We&#039;re HERE,. We&#039;re Queer, F#@king DEAL With It!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 10:52:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>NAMING NAMES: The 10 Democratic Senators Who DO NOT Support Same Sex Marriage</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/naming-names-10-democratic-senators-support-sex-marriage.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/naming-names-10-democratic-senators-support-sex-marriage.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 10:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cowards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DEM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DNC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politicians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prop 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traitors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23239</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; 1. Sen. Bob Casey (D-Pa.) backs civil unions but not gay marriage. &#8220;In the past, Senator Casey has supported civil unions and he is closely following the debate around DOMA. He intends to thoroughly review any legislation on this when it comes before the Senate,&#8221; said Casey&#8217;s spokesman John Rizzo. Asked if the senator [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><strong><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/LOSER.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23240" alt="LOSER" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/LOSER.png" width="299" height="189" /></a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>1. Sen. Bob Casey (D-Pa.)</strong> backs civil unions but not gay marriage.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the past, Senator Casey has supported civil unions and he is closely following the debate around DOMA. He intends to thoroughly review any legislation on this when it comes before the Senate,&#8221; said Casey&#8217;s spokesman John Rizzo.</p>
<p>Asked if the senator supports the repeal of DOMA, Rizzo simply repeated that Casey will review any legislation that comes before the Senate.</p>
<p><strong>2. Sen. Joe Manchin (D-W.Va.)</strong> continues to back DOMA, in addition to opposing same-sex marriage.</p>
<p>&#8220;Senator Manchin believes that a marriage is a union between one man and one woman. His beliefs are guided by his faith, and he supports the Defense of Marriage Act,&#8221; said Manchin spokeswoman Katie Longo.</p>
<p><strong>3. Sen. Kay Hagan (D-N.C.)</strong> has not publicly come out in support of marriage equality, although she did oppose North Carolina&#8217;s constitutional ban on same-sex marriage. In a statement last year, she said it would have &#8220;<a href="http://www.advocate.com/news/daily-news/2012/02/22/senator-kay-hagan-speaks-out-against-antigay-amendment-1" target="_hplink">far-reaching negative consequences</a> for our families, our children and our communities.&#8221; In 2008, Q-Notes also reported that Hagan said she believed the issue should be <a href="http://goqnotes.com/top2008/top09_030808.html" target="_hplink">left up to the states to decide</a>.</p>
<p><strong>4. Sen. Bill Nelson (D-Fla.)</strong> believes marriage is between a man and a woman.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sen. Nelson strongly supports civil rights for same-sex couples, while believing marriage should be between a man and a woman,&#8221; Nelson spokesman Ryan Brown said in a statement. &#8220;The issue will likely be decided by the U.S. Supreme Court before the end of the year.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>5. Sen. Heidi Heitkamp (D-N.D.)</strong> supported allowing states to decide what to do about marriage but did not take a position beyond that.</p>
<p>&#8220;Senator Heitkamp believes this should be handled on a state-by-state basis,&#8221; said Heitkamp&#8217;s communications director, Whitney Phillips.</p>
<p><strong>6. Sen. Mary Landrieu (D-La.)</strong> has mostly shied away from discussing gay marriage in public, <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/rebeccaberg/at-risk-democratic-senators-shy-away-from-marriage-equality" target="_hplink">offering only</a> her support for people&#8217;s right to &#8220;love who they love.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I feel very strongly that people should be allowed to love who they love, but unfortunately my state has a very strong ban against gay marriage constitutionally, so I&#8217;m going to have to think really carefully and listen to the voters of my state about that issue,&#8221; Landrieu said. &#8220;But it&#8217;s very tough because I think most people believe that people should love who they love.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Louisiana senator, who is up for reelection in 2014, <a href="http://www.landrieu.senate.gov/?p=press_release&amp;id=303" target="_hplink">voted against</a> an amendment in 2006 that would place a constitutional ban of same-sex marriage, even though at the time she defined marriage as &#8220;a sacred union between one man and one woman.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>7. Sen. Tom Carper (D-Del.)</strong> opposes DOMA and co-signed an amicus brief last much that urged the Supreme Court to invalidate Section 3 of that law. But the senator has yet to endorse same-sex marriage as a legal right.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sen. Carper was proud to support Delaware’s efforts to enact Civil Union legislation and earlier this month he joined 211 of his Congressional colleagues in co-signing the Amicus brief that urges the Supreme Court to invalidate Section 3 of DOMA,&#8221; his office said in a statement. &#8220;He has also said that he would vote to repeal DOMA. He also opposed President Bush’s attempt to enact a constitutional amendment to define marriage as between one man and one woman. Like many Americans including Presidents Obama and Clinton, Sen. Carper’s views on this issue have evolved, and continue to evolve. He continues to give this issue a great deal of consideration.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>8. Sen. Tim Johnson (D-S.D.)</strong> does not support same-sex marriage.</p>
<p>&#8220;He has not changed his position on marriage equality,&#8221; Johnson&#8217;s office said. Asked if that meant he does support the right of a gay couple to marry, the office replied: &#8220;No.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>9. Sen. Joe Donnelly (D-Ind.)</strong> <a href="http://www.wsbt.com/news/wsbt-donnelly-splits-with-obama-on-samesex-marriage-20120510,0,1902684.story" target="_hplink">opposed same-sex marriage during the campaign</a>. His office said it would send offer a statement of explanation for his current position, though it hadn&#8217;t done so by the time of publication.</p>
<p><strong>10. Sen. Mark Pryor (D-Ark.)</strong> does not support same-sex marriage.</p>
<p>&#8220;Senator Pryor’s position on same-sex marriage has not changed,&#8221; said his spokeswoman, Lucy Speed. Was that opposed to gay marriage? &#8220;Yes,&#8221; she replied.</p></blockquote>
<p>Considering that same-sex marriage support  is an official  plank of the Democratic Party each of those l;listed above should be chastised by the DNC and<em><strong>  NOT ONE THEM</strong></em> should get one red cent for re-election campaigns from the Democratic national Committee.</p>
<p>ELECT BETTER DEMOCRATS.</p>
<pre>Source:  <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/gay-marriage-rights_n_2957319.html?ncid=edlinkusaolp00000003&amp;ir=Gay%20Voices">Huffington Post:</a></pre>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/naming-names-10-democratic-senators-support-sex-marriage.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>LGBT Allies Ban Together To Welcome Gay Athletes</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/lgbt-allies-ban-gay-athletes.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/lgbt-allies-ban-gay-athletes.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 01:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brendon Ayanbadejo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gays in sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lgbt allies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lgnt advocates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taylor Hudson]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23235</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is sometimes astonishing to witness those men and women that dedicate their lives to fair and equal treatment, regardless of race, gender, and sexual orientation. And as the result of more rumors that an NFL player may come out soon it has called attention to those LGBT allies that support equal rights. Many of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/american_football.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23236" alt="american_football" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/american_football.jpg" width="177" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>It is sometimes astonishing to witness those men and women that dedicate their lives to fair and equal treatment, regardless of race, gender, and sexual orientation. And as the result of more rumors that an NFL player may come out soon it has called attention to those LGBT allies that support equal rights. Many of them current and former athletes are speaking out calling for their perspective leagues to be welcoming and supporting. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/gay-nfl-player_n_2958262.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>&#8220;We want to let this NFL player &#8212; or any closeted gay player &#8212; know that you have backup. Your community, whether it is your teammates or your fan base is here to support you,&#8221; said Hudson Taylor, founder and executive director of Athlete Ally, in a statement. Athlete Ally is a 11,000-member group that works to end homophobia in sports.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>NFL linebacker Scott Fujita, who is an Athlete Ally ambassador and most recently played with the Cleveland Browns, added, &#8220;The last thing we want to do is pressure someone into coming out or send a message that coming out is in some way better or more courageous than not. Everyone is different and has his or her own way of living life. At the same time, encouraging fans to stand up for inclusion in sports is fundamental to Athlete Ally&#8217;s mission and inextricably bound to moments like this.&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>&#8220;This isn&#8217;t about one player, it&#8217;s about all of us,&#8221; said Baltimore Ravens linebacker Brendon Ayanbadejo, who is chairman of the Athlete Ally Advisory Board, in a statement. &#8220;It&#8217;s about being a good teammate and a loyal fan. It&#8217;s about respect and everything the NFL stands for.&#8221;</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>How soon will we see an openly gay man/woman in professional sports? Could it happen this year? Anything is possible. But lets not kid ourselves. National sports leagues are known for their overt homophobia that only in the past few years is publicly reprimanded. That&#8217;s what makes allies like this so important because it shows that these men and women can and should be who they are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/lgbt-allies-ban-gay-athletes.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NOM&#8217;s Brian Brown(shirt) LIES and RANTS to the Washington Post &#8211; Video</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brownshirt-lies-rants-washington-post-video.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brownshirt-lies-rants-washington-post-video.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 22:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brian Brown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hate rally]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NOM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prop 8]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23228</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Its egregious!&#8221;  LOL! What a loser. (And ugly to boot) And the number of haters at the NOM Rally was more like 5,000.  Many of them bused in by Ruben Diaz which is extremely pathetic considering that they&#8217;ve been planning, begging and working with the FRC for months on this hate March. FAIL! &#160; &#160;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><center><iframe src="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/video/videoEmbed.html?uuid=837378ae-9653-11e2-9e23-09dce87f75a1&amp;noheadline=0" height="325" width="454" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></center><em><strong>&#8220;Its egregious!&#8221;  LOL!</strong></em></p>
<p>What a loser. <em>(And ugly to boot)</em></p>
<p>And the number of haters at the NOM Rally was more like 5,000.  Many of them bused in by Ruben Diaz which is extremely pathetic considering that they&#8217;ve been planning, begging and working with the FRC for months on this hate March.</p>
<p><strong>FAIL!</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brownshirt-lies-rants-washington-post-video.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prop 8 Supreme Court Transcript and Audio Recording Released &#8211; Read, Listen HERE!</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/prop-8-supreme-court-transcript-audio-recording-released-read-listen-here.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/prop-8-supreme-court-transcript-audio-recording-released-read-listen-here.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prop 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recording]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SCOTUS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supreme Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transcript]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23223</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[And here&#8217;s the transcript]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Gay-kiss1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23224" alt="Gay kiss" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Gay-kiss1.png" width="299" height="186" /></a></p>
<p><center><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F85024873" height="166" width="75%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe></center>And here&#8217;s the <a href="http://www.supremecourt.gov/oral_arguments/argument_transcripts/12-144a.pdf" target="_blank">transcript</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/prop-8-supreme-court-transcript-audio-recording-released-read-listen-here.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NOM&#8217;s Brian Brown: If We Lose We&#8217;ll Force A Constitutional Amendment Against Gay Marriage</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brown-lose-force-constitutional-amendment-gay-marriage.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brown-lose-force-constitutional-amendment-gay-marriage.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 09:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[con men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Douchebag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prop 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SCOTUS]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23217</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I think we’re going to win these cases. But say the worst happens and we lose in a broad way – that means that the Court somehow does a Roe, a Roe v. Wade, on marriage and says that all these state constitutional amendments are overturned, gay marriage is now a constitutional right – well, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Bryan-Brown-evil.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23218" alt="Bryan Brown evil" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Bryan-Brown-evil.png" width="298" height="183" /></a></p>
<p><em>&#8220;I think we’re going to win these cases. But say the worst happens and we lose in a broad way – that means that the Court somehow does a Roe, a Roe v. Wade, on marriage and says that all these state constitutional amendments are overturned, gay marriage is now a constitutional right – well, we’re  going to press forward on a Federal Marriage Amendment. We’ve always  supported a Federal Marriage Amendment, and there’s a lot of  misconceptions about it. Some people try and argue, ‘Well, this is  against federalism.’ No, our founders gave us a system where we can  amend the Constitution.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;We shouldn’t have to do this, we shouldn’t have  to worry about activist judges, you know, making up out of thin air a  constitutional right that obviously none of our founders found there and no one found there until quite recently. But if we do, for us, the  Federal Marriage Amendment is a way that people can stand up and say, ‘Enough is enough.’ We need a solution in this country, we cannot be, as Lincoln said, half slave, half free. We can’t have a country on key  moral questions where we’re just, where we don’t have a solution. And if the Court forces a solution, the way we’ll amend that is through  the  Federal Marriage Amendment.&#8221;</em> &#8211; National Organization for Marriage hate group leader <a href="http://www.rightwingwatch.org/content/nom-s-brown-invokes-lincoln-push-federal-marriage-amendment-we-cannot-be-half-slave-half-fre" target="_blank">Brian Brown</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Knowing that he&#8217;s going to lose the Supreme Court case against DOMA and Prop 8 professional hater and  fake University doctorate holder &#8220;Dr.&#8221; Brian Brown is covering his overly ample fat ass by laying out his income strategies for the next four years.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brown-lose-force-constitutional-amendment-gay-marriage.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rapper A$AP Rocky Says Hip Hop Culture Evolving On Gay Movement</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/rapper-aap-rocky-hip-hop-culture-evolving-gay-movement-right.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/rapper-aap-rocky-hip-hop-culture-evolving-gay-movement-right.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 23:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A$AP Rocky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civil rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay and black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jay Z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT musicans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT rappers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23213</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s no secret that the Hip Hop music, widely associated with the African American community has been slated as one of the more homophobic (which I do not agree with at all). But from statisticians to casual observers believe that this confounded belief has seen a decrease as more affluent members of the African American community evolve [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="http://media.ticketmaster.com/tm/en-us/dbimages/130237a.jpg" /></p>
<p>It&#8217;s no secret that the Hip Hop music, widely associated with the African American community has been slated as one of the more homophobic (which I do not agree with at all). But from statisticians to casual observers believe that this confounded belief has seen a decrease as more affluent members of the African American community evolve in their assessment of gay rights, more have been vocal about it. Rapper A$AP Rocky is also in agreement of this noting how legends in the HipHop community are welcoming LGBT fans and musicians. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/rapper-asap-rocky-gay-thing-hip-hop_n_2950676.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>Harlem native <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/24/longliveasap-no-1-asap-rocky-who-is-asap-rocky_n_2541707.html" target="_hplink">A$AP Rocky</a> recently sounded off on &#8220;the gay thing&#8221; in hip hop during an interview with Alexander Wang for <a href="http://www.interviewmagazine.com/music/aap-rocky/#page3" target="_hplink">Interview Magazine.</a> The &#8220;Goldie&#8221; rapper says he wants to use his platform as an artist to let people know how he feels about the hot button topic.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>“So now that I’m here and I’ve got a microphone in my hand and about 6,000 people watching me, I need to tell them how I feel,&#8221; he said. &#8220;For instance, one big issue in hip hop is the gay thing. It’s 2013, and it’s a shame that, to this day, that topic still gets people all excited. It’s crazy. And it makes me upset that this topic even matters when it comes to hip hop, because it makes it seem like everybody in hip hop is small-minded or stupid &#8212; and that’s not the case.&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Rocky said that he treats everybody equal and he wants his listeners and followers to do the same. &#8220;We’ve got people <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/05/14/jay-z-gay-marriage-obama_n_1516614.html" target="_hplink">like Jay-Z</a>. We’ve got people <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/23/kanye-west-rant-grammys-jay-z-justin-timberalke_n_2751622.html" target="_hplink">like Kanye</a>. We’ve got people like me. We’re all prime examples of people who don’t think like that. I treat everybody equal, and so I want to be sure that my listeners and my followers do the same if they’re gonna represent me. And if I’m gonna represent them, then I also want to do it in a good way.”</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>So with this wave that&#8217;s taken over the country as far as acceptance, does this mean that we will see more artists and musicians emerge from the Hip Hop community that are members of the LGBT community? It certainly appears that it&#8217;s more plausible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/rapper-aap-rocky-hip-hop-culture-evolving-gay-movement-right.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>GLAAD Drops &#8220;Gay &amp; Lesbian&#8221; From Name, Will Now Be Knowm As GLAAD.  Huh?</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/glaad-drops-gay-lesbian-name-knowm-glaad-huh.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/glaad-drops-gay-lesbian-name-knowm-glaad-huh.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 23:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[branding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GLAAD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stupid]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23209</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[GLAAD has officially ended the usage of their full name, the Gay &#38; Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation as not to alienate transsexuals. So from now on they will be known just by their old letters GLAAD. &#8220;It is a natural progression that reflects the work GLAAD&#8217;s staff is already leading,&#8221; said [spokesman Wilson] Cruz. &#8220;We respect and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/GLAAD1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23210" alt="GLAAD" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/GLAAD1.png" width="300" height="190" /></a>GLAAD has <a href="http://www.glaad.org/blog/glaad-affirms-commitment-trans-people-lgbt-community-and-allies-melissa-harris-perry-show" target="_blank">officially ended</a> the usage of their full name, the<em> Gay &amp; Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation </em>as not to alienate transsexuals. So from now on they will be known just by their old letters GLAAD.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is a natural progression that reflects the work GLAAD&#8217;s staff is already leading,&#8221; said [spokesman Wilson] Cruz. &#8220;We respect and honor the full name that the organization was founded with, but GLAAD&#8217;s work has expanded beyond fighting defamation to changing the culture. Our commitment to marriage equality, employment nondiscrimination, and other LGBT issues is stronger than ever, and now our name reflects our work on transgender issues as well as our work with allies.&#8221;</p>
<p>Okay.  Now I am not being transphobic here but is this absolutely the stupidest thing that you ever heard of?</p>
<p>Remember two years ago the Gay and Lesbian Task Forced dropped the &#8220;gay&#8221; and &#8220;lesbian&#8221; to just the Task Force.</p>
<p>It is a very sad day when the words Gay and Lesbian are deemed inappropriate so a &#8220;company&#8221; can brand itself to be more mainstream and inclusive to make more money.</p>
<p>But perhaps in a way its a good thing.</p>
<p>After all what intelligent, self-respecting gay, lesbian, or transsexual wants to be associated with a bunch of gAy-list  ass kissing starfuckers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/glaad-drops-gay-lesbian-name-knowm-glaad-huh.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mike Signorile: Grassroots Activists And NOT Gay Inc. Got Us To The Supreme Court &#8211; TESTIFY!</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/mike-signorile-grassroots-activists-gay-supreme-court-testify.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/mike-signorile-grassroots-activists-gay-supreme-court-testify.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 22:03:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinions and Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AMFER]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom To Marry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gayinc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HRC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prop 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SCOTUS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supreme Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Truth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23206</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Whether it was ACT UP organizing civil disobedience at the height of the government ignorance of the AIDS epidemic in the late &#8217;80s, or Get Equal members chaining themselves to the White House fence to push the president on &#8216;don&#8217;t ask, don&#8217;t tell,&#8217; it took brave people who put their reputations, their privacy, their futures, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><em><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Bitchslap.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23207" alt="Bitchslap" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Bitchslap.png" width="300" height="173" /></a></em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Whether it was ACT UP organizing civil disobedience at the height of the government ignorance of the AIDS epidemic in the late &#8217;80s, or Get Equal members chaining themselves to the White House fence to push the president on &#8216;don&#8217;t ask, don&#8217;t tell,&#8217; it took brave people who put their reputations, their privacy, their futures, their jobs, their families and sometimes literally their own bodies on the line to push things forward. They withstood attack not just from antigay zealots,the police and the media, but from the gay establishment, telling them to just be good little boys and girls.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Sometimes these champions weren&#8217;t even gay themselves but were allies of gay rights as well: When San Francisco Mayor Gavin Newsom began marrying couples in San Francisco in 2004, the Democratic establishment, and the gay establishment which is very much a part of it, went ballistic. It affected Newsom&#8217;s political career, but there&#8217;s no doubt Newsom is a hero of marriage equality whose action was pivotal.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;If not for grass-roots activists pressuring President Obama, gay leaders seemed likely to have given him a pass on &#8216;don&#8217;t ask, don&#8217;t tell&#8217; repeal in his first term and on defending DOMA in court, let alone moving forward on marriage equality. So let&#8217;s not forget these brave people as we watch all the talk shows and read the media interviews which highlight the very gay leaders who were often opposed to the exact strategy they&#8217;re now embracing.&#8221; &#8211; <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/michelangelo-signorile/how-we-got-to-the-supreme_b_2947931.html" target="_blank">Michelangelo Signorile</a></em></p></blockquote>
<p>Remember way back when in May 2009, when AMFER (who as led by Chad Griffin before he sold out to HRC  lined up Ted Olson and David Boies to argue the  shit out of Prop 8′s unconstitutionality, America and California’s Gay Inc.  groups were furious.</p>
<p>HRC joined Freedom to Marry, ACLU, Lamda Legal, GLAAD,  Log Cabin Republicans, and PFLAG <a href="http://www.queerty.com/is-filing-a-lawsuit-against-prop-8-actually-the-worst-idea-ever-20090527/">in  denouncing the <em>Perry v. Schwarzenegger</em> lawsuit</a>, saying in an open  letter, “<em><strong>Rather than filing premature lawsuits, we need to talk to our friends,  family and neighbors, and help them understand why denial of the freedom to  marry is wrong.”</strong></em></p>
<p>They bitched and moaned and wanted no part of it.  <em>UNTIL</em> it looked like it might actually win and then they made a 360 and started taking credit for it.</p>
<p>These Gay Inc. groups proved that while they remain sometimes SLIGHTLY useful, <em><strong>they  are not necessary to securing LGBT rights</strong>.</em></p>
<p>That has been proven,  And that is the way it should be.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/mike-signorile-grassroots-activists-gay-supreme-court-testify.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>DISGUSTING! &#8211; &#8220;On met les enfants devant&#8221; Toddlers Used As Human Shields At Paris Gay Hate Rally</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/disgusting-on-met-les-enfants-devant-toddlers-human-shields-paris-gay-hate-rally.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/disgusting-on-met-les-enfants-devant-toddlers-human-shields-paris-gay-hate-rally.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 09:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NOM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terrorist]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23200</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[News agencies from  France are reporting that yesterday&#8217;s NOM approved anti-gay hate march in Paris turned violent when protesters attempted to march down the off-limits Champs Elysees, prompting riot police to respond with force and with tear gas. Christine Boutin, leader of the French Christian Democratic Party, and one of National Organization for Marriage&#8217;s speakers at their [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Toddlers-used-as-human-shields-in-France.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23201" alt="Toddlers used as human shields in France" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Toddlers-used-as-human-shields-in-France.png" width="295" height="186" /></a></p>
<p>News agencies from  France are reporting that yesterday&#8217;s NOM approved anti-gay hate march in Paris <a href="http://www.thelocal.fr/page/view/clashes-amid-last-ditch-anti-gay-marriage-protests#.UU9ZH5zkl_O" target="_blank">turned violent</a> when protesters attempted to march down the off-limits Champs Elysees, prompting riot police to respond with force and with tear gas.</p>
<p>Christine Boutin, leader of the French Christian Democratic Party, and one of National Organization for Marriage&#8217;s speakers at their forthcoming anti-gay hate march in Washington, DC was seen lying on the ground in the Champs-Elysees, after being tear-gassed by police during the demonstration, after clashing with the police herself.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>100 to 200 frustrated protestors had reportedly attempted to breach a police barricade blocking them from entering the Champs Elysees. In response, riot police forcibly pushed them back from the fences, as well as spraying them with tear gas. Jean-François Copé, leader of the centre-right opposition UMP party, who was present at the protest, called for President Hollande to be &#8220;held to account&#8221;, and expressed his &#8220;indignation&#8221; that tear gas had been deployed &#8220;against families present with their children.&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://americablog.com/2013/03/violent-protest-paris-gay-marriage.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Americablog+%28AMERICAblog+News%29&amp;utm_content=Google+Reader" target="_blank">John Aravosis</a>, from AmericaBlog is also reporting that anti-gay protestors also attempted to use their children as &#8220;human shields&#8221; against police.</p>
<p><em>“On met les enfants devant, on met les enfants devant.”</em> TRANSLATION:  “Put the kids in front, put the kids in front,” a father yells to other  protesters, as he approached the police line with his three-year old  child perilously perched on his shoulders right after the police used  tear gas and batons, telling the protesters to back up.</p>
<p><strong>DISGUSTING.</strong></p>
<p>So much for the anti-gay <em>&#8220;it&#8217;s all for the best interest of children&#8221;</em> lie.</p>
<p><em><strong>Les talibans francais.</strong></em></p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/yVcovWO-weo" height="250" width="450" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/disgusting-on-met-les-enfants-devant-toddlers-human-shields-paris-gay-hate-rally.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Big Bang Theory Gay Star Goes In Drag For Rocky Horror</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/big-bang-theory-star-drag-rocky-horror.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/big-bang-theory-star-drag-rocky-horror.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jim Parsons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT actors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openly gay actors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Big Bang Theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Rocky Horror Picture Show]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23197</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Jim Parsons, known for his uber nerd persona Sheldon Cooper on The Big Bang Theory took to the stage to work the wildly sucessful cult classic Rocky Horror Picture Show. Showing off some leg and a lot of attitude Parsons seems to completely transform in front of thee audience. Here&#8217;s more: Parsons, who nabbed Emmy Awards in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gadgets/slideshows/287895/slide_287895_2252777_free.jpg?1363970722810" width="430" height="630" /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Jim Parsons, known for his uber nerd persona Sheldon Cooper on T<em>he Big Bang Theory</em> took to the stage to work the wildly sucessful cult classic Rocky Horror Picture Show. Showing off some leg and a lot of attitude Parsons seems to completely transform in front of thee audience. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/jim-parsons-in-drag-_n_2933487.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices#slide=2252777">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>Parsons, who <a href="http://www.emmys.com/celebrities/jim-parsons" target="_hplink">nabbed Emmy Awards</a> in 2010 and 2011 for his turn as the geeky Sheldon Cooper on &#8220;Theory,&#8221; played the role of Dr. Frank-N-Furter from &#8220;The Rocky Horror Picture Show&#8221; at the 21st annual &#8220;A Night at Sardi&#8217;s&#8221; event in Hollywood. Proceeds from the event reportedly benefitted the Alzheimer&#8217;s Association, <a href="http://www.justjared.com/2013/03/21/jim-parsons-kaley-cuoco-big-bang-theory-as-rocky-horror-for-alzheimers/" target="_hplink">according to Just Jared</a>.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Joining Parsons onstage for the performance were co-stars Kaley Cuoco, Mayim Bialik and Johnny Galecki, as well as &#8220;Wings&#8221; actor Steven Weber.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/05/23/jim-parsons-gay-big-bang-theory-star_n_1539988.html" target="_hplink">Parsons&#8217; sexuality</a> was confirmed in a New York Times article last year. Of the 39-year-old actor, who was then starring on Broadway in a revival of &#8220;Harvey,&#8221; <a href="http://theater.nytimes.com/2012/05/27/theater/jim-parsons-prepares-for-his-lead-role-in-harvey.html?_r=0" target="_hplink">writer Patrick Healy noted</a>, &#8220;Mr. Parsons is gay and in a 10-year relationship.&#8221;</em></strong></p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/big-bang-theory-star-drag-rocky-horror.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.331 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-27 08:13:59 -->
