<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Back2Stonewall</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com</link>
	<description>An Unapologetic LGBT News Site - We&#039;re HERE,. We&#039;re Queer, F#@king DEAL With It!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 09:56:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>NOM&#8217;s Brian Brown: If We Lose We&#8217;ll Force A Constitutional Amendment Against Gay Marriage</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brown-lose-force-constitutional-amendment-gay-marriage.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brown-lose-force-constitutional-amendment-gay-marriage.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 09:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[con men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Douchebag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prop 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SCOTUS]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23217</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I think we’re going to win these cases. But say the worst happens and we lose in a broad way – that means that the Court somehow does a Roe, a Roe v. Wade, on marriage and says that all these state constitutional amendments are overturned, gay marriage is now a constitutional right – well, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Bryan-Brown-evil.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23218" alt="Bryan Brown evil" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Bryan-Brown-evil.png" width="298" height="183" /></a></p>
<p><em>&#8220;I think we’re going to win these cases. But say the worst happens and we lose in a broad way – that means that the Court somehow does a Roe, a Roe v. Wade, on marriage and says that all these state constitutional amendments are overturned, gay marriage is now a constitutional right – well, we’re  going to press forward on a Federal Marriage Amendment. We’ve always  supported a Federal Marriage Amendment, and there’s a lot of  misconceptions about it. Some people try and argue, ‘Well, this is  against federalism.’ No, our founders gave us a system where we can  amend the Constitution.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;We shouldn’t have to do this, we shouldn’t have  to worry about activist judges, you know, making up out of thin air a  constitutional right that obviously none of our founders found there and no one found there until quite recently. But if we do, for us, the  Federal Marriage Amendment is a way that people can stand up and say, ‘Enough is enough.’ We need a solution in this country, we cannot be, as Lincoln said, half slave, half free. We can’t have a country on key  moral questions where we’re just, where we don’t have a solution. And if the Court forces a solution, the way we’ll amend that is through  the  Federal Marriage Amendment.&#8221;</em> &#8211; National Organization for Marriage hate group leader <a href="http://www.rightwingwatch.org/content/nom-s-brown-invokes-lincoln-push-federal-marriage-amendment-we-cannot-be-half-slave-half-fre" target="_blank">Brian Brown</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Knowing that he&#8217;s going to lose the Supreme Court case against DOMA and Prop 8 professional hater and  fake University doctorate holder &#8220;Dr.&#8221; Brian Brown is covering his overly ample fat ass by laying out his income strategies for the next four years.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brown-lose-force-constitutional-amendment-gay-marriage.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rapper A$AP Rocky Says Hip Hop Culture Evolving On Gay Movement</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/rapper-aap-rocky-hip-hop-culture-evolving-gay-movement-right.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/rapper-aap-rocky-hip-hop-culture-evolving-gay-movement-right.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 23:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A$AP Rocky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civil rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay and black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jay Z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT musicans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT rappers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23213</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s no secret that the Hip Hop music, widely associated with the African American community has been slated as one of the more homophobic (which I do not agree with at all). But from statisticians to casual observers believe that this confounded belief has seen a decrease as more affluent members of the African American community evolve [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="http://media.ticketmaster.com/tm/en-us/dbimages/130237a.jpg" /></p>
<p>It&#8217;s no secret that the Hip Hop music, widely associated with the African American community has been slated as one of the more homophobic (which I do not agree with at all). But from statisticians to casual observers believe that this confounded belief has seen a decrease as more affluent members of the African American community evolve in their assessment of gay rights, more have been vocal about it. Rapper A$AP Rocky is also in agreement of this noting how legends in the HipHop community are welcoming LGBT fans and musicians. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/rapper-asap-rocky-gay-thing-hip-hop_n_2950676.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>Harlem native <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/24/longliveasap-no-1-asap-rocky-who-is-asap-rocky_n_2541707.html" target="_hplink">A$AP Rocky</a> recently sounded off on &#8220;the gay thing&#8221; in hip hop during an interview with Alexander Wang for <a href="http://www.interviewmagazine.com/music/aap-rocky/#page3" target="_hplink">Interview Magazine.</a> The &#8220;Goldie&#8221; rapper says he wants to use his platform as an artist to let people know how he feels about the hot button topic.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>“So now that I’m here and I’ve got a microphone in my hand and about 6,000 people watching me, I need to tell them how I feel,&#8221; he said. &#8220;For instance, one big issue in hip hop is the gay thing. It’s 2013, and it’s a shame that, to this day, that topic still gets people all excited. It’s crazy. And it makes me upset that this topic even matters when it comes to hip hop, because it makes it seem like everybody in hip hop is small-minded or stupid &#8212; and that’s not the case.&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Rocky said that he treats everybody equal and he wants his listeners and followers to do the same. &#8220;We’ve got people <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/05/14/jay-z-gay-marriage-obama_n_1516614.html" target="_hplink">like Jay-Z</a>. We’ve got people <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/23/kanye-west-rant-grammys-jay-z-justin-timberalke_n_2751622.html" target="_hplink">like Kanye</a>. We’ve got people like me. We’re all prime examples of people who don’t think like that. I treat everybody equal, and so I want to be sure that my listeners and my followers do the same if they’re gonna represent me. And if I’m gonna represent them, then I also want to do it in a good way.”</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>So with this wave that&#8217;s taken over the country as far as acceptance, does this mean that we will see more artists and musicians emerge from the Hip Hop community that are members of the LGBT community? It certainly appears that it&#8217;s more plausible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/rapper-aap-rocky-hip-hop-culture-evolving-gay-movement-right.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>GLAAD Drops &#8220;Gay &amp; Lesbian&#8221; From Name, Will Now Be Knowm As GLAAD.  Huh?</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/glaad-drops-gay-lesbian-name-knowm-glaad-huh.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/glaad-drops-gay-lesbian-name-knowm-glaad-huh.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 23:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[branding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GLAAD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stupid]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23209</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[GLAAD has officially ended the usage of their full name, the Gay &#38; Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation as not to alienate transsexuals. So from now on they will be known just by their old letters GLAAD. &#8220;It is a natural progression that reflects the work GLAAD&#8217;s staff is already leading,&#8221; said [spokesman Wilson] Cruz. &#8220;We respect and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/GLAAD1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23210" alt="GLAAD" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/GLAAD1.png" width="300" height="190" /></a>GLAAD has <a href="http://www.glaad.org/blog/glaad-affirms-commitment-trans-people-lgbt-community-and-allies-melissa-harris-perry-show" target="_blank">officially ended</a> the usage of their full name, the<em> Gay &amp; Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation </em>as not to alienate transsexuals. So from now on they will be known just by their old letters GLAAD.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is a natural progression that reflects the work GLAAD&#8217;s staff is already leading,&#8221; said [spokesman Wilson] Cruz. &#8220;We respect and honor the full name that the organization was founded with, but GLAAD&#8217;s work has expanded beyond fighting defamation to changing the culture. Our commitment to marriage equality, employment nondiscrimination, and other LGBT issues is stronger than ever, and now our name reflects our work on transgender issues as well as our work with allies.&#8221;</p>
<p>Okay.  Now I am not being transphobic here but is this absolutely the stupidest thing that you ever heard of?</p>
<p>Remember two years ago the Gay and Lesbian Task Forced dropped the &#8220;gay&#8221; and &#8220;lesbian&#8221; to just the Task Force.</p>
<p>It is a very sad day when the words Gay and Lesbian are deemed inappropriate so a &#8220;company&#8221; can brand itself to be more mainstream and inclusive to make more money.</p>
<p>But perhaps in a way its a good thing.</p>
<p>After all what intelligent, self-respecting gay, lesbian, or transsexual wants to be associated with a bunch of gAy-list  ass kissing starfuckers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/glaad-drops-gay-lesbian-name-knowm-glaad-huh.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mike Signorile: Grassroots Activists And NOT Gay Inc. Got Us To The Supreme Court &#8211; TESTIFY!</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/mike-signorile-grassroots-activists-gay-supreme-court-testify.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/mike-signorile-grassroots-activists-gay-supreme-court-testify.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 22:03:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinions and Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AMFER]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exposed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom To Marry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gayinc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HRC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prop 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SCOTUS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supreme Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Truth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23206</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Whether it was ACT UP organizing civil disobedience at the height of the government ignorance of the AIDS epidemic in the late &#8217;80s, or Get Equal members chaining themselves to the White House fence to push the president on &#8216;don&#8217;t ask, don&#8217;t tell,&#8217; it took brave people who put their reputations, their privacy, their futures, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><em><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Bitchslap.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23207" alt="Bitchslap" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Bitchslap.png" width="300" height="173" /></a></em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Whether it was ACT UP organizing civil disobedience at the height of the government ignorance of the AIDS epidemic in the late &#8217;80s, or Get Equal members chaining themselves to the White House fence to push the president on &#8216;don&#8217;t ask, don&#8217;t tell,&#8217; it took brave people who put their reputations, their privacy, their futures, their jobs, their families and sometimes literally their own bodies on the line to push things forward. They withstood attack not just from antigay zealots,the police and the media, but from the gay establishment, telling them to just be good little boys and girls.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Sometimes these champions weren&#8217;t even gay themselves but were allies of gay rights as well: When San Francisco Mayor Gavin Newsom began marrying couples in San Francisco in 2004, the Democratic establishment, and the gay establishment which is very much a part of it, went ballistic. It affected Newsom&#8217;s political career, but there&#8217;s no doubt Newsom is a hero of marriage equality whose action was pivotal.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;If not for grass-roots activists pressuring President Obama, gay leaders seemed likely to have given him a pass on &#8216;don&#8217;t ask, don&#8217;t tell&#8217; repeal in his first term and on defending DOMA in court, let alone moving forward on marriage equality. So let&#8217;s not forget these brave people as we watch all the talk shows and read the media interviews which highlight the very gay leaders who were often opposed to the exact strategy they&#8217;re now embracing.&#8221; &#8211; <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/michelangelo-signorile/how-we-got-to-the-supreme_b_2947931.html" target="_blank">Michelangelo Signorile</a></em></p></blockquote>
<p>Remember way back when in May 2009, when AMFER (who as led by Chad Griffin before he sold out to HRC  lined up Ted Olson and David Boies to argue the  shit out of Prop 8′s unconstitutionality, America and California’s Gay Inc.  groups were furious.</p>
<p>HRC joined Freedom to Marry, ACLU, Lamda Legal, GLAAD,  Log Cabin Republicans, and PFLAG <a href="http://www.queerty.com/is-filing-a-lawsuit-against-prop-8-actually-the-worst-idea-ever-20090527/">in  denouncing the <em>Perry v. Schwarzenegger</em> lawsuit</a>, saying in an open  letter, “<em><strong>Rather than filing premature lawsuits, we need to talk to our friends,  family and neighbors, and help them understand why denial of the freedom to  marry is wrong.”</strong></em></p>
<p>They bitched and moaned and wanted no part of it.  <em>UNTIL</em> it looked like it might actually win and then they made a 360 and started taking credit for it.</p>
<p>These Gay Inc. groups proved that while they remain sometimes SLIGHTLY useful, <em><strong>they  are not necessary to securing LGBT rights</strong>.</em></p>
<p>That has been proven,  And that is the way it should be.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/mike-signorile-grassroots-activists-gay-supreme-court-testify.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>DISGUSTING! &#8211; &#8220;On met les enfants devant&#8221; Toddlers Used As Human Shields At Paris Gay Hate Rally</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/disgusting-on-met-les-enfants-devant-toddlers-human-shields-paris-gay-hate-rally.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/disgusting-on-met-les-enfants-devant-toddlers-human-shields-paris-gay-hate-rally.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 09:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NOM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terrorist]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23200</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[News agencies from  France are reporting that yesterday&#8217;s NOM approved anti-gay hate march in Paris turned violent when protesters attempted to march down the off-limits Champs Elysees, prompting riot police to respond with force and with tear gas. Christine Boutin, leader of the French Christian Democratic Party, and one of National Organization for Marriage&#8217;s speakers at their [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Toddlers-used-as-human-shields-in-France.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23201" alt="Toddlers used as human shields in France" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Toddlers-used-as-human-shields-in-France.png" width="295" height="186" /></a></p>
<p>News agencies from  France are reporting that yesterday&#8217;s NOM approved anti-gay hate march in Paris <a href="http://www.thelocal.fr/page/view/clashes-amid-last-ditch-anti-gay-marriage-protests#.UU9ZH5zkl_O" target="_blank">turned violent</a> when protesters attempted to march down the off-limits Champs Elysees, prompting riot police to respond with force and with tear gas.</p>
<p>Christine Boutin, leader of the French Christian Democratic Party, and one of National Organization for Marriage&#8217;s speakers at their forthcoming anti-gay hate march in Washington, DC was seen lying on the ground in the Champs-Elysees, after being tear-gassed by police during the demonstration, after clashing with the police herself.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>100 to 200 frustrated protestors had reportedly attempted to breach a police barricade blocking them from entering the Champs Elysees. In response, riot police forcibly pushed them back from the fences, as well as spraying them with tear gas. Jean-François Copé, leader of the centre-right opposition UMP party, who was present at the protest, called for President Hollande to be &#8220;held to account&#8221;, and expressed his &#8220;indignation&#8221; that tear gas had been deployed &#8220;against families present with their children.&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://americablog.com/2013/03/violent-protest-paris-gay-marriage.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Americablog+%28AMERICAblog+News%29&amp;utm_content=Google+Reader" target="_blank">John Aravosis</a>, from AmericaBlog is also reporting that anti-gay protestors also attempted to use their children as &#8220;human shields&#8221; against police.</p>
<p><em>“On met les enfants devant, on met les enfants devant.”</em> TRANSLATION:  “Put the kids in front, put the kids in front,” a father yells to other  protesters, as he approached the police line with his three-year old  child perilously perched on his shoulders right after the police used  tear gas and batons, telling the protesters to back up.</p>
<p><strong>DISGUSTING.</strong></p>
<p>So much for the anti-gay <em>&#8220;it&#8217;s all for the best interest of children&#8221;</em> lie.</p>
<p><em><strong>Les talibans francais.</strong></em></p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/yVcovWO-weo" height="250" width="450" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/disgusting-on-met-les-enfants-devant-toddlers-human-shields-paris-gay-hate-rally.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Big Bang Theory Gay Star Goes In Drag For Rocky Horror</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/big-bang-theory-star-drag-rocky-horror.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/big-bang-theory-star-drag-rocky-horror.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jim Parsons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT actors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openly gay actors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Big Bang Theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Rocky Horror Picture Show]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23197</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Jim Parsons, known for his uber nerd persona Sheldon Cooper on The Big Bang Theory took to the stage to work the wildly sucessful cult classic Rocky Horror Picture Show. Showing off some leg and a lot of attitude Parsons seems to completely transform in front of thee audience. Here&#8217;s more: Parsons, who nabbed Emmy Awards in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gadgets/slideshows/287895/slide_287895_2252777_free.jpg?1363970722810" width="430" height="630" /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Jim Parsons, known for his uber nerd persona Sheldon Cooper on T<em>he Big Bang Theory</em> took to the stage to work the wildly sucessful cult classic Rocky Horror Picture Show. Showing off some leg and a lot of attitude Parsons seems to completely transform in front of thee audience. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/jim-parsons-in-drag-_n_2933487.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices#slide=2252777">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>Parsons, who <a href="http://www.emmys.com/celebrities/jim-parsons" target="_hplink">nabbed Emmy Awards</a> in 2010 and 2011 for his turn as the geeky Sheldon Cooper on &#8220;Theory,&#8221; played the role of Dr. Frank-N-Furter from &#8220;The Rocky Horror Picture Show&#8221; at the 21st annual &#8220;A Night at Sardi&#8217;s&#8221; event in Hollywood. Proceeds from the event reportedly benefitted the Alzheimer&#8217;s Association, <a href="http://www.justjared.com/2013/03/21/jim-parsons-kaley-cuoco-big-bang-theory-as-rocky-horror-for-alzheimers/" target="_hplink">according to Just Jared</a>.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Joining Parsons onstage for the performance were co-stars Kaley Cuoco, Mayim Bialik and Johnny Galecki, as well as &#8220;Wings&#8221; actor Steven Weber.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/05/23/jim-parsons-gay-big-bang-theory-star_n_1539988.html" target="_hplink">Parsons&#8217; sexuality</a> was confirmed in a New York Times article last year. Of the 39-year-old actor, who was then starring on Broadway in a revival of &#8220;Harvey,&#8221; <a href="http://theater.nytimes.com/2012/05/27/theater/jim-parsons-prepares-for-his-lead-role-in-harvey.html?_r=0" target="_hplink">writer Patrick Healy noted</a>, &#8220;Mr. Parsons is gay and in a 10-year relationship.&#8221;</em></strong></p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/big-bang-theory-star-drag-rocky-horror.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Today In Gay History &#8211; March 24, 1987: ACT UP Stages Its First Major Protest. Seventeen Arrested</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/today-gay-history-march24.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/today-gay-history-march24.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 23:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1987]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Act Up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NYC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[protest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Today In Gay History]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23189</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[March 24, 1987 - ACT UP stages its first major demonstration. Seventeen protestors are arrested. Outraged by the government&#8217;s mismanagement of the AIDS crisis, LGBT and straight concerned individuals unite to form the AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power. ACT UP&#8217;s first demonstration takes place three weeks later on March 24th 1987 on Wall Street, the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">
<p><strong>March 24, 1987 -</strong> <em>ACT UP</em> stages its first major demonstration. Seventeen protestors<br />
are arrested.</p>
<p>Outraged by the government&#8217;s mismanagement of the AIDS crisis, LGBT and straight concerned individuals unite to form the AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power.</p>
<p>ACT UP&#8217;s first demonstration takes place three weeks later on March 24th 1987 on Wall Street, the financial center, to protest the profiteering of pharmaceutical companies (especially Burroughs Wellcome, manufacturer of AZT). Over 250 people participated in the protest.</p>
<p>ACT UP&#8217;s flyer for the event listed its demands:</p>
<h2 align="center">NO MORE BUSINESS AS USUAL!</h2>
<h2 align="center">Come to Wall Street in front of Trinity Church at 7AM Tuesday March 24 for a</h2>
<h1 align="center"><span style="font-size: large;">MASSIVE AIDS DEMONSTRATION</span></h1>
<h2 align="center"><span style="font-size: xx-small;">To demand the following</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-size: xx-small;">1. Immediate release by the Federal Food &amp; Drug Administration of drugs that might help save our lives.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-size: xx-small;">These drugs include: Ribavirin (ICN Pharmaceuticals); Ampligen (HMR Research Co.); Glucan (Tulane University School of Medicine); DTC (Merieux); DDC (Hoffman-LaRoche); AS 101 (National Patent Development Corp.); MTP-PE (Ciba-Geigy); AL 721 (Praxis Pharmaceuticals).</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: xx-small;">2. Immediate abolishment of cruel double-blind studies wherein some get the new drugs and some don&#8217;t.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: xx-small;">3. Immediate release of these drugs to everyone with AIDS or ARC.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: xx-small;">4. Immediate availability of these drugs at affordable prices. Curb your greed!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: xx-small;">5. Immediate massive public education to stop the spread of AIDS.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: xx-small;">6. Immediate policy to prohibit discrimination in AIDS treatment, insurance, employment, housing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: xx-small;">7. Immediate establishment of a coordinated, comprehensive, and compassionate national policy on AIDS.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: xx-small;">President Reagan, nobody is in charge!</span></p>
<h3 align="center"><span style="font-size: small;">AIDS IS THE BIGGEST KILLER IN NEW YORK CITY<br />
OF YOUNG MEN AND WOMEN</span></h3>
<p>The first few minutes of the clip below from Fight Back Fight AIDS: 15 Years of ACT UP is some of the only remaining footage of the protest.</p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/1668083" height="375" width="500" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe><a href="http://vimeo.com/1668083">Fight Back Fight AIDS: 15 Years of ACT UP clip</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/frameline">Frameline</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</center>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/today-gay-history-march24.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watch the NEW Leaked Second Trailer for WORLD WAR Z &#8211; Video</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/watch-leaked-trailer-world-war-video-2.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/watch-leaked-trailer-world-war-video-2.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 22:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GayGeek - All Things Gay and Geeky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brad Pitt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay geek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Max Brooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trailer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World War Z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zombies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23181</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s a new leaked look at Brad Pitt and Paramount Pictures World War Z with the second trailer which was supposed to be released tomorrow. For those of you who have read Max Brook&#8217;s awesome book of the same title you&#8217;ll see little resemblance between it and the movie other than the title and the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here&#8217;s a new leaked look at Brad Pitt and Paramount Pictures World War Z with the second trailer which was supposed to be released tomorrow.</p>
<p>For those of you who have read Max Brook&#8217;s awesome book of the same title you&#8217;ll see little resemblance between it and the movie other than the title and the main characters name.  Which is a pity.  But it does seem to be a serviceable action packed zombie apocalypse flick never the less.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><center><script type="text/javascript" src="http://www.springboardplatform.com/js/overlay"></script><iframe id="ro012_691251" src="http://cms.springboardplatform.com/embed_iframe/37/video/691251/ro012/ropeofsilicon.com/10" height="350" width="500" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/watch-leaked-trailer-world-war-video-2.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What The HELL Was CBS Thinking Having FRC Hate Group President Tony Perkins on Face The Nation?</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/gay-marriage-advocate-evan-wolfson-faceplams-frcs-tony-perkins-face-nation.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/gay-marriage-advocate-evan-wolfson-faceplams-frcs-tony-perkins-face-nation.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 21:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accounability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Face the Nation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay Marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shameful]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23174</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Freedom to Marry&#8217;s Evan Wolfson, Baltimore Ravens linebacker Brendon Ayanbadejo, Family Research Council&#8217;s Tony Perkins, Daily Beast journalist David Frum, and Alliance Defending Freedom&#8217;s Austin Nimocks participated in a roundtable this morning on Face the Nation to discuss the upcoming arguments at the Supreme Court and the rising support for marriage equality in the nation Said [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Tony-Perkins-FRC-KKK5.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23176" alt="Tony Perkins FRC KKK" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Tony-Perkins-FRC-KKK5.png" width="300" height="188" /></a></p>
<p>Freedom to Marry&#8217;s Evan Wolfson, Baltimore Ravens linebacker Brendon Ayanbadejo, Family Research Council&#8217;s Tony Perkins, <em>Daily Beast</em> journalist David Frum, and Alliance Defending Freedom&#8217;s Austin Nimocks participated in a roundtable this morning <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/face-the-nation/" target="_self">on <em>Face the Nation</em></a> to discuss the upcoming arguments at the Supreme Court and the rising support for marriage equality in the nation</p>
<p><strong>Said Wolfson to Perkins:</strong></p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;Marriage is not defined by who is denied it. When gay people share in the freedom to marry, it doesn&#8217;t change your marriage, it doesn&#8217;t change Tony Perkins&#8217; marriage. My marriage is my marriage. And it means that I&#8217;m able to share in the same aspirations of commitment and love and support and dedication and connectedness, and that my parents are able to dance at our wedding. And our familiy and friends are able to support and celebrate and hold us accountable for the commitment we&#8217;ve made to one another. That takes nothing away from anyone else&#8230;</em></p>
<p><em>&#8230;The gay people are not going to use up all the marriage licenses when we enter marriage. And this is not just somebody saying it. We now have nine states including the District of Columbia, fourteen countries on four continents in which gay people share in the freedom to marry and the result is families are helped and no one is hurt.&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>It&#8217;s an interesting segment, even though Bob Schieffer is obviously cluessless on the subject of same sex marriage.</p>
<p>But the question remains WHY does CBS invite Tony Perkins the leader of an <em><strong>officially identified hate group</strong> </em>on Face the Nation and give him  credibility on broadcast television.</p>
<p><em>Face the Nation </em>and<em> CBS </em>should be ashamed of themselves.</p>
<p><center><object width="425" height="279" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="src" value="http://cnettv.cnet.com/av/video/cbsnews/atlantis2/cbsnews_player_embed.swf" /><param name="background" value="#333333" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="flashvars" value="si=254&amp;contentValue=50143470&amp;shareUrl=http://www.cbsnews.com/video/watch/?id=50143470n" /><embed width="425" height="279" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://cnettv.cnet.com/av/video/cbsnews/atlantis2/cbsnews_player_embed.swf" background="#333333" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" flashvars="si=254&amp;contentValue=50143470&amp;shareUrl=http://www.cbsnews.com/video/watch/?id=50143470n" /></object></center>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/gay-marriage-advocate-evan-wolfson-faceplams-frcs-tony-perkins-face-nation.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Overheard On The NYC Subway: Two Construction Workers Talk About Their Gay Sons</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/overheard-nyc-subway-construction-workers-talk-gay-sons.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/overheard-nyc-subway-construction-workers-talk-gay-sons.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 12:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinions and Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heartwarming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NYC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Subway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unconditional love]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23170</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Two construction workers talking on a NYC subway train at Penn Station: Guy #2:  No more kids for you two? Guy #1:  No, she figures we’re both getting too old for a baby. Guy #2:  How is your boy anyway?  Haven’t seen him in awhile. Guy #1:  Oh John’s good, pitching this year varsity. Guy [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Two-Construction-Workers.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23171" alt="Two Construction Workers" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Two-Construction-Workers.png" width="300" height="185" /></a></p>
<p>Two construction workers talking on a NYC subway train at Penn Station:</p>
<blockquote><p>Guy #2:  No more kids for you two?<br />
<strong>Guy #1:  No, she figures we’re both getting too old for a baby.</strong><br />
Guy #2:  How is your boy anyway?  Haven’t seen him in awhile.<br />
<strong>Guy #1:  Oh John’s good, pitching this year varsity.</strong><br />
Guy #2: He’ll definitely have the girls hanging around him now.<br />
<strong>Guy #1:  Yeah if he had any time for them.</strong><br />
Guy #2:  Focused on baseball?<br />
<strong>Guy #1:  Focused on boys.</strong><br />
Guy #2:  You’re shittin me!<br />
<strong>Guy #1:  I kid you not.  Came out to me and Mary Ann bold as daylight last year.</strong><br />
Guy #2:  Well I’ll be damned!  I’m not supposed to know it but I overheard Patrick Junior tell his sister he might be gay not two months ago.<br />
<strong>Guy #1:  We all saw that coming though.</strong><br />
Guy #2:  You’re the second person to say that.  How’d everybody see it but me?<br />
<strong>Guy #1:  It was just a feelin Pat.  He was always a little soft, ya know?</strong><br />
Guy #2:  I guess you’re right.  But damn Charlie, we both have gay kids.  What do we do now?  Both our sons are gay.<br />
<strong>Guy #1:  We don’t do anything.  We let em be gay and if some kid calls em a faggot we go to their house and raise hell with the parents like normal.</strong><br />
Guy #2:  Well I guess John and Lucinda won’t be getting together like we thought awhile ago.<br />
<strong>Guy #1:  Guess not.</strong><br />
<em>**long pause**</em><br />
Guy #2:  Hey Charlie, you thinkin what I’m thinkin?<br />
<strong>Guy #1:  I was for about half a second then it got weird and I started thinkin about somethin else instead.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>From: <a href="http://soletstalkabout.com/post/45838945526/heard-on-the-subway-talking-about-your-gay-son">SoLetsTalk.com</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/overheard-nyc-subway-construction-workers-talk-gay-sons.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.322 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-26 09:04:29 -->
