<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Back2Stonewall</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com</link>
	<description>An Unapologetic LGBT News Site - We&#039;re HERE,. We&#039;re Queer, F#@king DEAL With It!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 09:46:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>BUSTED! &#8211; AFTAH&#8217;s Peter LaBarbera Arrested In Illinois Sex Sting</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/busted-aftahs-peter-labarbera-arrested-illinois-sex-sting.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/busted-aftahs-peter-labarbera-arrested-illinois-sex-sting.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 09:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23480</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[HAPPY APRIL FOOLS DAY!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/dQw4w9WgXcQ?rel=0" height="315" width="420" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>HAPPY APRIL FOOLS DAY!</strong></h2>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/04/busted-aftahs-peter-labarbera-arrested-illinois-sex-sting.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arizona Congressman Won&#8217;t Support His Gay Son&#8217;s Right To Marry</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/arizona-congressman-support-gay-sons-marry.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/arizona-congressman-support-gay-sons-marry.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 02:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civil rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Sqalmon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[r]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rob Portman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23474</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You would think after Rob Portman&#8217;s announcement several weeks ago coming out in support of marriage equality since he has a son who is gay would show a trend with the religion-obsessed extremists of the republican party changing their views. Some felt it would give other politicians that are in the same situation more incentive [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Gay-Wedding-Rings1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-23475" alt="Gay-Wedding-Rings" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Gay-Wedding-Rings1-300x255.png" width="300" height="255" /></a></p>
<p>You would think after Rob Portman&#8217;s announcement several weeks ago coming out in support of marriage equality since he has a son who is gay would show a trend with the religion-obsessed extremists of the republican party changing their views. Some felt it would give other politicians that are in the same situation more incentive to support LGBT rights. But as the case goes of Congressman Matt Salmon from Arizona, that belief may be a little premature to say the least.</p>
<p>Salmon stated in an interview this past week that even though he loves his son more than anything, he has not yet reached that evolution that Portman has obtained. Here&#8217;s<a href="http://www.azfamily.com/news/Gay-son-doesnt-change-congressmans-view-on-gay-marriage-200686251.html"> more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>In a recent interview with 3TV, Salmon said that while he has a son who is gay, he’s not a supporter of same-sex marriage.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>“I’m just not there in believing in my heart,” said Salmon, adding, “My son is one of the most important people in my life. I love him more than I can say.”</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Rep. Salmon has maintained a reputation as a staunch social conservative throughout his political career.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Republican Senator Rob Portman recently announced that he had changed his opinion on same-sex marriage after learning that his son is gay.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>“It doesn’t mean I don’t have respect, it doesn’t mean I don’t sympathize with some of the issues, it means I haven’t evolved to that station, Rob Portman apparently has,” said Salmon.</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Salmon says he does sympathize some of the issues but doesn&#8217;t seem to make an effort as to clarify what those issues are that he supports. Would he be willing to support his son&#8217;s right to fair and equal job treatment in the workforce and work towards making bills such as ENDA (Employee Non Discrimination Act)? Would he support more federal laws that outlaw hate crimes in this country? I guess we would have to look at his voting record while in congress but from his stringent conservatism I doubt it.</p>
<p>That has to hurt hearing a parent either does not support who their child is or that they seem to be struggling so hard with reaching a level of acceptance of who they are and their right to live any way they choose. Much worse when those views of the parent are so public. Even though this is a family issue, his opinion doesn&#8217;t only affect his family. It affects</p>
<p>But it still doesn&#8217;t excuse Congressman Salmon&#8217;s position on the matter. Moreover it leads to even more an unfavorable opinion that he so vaguely discusses that he has not reached a level of understanding yet no clear justification of why he has this stance. It wouldn&#8217;t make the situation any easier for their relationship as father and son, or his constituents that happen to be LGBT.  Sounds like Salmon needs to learn more about LGBT rights and it&#8217;s history so he sees that having this view is oppressive to LGBT and to his family.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/arizona-congressman-support-gay-sons-marry.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>HRC Discriminates at SCOTUS Hearing to End Discrimination</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/hrc-discriminates-scotus-hearing-discrimination.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/hrc-discriminates-scotus-hearing-discrimination.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 02:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tim Franco</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay inc.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HRC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HRC Sucks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23457</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[During the protest on the steps of the Supreme Court during the SCOTUS DOMA hearing, members of the LGBT organization GetEQUAL faced some unsettling discrimination. As anyone who has protested or or joined a rally for LGBT rights knows, there are always protesters. Usually they are holding sings saying how God hates gays and that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/SCOTUS-DOMA.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-23458" alt="SCOTUS DOMA" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/SCOTUS-DOMA-300x224.jpg" width="300" height="224" /></a>During the protest on the steps of the Supreme Court during the SCOTUS DOMA hearing, members of the LGBT organization GetEQUAL faced some unsettling discrimination.</p>
<p>As anyone who has protested or or joined a rally for LGBT rights knows, there are always protesters. Usually they are holding sings saying how God hates gays and that all gays are going to hell for being sinners. Well during the DOMA protests, transgender members of GetEQUAL faced discrimination from a group that they thought would be the last group in the world to discriminate, especially against transgender individuals..</p>
<p>According to an independent blog, <a href="http://oblogdeeoblogda.me/2013/03/29/activists-seeing-red-over-hrc-antics-at-scotus-hearings/" target="_blank">O-blog-dee-o-blog-da </a>, members of GetEQUAL were flying a  trans flag outside the Supreme Court building on the DOMA day and placed near the podium.  C.D. Kirven, GetEQUAL board member, was waving that trans flag most prominently when GetEQUAL, who were challenging Westboro Baptist Church, were told to remove their flag by members of the HRC. The HRC&#8217;s reason behind requesting GetEQUAL members to remove their flag was because they said Marriage Equality was not a &#8220;transgender issue&#8221;.</p>
<p>According to another website, <a href="http://www.bilerico.com/2013/03/hrc_and_the_trans_flag_incident.php?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+BilericoProject+(The+Bilerico+Project)" target="_blank">The Bilerico Project</a>, blogger Jerame Davis, who was at the event, reported the following on his blog:</p>
<blockquote><p>Through the bustle and the crowd, I could discern that the HRC staffer was discussing the transgender equality flag the young man was waving. It was clear the staffer wanted him to move or to stop displaying the flag. It was also clear that the young trans man holding the flag was at the edge of his training (and his wits) in dealing with the situation as was the staffer. The HRC staffer moved on just as we got within speaking distance, so we asked the man with the flag what had happened.</p>
<p>He told us that the staffer had been harassing him about his flag and that he wasn&#8217;t going to move. He told us the staffer had stopped on three occasions to ask him to move or stop displaying the flag. He also mentioned that the staffer had denigrated trans issues in some manner, but I know this staffer and I cannot imagine they have any sort of anti-trans animus, so I chalked that up to a misunderstanding.</p></blockquote>
<p>Since I first heard this story reported from a Tumblr post, I have been trying to get clarification on it. When the story first broke on Twitter via the Tumblr post, I found no other supporting information on the net to verify this happened. I spoke to a friend who is a huge supporter of the HRC, and although I feel his opinion was bias, he stated that he would couldn&#8217;t believe for a moment that the HRC would act in this manner.</p>
<p>Based on his reaction combined with my inability, at the time, to find information online to support this story, I decided I would email GetEQUAL and asked for clarification. I sent them an email on Thursday March 28. I mentioned in the email about what I had heard and sent them the Tumblr link I had found the story on. I asked them if any part of this story were true and if it were in fact the Human Rights Campaign that was involved in this. As of today, Sunday March 31, I hadn&#8217;t received a response back. I decided that I would send them a follow up email today asking again for clarification in the story. I told them in today&#8217;s email that I had heard that it could have been two possible organizations named HRC. One being the Human Rights Coalition and the other being of course the Human Rights Campaign. I did some research on the Human Rights Coalition, and from what I found, they are an advocacy group located in Pennsylvania who fights for the right of prisoners, not a group I would expect to be present during the DOMA protests. I have also decided I will be sending an email to the Human Rights Campaign asking for clarification in this story as well. Once I receive a response, if any, from either organization, I&#8217;ll make sure I pass it on to our readers on Back2Stonewall.</p>
<p>As I told GetEQUAL, unity and support of all is the only way we can move forward in our fight for LGBT rights.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/hrc-discriminates-scotus-hearing-discrimination.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watch the First Teaser Trailer for TRUE BLOOD Season 6 &#8211; The Wrath of Billith! &#8211; Video</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/watch-teaser-trailer-true-blood-season-6-wrath-billith-video.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/watch-teaser-trailer-true-blood-season-6-wrath-billith-video.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 20:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GayGeek - All Things Gay and Geeky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Billith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fangbangers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Season 6 Trailer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sookie Stackhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[True Blood]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23451</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I gotta say that after reading all the Sookie Stackhouse books HBO is  so far off the books original storylines that I can&#8217;t even tell you what happens next. But hey,  as long as Eric, Jason and Alceide keep taking off their clothes I&#8217;m there! True Blood Season 6 Debuts June 16th at 9:00 pm.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I gotta say that after reading all the Sookie Stackhouse books HBO is  so far off the books original storylines that I can&#8217;t even tell you what happens next.</p>
<p>But hey,  as long as Eric, Jason and Alceide keep taking off their clothes I&#8217;m there!</p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/INJC8eHNNHM" height="250" width="450" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center><br />
True Blood Season 6 Debuts June 16th at 9:00 pm.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/watch-teaser-trailer-true-blood-season-6-wrath-billith-video.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bisexual California Teen Called &#8220;Faggot&#8221;, Attacked Police Refuse To Call It A Hate Crime</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/bisexual-california-teen-called-faggot-attacked-police-refuse-call-hate-crime.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/bisexual-california-teen-called-faggot-attacked-police-refuse-call-hate-crime.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 12:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bisexual]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elk Grove CA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faggot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hate crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Police]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23448</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Openly bisexual 16-year-old  Max Aistrup and his friends were called anti-gay slurs, beaten and robbed in a public park in Elk Grove, California but local police are dragging their feet and are refusing to call a hate crime. 16-year-old, Max knows what it’s like being bullied. Only this time, it wasn’t just words, but punches. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Hate-Crimes.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23449" alt="Hate Crimes" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Hate-Crimes.png" width="300" height="179" /></a></p>
<p>Openly bisexual 16-year-old  Max Aistrup and his friends were called anti-gay slurs, beaten and robbed in a public park in Elk Grove, California but local police are dragging their feet and are refusing to call a hate crime.</p>
<p>16-year-old, Max knows what it’s like being bullied. Only this time, it wasn’t just words, but punches.</p>
<p>“They called us &#8220;faggots&#8221;  Anything you can think of they pretty much said,”</p>
<p>Aistrup says he and his friends were attacked in broad daylight walking through a quiet, well-kept Elk Grove Park. He says seven guys came up to them and started making anti-gay comments</p>
<p>Two of Aistrup’s friends were jumped while he and a third friend ran off to dial 911. By the time police arrived, the attackers were already gone with Aistrup’s Xbox — taken from his friend’s backpack.</p>
<p>“When I found out about the slurs, I had smoke coming out of my ears like the cartoons,” said Earl McComb, Aistrup’s father. McComb is furious, convinced his 16-year-old was targeted simply for who he is.</p>
<p>“I have no room in my life for hate or intolerance,” he said.</p>
<p>But Elk Grove police are treating this as a robbery, not a hate crime — saying it remains unclear what the motivation was.</p>
<p>However, Max Aistrup says homophobic slurs leave little doubt. “That’s the moment you cross the line,”</p>
<p>Now if only the Elk Grove Police were as smart as a 16-year-old boy and could realize that.</p>
<p>Hate crime laws and legislation does absolutely nothing if the authorities refuse to use it.</p>
<p><center>Call the Elk Grove Police Deptartment Main Administration Number  at-919-478-8000</center>A hate crime is a hate crime.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/bisexual-california-teen-called-faggot-attacked-police-refuse-call-hate-crime.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyonce Speaks Out For Same-Sex Marriage: &#8220;We all should be able to put a ring on it&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/beyonce-speaks-marriage-equality.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/beyonce-speaks-marriage-equality.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 00:58:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beyonce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brendon Ayanbadejo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jay Z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT advocates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prop 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SCOTUS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supreme Court]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23440</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the past week during the initial Supreme Court hearings regarding the Prop 8 and DOMA cases calling into the question of banning same sex marriage is unconstitutional, many celebrities voiced their support. We knew we have always had the support of some that spoke up like  music icon Madonna and NFL star from the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://www.racialicious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Beyonce-Knowles-closeup-1024x576.jpg" width="430" height="242" /></p>
<p>Over the past week during the initial Supreme Court hearings regarding the Prop 8 and DOMA cases calling into the question of banning same sex marriage is unconstitutional, many celebrities voiced their support. We knew we have always had the <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/33-straight-star-allies-lgbt-rights_n_2979254.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices#slide=2280622">support</a> of some that spoke up like  music icon Madonna and NFL star from the Baltimore Ravens Brendon Ayanbadejo.</p>
<p>But with others that are given high social status we are not always so sure until recently, as is the case with Beyonce, who finally spoke up in support for same sex marriage. The multifaceted musician, actress, and business mogul took the opportunity to let her fans know that it is time for us as a society to ensure that we all have the right to love whomever we want:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://wac.450f.edgecastcdn.net/80450F/thedrop.fm/files/2013/03/beyonce.jpg" />This does come as a big relief to many of her fans that are LGBT and have wondered for so long why she chose to not vocally state what her opinion was on the issue. Coupled with the fact that her husband, Jay-Z has expressed numerous times his support of marriage equality, alongside President Obama last year, Beyonce&#8217;s silence did make some wonder if she did not share the same view.</p>
<p>Some believed it was out of fear of how some of her fanbase would react to her supporting same sex marriage. But that would be problematic as a sizable portion of her fans are gay men. Yet Beyonce has never been an artist to give too much credence to the opinion of others, no matter how respect and appreciation she may have for their support so it&#8217;s reasonable to believe that this latest gesture is genuine. .</p>
<p>But in typical, methodically honed timing, the triple threat decided to vocalize her opinion in her own way and own time. And that is why we love her. As it should be for anyone, they should be able to express how they feel in whatever way they see fit. Can&#8217;t help but respect that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/beyonce-speaks-marriage-equality.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>First Look:  Watch the Redband Trailer for Kick-Ass 2 &#8211; Video</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/look-watch-redband-trailer-kick-ass-2-video.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/look-watch-redband-trailer-kick-ass-2-video.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 23:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GayGeek - All Things Gay and Geeky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay geek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kick-Ass 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redband trailer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23436</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Get More: Morris Chesnut, John Leguizamo, Aaron Johnson, Christopher Mintz-Plasse, Jim Carrey, Movie Trailers, Movies Blog &#160;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><center></p>
<div style="background-color: #000000; width: 520px;">
<div style="padding: 4px;"><iframe src="http://media.mtvnservices.com/embed/mgid:uma:video:mtv.com:887615/cp~id%3D1703507%26vid%3D887615%26instance%3Dmtv%26uri%3Dmgid%3Auma%3Avideo%3Amtv.com%3A887615" height="288" width="500" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: left; background-color: #ffffff; padding: 4px; margin-top: 4px; margin-bottom: 0px; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 12px;">Get More:<br />
<a style="color: #439cd8;" href="http://www.mtv.com/movies/person/11314/personmain.jhtml" target="_blank">Morris Chesnut</a>, <a style="color: #439cd8;" href="http://www.mtv.com/movies/person/36703/personmain.jhtml" target="_blank">John Leguizamo</a>, <a style="color: #439cd8;" href="http://www.mtv.com/movies/person/315970/personmain.jhtml" target="_blank">Aaron Johnson</a>, <a style="color: #439cd8;" href="http://www.mtv.com/movies/person/459271/personmain.jhtml" target="_blank">Christopher Mintz-Plasse</a>, <a style="color: #439cd8;" href="http://www.mtv.com/movies/person/10030/personmain.jhtml" target="_blank">Jim Carrey</a>, <a style="color: #439cd8;" href="http://www.mtv.com/movies/trailer_park/" target="_blank">Movie Trailers</a>, <a style="color: #439cd8;" href="http://moviesblog.mtv.com/" target="_blank">Movies Blog</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/look-watch-redband-trailer-kick-ass-2-video.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oprah&#8217;s Buddy &#8220;Pastor&#8221; Joel Osteen: We&#8217;re For Everybody Except The Gays &#8211; Video</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/oprahs-buddy-pastor-joel-osteen-gays-video.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/oprahs-buddy-pastor-joel-osteen-gays-video.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 22:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bigot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Con Man]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jake Tapper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joel Osteen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oprah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23433</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Con-man and gay face Joel Osteen (a Oprah discovery)of the Houston TX megachurch Lakewood, appeared on The Lead with Jake Tapper to pitch his mew book I Declare and talked about his right-wing christian-fest biblical show &#8220;The Bible&#8221; and let it be known that he doesn&#8217;t believe in or support same-sex marriage because has he doesn&#8217;t [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Con-man and gay face Joel Osteen (a Oprah discovery)of the Houston TX megachurch Lakewood, appeared on The Lead with Jake Tapper to pitch his mew book <i>I Declare</i> and talked about his right-wing christian-fest biblical show &#8220;The Bible&#8221; and let it be known that he doesn&#8217;t believe in or support same-sex marriage because has he doesn&#8217;t see <em>“same-sex in the scripture.”</em></p>
<p>“It&#8217;s a fine line,” Osteen answered.  “We&#8217;re for everybody, but, of course, as a Christian pastor my base is off what I believe the Scripture says.  Marriage is between a male and a female.  But again, we&#8217;re for everybody.  But that&#8217;s where I draw the line.”</p>
<p>Tapper followed up by asking Osteen whether he believes that gay couples should have access to some basic rights.</p>
<p>“I think so.  You know, I think we have to be compassionate about it all.  We&#8217;re not against everybody.  And there are certainly people who love each other and I believe they should have those rights.  I just … you know, when I come back to the Scripture, as much as I&#8217;m for everybody, I don&#8217;t see same-sex in the Scripture.”</p>
<p>Well Osteen is right about one thing.  Same-sex marriage isn&#8217;t in the scriptures but also no where in the Bible does <strong>it specifically say that same-sex marriage is not allowed or the fact that it is only between one man and one woman </strong>although it does mention marriage between one man and many women.  After all, the nation of Israel comes from the offspring of the four “wives” (2 wives, 2 concubines) of Jacob.  <em>Polygamy and sexual slavery anyone? Its in the scripture so it must be okay!</em></p>
<p>The whole interview was a thinly veiled attempt by Osteen to hide his bigotry.  And not a very good one at that and as much as I like Jake Tapper he should have called Osteen out on his woeful rhetoric.</p>
<p>And as for Miss Oprah.  I&#8217;ve been waiting for years for an apology from her for her &#8220;discovery&#8221;of this anti-gay bigot and using him on her daytime talk show and legitimizing him as a &#8220;Man of God&#8221;</p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/zqzJvIpuquk" height="250" width="450" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/oprahs-buddy-pastor-joel-osteen-gays-video.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ohio Crazy Janet Porter Begs For Money To Make Propaganda Filled Anti-Gay &#8220;Documentary&#8221; &#8211; Video</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/ohio-crazy-janet-porter-begs-money-propaganda-filled-anti-gay-documentary-video.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/ohio-crazy-janet-porter-begs-money-propaganda-filled-anti-gay-documentary-video.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 11:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bigot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith2Action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Janet Porter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kick(intheass)starter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lunatic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ohio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[propaganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serial killers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23427</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ohio based hate group Faith2Action&#8217;s Janet Porter (a Linda Harvey wannabee) is out with a low budget trailer and begging for right-wing welfare (money donations) to make her new anti-gay propaganda filled  &#8221;documentary&#8221; The Criminalization of Christianity that warns America that “time and freedom are running out” in the fight to stop the gay rights [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ohio based hate group <em>Faith2Action&#8217;s</em> Janet Porter <em>(a Linda Harvey wannabee)</em> is out with a low budget trailer and begging for right-wing welfare <em>(money donations)</em> to make her new anti-gay propaganda filled  &#8221;documentary&#8221; <em>The Criminalization of Christianity</em> that warns America that “time and freedom are running out” in the fight to stop the gay rights movement and “If homosexual activists achieve their goal of the criminalization of Christianity.” <strong>*GASP!*</strong></p>
<p>D-List hater Porter formerly known as Janet Folger, is the founder and president of <a href="http://f2a.org/">Faith2Action,</a> a site dedicated to defending &#8220;<a title="Pro-family" href="/wiki/Pro-family">pro-family</a>&#8221; values but mostly known for as a group opposing the Local Law Enforcement Hate Crimes Prevention Act of 2007.</p>
<p>Porter has compared  homosexuality to &#8220;alcoholism&#8221; and &#8220;kleptomania&#8221; and firmly <em>(and delusionally)</em> believes that &#8220;Christians&#8221; are being victimized by the <a title="Media" href="/wiki/Media">media</a> and popular culture and that gay rights groups have persuaded Americans that Christians who condemn homosexuality are intolerant, while actually it is gay people and their supporters who are intolerant of Christians.</p>
<p>In her disgusting trailer below, Porter claims that gay rights advocates are “threatening marriage,” “threatening our children” and “threatening freedom” and makes references to the Jerry Sandusky being gay and his  abuse case<em> (Sandusky was married and not gay</em>), Chick-fil-A,  and a Michael Swift article from 1987 which Religious Right lunatics still over 25 years later apparently don&#8217;t realize was <a href="http://www.ralliance.org/GayAgenda.html">satire</a> along with scary ominous music and a link on their website to <strong>&#8220;DONATE&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>What is it about the midwest and its high rate of producing serial killers and anti-gay &#8220;christian&#8221; lunatics?</p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/OsQM-CK0La4" height="250" width="450" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/ohio-crazy-janet-porter-begs-money-propaganda-filled-anti-gay-documentary-video.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marie Osmond Stands Up Against Her Anti-Gay Family Speaks Out For LGBT Equality: VIDEO</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/marie-osmond-stands-anti-gay-family-speaks-lgbt-equality-video.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/marie-osmond-stands-anti-gay-family-speaks-lgbt-equality-video.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 10:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civil rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LDS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marie Osmond]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mormon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[straight ally]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Utah]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23424</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Coming right on the heels of her families hateful anti-gay &#8220;Celebration of Marriage&#8221; rally in Salt Lake City, UT this past week Marie Osmond talked with Diane Sawyer and let her know that she believes in marriage equality. &#8220;The God that I believe in is a god of love, not fear. I don&#8217;t tell my [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Coming right on the heels of her families hateful anti-gay <a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/osmond-family-host-anti-gay-marriage-hate-rally-slc-utah.html">&#8220;Celebration of Marriage&#8221; </a>rally in Salt Lake City, UT this past week Marie Osmond talked with Diane Sawyer and let her know that she believes in marriage equality.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;The God that I believe in is a god of love, not fear. I don&#8217;t tell my children if you&#8217;re not good you&#8217;re going to Hell. I tell my children that God will be there for them when they struggle. That&#8217;s the God I believe in&#8230;I believe in [my lesbian daughter's] civil rights, as a mother. I think my daughter deserves everything that she desires in life. She&#8217;s a good girl. She&#8217;s a wonderful child. I don&#8217;t think God made one color flower. I think he made many&#8230;&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>It is nice to see Marie Osmond finally standing against her anti-gay family and the Mormon church and speaking out for the civil rights of gays and lesbians and supporting her lesbian daughter.</p>
<p><em><strong>BRAVA DIVA!</strong></em></p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/oAz4HJ-IFf0" height="250" width="450" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/marie-osmond-stands-anti-gay-family-speaks-lgbt-equality-video.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.199 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-01 07:51:05 -->
