<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Back2Stonewall</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com</link>
	<description>An Unapologetic LGBT News Site - We&#039;re HERE,. We&#039;re Queer, F#@king DEAL With It!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 09:54:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>KY Legislature Overides Governors VETO, Votes Religious Freedom To Discriminate Bill Into Law</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/ky-legislature-overides-governors-veto-votes-religious-freedom-discriminate-bill-law.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/ky-legislature-overides-governors-veto-votes-religious-freedom-discriminate-bill-law.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 09:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[assholes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bigots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kentucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pander]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religious freedom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shamefull]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23264</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Kentucky House and Senate voted by overwhelming margins Tuesday night to override Gov. Steve Beshear’s veto of the controversial “religious freedom” bill that would not only give religious organizations but also individuals the right to ignore any state or city anti-discrimination laws on the basis of &#8220;religious freedom&#8221; The House’s 79-15 vote sent House [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Most-evil.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23265" alt="Most evil" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Most-evil.png" width="300" height="173" /></a></p>
<p>The Kentucky House and Senate voted by overwhelming margins Tuesday night to override Gov. Steve Beshear’s veto of the controversial “religious freedom” bill that would not only give religious organizations but also individuals the right to ignore any state or city anti-discrimination laws on the basis of &#8220;religious freedom&#8221;</p>
<p>The House’s 79-15 vote sent House Bill 279 to the Senate, which voted 32-6 to override the Governors VETO.</p>
<p>Kentucky Governor Steve Beshear released a statement saying he was disappointed with the override of the only bill he vetoed in the 2013 legislative session. “As I explained in my veto message, I have significant concerns that this bill will cause serious unintentional consequences that could threaten public safety, health care, and individuals’ civil rights.”</p>
<p>HB 279 says that government shall not infringe on any person’s sincerely held religious beliefs unless it can show with “clear and convincing evidence” some compelling governmental interest for doing so.</p>
<p>Gay-rights and human-rights groups led the opposition to the bill, warned that it could be used to challenge local laws in Louisville, Lexington, Covington and Vicco designed to protect not only gays and lesbians from discrimination but could also be used to override racial and anti-discrimination laws geared to protect women. And possibly result in the withholding of needed medical care or te withholding of abortions using religious beliefs as a justification for abuse.</p>
<p>Chris Hartman, director of the Fairness Campaign, noted that the bill passed as the U.S. Supreme Court hears arguments on same-sex marriage. “Today the commonwealth took a step backwards in protecting its residents at the same time the United States Supreme Court was hearing arguments that will advance the rights of Americans. It’s sad and it’s disheartening,” he said.</p>
<p>While the Kentucky Senate is Republican controlled,  Kentucky&#8217;s House is overwhelming Democratic.  House Speaker Greg Stumbo, D-Prestonsburg, cowardly declined to give a final tally for the vote to override Gov. Steve Beshear&#8217;s veto of House Bill 279</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/ky-legislature-overides-governors-veto-votes-religious-freedom-discriminate-bill-law.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>From Stonewall to the Supreme Court, LGBT Accomplishments Over The Decades</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/stonewall-supreme-court-lgbt-accomplishments-decades.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/stonewall-supreme-court-lgbt-accomplishments-decades.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 02:35:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tim Franco</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT History]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23253</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While we all sit glued to the internet and television waiting for history to be made with the Supreme Court Prop 8 and DOMA decisions, I can&#8217;t help but think of how much the LGBT community has progressed over the years. On Tuesday of this week, when we all were intently waiting for the Supreme [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/InjusticeToOne.gif"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-23254" alt="InjusticeToOne" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/InjusticeToOne.gif" width="225" height="201" /></a>While we all sit glued to the internet and television waiting for history to be made with the Supreme Court Prop 8 and DOMA decisions, I can&#8217;t help but think of how much the LGBT community has progressed over the years.</p>
<p>On Tuesday of this week, when we all were intently waiting for the Supreme Court to make it&#8217;s decision on Prop 8, the thought hit me as to how historic this is. I started thinking back to how much things have changed even in the last 10 to 15 years. I remember when Will &amp; Grace debuted on NBC how it stirred up many conversations about a &#8220;gay&#8221; show on television. I also remember finding out the reason the show came to an end was because the NBC executive, at the time, didn&#8217;t find it &#8220;appropriate&#8221; to have a television show on his network that promoted &#8220;the gay lifestyle&#8221;. Now, only 7 years later, I can turn on the same network, NBC and find the show The New Normal which not only features a loving and &#8220;normal&#8221; gay couple, but one who is planning on having a family, basically portraying society&#8217;s &#8220;new normal&#8221;.</p>
<p>This shows an important paradigm shift in our society. In 2006 one of the most popular television shows in history was pulled off the air because it had to many homosexual references and now only 7 years later it is airing a show about same sex couple for what they are, 2 people in a normal, loving and stable relationship.</p>
<p>This is a perfect example at the amount of change that has lead us to the monumental times we are now in. If we think all the way back to June 28, 1969, patrons of a Greenwich Village bar decided to stand up for the first time to New York City police. They stood up and said for the first time out loud that they were going to be treated equally. They had the bravery to stand up in a time where it was still illegal in many places for homosexuals to get together in a setting like a bar.</p>
<p>Then in 1977 an amazing thing happened in San Francisco. One of the pioneers and truly a hero in the LGBT community made his stand.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Gay brothers and sisters,&#8230; You must come out. Come out&#8230; to your parents&#8230; I know that it is hard and will hurt them but think about how they will hurt you in the voting booth! Come out to your relatives&#8230; come out to your friends&#8230; if indeed they are your friends. Come out to your neighbors&#8230; to your fellow workers&#8230; to the people who work where you eat and shop&#8230; come out only to the people you know, and who know you. Not to anyone else. But once and for all, break down the myths, destroy the lies and distortions. For your sake. For their sake. For the sake of the youngsters who are becoming scared by the votes from Dade to Eugene.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>In 1977 Harvey Milk won a seat as a San Francisco city supervisor. While he was in office he began organizing rallies for gay rights as well was responsible for passing a stringent gay rights ordinance for the city. Sadly on November 27, 1978 Harvey Milk and city Mayor George Moscone were assassinated by Dan White.</p>
<p>Over the years the LGBT community has had many heroes. In my opinion each one of us who stands up for equality and refuse to let fear control us are heroes. Earlier today I read a post that stated that one person felt they did more for LGBT rights that others because he spent a lot of his own money and personally went to Washington DC and rallied for rights. I have to say that I think it&#8217;s amazing that he was able and willing to do that, but the point was made that not all of us may have those resources. Another point was made that every person who voices their support for LGBT equality is doing something invaluable to the fight for LGBT rights.</p>
<p>I made a comment that it is not one single act that one of us does that helps move this fight forward, it is a combination of all our actions, big and small that make this fight work. The person who is not afraid to tell their family, their friends and the world who they are is just as important as the person who goes to Washington or joins rallies. The two boyfriends who walk down the street not afraid to hold hands tell society that they will accept nothing less than to be treated equally. The lesbian couple who went to the Michigan Supreme Court to challenge the adoption laws and marriage laws in the state are showing society that they are tired of being considered second class. To every LGBT person and the amazing straight allies who went to the voting booth last November and choose a candidate both Federally and Local who they knew would support LGBT rights told the country that it&#8217;s time for change. To the brave individuals who went to the Unites States Supreme Court to have Prop 8 and DOMA challenged are telling America that it is now the time for change. Every action combined is what brought us to this point. From holding hands, to refusing to be afraid to be who we are and to standing up for the rights that we deserve, all these actions big and small have allowed us to achieve everything we have over the years.</p>
<p>I was sitting at work yesterday reflecting about this and I was thinking. This is history in the making. The excitement I felt along with millions of other Americans must have been the same excitement that was felt in 1964 when the Civil Rights Act was passed and in 1967 when the Supreme Court voided the ban on interracial marriages. I keep thinking about my kids, picturing them opening their history books (or probably iPads) and reading about what is happening this week. It makes me incredibly proud to be alive to witness this historic event as well as doing everything I can to make change happen. Congratulations to all of us gay and straight  This is truly an accomplishment. To quote an amazing man who made it his life&#8217;s mission to fight for equality -</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;An injustice to one is an injustice to all&#8221; &#8211; Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/stonewall-supreme-court-lgbt-accomplishments-decades.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>From Gaybies To Love Me Maybes; Tales Of Being Openly Gay</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/gaybies-love-maybes-tales-openly-gay.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/gaybies-love-maybes-tales-openly-gay.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 01:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinions and Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay categories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay categorization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay couples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay esteem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay labels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay lifestyles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay man]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay names]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay outlook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay perception]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay self esteem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay self hate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay Sex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay sex categories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay stigma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growing up gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[in the closet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life after coming out of the closet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stages of development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23060</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Okay I&#8217;m back here again. After I said that I had written the last tale of growing up gay I realized that the story didn&#8217;t end there for me. Nor does it end for the rest of us when we come out. Why? Because we continue to grow and change. Evolve. Most notably this all [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-TW1O2m-L2A0/TuiFtIhqnuI/AAAAAAAAAno/sZZ_PK3PrnE/s1600/img18_Gayart.JPG" width="518" height="346" /></p>
<p>Okay I&#8217;m back here again. After I said that I had written the last tale of growing up gay I realized that the story didn&#8217;t end there for me. Nor does it end for the rest of us when we come out. Why? Because we continue to grow and change. Evolve. Most notably this all happens within the first couple of years. You discover so much about what being gay means to you. All the existential introspective listening to music while pondering your life occurs in this time period.</p>
<p>So I wanted to again write about the experiences I&#8217;ve had and to the best of my ability generalize it as I feel many gay men may have at some point experienced these stages. Because we reconcile those experiences and learn from our past when we talk about them. This isn&#8217;t so much a tale as it is just an exercise in random, yet meaningful, assortments of different stages/aspects we go through.</p>
<p><strong>Gaybies</strong></p>
<p>This is the term given to gay men the first year that they are officially out of the closet. It&#8217;s generalized that way because in a sense you&#8217;ve been born again. The world is new, and this is the time when you can actually celebrate who you are openly.  Everything in the world seems so big. More real. You could definitely compare it to the first time Mary Tyler Moore walked the streets of New York City. You feel so revitalized and aware of pleasures, both simplistic and deep.</p>
<p>There are so many firsts that occur when you step out into the world as a gay man. No more trying to hide the fact that you love men and want to have sex with them. You openly talk about sex. Some of us during this stage just want sex. Lots and lots of sex. One of the many advantages of being a member of this community is that you&#8217;ll find out is that sex isn&#8217;t hard to find.  And I certainly will not begrudge anyone that partakes in this behavior (safely).</p>
<p>It&#8217;s all exciting and you want to soak up every catch phrase and whatever the in thing to do is at that time. Go to every gay bar that you can get into. The rush of excitement every time you write down the words &#8220;I&#8217;m gay&#8221;. You take a deep breath every time you say it to someone who doesn&#8217;t know the truth yet and are either greeted with a displeasing reaction so you can give a quick rebuttal that you&#8217;ve rehearsed a thousand times mentally. Or take a huge sigh of relief when they are welcoming and loving.</p>
<p>But this stage isn&#8217;t all fun. Just with everything else in life this time period teaches you that there is a darker side to just about every community. More notably, this is when you find out about rejection. Scathing, brutally honest rejection. I&#8217;m not talking about when a crush says no thank you after you have finally worked up the courage to ask them out. It&#8217;s when you walk up to a prospective guy to show interest in you will flat out tell you whether they like you or not.</p>
<p>They will unabashedly tell you everything that&#8217;s right or wrong with you. Wrong hair, terrible shoes, lame accessories, ill-fitting clothes, dieting tips and workout routines they think would help you look better. That&#8217;s just in the first minute of talking to him. We also quickly learn about the social hierarchy of sex and how many will immediately size you up within 3 seconds and label you a top, bottom, verse, dom top. power bottom, vers top, vers bottom or anything in between. You will also be categorized based on size and body hair as if you are a new produce that needs to be bagged tagged and shelved until ready for use,</p>
<p>It could range from gym rat, otter, bear, leather daddy, twink, cub, &#8220;straight acting&#8221; gaypster (gay hipster) gaymer (gay gamer) bromo (gay dude bro) manther (gay cougar), a bunch of other lame inane adjectives or the ever so dreaded &#8220;average&#8221;. In my first year of being out, I&#8217;d say the labels is what I struggled with most because I outright abhor them. As many gay people of color will tell you, we&#8217;ve already had enough with being categorized just by your natural appearance.  I&#8217;m in no way knocking it if you feel like they embody your personality. But my free loving nature resists any attempts to categorization or labels. .</p>
<p><strong>Anger/Rejection of Perceived Gay Norms</strong></p>
<p>After your gayby year, you feel like you&#8217;ve got the hang of it. Because this is most likely the most self-indulgent superficial year of your life. At least it was for me. I took full advantage of all the gay world had to offer and more. But I came down hard to reality after that year. Because we learn about how we are truly affected by society and what is really going on with us. Our problems as a community. This can result in a lot of anger.</p>
<p>The reality of the world may lead to this stage of anger because as both an outsider and eventually an insider you see vanity and self-absorbed tendencies to the max. After that much self-indulgence you become frustrated because that has been your world for such a long time. Failing to realize the true complexity the gay community could appear to have a total disregard for feelings or a total lack of acceptance to any differences. There&#8217;s more than likely frustration that accompanies this because you felt that it was different. Then you learn that it is all about the places you go and the people you associate.</p>
<p>This time is also marked by, depending on your perspective, harsh realization that people don&#8217;t always equate sex with love. Or maybe you’re angry because you are just fed up with the archaic labels and shallow pace the gay community seems to be set in. You may see the majority of gay men as superficial egotistical airbags.</p>
<p>This is the time where you may become outspoken and angry at society. Angered how religion and God&#8217;s Word is twisted to fit man&#8217;s image when it&#8217;s fueled by greed and power. You begin to reciprocate the anger that is directed at you because you remember all the times you were afraid of being who you were before coming out.  You are angry because you feel like you always have to be on guard to protect yourself from those incensed with hate and bigotry.</p>
<p><strong>Introspection of Gay Lifestyles</strong></p>
<p>This is when we look inside for answers because we want to make sense of this community. All the things that you have learned and all the feelings of anger and frustration build to a point where you quietly back away from all things gay. It&#8217;s not so much that you don&#8217;t want to be gay it&#8217;s your way of searching for answers. You ask yourself how you can find contentment in so much chaos. You speculate and theorize about how you can coexist with this pace. Then you begin to question your outlook.</p>
<p>This is the time that you learn the true nature of your sexuality. You learn the mechanics of having sex with another man. And now that you&#8217;re listening and asking real questions about life, you learn and hear the real personal impact of HIV/AIDS from the people you meet. You realize they are not the virus, that they are people.</p>
<p>This is also when you question everything that you had to push back out of your mind because being gay was the only thing that mattered. But now you&#8217;re learning that it&#8217;s only one aspect of who you are. You question the very notion of faith and what you believe to be truth or creature comforts.</p>
<p>You&#8217;ve learned about activism and how to get involved in fundraisers for hospice care and youth centers. You donate to the cause and let your actions speak for you rather than heated emotions taking over. You reconcile so much of the anger you had both with yourself and with society. Sometimes, after years of being in this community, the sad, detached, distrustful, and overall apprehensive feelings of expecting anyone of real value coming into your life has merely been the result of your outlook.</p>
<p><strong>Gay Acceptance</strong></p>
<p>All this time you&#8217;ve spent thinking, wondering who you are and what gay means, you come to a serene, clear moment that places all of these emotions that you&#8217;ve had about the gay community and about yourself. Again you learn to not look at any person or situation by the few superficial aspects that commonly define them.</p>
<p>This is when you&#8217;ve finally and completely accepted yourself and your sexuality. No longer do you feel like you have to declare how masculine you are to prove your worth as a man  No longer are you concerned with how gay you look because you know that you can only live your life. Instead of being angry and having resentment towards those that do have it all together or all the advantages of society. this is the time where you just take action accordingly.</p>
<p>Getting involved to help when and where you can. By this time in your life you realize that maybe you shouldn&#8217;t look at movies or base finding love off of sitcoms. That true genuine people are around that will share your interests and concerned for your well-being. At this point when you write the words &#8220;I&#8217;m gay&#8221; you see it as just a part of who you are, like hair color or height. This is the time marked by when you&#8217;re looking for someone to spend your life with, you aren&#8217;t too concerned with him being a top or bottom as chemistry will work that all out, You&#8217;ll care more about if he&#8217;s genuine, engaging, and considerate to who you are and building your lives together.</p>
<p>These are when you have friends in your life that instead of picking you a part because of their own neuroses will always pick you up when you fall. You are finally able to see a plethora of loving, caring men that truly want to help you gain your identity that&#8217;s separate from all the inane sometimes uninspired labels. All visible from the beginning that maybe you overlooked. You will learn that you&#8217;ve learned that you are not just a letter to the acronym of LGBT and neither are the rest of the men of this community. You recognize that gay is not the subgroup in this community. This the moment that you truly are a complete, actualized being.</p>
<p>Again this is a very rough assortment of some of what we experience. Some of us go through all these aspects and stages one at a time, all at the same time or none at all. This was basically to show that we are in fact always growing no matter what stage.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/gaybies-love-maybes-tales-openly-gay.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NAMING NAMES: The 10 Democratic Senators Who DO NOT Support Same Sex Marriage</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/naming-names-10-democratic-senators-support-sex-marriage.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/naming-names-10-democratic-senators-support-sex-marriage.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 10:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cowards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DEM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DNC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politicians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prop 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traitors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23239</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; 1. Sen. Bob Casey (D-Pa.) backs civil unions but not gay marriage. &#8220;In the past, Senator Casey has supported civil unions and he is closely following the debate around DOMA. He intends to thoroughly review any legislation on this when it comes before the Senate,&#8221; said Casey&#8217;s spokesman John Rizzo. Asked if the senator [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><strong><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/LOSER.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23240" alt="LOSER" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/LOSER.png" width="299" height="189" /></a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>1. Sen. Bob Casey (D-Pa.)</strong> backs civil unions but not gay marriage.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the past, Senator Casey has supported civil unions and he is closely following the debate around DOMA. He intends to thoroughly review any legislation on this when it comes before the Senate,&#8221; said Casey&#8217;s spokesman John Rizzo.</p>
<p>Asked if the senator supports the repeal of DOMA, Rizzo simply repeated that Casey will review any legislation that comes before the Senate.</p>
<p><strong>2. Sen. Joe Manchin (D-W.Va.)</strong> continues to back DOMA, in addition to opposing same-sex marriage.</p>
<p>&#8220;Senator Manchin believes that a marriage is a union between one man and one woman. His beliefs are guided by his faith, and he supports the Defense of Marriage Act,&#8221; said Manchin spokeswoman Katie Longo.</p>
<p><strong>3. Sen. Kay Hagan (D-N.C.)</strong> has not publicly come out in support of marriage equality, although she did oppose North Carolina&#8217;s constitutional ban on same-sex marriage. In a statement last year, she said it would have &#8220;<a href="http://www.advocate.com/news/daily-news/2012/02/22/senator-kay-hagan-speaks-out-against-antigay-amendment-1" target="_hplink">far-reaching negative consequences</a> for our families, our children and our communities.&#8221; In 2008, Q-Notes also reported that Hagan said she believed the issue should be <a href="http://goqnotes.com/top2008/top09_030808.html" target="_hplink">left up to the states to decide</a>.</p>
<p><strong>4. Sen. Bill Nelson (D-Fla.)</strong> believes marriage is between a man and a woman.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sen. Nelson strongly supports civil rights for same-sex couples, while believing marriage should be between a man and a woman,&#8221; Nelson spokesman Ryan Brown said in a statement. &#8220;The issue will likely be decided by the U.S. Supreme Court before the end of the year.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>5. Sen. Heidi Heitkamp (D-N.D.)</strong> supported allowing states to decide what to do about marriage but did not take a position beyond that.</p>
<p>&#8220;Senator Heitkamp believes this should be handled on a state-by-state basis,&#8221; said Heitkamp&#8217;s communications director, Whitney Phillips.</p>
<p><strong>6. Sen. Mary Landrieu (D-La.)</strong> has mostly shied away from discussing gay marriage in public, <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/rebeccaberg/at-risk-democratic-senators-shy-away-from-marriage-equality" target="_hplink">offering only</a> her support for people&#8217;s right to &#8220;love who they love.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I feel very strongly that people should be allowed to love who they love, but unfortunately my state has a very strong ban against gay marriage constitutionally, so I&#8217;m going to have to think really carefully and listen to the voters of my state about that issue,&#8221; Landrieu said. &#8220;But it&#8217;s very tough because I think most people believe that people should love who they love.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Louisiana senator, who is up for reelection in 2014, <a href="http://www.landrieu.senate.gov/?p=press_release&amp;id=303" target="_hplink">voted against</a> an amendment in 2006 that would place a constitutional ban of same-sex marriage, even though at the time she defined marriage as &#8220;a sacred union between one man and one woman.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>7. Sen. Tom Carper (D-Del.)</strong> opposes DOMA and co-signed an amicus brief last much that urged the Supreme Court to invalidate Section 3 of that law. But the senator has yet to endorse same-sex marriage as a legal right.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sen. Carper was proud to support Delaware’s efforts to enact Civil Union legislation and earlier this month he joined 211 of his Congressional colleagues in co-signing the Amicus brief that urges the Supreme Court to invalidate Section 3 of DOMA,&#8221; his office said in a statement. &#8220;He has also said that he would vote to repeal DOMA. He also opposed President Bush’s attempt to enact a constitutional amendment to define marriage as between one man and one woman. Like many Americans including Presidents Obama and Clinton, Sen. Carper’s views on this issue have evolved, and continue to evolve. He continues to give this issue a great deal of consideration.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>8. Sen. Tim Johnson (D-S.D.)</strong> does not support same-sex marriage.</p>
<p>&#8220;He has not changed his position on marriage equality,&#8221; Johnson&#8217;s office said. Asked if that meant he does support the right of a gay couple to marry, the office replied: &#8220;No.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>9. Sen. Joe Donnelly (D-Ind.)</strong> <a href="http://www.wsbt.com/news/wsbt-donnelly-splits-with-obama-on-samesex-marriage-20120510,0,1902684.story" target="_hplink">opposed same-sex marriage during the campaign</a>. His office said it would send offer a statement of explanation for his current position, though it hadn&#8217;t done so by the time of publication.</p>
<p><strong>10. Sen. Mark Pryor (D-Ark.)</strong> does not support same-sex marriage.</p>
<p>&#8220;Senator Pryor’s position on same-sex marriage has not changed,&#8221; said his spokeswoman, Lucy Speed. Was that opposed to gay marriage? &#8220;Yes,&#8221; she replied.</p></blockquote>
<p>Considering that same-sex marriage support  is an official  plank of the Democratic Party each of those l;listed above should be chastised by the DNC and<em><strong>  NOT ONE THEM</strong></em> should get one red cent for re-election campaigns from the Democratic national Committee.</p>
<p>ELECT BETTER DEMOCRATS.</p>
<pre>Source:  <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/gay-marriage-rights_n_2957319.html?ncid=edlinkusaolp00000003&amp;ir=Gay%20Voices">Huffington Post:</a></pre>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/naming-names-10-democratic-senators-support-sex-marriage.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>LGBT Allies Ban Together To Welcome Gay Athletes</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/lgbt-allies-ban-gay-athletes.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/lgbt-allies-ban-gay-athletes.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 01:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brendon Ayanbadejo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gays in sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lgbt allies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lgnt advocates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taylor Hudson]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23235</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is sometimes astonishing to witness those men and women that dedicate their lives to fair and equal treatment, regardless of race, gender, and sexual orientation. And as the result of more rumors that an NFL player may come out soon it has called attention to those LGBT allies that support equal rights. Many of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/american_football.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23236" alt="american_football" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/american_football.jpg" width="177" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>It is sometimes astonishing to witness those men and women that dedicate their lives to fair and equal treatment, regardless of race, gender, and sexual orientation. And as the result of more rumors that an NFL player may come out soon it has called attention to those LGBT allies that support equal rights. Many of them current and former athletes are speaking out calling for their perspective leagues to be welcoming and supporting. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/gay-nfl-player_n_2958262.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>&#8220;We want to let this NFL player &#8212; or any closeted gay player &#8212; know that you have backup. Your community, whether it is your teammates or your fan base is here to support you,&#8221; said Hudson Taylor, founder and executive director of Athlete Ally, in a statement. Athlete Ally is a 11,000-member group that works to end homophobia in sports.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>NFL linebacker Scott Fujita, who is an Athlete Ally ambassador and most recently played with the Cleveland Browns, added, &#8220;The last thing we want to do is pressure someone into coming out or send a message that coming out is in some way better or more courageous than not. Everyone is different and has his or her own way of living life. At the same time, encouraging fans to stand up for inclusion in sports is fundamental to Athlete Ally&#8217;s mission and inextricably bound to moments like this.&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>&#8220;This isn&#8217;t about one player, it&#8217;s about all of us,&#8221; said Baltimore Ravens linebacker Brendon Ayanbadejo, who is chairman of the Athlete Ally Advisory Board, in a statement. &#8220;It&#8217;s about being a good teammate and a loyal fan. It&#8217;s about respect and everything the NFL stands for.&#8221;</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>How soon will we see an openly gay man/woman in professional sports? Could it happen this year? Anything is possible. But lets not kid ourselves. National sports leagues are known for their overt homophobia that only in the past few years is publicly reprimanded. That&#8217;s what makes allies like this so important because it shows that these men and women can and should be who they are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/lgbt-allies-ban-gay-athletes.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NOM&#8217;s Brian Brown(shirt) LIES and RANTS to the Washington Post &#8211; Video</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brownshirt-lies-rants-washington-post-video.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brownshirt-lies-rants-washington-post-video.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 22:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brian Brown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hate rally]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NOM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prop 8]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23228</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Its egregious!&#8221;  LOL! What a loser. (And ugly to boot) And the number of haters at the NOM Rally was more like 5,000.  Many of them bused in by Ruben Diaz which is extremely pathetic considering that they&#8217;ve been planning, begging and working with the FRC for months on this hate March. FAIL! &#160; &#160;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><center><iframe src="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/video/videoEmbed.html?uuid=837378ae-9653-11e2-9e23-09dce87f75a1&amp;noheadline=0" height="325" width="454" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></center><em><strong>&#8220;Its egregious!&#8221;  LOL!</strong></em></p>
<p>What a loser. <em>(And ugly to boot)</em></p>
<p>And the number of haters at the NOM Rally was more like 5,000.  Many of them bused in by Ruben Diaz which is extremely pathetic considering that they&#8217;ve been planning, begging and working with the FRC for months on this hate March.</p>
<p><strong>FAIL!</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brownshirt-lies-rants-washington-post-video.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prop 8 Supreme Court Transcript and Audio Recording Released &#8211; Read, Listen HERE!</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/prop-8-supreme-court-transcript-audio-recording-released-read-listen-here.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/prop-8-supreme-court-transcript-audio-recording-released-read-listen-here.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prop 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recording]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SCOTUS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supreme Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transcript]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23223</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[And here&#8217;s the transcript]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Gay-kiss1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23224" alt="Gay kiss" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Gay-kiss1.png" width="299" height="186" /></a></p>
<p><center><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F85024873" height="166" width="75%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe></center>And here&#8217;s the <a href="http://www.supremecourt.gov/oral_arguments/argument_transcripts/12-144a.pdf" target="_blank">transcript</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/prop-8-supreme-court-transcript-audio-recording-released-read-listen-here.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NOM&#8217;s Brian Brown: If We Lose We&#8217;ll Force A Constitutional Amendment Against Gay Marriage</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brown-lose-force-constitutional-amendment-gay-marriage.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brown-lose-force-constitutional-amendment-gay-marriage.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 09:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Religious Morons and Anti-Gay Idiots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[con men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Douchebag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prop 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SCOTUS]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23217</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I think we’re going to win these cases. But say the worst happens and we lose in a broad way – that means that the Court somehow does a Roe, a Roe v. Wade, on marriage and says that all these state constitutional amendments are overturned, gay marriage is now a constitutional right – well, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Bryan-Brown-evil.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23218" alt="Bryan Brown evil" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Bryan-Brown-evil.png" width="298" height="183" /></a></p>
<p><em>&#8220;I think we’re going to win these cases. But say the worst happens and we lose in a broad way – that means that the Court somehow does a Roe, a Roe v. Wade, on marriage and says that all these state constitutional amendments are overturned, gay marriage is now a constitutional right – well, we’re  going to press forward on a Federal Marriage Amendment. We’ve always  supported a Federal Marriage Amendment, and there’s a lot of  misconceptions about it. Some people try and argue, ‘Well, this is  against federalism.’ No, our founders gave us a system where we can  amend the Constitution.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;We shouldn’t have to do this, we shouldn’t have  to worry about activist judges, you know, making up out of thin air a  constitutional right that obviously none of our founders found there and no one found there until quite recently. But if we do, for us, the  Federal Marriage Amendment is a way that people can stand up and say, ‘Enough is enough.’ We need a solution in this country, we cannot be, as Lincoln said, half slave, half free. We can’t have a country on key  moral questions where we’re just, where we don’t have a solution. And if the Court forces a solution, the way we’ll amend that is through  the  Federal Marriage Amendment.&#8221;</em> &#8211; National Organization for Marriage hate group leader <a href="http://www.rightwingwatch.org/content/nom-s-brown-invokes-lincoln-push-federal-marriage-amendment-we-cannot-be-half-slave-half-fre" target="_blank">Brian Brown</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Knowing that he&#8217;s going to lose the Supreme Court case against DOMA and Prop 8 professional hater and  fake University doctorate holder &#8220;Dr.&#8221; Brian Brown is covering his overly ample fat ass by laying out his income strategies for the next four years.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/noms-brian-brown-lose-force-constitutional-amendment-gay-marriage.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rapper A$AP Rocky Says Hip Hop Culture Evolving On Gay Movement</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/rapper-aap-rocky-hip-hop-culture-evolving-gay-movement-right.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/rapper-aap-rocky-hip-hop-culture-evolving-gay-movement-right.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 23:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment - Travel - Leisure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A$AP Rocky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civil rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay and black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jay Z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT musicans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT rappers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23213</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s no secret that the Hip Hop music, widely associated with the African American community has been slated as one of the more homophobic (which I do not agree with at all). But from statisticians to casual observers believe that this confounded belief has seen a decrease as more affluent members of the African American community evolve [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="http://media.ticketmaster.com/tm/en-us/dbimages/130237a.jpg" /></p>
<p>It&#8217;s no secret that the Hip Hop music, widely associated with the African American community has been slated as one of the more homophobic (which I do not agree with at all). But from statisticians to casual observers believe that this confounded belief has seen a decrease as more affluent members of the African American community evolve in their assessment of gay rights, more have been vocal about it. Rapper A$AP Rocky is also in agreement of this noting how legends in the HipHop community are welcoming LGBT fans and musicians. Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/rapper-asap-rocky-gay-thing-hip-hop_n_2950676.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices">more</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>Harlem native <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/24/longliveasap-no-1-asap-rocky-who-is-asap-rocky_n_2541707.html" target="_hplink">A$AP Rocky</a> recently sounded off on &#8220;the gay thing&#8221; in hip hop during an interview with Alexander Wang for <a href="http://www.interviewmagazine.com/music/aap-rocky/#page3" target="_hplink">Interview Magazine.</a> The &#8220;Goldie&#8221; rapper says he wants to use his platform as an artist to let people know how he feels about the hot button topic.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>“So now that I’m here and I’ve got a microphone in my hand and about 6,000 people watching me, I need to tell them how I feel,&#8221; he said. &#8220;For instance, one big issue in hip hop is the gay thing. It’s 2013, and it’s a shame that, to this day, that topic still gets people all excited. It’s crazy. And it makes me upset that this topic even matters when it comes to hip hop, because it makes it seem like everybody in hip hop is small-minded or stupid &#8212; and that’s not the case.&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Rocky said that he treats everybody equal and he wants his listeners and followers to do the same. &#8220;We’ve got people <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/05/14/jay-z-gay-marriage-obama_n_1516614.html" target="_hplink">like Jay-Z</a>. We’ve got people <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/23/kanye-west-rant-grammys-jay-z-justin-timberalke_n_2751622.html" target="_hplink">like Kanye</a>. We’ve got people like me. We’re all prime examples of people who don’t think like that. I treat everybody equal, and so I want to be sure that my listeners and my followers do the same if they’re gonna represent me. And if I’m gonna represent them, then I also want to do it in a good way.”</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>So with this wave that&#8217;s taken over the country as far as acceptance, does this mean that we will see more artists and musicians emerge from the Hip Hop community that are members of the LGBT community? It certainly appears that it&#8217;s more plausible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/rapper-aap-rocky-hip-hop-culture-evolving-gay-movement-right.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>GLAAD Drops &#8220;Gay &amp; Lesbian&#8221; From Name, Will Now Be Knowm As GLAAD.  Huh?</title>
		<link>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/glaad-drops-gay-lesbian-name-knowm-glaad-huh.html</link>
		<comments>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/glaad-drops-gay-lesbian-name-knowm-glaad-huh.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 23:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will Kohler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT News From Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[branding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GLAAD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stupid]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.back2stonewall.com/?p=23209</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[GLAAD has officially ended the usage of their full name, the Gay &#38; Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation as not to alienate transsexuals. So from now on they will be known just by their old letters GLAAD. &#8220;It is a natural progression that reflects the work GLAAD&#8217;s staff is already leading,&#8221; said [spokesman Wilson] Cruz. &#8220;We respect and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/GLAAD1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-23210" alt="GLAAD" src="http://www.back2stonewall.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/GLAAD1.png" width="300" height="190" /></a>GLAAD has <a href="http://www.glaad.org/blog/glaad-affirms-commitment-trans-people-lgbt-community-and-allies-melissa-harris-perry-show" target="_blank">officially ended</a> the usage of their full name, the<em> Gay &amp; Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation </em>as not to alienate transsexuals. So from now on they will be known just by their old letters GLAAD.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is a natural progression that reflects the work GLAAD&#8217;s staff is already leading,&#8221; said [spokesman Wilson] Cruz. &#8220;We respect and honor the full name that the organization was founded with, but GLAAD&#8217;s work has expanded beyond fighting defamation to changing the culture. Our commitment to marriage equality, employment nondiscrimination, and other LGBT issues is stronger than ever, and now our name reflects our work on transgender issues as well as our work with allies.&#8221;</p>
<p>Okay.  Now I am not being transphobic here but is this absolutely the stupidest thing that you ever heard of?</p>
<p>Remember two years ago the Gay and Lesbian Task Forced dropped the &#8220;gay&#8221; and &#8220;lesbian&#8221; to just the Task Force.</p>
<p>It is a very sad day when the words Gay and Lesbian are deemed inappropriate so a &#8220;company&#8221; can brand itself to be more mainstream and inclusive to make more money.</p>
<p>But perhaps in a way its a good thing.</p>
<p>After all what intelligent, self-respecting gay, lesbian, or transsexual wants to be associated with a bunch of gAy-list  ass kissing starfuckers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.back2stonewall.com/2013/03/glaad-drops-gay-lesbian-name-knowm-glaad-huh.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.250 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-28 11:15:24 -->
