<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>unbrave girl</title>
	
	<link>http://www.unbravegirl.com</link>
	<description>welcome to the unbrave world!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 12:46:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
			<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Unbravegirl" /><feedburner:info uri="unbravegirl" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>Unbravegirl</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>On Running and Fear and the Big, Bad, Horrible Things</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Unbravegirl/~3/dCKurugsYZU/</link>
		<comments>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/on-running-and-fear/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 12:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blah, Blah, Blah (I can't even remember what this was about)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Challenges, Feats of Derring-Do and Stuff That Almost Killed Me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[danger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ME]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[running]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.unbravegirl.com/?p=6170</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p></p> On Monday evening, I sat down at my computer. I started reading news stories about the Boston Marathon bombing. And I cried. <p>Then I did something I’ve been meaning to do ever since I returned to the States this summer. Something I came close to doing a few times, but then I kept chickening [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_9070.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6173" alt="IMG_9070" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_9070-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>On Monday evening, I sat down at my computer. I started reading <a href="http://www.theatlanticwire.com/national/2013/04/photos-stories-kindness-boston-marathon-bombing/64258/">news stories about the Boston Marathon bombing</a>. And I cried.</p>
<p>Then I did something I’ve been meaning to do ever since I returned to the States this summer. Something I came close to doing a few times, but then I kept chickening out.</p>
<p>I signed up for a race – a <a href="http://giving.roswellpark.org/TeamCureChallenge/TOPS-5K-10K">10K in August to benefit Roswell Park Cancer Institute.</a></p>
<p>This will be my first race since <a title="The 10K Race of Doom (Part 2! Yay! I Didn’t Die! I think.)" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2012/05/great-wall-10k-part-2/">the Great Wall 10K in China</a>. And my first race in the States.</p>
<p>Even though I ran quite a few races in Asia, I&#8217;ve always been really intimidated about running a race here in the States.</p>
<p>After all, being the big, fat, slow, white girl was fine in Asia. A lot of people in Asia just kind of expect you to be a big, fat, slow white girl if you’re from America.</p>
<p>What can I say?</p>
<p>I was just living up to their expectations.</p>
<p>But here?</p>
<p>People around here probably know that not all white girls run like they’re stuck in five feet of Jello. Really, really thick Jello. The kind that’s probably made out of concrete.</p>
<p>And I’ve let fear – the fear that I’m going to be too slow and too self conscious and too surrounded by people in Spandex who actually know what they’re doing– stop me from signing up for a race.</p>
<p>But, you know what, guys?</p>
<p>Fear can go suck it.</p>
<p>And, cancer can go suck it, too.</p>
<p>Growing up, I’d always dreaded doing anything remotely athletic and competitive.</p>
<p>I hated gym class.</p>
<p>I couldn’t kick balls or jump ropes. I couldn&#8217;t balance on the balance beam. And the best I could manage to do on the climbing rope was to just kind of hang off the end like a bloated piñata until it became painful for everyone to watch and the gym teacher would take pity on me and let me sit down.</p>
<p>I did join the girl’s lacrosse team in high school. But that was only because it was the only sports team that didn’t require try-outs.</p>
<p>That and the plaid skirts. I was really into the plaid skirts.</p>
<div id="attachment_6177" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2938.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6177  " alt="I'm the terribly red-faced girl sitting on my coach's lap. I was obviously there for the comic relief." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2938-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I&#8217;m the red-faced girl, making goofy facial expressions &amp; sitting on my coach&#8217;s lap. Because what I lacked in athleticism, I made up for in social graces. Obviously.</p></div>
<p>I spent the majority of my time on the bench, cheering on my team or faking cramps to get out of actually having to play in a game.</p>
<p>And, my senior year, when the team started requiring try-outs, I didn’t even bother showing up to try out. I told myself I was too busy doing important senior year things. Like <a title="Nerding Out at Old Fort Niagara" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/old-fort-niagara/">reading historical fiction </a>and fake-singing in chorus and having crushes on boys I would never talk to.</p>
<p>I didn’t start running until about ten years ago – and I only started doing it then because it was the only form of exercise I could think of that didn’t require fancy stuff like gym equipment and hand-eye coordination.</p>
<p>And then I moved to Japan and started hanging out with runner people.</p>
<p>You know how it is.</p>
<p>You start hanging out with a bunch of runner people. And they somehow convince you that you’re runner people, too. They coerce you into signing up for a race with promises of free t-shirts. And the next thing you know, you’re standing in a parking lot holding a box of freeze-dried fish you just “won” at your first 5K.</p>
<div id="attachment_6171" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/DSC04915.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6171" alt="DSC04915" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/DSC04915-300x244.jpg" width="300" height="244" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">So this happened.</p></div>
<p>(Don’t be too impressed, guys. Everyone “won” fish at that race.)</p>
<p>If you’d told me back in high school that I would one day run <a title="Going the Distance" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2009/12/first-marathon-experience/">a full marathon</a>, I never would have believed you.</p>
<p>In fact, I can hardly believe you now.</p>
<p>I did a <i>wha</i>t?</p>
<p>Are you sure about that?</p>
<div id="attachment_6172" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 190px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/091129_12470001.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6172" alt="It's true! I ran a full marathon! I even have the grainy cell phone photos of runners in monkey costumes to prove it!" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/091129_12470001-180x300.jpg" width="180" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">It&#8217;s true! I ran a full marathon! I even have the grainy cell phone photos of runners in monkey costumes to prove it!</p></div>
<p>Even now I still don’t consider myself a runner. Not like some people are runners.</p>
<p>But doing races has never been about running for me.</p>
<p>Doing races has been about defying.</p>
<p>It was about defying every single bad memory of gym class.</p>
<p>It was about defying the dubious looks of my Japanese colleagues and students when I told them I was planning to run a 5K. Then a 10K. Then a half-marathon. Then a full marathon.</p>
<p>It was about defying my mother who would announce I was going to die every time I would announce I was signing up for another race.</p>
<p>It was about defying that little voice in my head. The voice that was always telling me, “You can’t do this. You’re not one of <i>those people</i>. You’re not a runner. You’re too fat. You’re too slow. Listen to your mother &#8212; you <em>are</em> going to die! Listen to me! Just give up and go back to your couch already.”</p>
<p>And I’d like to think that running this race in August will be my teeny tiny way of defying the Big, Bad, Horrible Thing that happened in Boston on Monday.</p>
<p>And all the Big, Bad, Horrible Things that happen in the world everyday.</p>
<p>The Big, Bad, Horrible Things that cause us to fear and hate and distrust each other.</p>
<p>The Big, Bad, Horrible Things that make us believe those little voices in our heads – the ones that are telling us that it&#8217;s all too scary and we should just give up and go back to our couches already.</p>
<p>Because, you know, what, guys?</p>
<p>Those Big, Bad, Horrible Things?</p>
<p>They can go suck it, too.</p>
<p><i>Do you run races? How did you get your start? Or have you ever wanted to run a race, but haven&#8217;t yet? What&#8217;s stopping you? (And if you want me to be your pushy runner person friend who coerces you into signing up for a race with promises of free t-shirts, I totally will. Trust me on this.)<br />
</i></p>
<p> </p>
<p><i>P.S. So now that I’ve stopped bugging you about voting for me for the <a title="Thank You! I Got You Unicorns! And I’m Totally Not Even Lying This Time!" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/2013-bloggies-win/">Bloggies</a>, I can start bugging you about donating to <a href="http://TOPS5K10K2013.kintera.org/unbravegirl">my race fundraising</a>, right? Because, uh, I kind of made this ridiculous goal of raising $500 for cancer research. But if anybody can help me reach a ridiculous goal, it&#8217;s you guys, amirite or AMIRITE? Let&#8217;s totally make this happen, okay?</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/on-running-and-fear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/on-running-and-fear/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Weeklyish Challengey Thingie: Do Stuff on My Own</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Unbravegirl/~3/EAYiEyJuHfs/</link>
		<comments>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/do-stuff-on-my-own/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Challenges, Feats of Derring-Do and Stuff That Almost Killed Me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ME]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solo travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.unbravegirl.com/?p=6136</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p></p> You know how I’m always going on and on about how awesome it is to do stuff solo, like traveling? And how it’s super awesome because you can eat potato chips for dinner or be a total nerd and nobody has to know? <p>That is, of course, until you blather on endlessly about it [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_0148.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6137" alt="IMG_0148" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_0148-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>You know how I’m always going on and on about how awesome it is to do stuff solo, like traveling? And how it’s super awesome because you can eat potato chips for dinner or be <a title="Nerding Out at Old Fort Niagara" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/old-fort-niagara/">a total nerd</a> and nobody has to know?</p>
<p>That is, of course, until you blather on endlessly about it on your blog and then <i>everybody</i> has to know. Whether or not they even <i>want</i> to know.</p>
<p>Well, you guys, it turns out I’m a big fat liar-pants.</p>
<p>You see, I haven’t exactly been flying solo since <a title="On Going Home" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2012/07/home/">returning to the States this past summer</a>.</p>
<p>I haven’t really done much solo traveling in the past nine months. The <a title="Five Reasons Why Taking the Train in the States Isn’t Crazy. So Stop Looking at Me So Funny" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/02/five-reasons-to-take-the-train-in-the-states/">one big trip I’ve taken so far </a>– to Washington, DC, and Durham, NC, this past winter – was spent visiting friends for the most part.</p>
<p>In fact, I haven&#8217;t really done much of anything by myself except for the occasional meal out or pants-shopping spree. After all, nobody needs to witness me attempting to shove my lower half into a pair of skinny jeans. And then eating a bucket of peanut butter cup ice cream for dinner afterwards because sometimes ice cream is the only thing that will dull the pain.</p>
<p>In fact, I rather wish I didn’t have to witness any of that myself.</p>
<p>Mind you, my not-doing-stuff-solo isn’t because I have a whole bunch of awesome friends around who are always volunteering to go out with me.</p>
<p>All in all, I have about three people I can regularly count on to do stuff with me.</p>
<p>And two of those people happen to be <a title="Stuff I Really Kind of Like about My Life at Home: My Parents" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2012/12/my-parents/">my parents</a>.</p>
<p>I know I should be working harder on going out to meet new people and reconnecting with old friends in the area. But seeing as I’m not entirely sure how long I’ll be in Buffalo, I haven&#8217;t really been putting that much effort into my social life.</p>
<p>After all, I don’t want to get people all excited about me, and then up and leave. That would just be rude, wouldn&#8217;t it?</p>
<div id="attachment_5526" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_6135.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5526" alt="Obviously once you get to know me, you're never going to want me to leave. OBVIOUSLY." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_6135-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Obviously once you get to know me, you&#8217;re never going to want me to leave. OBVIOUSLY.</p></div>
<p>The reason why I haven’t been doing much stuff on my own since my return is because it makes me feel a bit, umm, well, self-conscious.</p>
<p>It’s stupid.</p>
<p>I know.</p>
<p>You’d think six years of being the big, sweaty, white girl in Asia would have effectively cured me of any self-consciousness.</p>
<p>But doing stuff on my own in Asia was just one more weird thing I did that none of the locals really did – like eating cheese and running in public and regularly breaking out into hives. People were already staring at me – why not just give them one more thing to stare at me for?</p>
<p>But it’s different here.</p>
<p>There’s something about doing stuff on my own in the States which makes me feel like I’m the fourteen-year-old, new kid at school again. And nobody in the cafeteria wants to sit with me.</p>
<p>Probably because I’m wearing the shirt my mom made me. Which I <em>thought</em> was really awesome when I spent the last two weeks planning what to wear. But when I showed up at school, I realized nobody else was wearing a handmade shirt – a handmade shirt that just so happens to match a handmade skirt. Because, you guys, I can’t help it if I was just ahead of the fashion trends. (I’m still waiting for that trend to come in, by the way.)</p>
<div id="attachment_5732" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_8407.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5732" alt="Obviously I've always been ahead of the times fashion-wise. OBVIOUSLY." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_8407-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Obviously I&#8217;ve always been ahead of the times fashion-wise. OBVIOUSLY.</p></div>
<p>Recently, I decided this whole being-self-conscious-about-doing-solo-stuff thing needs to stop.</p>
<p>I need to be cool with doing stuff on my own again.</p>
<p>Because, you know, sometimes you just want to do stuff and there’s nobody around to do that stuff with.</p>
<p>So what are you going to do?</p>
<p>Just not do the stuff?</p>
<p>That’s stupid.</p>
<p>Plus, there are only so many times you can take your mom and dad out on a date before you start feeling a bit lame. Or they stop answering your calls. Whichever one comes first.</p>
<p>So a few weeks ago, I decided I needed to start doing more stuff on my own.</p>
<p>I started things off easy with a few tours of places around town. Including, the funky <a href="http://www.darwinmartinhouse.org/">Darwin Martin house</a>, a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_Lloyd_Wright">Frank Lloyd Wright</a> designed house in Buffalo.</p>
<div id="attachment_6138" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 240px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_1263.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6138" alt="Darwin D. Martin House" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_1263-230x300.jpg" width="230" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Darwin D. Martin House</p></div>
<p>And Buffalo’s majestic <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buffalo_City_Hall">City Hall.</a></p>
<div id="attachment_6141" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_1723.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6141" alt="City Hall" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_1723-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">City Hall</p></div>
<p>In case you’ve never been on a tour by yourself, I totally recommend you do one.</p>
<p>Tours are the perfect solo activity.</p>
<p>You don’t have to introduce yourself to anyone or make small talk. Heck, you don’t even have to talk at all. But, if you do, say, ask the tour guide eleventy-billion nerdy questions, that’s cool, too.</p>
<p>Plus, you can pretend like you’re not from around here, and you’re just in town on some top-secret, solo-stuff-business, and that’s why you’re alone. Not because you don’t have any friends and your mom and dad aren’t returning any of your calls or anything.</p>
<p>I’ve also been to the movies on my own a few times. Which, honestly, is my favorite way to go to the movies EVER.</p>
<p>Seriously, you guys, if you’ve never been to a movie alone, you need to go right now.</p>
<p>Solo cinema-going is the best!</p>
<p>You can watch any movie you want. You never have to share your armrest. And you can eat popcorn for dinner and cry through all the cheesy parts of the movie and nobody has to know.</p>
<div id="attachment_6140" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_9727.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6140" alt="Dinner is SERVED!" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_9727-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dinner is SERVED!</p></div>
<p>That is, of course, until you blather all about it on your blog.</p>
<p>This week, I decided to step things up a notch.</p>
<p>I decided to go to a local networking event I&#8217;d heard about on <a href="https://twitter.com/unbravegirl">Twitter</a>. This was exactly the type of thing I would usually never want to do on my own – you know, the kind of thing that involves mingling and talking to people I don’t know. All without a tour guide there to answer all my nerdy questions or a bucket of popcorn to cry into.</p>
<p>The only way I managed to convince myself to go was because I knew there was going to be free pizza and <a title="Unbrave Eats: Buffalo Wings" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/buffalo-wings/">chicken wings</a> there.</p>
<div id="attachment_5938" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_9829.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5938" alt="Oh, the things I do for wings." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_9829-300x224.jpg" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Oh, the things I do for wings.</p></div>
<p>And because I told myself that I could write a blog post about it afterwards.</p>
<p>Mind you, when I originally imagined this blog post, the title was going to be something like “Weeklyish Challengey Thingie: Meet New People That Are Totally Not My Parents” or “How to Not Be Totally Socially Awkward AT ALL.”</p>
<p>So, umm, yeah, spoiler alert: those things didn’t happen.</p>
<p>When I showed up at the event, I was a bit surprised to see that everyone was already sitting at tables eating their free pizza and wings.</p>
<p>This was even worse than I thought it was going to be.</p>
<p>I hadn’t known it was going to be <i>that kind</i> of event. You know, the kind where you actually have to sit down and talk to people.</p>
<p>Since it was at a bar, I thought it was going to be more like a stand-up-and-mingle event. The kind where you can easily disguise the fact that you’re alone by standing next to a big bunch of people while nodding your head with the conversation and laughing at all their jokes and totally acting like you’re their new best friend. Even though they’re shooting you weird looks and inching away from you because you just laugh-snorted blue cheese through your nose.</p>
<p>But doing sit-down events on your own is totally the worst, amirite?</p>
<div id="attachment_6160" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 239px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_8031.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6160  " alt="Gah! The dreaded sit-down event. Luckily, this one came with assigned seats &amp; free booze." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_8031-229x300.jpg" width="229" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Gah! The dreaded sit-down event! Thank god for booze!</p></div>
<p>We should just go ahead and ban all sit-down events already. Especially any sit-down event that requires you to find your own seat. That’s just asking for bad high school cafeteria flashbacks.</p>
<p>I quickly grabbed some pizza and wings and an informational handout, made my way to an empty table in the back of the room and sat down.</p>
<p>And, then, I did the only thing I could think to do – I stared at the informational handout like it was the most exciting informational handout I’d ever seen in my life. Like, “Wow, guys, have you seen all this information on this handout? It’s crazy! I can’t even tear my eyes off all this information! I could never feel lonely and awkward with all this information to keep me company! Yay, information!”</p>
<p>Of course, I know I should have just asked someone if I could sit down at their table.</p>
<p>But, in my defense, most of the tables were already pretty full.</p>
<p>And, you guys, there are only so many challengey things I can force myself to do in one week. This week I was just working on getting myself to a social event. Next week, I might actually work on being social at that social event.</p>
<p>Luckily, the event organizers started talking to the group soon after I sat down.</p>
<p>This made me feel a lot less awkward.</p>
<p>That is until one of the organizers started explaining that we shouldn’t feel awkward if we didn’t know anybody there. And, of course, she said all of that while looking directly at me. Which caused everyone else to look at me.</p>
<p>Let’s just say this was not an effective technique to make me feel less awkward.</p>
<p>After the organizers finished up their talk and I had managed to scarf down some of my pizza and wings, I did the only thing I could think to do – I ran away.</p>
<p>I pretended to head to the bathroom, but, instead, I made a beeline for the front door, hopped in my car and found myself driving to the nearest ice cream place I could find. Because sometimes ice cream is the only thing that will dull the pain.</p>
<div id="attachment_6163" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2884.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6163" alt="Ah, ice cream! Awkwardness? What awkwardness?" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2884-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ah, ice cream! Awkwardness? What awkwardness?</p></div>
<p>I felt a little bit bad about giving up so early on being social.</p>
<p>But not <em>that</em> bad.</p>
<p>I mean, isn’t one of the joys of doing stuff on your own, the fact that you can totally fail at that stuff and run away from an entire roomful of strangers without talking to anyone and go drown your awkwardness in a bucket of peanut butter cup ice cream and nobody has to know?</p>
<p>That is, of course, until you blather all about it on your blog.</p>
<p><em>Do you like to do stuff on your own? What’s your favorite thing to do solo? What’s your least favorite?<br />
</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/do-stuff-on-my-own/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>39</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/do-stuff-on-my-own/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Advice You Really Shouldn’t Follow: How to Become Famous on the Internet</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Unbravegirl/~3/1QHSVU8tGCs/</link>
		<comments>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/how-to-become-famous-on-the-internet/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 12:13:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice You Shouldn't Follow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ME]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thailand]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.unbravegirl.com/?p=6070</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s been a while since I’ve dished out some advice. <p>Probably because it’s been a while since any of you have asked me for advice.</p> <p>I can’t imagine why.</p> <p>After absolutely no new advice questions for weeks, I finally got an email the other day from the adorably named Mumun. The email came with the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a while since I’ve dished out <a title="Advice You Really Shouldn’t Follow: How To Travel With Annoying People" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/how-to-travel-with-annoying-people/">some advice</a>.</p>
<p>Probably because it’s been a while since any of you have asked me for advice.</p>
<p>I can’t imagine why.</p>
<div id="attachment_5526" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_6135.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5526 " alt="What? You don't think this girl is capable of giving good advice? Okay, maybe you have a point." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_6135-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">What? You don&#8217;t think this girl is capable of giving good advice?<br />Okay, maybe you have a point.</p></div>
<p>After absolutely no new advice questions for weeks, I finally got an email the other day from the adorably named Mumun. The email came with the equally adorable subject line: “I need advice that I don’t think I’ll need.”</p>
<p>Well, I think we can all agree that she came to the right lady! Because, not to brag or anything, but I’m pretty much awesome at giving advice to people that they don&#8217;t think they&#8217;ll need.</p>
<p>Like I can now tell you how to <a title="Thank You! I Got You Unicorns! And I’m Totally Not Even Lying This Time!" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/2013-bloggies-win/">put unicorn horns on ponies</a>. And cats. And one-eyed chihuahuas.</p>
<p>I bet you never thought you’d need to know how to do that, huh?</p>
<p>(Answer: get your mom to do it. Because you’re too busy “checking the lighting.”)</p>
<p>Mumun’s email went something like this:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;"><em>I have a <a href="http://indohoy.com/">travel blog</a> that is specifically about my own country (psst&#8230; Indonesia). I really want it to go Rambo-famous and become internationally known so I can legally trash hotels like Rambo (wait, that&#8217;s the wrong movie), and it would be nice if more people came by. But I don&#8217;t know how? Aside from writing stupid stories about myself, what should I do?</em></p>
<p>First of all, writing stupid stories about yourself is always the key to success.</p>
<p>ALWAYS.</p>
<p>Secondly, I don’t usually like to give out blogging advice on my blog. Mostly because there are lots of really awesome bloggy people out there dishing out really awesome bloggy advice (like <a href="http://joythebaker.com/2013/02/10-real-talk-blog-tips-part-ii/">here</a> and <a href="http://www.everywhereist.com/my-16-tips-for-beginning-bloggers/">here</a> and <a href="http://thepioneerwoman.com/blog/2010/09/ten-important-things-ive-learned-about-blogging/">here</a>).</p>
<p>These people really know their stuff.</p>
<p>I really do not.</p>
<p>Maybe you’ve noticed?</p>
<p>But how could I resist answering an email with so many references to Rambo?</p>
<p>I could not.</p>
<p>So here goes:</p>
<h4>How to Have an Internationally Known Blog in 12 Easy Steps (Or 6 long years. Whichever one comes first.)</h4>
<h5>Step 1:<b> </b></h5>
<p>Move to Japan.</p>
<div id="attachment_6085" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4702.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6085 " alt="Obligatory teeny-tiny-sake-cup drinking shot." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4702-300x269.jpg" width="300" height="269" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Yeah! I&#8217;m in Japan! And now I must drink everything from teeny tiny cups. It&#8217;s a rule.</p></div>
<p>Start your first blog.</p>
<p>Make sure to give it some kind of funky name that no one can remember or spell. Bonus points if you can give it a name in some foreign language that almost no one (including yourself) speaks, like, say, umm, lemmethinkforasecond, Japanese!</p>
<p>Write your first blog post. Make sure it’s about something really poignant and meaningful. Something that really shows you’re having an Authentic Experience.</p>
<p>Like, say, your lunch.</p>
<div id="attachment_6073" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_0559.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6073" alt="Dear Blog, I ate this today. The end." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_0559-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dear Blog,<br />I ate this today.<br />The end.</p></div>
<p>Email all your friends and family members to tell them that you’ve started a blog and send them the link.</p>
<p>Take their silence as a sign that they’re too busy reading your blog to email you back. Or comment. Or answer your calls.</p>
<h5>Step 2:</h5>
<p>Start writing longer, more blathery posts. About topics that really show the reader the workings of your inner soul.</p>
<p>Like, say, your couch.</p>
<div id="attachment_6074" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japan-couch.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6074 " alt="Ta-da! My Japanese couch! As you can see it was very... umm.. beige." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/japan-couch-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dear Blog,<br />I have a new couch.<br />It is very&#8230; umm&#8230; beige.<br />The end.</p></div>
<p>Hardly ever use photos. And when you do make sure those photos are dark and kind of blurry and taken with your teeny tiny cell phone camera.</p>
<p>After all, you wouldn&#8217;t want to show too much.</p>
<p>You need to maintain an aura of mystery, you know.</p>
<p>As well as an aura of &#8220;Did she take that photo in the bathroom? I think that&#8217;s a photo from the bathroom. I hope she washed her hands.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_6113" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_5427.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6113" alt="IMG_5427" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_5427-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Totally taken in the bathroom. But who doesn&#8217;t love a good shot of bathroom slippers?</p></div>
<h5>Step 3:</h5>
<p>Get your first comment ever from someone who is neither a friend of yours nor biologically related to you.</p>
<p>Jump up and down. A lot.</p>
<p>Because, obviously, you’re on the brink of Internet stardom.</p>
<h5>Step 4:</h5>
<p>Join <a href="http://www.facebook.com/unbravegirlblog">Facebook</a>.</p>
<p>Start harassing all your Facebook friends into reading your blog.</p>
<p>Take their silence as a sign that they’re too busy reading your blog to like the link. Or comment on the link.</p>
<p>And that’s probably also why they de-friended you on Facebook – they’re simply too busy reading your awesome blog posts to be your friend. Whatever. That&#8217;s cool.</p>
<h5>Step 5:</h5>
<p>Change the name of your blog to something that’s a lot easier to spell. And doesn&#8217;t require any foreign language training to remember.</p>
<p>Spend about a week changing your blog over to a blogging platform that no one ever uses. Probably because it&#8217;s ridiculous and breaks down a lot and makes your blog almost impossible to find with a Google search.</p>
<p>After all, you don&#8217;t want to make it <em>that</em> easy for people to get to your blog. You need to play hard to get.</p>
<h5>Step 6:</h5>
<p>Join <a href="https://twitter.com/unbravegirl">Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>Realize that Twitter is even better than Facebook because people are on there ALL THE TIME. Unlike your Facebook friends who are always doing stupid stuff like sleeping or going to work or de-friending you.</p>
<p>Start following other bloggers on Twitter.</p>
<p>Because, guess what?</p>
<p>Other bloggers <i>exist.</i></p>
<p>You had no idea.</p>
<p>You were pretty sure you were the only one.</p>
<p>Start reading other blogs and realize that blogging is actually this thing that people take pretty seriously.</p>
<p>You had no idea.</p>
<p>Notice that no one else is writing blog posts about their couches – instead they are writing informative pieces with lots of bullet points.</p>
<p>Wonder if you should be doing that too. But you <i>hate</i> bullet points and you <i>love</i> your couch.</p>
<p>Keep writing about your couch.</p>
<h5>Step 7:</h5>
<p><a title="Hit the Road: the Unbrave Girl’s Checklist for Packing up, Picking up &amp; Leaving" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2010/03/leaving-checklist/">Leave Japan.</a> And your couch.</p>
<p>Start traveling and writing about non-couch-related things. Like <a title="All by Myself: How I’m Avoiding Lonely" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2010/04/avoiding-lonely/">cats</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_6075" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 220px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_1627.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6075 " alt="Dear Blog,  Here is a cat. Blah, blah, blah. The end." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_1627-210x300.jpg" width="210" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dear Blog,<br />CATS! I LOVE CATS! CATS! CATS! CATS!<br />The end.</p></div>
<p>Get over a hundred hits to your blog in a few hours after a kind-of-big-deal blogger tweets a link to one of your posts. This is more hits than your blog has received in EVER.</p>
<p>OMIGOD. OMIGOD. OMIGOD. OMIGOD.</p>
<p>You probably shouldn’t sleep tonight in case a Hollywood agent needs to call you to get the rights to your blog to turn it into a movie.</p>
<p>Also, you need to think about who is going to play you in the movie. Is Angelina Jolie too obvious? And can she type? Because most of the movie is going to be her typing.</p>
<p>Google search “Angelina Jolie typing.”</p>
<p>Be disturbed by the results.</p>
<h5>Step 8:</h5>
<p>Travel some more.</p>
<p>Go to <a title="Unbrave Girl Gets Happy: Perfectly Pleasant in Chiang Mai" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2010/10/perfectly-pleasant-in-chiang-mai/">Chiang Mai</a> because everyone else is doing it.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_7014.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6091" alt="IMG_7014" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_7014-229x300.jpg" width="229" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Finally switch your blog over to <a href="http://wordpress.org/">WordPress</a>.</p>
<p>Because everyone else is doing that, too.</p>
<p>BLOGGER PEER PRESSURE, you guys. It&#8217;s real.</p>
<h5>Step 9:</h5>
<p>Move to <a title="A Love Letter to China: 5 Reasons I Have a Crush On My New Home" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2011/02/a-love-letter-to-china/">China.</a></p>
<p>Get a new couch.</p>
<div id="attachment_4424" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/IMG_9324.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4424" alt="IMG_9324" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/IMG_9324-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dear Blog,<br />I have just found the meaning of life.<br />And it is orange and brown and MAGNIFICENT.<br />The end.</p></div>
<p>Write about your new couch.</p>
<p>Win a <a title="I won! I won! I won! (Alternative title: Wheeeeeeeeeeee!)" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2012/03/bloggies/">kind-of-big-deal-award</a>.</p>
<p>These two things are probably related.</p>
<p>Just saying.</p>
<h5>Step 10:</h5>
<p>Attempt to write <a title="My Big Fat Blog: How I’m Going to Downsize My Blog Posts &amp; How You’re Going to Help" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2011/12/my-big-fat-blog/">shorter, less blathery posts.</a></p>
<p>Fail miserably.</p>
<p>Start taking photos of EVERYTHING and put them on your blog. Because, apparently, people like to look at things and not just words all the time.</p>
<p>Include lots of dark, blurry bathroom photos. After all, you wouldn&#8217;t want to forget your roots.</p>
<div id="attachment_6117" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_3476.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6117 " alt="Oh, hello, Chinese train bathroom. I do not miss you." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_3476-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Oh, hello, dark Chinese train bathroom. I do not miss you.</p></div>
<h5>Step 11:</h5>
<p>Move<a title="On Going Home" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2012/07/home/"> home.</a></p>
<p>Get another couch which is not nearly as exciting as your old couch.</p>
<div id="attachment_4420" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/IMG_7889.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4420    " alt="Presenting: My New Couch! Obviously, not the looker my Chinese couch was. Which probably explains the lack of hot guys." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/IMG_7889-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dear Blog,<br />This is my new couch.<br />I know. I can see the disappointment in your eyes already.<br />I&#8217;m sorry.</p></div>
<p>Compensate by getting a cat. Start <a title="Weeklyish Challengey Thingie: Demouse the House" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2012/11/demouse-the-house/">writing about your cat.</a></p>
<div id="attachment_4951" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 289px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/IMG_0423.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4951 " alt="Totally a cure for the common cold. Trust me." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/IMG_0423-279x300.jpg" width="279" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">But I got a cat! So that makes things better, right?</p></div>
<p>Decide to start an advice column on your blog.</p>
<p>And by &#8220;advice column&#8221; I mean &#8220;just an excuse to write stupid stories about yourself.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tell all your readers that you will now be answering all their questions about everything ever.</p>
<p>Take their silence as a sign that they’re too busy reading your blog posts to email you with their questions about everything ever. Whatever. That&#8217;s cool.</p>
<h5>Step 12</h5>
<p>Totally start trashing hotel rooms.</p>
<p>And by &#8220;trashing&#8221; I mean &#8220;take lots of photos of the bathroom because everyone loves a good bathroom photo, amirite?&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_6111" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_1059.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6111" alt="IMG_1059" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_1059-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ooo, la, la. Fancy hotel bathroom, I DO miss you!</p></div>
<p><em>Have any blogging or how-to-get-kind-of-famous-on-the-Internet tips you&#8217;d like to share? </em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Or want to get some advice from me? Leave your question in the comments, send your question via the <a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/contact/">contact form </a>or shoot me an email at unbravegirl at gmail.com</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/how-to-become-famous-on-the-internet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>65</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/how-to-become-famous-on-the-internet/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Buffalo Boom Days or “Celebrating Spring in an Empty Grain Silo. As You Do.”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Unbravegirl/~3/FCV-8LHAUVw/</link>
		<comments>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/buffalo-boom-days/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 21:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Places I've Been... Besides My Couch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buffalo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ME]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.unbravegirl.com/?p=6021</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p></p> Spring has finally sprung in Buffalo! <p>Sure, as of Monday, the weather was all fifty-billion-degrees-below-zero and crazy-pants-blowing-snow. Which meant I froze my toes off at the Dyngus Day Parade despite the two pairs of socks I was wearing and the warming effects of Polish beer.</p> <p>But, as of today, I haven’t seen snow for [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2867.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6028" alt="IMG_2867" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2867-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Spring has finally sprung in Buffalo!</p>
<p>Sure, as of Monday, the weather was all fifty-billion-degrees-below-zero and crazy-pants-blowing-snow. Which meant I froze my toes off at the <a title="What the Dyngus is Dyngus Day? And Other Mysteries of Buffalo" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/dyngus-day/">Dyngus Day Parade </a>despite the two pairs of socks I was wearing and the warming effects of Polish beer.</p>
<p>But, as of today, I haven’t seen snow for at least four days, you guys!</p>
<p>FOUR DAYS!</p>
<p>That’s got to be some kind of Buffalo record or something.</p>
<p>I was even able to pull out some of my non-boot shoes this week. I can’t tell you how excited I was about that.</p>
<p>I may start rocking the flats-with-no-socks look one of these days. At which point I will probably have to be sedated because I will be so excited.</p>
<div id="attachment_4549" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/IMG_7906.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4549 " alt="I can NOT even wait for this to start happening." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/IMG_7906-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Can NOT even wait for this to start happening.</p></div>
<p>It’s not just the weather and my wardrobe which have been showing signs of spring, though.</p>
<p>The local hotdog stand is open again for business. Which is a good thing because I’m pretty sure my life would have lost all meaning if I had to make it through another week without a footlong and some curly fries.</p>
<div id="attachment_6029" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2882.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6029 " alt="THIS you guys. " src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2882-300x247.jpg" width="300" height="247" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Hello, Meaning of Life. It&#8217;s nice to see you again.</p></div>
<p>Flowers have started to spring up on the farm.</p>
<div id="attachment_6032" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2919.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6032 " alt="Yes, that is a rooster in the background. It is a proven fact that roosters improve all flower photography." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2919-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Yes, that is a rooster in the background. It is a proven fact that roosters improve all flower photography by at least 100%.</p></div>
<p>And my parent’s laundry room has been taken over by an immense box of baby chicks.</p>
<p>What?</p>
<p>Isn’t that how you tell whether or not it’s spring?</p>
<p>When a room in your house is overtaken by baby farm animals?</p>
<p>Because that’s pretty much how spring works around here.</p>
<div id="attachment_6030" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2903.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6030" alt="It is also a proven fact that doing laundry is about 100 times more fun if there is a big box of baby chicks nearby." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2903-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">It is also a proven fact that doing laundry is about 100 times more fun if there is a big box of baby chicks nearby.</p></div>
<p>To make things <i>really</i> official, this Saturday, Buffalo held its big spring kick-off event, <a href="http://www.buffalorising.com/2013/03/by-girlfridaynow-that-the-first.html">Boom Days.</a></p>
<p>Boom Days is so named as it celebrates the lifting of the Niagara River <a href="http://www.niagarafrontier.com/icebridge.html">Ice Boom</a> – a series of large chains and steel beams strung across the mouth of the river that break up large chunks of ice to prevent the ice from entering the hydroelectric plant.</p>
<p>What?</p>
<p>Isn’t that how people in your town tell whether or not it’s spring?</p>
<p>When the giant ice-breaking thingies are lifted from the river?</p>
<p>Because that’s pretty much how spring works around here.</p>
<p>Mind you, from what I could tell, the celebration did not involve the actual lifting of the boom.</p>
<p>When I first heard about the event, I was imagining all the people of Buffalo banding together to lift the boom out of the water or something like that. Which would have been pretty cool, I think. But probably would have required a lot more upper arm strength than I currently possess.</p>
<p>The party <em>did</em> involve a lot of empty, industrial grain silos, though. Which is probably about the next best thing to giant ice-breaking thingies.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2741.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6022" alt="IMG_2741" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2741-300x214.jpg" width="300" height="214" /></a></p>
<p>It turns out that Buffalo just so happens to have a lot of empty, industrial grain silos around.</p>
<p>You see, back in the day, Buffalo was like the <a href="http://www.buffalohistoryworks.com/grain/history/history.htm">Grain Capital of the World </a>due to its handy location next to the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Erie_Canal">Erie Canal</a>. Grain from farms in the Midwest would be shipped into Buffalo to be processed and then shipped off to other parts of the world.</p>
<p>While some of the silos are still in use today, most of them are empty.</p>
<p>Which means bad things for Buffalo’s economy, I suppose.</p>
<p>But good things for Buffalo’s partying.</p>
<p>Because, you guys, in case you’ve never hung out in an empty grain silo before, a silo can make a pretty awesome place to party.</p>
<div id="attachment_6034" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2771.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6034 " alt="Party Central right here." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2771-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Party Central RIGHT HERE.</p></div>
<p>It&#8217;s kind of like the ultimate party basement.</p>
<p>You know, how the coolest kid in school always had the coolest party basement &#8212; the kind of basement that was super huge and had a mini-fridge and not one but <em>two</em> foosball tables?</p>
<p>Well, the grain silos are <em>even better</em> than that basement.</p>
<p>Except the mini-fridge and foosball tables have been replaced with grain kilns.</p>
<div id="attachment_6046" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2805.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6046 " alt="Okay, maybe not as fun as a foosball table. But surprisingly pretty, no?" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2805-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A grain kiln. Okay, maybe not as fun as a foosball table. But surprisingly pretty, no?</p></div>
<p>The acoustics were perfect for the live band that was performing.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2777.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6036" alt="IMG_2777" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2777-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>And there was tons of funky wall art and cool graffiti all over the insides of the silos. You know, in case you&#8217;re the type of person who likes her parties arty.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2841.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6026" alt="IMG_2841" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2841-247x300.jpg" width="247" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>You could even try your hand at making your own funky wall art.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2746.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6056" alt="IMG_2746" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2746-283x300.jpg" width="283" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>There were also <a href="http://www.preservationbuffaloniagara.org/buffalo-tours/">historic tours</a> of the silos.</p>
<p>You know, in case you&#8217;re like me and you like your parties totally <a title="Nerding Out at Old Fort Niagara" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/old-fort-niagara/">nerdy.</a></p>
<p>I learned all kinds of fascinating silo facts during the tour. Like how the grain actually gets into the silo. (Hint: There are elevators involved. Elevators! Who knew? And here all along I had imagined grain to be the healthy, stairs-taking type.)</p>
<div id="attachment_6038" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2816.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6038" alt="One of the grain elevators. Or at least I think this was a grain elevator. I was having trouble keeping my silo facts straight." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2816-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">One of the grain elevators. Or at least I think this was a grain elevator. I was having trouble keeping my silo facts straight.</p></div>
<p>And, of course, as with any good party, there was ready access to beer and boxed wine.</p>
<div id="attachment_6035" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2773.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6035 " alt="Get your beer &amp; boxed win here!" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2773-300x269.jpg" width="300" height="269" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Get your beer &amp; boxed wine here!</p></div>
<p>What?</p>
<p>Isn’t that how people in your town celebrate spring?</p>
<p>By getting sloshed in an empty grain silo?</p>
<p>Because that’s pretty much how spring works around here.</p>
<p><i>What&#8217;s your favorite way to celebrate the start of spring?</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/buffalo-boom-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/buffalo-boom-days/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>What the Dyngus is Dyngus Day? And Other Mysteries of Buffalo</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Unbravegirl/~3/GHtpfm7eZ7E/</link>
		<comments>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/dyngus-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 11:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Places I've Been... Besides My Couch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buffalo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ME]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.unbravegirl.com/?p=5966</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You know when you’re telling a story about something your family used to do all the time when you were growing up &#8212; something you just assumed everyone did with their families when they were growing up. <p>And you’re all like, “Hey, remember when your parents would make you pose for family photos with goats? [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You know when you’re telling a story about something your family used to do all the time when you were growing up &#8212; something you just assumed everyone did with their families when they were growing up.</p>
<p>And you’re all like, “Hey, remember when your parents would make you pose for family photos with goats? Wasn’t that <i>so</i> annoying?”</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_8925.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-4680" alt="IMG_8925" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_8925-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>Or, “Hey, how about when you wanted to go to the mall, but your parents wouldn’t let you because they were too busy plucking turkeys in the driveway. <i>Parents!</i> Amirite?”</p>
<div id="attachment_6007" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2677.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6007    " alt="IMG_2677" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2677-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Notice I am not in this picture. Probably because I was trying to hitch-hike my way to the mall.</p></div>
<p>And then the person you’re talking to just kind of stares at you.</p>
<p>And you have that awkward realization that he has absolutely no idea what you’re talking about because he has never had to pose in a family photo with goats or put up with driveway turkey-plucking.</p>
<p>And then you have to be all like, “Ha, ha, just kidding. My family totally <i>never</i> did that. Because that would just be so <i>weird.</i> Only really weird weirdos would do something like that, right?”</p>
<p>Well, I’ve been having a lot of those moments lately.</p>
<p>But not about my family.</p>
<p>Come on, I think we <em>all</em> knew they were weird.</p>
<div id="attachment_4714" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 232px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_8436.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4714 " alt="I've shown you this picture of my mother before, right?" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_8436-222x300.jpg" width="222" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I&#8217;ve introduced you to my mother before, right?</p></div>
<p>Instead, I’ve been having those moments about Buffalo.</p>
<p>Since <a title="On Going Home" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2012/07/home/">coming home</a> this past summer, I’ve noticed a few things that we do in this city that I just assumed other people did in other American cities. And then I start talking about those things with people who aren’t from around here, and they’re all like, “Come again?”</p>
<p>For example, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Butter_lamb">butter lambs.</a></p>
<div id="attachment_5979" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2512.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5979 " alt="IMG_2512" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2512-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Behold, butter lambs!</p></div>
<p>Butter lambs started popping up in the stores around Buffalo about a week or two before Easter.</p>
<p>And they are pretty much exactly what they sound like – a lamb made out of butter.</p>
<p>When I was growing up, my friends would talk about getting butter lambs for Easter dinner.</p>
<p>It just seemed like this thing that people did.</p>
<p>Mind you, my family had never had a butter lamb. But I didn’t think much about that. My parents were always depriving us of awesome things everyone else on the planet got to partake in – like sugar cereals, store bought meat and jelly sandals.</p>
<p>I just assumed that butter lambs were just another thing that everyone on the planet got to do except for us.</p>
<p>And then this weekend, I went to the <a href="http://broadwaymarket.org/">Broadway Market</a>, a big old-fashioned market in Buffalo.</p>
<div id="attachment_5989" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2513.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5989" alt="Broadway Market" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2513-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Broadway Market</p></div>
<p>I took some photos of butter lambs on display and posted them on my <a href="http://www.facebook.com/unbravegirlblog">Facebook page</a>.</p>
<p>It wasn’t until a few people asked me what the heck a butter lamb was that I realized that, oh, this is not really a thing that everyone in the world just does.</p>
<p>Sure, enough, after a little Google searching, I discovered all the sites for <a href="http://www.buffalobutterlambs.com/history/history.html">butter-lamb-related items</a> were all Buffalo-based.</p>
<p>How is this even possible, guys? How is Buffalo the only place in the world that knows how adorable butter in the shape of a cute, fuzzy sheep can be?</p>
<p>I mean, <i>come on. </i></p>
<p>EVERYONE should know that.</p>
<p>And there’s <a href="http://www.dyngusdaybuffalo.com/">Dyngus Day</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2538.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5969" alt="IMG_2538" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2538-300x239.jpg" width="300" height="239" /></a></p>
<p>Like butter lambs, I grew up hearing about Dyngus Day but never participating in it.</p>
<p>Dyngus Day is kind of like the Polish version of Mardis Gras. Except instead of celebrating before the beginning of Lent, it celebrates at the end of it as it&#8217;s held on Easter Monday each year.</p>
<p>As with Mardis Gras, there is a parade and drinking and general revelry.</p>
<p>But with Dyngus Day there’s the added bonus of being able to hit people you like with pussywillows and spray them with water. Because what says, “Hey, you, I think you’re pretty special” more than hitting someone over the head with a tree branch and then dousing them with ice cold water?</p>
<div id="attachment_5982" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 228px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2514.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5982 " alt="Pussy willows. When chocolate or diamond rings just won't do." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2514-218x300.jpg" width="218" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pussy willows. How to TRULY tell someone you care.</p></div>
<p>I just assumed Dyngus Day was celebrated in most American cities with large Polish populations. Kind of like how St. Patrick’s Day is celebrated in cities with large Irish populations. Except I figured Dyngus Day would feature a lot less green beer and a lot more sauerkraut.</p>
<p>It turns out that Dyngus Day is yet another thing that is really not done that much outside of Buffalo – it’s not even done that much in Poland. Or, at least not to the extent that it’s done here in Buffalo.</p>
<p>I mean, we even have our own Dyngus Day guidebook here.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_1881.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5967" alt="IMG_1881" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_1881-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>You know, because you’d hate to be hitting people over the head with pussywillows without some proper instruction.</p>
<div id="attachment_6008" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2686.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6008" alt="IMG_2686" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2686-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Brushing up on my pussywillow-wielding techniques.</p></div>
<p>This week I got to attend my very first Dyngus Day. And it was pretty much everything I could have hoped for and more.</p>
<p>There was a fire-breathing dragon.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2536.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5968" alt="IMG_2536" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2536-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>And Polish dancers.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_26601.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5999" alt="IMG_2660" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_26601-300x223.jpg" width="300" height="223" /></a></p>
<p>And people dressed up as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pierogy">pierogies</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2551.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5970" alt="IMG_2551" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2551-265x300.jpg" width="265" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>There were even zombies. Because, apparently, even the living dead enjoy themselves a little Dyngus.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2588.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5974" alt="IMG_2588" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2588-298x300.jpg" width="298" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>And just like at Mardis Gras, people on the floats were throwing colored beads into the crowds.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2572.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5971" alt="IMG_2572" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2572-300x292.jpg" width="300" height="292" /></a></p>
<p>Luckily, unlike Mardi Gras, you didn’t have to lift up your shirt to get them. As it was about fifty billion degrees below zero and blowing snow.</p>
<p>Because fifty billion degrees below zero and blowing snow in April?</p>
<p>That&#8217;s also totally a weird Buffalo thing.</p>
<div id="attachment_5980" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2637.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5980" alt="Crazy-pants blowing snow? In April? Because BUFFALO." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2637-300x281.jpg" width="300" height="281" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Crazy-pants blowing snow? In April? Because BUFFALO.</p></div>
<p>And, of course, there was plenty of sauerkraut.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2649.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5976" alt="IMG_2649" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2649-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>And Polish beer.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2657.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5977" alt="IMG_2657" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2657-300x238.jpg" width="300" height="238" /></a></p>
<p>Which, I have to say, tasted a lot like regular beer. I was expecting something a bit more Polish-tasting. Like you know how Corona is usually served with a lime? This stuff should totally be served with a mini-pierogy or some <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go%C5%82%C4%85bki">golumpki </a>or something.</p>
<p>As wonderful as all the dragons and Polish zombies and sauerkraut were, my favorite part of the festivities definitely had to be the Kiel-bus-a.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2581.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5972" alt="IMG_2581" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2581-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>Because, I mean, BEST NAME EVER.</p>
<p>AND they were throwing free sausage from the bus!</p>
<p>Free sausage, you guys! Free sausage is only like my favorite kind of sausage!</p>
<p>Sadly, as much as I tried, I wasn’t able to get my hands on a lucky link. So I had to ask some guy I had just met if I could take a picture of his sausage. That’s always a fun way to break the ice.</p>
<div id="attachment_5973" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2582.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5973 " alt="Hey, sir, do you mind if I take a picture of your sausage?" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_2582-300x238.jpg" width="300" height="238" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Hey, sir, I know we just met, but do you mind if I take a picture of your sausage?</p></div>
<p>And, again, I was left wondering how this type of thing doesn&#8217;t exist in more parts of the world.</p>
<p>I mean,  how is it that Buffalo is the only place in the world that knows how wonderful free sausage thrown from strangers in a mini-bus can be?</p>
<p>I mean, <i>come on. </i></p>
<p>EVERYONE should know that.</p>
<p><em>What unusual traditions or festivals does your hometown or current home celebrate?</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/dyngus-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/04/dyngus-day/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Unbrave Eats: Buffalo Wings</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Unbravegirl/~3/ngx2dm9BnrM/</link>
		<comments>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/buffalo-wings/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 16:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food (aka The Reason I Can't Fit Into My Pants)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buffalo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[danger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ME]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.unbravegirl.com/?p=5922</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You guys, can you believe I’ve been living in Buffalo for the past nine months and I have yet to really say anything about Buffalo wings on my blog? <p>Trust me, this is not because I haven’t been eating my fair share of Buffalo wings since my return.</p> <p>I mean, this is me we’re talking [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You guys, can you believe I’ve been living in Buffalo for the past nine months and I have yet to really say anything about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buffalo_wing">Buffalo wings</a> on my blog?</p>
<p>Trust me, this is not because I haven’t been eating my fair share of Buffalo wings since my return.</p>
<div id="attachment_5934" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_7606.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5934" alt="IMG_7606" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_7606-300x256.jpg" width="300" height="256" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Buffalo wings &amp; me. Reunited at last!</p></div>
<p>I mean, this is <i>me </i>we’re talking about here.</p>
<p>I’ve been eating my fair share of EVERYTHING since my return.</p>
<div id="attachment_4573" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/IMG_6919.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4573" alt="And by &quot;everything&quot; I mean &quot;ALL THE CHEESE&quot;" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/IMG_6919-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">And by &#8220;everything&#8221; I mean &#8220;ALL THE CHEESE&#8221;</p></div>
<p>Except for maybe kale. I’m most definitely behind on my kale consumption. In fact, I don’t think I’ve ever eaten kale, like, EVER. I can’t say I feel too bad about that.</p>
<p>The reason why I haven’t yet talked about Buffalo wings on my blog is because, well, I don’t like to sound all preachy and tell people they’re doing stuff wrong.</p>
<p>At least not on my blog.</p>
<p>In real life, I have absolutely no problem with being a preachy jerk and telling people they’re doing stuff wrong all the time.</p>
<p>I mean, seriously, you guys, <i>someone</i> needs to tell them.</p>
<p>And that someone might as well be me.</p>
<p>But in my bloggy life, I want people to like me.</p>
<p>So that’s why I never write posts like “Top Ten Things You’re Doing Wrong While Traveling” or “Reasons Why You’re Wrong. I Bet You Can’t Even Read This Right Because You Do Everything Wrong. In Fact, I Bet Your Name is Wrongity Wrongpants III. That’s How Wrong You Are ALL THE TIME.”</p>
<p>But, here’s the thing, guys, about the Buffalo wings?</p>
<p>YOU’RE TOTALLY DOING THEM ALL WRONG.</p>
<p>Unless, of course, you grew up in Buffalo or have spent considerable time in Buffalo.</p>
<p>In which case, you might be doing them right.</p>
<p>But we never can be too sure.</p>
<p>You may have to complete some kind of test or something to prove to me that you know what you’re doing.</p>
<p>You see, in order to be considered a Buffalo wing, the wing needs to meet a number of strict requirements.</p>
<p>And these requirements go like this:</p>
<p>1. The wings must be deep-fried. There is no such thing as a “baked Buffalo wing.” Sure, you will see such a creation advertised on menus. You should probably just go ahead and burn that menu because it’s a LIAR.</p>
<p>2. The wings must be covered in hot sauce. Not barbecue sauce. Not Italian marinade. Not honey-soy-pineapple-pomegranate-Jamaican-Southwestern-jerk-STOP-IT-JUST-STOP-IT-YOU’RE-MAKING-MY-HEAD-HURT sauce.</p>
<p>3. The wings must have bones in them. Again, you may see something called “boneless Buffalo wings” on a menu here or there but that’s only because you didn’t burn the menu when I already expressly told you to. Sheez. Must I be the one forced to go around the world burning menus? Because I will. I really will.</p>
<p>4. The wings must be served with blue cheese dressing on the side. Do not even ask for ranch dressing. Just don’t. Listen to me. If you ask for ranch dressing instead of blue cheese dressing, this will be justification enough for the server to set<i> you </i>on fire. Don’t say you haven’t been warned.</p>
<p>I know this all sounds a bit strict.</p>
<p>So I’m going to go easy on you guys.</p>
<p>First, I’ll totally let you order the mild wings. Because, honestly, I’m a mouth-wimp myself and can’t handle anything above a medium without my mouth threatening to leave my face.</p>
<p>I’ll also let you get your wings from any restaurant or bar or pizza joint or hole-in-the-wall you want. Whereas some Buffalonians I know are extremely particular about this kind of thing. Like, you have to get wings from &#8220;their place&#8221;, or they will probably never talk to you again. I’m not even kidding you.</p>
<p>While pretty much any restaurant or bar in the city serves Buffalo wings, the two big Buffalo wing contenders are <a href="http://www.anchorbar.com/">Anchor Bar</a> and <a href="http://www.duffswings.com/">Duff’s.</a></p>
<p>If I have people in town visiting me, I usually take them to the Anchor Bar.</p>
<p>This is because Anchor Bar is where Buffalo wings <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anchor_Bar">were originally invented,</a> and I’m all about the history.</p>
<div id="attachment_5932" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_7597.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5932" alt="Anchor Bar. This is where the magic first happened." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_7597-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Anchor Bar. This is where the magic first happened.</p></div>
<p>I’m also all about cheesy statues and kitschy doodads, which Anchor Bar happens to have a lot of.</p>
<div id="attachment_5933" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_7602.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5933" alt="IMG_7602" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_7602-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">At the Anchor Bar. Who doesn&#8217;t love a good kissing waitress statue?</p></div>
<p>But many people I know swear by Duff’s, which is a local chain of chicken wing joints.</p>
<p>I’d only ever been to Duff’s once in my life, and I couldn’t really remember much about my visit. Probably because I&#8217;m blocking out the memory as I was in a lot of pain at the time. You see, I went with a friend who bullied me into ordering wings so hot my face started to melt off. It wasn’t pleasant.</p>
<p>But I was excited to have a do-over with Duff’s this week when a friend invited me there for a get-together.</p>
<p> </p>
<div id="attachment_5924" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2430.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5924" alt="Notice the crazy-pants blowing snow. In March. Because, of course, Buffalo." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2430-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Notice the crazy-pants blowing snow. In March. Because, of course, Buffalo.</p></div>
<p>I was a bit worried, though, when I entered, and this sign was the very first thing that greeted me.</p>
<div id="attachment_5925" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2432.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5925 " alt="Ahhh!" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2432-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Yikes!</p></div>
<p>Apparently, this was not just a warning, but the restaurant’s motto, as it was all over the place – from the servers’ t-shirts to the menus.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2433.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5926" alt="IMG_2433" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2433-237x300.jpg" width="237" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Luckily, not all the wings were some version of hot &#8212; they did have a mild option. And it wasn’t labeled “Mild <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Is</span> Still Totally Going to Melt Your Face Off.”</p>
<p>Despite my face-melting fears, I ended up going with something called “mild medium,” which was supposed to be a little bit hotter than the mild. I wasn&#8217;t going to, but everyone at the table around me was ordering medium and hot wings, and I felt like ordering just the mild would be way too wimpy. Even for me.</p>
<p>Besides, who needs a face?</p>
<p>My friend who was sitting next to me ordered the “medium light” wings – which were supposed to be a notch of hotness above my order. They came out slathered in so much hot sauce my eyes actually started to sting.</p>
<div id="attachment_5929" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 245px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2446.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5929  " alt="IMG_2446" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2446-235x300.jpg" width="235" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Medium Light Is Still Slathery &amp; Eye-Hurtingly-Hot</p></div>
<p>Seriously, you guys, it’s not just my mouth that’s a wimp &#8212; my entire face is a wuss. Even my eyes are like, “Ahh, ahh, too much hot! Why are you always trying to set us on fire?”</p>
<p>When my order came out, my wings looked decidedly less slathery.  While they still had a nice kick to them, I was able to get through half of them without my face melting off.</p>
<div id="attachment_5930" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 280px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2451.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5930 " alt="" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2451-270x300.jpg" width="270" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mild Medium Is Probably Not Going to Kill You. Phew!</p></div>
<p>That was a good thing.</p>
<p>Because, actually, as it turns out, I do kind of need my face.</p>
<p>I also really enjoyed the fact that the stalks of celery they served with the wings were HUGE. I’m usually not the type to rave about a vegetable – especially one as flavorless as celery &#8212; but, seriously, this celery was not messing around, you guys.</p>
<p>And, while my order definitely lived up to the aforementioned set of Super Strict Buffalo Wing Rules and Regulations, I was a bit surprised to see that the menu at Duff’s included a barbecue wing option.</p>
<p> </p>
<div id="attachment_5927" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 249px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2436.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5927  " alt="" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2436-239x300.jpg" width="239" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">BBQ? WTF?</p></div>
<p>Which we all know is TOTALLY AGAINST THE RULES.</p>
<p>I was really hoping it was some kind of test or joke or something.</p>
<p>Like, if you ordered the barbecue wings, the floor would open up and swallow you whole or a bucket of blue cheese would land on your head like on some kind of Japanese game show.</p>
<p>But then my friend ordered the barbecue wings AND a side of ranch dressing.</p>
<p>Mind you, this is a friend who grew up in Buffalo and has spent much of her adult life here. She, of all people, should have known better.</p>
<p>(In her defense, she said the ranch dressing was for her fries. But I wasn&#8217;t so sure I could trust anything coming out of her mouth after the whole ordering-barbecue-wings incident. I now even suspect she&#8217;s been lying about growing up in Buffalo. It&#8217;s possible she grew up in some place like California, where all the Buffalo wings are made out of tofu and coated in honey-soy-ginger sauce and happy thoughts.)</p>
<p>Surprisingly, her order of barbecue wings came out, she ate them, and nothing bad happened to her.</p>
<p>You know, besides me totally losing all respect for her.</p>
<p>Ha, ha, just kidding.</p>
<p>Kind of.</p>
<p><i>What’s your favorite hometown food? And are people in other parts of the world always getting it wrong?</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/buffalo-wings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/buffalo-wings/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Thank You! I Got You Unicorns! And I’m Totally Not Even Lying This Time!</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Unbravegirl/~3/Fk-7uhTIF0w/</link>
		<comments>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/2013-bloggies-win/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 22:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blah, Blah, Blah (I can't even remember what this was about)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bloggies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ME]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unicorns]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.unbravegirl.com/?p=5859</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In case you missed the announcement at the end of my last post and the fifty billion times I screamed about it on the Facebook and the Twitter, this happened on Sunday:   <p>I could pretend to be all surprised and, like, “Wow, I had no idea I would win.”</p> <p>But I&#8217;m not going to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In case you missed the announcement at the end of <a title="Lewiston, NY: Small Town, Big History" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/lewiston-ny/">my last post</a> and the fifty billion times I screamed about it on the <a href="www.facebook.com/unbravegirlblog">Facebook</a> and the <a href="https://twitter.com/unbravegirl">Twitter</a>, <a href="2013.bloggi.es">this</a> happened on Sunday:</p>
<p> </p>
<div id="attachment_5861" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Picture-3.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5861 " alt="" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Picture-3-300x201.png" width="300" height="201" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">AAAAHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHH!</p></div>
<p>I could pretend to be all surprised and, like, “Wow, I had no idea I would win.”</p>
<p>But I&#8217;m not going to lie.</p>
<p>I kind of had an idea I was going to win.</p>
<p>Mind you, this is not because I think my blog is a better travel blog than any of the other super awesome travel blogs that were nominated.</p>
<p>I mean, come on, now.</p>
<p>Not only do I not think my blog is a better travel blog, I don&#8217;t even really think my blog is a travel blog. I mean, wouldn&#8217;t that require me to actually write about travel or something?</p>
<p>Instead, <a title="Weeklyish Challengey Thingie: Demouse the House" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2012/11/demouse-the-house/">I write about my cat</a>.</p>
<p>And then I post photos of myself in my bathrobe.</p>
<div id="attachment_4712" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 244px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_9088.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4712" alt="Well, hello there." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_9088-234x300.jpg" width="234" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Well, hello there.</p></div>
<p>But I do think my readers are pretty much THE BEST BLOG READERS ON THE FACE OF THE PLANET EVER.</p>
<p>If anybody could have made this happen, it would totally be you guys.</p>
<p>Now I know <a title="Thank you for your support. And for almost getting me arrested. But mostly for your support." href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/02/2013-bloggies-nomination/">I said I’d give you all ponies</a> if I won.</p>
<p>But I decided you deserve something even more awesomer than ponies.</p>
<p>And, of course, we all know that unicorns are better than ponies.</p>
<p>But do you know what’s even better than a unicorn?</p>
<p>A UNICORN-PONY!</p>
<p>Or, what I like to call, a Unicornie!</p>
<div id="attachment_5867" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 247px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2498.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5867" alt="Ta-da! She's all yours! " src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2498-237x300.jpg" width="237" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ta-da! She&#8217;s all yours!</p></div>
<p>As you can see, there&#8217;s only one of her and a whole lot of you, so you&#8217;re probably going to have to take turns. Maybe someone could come up with some kind of sign-up sheet, or something?</p>
<p>But, that&#8217;s not all, folks!</p>
<p>Because, seriously, have you ever known me to NOT totally overdo something?</p>
<p>I mean, come on, this is <em>me</em> we&#8217;re talking about here.</p>
<p>I also got you this super magical uni-cat:</p>
<div id="attachment_5869" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 288px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2461.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5869 " alt="IMG_2461" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2461-278x300.jpg" width="278" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">See? MAGICAL.</p></div>
<p>And this other super magical uni-cat:</p>
<div id="attachment_5864" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 250px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2476.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5864" alt="IMG_2476" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2476-240x300.jpg" width="240" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">SO, SO, SO MAGICAL.</p></div>
<p>Because you can never have enough cats. Especially magical unicorn cats. (What? It&#8217;s true. You can&#8217;t. Cats are like cheese. The more you have in your life, the awesomer your life becomes.)</p>
<p>But there&#8217;s more!</p>
<p>There&#8217;s also this amazing one-eyed uni-chihuahua:</p>
<div id="attachment_5863" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 231px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2471.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5863   " alt="IMG_2471" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2471-221x300.jpg" width="221" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The one and only one-eyed, one-horned wonder!</p></div>
<p>I assure you what he lacks in vision, he totally makes up for in MAGIC.</p>
<p>And, don&#8217;t worry, his missing eyeball is not the result of his getting into a horn fight with one of the uni-cats.</p>
<p>Although, I think we all know who’d win if that ever happened.</p>
<p>It would have to be this tough guy right here:</p>
<div id="attachment_5865" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2485.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5865" alt="Bad-assest uni-cat EVER, amirite?" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2485-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Bad-assest uni-cat EVER, amirite?</p></div>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Umm, I don&#8217;t really have any questions for you right now. I just   really wanted to say THANK YOU and YOU ROCK and you deserve about twenty-billion unicorns but these were the only animals that would allow us to put horns on their heads without trampling us to death or pecking out our eyeballs. Oh, and I need to thank <a title="Stuff I Really Kind of Like about My Life at Home: My Parents" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2012/12/my-parents/">my Mom</a> who made the unicorn horns because  I can&#8217;t really be trusted with glitter and spray paint.<br />
</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/2013-bloggies-win/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/2013-bloggies-win/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Lewiston, NY: Small Town, Big History</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Unbravegirl/~3/MJdjUh_MMGo/</link>
		<comments>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/lewiston-ny/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 12:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Places I've Been... Besides My Couch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[donuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ME]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[off the beaten track]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.unbravegirl.com/?p=5796</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p></p> This may sound strange coming from a girl who’s spent most of the past decade living overseas, but I’ve always dreamed of moving to some small town in America. <p>You know, the kind of town with a quaint little Main Street that’s lined with family-owned businesses, cute cafes and that one bar where everyone [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2198.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5815" alt="IMG_2198" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2198-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>This may sound strange coming from a girl who’s spent most of the past decade living overseas, but I’ve always dreamed of moving to some small town in America.</p>
<p>You know, the kind of town with a quaint little Main Street that’s lined with family-owned businesses, cute cafes and that one bar where everyone hangs out after work.</p>
<p>The kind of town where everyone smiles and greets you when you walk down the sidewalk.</p>
<p>The kind of town where everyone in the local bakery knows your name and what kind of pie you want and doesn’t make a big deal about it if you happen to replace all your meals with pie for a week because it’s just this thing you’re doing right now, okay?</p>
<div id="attachment_4941" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/IMG_9739.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4941" alt="Breakfast, lunch, &amp; dinner. COVERED." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/IMG_9739-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Breakfast, lunch, &amp; dinner. COVERED.</p></div>
<p>In this dream, the locals would be a loveable, ragtag bunch – a mix of down-to-Earth good people and offbeat, quirky folks.</p>
<p>Of course, at first they would be wary of me and my big city ways. (What? I’m from <a href="https://plus.google.com/photos/109701488495992792701/albums/5825899316356522721">Buffalo</a>. It’s a big city. Kind of.)</p>
<p>But slowly they would come to embrace me as one of their own. Especially after I save the local bowling alley. And cure the high school football star from a nasty mystery illness. And, then, there would be an on-again, off-again romance with a certain, feisty airplane pilot.</p>
<p>If this all sounds a bit familiar it’s probably because I was more than a little bit obsessed with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Northern_Exposure"><i>Northern Exposure</i> </a>when I was in high school. And then <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ed_%28TV_series%29"><i>Ed</i></a>. Do we all remember <i>Ed</i>? Omigod, I had such a crush on Ed. And, yes, it’s possible I’ve watched more than a few episodes of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hart_of_Dixie"><i>Hart of Dixie </i></a>lately. Why do you ask?</p>
<p>I’ve obviously yet to fulfill my TV-dramedy-induced dreams of moving to Small Town, USA. Probably, because, well, I’ve been a bit too busy moving to <a title="The Lingshan Wonderland of Buddhism (And, yes, it is just as awesome as it sounds)" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2012/04/lingshan-buddha/">Big Huge Massive City of Four Million People That No One Has Ever Heard Of, China</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_5624" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_8691.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5624" alt="Yeah, not quite small-town America." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_8691-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Yeah, not quite small-town America.</p></div>
<p>But I do so enjoy visiting small towns in the States and imagining what my life might be like if I lived there.</p>
<p>On my recent visit to Lewiston, NY, I got to do just that.</p>
<p>Located a mere fifteen minutes away from <a href="http://www.niagara-usa.com/">Niagara Falls</a>, <a href="http://historiclewiston.org/index.html">Lewiston</a> is pretty much the perfect American small town.</p>
<p>And it has been for some time.</p>
<p>Established in 1822, after hundreds of years of Native American and European settlement, Lewiston has a whole lot of history jam-packed into its tiny circumference.</p>
<p>In fact, it seemed like half of the buildings in the town had plaques outside of them boasting exactly how historic they were.</p>
<div id="attachment_5816" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2199.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5816" alt="Ooo, historical." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2199-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ooo, historical.</p></div>
<p>And the other half of the buildings had signs on them telling people that they were private residences. You know you’re living in a historic town when you have to put a sign on your house that says, “Sorry, guys, this is not a museum. It’s just my house. And you can’t come in. Move along now.”</p>
<p>Before hitting up the town’s downtown area, I stopped by one of Lewiston’s main attractions &#8212; the <a href="http://www.fatimashrine.com/">Our Lady of Fatima Shrine.</a></p>
<p> </p>
<div id="attachment_5802" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 256px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2038.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5802" alt="Our Lady of Fatima Shrine" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2038-246x300.jpg" width="246" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Our Lady of Fatima Shrine</p></div>
<p>Started in 1963, the shrine is stunning with its glass-domed basilica, topped with a thirteen-foot tall statue of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Our_Lady_of_F%C3%A1tima">Our Lady of Fatima</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_5801" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2034.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5801" alt="IMG_2034" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2034-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Statue on top of the shrine</p></div>
<p>Inside the basilica, mass was being held when I got there.</p>
<div id="attachment_5800" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2026.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5800" alt="Inside the shrine" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2026-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Inside the shrine</p></div>
<p>So I checked out the two small, peaceful chapels, where a few people were quietly praying.</p>
<div id="attachment_5799" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 234px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2020.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5799" alt="One of the chapels" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2020-224x300.jpg" width="224" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">One of the chapels</p></div>
<p>Outside of the basilica, the grounds house over one hundred life-size marble statues of the saints.</p>
<div id="attachment_5804" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2071.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5804" alt="One of the many statues on the grounds" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2071-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">One of the many statues on the grounds</p></div>
<p>There was even a giant rosary made up of lights.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2053.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5803" alt="IMG_2053" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2053-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>As cool as the building and all the statues were, definitely my favorite part about visiting the shrine was meeting Father Julio.</p>
<p>As it was Friday, the Father was in the kitchen preparing for the afternoon’s fish fry when I arrived. You see, as well as being one of the priests at the basilica, Father Julio also happens to be the Chief Fish Fryer.</p>
<p>In addition to giving me a brief overview of the basilica’s history and a quick tour, the Father informed me that the secret to a successful fish fry is all in the coleslaw (who knew?) and then he blessed me.</p>
<p>I’m telling you guys, if I ever fulfill my dream of moving to small-town America, there had better be a fish-frying Father there.</p>
<p>I mean, I think that should be some kind of requirement in every small town in America, right? Everyone who lives there has to have some secret, unexpected skill. Like, <a title="LeRoy, New York: Home to the Jello Gallery… and Possibly Me" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/jello-gallery-leroy-new-york/">the town mayor is also the museum’s tour guide</a>. The local librarian is a weekend chili-eating champion. And all the priests should be able to fry fish and dispense coleslaw tips.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, I wasn’t able to stick around long enough to try the shrine’s famed coleslaw, as the next stop on my tour was lunch at <a href="http://www.brickyardpub.com/">The Brickyard Pub &amp; BBQ</a> in downtown Lewiston.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2104.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5808" alt="IMG_2104" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2104-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>I could smell the barbecue fumes coming from the restaurant before I could even see it.</p>
<p>And then I spotted a huge pile of firewood behind the restaurant, which was stacked up ready to be used in the pit smoker.</p>
<div id="attachment_5805" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 251px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2078.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5805" alt="Oh, yeah." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2078-241x300.jpg" width="241" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Oh, yeah.</p></div>
<p>That, my friends, is <i>always</i> a good sign.</p>
<p>Jam-packed with locals on their Friday lunch breaks, The Brickyard is totally <i>the </i>place to hang out. It’s the kind of place where you know everyone and everyone knows you and you don’t have to be all embarrassed about having food all over your face because you’re with friends, you know?</p>
<div id="attachment_5806" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2086.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5806" alt="We're all friends, here, right, guys?" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2086-300x215.jpg" width="300" height="215" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">We&#8217;re all friends, here, right, guys?</p></div>
<p>Which is a good thing because I’m pretty sure I had food all over my face the entire time I was there.</p>
<p>On the waitress’ suggestion, I ordered something called a Po’ Boy, which was a big, delicious mess of a sandwich piled high with pulled pork and coleslaw.</p>
<div id="attachment_5807" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2094.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5807" alt="My meal. Before it ended up all over my face." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2094-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My meal. Before it ended up all over my face.</p></div>
<p>It sounded like a strange combination at first, but the coleslaw really added a nice tanginess and crunch to the sweet, smokiness of the pulled pork.</p>
<p>Which just goes to show you that it’s possible the secret to EVERYTHING good in life is coleslaw.</p>
<p>Seriously, who knew?</p>
<p>After I managed to scrub all my lunch off my face, I then stopped by the very swanky <a href="http://www.bartonhillhotel.com/">Barton Hill Hotel and Spa</a>, where I was scheduled to meet up with local historian, Tim Henderson.</p>
<div id="attachment_5814" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 273px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2186.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5814" alt="Barton Hill Hotel &amp; Spa" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2186-263x300.jpg" width="263" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Barton Hill Hotel &amp; Spa</p></div>
<p>Even though the family-owned boutique hotel has only been around for about seven years, it totally fits into the town’s quirky, historic feel.</p>
<p>There were even cannonballs in the lobby.</p>
<div id="attachment_5810" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2117.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5810" alt="The lobby. And its cannonballs." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2117-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The lobby. And its cannonballs.</p></div>
<p>Cannonballs, you guys!</p>
<p>The next time I stay in a hotel there’d better be cannonballs in the lobby. That’s all I have to say.</p>
<p>Tim Henderson gave me a low-down on Lewiston’s extensive history, including its involvement in the Underground Railroad. As Lewiston is just across the river from Canada, it was the final stop for many escaped slaves before they reached freedom.</p>
<p>He showed me the <a href="http://historiclewiston.org/freedomcrossing.html">Freedom Crossing Monument</a>, which was built to commemorate the Underground Railroad. And, which he just so happened to be one of the models for.</p>
<div id="attachment_5811" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2129.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5811  " alt="Freedom Crossing Monument &amp; Tim" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2129-300x232.jpg" width="300" height="232" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Freedom Crossing Monument &amp; Tim Henderson &#8212; historian/sculpture model</p></div>
<p>See?</p>
<p>I told you everyone in small-town America needs a secret, unexpected skill – like, say, sculpture model.</p>
<p>He also informed me that Lewiston was the birthplace of the first cocktail. You see, back in the 1800’s a tavern-keeper named Catherine Hustler started mixing up gin drinks with rooster feathers, and, hence, the name “cocktail” was born.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2205.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5821" alt="IMG_2205" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2205-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>I even got to visit her grave, which is in the local cemetery.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2133.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5812" alt="IMG_2133" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2133-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>That was pretty cool. I mean, this woman is like my HERO. Cocktails are only one of my most favoritest alcoholic drinks EVER.</p>
<p>Although I wish I would have known I was going to visit her grave, so I could have properly prepared to pay my respects. Like, with a bouquet of swizzle sticks or something.</p>
<p>Before leaving Lewiston, I took one last walk down the town’s main road, Center Street, where, as to be expected, people smiled and greeted me as I went by.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2106.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5809" alt="IMG_2106" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2106-218x300.jpg" width="218" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>The street is jam-packed with quirky, little, locally-owned mom and pop shops. Or grandpop shops, as the case may be.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2200.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5822" alt="IMG_2200" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2200-300x277.jpg" width="300" height="277" /></a></p>
<p>There was even a local travel agent. Like, a place that you could actually walk in and talk to a real-live human being about booking a trip. And not have to deal with some creepy, heartless Expedia robot. I had no idea this kind of place still existed.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2209.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5817" alt="IMG_2209" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2209-300x203.jpg" width="300" height="203" /></a></p>
<p>And, of course, there was a <a href="http://www.dicamillobakery.com/">bakery</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2217.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5819" alt="IMG_2217" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2217-224x300.jpg" width="224" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Which, of course, I went in.</p>
<p>And, of course, I stared at all the pie.</p>
<p>But then I opted for a maple-apple donut instead. Because you know us big city types &#8212; we can&#8217;t be trusted.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re always talking about pie, and then we just go ahead and order donuts.</p>
<div id="attachment_5818" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2210.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5818" alt="Maple-apple donut. Kind of like pie. But more donuty." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2210-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Maple-apple donut. Kind of like pie. But more donuty.</p></div>
<p> </p>
<p><i>Do you like to visit small towns? What’s your favoritest small town that you’ve ever visited?</i></p>
<p><i> </i></p>
<p><i>P.S. I&#8217;d like to thank the <a href="http://www.niagara-usa.com/">Niagara Tourism &amp; Convention Corporation</a> for arranging my tour of Lewiston. I’d also like to thank Father Julio at <a href="http://www.fatimashrine.com/">Our Lady of Fatima Shrine</a>, Cheryl Suitor of <a href="http://www.bartonhillhotel.com/">Barton Hill Hotel and Spa</a> and Tim Henderson of <a href="http://www.historiclewiston.org/index.html">Historic Lewiston</a> for taking the time to talk to me. </i><i>And I’d like to thank Catherine Hustler. You know, for all the cocktails.</i></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>P.P.S. And, OMIGOD, super huge THANK YOU to all of you who voted for me for the <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es/">Bloggie for Best Travel Weblog.</a> We did it, guys! I won! And now, if you&#8217;ll excuse me, I need to go find you all some ponies.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/lewiston-ny/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>38</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/lewiston-ny/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Unbrave Eats: Maple Weekend</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Unbravegirl/~3/FeOaRt9E0zo/</link>
		<comments>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/maple-weekend/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 11:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food (aka The Reason I Can't Fit Into My Pants)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ME]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.unbravegirl.com/?p=5750</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p></p> Have you ever really thought about maple syrup? <p>Like, really, really thought about it?</p> <p>Like how does maple syrup even exist? I mean, who was the first person that decided, “Hey, why don’t we just tap into this tree over here and if some kind of liquid comes out, let’s boil it down and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2300.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5757" alt="IMG_2300" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2300-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>Have you ever really thought about maple syrup?</p>
<p>Like, really, <i>really</i> thought about it?</p>
<p>Like how does maple syrup even exist? I mean, who was the first person that decided, “Hey, why don’t we just tap into this tree over here and if some kind of liquid comes out, let’s boil it down and pour it over some stuff.”</p>
<p>I mean, seriously, who <i>did</i> that?</p>
<p>Because we really need to have some kind of holiday already to celebrate that person.</p>
<p>I imagine this holiday would be like a cross between Christmas and The Best Day in the World Ever.</p>
<p>Instead of decorating Christmas trees, of course, we would decorate Maple trees.</p>
<p>And instead of Santa Claus there would be Syrup Sprites, who would bring gallon jugs of maple syrup to all the good little boys and girls. And to me because I&#8217;d really like a gallon jug of maple syrup, too, thank you very much.</p>
<p>And we would all eat pancakes all day long until we&#8217;re sick of eating pancakes. Which would never even happen because, you guys, you can’t get sick of eating pancakes. That’s not humanly possible, okay?</p>
<p>Well, it turns out that that holiday actually does kind of exist.</p>
<p>At least, here in New York State.</p>
<p>And it’s called <a href="http://www.mapleweekend.com/">Maple Weekend</a>.</p>
<p>Despite what the name might have you believe, Maple Weekend actually lasts two weekends. Because, really, when it comes to maple syrup it’s best not to limit yourself.</p>
<p>During those two weekends you can visit local farms that produce maple syrup. And you can even go into their sugar shacks! (What? That’s not a dirty word. I swear, you guys. “Sugar shack” is the building where they make the syrup. It also happens to be the name of my future home. Just so you know.)</p>
<p>And, of course, Maple Weekend involves pancakes.</p>
<p>But not just <i>any</i> kind of pancakes.</p>
<p>These are ALL-YOU-CAN-EAT PANCAKES!</p>
<p>Which to me sounded like a challenge &#8212; a challenge I willingly accepted last Saturday when I went to <a href="http://www.mooresmaple.com/">Moore’s Maple Shack Pancake House</a> to celebrate the first Maple Weekend of the year.</p>
<div id="attachment_5751" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 240px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2269.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5751 " alt="IMG_2269" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2269-230x300.jpg" width="230" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Another possible name for my future home: Maple Shack Pancake House. Just keeping my options open.</p></div>
<p>This, apparently, is one of <i>the</i> places to go in the area, as we had to wait in line at least an hour before we were seated.</p>
<p>Luckily, the lobby was full of stuff to keep us entertained while we waited.</p>
<p>Like pancake drawings.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2272.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5752" alt="IMG_2272" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2272-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>And fascinating maple syrup facts.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2273.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5753" alt="IMG_2273" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2273-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>Because you never know when there might be a quiz.</p>
<p>Inside the pancake house, there were even more things to keep us entertained.</p>
<p>Like lots of old-timey knick-knacks and saw paintings. I mean, a pancake house really isn’t complete without a little saw art, amirite?</p>
<div id="attachment_5755" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2284.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5755" alt="IMG_2284" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2284-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ooo, saw art!</p></div>
<p>And for our reading pleasure there was a detailed family history on the back of our menu. Possibly, well, a bit <i>too</i> detailed.</p>
<div id="attachment_5756" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2285.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5756 " alt="IMG_2285" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2285-300x222.jpg" width="300" height="222" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Check out the 3rd paragraph &#8212; it&#8217;s a doozy!</p></div>
<p>Because, really, while I feel bad for Earl, I’m not so sure if I want to hear about his heart stents before breakfast.</p>
<p>And, of course, there was a maple syrup quiz.</p>
<div id="attachment_5767" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_22801.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5767" alt="IMG_2280" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_22801-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I totally knew there was going to be a quiz, you guys! I should have studied harder!</p></div>
<p>But, the real reason why we were there was not for the wall art and maple trivia, but for the pancakes and syrup, of course.</p>
<p>And, well, there were definitely some pancakes.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2303.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5759" alt="IMG_2303" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2303-300x202.jpg" width="300" height="202" /></a></p>
<p>And there was definitely some syrup.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2301.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5758" alt="IMG_2301" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2301-253x300.jpg" width="253" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>And then there were some more pancakes.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2304.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5760" alt="IMG_2304" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2304-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>And some more syrup.</p>
<div id="attachment_5761" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2307.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5761" alt="Umm, where did all the syrup go?" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2307-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Umm, where did all the syrup go?</p></div>
<p>Until none of us could eat any more pancakes. Which, apparently, is totally humanly possible. I really had no idea.</p>
<p>After breakfast, we headed out to the sugar shack to watch the maple syrup being made.</p>
<p>It turns out this is a rather high-tech, scientific process involving lots of big shiny equipment. And absolutely no sprites.</p>
<div id="attachment_5762" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2315.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5762 " alt="IMG_2315" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2315-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ooo, shiny. But about the sprites&#8230;</p></div>
<p>There was also a gift shop where you could stock up on all your essentials like syrup and cotton candy. Because, yes, I live in a world where syrup and cotton candy are totally considered essentials.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2318.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5763" alt="IMG_2318" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2318-214x300.jpg" width="214" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>And, then, because we hadn’t had nearly enough maple action for the day, we decided to hop on a wagon and head into the woods to see the sap being tapped from the trees.</p>
<div id="attachment_5764" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2334.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5764" alt="IMG_2334" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2334-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">On the wagon into the woods.</p></div>
<p>Which, also, turned out to be a rather technical process involving a lot of rubber tubing.</p>
<div id="attachment_5782" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2338.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5782" alt="IMG_2338" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2338-300x193.jpg" width="300" height="193" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ooo, very tube-y.</p></div>
<p>I do have to admit, the tubing did look quite festive as it ran from tree to tree across the forest. It was almost like the trees were decorated for the holiday.</p>
<p>Except next year, I&#8217;d suggest they add a little bit of tinsel.</p>
<p>And sprites. Let&#8217;s not forget about the sprites.</p>
<p><em>Are you a lover of the maple syrup? What do you like to put it on? Where do you go to get your maple syrup fix?</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/maple-weekend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>38</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/maple-weekend/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Nerding Out at Old Fort Niagara</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Unbravegirl/~3/fSUAzPKu2AM/</link>
		<comments>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/old-fort-niagara/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 20:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Places I've Been... Besides My Couch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ME]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.unbravegirl.com/?p=5699</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p></p> You guys, I have a teensy little confession to make. <p>I am a nerd.</p> <p>I know.</p> <p>Shocking, right?</p> <p>Up until now, I bet you thought I was the hippest bombdiggity on the Internet, yo.</p> <p>(Confession: I have no idea what a bombdiggity is. I just heard it on a commercial.)</p> <p>But, it’s true, guys.</p> [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2008.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5718" alt="IMG_2008" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2008-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>You guys, I have a teensy little confession to make.</p>
<p>I am a nerd.</p>
<p>I know.</p>
<p>Shocking, right?</p>
<p>Up until now, I bet you thought I was the hippest bombdiggity on the Internet, yo.</p>
<p>(Confession: I have no idea what a bombdiggity is. I just heard it on a commercial.)</p>
<p>But, it’s true, guys.</p>
<p>I’m a total nerdball.</p>
<p>One of my favorite activities to do as a child was to memorize random facts from the set of animal flashcards we had at my school, and then attempt to amaze my classmates with my extensive knowledge of water buffalo. (Mind you, they did a very good job of hiding their amazement. By telling me to go away.)</p>
<p>I spent my teenage years secretly reading <a title="Stuff I Really Kind of Like About My Life in China: Old Timey Villages" href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/2011/12/old-timey-villages/">historical fiction novels</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_5732" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_8407.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5732 " alt="Don't let my sophisticated beret-wearing fool you. I was actually a nerd!" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_8407-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Nerd alert. Don&#8217;t let my sophisticated beret-wearing fool you.</p></div>
<p>And you should probably never challenge me to a game of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trivial_Pursuit">Trivial Pursuit</a> because I <i>will</i> play dirty. Plus, you know, if there’s ever a question about water buffalo, you are so going <i>down.</i> Consider yourself warned.</p>
<p>I try to keep my nerdy tendencies on the down low when I’m hanging out with friends so that, you know, they’ll keep on hanging out with me.</p>
<p>Every once in a while I get a bit tipsy and let on that I know way too much about nerdy stuff like Elizabethan book-binding.</p>
<p>But usually I’m pretty good at playing it cool.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1107.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5720" alt="IMG_1107" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1107-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>I mean, OBVIOUSLY.</p>
<p>But I have absolutely no qualms about letting my geek flag fly when I’m on my own or in front of random strangers.</p>
<p>Which is one of the reasons why I love traveling solo so much – I can basically be the biggest nerd there is and nobody has to know. (Well, that, and the fact that I can wear the same pants for five days straight and nobody has to know. And, you know, eat two breakfasts and nobody has to know. And pretty much DO EVERYTHING EVER and nobody has to know.)</p>
<p>So I was super excited when the <a href="http://www.niagara-usa.com/">Niagara Tourism and Convention Corporation</a> invited me to visit <a href="http://oldfortniagara.org/">Old Fort Niagara</a> and write a post about my experience as a solo traveler there.</p>
<p>Located less than half an hour away from Niagara Falls, NY, the fort dates all the way back to 1726 when it was built by the French as a means of controlling the Great Lakes, and, subsequently, it played an integral role in the French &amp; Indian War, the American Revolution and the War of 1812. The fort, which is now a National Historic Landmark, is <a href="http://oldfortniagara.org/visit/admissions.php">open to the public</a> year-round and hosts a number of <a href="http://oldfortniagara.org/events/">cultural events</a>.</p>
<p>And, well, as far as opportunities to be a total nerdball in public, it doesn’t really get much better than visiting a 300-year-old military fort, now does it?</p>
<div id="attachment_5729" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1917.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5729" alt="At Old Fort Niagara. Things about to get nerdy up in here." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1917-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">At Old Fort Niagara. Things about to get nerdy up in here.</p></div>
<p>When I arrived at the Fort on Friday morning, I was greeted by Jason Buckley, the staff member who would be giving me a tour of the museum and grounds.</p>
<p>I felt a bit bad for the guy.</p>
<p>I mean, he probably had no idea he was in for a two-hour nerdy question-fest by yours truly.</p>
<p>We started off the tour by watching a video that showed a brief overview of the fort’s history.</p>
<div id="attachment_5722" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 276px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1885.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5722" alt="Movie time!" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1885-266x300.jpg" width="266" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Movie time!</p></div>
<p>Honestly, it was all a bit confusing for me because it was nine o’clock in the morning, and I was severely under-caffeinated, and, while I am a huge history nerd, I have never been particularly good at dates or really anything that involves numbers.</p>
<p>Plus, the Fort changed hands almost a half dozen times in less than a hundred years – from French control to British control to American control and then back again to British control before it was finally ceded to the United States in 1815.</p>
<p>Trying to keep track of all of that felt kind of like trying to keep track of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taylor_Swift">Taylor Swift</a>’s love life.</p>
<p>Except with a lot less angsty pop songs.</p>
<p>And a lot more funky hats and half-clad Native American dudes.</p>
<p>Not that I’m complaining as I am a fan of both funky hats and half-clad Native American dudes.</p>
<p>Because, I mean, who isn’t?</p>
<div id="attachment_5721" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 242px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_18861.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5721" alt="Why, hello there, sir." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_18861-232x300.jpg" width="232" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Why, hello there, sir.</p></div>
<p>What the movie failed to mention, and what I learned later on in the tour of the museum, was that all that warring and fort-seiging and basically the entire colonization of North America was caused by beavers.</p>
<p>Yes, BEAVERS.</p>
<p>You see, apparently, everyone in Europe was all crazy about felt hats like this one:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1891.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5702" alt="IMG_1891" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1891-266x300.jpg" width="266" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>And, apparently, the best kind of felt was made from beaver fur.</p>
<p>And, apparently, the best kind of beaver fur could be found on beavers in North America – specifically those found in Northern United States and Canada.</p>
<p>And, apparently, the French and English were all like, “Let’s go get us some beaver fur. And colonize a continent. And, you know, have a whole bunch of wars and stuff.”</p>
<p>So, yes, beavers.</p>
<p>Totally to blame.</p>
<p>POSSIBLY FOR EVERYTHING.</p>
<p>Which just goes to show you that you probably shouldn’t trust any mammals with webbed feet.</p>
<div id="attachment_5701" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 239px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1889.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5701 " alt="Not to be trusted." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1889-229x300.jpg" width="229" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Totally cute. And totally not to be trusted.</p></div>
<p>Another fun fact that I didn’t know about until my tour of the museum was that back in the day, soldiers drank something called “<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Small_beer">small beer</a>” for Vitamin C.</p>
<div id="attachment_5703" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 272px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1893.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5703 " alt="Old-timey beer keg. " src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1893-262x300.jpg" width="262" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Old-timey beer keg.</p></div>
<p>I think this means we can all just go ahead and replace our breakfast orange juice with a nice tall glass of beer. And when someone asks you why you’re drinking beer at eight o’clock in the morning you can reply, “Because HISTORY, okay?”</p>
<p>In addition to its enlightening displays on beavers and beer, the museum also housed an extensive collection of old weapons.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1907.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5706" alt="IMG_1907" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1907-300x202.jpg" width="300" height="202" /></a></p>
<p>There were also the remnants of the original flag that used to fly over the fort, which just so happens to be one of the oldest surviving American flags.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1899.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5705" alt="IMG_1899" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1899-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>As fascinating as the museum was, my favorite part of the tour was definitely when we left the museum and stepped out on to the grounds of the fort.</p>
<p>I totally felt like I was stepping back in history.</p>
<div id="attachment_5739" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1909.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5739" alt="History, here I come!" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1909-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">History, here I come!</p></div>
<p>I was tempted to start acting all old-timey and throw out some old-timey slang words. But, sadly, I don’t know any old-timey slang words as they hardly ever have any old-timey slang words in commercials.</p>
<p>While the fort has been the home of almost one hundred different buildings during its history, today the grounds of the fort contain about a dozen different structures, including many of the original buildings as well as some reconstructed ones.</p>
<p>There were a couple big, impressive stone gates.</p>
<div id="attachment_5719" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 259px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2010.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5719 " alt="Ooo, impressive." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2010-249x300.jpg" width="249" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ooo, very big and gate-y.</p></div>
<p>There was a storehouse that is now full of displays.</p>
<p>Like this one about the different names for barrels:</p>
<div id="attachment_5709" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1935.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5709" alt="Firkins and hogsheads and butts and puncheons, oh my!" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1935-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Firkins and hogsheads and butts and puncheons, oh my!</p></div>
<p>Which, I’m not even kidding you, was totally fascinating. And I can’t guarantee you that I won’t get drunk some point soon and start pulling out all my newfound barrel vocabulary.</p>
<p>And there was a bakehouse where they used to bake a million-billion loaves of bread each day.</p>
<div id="attachment_5711" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1945.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5711 " alt="In the bakehouse. Sadly, there were no free bread samples." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1945-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">In the bakehouse. Sadly, there were no free bread samples. Because I could always go for some free bread.</p></div>
<p>By far the most impressive building on the grounds is definitely the French Castle. It also happened to be the oldest building at the fort.</p>
<p> </p>
<div id="attachment_5710" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1944.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5710" alt="The French Castle" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1944-300x209.jpg" width="300" height="209" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The French Castle</p></div>
<p>This is where you could see how the soldiers really lived.</p>
<p>Which, honestly, didn’t seem that bad to me. I mean, usually when I imagine the lives of Eighteenth and Nineteenth Century soldiers (and, yes, I have been known to imagine that kind of thing on occasion), I imagine a lot of hardship.</p>
<p>Not an indoor well decorated with oil paintings.</p>
<div id="attachment_5712" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 221px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1949.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5712" alt="Indoor well with fancy French-looking painting above it. Ooo, la, la!" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1949-211x300.jpg" width="211" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Indoor well with fancy French-looking painting above it. Ooo, la, la!</p></div>
<p>Sure, the barracks room looked like it might be kind of a tight squeeze, especially considering it used to house thirty soldiers.</p>
<div id="attachment_5714" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1984.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5714" alt="The barracks room" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1984-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The barracks room</p></div>
<p>But, honestly, I’ve seen worse at some hostels.</p>
<p>And check out these officer’s digs:</p>
<div id="attachment_5716" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2000.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5716" alt="Officer's quarters" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2000-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Officer&#8217;s quarters</p></div>
<p>Pretty fancy pants, right?</p>
<p>The officer’s dining room even had a table set up for the serving of booze and hot chocolate. Somehow I never imagined military officers hanging out, drinking booze and hot chocolate.</p>
<p>I mean, add my cat and a bathrobe, and that sounds pretty much like my typical Friday night.</p>
<div id="attachment_5715" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 274px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1997.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5715" alt="This was where the hot chocolate &amp; booze were served. Again, sadly, no free samples were given out on the tour." src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1997-264x300.jpg" width="264" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This was where the hot chocolate &amp; booze were served. Again, sadly, no free samples were given out on the tour.</p></div>
<p>As if my whole tour wasn’t totally awesome enough and so full of interesting tidbits of information that I simply cannot wait to blather on about at the next party I happen to get a bit too tipsy at, I then got to learn how to shoot a musket.</p>
<p>A MUSKET, YOU GUYS.</p>
<div id="attachment_5713" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 248px"><a href="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1969.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5713" alt="Musket demonstration by Old Fort Niagara staff member" src="http://www.unbravegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1969-238x300.jpg" width="238" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Musket demonstration by Old Fort Niagara staff member</p></div>
<p>So, in addition to knowing way too much about beavers and beer and barrels, I now know how to operate old-timey firearms.</p>
<p>You all might want to watch your backs.</p>
<p>Or, at least, make a point of not inviting me to any of your parties.</p>
<p><i>What historic place did you visit and love and then talk about way too much at parties later?</i></p>
<p> </p>
<p><i>P.S. I’d like to give a huge thank you to the fine people of <a href="http://www.niagara-usa.com/">Niagara Tourism and Convention Corporation</a> for arranging my tour and to Jason Buckley at <a href="http://oldfortniagara.org/">Old Fort Niagara</a> for giving me an awesome tour and for putting up with my countless questions about barrels and beavers and bedbugs and pretty much EVERYTHING EVER.</i></p>
<p> </p>
<p><i>P.P.S. It’s the last day to vote for the <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es/">Bloggies</a>! Voting closes tonight (Sunday, March 17<sup>th</sup>) at 10 PM EDT. If you haven’t voted already, would you please consider voting for me for the Best Travel Weblog? I would love you forever. And I promise not to bore you at parties with talk of barrels. Okay, so maybe I can’t promise that, but I WILL totally love you forever.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/old-fort-niagara/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.unbravegirl.com/2013/03/old-fort-niagara/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.456 seconds. --><!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-17 08:48:48 --><!-- Compression = gzip -->
