<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Queerty</title>
	
	<link>http://www.queerty.com</link>
	<description>Free of an agenda. Except that gay one.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 11:37:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/queerty2" /><feedburner:info uri="queerty2" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><geo:lat>40.732509</geo:lat><geo:long>-73.989358</geo:long><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site, subject to copyright and fair use.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item>
		<title>Archie’s Resident Gay, Kevin Keller, Gets His Own Young-Adult Novel</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/FB-BvWPYI94/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/archies-resident-gay-kevin-keller-gets-his-own-young-adult-novel-20130401/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 11:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[archie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gays in comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kevin keller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[out in print]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255706</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Kevin Keller made history in 2011 as the first openly gay character in the history of Archie Comics. Now the out teen, who has had his own miniseries and ongoing comic, is breaking boundaries (and formats) with a new hardcover young-adult novel. Due out April 18, Kevin (Penguin, $9.99) looks at Keller&#8217;s early years as [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-255707" alt="kevin" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/kevin.jpg" width="190" height="261" />Kevin Keller made history in 2011 as the first openly gay character in the history of Archie Comics. Now the out teen, who has had his own miniseries and ongoing comic, is breaking boundaries (and formats) with a new hardcover young-adult novel.</p>
<p>Due out April 18,<em> Kevin </em>(Penguin, $9.99) looks at Keller&#8217;s early years as a middle-school military brat facing the prom, an amorous female friend, and a boy who acts like he doesn&#8217;t know Kevin exists.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is a book I would have hugged if I&#8217;d had it as a child,&#8221; says publisher Francesco Sedita. &#8220;I hope it has that effect on children and adults today.&#8221;</p>
<p>Comics and children&#8217;s book author Paul Kupperberg is penning the one-off title. Kupperberg—who has written for <i>Superman</i>, <i>Action Comics</i>, <i>Supergirl</i>, and <i>Superboy, </i>among others<i>—</i>was responsible for getting an adult Kevin married to his partner in a fantasy issue of <em>Life With Archie</em><strong>.</strong></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=FB-BvWPYI94:Xxmmn0j5R6U:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=FB-BvWPYI94:Xxmmn0j5R6U:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/archies-resident-gay-kevin-keller-gets-his-own-young-adult-novel-20130401/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/archies-resident-gay-kevin-keller-gets-his-own-young-adult-novel-20130401/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Applebee’s Employee Says He Was Gay Bashed By Co-Worker’s Husband, Then Fired Due To Bad Publicity</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/-0KG184Z4EA/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/applebees-gay-bashing-20130401/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 11:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Primary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[applebees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay Bashing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hate Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wisconsin]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255826</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A gay employee at a Wisconsin Applebee&#8217;s claims he was brutally attacked by the husband of a co-worker only to be told that he would no longer be welcome at work due to the bad publicity it would generate. According to Timothy Phares (right) of Rice Lake, he and his sister Krista katherine were getting [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/applebees-gay-bashing-20130401/applebees-bashing/" rel="attachment wp-att-255831"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255831" style="margin: 10px;" alt="applebees-bashing" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/04/applebees-bashing-360x479.jpg" width="252" height="335" /></a>A gay employee at a Wisconsin Applebee&#8217;s claims he was brutally attacked by the husband of a co-worker only to be told that <em>he</em> would no longer be welcome at work due to the bad publicity it would generate.</p>
<p>According to Timothy Phares (<em>right</em>) of Rice Lake, he and his sister Krista katherine were getting out of their car in the parking lot of a Perkins restaurant on March 17 when Shannon Hendricks and her husband Rien pulled up behind them in an SUV.</p>
<p>“(Rien Hendricks) was getting out of his vehicle, and he said, ‘Fucking faggot, I’m going to kill you,’&#8221; Phares told the <a href="http://www.wisconsingazette.com/wisconsin-gaze/applebees-employee-gay-bashed-by-husband-of-co-worker-says-he-was-told-not-to-return-to-work-due-to-bad-publicity.html" target="_blank"><em>Wisconsin Gazette</em></a>.</p>
<p>Hendricks reportedly struck Phares with a wooden two-by-four. In a written statement, Krista katherine said she heard her brother&#8217;s head hit the pavement. Phares lost consciousness and doesn&#8217;t remember anything until waking up in the hospital.</p>
<p>Phares suffered head and facial abrasions as well as multiple facial fractures that he says will ultimately require surgery to implant metal plates.</p>
<p>Rien Hendricks was taken into custody and charged with substantial battery, a Class 1 felony. Phares said the assault is not being prosecuted as a hate crime despite the homophobic slur both he and his sister reported hearing. Shannon Hendricks has not only retained her position at Applebee&#8217;s but has not been charged with her role in the attack.</p>
<p>Phares doesn&#8217;t know what prompted the attack, though a local source tells the <em>Wisconsin Gazette</em> his &#8220;behavior&#8221; had something to do with it. A few days earlier, Phares, an Applebee&#8217;s server, was treated abusively by a customer, who had made several derogatory and anti-gay comments towards him. Following company policy, he asked manager Tara Steinberg to assign someone else to the table.</p>
<p>The customer apparently called the next day and threatened never to come back unless Phares was fired. Steinberg said she would write him up, leading Phares to put in his two-weeks notice, which he later rescinded. After the attack by Hendricks, however, Steinberg said the restaurant didn&#8217;t <em>want</em> Phares back due to the amount of negative publicity it had attracted.</p>
<p>But Greg Flynn, CEO of Apple American Group franchise, intervened and got Phares reinstated. Still, Phares doesn&#8217;t feel safe on the job as the husband of <em>another</em> co-worker threatened to kill him if he returned to Applebee&#8217;s.</p>
<p>He was also disappointed when the chain initially refused to remove homophobic comments on its Facebook page.</p>
<p>The company has a non-discrimination policy that includes sexual orientation and gender identity, and also provides domestic partnership benefits, but when the <em>Gazette</em> informed them about the Facebook comments, corporate marketing manager Katy Sincko said they were not &#8220;in the practice of hiding things on there.&#8221; 20 minutes later, however, Sincko called to say that the slurs had been removed.</p>
<p>As for Phares, he&#8217;s found support &#8212; and job offers &#8212; from his family and local residents of Rice Lake, who he says &#8220;have come a long way.&#8221;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=-0KG184Z4EA:bB--OZ9f6EQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=-0KG184Z4EA:bB--OZ9f6EQ:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/applebees-gay-bashing-20130401/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/applebees-gay-bashing-20130401/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>The Dentist Appointment: A Father’s Nightmare</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/yQqyueYtuX0/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/the-dentist-appointment-a-fathers-nightmare-20130401/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 10:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Raising My Rainbow</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raising my rainbow]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255003</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week, C.J. had to have a small dental procedure done that required him to go under anesthesia.  Of course his dad and I were a nervous wreck the weeks and days leading up to the morning of the 7am appointment. The night before, we fed C.J. a big dinner and dessert because he wouldn’t [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-255814" alt="dentist" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/dentist-360x246.jpg" width="281" height="192" />Last week, C.J. had to have a small dental procedure done that required him to go under anesthesia.  Of course his dad and I were a nervous wreck the weeks and days leading up to the morning of the 7am appointment.</p>
<p>The night before, we fed C.J. a big dinner and dessert because he wouldn’t be able to eat for at least 15 hours.  We gave him a bath with Strawberry Shortcake bubble bath and tucked him into bed wearing his favorite Disney Princess nightgown.</p>
<p>My alarm went off extra early in the morning.  I turned it off and rolled over to wake up C.J.’s Dad.  He was staring at me with big, bright eyes that startled me.</p>
<p>“What?!” I said/asked/gasped.</p>
<p>“I had the worst dream last night,” he said.</p>
<p>“What was it about?”</p>
<p>“<a href="http://raisingmyrainbow.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-33.jpg"><img class="alignright" alt="Mural from the dentist's office..." src="http://raisingmyrainbow.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-33.jpg?w=224" width="224" height="300" /></a>I had a dream that when C.J. woke up from the anesthesia he liked boy stuff.  That he was gender-conforming.”</p>
<p>“Why is that a bad dream?” I asked.  It seemed like a weird dream, but not a “bad” one.</p>
<p>Because that’s not my boy. My boy likes girl stuff,&#8221; he explained. He then recalled the dream for me:</p>
<blockquote><p>We went to the dentist and I was holding him and they gave him the shot and he went under.</p>
<p>We waited for like an hour-and-a-half and they came out to tell us that he was coming to and we went back to be with him. We walked in and he was coming out of it and he said ‘Hey Dad, what’s up?’  He said it just like his brother says it. I was stroking his head and he looked down and saw that he was wearing his Disney Princess nightgown and he asked ‘Why did you dress me in this? Why am I wearing this?’  He was really mad.</p>
<p>I told him that he was wearing it because it was his favorite nightgown and he kept getting more and more fired up.  He wanted another shirt. He wanted a boy’s shirt.  He was pissed off and didn’t even want to ride home with the nightgown on.</p>
<p>He totally wasn’t himself.  His mannerisms were all boy, like his brother.</p>
<p>I kept asking you and the dentist if he was okay, if he was fine.  The dentist told me that the procedure was a total success.  I said that it wasn’t, that he was totally different. I got upset because something was wrong.  He was not acting like himself.  And you and the dentist were downplaying it.</p>
<p>‘What’s wrong with him?! What’s wrong with him?!’ I started yelling.  And, you asked if I was happy because the anesthesia got him out of his gender-nonconforming phase and that he was normal now.</p>
<p>I grabbed you and said ‘he’s not effing normal now, not like this!’</p>
<p>I was so pissed because people kept saying that now he was normal and fine. I yelled at the dentist, ‘What did you do to my effing kid!?’ and everybody was looking at me like I was crazy.  You and the dentist kept saying that I should be happy that he liked boy stuff now.  But I was yelling and so pissed off asking what they had done to my son.</p>
<p>It wasn’t him.  He had changed.  To me that wasn’t ‘normal.’  C.J. is normal the way he is.</p>
<p>My boy likes girl stuff.  That’s his normal. My boy likes girl toys and girl clothes and saying things like ‘Ohh, heyyyy’ and ‘Drama-bomb!’  I don’t know what I would do now if he changed and started liking boy stuff. I don’t want him to change.”</p></blockquote>
<p>He finished telling me about his dream and we stared at each other.</p>
<p><a href="http://raisingmyrainbow.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-11.jpg"><img class="alignleft" alt="photo 1" src="http://raisingmyrainbow.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-11.jpg?w=224" width="190" height="254" /></a>“Oh, baby, it’s going to be fine.  He’s not going to change,” I said.  What if my husband was clairvoyant?  What if the anesthesia was going to make our gender-nonconforming boy conform?</p>
<p>I couldn’t bear to think about him changing either.</p>
<p>Three hours later C.J. woke up from the anesthesia. He got upset when the dentist gave him a “boy’s toothbrush” instead of a “girl’s toothbrush.”  When we got home he gathered his Barbie dolls and Monster High girls to comfort him as he watched old episodes of <em>iCarly</em>.</p>
<p>He was and still is gender-nonconforming. The anesthesia didn’t change him.  My husband is not a clairvoyant. For all of those things, and so much more, I am a very thankful mama.  There was a time when all we wanted was for C.J. to conform to traditional gender norms.  Now, the thought of him doing so doesn’t feel right.</p>
<p>It feels like a bad dream.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=yQqyueYtuX0:amtKLfmTfdQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=yQqyueYtuX0:amtKLfmTfdQ:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/the-dentist-appointment-a-fathers-nightmare-20130401/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/the-dentist-appointment-a-fathers-nightmare-20130401/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>NYC Archbishop Dolan To Gays: “I Love You, Too”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/_zne8H8DETY/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/nyc-archbishop-dolan-to-gays-i-love-you-too-20130401/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 10:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archbishop Dolan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Catholic Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Catholics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[timothy dolan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255807</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fresh from helping to elect the new pope, New York&#8217;s Cardinal Timothy M. Dolan hit the talk-show circuit on Easter Sunday to tell America the Church should be better about loving gay people. No, really. On ABC&#8217;s This Week, Dolan told George Stephanopoulos the Church needs &#8220;to do better to see that our defense of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="size-full wp-image-196838 alignright" alt="cardinal dolan" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2012/04/cardinal-dolan.jpg" width="222" height="222" />Fresh from helping to elect the new pope, New York&#8217;s Cardinal Timothy M. Dolan <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/01/nyregion/dolan-church-should-be-more-welcoming-of-gays.html?hp&amp;_r=1&amp;">hit the talk-show circuit on Easter Sunday</a> to tell America the Church should be better about loving gay people.</p>
<p>No, really.</p>
<p>On ABC&#8217;s <em>This Week, </em>Dolan told George Stephanopoulos the Church needs &#8220;to do better to see that our defense of marriage is not reduced to an attack on gay people.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ya think?</p>
<p>&#8220;I admit, we haven’t been too good at that,&#8221; continued Dolan. &#8220;We try our darnedest to make sure we’re not an anti-anybody.”</p>
<p>Then, Stephanopoulos asked His Excellency how he&#8217;d be better about not pissing all over the gays.</p>
<blockquote><p>“Well, the first thing I’d say to them is: ‘I love you, too. And God loves you. And you are made in God’s image and likeness. And — and we — we want your happiness,&#8221; Dolan said. &#8220;But—and you’re entitled to friendship—but we also know that God has told us that the way to happiness, that — especially when it comes to sexual love — that is intended only for a man and woman in marriage, where children can come about naturally.”</p></blockquote>
<p>You love us? You love us like Ike loved Tina.</p>
<p>On CBS&#8217; <em>Face the Nation,</em> Dolan reiterated that marriage is &#8220;one man, one woman,&#8221; and told Bob Schieffer that the Church&#8217;s problem isn&#8217;t one of intransigence, it&#8217;s just PR. The Vatican just needs to figure out  “how to remain faithful to what we believe are God-given, revealed, settled, unchanging principles without losing our people, who more and more question them.”</p>
<p>“We can try to do better in the way we present them with more credibility and in a more compelling way.”</p>
<p>Ooh, compelling! Like <em>Real Housewives of Vatican City</em>?</p>
<p>In his Easter sermon at St. Patrick&#8217;s Cathedral, Dolan said Catholicism 2.0 is gonna blow us away. “The Church, with a capital C, is undergoing renewal, repair, resurrection—I kind of think we’re seeing it today in a particularly fresh and new way with our beloved new Holy Father.”</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=_zne8H8DETY:ZilIcxaJrfs:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=_zne8H8DETY:ZilIcxaJrfs:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/nyc-archbishop-dolan-to-gays-i-love-you-too-20130401/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/nyc-archbishop-dolan-to-gays-i-love-you-too-20130401/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Chair Of Georgia GOP: Straight People Will Commit Fraud To Get Gay-Married</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/Kfo2i3JQTWs/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/chair-of-georgia-gop-straight-people-will-commit-fraud-to-get-gay-married-20130401/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 10:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[georgia republican party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GOP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sue everhart]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255646</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lord, I’m going to get in trouble over this, but it is not natural for two women or two men to be married. If it was natural they would have the equipment to have a sexual relationship. You may be as straight as an arrow, and you may have a friend that is as straight [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="giantquote">
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-255648" alt="Sue-Everhart2" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Sue-Everhart2.jpg" width="202" height="243" />Lord, I’m going to get in trouble over this, but it is not natural for two women or two men to be married. If it was natural they would have the equipment to have a sexual relationship.</p>
<p>You may be as straight as an arrow, and you may have a friend that is as straight as an arrow. Say you had a great job with the government where you had this wonderful health plan. I mean, what would prohibit you from saying that you’re gay, and y’all get married and still live as separate, but you get all the benefits? I just see so much abuse in this it’s unreal.</p>
<p>I believe a husband and a wife should be a man and a woman, the benefits should be for a man and a woman. There is no way that this is about equality. To me, it’s all about a free ride.”</p>
</div>
<p><strong>Sue Everhart</strong>, <em>chairwoman of the Georgia Republican Party, in the</em> <a href="http://www.mdjonline.com/pages/full_story/push?article-Cobb+sounds+off+as+Facebook+goes+red+in+support+of+gay+marriage%20&amp;id=22108736">Marietta Daily Journal. </a><em>Apparently Everhart believes it&#8217;s impossible for a man and a woman to come up with such a fiendish scheme.</em></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=Kfo2i3JQTWs:-BXKGAaeYuE:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=Kfo2i3JQTWs:-BXKGAaeYuE:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/chair-of-georgia-gop-straight-people-will-commit-fraud-to-get-gay-married-20130401/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/chair-of-georgia-gop-straight-people-will-commit-fraud-to-get-gay-married-20130401/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Renowned Neurosurgeon, Johns Hopkins Commencement Speaker Compares Gay Marriage To Pedophiles, Bestiality</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/Mw-kvLxmgv0/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/renowned-neurosurgeon-johns-hopkins-commencement-speaker-compares-gay-marriage-to-pedophiles-bestiality-20130401/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 10:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ben carson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Johns Hopkins University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255818</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Noted neurosurgeon Dr. Ben Carson stuck his foot in it last week on Sean Hannity&#8217;s radio show when he was asked about marriage equality. “Well, my thoughts are that marriage is between a man and a woman. It’s a well-established, fundamental pillar of society and no group—be they gays, be they NAMBLA, be they people [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-255819" alt="Ben Carson" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/04/Ben_Carson_cropped.jpg" width="198" height="202" />Noted neurosurgeon Dr. Ben Carson stuck his foot in it last week on Sean Hannity&#8217;s radio show when he was asked about marriage equality.</p>
<blockquote><p>“Well, my thoughts are that marriage is between a man and a woman. It’s a well-established, fundamental pillar of society and no group—be they gays, be they NAMBLA, be they people who believe in bestiality&#8230; It doesn’t matter what they are. They don’t get to change the definition.</p>
<p>It’s not something that is against gays—it’s against anybody who wants to come along and change the fundamental definitions of pillars of society. It has significant ramifications.”</p></blockquote>
<p>We&#8217;re used to venomous right-wingers comparing homosexuality to child molesting and bestiality, but not the head of pediatric neurology at Johns Hopkins Hospital and a specialist in separating conjoined twins.</p>
<p>Oh, and a recipient of the Presidential Medal of Freedom.</p>
<p>Carson tried to do damage control on MSNBC later in the week, saying, &#8220;If anybody was offended, I apologize to you. But what I was basically saying is that there is no group [that is equal to straight couples]. I wasn’t equating those things, I don’t think they’re equal.”</p>
<p>You can always count on a conservative to come through with an &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry you took it that way&#8221; apology. Especially one getting active in Republican politics: Besides speaking at CPAC, Carson addressed the National Prayer Breakfast in February, has popped up repeatedly on Fox News and said he&#8217;d run for office if God told him to.</p>
<p>The real sticking point is that Carson is set to give t<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/ben-carson-johns-hopkins_n_2980578.html">he commencement address at Hopkins&#8217; School of Medicine</a>. A group of students have launched <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1kD4un2PScJESGRqtcA7JCI8M7PsUkkJyFRQ-qtPrQWU/viewform" target="_blank">a petition</a> to get him replaced:</p>
<blockquote><p> At the time of his nomination, Dr. Carson was known to most of us as a world-class neurosurgeon and passionate advocate for education. Many of us had read his books and looked up to him as a role model in our careers.</p>
<p>Since then, however, several public events have cast serious doubt on the appropriateness of having Dr. Carson speak at our graduation.</p>
<p>On March 26, on Sean Hannity’s Fox News program, Dr. Carson compared gay relationships with pedophilia and bestiality: “Well, my thoughts are that marriage is between a man and a woman. It’s a well-established, fundamental pillar of society and no group, be they gays, be they NAMBLA, be they people who believe in bestiality. It doesn’t matter what they are. They don’t get to change the definition. “</p>
<p>On February 7, Dr. Carson used the National Prayer Breakfast speech— which, like our commencement ceremony, is an historically nonpartisan event — to deride Obamacare, advocate lower taxes for the wealthy, and suggest that Christianity requires supporting Republican policies.</p>
<p>Dr. Carson has also used his platform as a famous neurosurgeon to promote the rejection of evolution: “Ultimately, if you accept the evolutionary theory,” he said, in a statement that would apply to the majority of students and faculty at Johns Hopkins, “you dismiss ethics, you don’t have to abide by a set of moral codes, you determine your own conscience based on your own desires.” This belief of Dr. Carson’s was unknown to many of us at the time of his nomination.</p>
<p>We retain the highest respect for Dr. Carson’s achievements and value his right to publicly voice political views. Nevertheless, we feel that these expressed values are incongruous with the values of Johns Hopkins and deeply offensive to a large proportion our student body.</p></blockquote>
<p>Carson offered to step down to avoid taking attention away from the graduates (too late) but as of the weekend, the school has not announced any decision to disinvite Carson. A college spokesman told <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/ben-carson-johns-hopkins_n_2980578.html">Huffington Post</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Dr. Carson is a distinguished Johns Hopkins surgeon and scientist chosen to speak at the School of Medicine diploma ceremony because of his extraordinary accomplishments as a neurosurgeon and his many contributions as an advocate for education and children.</p>
<p>He was not asked to speak because of his personal political, religious or social views. His personal views are just that, his own. When he speaks about them, he is not speaking on behalf of Johns Hopkins.”</p></blockquote>
<p>That line can sometimes work when you&#8217;re talking about an author or an actor, someone whose output is creative and separate from their personal life. But Carson&#8217;s opinion on homosexuality, on the Affordable Care Act—on <em>evolution, </em>for God&#8217;s sake—are very relevant to his work, and to his qualification to give sage advice to young doctors about to enter the field.</p>
<p><em>Photo: White House</em></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=Mw-kvLxmgv0:wMr6gPbtRAQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=Mw-kvLxmgv0:wMr6gPbtRAQ:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/renowned-neurosurgeon-johns-hopkins-commencement-speaker-compares-gay-marriage-to-pedophiles-bestiality-20130401/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/renowned-neurosurgeon-johns-hopkins-commencement-speaker-compares-gay-marriage-to-pedophiles-bestiality-20130401/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>8 Ridiculous Sexy Male Bunny Stock Photos</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/wB0eVygNGgs/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/8-ridiculous-sexy-male-bunny-stock-photos-20130331/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 16:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Stacy Lambe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bunny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[male bunnies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock photos]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255765</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oh to be a stock photo model and take these ridiculous Easter/bunny-themed portraits&#8230; 1. (Image: Shutterstock) 2. (Image: Shutterstock) 3. (Image: Shutterstock) 4. (Image: Shutterstock) 5. (Image: Shutterstock) 6. (Image: Shutterstock) 7. (Image: iStockphoto) 8. (Image: iStockphoto)]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oh to be a stock photo model and take these ridiculous Easter/bunny-themed portraits&#8230;</p>
<p>1.</p>
<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-lovely-couple-in-rabbit-costumes-with-carrots-and-eggs-131728343.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255769" alt="stock-photo-lovely-couple-in-rabbit-costumes-with-carrots-and-eggs-131728343" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-lovely-couple-in-rabbit-costumes-with-carrots-and-eggs-131728343.jpg" width="300" height="470" /></a><small>(Image: <a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/pic-131728343/stock-photo-lovely-couple-in-rabbit-costumes-with-carrots-and-eggs.html?src=71322C82-9A20-11E2-8B41-22571472E43D-1-21">Shutterstock</a>)</small></p>
<p>2.</p>
<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-funny-image-of-muscular-male-model-topless-wearing-bunny-ears-celebrating-success-over-green-88936870.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255771" alt="stock-photo-funny-image-of-muscular-male-model-topless-wearing-bunny-ears-celebrating-success-over-green-88936870" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-funny-image-of-muscular-male-model-topless-wearing-bunny-ears-celebrating-success-over-green-88936870.jpg" width="300" height="470" /></a><small>(Image: <a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/pic-88936870/stock-photo-funny-image-of-muscular-male-model-topless-wearing-bunny-ears-celebrating-success-over-green.html?src=71322C82-9A20-11E2-8B41-22571472E43D-1-7">Shutterstock</a>)</small></p>
<p>3.</p>
<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-lovely-man-in-rabbit-costume-with-carrots-130784066.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255772" alt="stock-photo-lovely-man-in-rabbit-costume-with-carrots-130784066" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-lovely-man-in-rabbit-costume-with-carrots-130784066.jpg" width="450" height="320" /></a><small>(Image: <a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/pic-130784066/stock-photo-lovely-man-in-rabbit-costume-with-carrots.html?src=71322C82-9A20-11E2-8B41-22571472E43D-1-24">Shutterstock</a>)</small></p>
<p>4.</p>
<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-portrait-of-cheerful-pink-rabbit-is-proud-of-his-carrot-isolated-on-white-background-78191149.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255774" alt="stock-photo-portrait-of-cheerful-pink-rabbit-is-proud-of-his-carrot-isolated-on-white-background-78191149" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-portrait-of-cheerful-pink-rabbit-is-proud-of-his-carrot-isolated-on-white-background-78191149.jpg" width="300" height="470" /></a><small>(Image: <a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/pic-78191149/stock-photo-portrait-of-cheerful-pink-rabbit-is-proud-of-his-carrot-isolated-on-white-background.html?src=C881ED24-9A20-11E2-859B-22571472E43D-1-19">Shutterstock</a>)</small></p>
<p>5.</p>
<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-glamorous-man-with-bunny-15147166.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255775" alt="stock-photo-glamorous-man-with-bunny-15147166" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-glamorous-man-with-bunny-15147166.jpg" width="283" height="470" /></a><small>(Image: <a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/pic-15147166/stock-photo-glamorous-man-with-bunny.html?src=C881ED24-9A20-11E2-859B-22571472E43D-3-43">Shutterstock</a>)</small></p>
<p>6.</p>
<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-man-wearing-bunny-hat-with-golden-eggs-in-the-hands-49289284.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255776" alt="stock-photo-man-wearing-bunny-hat-with-golden-eggs-in-the-hands-49289284" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-man-wearing-bunny-hat-with-golden-eggs-in-the-hands-49289284.jpg" width="339" height="470" /></a><small>(Image: <a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/pic-49289284/stock-photo-man-wearing-bunny-hat-with-golden-eggs-in-the-hands.html?src=71322C82-9A20-11E2-8B41-22571472E43D-1-13">Shutterstock</a>)</small></p>
<p>7.</p>
<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-561378-pet.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255777" alt="stock-photo-561378-pet" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-561378-pet.jpg" width="253" height="380" /></a><small>(Image: <a href="http://www.istockphoto.com/stock-photo-561378-pet.php?st=73a4f50">iStockphoto</a>)</small></p>
<p>8.</p>
<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-2282655-muscle-bunny.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255778" alt="stock-photo-2282655-muscle-bunny" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/stock-photo-2282655-muscle-bunny.jpg" width="380" height="253" /></a><small>(Image: <a href="http://www.istockphoto.com/stock-photo-2282655-muscle-bunny.php?st=73a4f50">iStockphoto</a>)</small></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=wB0eVygNGgs:6yrl_XFsXLw:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=wB0eVygNGgs:6yrl_XFsXLw:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/8-ridiculous-sexy-male-bunny-stock-photos-20130331/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/8-ridiculous-sexy-male-bunny-stock-photos-20130331/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>AZ Congressman With Gay Son Is Still Against Same-Sex Marriage</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/7wG0isN2NZQ/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/az-congressman-with-gay-son-is-still-against-same-sex-marriage-20130331/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 16:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arizon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay republicans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff flake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kent Flake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matt salmon]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255738</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For every Rob Portman there&#8217;s a dozen Republicans that still don&#8217;t support marriage equality even though they have gay kids. The latest one to crawl out of the woodwork is Arizona congressman Matt Salmon. In an interview with Arizona 3TV, the Mormon politician shared that though his youngest son, Matt Jr., is openly gay, he&#8217;s [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-255762" style="margin: 5px 10px;" alt="matt salmon" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-31-at-12.28.40-PM.png" width="217" height="262" />For every Rob Portman there&#8217;s a dozen Republicans that still don&#8217;t support marriage equality <a href="http://www.queerty.com/its-all-relative-7-prominent-republicans-with-gay-family-members-20130320/">even though they have gay kids</a>. The latest one to crawl out of the woodwork is Arizona congressman Matt Salmon.</p>
<p>In an interview with Arizona 3TV, the Mormon politician shared that though <a href="http://www.azfamily.com/news/Gay-son-doesnt-change-congressmans-view-on-gay-marriage-200686251.html">his youngest son, Matt Jr., is openly gay,</a> he&#8217;s not interested in giving him equal rights.</p>
<p>&#8220;It doesn’t mean I don’t have respect—it doesn’t mean I don’t sympathize with some of the issues, it means I haven’t evolved to that station Rob Portman apparently has,” said Salmon. “I’m just not there in believing in my heart,” said Salmon “My son is one of the most important people in my life. I love him more than I can say.”</p>
<p>Daddy has an odd way of showing it: Rep. Salmon voted for DOMA in 1996, tried to ban gays and lesbians in D.C. from adopting children, and has pushed numerous other anti-LGBT measures. Even Matt Jr.&#8217;s mom, Nancy, helped raise some $50,000 for Proposition 107, which sought to ban same-sex marriage, civil unions, and domestic partnerships in the Grand Canyon State.</p>
<p>In 2010, the <a href="http://www.phoenixnewtimes.com/2010-09-16/news/over-the-rainbow-the-namesake-son-of-conservative-mormon-matt-salmon-wants-to-make-a-name-for-himself-in-republican-politics-only-he-s-gay/"><em>Phoenix New Times</em> reported</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p> The Salmons have been so vocally anti-gay over the years that some local politicians, frankly, rejoiced when one of their four kids came out.</p>
<p><img class="alignright" alt="matt salmon kent flake" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-31-at-12.26.41-PM.png" width="229" height="285" />&#8220;There were a lot of us 10 years ago that prayed one of Matt Salmon&#8217;s kids would turn out gay,&#8221; says Steve May. &#8220;Not because we wanted to cause any problems or pain for anybody, but because we believe that gay children will change the hearts and minds of their parents.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Wanna bet Rep. Salmon will &#8220;evolve&#8221; on LGBT equality five minutes after the majority of his constituents do and it becomes politically expedient?But the Salmon family situation is truly fascinating: Not only is Matt Jr. out but he&#8217;s the president of the Arizona Log Cabin Republicans—and his partner is Kent Flake, second cousin of right-wing Arizona Sen. Jeff Flake.The Flakes and Salmons (gotta love those names) have chilled toward their gay progeny: Matt Jr&#8217;s siblings unfriended him on Facebook when he started posting about his life with Kent. And Kent&#8217;s family has no interest in meeting the love of their son&#8217;s life: &#8220;I&#8217;ve asked them many times to meet him, and they don&#8217;t want to see him,&#8221; Flake says. &#8220;My dad&#8217;s last comment to me was that he didn&#8217;t want him around our family, his kids, or his grandkids.&#8221;Republican family values hard at work, folks!</p>
<p><em>Photos: <a href="http://www.jpphoto.co">Jamie Peachey</a></em></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=7wG0isN2NZQ:an5neeCBo6c:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=7wG0isN2NZQ:an5neeCBo6c:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/az-congressman-with-gay-son-is-still-against-same-sex-marriage-20130331/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/az-congressman-with-gay-son-is-still-against-same-sex-marriage-20130331/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Celebrate Easter With Lady Bunny, Steam Room Egg Hunts &amp; A Creepy Lamb Loaf</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/TMIkYHLbwls/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/easter-videos-20130331/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 16:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Primary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charles phoenix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conan O'Brien]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lady Bunny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steam room stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255634</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Happy Easter! Don&#8217;t call it a comeback, Christ has been here for years. Whether you subscribe to the idea of a Zombie Jesus, or just like having a reason to eat a giant chocolate bunny by your lonesome while wearing a festive bonnet, these three videos will have you hopping with laughter. It&#8217;s Easter in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/easter-videos-20130331/lady-bunny-easter/" rel="attachment wp-att-255734"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255734" alt="lady-bunny-easter" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/lady-bunny-easter-670x667.jpg" width="510" height="508" /></a></p>
<p>Happy Easter! Don&#8217;t call it a comeback, Christ has been here for years. Whether you subscribe to the idea of a Zombie Jesus, or just like having a reason to eat a giant chocolate bunny by your lonesome while wearing a festive bonnet, these three videos will have you <em>hopping</em> with laughter.<br />
<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/sEDeObuqrMA?rel=0" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>It&#8217;s Easter in the steam room and somebody&#8217;s goin&#8217; a-huntin&#8217;.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/kDZvDRME2tY?rel=0" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Get ready for a lot of pedophile jokes. Like, 4 minutes worth. NSFW.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe src="http://teamcoco.com/embed/v/49908" height="465" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>A sequined bolero tie-wearing Charles Phoenix shows Conan the disturbing history of grown men in bunny suits and the even more disturbing lamb-shaped meatloaf.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=TMIkYHLbwls:4-v1ZtDeFRc:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=TMIkYHLbwls:4-v1ZtDeFRc:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/easter-videos-20130331/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/easter-videos-20130331/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Tumblr Alert: Instabeards</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/B_tw8Kc3enM/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/tumblr-alert-instabeards-20130331/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 16:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Stacy Lambe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[instabeards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scruff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tumblr]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255744</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you don&#8217;t already follow Instabeards then you really should. The site collects all the scruffy guys from Instagram in one woof-y Tumblr. If nothing else, it&#8217;s a way to find new guys on Instagram. Check out a few highlights below: (Image) (Image) (Image)]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you don&#8217;t already follow <strong><a href="http://instabeards.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Instabeards</a></strong> then you really should. The site collects all the scruffy guys from Instagram in one woof-y Tumblr. If nothing else, it&#8217;s a way to find new guys on Instagram. Check out a few highlights below:</p>
<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/tumblr_mjvxpwRZCv1rq6xvjo1_400.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255745" alt="tumblr_mjvxpwRZCv1rq6xvjo1_400" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/tumblr_mjvxpwRZCv1rq6xvjo1_400.jpg" width="400" height="400" /></a><small>(<a href="http://instabeards.tumblr.com/post/45723873224/akiless-90">Image</a>)</small></p>
<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/tumblr_mk9imjiEC61rq6xvjo1_400.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255747" alt="tumblr_mk9imjiEC61rq6xvjo1_400" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/tumblr_mk9imjiEC61rq6xvjo1_400.jpg" width="400" height="400" /></a><small>(<a href="http://instabeards.tumblr.com/post/46327834279/fternes">Image</a>)</small></p>
<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/tumblr_mk5wqgyMsn1rq6xvjo1_400.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255748" alt="tumblr_mk5wqgyMsn1rq6xvjo1_400" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/tumblr_mk5wqgyMsn1rq6xvjo1_400.jpg" width="400" height="400" /></a><small>(<a href="http://instabeards.tumblr.com/post/46151853360/almog9">Image</a>)</small></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=B_tw8Kc3enM:yGBEDPQlfk4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=B_tw8Kc3enM:yGBEDPQlfk4:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/tumblr-alert-instabeards-20130331/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/tumblr-alert-instabeards-20130331/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Watch: The Teaser For Season Six Of “True Blood”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/DrMEJAAWOrw/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-the-teaser-for-season-six-of-true-blood-20130331/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 15:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Stacy Lambe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joe manganiello]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trailer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[True Blood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vampires]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255739</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Looks like there&#8217;s going to be plenty of vampire goo, angry Tara and Joe Manganiello&#8217;s abs. Oh my! The show premieres June 16th.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Dum9haCWpgA" height="338" width="601" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Looks like there&#8217;s going to be plenty of vampire goo, angry Tara and Joe Manganiello&#8217;s abs. Oh my! The show premieres June 16th. </p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=DrMEJAAWOrw:Sn8Wv2XacAo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=DrMEJAAWOrw:Sn8Wv2XacAo:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-the-teaser-for-season-six-of-true-blood-20130331/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-the-teaser-for-season-six-of-true-blood-20130331/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>The Time Freddie Mercury Snuck Princess Diana Into A Gay Club Dressed As A Boy</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/74dh2j6CWHs/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/the-time-freddie-mercury-snuck-princess-diana-into-a-gay-club-dressed-as-a-boy-20130331/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 15:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freddie Mercury]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Princess Diana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[royal vauxhall tavern]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255733</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Back in the late 1980s, queer singer Freddie Mercury brought Princess Diana to a London gay club in disguise, according to a new book by British actress Cleo Rocos. In The Power of Positive Drinking, Rocos explains how she and gay comedian Kenny Everett accompanied the rocker and the royal to Royal Vauxhall Tavern, the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-255735" alt="diana freddie" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/diana-freddie-360x215.jpg" width="329" height="197" />Back in the late 1980s, queer singer Freddie Mercury brought Princess Diana <a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/freddie-mercury-smuggled-princess-diana-into-a-gay-club-dressed-as-a-man-8555453.html">to a London gay club in disguise</a>, according to a new book by British actress Cleo Rocos.</p>
<p>In <em>The Power of Positive Drinking, </em>Rocos explains how she and gay comedian Kenny Everett accompanied the rocker and the royal to Royal Vauxhall Tavern, the oldest gay bar in South London, with Diana disguised in an army jacket, cap and dark sunglasses.</p>
<p>Rocos says the princess looked &#8220;like a beautiful young man.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;When we walked in&#8230; we felt she was obviously Princess Diana and would be discovered at any minute. But people just seemed to blank her. She sort of disappeared. But she loved it.&#8221;</p>
<div>
<p>Apparently the presence of the three other celebrities allowed Diana to mingle undetected and even order a round of drinks.</p>
<p>Oh, to be in England!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=74dh2j6CWHs:F2nnuEmTCsA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=74dh2j6CWHs:F2nnuEmTCsA:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/the-time-freddie-mercury-snuck-princess-diana-into-a-gay-club-dressed-as-a-boy-20130331/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/the-time-freddie-mercury-snuck-princess-diana-into-a-gay-club-dressed-as-a-boy-20130331/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Madonna Baby-Daddy Carlos Leon Is The Son Of God In “Carlos Christ”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/5_0THnA-LsM/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-madonna-baby-daddy-carlos-leon-is-the-son-of-god-in-carlos-christ-20130331/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 10:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Primary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carlos Leon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael angelo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255599</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s not a lot gay about Easter, except for maybe the whole thing with the 33-year-old bachelor in a loincloth. So artist Michael Angelo (yes, that&#8217;s his real name) made this Passion play with Madonna&#8217;s Baby Daddy, Carlos Leon, cast as as Jesus. In the spirit of springtime and new beginnings, Michael Angelo&#8217;s film Carlos [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/61674130" height="281" width="500" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>There&#8217;s not a lot gay about Easter, except for maybe the whole thing with the 33-year-old bachelor in a loincloth. So artist Michael Angelo (yes, that&#8217;s his real name) made this Passion play with Madonna&#8217;s Baby Daddy, Carlos Leon, cast as as Jesus.</p>
<blockquote><p>In the spirit of springtime and new beginnings, Michael Angelo&#8217;s film <em>Carlos Christo</em> looks at the period of Jesus&#8217; life between his baptism and his resurrection through a secular and lyrical lens.</p>
<p>Despite being tempted by great fear about a painful destiny, Jesus makes the ultimate sacrifice because of his love for the future of humanity. Angelo&#8217;s film is meant to remind us that regardless of our religion or our choice to not practice one, it is through courage and empathy that we will see our world reborn.</p></blockquote>
<p>See, we&#8217;re not perving on Leon—it&#8217;s a spiritual thing.</p>
<p>Happy Easter, everyone!</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=5_0THnA-LsM:D8JL-wkiWvg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=5_0THnA-LsM:D8JL-wkiWvg:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-madonna-baby-daddy-carlos-leon-is-the-son-of-god-in-carlos-christ-20130331/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-madonna-baby-daddy-carlos-leon-is-the-son-of-god-in-carlos-christ-20130331/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Dustin Lance Black, Chad Griffin Fight For Equality in D.C.</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/hfOEiAk_t-4/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-dustin-lance-black-chad-griffin-fight-for-equality-in-d-c-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 21:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeremy Kinser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255715</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dustin Lance Black, Chad Griffin, Rob Reiner, and others are featured in a new video released by the American Foundation for Equal Rights (AFER). The footage offers interviews and a behind-the-scenes look at the heroic team who earlier this week descended upon Washington D.C. where the U.S. Supreme Court heard arguments for and against Proposition [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/nJOz_8L5BtE" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Dustin Lance Black, Chad Griffin, Rob Reiner, and others are featured in a new video released by the <a href="http://afer.org/">American Foundation for Equal Rights</a> (AFER). The footage offers interviews and a behind-the-scenes look at the heroic team who earlier this week descended upon Washington D.C. where the U.S. Supreme Court heard arguments for and against Proposition 8, a California law that bans same-sex marriages, and the Defense of Marriage Act (DOMA), a federal law defining marriage as between a man and woman.</p>
<p>&#8220;The is exactly what our judicial system is for and this is where we should be on this day,&#8221; says <a href="http://www.hrc.org/">Human Rights Campaign</a> president Griffin, who was a founding member of AFER.</p>
<p>&#8220;Everything we&#8217;re doing is about the next generation so the young people out there who are falling in love for the first time do so without judgment,&#8221; adds Black.</p>
<p>Actor Rory O&#8217;Malley, who appeared in both the Broadway and Los Angeles productions of <em>8</em>, Black&#8217;s play about the California court case, confesses he can&#8217;t wait until June, when a decision is expected to be made. Summer has never seemed so far away.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=hfOEiAk_t-4:7XlUR9PDYJA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=hfOEiAk_t-4:7XlUR9PDYJA:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-dustin-lance-black-chad-griffin-fight-for-equality-in-d-c-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-dustin-lance-black-chad-griffin-fight-for-equality-in-d-c-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>“Mad Men” Creator Reveals Why He Fired the Gay Character</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/YMfnJBqA7Gc/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/mad-men-creator-reveals-why-he-fired-the-gay-character-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 20:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeremy Kinser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255697</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With Mad Men returning April 7, the world eagerly awaits to see what&#8217;s it store for Don Draper, not to mention how the show&#8217;s wardrobe department will handle Jon Hamm&#8217;s battle of the bulge as the series moves into the tight-trousered late &#8217;60s. Yet many queer fans are still smarting over the departure of closeted [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/SAL-BELLHOP-MAD-MEN1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-255698 alignright" alt="SAL-BELLHOP-MAD-MEN" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/SAL-BELLHOP-MAD-MEN1.jpg" width="343" height="251" /></a>With <em>Mad Men</em> returning April 7, the world eagerly awaits to see what&#8217;s it store for Don Draper, not to mention how the show&#8217;s wardrobe department will handle Jon Hamm&#8217;s <a href="http://www.queerty.com/10-bulges-to-talk-about-other-than-jon-hamms-20130327/">battle of the bulge</a> as the series moves into the tight-trousered late &#8217;60s. Yet many queer fans are still smarting over the departure of closeted gay Sal Romano during season 3 and, rest assured, series creator Matthew Weiner empathizes with our anguish.</p>
<p>The Sterling Cooper art director, memorably played with just the right amount of swish by Bryan Batt, was a victim of the time. Although married to a female, he still yearned for fulfillment with a man, when he wasn&#8217;t busy swooning to Ann-Margret movies, that is. Romano was unceremoniously fired from the ad agency after he rebuffed the advances of a drunken male client.</p>
<p>It was a move that surprised and angered many hardcore fans, but Weiner says that while it was a tough decision, it was necessary in the interest of historical accuracy.</p>
<p>&#8220;More than with any other character, I&#8217;ve had lots of conversations about that,&#8221; Weiner tells <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887324105204578384404014782288.html?mod=WSJ_GoogleNews"><em>Wall Street Journal</em></a>. &#8220;I wanted to tell the story of how incredibly unfair it was for Sal, and that&#8217;s the sacrifice I made. It&#8217;s a gigantic moment in the series.&#8221;</p>
<p>As the series heads into its penultimate season, here&#8217;s hoping Sal makes a return in time to raise hell at the Stonewall riots.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=YMfnJBqA7Gc:f1oJrI-KQPc:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=YMfnJBqA7Gc:f1oJrI-KQPc:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/mad-men-creator-reveals-why-he-fired-the-gay-character-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/mad-men-creator-reveals-why-he-fired-the-gay-character-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>President of Gambia Still Wants to Kill Gays, But He Loves Wrestling</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/6wJUhqPZm-Y/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/president-of-gambia-says-gays-belong-in-female-prison-but-he-loves-wrestling-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 19:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeremy Kinser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255693</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Not that you were planning to visit Gambia anytime soon, but go ahead and erase a vacation to the notoriously antigay West African country off your bucket list. During an address to Gambia&#8217;s parliament March 28, president Yahta Jammeh, who previously announced he&#8217;d cut off the heads of gay people and that he can cure HIV/AIDS with [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/yahya-jammeh.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-255695 alignright" alt="yahya-jammeh" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/yahya-jammeh-360x248.jpg" width="360" height="248" /></a></p>
<p>Not that you were planning to visit Gambia anytime soon, but go ahead and erase a vacation to the notoriously antigay West African country off your bucket list.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.freedomnewspaper.com/Homepage/tabid/36/newsid367/8550/Jammeh-Says-Gambias-Growing-Murder-Rate-Will-Lead-To-The-Moratorium-On-The-Execution-Of-Death-Row-Inmates-Being-Lifted-Without-Any-Further-Notice/Default.aspx">During an address</a> to Gambia&#8217;s parliament March 28, president Yahta Jammeh, who previously announced he&#8217;d cut off the heads of gay people and that <a href="http://www.queerty.com/gambian-president-claims-to-have-cured-dozens-of-hiv-patients-with-herbs-20121015/">he can cure HIV/AIDS</a> with herbs, , continued his antigay diatribe. Jammeh took the opportunity to send out yet another warning that gays are not welcome in his nation.</p>
<p>“Homosexuality is anti-humanity. I have never seen homosexual chicken, or turkey..,&#8221; Jammeh said during the speech. (We guess he hasn&#8217;t seen <a href="http://www.queerty.com/watch-what-if-homosexual-animals-had-the-hang-ups-gay-humans-did-20120721/">this video</a>.) &#8220;If you are convicted of homosexuality in this country, there will be no mercy for offenders. We will put you in the female wing of the prison,” Jammeh continues.</p>
<p>“We want the population to grow. There will be children in this country. Homosexuality is anti-god, anti-human, and anti-civilization. Homosexuals are not welcome in the Gambia. If we catch you, you will regret why you are born [sic]. I have buffalos from South Africa and Brazil and they never date each other. We are ready to eat grass but we will not compromise on this. Allowing homosexuality means allowing satanic rights. We will not allow gays here.”</p>
<p>Yet for someone so virulently opposed to hot man-on-man action, Jammeh apparently loves a Half-Nelson. He curiously <a href="http://www.freedomnewspaper.com/Homepage/tabid/36/newsid367/8547/Gambias-President-Says-Wrestling-Will-Now-Be-Part-Of-Gambias-Educational-Curriculum-System/Default.aspx">issued a mandate</a> that makes wrestling part of Gambia&#8217;s educational curriculum.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=6wJUhqPZm-Y:Zs-Mv_P-d8g:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=6wJUhqPZm-Y:Zs-Mv_P-d8g:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/president-of-gambia-says-gays-belong-in-female-prison-but-he-loves-wrestling-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/president-of-gambia-says-gays-belong-in-female-prison-but-he-loves-wrestling-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Elizabeth Taylor and Montgomery Clift: Were They Lovers Off-Screen?</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/Xwto4qm_Mz0/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/elizabeth-taylor-and-montgomery-clift-were-they-lovers-off-screen-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 19:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeremy Kinser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255684</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Who was the most beautiful couple in cinema history you ask? Sure, there&#8217;s support for Brad and Angie, as well as Heath and Jake. Yet, as good gays, we think none can compare to the fabled pairing of movie legends Elizabeth Taylor and Montgomery Clift. The epically hetero Taylor, who would become a tirelessly devoted [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Who was the most beautiful couple in cinema history you ask? Sure, there&#8217;s support for Brad and Angie, as well as Heath and Jake. Yet, as good gays, we think none can compare to the fabled pairing of movie legends Elizabeth Taylor and Montgomery Clift.</p>
<p>The epically hetero Taylor, who would become a tirelessly devoted friend to the gay community during the early years of the AIDS epidemic, and the tragically closeted Clift torridly tangled in three films (<em>A Place in the Sun</em>, <em>Raintree County</em>, and<em> Suddenly, Last Summer</em>), but was their passion consummated off-screen, as well? Screen legend Debbie Reynolds claims it was.</p>
<p>In her upcoming memoir, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Unsinkable-A-Memoir-Debbie-Reynolds/dp/0062213652"><em>Unsinkable</em> (out Tuesday</a>), Carrie Fisher&#8217;s unbridled mommy, who would infamously lose hubby Eddie Fisher to Taylor in 1958, remembers an incident at a party at Taylor&#8217;s Hollywood Hills mansion that indicates the easy-on-the-eyes duo didn&#8217;t save the smolder for the camera.</p>
<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/LizandMonty.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-255649 alignleft" style="margin: 5px 10px;" alt="LizandMonty" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/LizandMonty-360x277.jpg" width="285" height="219" /></a>Reynolds recalls her surprise watching as Clift and Taylor, then married to stuff British actor Michael Wilding, &#8220;laughed and giggled while making out in the water in front of us all&#8230; Even though Monty had boyfriends as well as girlfriends, it was obvious that he and Elizabeth had been intimate. Elizabeth could seduce any man, gay or straight,&#8221; Reynolds writes.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, this was the same night that the otherwise gay Clift, who&#8217;s many demons included an affair with the bottle, had consumed too much alcohol and crashed his car after leaving the bash, disfiguring  his impossibly beautiful face. It&#8217;s become Hollywood lore that upon hearing the news of the accident, Taylor rushed to assist her beloved friend.</p>
<p>&#8220;Elizabeth stuck her hand in his mouth, felt the back of his throat where some of his teeth had become lodged after being knocked out, and pulled them to prevent him from choking,&#8221; Reynolds says of her fellow icon. &#8220;He might have died if she hadn&#8217;t come to his aid.&#8221; Clift would eventually die at age 45 in 1966 , while Taylor would survive until 2011.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve long admired Taylor&#8217;s passion, particularly her slavish devotion to her LGBT friends and tireless commitment to raising awareness for HIV/AIDS, but Reynolds&#8217; anecdote begs a question: Would you have switched teams for Elizabeth Taylor?</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=Xwto4qm_Mz0:vRVYGF7ky1I:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=Xwto4qm_Mz0:vRVYGF7ky1I:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/elizabeth-taylor-and-montgomery-clift-were-they-lovers-off-screen-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/elizabeth-taylor-and-montgomery-clift-were-they-lovers-off-screen-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Marie Osmond Wants Marriage Equality for Her Lesbian Daughter</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/OD7ymTr0yHE/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-marie-osmond-wants-marriage-equality-for-her-lesbian-daughter-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 17:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeremy Kinser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diane Sawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marie osmond]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mormons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religion]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255663</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Marie Osmond, the wholesome entertainer who once sang about being a little bit country, has come out whole lot in favor of marriage equality. The singer has taken the stance to support her daughter Jessica Blosil, who came out to her as a lesbian at age 17. &#8220;The God that I believe in is a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/oAz4HJ-IFf0" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Marie Osmond, the wholesome entertainer who once sang about being a little bit country, has come out whole lot in favor of marriage equality. The singer has taken the stance to support her daughter Jessica Blosil, who came out to her as a lesbian at age 17.</p>
<p>&#8220;The God that I believe in is a god of love, not fear,” Osmond, who was raised Mormon along with her eight famous brothers, tells ABC’s Diane Sawyer. “I don&#8217;t tell my children if you&#8217;re not good you&#8217;re going to Hell. I tell my children that God will be there for them when they struggle. That&#8217;s the God I believe in&#8230;I believe in [Jessica's] civil rights, as a mother.</p>
<p>The singer, whose memoir <em>The Key is Love </em>will be published Tuesday, tells ABC&#8217;s Diane Sawyer about the day her now-22 year-old daughter came out to her while still a teen. &#8220;My heart broke for her,&#8221; Osmond recalls. &#8220;I think it&#8217;s easier now, but not as a 17-year-old child.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think my daughter deserves everything that she desires in life,&#8221; Osmond adds. &#8220;She&#8217;s a good girl. She&#8217;s a wonderful child. I don&#8217;t think God made one color flower. I think he made many&#8230;&#8221;</p>
<p>Perhaps less surprising is news that Marie&#8217;s opinion is in sharp contrast to some other, more traditional members of her large Mormon family. Osmond&#8217;s oldest brother Alan and his wife Suzanne, took time away from entertaining Branson, Missouri tourists, to host an anti-marriage equality rally in Salt Lake City, Utah last Tuesday.</p>
<p>In a week with marriage equality again dominating the national headlines and even <a href="http://www.queerty.com/rush-limbaugh-gay-marriage-inevitable-20130329/" target="_blank">Rush Limbaugh conceding</a>, Marie&#8217;s commendable support inspired Sawyer to name her ABC&#8217;s Person of the Week. We agree. Let&#8217;s hear from you, Donny.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=OD7ymTr0yHE:BlRFKaoeyQg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=OD7ymTr0yHE:BlRFKaoeyQg:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-marie-osmond-wants-marriage-equality-for-her-lesbian-daughter-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-marie-osmond-wants-marriage-equality-for-her-lesbian-daughter-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: For A Good Time, Ring Willam’s Bell</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/CLD8OoVwJMQ/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-for-a-good-time-ring-willams-bell-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 14:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drag race]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ring my bell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RuPaul's Drag Race]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Willam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Willam Belli]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255181</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Willam is the latest queen to pick up the phone in our new favorite web series, Ring My Bell, which in Ms. Belli&#8217;s manicured claws quickly devolves into a low class, high camp sex hotline. You&#8217;re welcome.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/i6KUjc5UMv8?rel=0" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Willam is the latest queen to pick up the phone in our new favorite web series, <em>Ring My Bell</em>, which in Ms. Belli&#8217;s manicured claws quickly devolves into a low class, high camp sex hotline. You&#8217;re welcome.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=CLD8OoVwJMQ:2MhqKhKBigg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=CLD8OoVwJMQ:2MhqKhKBigg:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-for-a-good-time-ring-willams-bell-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-for-a-good-time-ring-willams-bell-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Playwright Dan Fishback Discusses Gaycism, Self-Loathing And The Iraq War In “Waiting For Barbara”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/AXWk323e_mI/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/dan-fishback-waiting-for-barbara-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 12:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barbara Bush]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christine Quinn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dan fishback]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaycism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homophobia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internal homophobia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iraq War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mattilda bernstein sycamore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muslim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarah Schulman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the new normal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theater]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255623</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Playwright Dan Fishback covers a lot of territory in his humorous but highly provocative play, Waiting for Barbara: homophobia, privilege, power, racism &#8212; all rolled up and snorted through a 100 dollar bill. Set on the first night of the War in Iraq, two gay Yale seniors await the arrival of the President&#8217;s daughter to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/dan-fishback-waiting-for-barbara-20130330/waiting-for-barbara/" rel="attachment wp-att-255625"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-255625" style="margin: 10px;" alt="WAITING FOR BARBARA" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/WAITING-FOR-BARBARA-360x361.jpg" width="360" height="361" /></a>Playwright <a href="http://www.danfishback.com/" target="_blank">Dan Fishback</a> covers a lot of territory in his humorous but highly provocative play, <em>Waiting for Barbara</em>: homophobia, privilege, power, racism &#8212; all rolled up and snorted through a 100 dollar bill.</p>
<p>Set on the first night of the War in Iraq, two gay Yale seniors await the arrival of the President&#8217;s daughter to bring them to &#8220;an opening night war party.&#8221; While they wait, they drown their sorrows in cocaine and crystal meth, self-loathing and self-denial, and through their own twisted lenses, they envision what the war means for them and for America.</p>
<p>Fishback staged a reading at New York&#8217;s New Museum on the tenth anniversary of the start of the Iraq War, followed by a discussion of its themes. A few days later we had Dan analyze his own words to give us his unfiltered take on internal homophobia and gaycism in the LGBT community.</p>
<p>Warning: there&#8217;s some indelicate language ahead.</p>
<blockquote><p><b>Davenport</b>: I never thought I’d feel this way, but it’s like: I’m really thinking about gay people all over the world, and how we’re going to save them from the Muslims.</p>
<p><b>Bryce</b>: It’s our duty. It’s our duty as homosexuals to protect one another.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Queerty:<i> Do you think the plight of gays in the Muslim world has improved since the start of the wars?</i></strong></p>
<p><strong>Fishback:</strong> Oh god, no.  This is one of the big myths of Western imperialism – that war with Muslim countries will bring safety for women and queer people.  In the decade since our invasion of Iraq, hundreds if not thousands of gay men and trans women in Iraq have been systematically hunted down, tortured and killed by anti-queer death squads.  Some of the more gruesome torture involved cementing the anuses of the victims, and then force-feeding them laxatives so their intestines would explode.  This was not happening under Saddam.  So yeah, the War in Iraq has not been good for gay people, no.</p>
<p>And yet we still see this attitude that Americans should support violence against Muslim countries because those countries are homophobic.  (As if America is not also homophobic and transphobic – as if trans people in our own country are not also systematically murdered.)  You see it particularly in the discourse about Israel and Palestine, but if you talk to queer Palestinians, they all say that they will never see progress until the Occupation ends.  So if you partially justify the subjugation of Palestine because it is a homophobic place, you’re also ignoring the actual wishes of real queer Palestinians who are begging for freedom.  Recent writing by <a href="http://www.queerty.com/new-york-lgbt-center-lifts-ban-on-israeli-palestinian-conflict-20130217/" target="_blank">Sarah Schulman</a> is particularly helpful to understand this process, especially her book, <em>Israel/Palestine and the Queer International.</em></p>
<blockquote><p><b>Davenport</b>: Sam’s in love with you.</p>
<p><b>Bryce</b>: Sam’s in love with Barbara!</p>
<p><b>Davenport</b>: Sam is in love with power. Sam is in love with the power of being best friends with the First Daughter, and Sam is in love with the power of SUCKING YOUR PASTY-ASS BLUE-BLOOD YANKEE DICK.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Q:<i> One of the most interesting themes of the play is “proximity to power,” particularly how homosexuals in those positions – closeted or not – forsake the LGBT community, e.g. Ken Mehlman. Can you speak to that a bit?</i></strong></p>
<p><strong>F:</strong> One of the worst culprits of this kind of betrayal is Christine Quinn.  People support her because she’s a lesbian, but her actual policies are terrible for most queer people.  She supported turning St. Vincent’s Hospital in the still-gay West Village into a luxury condo high rise, as if gay people need wealthy neighbors more than they need a hospital.  She won’t pass paid sick leave, she’s supported our demonic Police Commissioner, the list goes on and on.  But the thing is: queer people are everywhere.  So when politicians like Quinn attack the poor, they attack the LGBT community.  When they attack immigrants, they attack the LGBT community.  When they attack people of color, they attack the LGBT community.</p>
<p>It happens over and over again – not just here, but in Western European countries too.  When white homosexuals gain access to political power, they consolidate it by joining the white heterosexual elite in oppressing some “other” group – like immigrants, the poor, or people of color.  This is being called “homonationalism,” which I think is a really helpful term, because it’s so widespread – the desperateness with which so many white homosexuals shit on whoever is beneath them in order to feel more secure in the power structure that, only a few years ago, would have eaten them alive.</p>
<blockquote><p><b>Davenport</b>: Jesus. Don’t get all Self-Loathing, Country Club Pity Poofter on me – it won’t work. I’m not going to feel sorry for you.</p>
<p><b>Bryce</b>: I don’t want you to feel sorry for me.</p>
<p><b>Davenport</b>: Good, cause I’m not going to…</p>
<p><b>Bryce</b>: I don’t care what you think.</p>
<p><b>Davenport</b>: Good, cause I think you’re a cry baby.</p>
<p><b>Bryce</b>: I’m a faggot.</p>
<p><b>Davenport</b>: Jeez. Give me a fucking break. You have no right to get like this.</p>
<p><b>Bryce</b>: I have no right…to be sad, when [my] friend says horrid, horrid things about [me]?</p>
<p><b>Davenport</b>: You have no idea.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Q:<i> These characters are particularly vicious towards one another, but you said it wasn’t much of a stretch from conversations you’ve heard. Why do you think there’s so much internal homophobia among gay men?</i></strong></p>
<p><strong>F:</strong> Homophobia means fear of gay people, and who is more afraid of gay men than other gay men?  There’s a great anthology by Mattilda Bernstein Sycamore called <em>Why Are Faggots So Afraid of Faggots?</em> which shines a light on this dynamic.  We are so deeply oppressed, and so deeply fucked up as children.  We retreat into our imaginations, we dissociate, we withdraw.  As adults, we’re suddenly confronted with the reality of other human beings and so often we can’t get beyond those initial defense mechanisms.  And because we’re still trapped in our defensive narcissism, so often gay men can’t understand that other people are real.  So we lash out, we project, we see other people as reflections of ourselves and we destroy them because it’s easier than dealing with our own self-hatred and guilt.  Just lurk in any gay bar late enough and you see this dynamic play itself out.  It’s depressing and disgusting and it’s the result of systemic cultural homophobia.</p>
<blockquote><p><b>Davenport</b>: We can <i>do </i>anything we fucking want. I mean…that’s like… THAT’S, LIKE, THE POINT. That’s the point of this war. We’re fighting this war so we can do WHATEVER WE FUCKING WANT.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Q: <i>After the play, talk turned to </i>The New Normal<i> and the sense that gay white males are somehow beyond racism. Why do you think that is?</i></strong></p>
<p><strong>F:</strong> So many white gay men seem to think that, because they are oppressed as homosexuals, they automatically understand ALL OPPRESSION, and are experts about all minority experiences, and therefore have a free pass to indulge in racist humor.  “I’m gay,” they say, “so I couldn’t <i>possibly </i>be racist.”  This is being called “<a href="http://www.queerty.com/gaycist-tv-characters-20120907/" target="_blank">gaycism</a>,” which I think is a pretty helpful term.  You also see it in white gay men’s attitudes towards women and trans people.  Like, in another Ryan Murphy show, <i>Glee</i>, one character is a trans woman of color, but she barely ever says anything because the writers obviously know nothing about trans people.  And yet they feel that they somehow own this experience because they are “LGBT,” and that T has got to mean something.  But the truth is that being a cisgender homosexual teaches you ABSOLUTELY NOTHING about transgender experience until you get to know transgender people, or read books by transgender authors.</p>
<p>It all comes down to this: In my eyes, being queer can lead you down two different paths – it can make you sensitive to other oppression experiences or it can make you oblivious to them.  It can make you humble or it can make you a dick.  It can make you confront your own internalized racism, misogyny, transphobia and homophobia with dignity and a genuine concern to become a better person, or it can make you shut down to any implication that you are anything but a progressive gay saint.  My hope is that more and more people use gay identity politics as a gateway drug to intersectionalism – so we can all tap into our revolutionary queer potential.</p>
<p>That’s the genius of being queer – we have the opportunity to inspect society from outside of it, to better understand how it’s broken.  What concerns me – and what <i>Waiting for Barbara </i>is about – is that, so many homosexuals are missing that opportunity.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=AXWk323e_mI:kNgHUW15cCU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=AXWk323e_mI:kNgHUW15cCU:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/dan-fishback-waiting-for-barbara-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/dan-fishback-waiting-for-barbara-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Malaysian Government Produces Anti-Gay Musical To Scare Kids Straight</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/mPdDuf8BbgQ/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/malaysian-government-produces-anti-gay-musical-to-scare-public-straight-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 11:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asmara Songsang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international LGBT rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theater]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255604</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If ever there was an art form us gays own (besides, y&#8217;know, all of them) its musical theater. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re so incensed that the Malaysian government has sponsored a musical aimed at teaching young people about the dangers of being LGBT. Asmara Songsang (or, Abnormal Desire) follows the lives of three queer gang members—we [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="article-body-blocks">
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255609" alt="Asmara Songsang" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Asmara-Songsang-670x444.jpg" width="650" height="430" /></p>
<p>If ever there was an art form us gays own (besides, y&#8217;know, all of them) its musical theater. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re so incensed that the Malaysian government has sponsored a musical aimed at teaching young people about the dangers of being LGBT.</p>
<p><em>Asmara Songsang</em> (or, <em>Abnormal Desire</em>) follows the lives of three queer gang members—we know they&#8217;re gay because they take drugs, throw loud parties and engage in casual sex. The trio&#8217;s Muslim neighbors try to bring the perverts back into the fold, but a convenient lighting storm slays those who refuse to change their evil ways. After a  lecture on the hideous wrongs of not being heterosexual, the entire cast comes out on stage with Malaysian flags and sings a song dedicated to national unity.</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-255608 alignright" alt="DSC2310" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/DSC2310-360x239.jpg" width="330" height="219" />Writer-director Rahman Adam, 73, says the goal of <em>Abnormal Desire </em>is to alert  youngsters and their parents as to &#8220;the bad things about LGBT.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Nowadays in Malaysia you read so many things in newspaper articles or write-ups about LGBT… because [LGBT] are going into schools and influencing the children,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Children need to recognize that men are for women, and women are for men. They are all out to have homosexual and lesbian sex, and although right now it is not so serious [in Malaysia], we need to act, to do something, to say something, to say that this is bad and not to follow it.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Malay <a href="http://blog.kakiseni.com/2013/03/oh-inverted-world/#more-694">blogger Alia Ali</a> calls <em>Asmara Songsang </em>&#8220;all-out propaganda&#8221; that&#8217;s not just bigoted, it&#8217;s poorly executed:</p>
<blockquote><p>Even if it wasn’t propagandistic, there were too many troubling issues: The part that gets to me the most is that according to the playwright, all non-heterosexuals seem to belong to a club. Membership is declared by choosing whether they want to be an L, G, B or T, then a partner (or “baby LGBT” as they call it) for them is found. Any sort of contact with the heteronormative world is cut off — in fact, they’ll fight tooth and nail to keep recruits in their clutches and away from their family. And since they’re immoral and not “normal”, they must of course drink heavily, take drugs, and make out right in public. They actively recruit members to join their side, turning straight people gay, and clearly don’t even live in reality.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/28/anti-gay-lgbt-musical-malaysia"><em>The Guardian</em> reports </a>that the musical features some of the country&#8217;s biggest TV stars and has played the national theater in Kuala Lumpur, in addition to public schools and universities across the largely Islamic country.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re guessing it won&#8217;t be heading to Broadway.</p>
<p><em>Photos: © Kakiseni Blog</em></p>
</div>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=mPdDuf8BbgQ:uo-R6OBYvNA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=mPdDuf8BbgQ:uo-R6OBYvNA:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/malaysian-government-produces-anti-gay-musical-to-scare-public-straight-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/malaysian-government-produces-anti-gay-musical-to-scare-public-straight-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrity Escort Chris Gaida Dishes From Behind The Velvet Rope</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/85eksi8Fz_8/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 10:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Primary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arm candy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celebrity escorts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chris gaida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christopher gaida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Escorts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Kardashian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[out in print]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pam Anderson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queen Latifah]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255405</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Usually when we think of the word &#8220;escort,&#8221; we think of guys who &#8220;lift luggage&#8221; for closeted preachers. But Chris Gaida is a legitimate escort—he goes along with big-name celebrities to red-carpet functions, making sure they get where they&#8217;re supposed to and have a nice time while they&#8217;re there. Gaida has escorted Taylor Swift, Kim [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img class="alignright size-large wp-image-255408" style="margin: 5px 10px;" alt="AM_ArmCandy_Cover_R1" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Final-Cover-High-Res-428x670.jpeg" width="277" height="433" />Usually when we think of the word &#8220;escort,&#8221; we think of guys who &#8220;lift luggage&#8221; for closeted preachers. But Chris Gaida is a legitimate escort—he goes along with big-name celebrities to red-carpet functions, making sure they get where they&#8217;re supposed to and have a nice time while they&#8217;re there.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Gaida has escorted Taylor Swift, Kim Kardashian, Betty White, Ricky Martin, Mariah Carey, Darren Kriss, Angelina Jolie and countless other stars.  He&#8217;s seen the sloppy drunks, the diva fits, and the &#8220;straight&#8221; movie stars who have their hands all over the male escorts.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Now, Caida, 38, is spilling some red-carpet T with his memoir, <a href="http://www.armcandybook.com.">Arm Candy</a>, In it, he delivers behind-the-scenes dish, reveals who in Hollywood is a pain in the posterior (you&#8217;d be surprised) and shares his personal coming-out storyc.</div>
<div></div>
<div>We chatted with the walker-turned-author about his exploits, the rules of the business, and clearing up the confusion that he&#8217;s not &#8220;that&#8221; kind of escort.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>How did you get involve in the escort business?<br />
</strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>I was fresh out of college when I landed a temp job at MTV Networks in New York. One day while trying to stay busy answering phones, some random guy approached my desk and asked if I would want to escort at the VH1 <em>Divas Live</em> show.  I told him no, as I heard about the casting couch and sleeping with someone was not the way I wanted to make it to the top.</div>
<div></div>
<div>He insisted that it was not a sexual job, so I decided to take the chance and escort at the show. From what he briefly described, it sounded cool, but also too good to be true—I didn&#8217;t want to end up in one of those <em>20/20</em> stories.  You know, the ones where some kid knew something was shady and did it anyway and wound up getting murdered.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Not only was I not murdered, but it was everything I could have imagined and more. I had all access to every celebrity, and sex was <em>not</em> on the menu.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>What&#8217;s entailed in a typical escorting job?</strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>Celebrity escorts exist at just about every award show and there are, on average, about 20-30 escorts per show.  There are a small group of us that work just about every show and then there are a few people that do it just a few times and then disappear forever. I imagine that they get frustrated because of the amount of work involved, and some get upset that they always have to take a back seat because the celebrity gets all of the attention. Other times they get fired because they do something stupid or don&#8217;t have the best interest of the celebrity in mind.  <img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-255415" alt="Christopher Gaida" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Christopher-Gaida-360x270.jpg" width="367" height="289" /></div>
<div></div>
<div>Basically we handle the celebrities experiences at award shows. From rehearsal to red carpet to the actual show, we make sure that not only the celebrities are well taken care of, but that the show producers get what they need to make the show the best that it can be. We bring the celebrities backstage when its time, handle media requests, coordinate script changes, rush celebrities past eager fans and coordinate timing and logistics for the show. I have to wear many different hats and deal with multiple personalities—sometimes within the same person.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Since these shows are mostly live, mistakes are not an option and not knowing an answer can cost you your job.  Its an incredible job, though, where you are able to literally spend an entire day with your favorite celebrity. Its nice to see how the other half lives and to experience a part of Hollywood that very few people have.  Even reporters and other crew members don&#8217;t have the access we do.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Do people assume you sleep with celebrities?</strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>People always wonder about that. That&#8217;s not part of the job at all, and never expected of anyone.  The insiders knows about this job and how important we are to making sure things flow properly and that the celebrities are clear in communication with the producers. A few times I have been asked out by the celebrities &#8220;people&#8221;—manager, publicist, make-up artist—but rarely has a celebrity themselves asked me out.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Who were some of the celebrities that surprised you—either with how diva-like they were or how cool they were?</strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>Pamela Anderson is one of the celebrities who has shocked me with how different she was in person than what I expected her to be. I expected this dumb blonde, but in real life she has it all together—she&#8217;s very savvy. In my book I apologize if I&#8217;m blowing her cover!  She not only seems to be an excellent mother, but an incredible business woman who knows how to work the dumb-blond image.</p>
</div>
<div>Another celebrity that surprised me was Queen Latifah.  I escorted her back before she became a big movie star and I assumed she would be difficult. I knew she was a rap artist and was on one TV show at the time, but that is all I knew.  The moment I met her though I realized how special she is.  She instantly treated me as if I was her brother or as if we known each other for years.  She was very welcoming and a very fun person to spend time with.  In my presence she was always happy and not a diva in anyway.  I still remember the expression on her face when we went to her suite in Las Vegas that production and booked for her.  It was like a scene from a movie where the doors opened and we both saw this big gorgeous room for the first time.  She lite up like a Christmas tree and was truly grateful for such an incredible room.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p><img class=" wp-image-255411 alignright" title="Chris and Darren Criss" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/darren-cris.jpg" width="234" height="186" /></p>
<p><strong>What are some of the never-break rules of being a celebrity escort? </strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>The Number One rule for a celebrity escort is to <em>never</em> lose your talent. Escorts usually just have one celebrity that they are with all day and night, and they are not allowed to lose sight of them. This may sound simple, but celebrities are often pulled in many different directions and with crowds of people and people pulling an escort away by asking questions or just talking it can be a challenge.  Ten seconds of giving someone directions can be a fatal mistake—because just that quickly the talent can be gone.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Other rules are to act professional at all times, don&#8217;t be late, know the venue inside and out, and  be prepared for everything.  An escort could be walking their celebrity to their dressing room only to find the hallway blocked. If that escort doesn&#8217;t know another route instantly then problems can occur.  I make sure I know where <em>every</em> hallway and door leads to, because you never know when you are going to make a hasty detour.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Have you escorted any gay celebrities—or covered for any who were in the closet?</strong></div>
<div>
I escorted the <em>Queer Eye For the Straight Guy</em> cast back in 2003, at the height of their fame. It was at the MTV Video Music awards and they were all extremely nice guys.  Two of the guys asked me out and I did go on dates with them both—though not the same night. No romance brewed, but it was a fun experience and I was happy to have spent some time getting to know them better.</div>
<div></div>

						<div id="slide-nav-top" class="navigation">
							<div class="nav-next"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/barbara-bach/">Next Photo &raquo;</a></div>					
														<div class="nav-center"><b>1 of 8</b></div>
						</div><!-- #nav-below -->				
				<div>
					<div class="entry-content">
						<div class="entry-attachment">
					<p class="attachment" id="gall">
					<a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/barbara-bach/" title="Celebrity Escort Chris Gaida Dishes From Behind The Velvet Rope" rel="attachment"><img width="428" height="670" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Final-Cover-High-Res-428x670.jpeg" class="attachment-large" alt="AM_ArmCandy_Cover_R1" />			
							</a></p>
						</div><!-- .entry-attachment -->
					</div><!-- .entry-content -->
				</div><!-- #post-## -->
				<div class="scrollable_holder"><a class="prev browse left"><img class="scroll-nav" src="http://d3qke3e8pe2nmf.cloudfront.net/wp/wp-content/themes/queerty_August2012_audit/images/gallery-left.png"></a><div class="scrollable"><div class="items"><div class="scroll-group"><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/am_armcandy_cover_r1/"><span>1</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Final-Cover-High-Res-50x50.jpeg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="AM_ArmCandy_Cover_R1" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/barbara-bach/"><span>2</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/barbara-bach-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="Chris with Barbara Bach" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/chris-gaida-bren-koombs/"><span>3</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/chris-gaida-bren-koombs-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="signing Arm Candy at Barnes &amp; Noble (Photo: Bren Cooms)" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/darren-cris/"><span>4</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/darren-cris-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="Chris and Darren Criss" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/gaida/"><span>5</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/gaida-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="With John tenny and Rebecca RomjiT" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/chris-gaida/"><span>6</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/chris-gaida-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="Some of Chri&#039;s celebrity clients" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/christopher-gaida-2/"><span>7</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Christopher-Gaida-2-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="Christopher Gaida and Kim Kardashian" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/christopher-gaida/"><span>8</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Christopher-Gaida-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="Christopher Gaida" /></a></div></div></div></div><a class="next browse right"><img class="scroll-nav" src="http://d3qke3e8pe2nmf.cloudfront.net/wp/wp-content/themes/queerty_August2012_audit/images/gallery-right.png"></a></div>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=85eksi8Fz_8:mskaThKDVM0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=85eksi8Fz_8:mskaThKDVM0:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Sorry, Republicans, The Supreme Court Killing DOMA Won’t Solve Your Problems</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/g6wxHsWfQuQ/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/sorry-republicans-the-supreme-court-killing-doma-wont-solve-your-problems-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 18:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JohnGallagher</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255586</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s a thread going around these days that the GOP establishment would like nothing more than for the Supreme Court to strike down DOMA. The establishment knows it can&#8217;t oppose marriage equality forever, and the cracks in its facade are already showing, both with Sen. Rob Portman&#8217;s announcement that he supports marriage equality and the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/elephant.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-255457" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/elephant.jpg" width="231" height="177" /></a>There&#8217;s a thread going around these days that the GOP establishment would like nothing more than for the Supreme Court <a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2013/03/the-scotus-ruling-the-gop-really-wants-89400.html">to strike down DOMA</a>.</p>
<p>The establishment knows it can&#8217;t oppose marriage equality forever, and the cracks in its facade are already showing, both with <a href="http://www.queerty.com/gop-senator-with-gay-son-embraces-marriage-equality-good-news-or-too-little-too-late-20130315/">Sen. Rob Portman&#8217;s announcemen</a>t that he supports marriage equality and the hint in the <a href="http://www.queerty.com/gop-knows-it-needs-to-talk-about-change-it-just-doesnt-want-to-actually-make-any-20130321/">2012 post-mortem report </a>that opposition to marriage is a demographic timebomb.</p>
<p>But if the Supreme Court decides to take the weasel road by striking down DOMA and leaving marriage up to the states, the GOP may have the worst of all possible worlds. Here&#8217;s why:</p>
<ul>
<li>Statewide ballot measures to approve marriage equality will multiply, which means the religious right will be out in force. If the party is wishy washy, they&#8217;ll be very angry, which will affect turnout for other races. If the party forsakes them altogether, there will be a gigantic rift in the party (which is bound to come anyway).</li>
<li>A Court ruling that kicks the can down the road is going to be the Lawyer Full Employment Act. We will start seeing lots of cases in which couples married in one state seek recognition in a state where they can&#8217;t marry. All of that means lots of publicity and more questions.</li>
<li>The party may modify, but individual candidates can&#8217;t. Can you imagine a GOP presidential primary slate in 2016 in which opposition to ballot measures isn&#8217;t a litmus test for the base?</li>
<li>The nutburgers are likely to get nuttier. The folks the party elevates aren&#8217;t renowned for their diplomacy, and when under the gun, <a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/weigel/2013/03/28/_be_they_gays_be_they_nambla_be_they_people_who_believe_in_beastiality.html">they say some pretty crazy and offensive things</a>, all in the party&#8217;s name.</li>
</ul>
<p>In short, things just get even messier for Republicans. Perhaps<a href="http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2013/03/next-stage-for-gay-rights-conservative-amnesia.html"> collective amnesia</a> will eventually solve their problem, but it&#8217;s not going anyway any time soon.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=g6wxHsWfQuQ:0huFmb1tOcM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=g6wxHsWfQuQ:0huFmb1tOcM:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/sorry-republicans-the-supreme-court-killing-doma-wont-solve-your-problems-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/sorry-republicans-the-supreme-court-killing-doma-wont-solve-your-problems-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Hunky Jesus And Other Easter Events Sure To Get You Hoppin’</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/kT3GMbWgO6E/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 17:53:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>koreykuhl</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dallas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaycities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaycities weekender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hunky Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leather and fetish weekend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm Springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sydney]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255428</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From San Franisco&#8217;s Hunky Jesus contest to the White Party in Palm Springs, GayCities serves up a calendar overflowing with Easter celebrations this weekend. Check out some of the highlights below or find an event near you with your GayCities Guide to Easter Weekend. &#160;  Easter Leather and Fetish Weekend in Berlin Easter in the Park [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/screen-shot-2012-04-09-at-3-13-11-pm-600x501/" rel="attachment wp-att-255429"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255429" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Screen-shot-2012-04-09-at-3.13.11-PM-600x501.png" width="600" height="501" /></a></p>
<p>From San Franisco&#8217;s <a href="http://sanfrancisco.gaycities.com/events/216352-easter-in-the-park-the-sisters-34th-anniversary-celebration">Hunky Jesus</a> contest to the <a href="http://palmsprings.gaycities.com/events/183033-white-party-palm-springs-2013">White Party</a> in <a href="http://palmsprings.gaycities.com">Palm Springs</a>, GayCities serves up a calendar overflowing with Easter celebrations this weekend. Check out some of the highlights below or find an event near you with your <a href="http://www.gaycities.com/events/tid/1207">GayCities Guide to Easter Weekend</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/screen-shot-2013-03-28-at-2-37-25-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-255430"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-255430" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-28-at-2.37.25-PM-360x270.png" width="360" height="270" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <a href="http://berlin.gaycities.com/events/164478-blf-ecmc-easter-in-berlin-german-mr-leather-2013">Easter Leather and Fetish Weekend</a> in <a href="http://berlin.gaycities.com/">Berlin</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/easter13b/" rel="attachment wp-att-255434"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255434" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Easter13b.jpg" width="282" height="236" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://dallas.gaycities.com/events/209995-easter-in-the-park-and-pooch-parade">Easter in the Park and Pooch Parade</a> in <a href="http://dallas.gaycities.com">Dallas</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/599320_10151716707931055_1642055595_n/" rel="attachment wp-att-255436"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-255436" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/599320_10151716707931055_1642055595_n-360x240.jpg" width="360" height="240" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://losangeles.gaycities.com/events/214110-vgl-weho-dodgeball-easter-eggstravaganza">Varsity Gay League Easter Extravaganza</a> in <a href="http://losangeles.gaycities.com">Los Angeles</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://sydney.gaycities.com/events/218864-stonewall-royal-gay-easter-show-weekend-2013" rel="attachment wp-att-255437"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-255437" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/526837_10151316107511167_49313935_n-360x270.jpg" width="360" height="270" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://sydney.gaycities.com/events/218864-stonewall-royal-gay-easter-show-weekend-2013">Gay Easter Show Weekend</a> in <a href="http://sydney.gaycities.com">Sydney</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://sanfrancisco.gaycities.com/events/216352-easter-in-the-park-the-sisters-34th-anniversary-celebration" rel="attachment wp-att-255435"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255435" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/hunky_jesus-250x166.jpg" width="250" height="166" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://sanfrancisco.gaycities.com/events/216352-easter-in-the-park-the-sisters-34th-anniversary-celebration">Hunky Jesus</a> in <a href="http://sanfrancisco.gaycities.com/">San Francisco</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://palmsprings.gaycities.com/events/183033-white-party-palm-springs-2013" rel="attachment wp-att-255431"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-255431" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/003-670x4051-360x217.jpg" width="360" height="217" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://palmsprings.gaycities.com/events/183033-white-party-palm-springs-2013">White Party </a><a href="http://palmsprings.gaycities.com">Palm Springs</a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong><em>Find an event near you with the <a href="http://www.gaycities.com/events/tid/1207">GayCities Guide to Easter Weekend</a></em><br />
</strong></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=kT3GMbWgO6E:7UQY7n3613w:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=kT3GMbWgO6E:7UQY7n3613w:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Michigan RNC Member Defends Posting About Gays’ “Filthy Lifestyle,” Refuses To Resign</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/IK0xijgrJUE/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/michigan-rnc-member-defends-posting-about-gays-filthy-lifestyle-refuses-to-resign-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 17:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255578</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Each week, Queerty picks one blowhard, hypocrite, airhead, sanctimonious prick or other enemy of all that is queer to be the Douche of the Week.  Have a nominee for DOTW? E-mail it to us at holla@queerty.com. Just when you think the goalposts have moved and our enemies have to camouflage their hatred in softer tones, a GOP [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-255588" alt="dave-agema" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/dave-agema.jpg" width="300" height="215" /><strong>Each week, Queerty picks one blowhard, hypocrite, airhead, sanctimonious prick or other enemy of all that is queer to be the Douche of the Week. </strong></p>
<div>
<p><strong>Have a nominee for DOTW? E-mail it to us at <a href="mailto:">holla@queerty.com</a>.</strong></p>
</div>
<p>Just when you think the goalposts have moved and our enemies have to camouflage their hatred in softer tones, a GOP honcho vomits up something we&#8217;d expect to hear from Jesse Helms (may he rot in Hell.)</p>
<p>Dave Agema, a member of the Michigan RNC committee, <a href="http://www.addictinginfo.org/2013/03/28/michigan-gop-official-reveals-himself-for-the-bigot-he-is-with-facebook-post/" target="_blank">posted a link on Facebook</a> to an article describing just how harmful homosexuality is, not just to those who practice it but to the general population.</p>
<p>Among the &#8220;facts&#8221; in “Everyone Should Know These Statistics on Homosexuals”:</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Homosexuals live unhealthy lifestyles, and have historically accounted for the bulk of syphilis, gonorrhea, Hepatitis B, the “gay bowel syndrome” (which attacks the intestinal tract), tuberculosis and cytomegalovirus.</li>
</ul>
<ul type="disc">
<li>73% of psychiatrists say homosexuals are less happy than the average person, and of those psychiatrists, 70% say that the unhappiness is NOT due to social stigmatization</li>
</ul>
<ul type="disc">
<li>33% of homosexuals ADMIT to minor/adult sex</li>
</ul>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Judge John Martaugh, chief magistrate of the New York City Criminal Court has said, “Homosexuals account for half the murders in large cities”</li>
</ul>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Captain William Riddle of the Los Angeles Police says, “30,000 sexually abused children in Los Angeles were victims of homosexuals”</li>
<li>Because homosexuals can&#8217;t reproduce naturally, they resort to recruiting children. Homosexuals can be heard chanting &#8220;TEN PERCENT IS NOT ENOUGH, RECRUIT, RECRUIT, RECRUIT&#8221; in their homosexual parades.<br />
<em>You can read the full article <a title="Tradition In Action Homepage" href="http://www.traditioninaction.org/index.htm" target="_blank">here </a></em></li>
</ul>
<p>Just on the face of it, these so-called factoids are obviously bullshit. &#8220;Homosexuals account for half of the murders in large cities&#8221;? We were obviously suspicious of that one—it turns out Judge Martaugh was on the bench in the 1940s and &#8217;50s, and was a crusader against immortality and perversion. (He&#8217;s theonewho convicted Lenny Bruce of  obscenity.) So he&#8217;s not exactly an objective authority on anything.</p>
<p>We couldn&#8217;t even find any mention of a &#8220;Captain William Riddle&#8221; on the LAPD, but based on the other assertions, he was probably on the beat during the Civil War.</p>
<p>The rest of these bullet points are either out of context, outdated, or outright lies.</p>
<p>Dozens of Michigan Republican leaders have called for Agema to resign. &#8220;This isn&#8217;t about what we believe either politically or as women and men of faith. This is about common decency,&#8221; said Dennis Lennox, who is leading the call for Agema&#8217;s ousting. “We do not have confidence in Mr. Agema representing the best interests of our fellow Michigan Republicans and as a result ask him to resign from his seat on the Republican National Committee.&#8221;</p>
<p>Agema says calls for him to step down are &#8220;a joke.&#8221; In an email to the <em>Detroit</em> <em>Free Press</em> on Thursday, he accused “liberal Republicans” of twisting his words:</p>
<blockquote><p>“I think it was a piece worth sharing given the debate over gay marriage that is happening in the Supreme Court. I strongly maintain my position in support of marriage between a man and a woman and I will not back down from my core beliefs in support of strengthening the family.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Isn&#8217;t it the religious right who keep saying their opposition to marriage equality doesn&#8217;t mean they hate gays? We really wish you guys would make up your mind.</p>
<p>Before he was elected a member of the Michigan delegation to the RNC in 2012, Agema was a Michigan state representative from 2007 to 2012. He&#8217;s also the president of the Sabath House Ministries,  a member of the Allied Pilots Association and the NRA.</p>
<p>And, lest we forget: D<strong>he&#8217;s a douche!</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=IK0xijgrJUE:VI8OcOJx2lw:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=IK0xijgrJUE:VI8OcOJx2lw:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/michigan-rnc-member-defends-posting-about-gays-filthy-lifestyle-refuses-to-resign-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/michigan-rnc-member-defends-posting-about-gays-filthy-lifestyle-refuses-to-resign-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Jimmy Kimmel Asks You To Guess The Gay Marriage Supporter</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/LNM1n9Y6cPg/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-jimmy-kimmel-gay-marriage-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jimmy Kimmel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jimmy Kimmel Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255561</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Jimmy Kimmel had his studio audience guess how pedestrians would respond when asked if they supported gay marriage. As a follow-up, they were also given a choice between two potential same-sex life mates. The audience was surprised by some of the marriage supporters, though obviously more surprised by whom these men and women on the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/PNh2-2wIA14?rel=0" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Jimmy Kimmel had his studio audience guess how pedestrians would respond when asked if they supported gay marriage. As a follow-up, they were also given a choice between two potential same-sex life mates.</p>
<p>The audience was surprised by some of the marriage supporters, though obviously more surprised by whom these men and women on the street would choose to gay marry. People always sleep on Regis.</p>
<p>Part 2:</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/eReLL_nUSJU?rel=0" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=LNM1n9Y6cPg:4F0aUXK993A:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=LNM1n9Y6cPg:4F0aUXK993A:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-jimmy-kimmel-gay-marriage-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-jimmy-kimmel-gay-marriage-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>“My Anus Is Getting Beaten On”: Sports Announcer Michael Schiavello Give Internet The Giggles</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/jmZ7bFYxvW4/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/my-anus-is-getting-beaten-on-sports-announcer-michael-schiavello-give-internet-the-giggles-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[danny mainus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael schiavello]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ufc]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255571</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[WATCH: Whether announcer Michael Schiavello was intentionally mispronouncing MMA fighter Danny Mainus&#8217; name during this bout or not, the clip has been rocketing around the Interwebs. With all the serious marriage-equality news this week, we thought we&#8217;d give you a Friday funny here.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ogB05Y9YDFg" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><strong>WATCH:</strong> Whether announcer Michael Schiavello was intentionally mispronouncing MMA fighter Danny Mainus&#8217; name during this bout or not, the clip has been rocketing around the Interwebs. With all the serious marriage-equality news this week, we thought we&#8217;d give you a Friday funny here.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=jmZ7bFYxvW4:F3hBTEsTDrQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=jmZ7bFYxvW4:F3hBTEsTDrQ:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/my-anus-is-getting-beaten-on-sports-announcer-michael-schiavello-give-internet-the-giggles-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/my-anus-is-getting-beaten-on-sports-announcer-michael-schiavello-give-internet-the-giggles-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Dan Choi Fined $100 For DADT Protest</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/FA4_6N5Rdbc/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/dan-choi-fined-100-for-dadt-protest-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DADT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dan Choi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don't Ask Don't Tell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trials]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255560</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Former US Army lieutenant Dan Choi, who became the face of the movement to end Don&#8217;t Ask Don&#8217;t Tell, has been fined $100 for chaining himself to the White House in 2010. Choi, who was discharged from the Army after coming out on the Rachel Maddow Show, faced up to six months in federal prison [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-223325" alt="dan choi" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2012/09/dan-choi1.jpg" width="269" height="207" />Former US Army lieutenant Dan Choi, who became the face of the movement to end Don&#8217;t Ask Don&#8217;t Tell, <a href="http://politic365.com/2013/03/28/lt-dan-choi-found-guilty-for-white-house-protest-taken-to-va-hospital/">has been fined $100</a> for chaining himself to the White House in 2010.</p>
<p>Choi, who was discharged from the Army after coming out on the <em>Rachel Maddow Show</em>, faced up to six months in federal prison for his actions. (Others who participated in the demonstration pleaded guilty.) He will not face any prison time if he pays the fine.</p>
<p>Choi represented himself at trial, though it&#8217;s hardly his first time facing legal headaches: In December a Superior Court judge <a href="http://www.queerty.com/dan-choi-20121223/#ixzz2Owggv65Y">dismissed charges against Choi</a> relating to his participation in White House demonstration against the Keystone XL Pipeline. And in 2011, Choi was among a number of international activists arrested for holding a Moscow Pride event despite a ban by the city government.</p>
<p>That same year <a href="http://www.queerty.com/dan-choi-tackled-handcuffed-kicked-off-base-while-trying-to-attend-bradley-manning%e2%80%99s-hearing-draft-20111221/#ixzz2Owhaa8A3">military police wrestled Choi</a> to the ground before handcuffing him, threatening to charge him with resisting arrest and eventually kicking him off Fort Meade when he tried to attend accused Wikileaker Bradley Manning’s hearing.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=FA4_6N5Rdbc:9a5AltK6oCk:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=FA4_6N5Rdbc:9a5AltK6oCk:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/dan-choi-fined-100-for-dadt-protest-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/dan-choi-fined-100-for-dadt-protest-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Tom Daley’s New Man, “Teen Wolf” Goes Gay, Barbara Walters Retiring &amp; More!</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/8B7rmeYSr6M/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-tom-daley-teen-wolf-barbara-walters-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[archie comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arrow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barbara Walters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Behind the Candelabra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Rock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colton Haynes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harry Potter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Barrowman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matthew weiner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Melissa McCarthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MTV Movie Awards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new girl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pop brownies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard griffiths]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taylor swift]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teen wolf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tom daley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zac Efron]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255548</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[- Olympic hottie Tom Daley, apparently trying to asphyxiate us with cuteness, has adopted a pet piglet named Robby-Ray. - Taylor Swift will ruin the season finale of New Girl. - Even as an Archie character, Sue Sylvester is not having it. - Matthew Weiner knows you love gay art director Sal and doesn&#8217;t really [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-tom-daley-teen-wolf-barbara-walters-20130329/tom-daly-piglet/" rel="attachment wp-att-255555"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255555" alt="tom-daly-piglet" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/tom-daly-piglet.jpg" width="612" height="612" /></a></p>
<p>- Olympic hottie <strong>Tom Daley</strong>, apparently trying to asphyxiate us with cuteness, has <a href="https://twitter.com/TomDaley1994/status/317262175439839232" target="_blank">adopted a pet piglet</a> named Robby-Ray.</p>
<p>- <strong>Taylor Swift</strong> will <a href="http://insidetv.ew.com/2013/03/28/taylor-swift-new-girl-season-finale/" target="_blank">ruin the season finale</a> of <em>New Girl</em>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-tom-daley-teen-wolf-barbara-walters-20130329/glee-sue-archie/" rel="attachment wp-att-255556"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255556" style="margin: 10px;" alt="glee-sue-archie" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/glee-sue-archie-360x540.jpg" width="151" height="227" /></a>- Even as <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/donnad/exclusive-the-glee-cast-gets-their-archie-make-over" target="_blank">an <em>Archie</em> character</a>, Sue Sylvester is <em>not having it</em>.</p>
<p>- <strong>Matthew Weiner</strong> knows you love gay art director Sal and doesn&#8217;t really care &#8217;cause he&#8217;ll <a href="http://www.avclub.com/articles/matthew-weiner-knows-you-want-sal-back-on-mad-men,95733/" target="_blank">never work</a> in <em>Mad Men</em>&#8216;s town again!</p>
<p>- <em>Teen Wolf</em> will be having some <a href=" http://www.etonline.com/tv/132118_Jeff_Davis_Teen_Wolf_Season_Three_Interview/index.html" target="_blank">very hot gay teen wolf sex</a> this season that we&#8217;re bound to get a howl out of.</p>
<p>- Harry Potter&#8217;s uncle Vernon, <strong>Richard Griffiths</strong>, <a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/richard-griffiths-harry-potter-actor-dead-at-65-2013293" target="_blank">has died</a> at age 65 from complications after heart surgery.</p>
<p>- <strong>Barbara Walters</strong> is <a href="http://www.deadline.com/2013/03/barbara-walters-retirement-plan-abc/" target="_blank">reportedly retiring</a> in May 2014, but she&#8217;s been threatening to retire for the past 80 years so we&#8217;ll see if that cow actually goes out to pasture.</p>
<p>- <em>Entertainment Weekly</em> has an exclusive <a href="http://insidetv.ew.com/2013/03/28/behind-the-candelabra-trailer/" target="_blank">30-second preview</a> of <em>Behind the Candelabra</em> that&#8217;s drowning in sequined capes, hissy fits and statement rings, i.e. perfection.</p>
<p>- New couple alert! <em>Arrow</em>&#8216;s <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/lyapalater/colton-haynes-and-john-barrowman-hold-hands-at-the-airport" target="_blank"><strong>Colton Haynes</strong> and <strong>John Barrowman</strong></a>. Well, not really, but we&#8217;d seriously co-sign that Gay-December fauxmance.</p>
<p>- <strong>Melissa McCarthy</strong>, <strong>Zac Efron</strong>, <strong>Chris Rock</strong> and <a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/402716/mtv-movie-awards-guess-who-s-going-to-be-there" target="_blank">a bunch of other people</a> who have nothing better to do will present trophies at the <strong>MTV Movie Awards</strong>.</p>
<p>- And we are telling you. We&#8217;re not going until you watch this. And you-and you-AND YOU! You&#8217;re gonna love this:</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/8qoOtUMQ12k?rel=0" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=8B7rmeYSr6M:UXJP32pvj2g:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=8B7rmeYSr6M:UXJP32pvj2g:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-tom-daley-teen-wolf-barbara-walters-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-tom-daley-teen-wolf-barbara-walters-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>PHOTO: Official Renderings Of The NYC AIDS Memorial Released</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/1Jipv-iu6p8/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/photo-official-renderings-of-the-nyc-aids-memorial-released-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AIDS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AIDS Memorial Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HIV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255422</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Even as the LGBT community celebrates the national sea change happening on marriage equality, we mustn&#8217;t forget our darkest times: The final renderings for the NYC AIDS Memorial have been released by Studio a+i, the design firm creating the unique monument. The main feature for the memorial is an 18-foot steel canopy, which will frame a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255552" alt="aids_memorial_home-2" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/aids_memorial_home-2-670x356.jpg" width="566" height="300" /></div>
<p>Even as the LGBT community celebrates the national sea change happening on marriage equality, we mustn&#8217;t forget our darkest times: The final renderings for the <em><a href="http://nycaidsmemorial.org/" target="_blank">NYC AIDS Memorial</a></em> have been released by Studio a+i, the design firm creating the unique monument. The main feature for the memorial is an 18-foot steel canopy, which will frame a granite fountain and benches, as well as commemorative text on granite slabs. (The text will be curated by <em>Angels in America </em>playwright Tony Kushner and local activists, historians and artists.)</p>
<p>To bring the project to fruition, the AIDS Memorial Park Coalition has launched a capital campaign, which has already received $975,000 of a projected $4 million.</p>
<p>Ironically, the park will be located just outside the former St. Vincents Hospital, where so many early victims of the plague were treated. St. Vincent&#8217;s was closed in 2010 and is swiftly being transformed into luxury apartments.</p>
<p><em> </em>A memorial in a city where the epidemic had such an impact is a no-brainer. But is the design too sterile and unspecific? Will passersby even think of the thousands who suffered and died, who faced discrimination and hatred, when they stroll by? Or will they think its just another piece of public art.</p>
<p><strong>Play art critic in the comment section below.</strong></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255554" alt="aids_memorial_home1" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/aids_memorial_home1-670x356.jpg" width="650" height="345" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <img class="aligncenter" alt="aids_memorial_home-3" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/aids_memorial_home-3-670x356.jpg" width="650" height="345" /></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=1Jipv-iu6p8:TRHFBSWz9T0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=1Jipv-iu6p8:TRHFBSWz9T0:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/photo-official-renderings-of-the-nyc-aids-memorial-released-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/photo-official-renderings-of-the-nyc-aids-memorial-released-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Seattle Seahawks’ Chris Clemons: A Gay Player Coming Out Would Be “Selfish”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/VOU6Jv-TMgk/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/chris-clemons-gay-player-coming-out-selfish-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chris clemons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homophobia in sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seattle seahawks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tweet deck]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255537</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[News that a gay NFL player is considering coming out of the closet &#8212; unsurprisingly &#8212; isn&#8217;t sitting well with some players: namely Seattle Seahawks&#8217; defensive end Chris Clemons. Clemons took to the Twitter to express his reservations &#8212; and no he&#8217;s not a homophobe, he assured no one: Who on Gods earth is this [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/chris-clemons-gay-player-coming-out-selfish-20130329/chris-clemons/" rel="attachment wp-att-255540"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255540" style="margin: 10px;" alt="chris-clemons" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/chris-clemons.png" width="196" height="142" /></a>News that a gay NFL player is <a href="http://www.queerty.com/a-gay-nfl-player-is-strongly-considering-coming-out-in-the-next-few-months-20130326/" target="_blank">considering coming out of the closet</a> &#8212; unsurprisingly &#8212; isn&#8217;t sitting well with some players: namely Seattle Seahawks&#8217; defensive end Chris Clemons.</p>
<p>Clemons took to the Twitter to express his reservations &#8212; and <em>no</em> he&#8217;s not a homophobe, he assured no one:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>Who on Gods earth is this person saying he&#8217;s coming out of the closet in the NFL?</p>
<p>— Christopher Clemons (@chrisclemons91) <a href="https://twitter.com/chrisclemons91/status/316673438334980096">March 26, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p>One fan asked why he even cared and Clemons asserted the &#8220;logic&#8221; that the NFL is neither the time nor the place to be gay, since players had their chance before getting drafted:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/bill0004">bill0004</a> If you didn&#8217;t do it when you were in high school or college then why wait til your in the NFL? Whoever he is he didn&#8217;t just start</p>
<p>— Christopher Clemons (@chrisclemons91) <a href="https://twitter.com/chrisclemons91/status/316674124254674945">March 26, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async=""></script>Clemons later clarified that he thought it would be a rather &#8220;selfish act&#8221;:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/jack_humphreys4">jack_humphreys4</a> I&#8217;m not against anyone but I think it&#8217;s a selfish act.They just trying to make themselves bigger than the team.</p>
<p>— Christopher Clemons (@chrisclemons91) <a href="https://twitter.com/chrisclemons91/status/316676110442184704">March 26, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Then when someone inevitably accused him of homophobia, Clemons begged his pardon:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/hbonynge">hbonynge</a> No one said anything about be a homophobic.I just think something&#8217;s should be left at home.</p>
<p>— Christopher Clemons (@chrisclemons91) <a href="https://twitter.com/chrisclemons91/status/316682735584428032">March 26, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p>So Clemons is clearly only thinking about the team and not expressing his personal views on homosexuality, right? Well, <em>whatever</em>, the point is: it&#8217;s a reaction like Clemons&#8217; that prevents players from coming out in the first place and the real selfish act is denying LGBT youth a role model they can look up to.</p>
<p>Also, what does Clemons think an openly gay player will bring from his home exactly?</p>
<p>(<em>h/t</em>: <a href="http://www.cbssports.com/nfl/blog/eye-on-football/21965920/seahawks-de-chris-clemons-gay-player-coming-out-would-be-selfish-act" target="_blank"><em>CBS Sports</em></a>)</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=VOU6Jv-TMgk:6p4UmKycyTo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=VOU6Jv-TMgk:6p4UmKycyTo:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/chris-clemons-gay-player-coming-out-selfish-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/chris-clemons-gay-player-coming-out-selfish-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Singer Michelle Shocked Stages Bizarre Sit-In Protest</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/FsqJamdY3zk/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-singer-michelle-shocked-stages-bizarre-sit-in-protest-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[California]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homophobia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michelle shocked]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255530</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Michelle Shocked is singing a new tune &#8212; that of the victim. The alt-folk singer went on a homophobic tirade earlier this month which prompted mass cancellations of her U.S. tour. Since she&#8217;s got nothing but time these days, Shocked took her guitar and sense of righteous indignation to one of those canceled venues &#8212; [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/NPfktw4J1PQ?rel=0" height="480" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Michelle Shocked is singing a new tune &#8212; that of the victim. The alt-folk singer went on a <a href="http://www.queerty.com/alt-folk-singer-michelle-shocked-goes-on-homophobic-rant-tells-audience-god-hates-fags-20130318/" target="_blank">homophobic tirade</a> earlier this month which prompted <a href="http://www.queerty.com/michelle-shocked-sacked-20130320/" target="_blank">mass cancellations</a> of her U.S. tour.</p>
<p>Since she&#8217;s got nothing but time these days, Shocked took her guitar and sense of righteous indignation to one of those canceled venues &#8212; Moe&#8217;s Alley in Santa Cruz &#8212; and staged an old-fashion sit-in with her face covered and her mouth taped shut.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.santacruzsentinel.com/localnews/ci_22895145/singer-michelle-shock" target="_blank">AP reports</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>The tape across her mouth said &#8220;Silenced By Fear.&#8221; When asked a question, Shocked shook her head vigorously and strummed her guitar&#8230;She pointed to a sign inviting people to pick up a Sharpie marker and write on the white disposable safety suit she was wearing.</p></blockquote>
<p>The owner of Moe&#8217;s Alley, Bill Welch, said he&#8217;d be sending &#8220;some healing Santa Cruz energy her way.&#8221;</p>
<p>Previously, Shocked had planned to give <a href="http://www.pinknews.co.uk/2013/03/24/us-folk-singer-michelle-shocked-announces-talk-on-gay-bashing-but-not-welcome-at-proposed-venue/" target="_blank">a talk on gay bashing</a> at McCabe&#8217;s Club in Santa Monica, something McCabe&#8217;s promptly denied.</p>
<p>(<em>h/t</em>: <a href="http://www.towleroad.com/2013/03/shockedguitar.html" target="_blank"><em>Towleroad</em></a>)</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=FsqJamdY3zk:jjZll-dR-qA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=FsqJamdY3zk:jjZll-dR-qA:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-singer-michelle-shocked-stages-bizarre-sit-in-protest-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-singer-michelle-shocked-stages-bizarre-sit-in-protest-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Jon Stewart Tears Apart Conservative SCOTUS Arguments Against Gay Marriage</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/Ev7ANg0fk5s/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/jon-stewart-scotus-gay-marriage-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Antonin Scalia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jon Stewart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samuel Alito]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supreme Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Daily Show]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255515</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Between Samuel Alito claiming gay marriage is &#8220;newer than cell phones or the Internet&#8221; and Antonin Scalia alleging the &#8220;considerable disagreement&#8221; over the fitness of same-sex parents, Jon Stewart had a field gay day on last night&#8217;s The Daily Show.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://media.mtvnservices.com/embed/mgid:cms:video:thedailyshow.com:424861" height="360" width="640" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Between Samuel Alito claiming gay marriage is &#8220;newer than cell phones or the Internet&#8221; and Antonin Scalia alleging the &#8220;considerable disagreement&#8221; over the fitness of same-sex parents, Jon Stewart had a field <del>gay</del> day on last night&#8217;s <em>The Daily Show</em>.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=Ev7ANg0fk5s:-AqvCwyPi-E:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=Ev7ANg0fk5s:-AqvCwyPi-E:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/jon-stewart-scotus-gay-marriage-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/jon-stewart-scotus-gay-marriage-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>POLL: Only 2% Of Federal Employees Identify As LGBT</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/RTYv0llIdmY/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/poll-only-2-of-federal-employees-identify-as-lgbt-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255403</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[According to a poll in the government’s 2012 Employee Viewpoint Survey, only 2.2% of federal employees self-identify as gay, lesbian, bisexual or transgender. That&#8217;s less than the approximately 3.4% who did in a recent Gallup poll. For the first time, the Office of Personnel Management asked employees to answer questions about sexual orientation in the 2012 [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-255404" alt="office workers" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/office-workers-360x208.jpg" width="300" height="173" />According to a poll in the government’s 2012 <a href="http://www.fedview.opm.gov/2012files/2012_Government_Management_Report.PDF" target="_blank">Employee Viewpoint Survey</a>, only 2.2% of federal employees self-identify as gay, lesbian, bisexual or transgender. That&#8217;s less than the approximately 3.4% who did in a recent <a href="http://www.gallup.com/poll/158066/special-report-adults-identify-lgbt.aspx" target="_blank">Gallup poll</a>.</p>
<p>For the first time, the Office of Personnel Management asked employees to answer questions about sexual orientation in the 2012 survey. It is worth noting that 10.8% responded that they would prefer not to say, according to<a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/federal-eye/wp/2013/03/27/how-many-federal-workers-identify-as-lgbt/"> the <em>Washington Post</em>.</a></p>
<p>These numbers don&#8217;t exist in a vacuum: The Civil Service Commission <a href="http://govcentral.monster.com/benefits/articles/416-is-the-government-gay-friendly">didn&#8217;t lift its ban</a> on openly gay federal employees until 1975. President Clinton issued an executive order banning discrimination in granting security clearances in 1995, and outlawed anti-gay discrimination against all federal civilian staffers in 1998.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=RTYv0llIdmY:gc3ZDxOUixU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=RTYv0llIdmY:gc3ZDxOUixU:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/poll-only-2-of-federal-employees-identify-as-lgbt-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/poll-only-2-of-federal-employees-identify-as-lgbt-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Second Republican Senator Mulling Support Of Gay Marriage</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/H3DOmeGd0ug/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/sen-lisa-murkoswki-gay-marriage-support-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 13:21:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alaska]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[don young]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lisa Murkowski]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Begich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rob Portman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255514</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Alaska&#8217;s Republican Sen. Lisa Murkowski is currently &#8220;evolving&#8221; on her stance on gay marriage, which &#8212; should she reach the cro magnon phase by this weekend &#8212; would make her the second Republican Senator to support the issue after Rob Portman of Ohio &#8220;came out&#8221; two weeks ago. &#8220;I think it&#8217;s important to acknowledge that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/sen-lisa-murkoswki-gay-marriage-support-20130329/lisa_murkowski/" rel="attachment wp-att-255516"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255516" style="margin: 10px;" alt="Lisa_Murkowski" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Lisa_Murkowski-360x450.jpg" width="227" height="284" /></a>Alaska&#8217;s Republican Sen. Lisa Murkowski is currently &#8220;evolving&#8221; on her stance on gay marriage, which &#8212; should she reach the cro magnon phase by this weekend &#8212; would make her the second Republican Senator to support the issue after Rob Portman of Ohio &#8220;<a href="http://www.queerty.com/gop-senator-with-gay-son-embraces-marriage-equality-good-news-or-too-little-too-late-20130315/" target="_blank">came out</a>&#8221; two weeks ago.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think it&#8217;s important to acknowledge that there is a change afoot in this country in terms of how marriage is viewed,&#8221; Murkowski told the <a href="http://www.alaskastar.com/Alaska-Star/March-Issue-4-2013/Murkowskis-gay-marriage-views-evolving/" target="_blank"><em>Chugiak Eagle River Star</em></a>. &#8220;The term &#8216;evolving view&#8217; has been perhaps overused, but I think it is an appropriate term for me to use.&#8221;</p>
<p>Whereas Portman&#8217;s <a href="http://www.queerty.com/will-portman-opens-up-about-coming-out-20130325/" target="_blank">son&#8217;s homosexuality</a> was the impetus for his evolution on gay marriage, Murkowski cites her two young sons&#8217; relative &#8220;hipness&#8221; in her decision-making process.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;ve got two young sons who, when I ask them and their friends how they feel about gay marriage, kinda give me one of those looks like, &#8216;Gosh mom, why are you even asking that question?&#8217;&#8221;</p>
<p>Murkowski says her position may depend on what her constituents have to say since Alaska passed an amendment to its state constitution in 1998 defining marriage between one man and one woman. U.S. Sen. Mark Begich (D-AK) supports marriage equality while good ole Rep. Don &#8220;<a href="http://politicalticker.blogs.cnn.com/2013/03/29/alaska-congressman-walks-back-wetbacks/comment-page-1/" target="_blank">&#8216;Wetback&#8217; Backtrack</a>&#8221; Young opposes it.</p>
<p>&#8220;It may be that Alaska will come to revisit its position on gay marriage, and as a policy maker I am certainly reviewing that very closely,&#8221; Murkowski said. &#8220;We have so many issues in this country to focus on that worry us, that I question why there is such focus on the simple right of people to love whom they will.&#8221;</p>
<p>Well, let&#8217;s all just be thankful that Sen. Murkowski doesn&#8217;t have to pretend to care what former governor Sarah Palin has to say &#8212; if only Fox News felt the same way.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=H3DOmeGd0ug:rmT6X9lyGO0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=H3DOmeGd0ug:rmT6X9lyGO0:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/sen-lisa-murkoswki-gay-marriage-support-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/sen-lisa-murkoswki-gay-marriage-support-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Gay Soccer Player Retired Because “I Wouldn’t Have Been Able To Go Training The Next Day”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/OkqOHoHZWhY/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/robbie-rogers-on-coming-out-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay athletes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homophobia in sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IN QUOTES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openly gay athletes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robbie rogers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soccer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255506</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In football it&#8217;s obviously impossible to come out – because no-one has done it. No one. It&#8217;s crazy and sad. I thought: &#8216;Why don&#8217;t I step away and deal with this and my family and be happy?&#8217; Imagine going to training every day and being in that spotlight? It&#8217;s been a bit of a circus [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/robbie-rogers-on-coming-out-20130329/robbie-rogers/" rel="attachment wp-att-255508"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255508" style="margin: 10px;" alt="robbie-rogers" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/robbie-rogers-360x397.jpg" width="252" height="278" /></a></p>
<div class="giantquote">
<p>In football it&#8217;s obviously impossible to come out – because no-one has done it. No one. It&#8217;s crazy and sad. I thought: &#8216;Why don&#8217;t I step away and deal with this and my family and be happy?&#8217; Imagine going to training every day and being in that spotlight? It&#8217;s been a bit of a circus anyway – but that would have been crazy. And you wouldn&#8217;t have much control because clubs are pushing you in different directions.</p>
<p>&#8220;I was just fearful. I was very fearful how my team-mates were going to react. Was it going to change them? Even though I&#8217;d still be the same person would it change the way they acted towards me – when we were in the dressing room or the bus?&#8230;</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t think I would have been able to go training the next day. That would be so scary. The guys might have said, &#8216;That&#8217;s great, Robbie.&#8217; Maybe. But because no-one&#8217;s done it and because of the things I&#8217;ve heard in the dressing room I just thought: &#8216;I need to get away from this – make my announcement, find peace, go from there.&#8217;&#8221;</p>
</div>
<p>&#8211; <em>California-born 25-year-old former soccer player <strong>Robbie Rogers</strong> discusses <a href="http://www.queerty.com/uk-pro-soccer-player-comes-out-promptly-announces-retirement-20130215/" target="_blank">coming out and retiring</a> with</em> <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/mar/29/robbie-rogers-coming-out-gay" target="_blank">The Guardian</a>.<em> He describes himself in a</em> <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/29/sports/soccer/robbie-rogers-feels-free-after-revealing-he-is-gay.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=0" target="_blank">New York Times </a><em><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/29/sports/soccer/robbie-rogers-feels-free-after-revealing-he-is-gay.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=0" target="_blank">profile</a> as a Catholic and a conservative who has never even hooked up with a guy&#8230;.so free agent?</em></p>
<p><em>Photo: </em><a href="https://www.facebook.com/therobbierogers" target="_blank"><em>Facebook</em></a></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=OkqOHoHZWhY:zUaNo_0rU9U:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=OkqOHoHZWhY:zUaNo_0rU9U:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/robbie-rogers-on-coming-out-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/robbie-rogers-on-coming-out-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Urban Outfitters, Walmart And Other Brands That Want Nothing To Do With Gay Marriage</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/gLap0d92omY/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Primary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chick-fil-a]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate equality index]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exxon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HRC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Human Rights Campaign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban outfitters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wal Mart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255483</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Everyone and their mother has been going red in the past few days in support of marriage equality, including several high-profile brands &#8212; Bud Light, Smirnoff, Absolut&#8230;we&#8217;re sensing a trend here. Others have remained silent on the issue, but a new Tumblr is forcing companies out of the closet. Brand Equality features dozens of brand [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/bud-light/" rel="attachment wp-att-255490"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255490" style="margin: 10px;" alt="bud-light" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/bud-light-360x360.jpg" width="252" height="252" /></a>Everyone and their mother has been <a href="http://www.queerty.com/12-of-the-best-red-marriage-equality-facebook-profile-pics-weve-seen-20130327/" target="_blank">going red</a> in the past few days in support of marriage equality, including several high-profile brands &#8212; Bud Light, Smirnoff, Absolut&#8230;we&#8217;re sensing a trend here.</p>
<p>Others have remained silent on the issue, but a new Tumblr is forcing companies out of the closet. <a href="http://brandequality.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Brand Equality</a> features dozens of brand logos stylized with the Human Rights Campaign&#8217;s red equal sign &#8212; giving the assumption that they support marriage equality.</p>
<p>Brands have the option to say nothing and let the assumption ride; confirm their support; or request that their logo be removed, implying that they do <em>not</em> support marriage equality.</p>
<p>A sort of &#8220;<a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/28/tumblr-brands-marriage-equality/" target="_blank">public shaming</a>,&#8221; if you will; or complete transparency, if you won&#8217;t.  However, as <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/urban-outfitters-walmart-decline-gay-marriage-push-2013-3" target="_blank">Business Insider notes</a>, it&#8217;s possible that these brands &#8220;don&#8217;t allow for their logos to be reproduced for legal, trademark or intellectual property reasons.&#8221;</p>
<p>Either way, these four brands asked to have their logos removed. Brand Equality has replaced their original comments (below) with the more equitable &#8212; &#8220;So, do these brands want to be removed? Or to replace the image sent in with a ‘neutral’ stance? Just let us know. This is all about transparency.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/exxon-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-255487"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-255487" alt="exxon" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/exxon.png" width="404" height="446" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Exxon is the <a href="http://www.dallasvoice.com/exxon-mobil-hits-lgbt-1096894.html" target="_blank">first company</a> to receive a negative score from HRC&#8217;s Corporate Equality Index, and &#8220;is <a href="http://preview.hrc.org/issues/workplace/exxon-mobil-corporation.htm" target="_blank">the only U.S. employer</a> that has ever rescinded both a non-discrimination policy covering sexual orientation and domestic partner benefits, and is the only <em>Fortune </em>10 company that does not have a non-discrimination policy covering sexual orientation.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/urban/" rel="attachment wp-att-255488"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-255488" alt="urban" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/urban.png" width="395" height="437" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Urban Outfitters <a href="http://www.queerty.com/dont-buy-here-10-companies-that-hate-the-gays-20090224/" target="_blank">briefly removed</a> &#8212; only to restock &#8211;T-shirts supporting gay marriage from its stores, and donated 100% of sales to pro-marriage equality groups. The retailer, however, most recently caused outrage with a <a href="http://www.queerty.com/outrage-after-urban-outfitters-makes-a-closet-tranny-joke-on-a-gag-card-20120319/" target="_blank">&#8220;closet tranny&#8221; card</a>. Meanwhile, president and founder Richard Hayne <a href="http://www.queerty.com/miley-cyrus-reminds-tweens-that-urban-outfitters-supports-anti-gay-anal-froth-rick-santorum-20110527/" target="_blank">infamously donated</a> $13,500 to ultra-conservative <a href="http://spreadingsantorum.com/index2.html" target="_blank">anal sex byproduct</a> Rick Santorum over the years.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/wal-mart/" rel="attachment wp-att-255489"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-255489" alt="wal-mart" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/wal-mart.png" width="394" height="446" /></a>Walmart <a href="http://www.queerty.com/wal-mart-adds-trans-protections-to-employee-policies-do-we-have-to-shop-there-now-20110929/" target="_blank">recently added</a> trans protections to its employee non-discrimination policy, however, the mega-chain has a history of rolling back the courtesy with regards to the LGBT community, including: CEO Mike Duke signing a petition in 2008 to prevent Arkansas same-sex couples from adopting; allegedly demoting an employee and forcing him to wear a yellow vest after he came out; and receiving a 40 out of a possible 100 on HRC&#8217;s Equality Index.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/chick-fil-a-6/" rel="attachment wp-att-255486"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-255486" alt="chick-fil-a" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/chick-fil-a.png" width="393" height="430" /></a></p>
<p>We think it&#8217;s pretty safe to assume that this one legitimately doesn&#8217;t want to be associated with gay marriage, no matter how many <a href="http://www.queerty.com/ca-chick-fil-a-gives-away-free-food-to-pro-marriage-equality-supporters-20130328/" target="_blank">free waffle fries</a> it shoves down your throat.</p>
<p>Whether shamed or exposed in the name of transparency, do you think these brands want to purposefully distance themselves from marriage equality? <strong>Sound off in the comments.</strong></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=gLap0d92omY:ROiGjIz34LU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=gLap0d92omY:ROiGjIz34LU:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Ali Forney Center Makes Easter Time Plea For Christians To Acknowledge Religious Intolerance</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/JI35HdhJOuE/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-ali-forney-center-makes-easter-time-plea-for-christians-to-acknowledge-religious-intolerance-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ali forney center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carl Siciliano]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religious intolerence]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255387</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Though it doesn&#8217;t get the play Christmas does, this is a very religious week: As Jews the world over continue to celebrate the holiday of Passover, Christians are gearing up for Easter. So Carl Siciliano, director of New York&#8217;s Ali Forney Center, released an essay and a set of videos calling on Christians to recognize [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/P0016Uqaou4" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Though it doesn&#8217;t get the play Christmas does, this is a very religious week: As Jews the world over continue to celebrate the holiday of Passover, Christians are gearing up for Easter.</p>
<p>So Carl Siciliano, director of New York&#8217;s Ali Forney Center, released <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/carl-siciliano/christianity-and-the-parental-rejection-of-lgbt-youth_b_2966849.html" target="_blank">an essay</a> and <a href="http://www.aliforneycenter.org/stopreligiousrejection" target="_blank">a set of videos</a> calling on Christians to recognize the anti-LGBT climate prevalent in many churches, and how it can lead to queer youth being homeless or engaging in high-risk behavior.</p>
<blockquote><p>The videos feature clients of the Ali Forney Center describing instances of physical abuse, psychological torment, and rejection they suffered in Christian households, driving them out of their own homes. Incidents described by the youths include a client being strangled by his father, a Southern Baptist minister, during a homophobic rage, and another made to stay up all night reciting biblical verses condemning homosexuality.</p></blockquote>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;Decent people do not stand by in silence when children are being abused,&#8221; says Siciliano. &#8220;We need to recognize that the condemnation of LGBT people in churches leads to the abuse and rejection of LGBT children in far too many Christian homes. As Christians commanded to love one another, we need to demand that this climate of rejection stops.&#8221;.</p>
<p>So maybe instead of painting eggs and scarfing down chocolate bunnies, you could do somehting to help LGBT youth in need? For ideas, visit <strong><a href="http://www.aliforneycenter.org/index.cfm?">the Ali Forney website</a>. </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=JI35HdhJOuE:BXmAydPT_Nk:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=JI35HdhJOuE:BXmAydPT_Nk:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-ali-forney-center-makes-easter-time-plea-for-christians-to-acknowledge-religious-intolerance-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-ali-forney-center-makes-easter-time-plea-for-christians-to-acknowledge-religious-intolerance-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Kalamazoo Restaurant Owner Apologizes For Anti-Gay Facebook Posts</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/c04xh-Jt8us/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/kalamazoo-restaurant-owner-apologizes-for-anti-gay-facebook-posts-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kalamazoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kalamazoo Gay and Lesbian Resource Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smashburger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terry henderson]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255400</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Earlier this week, Queerty reported on Terry Henderson, the owner of a Smashburger restaurant in Kalamazoo, MI, who posted hate-filled updates on Facebook attacking both same-sex marriage and gays in the Boys Scouts. Hey Starbucks, want to celebrate traditional marriage with us? I didn&#8217;t think so? &#8220;Celebrate marriage with us. We are honoring God&#8217;s design [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this week, Queerty reported on Terry Henderson, the owner of a Smashburger restaurant in Kalamazoo, MI, who posted <a href="http://www.queerty.com/kalamazoo-smashburger-owner-bashes-marriage-equality-defends-boy-scout-ban-20130327/">hate-filled updates on Facebook</a> attacking both same-sex marriage and gays in the Boys Scouts.</p>
<blockquote><p>Hey Starbucks, want to celebrate traditional marriage with us? I didn&#8217;t think so?</p>
<p>&#8220;Celebrate marriage with us. We are honoring God&#8217;s design for marriage and celebrating all who have joined together as man and wife. Click LIKE if you&#8217;ve been married 10 YEARS!&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<div id="attachment_254993" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 309px"><img class="size-full wp-image-254993 " alt="Smashburger co-owners Terry and Jean Henderson" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-26-at-7.20.35-PM.png" width="299" height="179" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Smashburger co-owners Terry and Jean Henderson</p></div>
<p>In an earlier post, Henderson also bashed efforts to end the Boy Scouts ban on openly gay members.</p>
<blockquote><p>As an Eagle Scout, I personally know of an incident involving a sexual assault on a younger boy committed by an older homosexual boy (note, I did not use the politically correct term &#8220;gay&#8221;—let the hate mail begin). The Boy Scouts as well as many other youth organizations have had their reputations smeared in the past because they unintentionally and unknowingly allowed homosexual pedophiles into their ranks&#8230;</p>
<p>I ask, do you want your boy scout (or any parent&#8217;s scout) sharing a tent with an avowed homosexual? Are you content with the idea of your scout being led on overnight camping trips by openly homosexual males?</p>
<p>If not, please vote to help the Boy Scouts of America maintain its 100 year tradition of doing its best to do its duty to God and country. Don&#8217;t worry your vote is secret, unlike mine.</p></blockquote>
<p>On Wednesday, Henderson sent us an email apologizing for his posts:</p>
<div>
<blockquote><p>“I sincerely regret the comments that I recently made on my personal Facebook page.  The comments were inappropriate and frankly un-Christian and I would like to apologize to the gay and lesbian community and all those who were offended.</p>
<p>I have taken down my Facebook page as I realize the hurtful impact my comments have had.”</p></blockquote>
</div>
<p>We&#8217;ll leave it up to you to decide if Henderson truly had a change of heart, or realized that media coverage from Queerty and other sites was hurting his bottom line. (Henderson also runs a local <a href="http://west-michigan-marketing.com/about">marketing company).</a></p>
<p>Regardless, we appreciate his reply—and that he gave a real apology, not one of those &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry if you took it that way&#8221; cop-outs.</p>
<p>You can still help the LGBT community in Michigan with a donation to the <a href="http://goo.gl/15VZb">Kalamazoo Gay and Lesbian Resource Center.</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=c04xh-Jt8us:FDzQD7lmxWY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=c04xh-Jt8us:FDzQD7lmxWY:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/kalamazoo-restaurant-owner-apologizes-for-anti-gay-facebook-posts-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/kalamazoo-restaurant-owner-apologizes-for-anti-gay-facebook-posts-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Rush Limbaugh: Gay Marriage Is Inevitable So “Get With It”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/cRglqyJviWg/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/rush-limbaugh-gay-marriage-inevitable-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill O'Reilly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rush Limbaugh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255475</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Maybe Time magazine is right since conservatives are seemingly throwing in the towel left and predominately right on the whole gay marriage thing. First Bill O&#8217;Reilly nearly gave Stephen Colbert a satirical heart attack with his ambivalent endorsement and now soft-boiled potato and Republican stalwart Rush Limbaugh has weighed in on the issue. On his [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/rush-limbaugh-left-will-normalize-pedophilia-like-it-did-gay-marriage-20130108/rush-limbaugh-radio/" rel="attachment wp-att-241703"><img class="alignright  wp-image-241703" style="margin: 10px;" alt="rush-limbaugh-radio" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/01/rush-limbaugh-radio-360x268.jpg" width="252" height="188" /></a>Maybe <em>Time</em> magazine <a href="http://www.queerty.com/time-magazine-gay-marriage-already-won-20130328/" target="_blank">is right</a> since conservatives are seemingly throwing in the towel left and predominately right on the whole gay marriage thing.</p>
<p>First Bill O&#8217;Reilly nearly gave Stephen Colbert <a href="http://www.queerty.com/watch-stephen-colbert-bill-oreilly-gay-marriage-20130328/" target="_blank">a satirical heart attack</a> with his <a href="http://www.queerty.com/watch-bill-oreilly-criticizes-bible-thumping-gay-marriage-opponents-20130328/" target="_blank">ambivalent endorsement</a> and now soft-boiled potato and Republican stalwart Rush Limbaugh has weighed in on the issue.</p>
<p>On his radio show yesterday, Limbaugh called the fight against marriage equality &#8220;lost&#8221; and that it is now &#8220;inevitable,&#8221; regardless of what the Supreme Court decides on Prop 8 and DOMA.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Limbaugh said same-sex marriage opponents are being told &#8220;the country is changing and you better get with it and understand it. The genie is not getting put back in the bottle.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;And I think that&#8217;s right,&#8221; he added. &#8220;I don&#8217;t care what this court does with this particular ruling, Proposition 8. I think the inertia is clearly moving in the direction that there is going to be gay marriage at some point nationwide.&#8221;</p>
<p>So it&#8217;s not so much an enthusiastic &#8220;gay marriage is happening!&#8221; so much as a defeated &#8220;ugh, gay marriage&#8230;FINE!&#8221;</p>
<p>Limbaugh did, however, take issue with O&#8217;Reilly &#8220;marginalizing&#8221; opponents as &#8220;Bible-thumpers,&#8221; but argues that he and his lost the battle because they <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/post-politics/wp/2013/03/28/rush-limbaugh-gay-marriage-inevitable-conservatives-lost/" target="_blank">allowed the term</a> &#8220;marriage&#8221; to be &#8220;bastardized.&#8221;</p>
<p>Despite these conservative concessions, however, the fight is far from over so don&#8217;t rest on those liberal laurels quite yet, kids. Opinion may be in our favor, but as long as there are laws on the books that discriminate against LGBT people, there&#8217;s no real victory.</p>
<p>(<em>h/t</em>: <a href="http://www.gaystarnews.com/article/rush-limbaugh-predicts-gay-marriage-will-become-legal-nationwide-us280313" target="_blank"><em>Gay Star News</em></a>)</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=cRglqyJviWg:Aa9w1SIp0rE:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=cRglqyJviWg:Aa9w1SIp0rE:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/rush-limbaugh-gay-marriage-inevitable-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/rush-limbaugh-gay-marriage-inevitable-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.258 seconds. --><!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-01 07:37:45 --><!-- Compression = gzip -->
