<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Queerty</title>
	
	<link>http://www.queerty.com</link>
	<description>Free of an agenda. Except that gay one.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 14:41:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/queerty2" /><feedburner:info uri="queerty2" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><geo:lat>40.732509</geo:lat><geo:long>-73.989358</geo:long><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site, subject to copyright and fair use.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item>
		<title>WATCH: For A Good Time, Ring Willam’s Bell</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/CLD8OoVwJMQ/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-for-a-good-time-ring-willams-bell-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 14:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drag race]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ring my bell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RuPaul's Drag Race]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Willam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Willam Belli]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255181</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Willam is the latest queen to pick up the phone in our new favorite web series, Ring My Bell, which in Ms. Belli&#8217;s manicured claws quickly devolves into a low class, high camp sex hotline. You&#8217;re welcome.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/i6KUjc5UMv8?rel=0" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Willam is the latest queen to pick up the phone in our new favorite web series, <em>Ring My Bell</em>, which in Ms. Belli&#8217;s manicured claws quickly devolves into a low class, high camp sex hotline. You&#8217;re welcome.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=CLD8OoVwJMQ:2MhqKhKBigg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=CLD8OoVwJMQ:2MhqKhKBigg:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-for-a-good-time-ring-willams-bell-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-for-a-good-time-ring-willams-bell-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Playwright Dan Fishback Discusses Gaycism, Self-Loathing And The Iraq War In “Waiting For Barbara”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/AXWk323e_mI/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/dan-fishback-waiting-for-barbara-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 12:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barbara Bush]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christine Quinn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dan fishback]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaycism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homophobia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internal homophobia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iraq War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mattilda bernstein sycamore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muslim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarah Schulman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the new normal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theater]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255623</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Playwright Dan Fishback covers a lot of territory in his humorous but highly provocative play, Waiting for Barbara: homophobia, privilege, power, racism &#8212; all rolled up and snorted through a 100 dollar bill. Set on the first night of the War in Iraq, two gay Yale seniors await the arrival of the President&#8217;s daughter to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/dan-fishback-waiting-for-barbara-20130330/waiting-for-barbara/" rel="attachment wp-att-255625"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-255625" style="margin: 10px;" alt="WAITING FOR BARBARA" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/WAITING-FOR-BARBARA-360x361.jpg" width="360" height="361" /></a>Playwright <a href="http://www.danfishback.com/" target="_blank">Dan Fishback</a> covers a lot of territory in his humorous but highly provocative play, <em>Waiting for Barbara</em>: homophobia, privilege, power, racism &#8212; all rolled up and snorted through a 100 dollar bill.</p>
<p>Set on the first night of the War in Iraq, two gay Yale seniors await the arrival of the President&#8217;s daughter to bring them to &#8220;an opening night war party.&#8221; While they wait, they drown their sorrows in cocaine and crystal meth, self-loathing and self-denial, and through their own twisted lenses, they envision what the war means for them and for America.</p>
<p>Fishback staged a reading at New York&#8217;s New Museum on the tenth anniversary of the start of the Iraq War, followed by a discussion of its themes. A few days later we had Dan analyze his own words to give us his unfiltered take on internal homophobia and gaycism in the LGBT community.</p>
<p>Warning: there&#8217;s some indelicate language ahead.</p>
<blockquote><p><b>Davenport</b>: I never thought I’d feel this way, but it’s like: I’m really thinking about gay people all over the world, and how we’re going to save them from the Muslims.</p>
<p><b>Bryce</b>: It’s our duty. It’s our duty as homosexuals to protect one another.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Queerty:<i> Do you think the plight of gays in the Muslim world has improved since the start of the wars?</i></strong></p>
<p><strong>Fishback:</strong> Oh god, no.  This is one of the big myths of Western imperialism – that war with Muslim countries will bring safety for women and queer people.  In the decade since our invasion of Iraq, hundreds if not thousands of gay men and trans women in Iraq have been systematically hunted down, tortured and killed by anti-queer death squads.  Some of the more gruesome torture involved cementing the anuses of the victims, and then force-feeding them laxatives so their intestines would explode.  This was not happening under Saddam.  So yeah, the War in Iraq has not been good for gay people, no.</p>
<p>And yet we still see this attitude that Americans should support violence against Muslim countries because those countries are homophobic.  (As if America is not also homophobic and transphobic – as if trans people in our own country are not also systematically murdered.)  You see it particularly in the discourse about Israel and Palestine, but if you talk to queer Palestinians, they all say that they will never see progress until the Occupation ends.  So if you partially justify the subjugation of Palestine because it is a homophobic place, you’re also ignoring the actual wishes of real queer Palestinians who are begging for freedom.  Recent writing by <a href="http://www.queerty.com/new-york-lgbt-center-lifts-ban-on-israeli-palestinian-conflict-20130217/" target="_blank">Sarah Schulman</a> is particularly helpful to understand this process, especially her book, <em>Israel/Palestine and the Queer International.</em></p>
<blockquote><p><b>Davenport</b>: Sam’s in love with you.</p>
<p><b>Bryce</b>: Sam’s in love with Barbara!</p>
<p><b>Davenport</b>: Sam is in love with power. Sam is in love with the power of being best friends with the First Daughter, and Sam is in love with the power of SUCKING YOUR PASTY-ASS BLUE-BLOOD YANKEE DICK.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Q:<i> One of the most interesting themes of the play is “proximity to power,” particularly how homosexuals in those positions – closeted or not – forsake the LGBT community, e.g. Ken Mehlman. Can you speak to that a bit?</i></strong></p>
<p><strong>F:</strong> One of the worst culprits of this kind of betrayal is Christine Quinn.  People support her because she’s a lesbian, but her actual policies are terrible for most queer people.  She supported turning St. Vincent’s Hospital in the still-gay West Village into a luxury condo high rise, as if gay people need wealthy neighbors more than they need a hospital.  She won’t pass paid sick leave, she’s supported our demonic Police Commissioner, the list goes on and on.  But the thing is: queer people are everywhere.  So when politicians like Quinn attack the poor, they attack the LGBT community.  When they attack immigrants, they attack the LGBT community.  When they attack people of color, they attack the LGBT community.</p>
<p>It happens over and over again – not just here, but in Western European countries too.  When white homosexuals gain access to political power, they consolidate it by joining the white heterosexual elite in oppressing some “other” group – like immigrants, the poor, or people of color.  This is being called “homonationalism,” which I think is a really helpful term, because it’s so widespread – the desperateness with which so many white homosexuals shit on whoever is beneath them in order to feel more secure in the power structure that, only a few years ago, would have eaten them alive.</p>
<blockquote><p><b>Davenport</b>: Jesus. Don’t get all Self-Loathing, Country Club Pity Poofter on me – it won’t work. I’m not going to feel sorry for you.</p>
<p><b>Bryce</b>: I don’t want you to feel sorry for me.</p>
<p><b>Davenport</b>: Good, cause I’m not going to…</p>
<p><b>Bryce</b>: I don’t care what you think.</p>
<p><b>Davenport</b>: Good, cause I think you’re a cry baby.</p>
<p><b>Bryce</b>: I’m a faggot.</p>
<p><b>Davenport</b>: Jeez. Give me a fucking break. You have no right to get like this.</p>
<p><b>Bryce</b>: I have no right…to be sad, when [my] friend says horrid, horrid things about [me]?</p>
<p><b>Davenport</b>: You have no idea.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Q:<i> These characters are particularly vicious towards one another, but you said it wasn’t much of a stretch from conversations you’ve heard. Why do you think there’s so much internal homophobia among gay men?</i></strong></p>
<p><strong>F:</strong> Homophobia means fear of gay people, and who is more afraid of gay men than other gay men?  There’s a great anthology by Mattilda Bernstein Sycamore called <em>Why Are Faggots So Afraid of Faggots?</em> which shines a light on this dynamic.  We are so deeply oppressed, and so deeply fucked up as children.  We retreat into our imaginations, we dissociate, we withdraw.  As adults, we’re suddenly confronted with the reality of other human beings and so often we can’t get beyond those initial defense mechanisms.  And because we’re still trapped in our defensive narcissism, so often gay men can’t understand that other people are real.  So we lash out, we project, we see other people as reflections of ourselves and we destroy them because it’s easier than dealing with our own self-hatred and guilt.  Just lurk in any gay bar late enough and you see this dynamic play itself out.  It’s depressing and disgusting and it’s the result of systemic cultural homophobia.</p>
<blockquote><p><b>Davenport</b>: We can <i>do </i>anything we fucking want. I mean…that’s like… THAT’S, LIKE, THE POINT. That’s the point of this war. We’re fighting this war so we can do WHATEVER WE FUCKING WANT.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Q: <i>After the play, talk turned to </i>The New Normal<i> and the sense that gay white males are somehow beyond racism. Why do you think that is?</i></strong></p>
<p><strong>F:</strong> So many white gay men seem to think that, because they are oppressed as homosexuals, they automatically understand ALL OPPRESSION, and are experts about all minority experiences, and therefore have a free pass to indulge in racist humor.  “I’m gay,” they say, “so I couldn’t <i>possibly </i>be racist.”  This is being called “<a href="http://www.queerty.com/gaycist-tv-characters-20120907/" target="_blank">gaycism</a>,” which I think is a pretty helpful term.  You also see it in white gay men’s attitudes towards women and trans people.  Like, in another Ryan Murphy show, <i>Glee</i>, one character is a trans woman of color, but she barely ever says anything because the writers obviously know nothing about trans people.  And yet they feel that they somehow own this experience because they are “LGBT,” and that T has got to mean something.  But the truth is that being a cisgender homosexual teaches you ABSOLUTELY NOTHING about transgender experience until you get to know transgender people, or read books by transgender authors.</p>
<p>It all comes down to this: In my eyes, being queer can lead you down two different paths – it can make you sensitive to other oppression experiences or it can make you oblivious to them.  It can make you humble or it can make you a dick.  It can make you confront your own internalized racism, misogyny, transphobia and homophobia with dignity and a genuine concern to become a better person, or it can make you shut down to any implication that you are anything but a progressive gay saint.  My hope is that more and more people use gay identity politics as a gateway drug to intersectionalism – so we can all tap into our revolutionary queer potential.</p>
<p>That’s the genius of being queer – we have the opportunity to inspect society from outside of it, to better understand how it’s broken.  What concerns me – and what <i>Waiting for Barbara </i>is about – is that, so many homosexuals are missing that opportunity.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=AXWk323e_mI:kNgHUW15cCU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=AXWk323e_mI:kNgHUW15cCU:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/dan-fishback-waiting-for-barbara-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/dan-fishback-waiting-for-barbara-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Malaysian Government Produces Anti-Gay Musical To Scare Kids Straight</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/mPdDuf8BbgQ/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/malaysian-government-produces-anti-gay-musical-to-scare-public-straight-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 11:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asmara Songsang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international LGBT rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theater]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255604</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If ever there was an art form us gays own (besides, y&#8217;know, all of them) its musical theater. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re so incensed that the Malaysian government has sponsored a musical aimed at teaching young people about the dangers of being LGBT. Asmara Songsang (or, Abnormal Desire) follows the lives of three queer gang members—we [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="article-body-blocks">
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255609" alt="Asmara Songsang" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Asmara-Songsang-670x444.jpg" width="650" height="430" /></p>
<p>If ever there was an art form us gays own (besides, y&#8217;know, all of them) its musical theater. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re so incensed that the Malaysian government has sponsored a musical aimed at teaching young people about the dangers of being LGBT.</p>
<p><em>Asmara Songsang</em> (or, <em>Abnormal Desire</em>) follows the lives of three queer gang members—we know they&#8217;re gay because they take drugs, throw loud parties and engage in casual sex. The trio&#8217;s Muslim neighbors try to bring the perverts back into the fold, but a convenient lighting storm slays those who refuse to change their evil ways. After a  lecture on the hideous wrongs of not being heterosexual, the entire cast comes out on stage with Malaysian flags and sings a song dedicated to national unity.</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-255608 alignright" alt="DSC2310" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/DSC2310-360x239.jpg" width="330" height="219" />Writer-director Rahman Adam, 73, says the goal of <em>Abnormal Desire </em>is to alert  youngsters and their parents as to &#8220;the bad things about LGBT.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Nowadays in Malaysia you read so many things in newspaper articles or write-ups about LGBT… because [LGBT] are going into schools and influencing the children,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Children need to recognize that men are for women, and women are for men. They are all out to have homosexual and lesbian sex, and although right now it is not so serious [in Malaysia], we need to act, to do something, to say something, to say that this is bad and not to follow it.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Malay <a href="http://blog.kakiseni.com/2013/03/oh-inverted-world/#more-694">blogger Alia Ali</a> calls <em>Asmara Songsang </em>&#8220;all-out propaganda&#8221; that&#8217;s not just bigoted, it&#8217;s poorly executed:</p>
<blockquote><p>Even if it wasn’t propagandistic, there were too many troubling issues: The part that gets to me the most is that according to the playwright, all non-heterosexuals seem to belong to a club. Membership is declared by choosing whether they want to be an L, G, B or T, then a partner (or “baby LGBT” as they call it) for them is found. Any sort of contact with the heteronormative world is cut off — in fact, they’ll fight tooth and nail to keep recruits in their clutches and away from their family. And since they’re immoral and not “normal”, they must of course drink heavily, take drugs, and make out right in public. They actively recruit members to join their side, turning straight people gay, and clearly don’t even live in reality.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/28/anti-gay-lgbt-musical-malaysia"><em>The Guardian</em> reports </a>that the musical features some of the country&#8217;s biggest TV stars and has played the national theater in Kuala Lumpur, in addition to public schools and universities across the largely Islamic country.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re guessing it won&#8217;t be heading to Broadway.</p>
</div>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=mPdDuf8BbgQ:uo-R6OBYvNA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=mPdDuf8BbgQ:uo-R6OBYvNA:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/malaysian-government-produces-anti-gay-musical-to-scare-public-straight-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/malaysian-government-produces-anti-gay-musical-to-scare-public-straight-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrity Escort Chris Gaida Dishes From Behind The Velvet Rope</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/85eksi8Fz_8/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 10:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Primary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arm candy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celebrity escorts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chris gaida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christopher gaida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Escorts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Kardashian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[out in print]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pam Anderson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queen Latifah]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255405</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Usually when we think of the word &#8220;escort,&#8221; we think of guys who &#8220;lift luggage&#8221; for closeted preachers. But Chris Gaida is a legitimate escort—he goes along with big-name celebrities to red-carpet functions, making sure they get where they&#8217;re supposed to and have a nice time while they&#8217;re there. Gaida has escorted Taylor Swift, Kim [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img class="alignright size-large wp-image-255408" style="margin: 5px 10px;" alt="AM_ArmCandy_Cover_R1" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Final-Cover-High-Res-428x670.jpeg" width="277" height="433" />Usually when we think of the word &#8220;escort,&#8221; we think of guys who &#8220;lift luggage&#8221; for closeted preachers. But Chris Gaida is a legitimate escort—he goes along with big-name celebrities to red-carpet functions, making sure they get where they&#8217;re supposed to and have a nice time while they&#8217;re there.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Gaida has escorted Taylor Swift, Kim Kardashian, Betty White, Ricky Martin, Mariah Carey, Darren Kriss, Angelina Jolie and countless other stars.  He&#8217;s seen the sloppy drunks, the diva fits, and the &#8220;straight&#8221; movie stars who have their hands all over the male escorts.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Now, Caida, 38, is spilling some red-carpet T with his memoir, <a href="http://www.armcandybook.com.">Arm Candy</a>, In it, he delivers behind-the-scenes dish, reveals who in Hollywood is a pain in the posterior (you&#8217;d be surprised) and shares his personal coming-out storyc.</div>
<div></div>
<div>We chatted with the walker-turned-author about his exploits, the rules of the business, and clearing up the confusion that he&#8217;s not &#8220;that&#8221; kind of escort.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>How did you get involve in the escort business?<br />
</strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>I was fresh out of college when I landed a temp job at MTV Networks in New York. One day while trying to stay busy answering phones, some random guy approached my desk and asked if I would want to escort at the VH1 <em>Divas Live</em> show.  I told him no, as I heard about the casting couch and sleeping with someone was not the way I wanted to make it to the top.</div>
<div></div>
<div>He insisted that it was not a sexual job, so I decided to take the chance and escort at the show. From what he briefly described, it sounded cool, but also too good to be true—I didn&#8217;t want to end up in one of those <em>20/20</em> stories.  You know, the ones where some kid knew something was shady and did it anyway and wound up getting murdered.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Not only was I not murdered, but it was everything I could have imagined and more. I had all access to every celebrity, and sex was <em>not</em> on the menu.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>What&#8217;s entailed in a typical escorting job?</strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>Celebrity escorts exist at just about every award show and there are, on average, about 20-30 escorts per show.  There are a small group of us that work just about every show and then there are a few people that do it just a few times and then disappear forever. I imagine that they get frustrated because of the amount of work involved, and some get upset that they always have to take a back seat because the celebrity gets all of the attention. Other times they get fired because they do something stupid or don&#8217;t have the best interest of the celebrity in mind.  <img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-255415" alt="Christopher Gaida" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Christopher-Gaida-360x270.jpg" width="367" height="289" /></div>
<div></div>
<div>Basically we handle the celebrities experiences at award shows. From rehearsal to red carpet to the actual show, we make sure that not only the celebrities are well taken care of, but that the show producers get what they need to make the show the best that it can be. We bring the celebrities backstage when its time, handle media requests, coordinate script changes, rush celebrities past eager fans and coordinate timing and logistics for the show. I have to wear many different hats and deal with multiple personalities—sometimes within the same person.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Since these shows are mostly live, mistakes are not an option and not knowing an answer can cost you your job.  Its an incredible job, though, where you are able to literally spend an entire day with your favorite celebrity. Its nice to see how the other half lives and to experience a part of Hollywood that very few people have.  Even reporters and other crew members don&#8217;t have the access we do.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Do people assume you sleep with celebrities?</strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>People always wonder about that. That&#8217;s not part of the job at all, and never expected of anyone.  The insiders knows about this job and how important we are to making sure things flow properly and that the celebrities are clear in communication with the producers. A few times I have been asked out by the celebrities &#8220;people&#8221;—manager, publicist, make-up artist—but rarely has a celebrity themselves asked me out.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Who were some of the celebrities that surprised you—either with how diva-like they were or how cool they were?</strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>Pamela Anderson is one of the celebrities who has shocked me with how different she was in person than what I expected her to be. I expected this dumb blonde, but in real life she has it all together—she&#8217;s very savvy. In my book I apologize if I&#8217;m blowing her cover!  She not only seems to be an excellent mother, but an incredible business woman who knows how to work the dumb-blond image.</p>
</div>
<div>Another celebrity that surprised me was Queen Latifah.  I escorted her back before she became a big movie star and I assumed she would be difficult. I knew she was a rap artist and was on one TV show at the time, but that is all I knew.  The moment I met her though I realized how special she is.  She instantly treated me as if I was her brother or as if we known each other for years.  She was very welcoming and a very fun person to spend time with.  In my presence she was always happy and not a diva in anyway.  I still remember the expression on her face when we went to her suite in Las Vegas that production and booked for her.  It was like a scene from a movie where the doors opened and we both saw this big gorgeous room for the first time.  She lite up like a Christmas tree and was truly grateful for such an incredible room.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p><img class=" wp-image-255411 alignright" title="Chris and Darren Criss" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/darren-cris.jpg" width="234" height="186" /></p>
<p><strong>What are some of the never-break rules of being a celebrity escort? </strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>The Number One rule for a celebrity escort is to <em>never</em> lose your talent. Escorts usually just have one celebrity that they are with all day and night, and they are not allowed to lose sight of them. This may sound simple, but celebrities are often pulled in many different directions and with crowds of people and people pulling an escort away by asking questions or just talking it can be a challenge.  Ten seconds of giving someone directions can be a fatal mistake—because just that quickly the talent can be gone.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Other rules are to act professional at all times, don&#8217;t be late, know the venue inside and out, and  be prepared for everything.  An escort could be walking their celebrity to their dressing room only to find the hallway blocked. If that escort doesn&#8217;t know another route instantly then problems can occur.  I make sure I know where <em>every</em> hallway and door leads to, because you never know when you are going to make a hasty detour.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Have you escorted any gay celebrities—or covered for any who were in the closet?</strong></div>
<div>
I escorted the <em>Queer Eye For the Straight Guy</em> cast back in 2003, at the height of their fame. It was at the MTV Video Music awards and they were all extremely nice guys.  Two of the guys asked me out and I did go on dates with them both—though not the same night. No romance brewed, but it was a fun experience and I was happy to have spent some time getting to know them better.</div>
<div></div>

						<div id="slide-nav-top" class="navigation">
							<div class="nav-next"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/barbara-bach/">Next Photo &raquo;</a></div>					
														<div class="nav-center"><b>1 of 8</b></div>
						</div><!-- #nav-below -->				
				<div>
					<div class="entry-content">
						<div class="entry-attachment">
					<p class="attachment" id="gall">
					<a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/barbara-bach/" title="Celebrity Escort Chris Gaida Dishes From Behind The Velvet Rope" rel="attachment"><img width="428" height="670" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Final-Cover-High-Res-428x670.jpeg" class="attachment-large" alt="AM_ArmCandy_Cover_R1" />			
							</a></p>
						</div><!-- .entry-attachment -->
					</div><!-- .entry-content -->
				</div><!-- #post-## -->
				<div class="scrollable_holder"><a class="prev browse left"><img class="scroll-nav" src="http://d3qke3e8pe2nmf.cloudfront.net/wp/wp-content/themes/queerty_August2012_audit/images/gallery-left.png"></a><div class="scrollable"><div class="items"><div class="scroll-group"><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/am_armcandy_cover_r1/"><span>1</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Final-Cover-High-Res-50x50.jpeg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="AM_ArmCandy_Cover_R1" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/barbara-bach/"><span>2</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/barbara-bach-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="Chris with Barbara Bach" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/chris-gaida-bren-koombs/"><span>3</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/chris-gaida-bren-koombs-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="signing Arm Candy at Barnes &amp; Noble (Photo: Bren Cooms)" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/darren-cris/"><span>4</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/darren-cris-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="Chris and Darren Criss" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/gaida/"><span>5</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/gaida-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="With John tenny and Rebecca RomjiT" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/chris-gaida/"><span>6</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/chris-gaida-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="Some of Chri&#039;s celebrity clients" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/christopher-gaida-2/"><span>7</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Christopher-Gaida-2-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="Christopher Gaida and Kim Kardashian" /></a></div><div><a href="http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/christopher-gaida/"><span>8</span><img width="50" height="50" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Christopher-Gaida-50x50.jpg" class="attachment-50x50" alt="Christopher Gaida" /></a></div></div></div></div><a class="next browse right"><img class="scroll-nav" src="http://d3qke3e8pe2nmf.cloudfront.net/wp/wp-content/themes/queerty_August2012_audit/images/gallery-right.png"></a></div>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=85eksi8Fz_8:mskaThKDVM0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=85eksi8Fz_8:mskaThKDVM0:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/celebrity-escort-chris-gaida-dishes-from-behind-the-velvet-rope-20130330/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Sorry, Republicans, The Supreme Court Killing DOMA Won’t Solve Your Problems</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/g6wxHsWfQuQ/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/sorry-republicans-the-supreme-court-killing-doma-wont-solve-your-problems-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 18:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JohnGallagher</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255586</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s a thread going around these days that the GOP establishment would like nothing more than for the Supreme Court to strike down DOMA. The establishment knows it can&#8217;t oppose marriage equality forever, and the cracks in its facade are already showing, both with Sen. Rob Portman&#8217;s announcement that he supports marriage equality and the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/elephant.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-255457" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/elephant.jpg" width="231" height="177" /></a>There&#8217;s a thread going around these days that the GOP establishment would like nothing more than for the Supreme Court <a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2013/03/the-scotus-ruling-the-gop-really-wants-89400.html">to strike down DOMA</a>.</p>
<p>The establishment knows it can&#8217;t oppose marriage equality forever, and the cracks in its facade are already showing, both with <a href="http://www.queerty.com/gop-senator-with-gay-son-embraces-marriage-equality-good-news-or-too-little-too-late-20130315/">Sen. Rob Portman&#8217;s announcemen</a>t that he supports marriage equality and the hint in the <a href="http://www.queerty.com/gop-knows-it-needs-to-talk-about-change-it-just-doesnt-want-to-actually-make-any-20130321/">2012 post-mortem report </a>that opposition to marriage is a demographic timebomb.</p>
<p>But if the Supreme Court decides to take the weasel road by striking down DOMA and leaving marriage up to the states, the GOP may have the worst of all possible worlds. Here&#8217;s why:</p>
<ul>
<li>Statewide ballot measures to approve marriage equality will multiply, which means the religious right will be out in force. If the party is wishy washy, they&#8217;ll be very angry, which will affect turnout for other races. If the party forsakes them altogether, there will be a gigantic rift in the party (which is bound to come anyway).</li>
<li>A Court ruling that kicks the can down the road is going to be the Lawyer Full Employment Act. We will start seeing lots of cases in which couples married in one state seek recognition in a state where they can&#8217;t marry. All of that means lots of publicity and more questions.</li>
<li>The party may modify, but individual candidates can&#8217;t. Can you imagine a GOP presidential primary slate in 2016 in which opposition to ballot measures isn&#8217;t a litmus test for the base?</li>
<li>The nutburgers are likely to get nuttier. The folks the party elevates aren&#8217;t renowned for their diplomacy, and when under the gun, <a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/weigel/2013/03/28/_be_they_gays_be_they_nambla_be_they_people_who_believe_in_beastiality.html">they say some pretty crazy and offensive things</a>, all in the party&#8217;s name.</li>
</ul>
<p>In short, things just get even messier for Republicans. Perhaps<a href="http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2013/03/next-stage-for-gay-rights-conservative-amnesia.html"> collective amnesia</a> will eventually solve their problem, but it&#8217;s not going anyway any time soon.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=g6wxHsWfQuQ:0huFmb1tOcM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=g6wxHsWfQuQ:0huFmb1tOcM:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/sorry-republicans-the-supreme-court-killing-doma-wont-solve-your-problems-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/sorry-republicans-the-supreme-court-killing-doma-wont-solve-your-problems-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Hunky Jesus And Other Easter Events Sure To Get You Hoppin’</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/kT3GMbWgO6E/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 17:53:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>koreykuhl</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dallas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaycities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaycities weekender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hunky Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leather and fetish weekend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palm Springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sydney]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255428</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From San Franisco&#8217;s Hunky Jesus contest to the White Party in Palm Springs, GayCities serves up a calendar overflowing with Easter celebrations this weekend. Check out some of the highlights below or find an event near you with your GayCities Guide to Easter Weekend. &#160;  Easter Leather and Fetish Weekend in Berlin Easter in the Park [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/screen-shot-2012-04-09-at-3-13-11-pm-600x501/" rel="attachment wp-att-255429"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255429" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Screen-shot-2012-04-09-at-3.13.11-PM-600x501.png" width="600" height="501" /></a></p>
<p>From San Franisco&#8217;s <a href="http://sanfrancisco.gaycities.com/events/216352-easter-in-the-park-the-sisters-34th-anniversary-celebration">Hunky Jesus</a> contest to the <a href="http://palmsprings.gaycities.com/events/183033-white-party-palm-springs-2013">White Party</a> in <a href="http://palmsprings.gaycities.com">Palm Springs</a>, GayCities serves up a calendar overflowing with Easter celebrations this weekend. Check out some of the highlights below or find an event near you with your <a href="http://www.gaycities.com/events/tid/1207">GayCities Guide to Easter Weekend</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/screen-shot-2013-03-28-at-2-37-25-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-255430"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-255430" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-28-at-2.37.25-PM-360x270.png" width="360" height="270" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <a href="http://berlin.gaycities.com/events/164478-blf-ecmc-easter-in-berlin-german-mr-leather-2013">Easter Leather and Fetish Weekend</a> in <a href="http://berlin.gaycities.com/">Berlin</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/easter13b/" rel="attachment wp-att-255434"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255434" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Easter13b.jpg" width="282" height="236" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://dallas.gaycities.com/events/209995-easter-in-the-park-and-pooch-parade">Easter in the Park and Pooch Parade</a> in <a href="http://dallas.gaycities.com">Dallas</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/599320_10151716707931055_1642055595_n/" rel="attachment wp-att-255436"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-255436" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/599320_10151716707931055_1642055595_n-360x240.jpg" width="360" height="240" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://losangeles.gaycities.com/events/214110-vgl-weho-dodgeball-easter-eggstravaganza">Varsity Gay League Easter Extravaganza</a> in <a href="http://losangeles.gaycities.com">Los Angeles</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://sydney.gaycities.com/events/218864-stonewall-royal-gay-easter-show-weekend-2013" rel="attachment wp-att-255437"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-255437" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/526837_10151316107511167_49313935_n-360x270.jpg" width="360" height="270" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://sydney.gaycities.com/events/218864-stonewall-royal-gay-easter-show-weekend-2013">Gay Easter Show Weekend</a> in <a href="http://sydney.gaycities.com">Sydney</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://sanfrancisco.gaycities.com/events/216352-easter-in-the-park-the-sisters-34th-anniversary-celebration" rel="attachment wp-att-255435"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255435" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/hunky_jesus-250x166.jpg" width="250" height="166" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://sanfrancisco.gaycities.com/events/216352-easter-in-the-park-the-sisters-34th-anniversary-celebration">Hunky Jesus</a> in <a href="http://sanfrancisco.gaycities.com/">San Francisco</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://palmsprings.gaycities.com/events/183033-white-party-palm-springs-2013" rel="attachment wp-att-255431"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-255431" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/003-670x4051-360x217.jpg" width="360" height="217" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://palmsprings.gaycities.com/events/183033-white-party-palm-springs-2013">White Party </a><a href="http://palmsprings.gaycities.com">Palm Springs</a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong><em>Find an event near you with the <a href="http://www.gaycities.com/events/tid/1207">GayCities Guide to Easter Weekend</a></em><br />
</strong></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=kT3GMbWgO6E:7UQY7n3613w:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=kT3GMbWgO6E:7UQY7n3613w:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/hunky-jesus-and-other-easter-events-sure-to-get-you-hoppin-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Michigan RNC Member Defends Posting About Gays’ “Filthy Lifestyle,” Refuses To Resign</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/IK0xijgrJUE/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/michigan-rnc-member-defends-posting-about-gays-filthy-lifestyle-refuses-to-resign-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 17:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255578</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Each week, Queerty picks one blowhard, hypocrite, airhead, sanctimonious prick or other enemy of all that is queer to be the Douche of the Week.  Have a nominee for DOTW? E-mail it to us at holla@queerty.com. Just when you think the goalposts have moved and our enemies have to camouflage their hatred in softer tones, a GOP [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-255588" alt="dave-agema" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/dave-agema.jpg" width="300" height="215" /><strong>Each week, Queerty picks one blowhard, hypocrite, airhead, sanctimonious prick or other enemy of all that is queer to be the Douche of the Week. </strong></p>
<div>
<p><strong>Have a nominee for DOTW? E-mail it to us at <a href="mailto:">holla@queerty.com</a>.</strong></p>
</div>
<p>Just when you think the goalposts have moved and our enemies have to camouflage their hatred in softer tones, a GOP honcho vomits up something we&#8217;d expect to hear from Jesse Helms (may he rot in Hell.)</p>
<p>Dave Agema, a member of the Michigan RNC committee, <a href="http://www.addictinginfo.org/2013/03/28/michigan-gop-official-reveals-himself-for-the-bigot-he-is-with-facebook-post/" target="_blank">posted a link on Facebook</a> to an article describing just how harmful homosexuality is, not just to those who practice it but to the general population.</p>
<p>Among the &#8220;facts&#8221; in “Everyone Should Know These Statistics on Homosexuals”:</p>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Homosexuals live unhealthy lifestyles, and have historically accounted for the bulk of syphilis, gonorrhea, Hepatitis B, the “gay bowel syndrome” (which attacks the intestinal tract), tuberculosis and cytomegalovirus.</li>
</ul>
<ul type="disc">
<li>73% of psychiatrists say homosexuals are less happy than the average person, and of those psychiatrists, 70% say that the unhappiness is NOT due to social stigmatization</li>
</ul>
<ul type="disc">
<li>33% of homosexuals ADMIT to minor/adult sex</li>
</ul>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Judge John Martaugh, chief magistrate of the New York City Criminal Court has said, “Homosexuals account for half the murders in large cities”</li>
</ul>
<ul type="disc">
<li>Captain William Riddle of the Los Angeles Police says, “30,000 sexually abused children in Los Angeles were victims of homosexuals”</li>
<li>Because homosexuals can&#8217;t reproduce naturally, they resort to recruiting children. Homosexuals can be heard chanting &#8220;TEN PERCENT IS NOT ENOUGH, RECRUIT, RECRUIT, RECRUIT&#8221; in their homosexual parades.<br />
<em>You can read the full article <a title="Tradition In Action Homepage" href="http://www.traditioninaction.org/index.htm" target="_blank">here </a></em></li>
</ul>
<p>Just on the face of it, these so-called factoids are obviously bullshit. &#8220;Homosexuals account for half of the murders in large cities&#8221;? We were obviously suspicious of that one—it turns out Judge Martaugh was on the bench in the 1940s and &#8217;50s, and was a crusader against immortality and perversion. (He&#8217;s theonewho convicted Lenny Bruce of  obscenity.) So he&#8217;s not exactly an objective authority on anything.</p>
<p>We couldn&#8217;t even find any mention of a &#8220;Captain William Riddle&#8221; on the LAPD, but based on the other assertions, he was probably on the beat during the Civil War.</p>
<p>The rest of these bullet points are either out of context, outdated, or outright lies.</p>
<p>Dozens of Michigan Republican leaders have called for Agema to resign. &#8220;This isn&#8217;t about what we believe either politically or as women and men of faith. This is about common decency,&#8221; said Dennis Lennox, who is leading the call for Agema&#8217;s ousting. “We do not have confidence in Mr. Agema representing the best interests of our fellow Michigan Republicans and as a result ask him to resign from his seat on the Republican National Committee.&#8221;</p>
<p>Agema says calls for him to step down are &#8220;a joke.&#8221; In an email to the <em>Detroit</em> <em>Free Press</em> on Thursday, he accused “liberal Republicans” of twisting his words:</p>
<blockquote><p>“I think it was a piece worth sharing given the debate over gay marriage that is happening in the Supreme Court. I strongly maintain my position in support of marriage between a man and a woman and I will not back down from my core beliefs in support of strengthening the family.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Isn&#8217;t it the religious right who keep saying their opposition to marriage equality doesn&#8217;t mean they hate gays? We really wish you guys would make up your mind.</p>
<p>Before he was elected a member of the Michigan delegation to the RNC in 2012, Agema was a Michigan state representative from 2007 to 2012. He&#8217;s also the president of the Sabath House Ministries,  a member of the Allied Pilots Association and the NRA.</p>
<p>And, lest we forget: D<strong>he&#8217;s a douche!</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=IK0xijgrJUE:VI8OcOJx2lw:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=IK0xijgrJUE:VI8OcOJx2lw:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/michigan-rnc-member-defends-posting-about-gays-filthy-lifestyle-refuses-to-resign-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/michigan-rnc-member-defends-posting-about-gays-filthy-lifestyle-refuses-to-resign-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Jimmy Kimmel Asks You To Guess The Gay Marriage Supporter</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/LNM1n9Y6cPg/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-jimmy-kimmel-gay-marriage-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jimmy Kimmel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jimmy Kimmel Live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255561</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Jimmy Kimmel had his studio audience guess how pedestrians would respond when asked if they supported gay marriage. As a follow-up, they were also given a choice between two potential same-sex life mates. The audience was surprised by some of the marriage supporters, though obviously more surprised by whom these men and women on the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/PNh2-2wIA14?rel=0" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Jimmy Kimmel had his studio audience guess how pedestrians would respond when asked if they supported gay marriage. As a follow-up, they were also given a choice between two potential same-sex life mates.</p>
<p>The audience was surprised by some of the marriage supporters, though obviously more surprised by whom these men and women on the street would choose to gay marry. People always sleep on Regis.</p>
<p>Part 2:</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/eReLL_nUSJU?rel=0" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=LNM1n9Y6cPg:4F0aUXK993A:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=LNM1n9Y6cPg:4F0aUXK993A:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-jimmy-kimmel-gay-marriage-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-jimmy-kimmel-gay-marriage-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>“My Anus Is Getting Beaten On”: Sports Announcer Michael Schiavello Give Internet The Giggles</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/jmZ7bFYxvW4/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/my-anus-is-getting-beaten-on-sports-announcer-michael-schiavello-give-internet-the-giggles-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[danny mainus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael schiavello]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ufc]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255571</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[WATCH: Whether announcer Michael Schiavello was intentionally mispronouncing MMA fighter Danny Mainus&#8217; name during this bout or not, the clip has been rocketing around the Interwebs. With all the serious marriage-equality news this week, we thought we&#8217;d give you a Friday funny here.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ogB05Y9YDFg" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><strong>WATCH:</strong> Whether announcer Michael Schiavello was intentionally mispronouncing MMA fighter Danny Mainus&#8217; name during this bout or not, the clip has been rocketing around the Interwebs. With all the serious marriage-equality news this week, we thought we&#8217;d give you a Friday funny here.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=jmZ7bFYxvW4:F3hBTEsTDrQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=jmZ7bFYxvW4:F3hBTEsTDrQ:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/my-anus-is-getting-beaten-on-sports-announcer-michael-schiavello-give-internet-the-giggles-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/my-anus-is-getting-beaten-on-sports-announcer-michael-schiavello-give-internet-the-giggles-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Dan Choi Fined $100 For DADT Protest</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/FA4_6N5Rdbc/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/dan-choi-fined-100-for-dadt-protest-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DADT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dan Choi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don't Ask Don't Tell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trials]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255560</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Former US Army lieutenant Dan Choi, who became the face of the movement to end Don&#8217;t Ask Don&#8217;t Tell, has been fined $100 for chaining himself to the White House in 2010. Choi, who was discharged from the Army after coming out on the Rachel Maddow Show, faced up to six months in federal prison [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-223325" alt="dan choi" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2012/09/dan-choi1.jpg" width="269" height="207" />Former US Army lieutenant Dan Choi, who became the face of the movement to end Don&#8217;t Ask Don&#8217;t Tell, <a href="http://politic365.com/2013/03/28/lt-dan-choi-found-guilty-for-white-house-protest-taken-to-va-hospital/">has been fined $100</a> for chaining himself to the White House in 2010.</p>
<p>Choi, who was discharged from the Army after coming out on the <em>Rachel Maddow Show</em>, faced up to six months in federal prison for his actions. (Others who participated in the demonstration pleaded guilty.) He will not face any prison time if he pays the fine.</p>
<p>Choi represented himself at trial, though it&#8217;s hardly his first time facing legal headaches: In December a Superior Court judge <a href="http://www.queerty.com/dan-choi-20121223/#ixzz2Owggv65Y">dismissed charges against Choi</a> relating to his participation in White House demonstration against the Keystone XL Pipeline. And in 2011, Choi was among a number of international activists arrested for holding a Moscow Pride event despite a ban by the city government.</p>
<p>That same year <a href="http://www.queerty.com/dan-choi-tackled-handcuffed-kicked-off-base-while-trying-to-attend-bradley-manning%e2%80%99s-hearing-draft-20111221/#ixzz2Owhaa8A3">military police wrestled Choi</a> to the ground before handcuffing him, threatening to charge him with resisting arrest and eventually kicking him off Fort Meade when he tried to attend accused Wikileaker Bradley Manning’s hearing.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=FA4_6N5Rdbc:9a5AltK6oCk:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=FA4_6N5Rdbc:9a5AltK6oCk:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/dan-choi-fined-100-for-dadt-protest-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/dan-choi-fined-100-for-dadt-protest-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Tom Daley’s New Man, “Teen Wolf” Goes Gay, Barbara Walters Retiring &amp; More!</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/8B7rmeYSr6M/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-tom-daley-teen-wolf-barbara-walters-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[archie comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arrow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barbara Walters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Behind the Candelabra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Rock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colton Haynes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harry Potter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Barrowman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matthew weiner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Melissa McCarthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MTV Movie Awards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new girl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pop brownies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard griffiths]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taylor swift]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teen wolf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tom daley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zac Efron]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255548</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[- Olympic hottie Tom Daley, apparently trying to asphyxiate us with cuteness, has adopted a pet piglet named Robby-Ray. - Taylor Swift will ruin the season finale of New Girl. - Even as an Archie character, Sue Sylvester is not having it. - Matthew Weiner knows you love gay art director Sal and doesn&#8217;t really [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-tom-daley-teen-wolf-barbara-walters-20130329/tom-daly-piglet/" rel="attachment wp-att-255555"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255555" alt="tom-daly-piglet" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/tom-daly-piglet.jpg" width="612" height="612" /></a></p>
<p>- Olympic hottie <strong>Tom Daley</strong>, apparently trying to asphyxiate us with cuteness, has <a href="https://twitter.com/TomDaley1994/status/317262175439839232" target="_blank">adopted a pet piglet</a> named Robby-Ray.</p>
<p>- <strong>Taylor Swift</strong> will <a href="http://insidetv.ew.com/2013/03/28/taylor-swift-new-girl-season-finale/" target="_blank">ruin the season finale</a> of <em>New Girl</em>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-tom-daley-teen-wolf-barbara-walters-20130329/glee-sue-archie/" rel="attachment wp-att-255556"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255556" style="margin: 10px;" alt="glee-sue-archie" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/glee-sue-archie-360x540.jpg" width="151" height="227" /></a>- Even as <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/donnad/exclusive-the-glee-cast-gets-their-archie-make-over" target="_blank">an <em>Archie</em> character</a>, Sue Sylvester is <em>not having it</em>.</p>
<p>- <strong>Matthew Weiner</strong> knows you love gay art director Sal and doesn&#8217;t really care &#8217;cause he&#8217;ll <a href="http://www.avclub.com/articles/matthew-weiner-knows-you-want-sal-back-on-mad-men,95733/" target="_blank">never work</a> in <em>Mad Men</em>&#8216;s town again!</p>
<p>- <em>Teen Wolf</em> will be having some <a href=" http://www.etonline.com/tv/132118_Jeff_Davis_Teen_Wolf_Season_Three_Interview/index.html" target="_blank">very hot gay teen wolf sex</a> this season that we&#8217;re bound to get a howl out of.</p>
<p>- Harry Potter&#8217;s uncle Vernon, <strong>Richard Griffiths</strong>, <a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/richard-griffiths-harry-potter-actor-dead-at-65-2013293" target="_blank">has died</a> at age 65 from complications after heart surgery.</p>
<p>- <strong>Barbara Walters</strong> is <a href="http://www.deadline.com/2013/03/barbara-walters-retirement-plan-abc/" target="_blank">reportedly retiring</a> in May 2014, but she&#8217;s been threatening to retire for the past 80 years so we&#8217;ll see if that cow actually goes out to pasture.</p>
<p>- <em>Entertainment Weekly</em> has an exclusive <a href="http://insidetv.ew.com/2013/03/28/behind-the-candelabra-trailer/" target="_blank">30-second preview</a> of <em>Behind the Candelabra</em> that&#8217;s drowning in sequined capes, hissy fits and statement rings, i.e. perfection.</p>
<p>- New couple alert! <em>Arrow</em>&#8216;s <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/lyapalater/colton-haynes-and-john-barrowman-hold-hands-at-the-airport" target="_blank"><strong>Colton Haynes</strong> and <strong>John Barrowman</strong></a>. Well, not really, but we&#8217;d seriously co-sign that Gay-December fauxmance.</p>
<p>- <strong>Melissa McCarthy</strong>, <strong>Zac Efron</strong>, <strong>Chris Rock</strong> and <a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/402716/mtv-movie-awards-guess-who-s-going-to-be-there" target="_blank">a bunch of other people</a> who have nothing better to do will present trophies at the <strong>MTV Movie Awards</strong>.</p>
<p>- And we are telling you. We&#8217;re not going until you watch this. And you-and you-AND YOU! You&#8217;re gonna love this:</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/8qoOtUMQ12k?rel=0" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=8B7rmeYSr6M:UXJP32pvj2g:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=8B7rmeYSr6M:UXJP32pvj2g:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-tom-daley-teen-wolf-barbara-walters-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-tom-daley-teen-wolf-barbara-walters-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>PHOTO: Official Renderings Of The NYC AIDS Memorial Released</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/1Jipv-iu6p8/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/photo-official-renderings-of-the-nyc-aids-memorial-released-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AIDS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AIDS Memorial Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HIV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255422</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Even as the LGBT community celebrates the national sea change happening on marriage equality, we mustn&#8217;t forget our darkest times: The final renderings for the NYC AIDS Memorial have been released by Studio a+i, the design firm creating the unique monument. The main feature for the memorial is an 18-foot steel canopy, which will frame a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255552" alt="aids_memorial_home-2" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/aids_memorial_home-2-670x356.jpg" width="566" height="300" /></div>
<p>Even as the LGBT community celebrates the national sea change happening on marriage equality, we mustn&#8217;t forget our darkest times: The final renderings for the <em><a href="http://nycaidsmemorial.org/" target="_blank">NYC AIDS Memorial</a></em> have been released by Studio a+i, the design firm creating the unique monument. The main feature for the memorial is an 18-foot steel canopy, which will frame a granite fountain and benches, as well as commemorative text on granite slabs. (The text will be curated by <em>Angels in America </em>playwright Tony Kushner and local activists, historians and artists.)</p>
<p>To bring the project to fruition, the AIDS Memorial Park Coalition has launched a capital campaign, which has already received $975,000 of a projected $4 million.</p>
<p>Ironically, the park will be located just outside the former St. Vincents Hospital, where so many early victims of the plague were treated. St. Vincent&#8217;s was closed in 2010 and is swiftly being transformed into luxury apartments.</p>
<p><em> </em>A memorial in a city where the epidemic had such an impact is a no-brainer. But is the design too sterile and unspecific? Will passersby even think of the thousands who suffered and died, who faced discrimination and hatred, when they stroll by? Or will they think its just another piece of public art.</p>
<p><strong>Play art critic in the comment section below.</strong></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255554" alt="aids_memorial_home1" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/aids_memorial_home1-670x356.jpg" width="650" height="345" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <img class="aligncenter" alt="aids_memorial_home-3" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/aids_memorial_home-3-670x356.jpg" width="650" height="345" /></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=1Jipv-iu6p8:TRHFBSWz9T0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=1Jipv-iu6p8:TRHFBSWz9T0:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/photo-official-renderings-of-the-nyc-aids-memorial-released-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/photo-official-renderings-of-the-nyc-aids-memorial-released-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Seattle Seahawks’ Chris Clemons: A Gay Player Coming Out Would Be “Selfish”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/VOU6Jv-TMgk/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/chris-clemons-gay-player-coming-out-selfish-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chris clemons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homophobia in sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seattle seahawks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tweet deck]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255537</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[News that a gay NFL player is considering coming out of the closet &#8212; unsurprisingly &#8212; isn&#8217;t sitting well with some players: namely Seattle Seahawks&#8217; defensive end Chris Clemons. Clemons took to the Twitter to express his reservations &#8212; and no he&#8217;s not a homophobe, he assured no one: Who on Gods earth is this [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/chris-clemons-gay-player-coming-out-selfish-20130329/chris-clemons/" rel="attachment wp-att-255540"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255540" style="margin: 10px;" alt="chris-clemons" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/chris-clemons.png" width="196" height="142" /></a>News that a gay NFL player is <a href="http://www.queerty.com/a-gay-nfl-player-is-strongly-considering-coming-out-in-the-next-few-months-20130326/" target="_blank">considering coming out of the closet</a> &#8212; unsurprisingly &#8212; isn&#8217;t sitting well with some players: namely Seattle Seahawks&#8217; defensive end Chris Clemons.</p>
<p>Clemons took to the Twitter to express his reservations &#8212; and <em>no</em> he&#8217;s not a homophobe, he assured no one:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>Who on Gods earth is this person saying he&#8217;s coming out of the closet in the NFL?</p>
<p>— Christopher Clemons (@chrisclemons91) <a href="https://twitter.com/chrisclemons91/status/316673438334980096">March 26, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p>One fan asked why he even cared and Clemons asserted the &#8220;logic&#8221; that the NFL is neither the time nor the place to be gay, since players had their chance before getting drafted:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/bill0004">bill0004</a> If you didn&#8217;t do it when you were in high school or college then why wait til your in the NFL? Whoever he is he didn&#8217;t just start</p>
<p>— Christopher Clemons (@chrisclemons91) <a href="https://twitter.com/chrisclemons91/status/316674124254674945">March 26, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async=""></script>Clemons later clarified that he thought it would be a rather &#8220;selfish act&#8221;:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/jack_humphreys4">jack_humphreys4</a> I&#8217;m not against anyone but I think it&#8217;s a selfish act.They just trying to make themselves bigger than the team.</p>
<p>— Christopher Clemons (@chrisclemons91) <a href="https://twitter.com/chrisclemons91/status/316676110442184704">March 26, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Then when someone inevitably accused him of homophobia, Clemons begged his pardon:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/hbonynge">hbonynge</a> No one said anything about be a homophobic.I just think something&#8217;s should be left at home.</p>
<p>— Christopher Clemons (@chrisclemons91) <a href="https://twitter.com/chrisclemons91/status/316682735584428032">March 26, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p>So Clemons is clearly only thinking about the team and not expressing his personal views on homosexuality, right? Well, <em>whatever</em>, the point is: it&#8217;s a reaction like Clemons&#8217; that prevents players from coming out in the first place and the real selfish act is denying LGBT youth a role model they can look up to.</p>
<p>Also, what does Clemons think an openly gay player will bring from his home exactly?</p>
<p>(<em>h/t</em>: <a href="http://www.cbssports.com/nfl/blog/eye-on-football/21965920/seahawks-de-chris-clemons-gay-player-coming-out-would-be-selfish-act" target="_blank"><em>CBS Sports</em></a>)</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=VOU6Jv-TMgk:6p4UmKycyTo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=VOU6Jv-TMgk:6p4UmKycyTo:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/chris-clemons-gay-player-coming-out-selfish-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/chris-clemons-gay-player-coming-out-selfish-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Singer Michelle Shocked Stages Bizarre Sit-In Protest</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/FsqJamdY3zk/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-singer-michelle-shocked-stages-bizarre-sit-in-protest-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[California]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homophobia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michelle shocked]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255530</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Michelle Shocked is singing a new tune &#8212; that of the victim. The alt-folk singer went on a homophobic tirade earlier this month which prompted mass cancellations of her U.S. tour. Since she&#8217;s got nothing but time these days, Shocked took her guitar and sense of righteous indignation to one of those canceled venues &#8212; [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/NPfktw4J1PQ?rel=0" height="480" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Michelle Shocked is singing a new tune &#8212; that of the victim. The alt-folk singer went on a <a href="http://www.queerty.com/alt-folk-singer-michelle-shocked-goes-on-homophobic-rant-tells-audience-god-hates-fags-20130318/" target="_blank">homophobic tirade</a> earlier this month which prompted <a href="http://www.queerty.com/michelle-shocked-sacked-20130320/" target="_blank">mass cancellations</a> of her U.S. tour.</p>
<p>Since she&#8217;s got nothing but time these days, Shocked took her guitar and sense of righteous indignation to one of those canceled venues &#8212; Moe&#8217;s Alley in Santa Cruz &#8212; and staged an old-fashion sit-in with her face covered and her mouth taped shut.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.santacruzsentinel.com/localnews/ci_22895145/singer-michelle-shock" target="_blank">AP reports</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>The tape across her mouth said &#8220;Silenced By Fear.&#8221; When asked a question, Shocked shook her head vigorously and strummed her guitar&#8230;She pointed to a sign inviting people to pick up a Sharpie marker and write on the white disposable safety suit she was wearing.</p></blockquote>
<p>The owner of Moe&#8217;s Alley, Bill Welch, said he&#8217;d be sending &#8220;some healing Santa Cruz energy her way.&#8221;</p>
<p>Previously, Shocked had planned to give <a href="http://www.pinknews.co.uk/2013/03/24/us-folk-singer-michelle-shocked-announces-talk-on-gay-bashing-but-not-welcome-at-proposed-venue/" target="_blank">a talk on gay bashing</a> at McCabe&#8217;s Club in Santa Monica, something McCabe&#8217;s promptly denied.</p>
<p>(<em>h/t</em>: <a href="http://www.towleroad.com/2013/03/shockedguitar.html" target="_blank"><em>Towleroad</em></a>)</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=FsqJamdY3zk:jjZll-dR-qA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=FsqJamdY3zk:jjZll-dR-qA:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-singer-michelle-shocked-stages-bizarre-sit-in-protest-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-singer-michelle-shocked-stages-bizarre-sit-in-protest-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Jon Stewart Tears Apart Conservative SCOTUS Arguments Against Gay Marriage</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/Ev7ANg0fk5s/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/jon-stewart-scotus-gay-marriage-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Antonin Scalia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jon Stewart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samuel Alito]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supreme Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Daily Show]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255515</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Between Samuel Alito claiming gay marriage is &#8220;newer than cell phones or the Internet&#8221; and Antonin Scalia alleging the &#8220;considerable disagreement&#8221; over the fitness of same-sex parents, Jon Stewart had a field gay day on last night&#8217;s The Daily Show.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://media.mtvnservices.com/embed/mgid:cms:video:thedailyshow.com:424861" height="360" width="640" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Between Samuel Alito claiming gay marriage is &#8220;newer than cell phones or the Internet&#8221; and Antonin Scalia alleging the &#8220;considerable disagreement&#8221; over the fitness of same-sex parents, Jon Stewart had a field <del>gay</del> day on last night&#8217;s <em>The Daily Show</em>.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=Ev7ANg0fk5s:-AqvCwyPi-E:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=Ev7ANg0fk5s:-AqvCwyPi-E:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/jon-stewart-scotus-gay-marriage-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/jon-stewart-scotus-gay-marriage-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>POLL: Only 2% Of Federal Employees Identify As LGBT</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/RTYv0llIdmY/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/poll-only-2-of-federal-employees-identify-as-lgbt-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255403</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[According to a poll in the government’s 2012 Employee Viewpoint Survey, only 2.2% of federal employees self-identify as gay, lesbian, bisexual or transgender. That&#8217;s less than the approximately 3.4% who did in a recent Gallup poll. For the first time, the Office of Personnel Management asked employees to answer questions about sexual orientation in the 2012 [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-255404" alt="office workers" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/office-workers-360x208.jpg" width="300" height="173" />According to a poll in the government’s 2012 <a href="http://www.fedview.opm.gov/2012files/2012_Government_Management_Report.PDF" target="_blank">Employee Viewpoint Survey</a>, only 2.2% of federal employees self-identify as gay, lesbian, bisexual or transgender. That&#8217;s less than the approximately 3.4% who did in a recent <a href="http://www.gallup.com/poll/158066/special-report-adults-identify-lgbt.aspx" target="_blank">Gallup poll</a>.</p>
<p>For the first time, the Office of Personnel Management asked employees to answer questions about sexual orientation in the 2012 survey. It is worth noting that 10.8% responded that they would prefer not to say, according to<a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/federal-eye/wp/2013/03/27/how-many-federal-workers-identify-as-lgbt/"> the <em>Washington Post</em>.</a></p>
<p>These numbers don&#8217;t exist in a vacuum: The Civil Service Commission <a href="http://govcentral.monster.com/benefits/articles/416-is-the-government-gay-friendly">didn&#8217;t lift its ban</a> on openly gay federal employees until 1975. President Clinton issued an executive order banning discrimination in granting security clearances in 1995, and outlawed anti-gay discrimination against all federal civilian staffers in 1998.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=RTYv0llIdmY:gc3ZDxOUixU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=RTYv0llIdmY:gc3ZDxOUixU:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/poll-only-2-of-federal-employees-identify-as-lgbt-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/poll-only-2-of-federal-employees-identify-as-lgbt-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Second Republican Senator Mulling Support Of Gay Marriage</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/H3DOmeGd0ug/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/sen-lisa-murkoswki-gay-marriage-support-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 13:21:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alaska]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[don young]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lisa Murkowski]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Begich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rob Portman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255514</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Alaska&#8217;s Republican Sen. Lisa Murkowski is currently &#8220;evolving&#8221; on her stance on gay marriage, which &#8212; should she reach the cro magnon phase by this weekend &#8212; would make her the second Republican Senator to support the issue after Rob Portman of Ohio &#8220;came out&#8221; two weeks ago. &#8220;I think it&#8217;s important to acknowledge that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/sen-lisa-murkoswki-gay-marriage-support-20130329/lisa_murkowski/" rel="attachment wp-att-255516"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255516" style="margin: 10px;" alt="Lisa_Murkowski" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Lisa_Murkowski-360x450.jpg" width="227" height="284" /></a>Alaska&#8217;s Republican Sen. Lisa Murkowski is currently &#8220;evolving&#8221; on her stance on gay marriage, which &#8212; should she reach the cro magnon phase by this weekend &#8212; would make her the second Republican Senator to support the issue after Rob Portman of Ohio &#8220;<a href="http://www.queerty.com/gop-senator-with-gay-son-embraces-marriage-equality-good-news-or-too-little-too-late-20130315/" target="_blank">came out</a>&#8221; two weeks ago.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think it&#8217;s important to acknowledge that there is a change afoot in this country in terms of how marriage is viewed,&#8221; Murkowski told the <a href="http://www.alaskastar.com/Alaska-Star/March-Issue-4-2013/Murkowskis-gay-marriage-views-evolving/" target="_blank"><em>Chugiak Eagle River Star</em></a>. &#8220;The term &#8216;evolving view&#8217; has been perhaps overused, but I think it is an appropriate term for me to use.&#8221;</p>
<p>Whereas Portman&#8217;s <a href="http://www.queerty.com/will-portman-opens-up-about-coming-out-20130325/" target="_blank">son&#8217;s homosexuality</a> was the impetus for his evolution on gay marriage, Murkowski cites her two young sons&#8217; relative &#8220;hipness&#8221; in her decision-making process.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;ve got two young sons who, when I ask them and their friends how they feel about gay marriage, kinda give me one of those looks like, &#8216;Gosh mom, why are you even asking that question?&#8217;&#8221;</p>
<p>Murkowski says her position may depend on what her constituents have to say since Alaska passed an amendment to its state constitution in 1998 defining marriage between one man and one woman. U.S. Sen. Mark Begich (D-AK) supports marriage equality while good ole Rep. Don &#8220;<a href="http://politicalticker.blogs.cnn.com/2013/03/29/alaska-congressman-walks-back-wetbacks/comment-page-1/" target="_blank">&#8216;Wetback&#8217; Backtrack</a>&#8221; Young opposes it.</p>
<p>&#8220;It may be that Alaska will come to revisit its position on gay marriage, and as a policy maker I am certainly reviewing that very closely,&#8221; Murkowski said. &#8220;We have so many issues in this country to focus on that worry us, that I question why there is such focus on the simple right of people to love whom they will.&#8221;</p>
<p>Well, let&#8217;s all just be thankful that Sen. Murkowski doesn&#8217;t have to pretend to care what former governor Sarah Palin has to say &#8212; if only Fox News felt the same way.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=H3DOmeGd0ug:rmT6X9lyGO0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=H3DOmeGd0ug:rmT6X9lyGO0:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/sen-lisa-murkoswki-gay-marriage-support-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/sen-lisa-murkoswki-gay-marriage-support-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Gay Soccer Player Retired Because “I Wouldn’t Have Been Able To Go Training The Next Day”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/OkqOHoHZWhY/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/robbie-rogers-on-coming-out-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay athletes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homophobia in sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IN QUOTES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openly gay athletes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robbie rogers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soccer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255506</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In football it&#8217;s obviously impossible to come out – because no-one has done it. No one. It&#8217;s crazy and sad. I thought: &#8216;Why don&#8217;t I step away and deal with this and my family and be happy?&#8217; Imagine going to training every day and being in that spotlight? It&#8217;s been a bit of a circus [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/robbie-rogers-on-coming-out-20130329/robbie-rogers/" rel="attachment wp-att-255508"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255508" style="margin: 10px;" alt="robbie-rogers" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/robbie-rogers-360x397.jpg" width="252" height="278" /></a></p>
<div class="giantquote">
<p>In football it&#8217;s obviously impossible to come out – because no-one has done it. No one. It&#8217;s crazy and sad. I thought: &#8216;Why don&#8217;t I step away and deal with this and my family and be happy?&#8217; Imagine going to training every day and being in that spotlight? It&#8217;s been a bit of a circus anyway – but that would have been crazy. And you wouldn&#8217;t have much control because clubs are pushing you in different directions.</p>
<p>&#8220;I was just fearful. I was very fearful how my team-mates were going to react. Was it going to change them? Even though I&#8217;d still be the same person would it change the way they acted towards me – when we were in the dressing room or the bus?&#8230;</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t think I would have been able to go training the next day. That would be so scary. The guys might have said, &#8216;That&#8217;s great, Robbie.&#8217; Maybe. But because no-one&#8217;s done it and because of the things I&#8217;ve heard in the dressing room I just thought: &#8216;I need to get away from this – make my announcement, find peace, go from there.&#8217;&#8221;</p>
</div>
<p>&#8211; <em>California-born 25-year-old former soccer player <strong>Robbie Rogers</strong> discusses <a href="http://www.queerty.com/uk-pro-soccer-player-comes-out-promptly-announces-retirement-20130215/" target="_blank">coming out and retiring</a> with</em> <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/mar/29/robbie-rogers-coming-out-gay" target="_blank">The Guardian</a>.<em> He describes himself in a</em> <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/29/sports/soccer/robbie-rogers-feels-free-after-revealing-he-is-gay.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=0" target="_blank">New York Times </a><em><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/29/sports/soccer/robbie-rogers-feels-free-after-revealing-he-is-gay.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=0" target="_blank">profile</a> as a Catholic and a conservative who has never even hooked up with a guy&#8230;.so free agent?</em></p>
<p><em>Photo: </em><a href="https://www.facebook.com/therobbierogers" target="_blank"><em>Facebook</em></a></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=OkqOHoHZWhY:zUaNo_0rU9U:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=OkqOHoHZWhY:zUaNo_0rU9U:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/robbie-rogers-on-coming-out-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/robbie-rogers-on-coming-out-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Urban Outfitters, Walmart And Other Brands That Want Nothing To Do With Gay Marriage</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/gLap0d92omY/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Primary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chick-fil-a]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate equality index]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exxon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HRC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Human Rights Campaign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban outfitters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wal Mart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walmart]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255483</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Everyone and their mother has been going red in the past few days in support of marriage equality, including several high-profile brands &#8212; Bud Light, Smirnoff, Absolut&#8230;we&#8217;re sensing a trend here. Others have remained silent on the issue, but a new Tumblr is forcing companies out of the closet. Brand Equality features dozens of brand [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/bud-light/" rel="attachment wp-att-255490"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255490" style="margin: 10px;" alt="bud-light" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/bud-light-360x360.jpg" width="252" height="252" /></a>Everyone and their mother has been <a href="http://www.queerty.com/12-of-the-best-red-marriage-equality-facebook-profile-pics-weve-seen-20130327/" target="_blank">going red</a> in the past few days in support of marriage equality, including several high-profile brands &#8212; Bud Light, Smirnoff, Absolut&#8230;we&#8217;re sensing a trend here.</p>
<p>Others have remained silent on the issue, but a new Tumblr is forcing companies out of the closet. <a href="http://brandequality.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Brand Equality</a> features dozens of brand logos stylized with the Human Rights Campaign&#8217;s red equal sign &#8212; giving the assumption that they support marriage equality.</p>
<p>Brands have the option to say nothing and let the assumption ride; confirm their support; or request that their logo be removed, implying that they do <em>not</em> support marriage equality.</p>
<p>A sort of &#8220;<a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/28/tumblr-brands-marriage-equality/" target="_blank">public shaming</a>,&#8221; if you will; or complete transparency, if you won&#8217;t.  However, as <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/urban-outfitters-walmart-decline-gay-marriage-push-2013-3" target="_blank">Business Insider notes</a>, it&#8217;s possible that these brands &#8220;don&#8217;t allow for their logos to be reproduced for legal, trademark or intellectual property reasons.&#8221;</p>
<p>Either way, these four brands asked to have their logos removed. Brand Equality has replaced their original comments (below) with the more equitable &#8212; &#8220;So, do these brands want to be removed? Or to replace the image sent in with a ‘neutral’ stance? Just let us know. This is all about transparency.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/exxon-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-255487"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-255487" alt="exxon" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/exxon.png" width="404" height="446" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Exxon is the <a href="http://www.dallasvoice.com/exxon-mobil-hits-lgbt-1096894.html" target="_blank">first company</a> to receive a negative score from HRC&#8217;s Corporate Equality Index, and &#8220;is <a href="http://preview.hrc.org/issues/workplace/exxon-mobil-corporation.htm" target="_blank">the only U.S. employer</a> that has ever rescinded both a non-discrimination policy covering sexual orientation and domestic partner benefits, and is the only <em>Fortune </em>10 company that does not have a non-discrimination policy covering sexual orientation.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/urban/" rel="attachment wp-att-255488"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-255488" alt="urban" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/urban.png" width="395" height="437" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Urban Outfitters <a href="http://www.queerty.com/dont-buy-here-10-companies-that-hate-the-gays-20090224/" target="_blank">briefly removed</a> &#8212; only to restock &#8211;T-shirts supporting gay marriage from its stores, and donated 100% of sales to pro-marriage equality groups. The retailer, however, most recently caused outrage with a <a href="http://www.queerty.com/outrage-after-urban-outfitters-makes-a-closet-tranny-joke-on-a-gag-card-20120319/" target="_blank">&#8220;closet tranny&#8221; card</a>. Meanwhile, president and founder Richard Hayne <a href="http://www.queerty.com/miley-cyrus-reminds-tweens-that-urban-outfitters-supports-anti-gay-anal-froth-rick-santorum-20110527/" target="_blank">infamously donated</a> $13,500 to ultra-conservative <a href="http://spreadingsantorum.com/index2.html" target="_blank">anal sex byproduct</a> Rick Santorum over the years.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/wal-mart/" rel="attachment wp-att-255489"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-255489" alt="wal-mart" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/wal-mart.png" width="394" height="446" /></a>Walmart <a href="http://www.queerty.com/wal-mart-adds-trans-protections-to-employee-policies-do-we-have-to-shop-there-now-20110929/" target="_blank">recently added</a> trans protections to its employee non-discrimination policy, however, the mega-chain has a history of rolling back the courtesy with regards to the LGBT community, including: CEO Mike Duke signing a petition in 2008 to prevent Arkansas same-sex couples from adopting; allegedly demoting an employee and forcing him to wear a yellow vest after he came out; and receiving a 40 out of a possible 100 on HRC&#8217;s Equality Index.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/chick-fil-a-6/" rel="attachment wp-att-255486"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-255486" alt="chick-fil-a" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/chick-fil-a.png" width="393" height="430" /></a></p>
<p>We think it&#8217;s pretty safe to assume that this one legitimately doesn&#8217;t want to be associated with gay marriage, no matter how many <a href="http://www.queerty.com/ca-chick-fil-a-gives-away-free-food-to-pro-marriage-equality-supporters-20130328/" target="_blank">free waffle fries</a> it shoves down your throat.</p>
<p>Whether shamed or exposed in the name of transparency, do you think these brands want to purposefully distance themselves from marriage equality? <strong>Sound off in the comments.</strong></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=gLap0d92omY:ROiGjIz34LU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=gLap0d92omY:ROiGjIz34LU:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/brands-that-dont-want-to-be-associated-with-gay-marriage-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Ali Forney Center Makes Easter Time Plea For Christians To Acknowledge Religious Intolerance</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/JI35HdhJOuE/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-ali-forney-center-makes-easter-time-plea-for-christians-to-acknowledge-religious-intolerance-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ali forney center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carl Siciliano]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religious intolerence]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255387</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Though it doesn&#8217;t get the play Christmas does, this is a very religious week: As Jews the world over continue to celebrate the holiday of Passover, Christians are gearing up for Easter. So Carl Siciliano, director of New York&#8217;s Ali Forney Center, released an essay and a set of videos calling on Christians to recognize [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/P0016Uqaou4" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Though it doesn&#8217;t get the play Christmas does, this is a very religious week: As Jews the world over continue to celebrate the holiday of Passover, Christians are gearing up for Easter.</p>
<p>So Carl Siciliano, director of New York&#8217;s Ali Forney Center, released <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/carl-siciliano/christianity-and-the-parental-rejection-of-lgbt-youth_b_2966849.html" target="_blank">an essay</a> and <a href="http://www.aliforneycenter.org/stopreligiousrejection" target="_blank">a set of videos</a> calling on Christians to recognize the anti-LGBT climate prevalent in many churches, and how it can lead to queer youth being homeless or engaging in high-risk behavior.</p>
<blockquote><p>The videos feature clients of the Ali Forney Center describing instances of physical abuse, psychological torment, and rejection they suffered in Christian households, driving them out of their own homes. Incidents described by the youths include a client being strangled by his father, a Southern Baptist minister, during a homophobic rage, and another made to stay up all night reciting biblical verses condemning homosexuality.</p></blockquote>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;Decent people do not stand by in silence when children are being abused,&#8221; says Siciliano. &#8220;We need to recognize that the condemnation of LGBT people in churches leads to the abuse and rejection of LGBT children in far too many Christian homes. As Christians commanded to love one another, we need to demand that this climate of rejection stops.&#8221;.</p>
<p>So maybe instead of painting eggs and scarfing down chocolate bunnies, you could do somehting to help LGBT youth in need? For ideas, visit <strong><a href="http://www.aliforneycenter.org/index.cfm?">the Ali Forney website</a>. </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=JI35HdhJOuE:BXmAydPT_Nk:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=JI35HdhJOuE:BXmAydPT_Nk:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-ali-forney-center-makes-easter-time-plea-for-christians-to-acknowledge-religious-intolerance-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-ali-forney-center-makes-easter-time-plea-for-christians-to-acknowledge-religious-intolerance-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Kalamazoo Restaurant Owner Apologizes For Anti-Gay Facebook Posts</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/c04xh-Jt8us/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/kalamazoo-restaurant-owner-apologizes-for-anti-gay-facebook-posts-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kalamazoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kalamazoo Gay and Lesbian Resource Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smashburger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terry henderson]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255400</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Earlier this week, Queerty reported on Terry Henderson, the owner of a Smashburger restaurant in Kalamazoo, MI, who posted hate-filled updates on Facebook attacking both same-sex marriage and gays in the Boys Scouts. Hey Starbucks, want to celebrate traditional marriage with us? I didn&#8217;t think so? &#8220;Celebrate marriage with us. We are honoring God&#8217;s design [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this week, Queerty reported on Terry Henderson, the owner of a Smashburger restaurant in Kalamazoo, MI, who posted <a href="http://www.queerty.com/kalamazoo-smashburger-owner-bashes-marriage-equality-defends-boy-scout-ban-20130327/">hate-filled updates on Facebook</a> attacking both same-sex marriage and gays in the Boys Scouts.</p>
<blockquote><p>Hey Starbucks, want to celebrate traditional marriage with us? I didn&#8217;t think so?</p>
<p>&#8220;Celebrate marriage with us. We are honoring God&#8217;s design for marriage and celebrating all who have joined together as man and wife. Click LIKE if you&#8217;ve been married 10 YEARS!&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<div id="attachment_254993" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 309px"><img class="size-full wp-image-254993 " alt="Smashburger co-owners Terry and Jean Henderson" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-26-at-7.20.35-PM.png" width="299" height="179" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Smashburger co-owners Terry and Jean Henderson</p></div>
<p>In an earlier post, Henderson also bashed efforts to end the Boy Scouts ban on openly gay members.</p>
<blockquote><p>As an Eagle Scout, I personally know of an incident involving a sexual assault on a younger boy committed by an older homosexual boy (note, I did not use the politically correct term &#8220;gay&#8221;—let the hate mail begin). The Boy Scouts as well as many other youth organizations have had their reputations smeared in the past because they unintentionally and unknowingly allowed homosexual pedophiles into their ranks&#8230;</p>
<p>I ask, do you want your boy scout (or any parent&#8217;s scout) sharing a tent with an avowed homosexual? Are you content with the idea of your scout being led on overnight camping trips by openly homosexual males?</p>
<p>If not, please vote to help the Boy Scouts of America maintain its 100 year tradition of doing its best to do its duty to God and country. Don&#8217;t worry your vote is secret, unlike mine.</p></blockquote>
<p>On Wednesday, Henderson sent us an email apologizing for his posts:</p>
<div>
<blockquote><p>“I sincerely regret the comments that I recently made on my personal Facebook page.  The comments were inappropriate and frankly un-Christian and I would like to apologize to the gay and lesbian community and all those who were offended.</p>
<p>I have taken down my Facebook page as I realize the hurtful impact my comments have had.”</p></blockquote>
</div>
<p>We&#8217;ll leave it up to you to decide if Henderson truly had a change of heart, or realized that media coverage from Queerty and other sites was hurting his bottom line. (Henderson also runs a local <a href="http://west-michigan-marketing.com/about">marketing company).</a></p>
<p>Regardless, we appreciate his reply—and that he gave a real apology, not one of those &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry if you took it that way&#8221; cop-outs.</p>
<p>You can still help the LGBT community in Michigan with a donation to the <a href="http://goo.gl/15VZb">Kalamazoo Gay and Lesbian Resource Center.</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=c04xh-Jt8us:FDzQD7lmxWY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=c04xh-Jt8us:FDzQD7lmxWY:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/kalamazoo-restaurant-owner-apologizes-for-anti-gay-facebook-posts-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/kalamazoo-restaurant-owner-apologizes-for-anti-gay-facebook-posts-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Rush Limbaugh: Gay Marriage Is Inevitable So “Get With It”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/cRglqyJviWg/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/rush-limbaugh-gay-marriage-inevitable-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill O'Reilly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rush Limbaugh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255475</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Maybe Time magazine is right since conservatives are seemingly throwing in the towel left and predominately right on the whole gay marriage thing. First Bill O&#8217;Reilly nearly gave Stephen Colbert a satirical heart attack with his ambivalent endorsement and now soft-boiled potato and Republican stalwart Rush Limbaugh has weighed in on the issue. On his [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/rush-limbaugh-left-will-normalize-pedophilia-like-it-did-gay-marriage-20130108/rush-limbaugh-radio/" rel="attachment wp-att-241703"><img class="alignright  wp-image-241703" style="margin: 10px;" alt="rush-limbaugh-radio" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/01/rush-limbaugh-radio-360x268.jpg" width="252" height="188" /></a>Maybe <em>Time</em> magazine <a href="http://www.queerty.com/time-magazine-gay-marriage-already-won-20130328/" target="_blank">is right</a> since conservatives are seemingly throwing in the towel left and predominately right on the whole gay marriage thing.</p>
<p>First Bill O&#8217;Reilly nearly gave Stephen Colbert <a href="http://www.queerty.com/watch-stephen-colbert-bill-oreilly-gay-marriage-20130328/" target="_blank">a satirical heart attack</a> with his <a href="http://www.queerty.com/watch-bill-oreilly-criticizes-bible-thumping-gay-marriage-opponents-20130328/" target="_blank">ambivalent endorsement</a> and now soft-boiled potato and Republican stalwart Rush Limbaugh has weighed in on the issue.</p>
<p>On his radio show yesterday, Limbaugh called the fight against marriage equality &#8220;lost&#8221; and that it is now &#8220;inevitable,&#8221; regardless of what the Supreme Court decides on Prop 8 and DOMA.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Limbaugh said same-sex marriage opponents are being told &#8220;the country is changing and you better get with it and understand it. The genie is not getting put back in the bottle.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;And I think that&#8217;s right,&#8221; he added. &#8220;I don&#8217;t care what this court does with this particular ruling, Proposition 8. I think the inertia is clearly moving in the direction that there is going to be gay marriage at some point nationwide.&#8221;</p>
<p>So it&#8217;s not so much an enthusiastic &#8220;gay marriage is happening!&#8221; so much as a defeated &#8220;ugh, gay marriage&#8230;FINE!&#8221;</p>
<p>Limbaugh did, however, take issue with O&#8217;Reilly &#8220;marginalizing&#8221; opponents as &#8220;Bible-thumpers,&#8221; but argues that he and his lost the battle because they <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/post-politics/wp/2013/03/28/rush-limbaugh-gay-marriage-inevitable-conservatives-lost/" target="_blank">allowed the term</a> &#8220;marriage&#8221; to be &#8220;bastardized.&#8221;</p>
<p>Despite these conservative concessions, however, the fight is far from over so don&#8217;t rest on those liberal laurels quite yet, kids. Opinion may be in our favor, but as long as there are laws on the books that discriminate against LGBT people, there&#8217;s no real victory.</p>
<p>(<em>h/t</em>: <a href="http://www.gaystarnews.com/article/rush-limbaugh-predicts-gay-marriage-will-become-legal-nationwide-us280313" target="_blank"><em>Gay Star News</em></a>)</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=cRglqyJviWg:Aa9w1SIp0rE:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=cRglqyJviWg:Aa9w1SIp0rE:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/rush-limbaugh-gay-marriage-inevitable-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/rush-limbaugh-gay-marriage-inevitable-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Willie Nelson: “I’d Never Marry A Guy I Didn’t Like”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/s-gvYGv2BIU/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/willie-nelson-id-never-marry-a-guy-i-didnt-like-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IN QUOTES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Willie Nelson]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255450</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I never thought of marriage as something only for men and women. But I&#8217;d never marry a guy I didn&#8217;t like. It&#8217;s about human rights. As humanity, we&#8217;ve come through so many problems from the beginning to here.  I guess it finally had to come around to this. This is just another situation, another problem. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="giantquote">
<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-255451" alt="willie-joint gary miller" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/willie-joint-gary-miller-360x326.jpg" width="270" height="244" />I never thought of marriage as something only for men and women. But I&#8217;d never marry a guy I didn&#8217;t like.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s about human rights. As humanity, we&#8217;ve come through so many problems from the beginning to here.  I guess it finally had to come around to this. This is just another situation, another problem. We&#8217;ll work it out and move on. We&#8217;ll look back and say it was crazy that we ever even argued about this.&#8221;</p>
</div>
<p><strong>Willie Nelson</strong>,<em> giving his opinion on same-sex marriage, in </em><a href="http://www.texasmonthly.com/story/exclusive-willie-nelson-same-sex-marriage">Texas Monthly. </a></p>
<p><em>Photo: Gary Miller</em></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=s-gvYGv2BIU:ItlKOJNREQ0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=s-gvYGv2BIU:ItlKOJNREQ0:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/willie-nelson-id-never-marry-a-guy-i-didnt-like-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/willie-nelson-id-never-marry-a-guy-i-didnt-like-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Gay Activist Attacked By Russian Neo-Nazi As City Frustrates Pride Rally</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/j6l1_Xc40mg/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/gay-activist-attacked-by-russian-neo-nazi-as-city-frustrates-pride-rally-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255384</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For well over a year, Queerty has been dinging the dingbats with our esteemed Douche of the Week award. We thought it was only fair to honor those who do right by the LGBT community. Introducing the Queerty Bad-Ass of the Week. &#160; Even as the city council was frustrating his efforts to hold a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For well over a year, Queerty has been dinging the dingbats with our esteemed <a href="http://www.queerty.com/tag/douche-of-the-week/">Douche of the Week </a>award. We thought it was only fair to honor those who do right by the LGBT community.</p>
<p>Introducing the <strong>Queerty Bad-Ass of the Week.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/8QYJEDXgpGo" height="315" width="420" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Even as the city council was frustrating his efforts to hold a Pride rally, a gay activist in the city of Syktyvkar, Russia, was brutally assaulted by a neo-Nazi activist.</p>
<p>Artem Kalinin, who was trying to get clearance to hold a Pride parade in downtown Syktyvkar on Sunday, was being interviewed by a TV station when he was assaulted by Alex Kolegov, leader of a local neo-Nazi group (above).</p>
<p><em><a href="http://www.gaystarnews.com/article/gay-activist-badly-beaten-russian-city-bans-pride260313" target="_blank">Gay Star News</a></em> reports Kalinin reported the assault to police, but that Kolegov was not arrested.</p>
<p>Brusied but not beaten, Kalinin said the rally will go on as planned. Bowing to complaints from conservatives and religious groups, Mayor Ivan Pozdeyev denied Kalinin&#8217;s request to hold the demonstration in the center of the city—instead allowing it in a less central spot. Pozdeyev has a plan to prevent future conflict: he&#8217;s asked lawmakers to draft new legislation banning future Pride rallies.</p>
<p>Sadly, this isn&#8217;t Kalinin&#8217;s brush with homophobic violence. In March 2011, <a href="http://www.msmgf.org/index.cfm/id/11/aid/3329">he was attacked</a> during the city&#8217;s Week Against Homophobia:</p>
<blockquote><p>I felt a sudden punch on my head, from which I began to lose coordination. Blood gushed out of my head, leaking on my whole neck and the collar of the jacket. We began to fight, he began to hit an unknown object all over my body as I realized later, it was a stick with an iron knob. As always, the neighbors did not hear anything and did not see the floor of my porch was covered with splashes of blood.</p>
<p>During the scuffle I was able to escape&#8230; Perhaps because of the ice-covered ground, I fell. The assailant chased me from the door of my house, made a punch in my face and head area, the stick in the hands of the assailant at the moment I have not noticed.</p>
<p>I decided to reason the attacker and turned to him with the words: &#8220;Come on, calm down &#8230;&#8221; In response, I heard a familiar: &#8220;You&#8217;re a fag, I always wanted to kill you! If you want, I&#8217;ll kill you, I don&#8217;t care&#8230; &#8220;.</p>
<p>Also from his words, I realized that he had &#8220;a friend in police, who offered us to help trace you down, they won&#8217;t charge me for this&#8221;. Of course, I realized that the attacker knows nothing about criminal charges, feeling his full impunity. I was lying on the cold snow, the guy went methodically to offend me by applying successive kicks to the body. At this point, a couple of young people were walking on the sidewalk who have done nothing to call for help or to have at least some resistance to the attacker.</p>
<p>After some time,  the police crew arrived which I called earlier. Most of all I was struck by the reaction of these employees have taken the side of my abuser. The assailant went on to explain that I was &#8220;fag, there&#8217;s no need for him to get acquainted with the guys&#8221; and then asked the law enforcement officials: &#8220;Fags are not jailed nowadays?&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So the next time you think you&#8217;re too hung over to go to Pride, remember some people are risking their safety just to affirm their very existence.</p>
<p>All together now: <strong>Good on you!</strong></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=j6l1_Xc40mg:wr0Ux0Md2UM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=j6l1_Xc40mg:wr0Ux0Md2UM:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/gay-activist-attacked-by-russian-neo-nazi-as-city-frustrates-pride-rally-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/gay-activist-attacked-by-russian-neo-nazi-as-city-frustrates-pride-rally-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>R.I.P.: Tennessee’s “Don’t Say Gay” Bill Dies (Again) In House Committee</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/CK-MD_vAAtE/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/r-i-p-tennessees-dont-say-gay-bill-dies-again-in-house-committee-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don't Say Gay Bill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[john ragan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stacy Campfield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tennessee]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255364</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Stacy Campfield can&#8217;t catch a break: The homophobic state Senator from Tennessee has been trying to force an anti-gay measure on the Legislature for five years and they just won&#8217;t bite. The latest version of the &#8220;Don&#8217;t Say Gay&#8221; bill that Campfield originated in 2008 died in a House subcommittee on Tuesday for lack of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-207880" alt="stacey campfield" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2012/06/stacey-campfield.jpg" width="317" height="220" />Stacy Campfield can&#8217;t catch a break: The homophobic state Senator from Tennessee has been trying to force an anti-gay measure on the Legislature for five years and they just won&#8217;t bite. The latest version of the &#8220;Don&#8217;t Say Gay&#8221; bill that Campfield originated in 2008 <a href="http://www.salon.com/2013/03/27/tennessee_dont_say_gay_bill_dies_again/">died in a House subcommittee on Tuesday</a> for lack of a second.</p>
<p>Originally the measure would have banned teachers and administrators from discussing homosexuality with students—enforcing only “natural human reproduction science” in kindergarten through eighth grade.</p>
<p>The bill passed the Tennessee Senate in 2011 but didn&#8217;t clear the House. A newer version of the bill, introduced in January, would have instructed educators to tell parents if a student came out in school.</p>
<p>Rep. John Ragan (R-Oak Ride) also hoped to add a amendment instructing teachers to give students a referral for a therapist if they raised “lifestyle issues” like being gay.  “I’m disappointed. I thought it was a good bill. It was about school safety,” says Ragan, who plans to reintroduce the measure in the next legislative session.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=CK-MD_vAAtE:a5EznHotppQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=CK-MD_vAAtE:a5EznHotppQ:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/r-i-p-tennessees-dont-say-gay-bill-dies-again-in-house-committee-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/r-i-p-tennessees-dont-say-gay-bill-dies-again-in-house-committee-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Give Me Body: Top 5 Fitness Tips From Underwear Models</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/o37y90OgJ_k/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/give-me-body-top-5-fitness-tips-from-underwear-models-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Underwear Expert</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slideshows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underwear expert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Underwear expert 3]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=254587</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We spend a lot of time daydreaming about underwear models&#8211;mindlessly scrolling through the separate Tumblr account we have exclusively dedicated to tracking ripped, beautiful men in their skivvies. After wiping the drool from our chins, we often wonder how on earth they do it. Is it possible that we, too, might someday look as ridiculously [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/give-me-body-top-5-fitness-tips-from-underwear-models-20130329/model-fitness-tips-image2/" rel="attachment wp-att-254602"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-254602" alt="model-fitness-tips-image2" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/model-fitness-tips-image2.jpg" width="508" height="330" /></a></p>
<p>We spend a lot of time daydreaming about underwear models&#8211;mindlessly scrolling through the separate Tumblr account we have exclusively dedicated to tracking ripped, beautiful men in their skivvies. After wiping the drool from our chins, we often wonder how on earth they do it.</p>
<p>Is it possible that we, too, might someday look as ridiculously perfect in our man-panties? Probably not, but it&#8217;s fun to try. Or at least, it&#8217;s fun to trance out looking at pictures of models working out in their underwear.</p>
<p>Our friends at <a href="http://www.underwearexpert.com/">The Underwear Expert</a> asked some of these dudes how they achieve their chiseled physiques. Check out the top five fitness tips below.</p>
<p><em>Click <a href="http://www.underwearexpert.com/underwear-model-photos/">here</a> for more  from <a href="http://www.underwearexpert.com/">The Underwear Expert</a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-254739" alt="jeremy brink" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-25-at-7.49.56-PM.png" width="449" height="501" /></p>
<p><strong>5.</strong> According to <strong>Jeremy Brink</strong>, it all starts with the right attitude:</p>
<p>“Best advice I could give in terms of working out: Always bring the highest intensity to the gym. If you don’t, there’s really no point in being there and doing a half-assed workout. Go home and come back when you’re ready to bring it.”</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.queerty.com/give-me-body-top-5-fitness-tips-from-underwear-models-20130329/model-fitness-tips-01/" rel="attachment wp-att-254599"><img class="aligncenter" alt="model-fitness-tips-01" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/model-fitness-tips-01.jpg" width="509" height="338" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>4. Mike Stalker</strong> is all about his weekly weights.</p>
<p>“In the weight room, I basically follow a body-building type program, which focuses on one muscle group a day, and I lift for about 1 1/2 hours 5-6 days a week. I also try to do ab workouts about 3 times a week. An example of my week would look like: Monday- Chest, Tuesday- Back, Wednesday- Shoulders, Thursday- Legs, and Friday- arms. Then, on either Saturday or Sunday, I will focus solely on some sort of core workout.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <a href="http://www.queerty.com/give-me-body-top-5-fitness-tips-from-underwear-models-20130329/model-fitness-tips-04/" rel="attachment wp-att-254601"><img class="aligncenter" alt="model-fitness-tips-04" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/model-fitness-tips-04.jpg" width="600" height="334" /></a></p>
<p><strong>3.</strong> Personal trainer/model <strong>Go Green</strong> swears by decline push-ups:</p>
<p>“Decline push-ups are performed by propping your feet against a wall or on top of a bench or chair. The higher your feet are placed, the more severe the decline angle, and the more significant the isolation on specific muscle fibers,&#8221; says Green. &#8220;Decline push-ups incorporate the muscle fibers in the upper portion of the pectoralis major muscle, which means more bang for your push-up buck.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" alt="davey wavey" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-25-at-8.17.08-PM.png" width="477" height="445" /></p>
<p><strong>2. Davey Wavey</strong> gets inspiration from our Commander in Chief:</p>
<p>“Did you know that Barack Obama spends one hour a day exercising? If the leader of the free world has time to hit the gym, then so do you. It’s not a matter of not having enough time to exercise.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-254598" alt="Julian-Gabriel-Photos3" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Julian-Gabriel-Photos3-360x540.jpg" width="360" height="540" /></p>
<p><strong>1. Julian Gabriel</strong> on the importance of striking the right balance:</p>
<p>&#8220;I used to use a lot of weights and I was always trying to get bigger,&#8221; explains Gabriel. &#8220;As soon as I entered the modeling world, they were like &#8216;yeah, everything’s great but you need to tone that down.&#8217; So my current gym regimen is pretty much cardio-cardio-cardio and abs-abs-abs. I look at the weights from afar and say, “hi,” but then I keep walking the other way.”</p>
<p><em><br />
Photos: Go Green, Aydin Arjomand for The Underwear Expert, Luis Rafael for The Underwear Expert Oskar Cecere, Rick Day</em></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=o37y90OgJ_k:Lr3lpLDxM38:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=o37y90OgJ_k:Lr3lpLDxM38:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/give-me-body-top-5-fitness-tips-from-underwear-models-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/give-me-body-top-5-fitness-tips-from-underwear-models-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Want To Work For Queerty? We’re Looking For A Few Good Bloggers And Editors!</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/_Plo7XuWOjs/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/want-to-write-for-queerty-were-looking-for-a-few-good-bloggers-20130329/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=208898</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Queerty, the home of gay news and entertainment with bite, is hiring! We&#8217;re looking for writers and editors with strong journalism skills, a nose for news and the ability to turn around copy fast! We’re especially interested in bloggers who can cover politics (local and global) and the entertainment beat, as well as generalists. If [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright" alt="" src="http://walyou.com/img/old-manual-typewriters-robot-art-sculptures-1.jpg" width="279" height="234" /><strong>Queerty</strong>, the home of gay news and entertainment with bite, is hiring!</p>
<p>We&#8217;re looking for writers and editors with strong journalism skills, a nose for news and the ability to turn around copy fast! We’re especially interested in bloggers who can cover politics (local and global) and the entertainment beat, as well as generalists.</p>
<p>If you’re interested, send a short cover letter, resume and up to three writing samples (links are fine) to <a href="mailto:danavery@gaycities.com">chris@gaycities.com</a>.</p>
<p><em>No attachments please! </em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Image via <a title="Jeremy Mayer" href="http://jeremymayer.com/" target="_blank">Jeremy Mayer</a></em></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=_Plo7XuWOjs:jLJChdCFvp8:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=_Plo7XuWOjs:jLJChdCFvp8:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/want-to-write-for-queerty-were-looking-for-a-few-good-bloggers-20130329/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/want-to-write-for-queerty-were-looking-for-a-few-good-bloggers-20130329/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Did The Supreme Court Arguments On DOMA Finally Make It Okay To Call Opponents Of Same-Sex Marriage Bigots?</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/c3K8a5mplfw/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/did-the-supreme-court-arguments-on-doma-finally-make-it-okay-to-call-opponents-of-same-sex-marriage-bigots-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 21:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JohnGallagher</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elena kagan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paul clement]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255418</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Up to now, in the more civilized circles of debate, folks have carefully avoided calling opponents of same-sex marriage bigots. (The other side hasn&#8217;t been quite so circumspect.) But after the arguments at the Supreme Court yesterday, it&#8217;s hard to imagine how else to characterize opposition to marriage equality. It&#8217;s pretty clear that this has [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/800px-United_states_supreme_court_building.png"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-251067" alt="" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/800px-United_states_supreme_court_building-670x437.png" width="390" height="254" /></a>Up to now, in the more civilized circles of debate, folks have carefully avoided calling opponents of same-sex marriage bigots. (The other side hasn&#8217;t been <a href="http://livewire.talkingpointsmemo.com/entry/michigan-republican-faces-calls-for-resignation-after-anti">quite so circumspect</a>.)</p>
<p>But after the arguments at the Supreme Court yesterday, it&#8217;s hard to imagine how else to characterize opposition to marriage equality. It&#8217;s pretty clear that this has been a fig leaf all along, and now that momentum is on the side of equality, the leaf is about to fall.</p>
<p>The killer moment came when Supreme Court Justice Elena Kagan (you know, the one that&#8217;s<a href="http://www.politico.com/news/stories/0510/37114.html"> not a lesbian</a>) nailed Paul Clement, who argued on behalf of House Republicans to uphold the law. Clement was droning on about the wondrous merits of DOMA to make sure we kept our laws all neat and tidy when Kagan issued a harsh reality check.</p>
<p>&#8220;Well, is what happened in 1996—and I’m going to quote from the House Report here—is that ‘Congress decided … to express moral disapproval of homosexuality,’” <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/newsdesk/2013/03/why-the-gay-marriage-fight-is-over.html#ixzz2Orritoeb">Kagan asked</a>.  Clement was at a loss for words for a moment, and then came out with this defense: “Look, we are not going to strike down a statute just because a couple of legislators may have had an improper motive.”</p>
<p>And there you have it. Opponents of marriage equality have run out of excuses. DOMA was conceived in homophobia, which even by its defender&#8217;s admission, is wrong. So what&#8217;s left? Do people really oppose marriage equality because they are concerned about 1,100 federal statutes being out of whack with what states want to do?  Or is it because marriage equality means expressing moral approval and they can&#8217;t bring themselves to do that?</p>
<p>True, a lot of folks may just react reflexively to marriage equality. But that doesn&#8217;t make their opposition any less prejudiced. At some point, it&#8217;s fair to call it as we see it. That doesn&#8217;t mean branding people, but educating them.</p>
<p>But if you can&#8217;t point out their bigotry to them, can you ever educate them in how to get rid of it?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=c3K8a5mplfw:c8ci759MFaM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=c3K8a5mplfw:c8ci759MFaM:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/did-the-supreme-court-arguments-on-doma-finally-make-it-okay-to-call-opponents-of-same-sex-marriage-bigots-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/did-the-supreme-court-arguments-on-doma-finally-make-it-okay-to-call-opponents-of-same-sex-marriage-bigots-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Prop 8 Film In The Works, Justin Bieber’s Spit Lands Him In Legal Hot Water &amp; More!</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/hv0xwWAjTCY/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-prop-8-film-justin-bieber-spit-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 17:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amanda bynes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angelina Jolie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ashley judd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brad Pitt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brangelina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dustin lance black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joseph Gordon-Levitt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justin Bieber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miley Cyrus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peabody awards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pop brownies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prop 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rob Reiner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shia LeBeouf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spring breakers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wachowski siblings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zac Efron]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255370</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[- At least Miley Cyrus is being honest with herself these days. - Louie, Girls, Southland and Doctor Who were among this year&#8217;s Peabody Awards winners. - Rob Reiner is planning on bringing Dustin Lance Black&#8216;s Prop 8 play to the big screen&#8230;just as soon as the Supreme Court issues its ruling. You hear that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-prop-8-film-justin-bieber-spit-20130328/miley-twerk-1/" rel="attachment wp-att-255385"><img class="size-full wp-image-255385 alignnone" alt="miley-twerk-1" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/miley-twerk-1.gif" width="250" height="180" /></a> <a href="http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-prop-8-film-justin-bieber-spit-20130328/miley-twerk-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-255386"><img class="size-full wp-image-255386 alignnone" alt="miley-twerk-2" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/miley-twerk-2.gif" width="250" height="180" /></a></p>
<p>- At least <strong>Miley Cyrus</strong> is being <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/lyapalater/miley-cyrus-expains-her-twerking-talents" target="_blank">honest with herself</a> these days.</p>
<p>- <em>Louie</em>, <em>Girls</em>, <em>Southland</em> and <em>Doctor Who</em> were among this year&#8217;s <a href="http://www.hitfix.com/whats-alan-watching/girls-louie-doctor-who-win-peabody-awards" target="_blank"><strong>Peabody Awards</strong> winners</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-prop-8-film-justin-bieber-spit-20130328/prop-8-play/" rel="attachment wp-att-255394"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255394" style="margin: 10px;" alt="prop-8-play" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/prop-8-play-360x232.jpg" width="252" height="162" /></a>- <strong>Rob Reiner</strong> is planning on bringing <strong>Dustin Lance Black</strong>&#8216;s <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/adambvary/the-prop-8-case-could-be-a-movie-soon" target="_blank">Prop 8 play to the big screen</a>&#8230;just as soon as the Supreme Court issues its ruling. You hear that SCOTUS, you&#8217;re holding up a Hollywood film &#8212; get to twerk!</p>
<p>- Despite wearing a wedding ban in place of the Rock of Gibraltar known as her engagement ring, <strong>Angelina Jolie</strong> <a href="http://www.dlisted.com/2013/03/28/brangie-did-not-get-married" target="_blank">denied getting married</a> to noted househusband <strong>Brad Pitt</strong>.</p>
<p>- To the disappointment of Kentuckians <del>everywhere</del> somewhere,  <strong>Ashley Judd</strong> <a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/402112/ashley-judd-says-she-won-t-run-for-senate-in-kentucky-quot-thanks-for-even-considering-me-quot" target="_blank">won&#8217;t be running</a> for the U.S. Senate on the back of the Bluegrass State.</p>
<p>- <strong>The Wachowski siblings</strong> have <a href="http://insidetv.ew.com/2013/03/27/netflix-wachowskis-sense8-series/" target="_blank">teamed with Netflix</a> on their first TV project, a sci-fi thriller called <em>Sense8</em>.</p>
<p>- Proving that he&#8217;s the bigger man &#8212; or at least <a href="http://www.queerty.com/photo-shia-labeouf-is-looking-surprisingly-ripped-20130314/" target="_blank">the more ripped man</a> &#8212; <strong>Shia LeBeouf</strong> <a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/shia-labeouf-sits-front-row-at-orphans-broadway-play-weeks-after-quitting-amid-alec-baldwin-feud-2013273" target="_blank">sat front row</a> at a preview performance of <em>Orphans</em>, the Broadway show he unceremoniously quit last month.</p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/tommywes/joseph-gordon-levitt-is-hosting-a-new-tv-show" target="_blank">Here&#8217;s your chance</a> to finally work with <strong>Joseph Gordon-Levitt</strong> on that tasteful &#8220;art film&#8221; in which you two have unsimulated sex.</p>
<p>- Charming youngster<strong> Justin Bieber</strong> spit in his neighbor&#8217;s face after partaking in some particularly douchey activities, but the L.A. County&#8217;s D.A. office takes spitting crimes <a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/28/justin-bieber-prosecutors-take-spitting-crimes-seriously/" target="_blank">very seriously</a>.</p>
<p>- <strong>Amanda Bynes</strong> apparently <a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/amanda-bynes-wanders-around-new-york-citys-times-square-with-a-shirt-over-her-face-2013273" target="_blank">thinks she&#8217;s a ghost</a>. Probably because her career is dead.</p>
<p>- <strong>Zac Efron</strong> was in <em>High School Musical</em> and <em>don&#8217;t you forget it</em>! God knows Zac <a href="http://www.gossipcop.com/zac-efron-flaunt-2013-interview-high-school-musical-disney-fame/" target="_blank">doesn&#8217;t want you to</a>.</p>
<p>- We really weren&#8217;t that on board with <em>Spring Breakers</em>, but recast with Disney princesses it&#8217;s got hit written all over it:</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.collegehumor.com/e/6879066" height="369" width="600" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=hv0xwWAjTCY:0ZNHdc6G9-8:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=hv0xwWAjTCY:0ZNHdc6G9-8:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-prop-8-film-justin-bieber-spit-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-prop-8-film-justin-bieber-spit-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Sean Penn’s Son Spews Racist, Homophobic Slurs At Paparazzo</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/5tU2WdiIu8U/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/sean-penns-son-spews-racist-homophobic-slurs-at-paparazzo-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 16:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hopper penn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paparazzi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sean Penn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TMZ]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255376</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sean Penn&#8217;s legendary difficulty with paparazzi might be genetic: His 19-year-old son, Hopper, is in hot water for losing his cool and calling an African-American photographer a n***er and a f***ot. Hopper, the son of Sean and actress Robin Wright, was walking with his Academy-Award winning father when he shoved the shutterbug and spewed a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<article><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-255377" alt="hopper penn" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-28-at-12.20.54-PM.png" width="352" height="214" />Sean Penn&#8217;s legendary difficulty with paparazzi might be genetic: His 19-year-old son, Hopper, is in hot water for losing his cool and calling an African-American photographer a n***er and a f***ot.</p>
<p>Hopper, the son of Sean and actress Robin Wright, was walking with his Academy-Award winning father when he shoved the shutterbug and spewed a stream of invective. According <a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/26/sean-penn-son-hopper-penn-fight-paparazzi-photographer-video/#ixzz2OqtasytF">to TMZ</a><a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/26/sean-penn-son-hopper-penn-fight-paparazzi-photographer-video/" target="_blank" rel="external ext-linked">,</a> police came to investigate but the photographer didn&#8217;t press charges.</p>
<p>While it doesn&#8217;t excuse his behavior, the video on TMZ reveals that the photographer was goading Hopper to some extent before the celebutard shouted  &#8220;F*** you &#8230; you&#8217;re a f***ing f***ot &#8230; shut up you f***ing n***er.&#8221;</p>
<div>Back in 1987, Sean Penn was sentenced to two months in jail for assaulting a photographer—and got probation in 2009 for another paparazzi attack.</div>
<p>At least Hopper seems to be sorry about the whole sordid incident: “I was accosted by paparazzi and made to feel like an animal &#8211; threatened and under attack, but that does not condone my own actions,” he told TMZ. &#8220;I deeply regret my choice of words.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</article>
<div></div>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=5tU2WdiIu8U:SA2tfJodRKk:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=5tU2WdiIu8U:SA2tfJodRKk:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/sean-penns-son-spews-racist-homophobic-slurs-at-paparazzo-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/sean-penns-son-spews-racist-homophobic-slurs-at-paparazzo-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Salon Rates Politicians On The Gay-Marriage Courage-Meter</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/FjZxh4R13sM/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/salons-gay-marriage-courage-meter-shows-which-politicians-are-pioneers-and-which-are-just-jumping-on-the-bandwagon-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 16:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255369</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With politicians tripping themselves to come out in support of marriage equality, its hard to keep track of who has been at the vanguard of LGBT rights and who is just trying to ride some coattails. Fortunately Salon has produced this handy Gay Marriage Courage-Meter, which shows how much bravery various representatives displayed by supporting [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a title="Graph" href="http://media.salon.com/2013/03/gay_marriage_grid_960_logo.jpg"><img class="aligncenter" title="courage-meter" alt="" src="http://media.salon.com/2013/03/gay_marriage_grid_580.jpg" width="580" height="561" /></a></p>
<p>With politicians tripping themselves to come out in support of marriage equality, its hard to keep track of who has been at the vanguard of LGBT rights and who is just trying to ride some coattails. Fortunately Salon has produced this handy <a href="http://www.salon.com/2013/03/28/salons_gay_marriage_courage_meter/">Gay Marriage Courage-Meter,</a> which shows how much bravery various representatives displayed by supporting same-sex marriage.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not simply cut along party lines: GOP stalwart Dick Cheney gets more props than former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton.  Below, Salon&#8217;s Benjamin Wheelock and Blake Zeff explain how it works:</p>
<blockquote><p>On the x-axis is timing — who was ahead of the curve, and who just came to the party this week. The y-axis represents who showed guts and risked political capital for their support. Below the courage-meter is a short legend with background on the selections.</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-255372 " title="Steve Gunderson" alt="Steve Gunderson" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-28-at-12.05.50-PM.png" width="176" height="182" /></p>
<p><strong>Former Rep. Steve Gunderson </strong>(R-Wis.)<strong> – </strong>Outed as gay on the House floor two years earlier, the lone Republican to vote against Defense of Marriage Act (1996)</p>
<p><strong>Former Sen. Chuck Robb</strong> (D-Va.) – The lone Southern senator to vote against DOMA (1996)</p>
<p><strong>Former Sen. Bob Kerrey</strong> (D-Neb.) – A red-state senator to vote against DOMA, he also supported gay marriage in his losing 2012 race for Senate (1996)</p>
<p><strong>Former Sen. Carol Moseley-Braun</strong> (D-Ill.) – An early African-American LGBT supporter, she voted against DOMA (1996)</p>
<p><strong>Sen. Barbara Boxer</strong> (D-Calif.) and <strong>Sen. Dianne Feinstein</strong> (D-Calif.) – Voted against DOMA, from a blue state but one that would later support Proposition 8 (1996); Boxer was closer to facing reelection.</p>
<p><strong>Sen. Bernie Sanders</strong> (I-Vt.) – The socialist then-congressman was fairly entrenched in his at-large House seat when he voted against DOMA (1996)</p>
<p><strong>Former Gov. Eliot Spitzer</strong> (D-N.Y.) – Running for attorney general in 1998, announced his support for marriage equality before other statewide officials in his state (1998)<strong><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-120591" title="Gavin Newsom  " alt="Gavin Newsom  " src="http://www.queerty.com/wp/docs/2010/11/gavinnews00011-450x312.jpg" width="240" height="166" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Lt. Gov. Gavin Newsom </strong>(D-Calif.) – Issued marriage licenses as mayor of San Francisco, while harboring statewide ambitions (2004)</p>
<p><strong>Former Mayor Jason West</strong> (New Paltz) – The then 26-year-old Green Party mayor issued marriage licenses despite warnings he was breaking state law and could face penalties (2004)</p>
<p><strong>Gov. Lincoln Chafee</strong> (I-R.I.) – Then a Republican senator in a liberal state, publicly opposed President Bush’s proposed constitutional amendment banning gay marriage</p>
<p><strong>Vice President Dick Cheney</strong> – Expressed support for his gay daughter’s right to marry before many others; did not publicly push ticket or party to endorse position (2004)</p>
<p><strong>Gov. Andrew Cuomo</strong> (D-N.Y.) – Supported marriage equality before some in New York, and after others; shepherded marriage equality law to passage in 2011 (2006)</p>
<p><strong>Gov. Jerry Brown </strong>(D-Calif.) – As attorney general, asked court to invalidate Proposition 8 after it was voted through by his state, said he wouldn’t defend it in court (2008)</p>
<p><strong>Steve Schmidt</strong> (GOP political strategist) – Expressed support for marriage shortly after running his party’s <img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-40693" alt="bill-clinton-photograph" src="http://www.queerty.com/wp/docs/2009/02/bill-clinton-photograph-323x400.jpg" width="187" height="231" />presidential race; has not sought public office (2009)</p>
<p><strong>Former President Bill Clinton</strong> – Endorsement of marriage law in New York came before other national figures evolved, but well after he served in office (and signed DOMA) (2011)</p>
<p><strong>State Sen. Roy McDonald</strong> (R-N.Y.) and <strong>state Sen. Steve Saland</strong> (R-N.Y.) – After voting for marriage equality, these unsung heroes – both longtime Republican legislators – would lose their next elections (2011)</p>
<p><strong>Gov. Martin O’Malley</strong> (D-Md.) – Endorsed before Obama, but shortly after potential 2016 rival Cuomo helped passed law in New York (2011)</p>
<p><strong>Vice President Joe Biden</strong> – Spoke his mind on “Meet the Press,” expediting his boss’s announcement (2011)</p>
<p><strong>President Barack Obama</strong> – The first president to endorse marriage equality, and did so during election year; however, followed his vice president, and an early-career reversal on the issue (2012)</p>
<p><strong>Sen. Harry Reid</strong> (D-Nevada) – After Obama’s announcement, a raft of Democrats followed, including the Senate majority leader (2012)</p>
<p><strong>Rep. Richard Hanna</strong> (R-N.Y.) and <strong>Rep. Ileana Ros-Lehtinen</strong> (R-Fla.) – Only two House Republicans to sign Supreme Court brief calling same-sex marriage a constitutional right (2013)</p>
<p><strong>Hillary Clinton</strong> (former secretary of state) – An open question as to when she might have suppo<strong><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-252808" title="Rob Portman" alt="Rob Portman" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/473px-Rob_Portman_official_portrait_112th_Congress-360x455.jpg" width="193" height="243" /></strong>rted it had she not been secretary of state (and abstained from certain political discussions); announcement in 2013 bore no risk (2013)</p>
<p><strong>Sen. Rob Portman</strong> (R-Ohio) – Was first GOP senator to come out for gay marriage, after his son Will came out to him (2013)</p>
<p><strong>Sen. Kay Hagan</strong> (D-N.C.) – Expressed support for gay marriage this week; represents state won by Mitt Romney and faces reelection next year (2013)</p>
<p><strong>Sen. Mark Begich</strong> (D-Alaska) – Expressed support this week; represents red state and faces reelection next year (2013)</p>
<p><strong>Sen. Jon Tester</strong> (D-Mont.) – A few months after winning reelection, expressed his support for gay marriage; represents state won by Romney (2013)</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div data-toggle-group="story-13254069">
<p><strong>You can download the <a href="http://media.salon.com/2013/03/gay_marriage_grid_download.jpg">full-size image here.</a></strong></p>
</div>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=FjZxh4R13sM:EVPg_-cwPUg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=FjZxh4R13sM:EVPg_-cwPUg:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/salons-gay-marriage-courage-meter-shows-which-politicians-are-pioneers-and-which-are-just-jumping-on-the-bandwagon-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/salons-gay-marriage-courage-meter-shows-which-politicians-are-pioneers-and-which-are-just-jumping-on-the-bandwagon-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>PHOTOS: Broadway Bares 23 Gets Patriotic With “The United Strips Of America”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/PPw46ecvI-8/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/photos-broadway-bares-23-gets-patriotic-with-the-united-strips-of-america-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 15:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bc/efa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Broadway Bares]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Broadway Cares]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photos]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255350</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every year, the AIDS benefit Broadway Bares delights with a seductive series of bawdy burlesqsue routines featuring the hottest chorus boys and girls on the Great White Way. Kinky Boots choreographer Jerry Mitchell and his team always come up with a unique theme and this year its &#8220;the United Strips of America.&#8221;  We can&#8217;t wait [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XP2MY6pzBdI" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Every year, the AIDS benefit Broadway Bares delights with a seductive series of bawdy burlesqsue routines featuring the hottest chorus boys and girls on the Great White Way. <em>Kinky Boots </em>choreographer Jerry Mitchell and his team always come up with a unique theme and this year its &#8220;the United Strips of America.&#8221;  We can&#8217;t wait to see what the &#8220;Show Me State&#8221; delivers!</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://broadwaycares.org">Broadway Bares 23</a> hits the stage on Sunday, June 23, at <a href="http://newyork.gaycities.com">New York&#8217;s Roseland Ballroom</a>.</strong></p>
<p><em>Photos: Andrew Eccles</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255353" alt="Oregon_Timothy_Hughes" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Oregon_Timothy_Hughes-502x670.jpg" width="502" height="670" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255354" alt="Texas_Jeff_Metzler" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Texas_Jeff_Metzler-502x670.jpg" width="502" height="670" /> <img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255355" alt="Maine_Peter_Nelson" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Maine_Peter_Nelson-502x670.jpg" width="502" height="670" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255356" alt="Colorado_Julius_Carter" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Colorado_Julius_Carter-662x670.jpg" width="650" height="657" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255357" alt="California_Allyson_Carr" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/California_Allyson_Carr-502x670.jpg" width="502" height="670" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255358" alt="Hawaii_Christina_Black" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Hawaii_Christina_Black-502x670.jpg" width="502" height="670" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" alt="Broadway_Bares_23_art" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/Broadway_Bares_23_art-670x426.jpg" width="650" height="413" /></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=PPw46ecvI-8:WyUhqEA4Vsk:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=PPw46ecvI-8:WyUhqEA4Vsk:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/photos-broadway-bares-23-gets-patriotic-with-the-united-strips-of-america-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/photos-broadway-bares-23-gets-patriotic-with-the-united-strips-of-america-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Stephen Colbert “Shaken To The Core” Over Bill O’Reilly’s Gay Marriage Flip-Flop</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/gvv9uAkFMQA/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-stephen-colbert-bill-oreilly-gay-marriage-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 15:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill O'Reilly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stephen Colbert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the colbert report]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255345</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Stephen Colbert joins a flabbergasted nation in his shock over Papa Bear&#8217;s flip flop &#8212; &#8220;the gayest of all beach sandals&#8221; &#8212; on same-sex marriage, which (by Bill O&#8217;Reilly&#8217;s own admission) makes him only one step away from marrying a goat.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://media.mtvnservices.com/embed/mgid:cms:video:colbertnation.com:424810" height="360" width="640" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Stephen Colbert joins a flabbergasted nation in his shock over <a href="http://www.queerty.com/watch-bill-oreilly-criticizes-bible-thumping-gay-marriage-opponents-20130328/" target="_blank">Papa Bear&#8217;s flip flop</a> &#8212; &#8220;the gayest of all beach sandals&#8221; &#8212; on same-sex marriage, which (by Bill O&#8217;Reilly&#8217;s own admission) makes him only one step away from marrying a goat.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=gvv9uAkFMQA:-erJBLspb_Q:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=gvv9uAkFMQA:-erJBLspb_Q:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-stephen-colbert-bill-oreilly-gay-marriage-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-stephen-colbert-bill-oreilly-gay-marriage-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>PHOTOS: Marriage Equality Rally In Seattle</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/9tea6enMZpA/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/photos-marriage-equality-rally-in-seattle-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 15:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slideshows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[protest haus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255319</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[PHOTOS:  As the Supreme Court heard arguments over striking down the Defense of Marriage Act on Wednesday, hundreds of LGBTs and allies rallied at the U.S. Federal Courthouse in Seattle. Speakers included demonstration organizer Marley Blonsky and Sarah Toce, editor-in-chief of The Seattle Lesbian. Photos: Steph Brusig                &#160; [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="album_header_pagelet" data-referrer="album_header_pagelet">
<div><img class="aligncenter" title="seattle marriage equality" alt="seattle marriage equality" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/seattle-marriag-equality-670x465.jpg" width="555" height="385" /></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>PHOTOS:</strong>  As the Supreme Court heard arguments over striking down the Defense of Marriage Act on Wednesday, hundreds of LGBTs and allies rallied at the U.S. Federal Courthouse in Seattle. Speakers included demonstration organizer <strong>Marley Blonsky</strong> and <strong>Sarah Toce</strong>, editor-in-chief of <a href="http://theseattlelesbian.com/" target="_blank">The Seattle Lesbian</a>.</p>
<div>
<div><em>Photos: <a href="http://www.stephbrusig.com/">Steph Brusig</a></em></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div> <img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255325" alt="734024_290302414434188_745602073_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/734024_290302414434188_745602073_n-670x433.jpg" width="650" height="420" /></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255326" alt="45194_290302124434217_657300229_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/45194_290302124434217_657300229_n-670x546.jpg" width="650" height="529" /></div>
<div></div>
<div><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255327" alt="10020_290301817767581_1340010072_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/10020_290301817767581_1340010072_n-496x670.jpg" width="496" height="670" /></div>
<div></div>
<div><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255328" alt="253744_290301804434249_942575121_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/253744_290301804434249_942575121_n-670x518.jpg" width="650" height="502" /></div>
<div></div>
<div><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255329" alt="540126_290301754434254_919465861_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/540126_290301754434254_919465861_n-670x446.jpg" width="650" height="432" /></div>
<div></div>
<div><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255330" alt="24622_290301724434257_1161926299_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/24622_290301724434257_1161926299_n-670x464.jpg" width="650" height="450" /></div>
<div></div>
<div><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255331" alt="599524_290301634434266_473005483_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/599524_290301634434266_473005483_n-446x670.jpg" width="446" height="670" /></div>
<div></div>
<div><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255332" alt="544274_290301574434272_179059070_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/544274_290301574434272_179059070_n-670x446.jpg" width="650" height="432" /></div>
<div></div>
<div><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255333" alt="541140_290301557767607_1420699431_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/541140_290301557767607_1420699431_n-431x670.jpg" width="431" height="670" /></div>
<div></div>
<div>        <img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255338" alt="403060_290301144434315_1923674960_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/403060_290301144434315_1923674960_n-482x670.jpg" width="482" height="670" /></div>
<div></div>
<div><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255339" alt="388464_290301124434317_1004521738_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/388464_290301124434317_1004521738_n-481x670.jpg" width="481" height="670" /></div>
<div></div>
<div>  <img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255341" alt="599557_290301097767653_1130271937_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/599557_290301097767653_1130271937_n-564x670.jpg" width="564" height="670" /></div>
<div></div>
<div>  <img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255343" alt="530002_290301051100991_1709369617_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/530002_290301051100991_1709369617_n-446x670.jpg" width="446" height="670" /></div>
<div></div>
<div><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255344" alt="181008_290301054434324_885138533_n" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/181008_290301054434324_885138533_n-475x670.jpg" width="475" height="670" /></div>
<div><center> </center>&nbsp;</p>
<p><center> </center></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=9tea6enMZpA:nNnmZQjPe0c:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=9tea6enMZpA:nNnmZQjPe0c:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/photos-marriage-equality-rally-in-seattle-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/photos-marriage-equality-rally-in-seattle-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Obama: It’s “Right And Fair” For Constitution To Recognize Gay Marriage</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/vwLqygGBlaY/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/obama-its-right-and-fair-for-constitution-to-recognize-gay-marriage-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 14:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Defense of Marriage Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prop 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Proposition 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supreme Court]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255312</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In a pair of interviews yesterday, President Obama reaffirmed his and his administration&#8217;s commitment to marriage equality following two Supreme Court hearings that could have widespread impact on the issue. “I never predict what the court will do,” Obama said in an interview with Univision. “But I used to teach constitutional law, and there is [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/photos-give-your-facebook-page-a-marriage-equality-makeover-20130327/equal-obama/" rel="attachment wp-att-255161"><img class=" wp-image-255161 alignright" style="margin: 10px;" alt="equal-obama" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/equal-obama.jpg" width="278" height="269" /></a>In a pair of interviews yesterday, President Obama reaffirmed his and his administration&#8217;s commitment to marriage equality following two Supreme Court hearings that could have widespread impact on the issue.</p>
<p>“I never predict what the court will do,” Obama said in <a href="http://www.pinknews.co.uk/2013/03/28/president-obama-there-is-a-strong-basis-for-equal-marriage/" target="_blank">an interview with Univision</a>. “But I used to teach constitutional law, and there is certainly a strong basis for determining that in this age, given what we now know, given the changes that have been taking place in the states around the country, same-sex couples should be treated fairly and have the same rights benefits, be able to transfer property, all the rights and recognitions that heterosexual couples do.”</p>
<p>The SCOTUS heard <a href="http://www.queerty.com/justice-kennedy-sympathetic-to-gay-marriage-but-scotus-wary-of-national-legalization-20130326/" target="_blank">arguments about the constitutionality</a> of California&#8217;s ban on same-sex marriages, Proposition 8, on Tuesday and on Wednesday, 83-year-old widow Edie Windsor had her day in court <a href="http://www.queerty.com/majority-of-supreme-court-judges-question-doma-constitutionality-20130327/" target="_blank">challenging the Defense of Marriage Act</a>.</p>
<p>Solicitor General Donald Verrilli said that, if the Supreme Court struck down DOMA, it would be “difficult” for any state to defend its ban on same-sex marriage.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think not only is it right and fair but also consistent with our Constitution to recognize same-sex couples,” Obama said in another <a href="http://firstread.nbcnews.com/_news/2013/03/27/17490783-obama-on-rights-of-gay-couples-it-is-time-for-the-justices-to-examine-this-issue?lite" target="_blank">interview with Telemundo</a>. “It doesn&#8217;t mean everybody has to agree from a religious standpoint about this issue. It does mean that it is very important for us to remember that we&#8217;re a nation where everybody is supposed to be equal before the law.”</p>
<p>The Obama administration found DOMA to be unconstitutional in February 2011 and has since refused to defend it in court, though it has enforced the law. Leading up to the Supreme Court  hearings, the White House <a href="http://www.queerty.com/white-house-files-amicus-brief-asking-scotus-to-overturn-prop-8-20130228/" target="_blank">filed amicus briefs</a> asking the court to overturn Prop 8 and DOMA.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=vwLqygGBlaY:nMcWXkgr2Ew:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=vwLqygGBlaY:nMcWXkgr2Ew:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/obama-its-right-and-fair-for-constitution-to-recognize-gay-marriage-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/obama-its-right-and-fair-for-constitution-to-recognize-gay-marriage-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Time Magazine: “Gay Marriage Already Won”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/M1D0Hxnssm4/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/time-magazine-gay-marriage-already-won-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 14:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dan Avery</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Primary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time Magazine]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255314</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As the Supreme Court considers its verdicts on the two marriage-equality cases, Time magazine devoted its cover to the issue with two covers depicting an intimate moment between same-sex couples. And yes, the couples are real: Sarah Kate Ellis-Henderson and Kristen Ellis-Henderson tied the knot in New York and are raising two children. California natives Russell [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-255315" alt="time magazine" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/time-magazine-670x446.jpg" width="549" height="365" /><br />
As the Supreme Court considers its verdicts on the two marriage-equality cases, <em>Time</em> magazine devoted its cover to the issue with two covers depicting an intimate moment between same-sex couples. And yes, the couples are real: Sarah Kate Ellis-Henderson and Kristen Ellis-Henderson tied the knot in New York and are raising two children. California natives Russell Hart and Eric LaBonte (right) are waiting for same-sex marriage to be legal to get hitched.</p>
<p>&#8220;Whatever the Supreme Court decides, it seems clear that the majority of Americans feel marriage is a civil right and that denying that right to people because of their sexual orientation is a violation of equal protection under the law,&#8221; writes managing editor Rick Stengel. &#8220;We had a long debate in our offices about this week’s cover images of two same-sex couples. Some thought they were sensationalist and too in-your-face. Others felt the images were beautiful and symbolized the love that is at the heart of the idea of marriage. I agree with the latter, and I hope you do too.&#8221;<br />
<em>Photos: Peter Hapak</em></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=M1D0Hxnssm4:TSUn17cSFRU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=M1D0Hxnssm4:TSUn17cSFRU:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/time-magazine-gay-marriage-already-won-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>55</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/time-magazine-gay-marriage-already-won-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>PHOTOS: “RuPaul’s Drag Race” Queens Explain Why They Are #UnitedForMarriage</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/xG6sdd9-tsc/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/photos-rupauls-drag-race-queens-united-for-marriage-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 14:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slideshows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alyssa edwards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BeBe Zahara Benet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drag race]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jinkx monsoon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RuPaul's Drag Race]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tyra Sanchez]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Willam]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255301</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Some of RuPaul&#8217;s Drag Race&#8216;s most fabulous queens untucked their support for marriage equality as part of the United for Marriage campaign. (h/t: NewNowNext)]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/photos-rupauls-drag-race-queens-united-for-marriage-20130328/unitedformarriage_willam-jpg/" rel="attachment wp-att-255305"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255305" alt="unitedformarriage_willam.jpg" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/unitedformarriage_willam.jpg.jpeg" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>Some of <em>RuPaul&#8217;s Drag Race</em>&#8216;s most fabulous queens untucked their support for marriage equality as part of the <a href="http://www.lighttojustice.org/" target="_blank">United for Marriage campaign</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/photos-rupauls-drag-race-queens-united-for-marriage-20130328/tyra-unitedformarriage-jpg/" rel="attachment wp-att-255306"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255306" alt="tyra-unitedformarriage.jpg" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/tyra-unitedformarriage.jpg.jpeg" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/photos-rupauls-drag-race-queens-united-for-marriage-20130328/jinkx2unitedformarriage-jpg/" rel="attachment wp-att-255304"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255304" alt="jinkx2unitedformarriage.jpg" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/jinkx2unitedformarriage.jpg.jpeg" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/photos-rupauls-drag-race-queens-united-for-marriage-20130328/bebe-unitedformarriage-jpg/" rel="attachment wp-att-255303"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255303" alt="bebe-unitedformarriage.jpg" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/bebe-unitedformarriage.jpg.jpeg" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/photos-rupauls-drag-race-queens-united-for-marriage-20130328/alyssa-unitedformarriage-jpg/" rel="attachment wp-att-255302"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-255302" alt="alyssa-unitedformarriage.jpg" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/alyssa-unitedformarriage.jpg.jpeg" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>(<em>h/t</em>: <a href="http://www.newnownext.com/rupauls-drag-race-marriage-equality-gay-marriage/03/2013/" target="_blank"><em>NewNowNext</em></a>)</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=xG6sdd9-tsc:pDDmwLIUwWs:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=xG6sdd9-tsc:pDDmwLIUwWs:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/photos-rupauls-drag-race-queens-united-for-marriage-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/photos-rupauls-drag-race-queens-united-for-marriage-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>CA Chick-fil-A Gives Away Free Food At Marriage-Equality Rally</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/d4PI9008HiA/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/ca-chick-fil-a-gives-away-free-food-to-pro-marriage-equality-supporters-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 13:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[California]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chick-fil-a]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dan cathy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255279</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The owner of a California Chick-fil-A surprised supporters at a marriage-equality rally by giving out dozens of free meal coupons. Chick-Fil-A owner Dan Cathy has repeatedly voiced his opposition to gay marriage, and the chain has continued its donations to anti-gay organizations, but Corey Braun, the owner-operator of a Rancho Cucamonga Chick-fil-A, said that despite [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.queerty.com/ca-chick-fil-a-gives-away-free-food-to-pro-marriage-equality-supporters-20130328/chick-fil-a_meal/" rel="attachment wp-att-255294"><img class="alignright  wp-image-255294" style="margin: 10px;" alt="chick-fil-a_meal" src="http://queerty-prodweb.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/docs/2013/03/chick-fil-a_meal-360x324.jpg" width="252" height="227" /></a>The owner of a California Chick-fil-A surprised supporters at a marriage-equality rally by giving out dozens of free meal coupons.</p>
<p>Chick-Fil-A owner Dan Cathy has <a href="http://www.queerty.com/chick-fil-as-dan-cathy-cant-keep-his-craw-shut-about-biblical-families-20121004/" target="_blank">repeatedly</a> voiced his opposition to gay marriage, and the chain has <a href="http://www.queerty.com/dan-cathy-confirms-chick-fil-a-still-in-the-business-of-hate-20120924/" target="_blank">continued its donations</a> to anti-gay organizations, but Corey Braun, the owner-operator of a Rancho Cucamonga Chick-fil-A, said that despite its <del>fowl</del> foul record with the LGBT community, the franchise &#8220;has never been about hate.&#8221;</p>
<p>“There were a lot of things said over the past year,” Braun told the <a href="http://www.dailybulletin.com/ci_22883421/rancho-cucamonga-chick-fil-franchise-owner-gives-away" target="_blank"><em>Daily Bulletin</em></a>. “I wanted to show that Chick-fil-A doesn’t discriminate against anybody. We serve everyone. We’re happy to serve the community and this was an opportunity to have this group come in and show them our hospitality regardless of their beliefs, sexual orientation, or whatever. ”</p>
<p>Braun conveyed his deep-fried message of love and acceptance via a microphone and speakers to the stunned activists.</p>
<p>&#8220;The crowd was very accepting, of course,&#8221; said Eden Anderson, a board member with the local LGBT rights group Equality Inland Empire. &#8220;We got quiet and we were listening, and with some skepticism. But really, what I experienced with the community, is when people are open and apologetic and accepting, it&#8217;s touching to us. It feels like acceptance and we just want to be accepted and engaged in society, so when it&#8217;s confirmed, I think the overall reaction was, yes, certainly that Chick-fil-A in Rancho Cucamonga is welcoming to us. &#8221;</p>
<p>Anderson, however, still remembers the hundreds of hungry bigots who showed up last year to the Rancho Cucamonga location for Chick-fil-A Appreciation Day after LGBT advocates called for nationwide boycotts.</p>
<p>Luckily, it seems, time &#8212; and a spicy chicken sandwich &#8212; heals all wounds.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=d4PI9008HiA:OxNLlgR8J-c:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=d4PI9008HiA:OxNLlgR8J-c:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/ca-chick-fil-a-gives-away-free-food-to-pro-marriage-equality-supporters-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/ca-chick-fil-a-gives-away-free-food-to-pro-marriage-equality-supporters-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>VIDEO: Andrew Christian Model Philip Fusco Opens Up</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/WajvjmyEyFc/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/video-andrew-christian-model-philip-fusco-opens-up-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 12:29:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Underwear Expert</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Secondary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Morning Goods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philip fusco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underwear expert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Underwear expert 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[videos]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=254617</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[WATCH: It&#8217;s hard to say what we love most about Andrew Christian model Philip Fusco. His sexy Long Island accent, laid-back charm and beefy body all seem to tie for first place. The 25-year-old straight-but-not-narrow stud visited our friends at The Underwear Expert for an exclusive Model Talk video, where he shared some interesting details. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/q4wFJprTgQU" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><strong>WATCH: </strong>It&#8217;s hard to say what we love most about Andrew Christian model Philip Fusco. His sexy Long Island accent, laid-back charm and beefy body all seem to tie for first place.</p>
<p>The 25-year-old straight-but-not-narrow stud visited our friends at <a href="http://www.underwearexpert.com/">The Underwear Expert</a> for an exclusive Model Talk video, where he shared some interesting details. Among them was the fact that he&#8217;s never watched an episode of <em>RuPaul&#8217;s</em> <em>Drag Race</em>. We&#8217;d be happy to cuddle up for a marathon viewing—in matching pairs of Andrew Christians, of course.</p>
<p>Below, Davey Wavey tries to &#8220;turn&#8221; Fusco, with entertaining results.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/1OHKCzTXXV8" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><em>Visit <a href="http://www.underwearexpert.com/">The Underwear Expert</a> for more <a href="http://www.underwearexpert.com/videos/">model videos</a>.</em></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=WajvjmyEyFc:as96GoI4FZE:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=WajvjmyEyFc:as96GoI4FZE:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/video-andrew-christian-model-philip-fusco-opens-up-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/video-andrew-christian-model-philip-fusco-opens-up-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>WATCH: Bill O’Reilly Criticizes “Bible-Thumping” Gay Marriage Opponents</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/queerty2/~3/EtRHqwwICAc/</link>
		<comments>http://www.queerty.com/watch-bill-oreilly-criticizes-bible-thumping-gay-marriage-opponents-20130328/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 12:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lester Brathwaite</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queerty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TopStory_Primary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill O'Reilly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fox News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[O'Reilly Factor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.queerty.com/?p=255283</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The devil and the damned must be sipping mugs of hot chocolate while huddled together under layers of blankets &#8217;cause it&#8217;s a frosty day in hell. Fox News&#8217; Bill O&#8217;Reilly has seemingly evolved on the issue of gay marriage, which he once compared to bestiality. On Tuesday&#8217;s O&#8217;Reilly Factor, the pugnacious pundit argued that &#8220;the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><object id="flashObj" width="640" height="480" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0" bgcolor="#FFFFFF"><param name="flashVars" value="videoId=2257275647001&amp;playerID=1409164951001&amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAAETmrZQ~,EVFEM4AKJdRjek0MS21pRzf_GTDAM-xj&amp;domain=embed&amp;dynamicStreaming=true" /><param name="base" value="http://admin.brightcove.com" /><param name="seamlesstabbing" value="false" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="swLiveConnect" value="true" /><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /><param name="src" value="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1" /><param name="flashvars" value="videoId=2257275647001&amp;playerID=1409164951001&amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAAETmrZQ~,EVFEM4AKJdRjek0MS21pRzf_GTDAM-xj&amp;domain=embed&amp;dynamicStreaming=true" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><param name="swliveconnect" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="pluginspage" value="http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash" /><embed id="flashObj" width="640" height="480" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1" flashVars="videoId=2257275647001&amp;playerID=1409164951001&amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAAETmrZQ~,EVFEM4AKJdRjek0MS21pRzf_GTDAM-xj&amp;domain=embed&amp;dynamicStreaming=true" base="http://admin.brightcove.com" seamlesstabbing="false" allowFullScreen="true" swLiveConnect="true" allowScriptAccess="always" flashvars="videoId=2257275647001&amp;playerID=1409164951001&amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAAETmrZQ~,EVFEM4AKJdRjek0MS21pRzf_GTDAM-xj&amp;domain=embed&amp;dynamicStreaming=true" allowfullscreen="true" swliveconnect="true" allowscriptaccess="always" pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" /></object></p>
<p>The devil and the damned must be sipping mugs of hot chocolate while huddled together under layers of blankets &#8217;cause it&#8217;s a frosty day in hell.</p>
<p>Fox News&#8217; Bill O&#8217;Reilly has seemingly evolved on the issue of gay marriage, which he <a href="http://mediamatters.org/research/2009/05/12/oreillys-ark-gay-marriage-could-lead-to-goat-du/150069" target="_blank">once compared</a> to bestiality. On Tuesday&#8217;s <em>O&#8217;Reilly Factor</em>, the pugnacious pundit argued that &#8220;the homosexuals&#8221; have a compelling argument for marriage equality, while all their opponents have been able to do is &#8220;thump the Bible.&#8221;</p>
<p>For O&#8217;Reilly, same-sex marriage is basically a non-issue at this point since he doesn&#8217;t feel &#8220;strongly about it one way or another.&#8221; We guess ambivalence is about the same as evolution, even though conservatives tend to believe in the former, while denying that the latter even exists.</p>
<p><em>h/t</em>: <a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2013/03/bill-oreilly-gay-marriage-89368.html" target="_blank"><em>Politico</em></a></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=EtRHqwwICAc:qKkSCUviMrQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?a=EtRHqwwICAc:qKkSCUviMrQ:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/queerty2?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.queerty.com/watch-bill-oreilly-criticizes-bible-thumping-gay-marriage-opponents-20130328/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.queerty.com/watch-bill-oreilly-criticizes-bible-thumping-gay-marriage-opponents-20130328/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.282 seconds. --><!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-30 10:51:04 --><!-- Compression = gzip -->
