<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Everyone Is Gay</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 13:50:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.2</generator>
		<item>
		<title>March 27, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-27-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-27-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 15:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3263</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Hi Kristin and Dannielle, Do you guys have any suggestions on what to write as a… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-27-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;Hi Kristin and Dannielle, Do you guys have any suggestions on what to write as a first message to girls on online dating sites? I usually try and pick something specific in their profile and ask something or comment about it (let&#8217;s be honest, it&#8217;s usually about one of their favorite tv shows), but girls hardly ever respond. I guess I&#8217;m trying to treat it as a conversation starter, but maybe that&#8217;s not the right way to go? Thanks!&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>- Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3263"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>This is SO HARD YOU GUYS. I think the absolute best suggestion I can give is BE YOUR SELF. I know it sounds stupid, but if I were to get a message that said “hey I think you’re attractive and we should meet up” I would roll my eyes and click ‘delete’ immediately. BUT HOWEVER THO, If I got a message that said “Hey I noticed you also cry while listening to Taylor Swift, so we have that in common…” I would giggle like an idiot and respond within four seconds.</p>
<p>It’s super important that you’re the same human online as you are in real life. If you message someone ‘hey sexy’ and they respond ‘letz hook up’ and then you hang out and you hide your face the whole time and giggle, it’s just GOING TO BE WEIRD. SO, be you. Be exactly the type of human you’re going to be WHILST dating someone.</p>
<p>The fact of the matter is, you wanna find someone who will like you for being nervous and uncomfortable and awkward. So, if you’re messaging someone and you say “hi, so … you like Pretty Little Liars…” and they roll their eyes and don’t respond, WHO CARES, why would you want them to respond anyway!? You know? You want the girl who will be like “LOL YEA I DO, OMG I’M SO AWKWARD AND YOU’RE AWKWARD LETS DATE.” Keep. Being. You.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>Yeah… I think my advice would be to be yourself (as touted by the lovely Dannielle Owens-Reid) and also to let things evolve slowly.</p>
<p>If I got a message from someone that was like, “Hey, I’m also in Season 4 of Buffy OMG IT’S SO INTENSE RIGHT.” I would be like “AHHHH YES HOLY SHIT.” However, if the message was, “Hey, I totally watch Buffy, too, we should get together and watch it!” I would be like… I DON’T EVEN KNOW YOU STEP OFF.</p>
<p>Do you see what I mean? Let the point of your first contact be simple, to the point, and real.</p>
<p>Also, also &#8211; dating sites are not the best way to reflect on your abilities in getting dates. I know that sounds a little weird, but like, it is VERY difficult to get a grasp of someone’s personality through just a few sentences, a list of thoughts, and some pictures. So, when you don’t get a response from people &#8211; try to remember that it doesn’t reflect negatively on you as a person. Most times it has to do with a million other factors that are impossible to know through a computer screen.</p>
<p>All we can do is put ourselves out there and be nice. You are doing everything right &#8211; just be you, give it time and space, and you will find the people who share common interests and who are in the headspace to connect.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-27-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 26, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-26-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-26-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 15:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3260</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Me and my girlfriend don&#8217;t seem to have enough TIME for sexy times. We both work… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-26-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;Me and my girlfriend don&#8217;t seem to have enough TIME for sexy times. We both work long hours, usually 6 days a week, have busy schedules, and have several other people that we have to fit into our lives. Normally by the end of the day we&#8217;re both exhausted and while the sexy sentiment&#8217;s there, we&#8217;re often too tired to do anything about it &#8211; and when we do, the lack of sleep really affects me the following day and my work suffers. But she&#8217;s super sexy and the sex is amazing! Any suggestions? Help!&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>-Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3260"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>VACATIONZZZZ!!! I mean, it sounds so silly, but take vacations together and I don’t mean anything extravagant, I just mean take one or two days every once in a while where the two of you are just TOGETHER.</p>
<p>You’re in kind of an awesome place where you absolutely want to be getting down and your boo wants to get down, but you don’t have time. So now literally all you have to do is make time! Which is so easy. I mean, I understand not being able to make time ALL THE TIME, but you have to take a day or two. OR you could just switch things around so you have a few days where you both start work later or take a half-day or something. There are so many ways to work around schedules.</p>
<p>It seems so silly to make a schedule together, but you totally should. ALSO, you could make an actual paper calendar where your sexy days have pictures of sexy things. That way it’ll be fun and also you’ll remember because the calendar on the wall will have a giant picture of boobs?</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>Sexy calendar for the win.</p>
<p>I know this is likely a more simple answer than you were after… but you just have to <em>make </em>the time. Right now you have to make time for work, and it sounds like you are making time for other people &#8211; which, like you said, is important. However, making time for sex is also important.</p>
<p>Sure, spontaneous sex is wonderful and great and awesome, and I am sure that here and there it is a thing that will still happen. What you are asking about, though, is staying intimate with your boo when your lives are super busy. That requires dedication and work, and even though spontaneous sex is totally awesome… usually planned sex only feels “planned” for the first nanosecond.</p>
<p>Twice a week, mark off a time on your calendars that works for both of you (and please use Dannielle’s suggestion of marking those calendars with boobs and stuff). Look at it like any other commitment and push forward into the land of sexy. Take it a step further and if you’ve blocked off 7pm-8pm, text her a few times during the day with some idea of things you might do…</p>
<p>I believe in you.<br />
NTSSS NTSSS NTSSS NTSSS (&lt;-sexy music beats)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-26-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 25, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-25-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-25-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3258</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;What are several good hints that can indicate that I might be a lesbian?&#8221; -Question submitted… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-25-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;What are several good hints that can indicate that I might be a lesbian?&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>-Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3258"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>1. Turn on a Tegan and Sara song.<br />
-If you went to iTunes and had trouble choosing, you are a lesbian.<br />
-If you went to YouTube and had to look up how to spell “tegan” you are not.</p>
<p>2. Answer: What is your favorite season of The L Word?<br />
-If you say, “It’s a tie between Season 3 and Season 5,” you are a lesbian.<br />
-If you say, “Oh, I’ve been meaning to watch that,” you are not.</p>
<p>3. Answer: Flannel or converse?<br />
-If you thought, “LOL you can’t have one without the other,” you are a lesbian.<br />
-If you thought, “for what?” You are not.</p>
<p>4. Whitney.<br />
-If you thought “Slice me off a piece,” you are a lesbian.<br />
-If you thought “Houston?” You are a gay man.</p>
<p>5. Answer: Do you wanna bone womenz only?<br />
-Yes? You are a lesbian.<br />
-No? You are not.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>First I’d like to take the above quiz:</p>
<p>(1) I didn’t have trouble choosing, but I knew how to spell Tegan / (2) Season Carmen. / (3) Both, always. / (4) Houston. / (5) Who knows. Probably.</p>
<p>I think this means I am a mostly-lesbian-partial-gay-man.</p>
<p>Next, I’d like to give you my one hint:</p>
<p>Say aloud: “Hi my name is {your name}, and I am a lesbian.”</p>
<p>- If you want to make out with girls and you love the way that sounds &#8211; good for you, you are a lesbian.</p>
<p>- If you love to make out with girls and you hate the way that sounds &#8211; good for you, you can be whatever you want or you can just be {your name}.</p>
<p>- If you don’t love to make out with girls, YOU SHOULD TRY HARDER.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-25-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 22, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-22-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-22-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3256</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;So, I got offered the perfect internship this summer but, if I take it, I would… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-22-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;So, I got offered the perfect internship this summer but, if I take it, I would be far away from my serious boyfriend. I&#8217;m studying abroad right now, so we&#8217;ve already been apart since November and it&#8217;s really hard for both of us. So do I choose love or career? Decisions are so hard guys!&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>-Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3256"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>You have, like, 80 years of life left and you can be in love for all of those, but this internship will happen ONCE for TWO MONTHS. I always, always, always vote career in these situations.</p>
<p>I sound like the biggest asshole, but the thing is, you want to be with someone who will support your success and who loves when you’re offered cool shit. I mean, love is love you guys and if it’s supposed to work it, it absolutely will. I have friends who were long distance for 6 years, but they made it work and now they’ve been married and in the same home for 5 years. So, IT WORKED OUT.</p>
<p>The bottom line: If you don’t take the internship ONLY because of love, you’ll end up resenting your booboo for holding you back. I didn’t go on tour with Katy Perry bc of someone I was dating and I’m STILL PISSED.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>YOU COULD HAVE GONE ON TOUR WITH KATY PERRY?!<br />
**calls Dannielle for details*</p>
<p>Personally, I do not think Dannielle sounds like an asshole at all. You take the internship. If this were something where you would be away for an exceptionally long period of time then perhaps I would say, “talk it over with your boo, weigh the pros and cons, etcetera,” but this is NOT a long period of time. I know, I know, I am aware of how long even a few days feels without the person you love &#8211; but a few months where you are doing something brilliant will fly by. Trust. Me.</p>
<p>What’s more, I have found that time away from your boo can actually be really wonderful for your relationship. Missing someone is healthy. Planning Skype dates and sending pictures of your adventures or your boobs to each other &#8211; those are fun things that don’t happen as much when you are in the same city.</p>
<p>Take the internship.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-22-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Episode 73: March 21, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/episode-73-march-21-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/episode-73-march-21-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 12:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Watch Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3243</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[1. I live with my mom and she isn&#8217;t okay with me being gay. I want… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/episode-73-march-21-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/62309283" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
<h6>1. I live with my mom and she isn&#8217;t okay with me being gay. I want to leave but then she won&#8217;t pay for my education.</h6>
<h6>2. I want to get a dove for my one month anniversary but birds aren&#8217;t allowed in dorms. What should I do?</h6>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/episode-73-march-21-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 20, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-20-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-20-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 15:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3237</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;My girlfriend talks almost exclusively about herself, and when I manage to get a word in… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-20-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;My girlfriend talks almost exclusively about herself, and when I manage to get a word in edge-wise, I sometimes feel like she&#8217;s not so interested in what I have to say. I genuinely love hearing her talk about her life and what she&#8217;s been up to, but sometimes I can&#8217;t help but feel a little upset that she doesn&#8217;t ever seem eager for me to reciprocate. How can I address this problem without making her feel bad for dominating our conversations?&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>- Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3237"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>I actually know a few people like this, and it was difficult for me to understand at first, BUT I THINK I’VE FOUND THE KEY.</p>
<p>See, the thing is, all of us humans are wired differently, and we FOR SOME REASON assume everyone is wired exactly like us. POR EJEMPLO (spanish), your gf thinks that if you want to talk about stuff you’ll just do it, the way she does. She assumes that you’ll just be like ‘HAY THIS THING OMG LOL ALL THE STUFF’ because that is what she expects. AND THEN, you’re expecting her to be a little more like you, to have a conversation where she says some stuff and then you say some stuff and then you giggle and make out.</p>
<p>HERE IS HOW YOU FIX STUFF &#8211; Prepare her before you want to talk about something. It’ll make a little switch go off in her head that says ‘listening time.’ So, instead of just saying ‘I was in class and -’ (this is normally where she cuts you off and starts talking about her class), you should say, “omg, i have a funny story to tell you” and she’ll zoom in on you to hear your story. If she gets sidetracked, a gentle reminder “but i was saying about spanish class” and she’ll be like ‘OHYEASORRY’ and you’ll continue.</p>
<p>This works for basically anything, keep in mind she DOES WANNA KNOW all the things you have to say, her brain is just like ‘if she wants to tell me she will.’ So, work together and get your stories told!</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I agree with this method HOWEVER, I think this thing happens in relationships (romantic or sexy or otherwise) where we get used to a person’s behavior and then we ANTICIPATE their behavior and a lot of times that anticipation actually winds up affecting and informing the situation. Por ejemplo (also Spanish), since you are now in a place where you assume she is going to interrupt your story you are probably getting way more upset if she does interrupt <em>and also</em> telling your story a little differently because of how you feel.</p>
<p>The reason I am saying all of this is because I think you should also talk to her about how you are feeling &#8211; and I think it is possible to do that without making her feel like poop. Don’t say, “You interrupt me all the time and you never care about what I have to say.” That isn’t nice and isn’t productive. DO say, “Hey, sometimes when we are telling each other stories I feel like I can’t get my whole story out because you are really excited about chiming in &#8211; and I was wondering if we could try something where we let each other finish our stories before we talk about something else? I love you and I love hearing about your day and telling you about mine, but lately I have just been feeling a little frustrated because it is hard for me to stay on track with a story when we jump all over the place.”</p>
<p>I think if you combine that talk with the suggestions that Dannielle gave above, you are going to see some really awesome results. If she isn’t responsive and she rolls her eyes and says, “But your stories are always boring,” then buy her an ice cream cone, drop it on the sidewalk, and tell her to get out of your life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-20-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 19, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-13-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-13-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3210</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Does it make me less of a lesbian to like strap ons? So much gay panic… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-13-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;Does it make me less of a lesbian to like strap ons? So much gay panic you guys :(&#8220;</h6>
<p><em>-Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3210"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>Ugh no.</p>
<p>I wish people would lay off this theory already! Everyone likes different things when it comes to sexi time, and none of those things exclusively determine a human’s sexuality.</p>
<p>Sit back and think of all the reasons you like having sexi time with the person you like having sexi time with, if you say to yourself “I really only like doing it with her bc she has a vagina, nothing else appeals to me” then… shit, i guess I don’t know.</p>
<p>The things you like in bed are things you like in bed, and that’s it. They don’t always mean some gigantic force of nature is working against you to change who you are and what you think about yourself. Some lesbians like to watch gay man porn, some straight dudes like having stuff in their butts, some gay guys think boobs are awesome. It’s just sex, it’s a weird natural instinct thing that makes us rub our bodies together and smash our mouths against one another. IT’S WHATEVER.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>No. No. No. No. NO.</p>
<p>If you like strap-ons it doesn’t make you less of a lesbian. If you like to wear strap-ons it doesn’t make you less of a woman or a man or less trans or genderqueer or <em>anything.</em> If you bind your boobs or get turned on by leather or only like to kiss people on their ears or wear giant belt buckles or comb your hair to the right… you can still identify how you want, when you want, for the reasons that YOU want.</p>
<p>Just because “men” might be historically known to have PENISPARTS doesn’t mean that “they” (because WHO ARE WE EVEN TALKING ABOUT) get to corner the market on things that are a certain shape and may make your parts feel good. Does that make any sense?</p>
<p>You have sex the way you want. Explore what feels good to you. You may identify as a lady who loves ladies and find out through imagination that NOTHING turns you on more than imagining that you have an <em>actual</em> penis. After you are done fantasizing about your imaginary penis you might stroll down to the nail salon in your dress and heels. None of these things have to have an absolute bearing on what you are or are not. PEOPLE ARE COMPLEX. GENDER IS CONFUSING. SEX IS GREAT. HAVE A NICE DAY.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-13-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 18, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-18-2013-2/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-18-2013-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 15:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3228</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My boyfriend told me he has hooked up with guys in the past but he is… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-18-2013-2/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>My boyfriend told me he has hooked up with guys in the past but he is straight and wants to be with me. should I believe him?</h6>
<p><em>-Question submitted by Rachel<br />
<span id="more-3228"></span><br />
</em></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>You know, I’ve been in a situation like this before. I was dating a girl who was really upset by the fact that I had hooked up with a couple of guys not too terribly long before we’d started dating.</p>
<p>On the one hand, I totally got her point, it was weird for her because she’s always assumed I was gay and I’d only ever liked girls and ALL OF A SUDDEN I was like ‘LOL I KISS BOYS’ and she felt like she kind of didn’t know me.</p>
<p>On the other hand, it was in my past. I wasn’t making out with boys in that moment and I had no interest. It made me pretty upset, to be honest, because I was with HER. I wanted to be with her and only her. Forget about all the genders of the long list of people I’ve made out with in the past, I was ONLY making out with her and that’s what should have mattered.</p>
<p>That’s what I think you should focus on, your boyfriend being with you. Who cares who he’s dated in the past? Who cares if he used to like some guys? He is with you because he wants to be with <em>you</em>, trust him.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I agree one million percent.</p>
<p>I think that there is a HUGE stigma placed on men, especially, where if they have interest in other men it seems impossible to a lot of human beings that they would have any interest in ladies as well. I am not sure exactly where that comes from, but I am a huge believer in the fact that at the end of the day we are all people with feelings and brains and hearts and emotions, and that most of us simply don’t fall in any one “category” when it comes to sexuality.</p>
<p>This is about you trusting your partner. If you feel that you can’t trust him because of factors that you haven’t shared with us, then that needs more reflection on your end. If, however, you do trust him but just think that it might not be possible for a boy to like boys and also girls, then I can help ease your worries: they can, and they do.</p>
<p>I think it is wonderful that he felt close enough to you to trust you with another part of himself, another experience in his life that meant something to him. I say, trust him, thank him for his openness, and remain open to each other’s feelings &#8211; you can tell him about some of your confusions and ask questions! Just be open to dialogue and remember that him liking boys doesn’t mean he can’t like girls. That’s just plain silly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-18-2013-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 15, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-15-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-15-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3212</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[TRIGGER WARNING: This post contains themes/mention of self-injury and recovery. &#8220;I have a lot of scars… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-15-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>TRIGGER WARNING: This post contains themes/mention of self-injury and recovery.</h6>
<h6>&#8220;I have a lot of scars on my arms due to self harming and whenever I get confident enough to wear a short sleeved T-shirt my mam points out how marked they are and completely destroys my confidence again. No-one else mentions it and now I&#8217;m stuck with what to do; do I wear short sleeved things or hide my &#8216;ugly arms&#8217; from view?&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>- Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3212"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I think you should talk to your mom about it, let her know how she’s making you feel. AND, I think you should continue to wear short-sleeved shirts.</p>
<p>The fact of the matter is, this is a part of your past. Maybe it’s not something you’re proud of, or something you care to harp on forever, but it is a part of you. NEVER let your past dictate the way you live in the present. You are who you are because of the things you’ve learned from who you used to be.</p>
<p>When people ask questions, try to answer them. It might take a while before you’re totally comfortable, but I think the more comfortable you are talking about your past, the more comfortable you will be putting on that short-sleeved shirt. Next time you put that shirt on and walk into the living room and your mom makes a comment, ask her if she wants to talk about and tell her EXACTLY how you feel. Tell her you are ashamed and self-conscious, but you’re trying to get to a place where you don’t feel that way anymore. Hopefully a conversation will help her understand you and where you’re coming from AND it’ll let her know you need her support.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I agree wholeheartedly with Dannielle, and I think that it is important to also think about <em>why</em> your mom is saying these things to you, so that it might be easier to understand her words as products of fear and confusion and not solely as harsh and hurtful judgements.</p>
<p>A lot of parents take on the responsibility for all of the feelings and experiences that their kids have… and so knowing that at a time in your life you were hurting so badly that you cut yourself may affect her in ways that she doesn’t even fully understand. She might still be stuck on the fact that she couldn’t help you enough to take away that hurt &#8211; and it might be coming out of her mouth in ways that sound unfeeling and rude… but with conversation you may be able to both get to a place of better understanding. So. Talk to her and talk to her not only about those scars, but about that time in your life. She may need to understand more to be able to forgive herself for your past experiences.</p>
<p>Insofar as your scars go, I understand that they draw a certain amount of attention and conversation, and I think it is wonderful that you are at a place where you feel comfortable enough to allow for those moments, those conversations, and that larger understanding of yourself. One of my very best friends on this earth has an arm covered with scars from her past as a cutter; those scars mark a horribly difficult time in her life that she was able to overcome. Her scars are no longer a source of shame, but rather a marker of her growth and strength. We all have stories and struggles and marks and imperfections that tell our stories. Those are the things that make us human, and that make us beautiful.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-15-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Your Stories: Kai Davis</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/your-stories-kai-davis/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/your-stories-kai-davis/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3216</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Your Stories: Temporary Hiatus Hey beans! For the next month(ISH) we are going to take a… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/your-stories-kai-davis/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/PyRn4eClJQs" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"></iframe></p>
<h6>Your Stories: Temporary Hiatus</h6>
<p>Hey beans! For the next month(ISH) we are going to take a brief pause in our Your Stories project as we gather more footage and think about the best ways to keep it moving forward.</p>
<p>However! We love, love, love featuring your stories and work and such &#8211; so we are going to continue to feature videos of youth who we think are kicking a whole sh*tton of ass in a variety of ways.</p>
<p>This week we are featuring poet Kai Davis. The above was filmed in 2011 when Kai was a senior at Central High School in Philadelphia. Her passion as expressed through her poetry is provocative, moving and inspiring. To youth out there who are afraid that their words do not hold important meaning &#8211; they do, so speak them.</p>
<p>You can find more about Kai <a href="http://locksandglasses.tumblr.com/">on her tumblr.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/your-stories-kai-davis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
