<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Everyone Is Gay</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 13:50:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.2</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Episode 73: March 21, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/episode-73-march-21-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/episode-73-march-21-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 12:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Watch Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3243</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[1. I live with my mom and she isn&#8217;t okay with me being gay. I want… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/episode-73-march-21-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/62309283" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
<h6>1. I live with my mom and she isn&#8217;t okay with me being gay. I want to leave but then she won&#8217;t pay for my education.</h6>
<h6>2. I want to get a dove for my one month anniversary but birds aren&#8217;t allowed in dorms. What should I do?</h6>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/episode-73-march-21-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 20, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-20-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-20-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 15:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3237</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;My girlfriend talks almost exclusively about herself, and when I manage to get a word in… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-20-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;My girlfriend talks almost exclusively about herself, and when I manage to get a word in edge-wise, I sometimes feel like she&#8217;s not so interested in what I have to say. I genuinely love hearing her talk about her life and what she&#8217;s been up to, but sometimes I can&#8217;t help but feel a little upset that she doesn&#8217;t ever seem eager for me to reciprocate. How can I address this problem without making her feel bad for dominating our conversations?&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>- Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3237"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>I actually know a few people like this, and it was difficult for me to understand at first, BUT I THINK I’VE FOUND THE KEY.</p>
<p>See, the thing is, all of us humans are wired differently, and we FOR SOME REASON assume everyone is wired exactly like us. POR EJEMPLO (spanish), your gf thinks that if you want to talk about stuff you’ll just do it, the way she does. She assumes that you’ll just be like ‘HAY THIS THING OMG LOL ALL THE STUFF’ because that is what she expects. AND THEN, you’re expecting her to be a little more like you, to have a conversation where she says some stuff and then you say some stuff and then you giggle and make out.</p>
<p>HERE IS HOW YOU FIX STUFF &#8211; Prepare her before you want to talk about something. It’ll make a little switch go off in her head that says ‘listening time.’ So, instead of just saying ‘I was in class and -’ (this is normally where she cuts you off and starts talking about her class), you should say, “omg, i have a funny story to tell you” and she’ll zoom in on you to hear your story. If she gets sidetracked, a gentle reminder “but i was saying about spanish class” and she’ll be like ‘OHYEASORRY’ and you’ll continue.</p>
<p>This works for basically anything, keep in mind she DOES WANNA KNOW all the things you have to say, her brain is just like ‘if she wants to tell me she will.’ So, work together and get your stories told!</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I agree with this method HOWEVER, I think this thing happens in relationships (romantic or sexy or otherwise) where we get used to a person’s behavior and then we ANTICIPATE their behavior and a lot of times that anticipation actually winds up affecting and informing the situation. Por ejemplo (also Spanish), since you are now in a place where you assume she is going to interrupt your story you are probably getting way more upset if she does interrupt <em>and also</em> telling your story a little differently because of how you feel.</p>
<p>The reason I am saying all of this is because I think you should also talk to her about how you are feeling &#8211; and I think it is possible to do that without making her feel like poop. Don’t say, “You interrupt me all the time and you never care about what I have to say.” That isn’t nice and isn’t productive. DO say, “Hey, sometimes when we are telling each other stories I feel like I can’t get my whole story out because you are really excited about chiming in &#8211; and I was wondering if we could try something where we let each other finish our stories before we talk about something else? I love you and I love hearing about your day and telling you about mine, but lately I have just been feeling a little frustrated because it is hard for me to stay on track with a story when we jump all over the place.”</p>
<p>I think if you combine that talk with the suggestions that Dannielle gave above, you are going to see some really awesome results. If she isn’t responsive and she rolls her eyes and says, “But your stories are always boring,” then buy her an ice cream cone, drop it on the sidewalk, and tell her to get out of your life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-20-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 19, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-13-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-13-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3210</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Does it make me less of a lesbian to like strap ons? So much gay panic… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-13-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;Does it make me less of a lesbian to like strap ons? So much gay panic you guys <img src='http://www.everyoneisgay.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif' alt=':(' class='wp-smiley' /> &#8220;</h6>
<p><em>-Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3210"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>Ugh no.</p>
<p>I wish people would lay off this theory already! Everyone likes different things when it comes to sexi time, and none of those things exclusively determine a human’s sexuality.</p>
<p>Sit back and think of all the reasons you like having sexi time with the person you like having sexi time with, if you say to yourself “I really only like doing it with her bc she has a vagina, nothing else appeals to me” then… shit, i guess I don’t know.</p>
<p>The things you like in bed are things you like in bed, and that’s it. They don’t always mean some gigantic force of nature is working against you to change who you are and what you think about yourself. Some lesbians like to watch gay man porn, some straight dudes like having stuff in their butts, some gay guys think boobs are awesome. It’s just sex, it’s a weird natural instinct thing that makes us rub our bodies together and smash our mouths against one another. IT’S WHATEVER.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>No. No. No. No. NO.</p>
<p>If you like strap-ons it doesn’t make you less of a lesbian. If you like to wear strap-ons it doesn’t make you less of a woman or a man or less trans or genderqueer or <em>anything.</em> If you bind your boobs or get turned on by leather or only like to kiss people on their ears or wear giant belt buckles or comb your hair to the right… you can still identify how you want, when you want, for the reasons that YOU want.</p>
<p>Just because “men” might be historically known to have PENISPARTS doesn’t mean that “they” (because WHO ARE WE EVEN TALKING ABOUT) get to corner the market on things that are a certain shape and may make your parts feel good. Does that make any sense?</p>
<p>You have sex the way you want. Explore what feels good to you. You may identify as a lady who loves ladies and find out through imagination that NOTHING turns you on more than imagining that you have an <em>actual</em> penis. After you are done fantasizing about your imaginary penis you might stroll down to the nail salon in your dress and heels. None of these things have to have an absolute bearing on what you are or are not. PEOPLE ARE COMPLEX. GENDER IS CONFUSING. SEX IS GREAT. HAVE A NICE DAY.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-13-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 18, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-18-2013-2/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-18-2013-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 15:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3228</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My boyfriend told me he has hooked up with guys in the past but he is… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-18-2013-2/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>My boyfriend told me he has hooked up with guys in the past but he is straight and wants to be with me. should I believe him?</h6>
<p><em>-Question submitted by Rachel<br />
<span id="more-3228"></span><br />
</em></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>You know, I’ve been in a situation like this before. I was dating a girl who was really upset by the fact that I had hooked up with a couple of guys not too terribly long before we’d started dating.</p>
<p>On the one hand, I totally got her point, it was weird for her because she’s always assumed I was gay and I’d only ever liked girls and ALL OF A SUDDEN I was like ‘LOL I KISS BOYS’ and she felt like she kind of didn’t know me.</p>
<p>On the other hand, it was in my past. I wasn’t making out with boys in that moment and I had no interest. It made me pretty upset, to be honest, because I was with HER. I wanted to be with her and only her. Forget about all the genders of the long list of people I’ve made out with in the past, I was ONLY making out with her and that’s what should have mattered.</p>
<p>That’s what I think you should focus on, your boyfriend being with you. Who cares who he’s dated in the past? Who cares if he used to like some guys? He is with you because he wants to be with <em>you</em>, trust him.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I agree one million percent.</p>
<p>I think that there is a HUGE stigma placed on men, especially, where if they have interest in other men it seems impossible to a lot of human beings that they would have any interest in ladies as well. I am not sure exactly where that comes from, but I am a huge believer in the fact that at the end of the day we are all people with feelings and brains and hearts and emotions, and that most of us simply don’t fall in any one “category” when it comes to sexuality.</p>
<p>This is about you trusting your partner. If you feel that you can’t trust him because of factors that you haven’t shared with us, then that needs more reflection on your end. If, however, you do trust him but just think that it might not be possible for a boy to like boys and also girls, then I can help ease your worries: they can, and they do.</p>
<p>I think it is wonderful that he felt close enough to you to trust you with another part of himself, another experience in his life that meant something to him. I say, trust him, thank him for his openness, and remain open to each other’s feelings &#8211; you can tell him about some of your confusions and ask questions! Just be open to dialogue and remember that him liking boys doesn’t mean he can’t like girls. That’s just plain silly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-18-2013-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 15, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-15-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-15-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3212</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[TRIGGER WARNING: This post contains themes/mention of self-injury and recovery. &#8220;I have a lot of scars… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-15-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>TRIGGER WARNING: This post contains themes/mention of self-injury and recovery.</h6>
<h6>&#8220;I have a lot of scars on my arms due to self harming and whenever I get confident enough to wear a short sleeved T-shirt my mam points out how marked they are and completely destroys my confidence again. No-one else mentions it and now I&#8217;m stuck with what to do; do I wear short sleeved things or hide my &#8216;ugly arms&#8217; from view?&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>- Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3212"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I think you should talk to your mom about it, let her know how she’s making you feel. AND, I think you should continue to wear short-sleeved shirts.</p>
<p>The fact of the matter is, this is a part of your past. Maybe it’s not something you’re proud of, or something you care to harp on forever, but it is a part of you. NEVER let your past dictate the way you live in the present. You are who you are because of the things you’ve learned from who you used to be.</p>
<p>When people ask questions, try to answer them. It might take a while before you’re totally comfortable, but I think the more comfortable you are talking about your past, the more comfortable you will be putting on that short-sleeved shirt. Next time you put that shirt on and walk into the living room and your mom makes a comment, ask her if she wants to talk about and tell her EXACTLY how you feel. Tell her you are ashamed and self-conscious, but you’re trying to get to a place where you don’t feel that way anymore. Hopefully a conversation will help her understand you and where you’re coming from AND it’ll let her know you need her support.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I agree wholeheartedly with Dannielle, and I think that it is important to also think about <em>why</em> your mom is saying these things to you, so that it might be easier to understand her words as products of fear and confusion and not solely as harsh and hurtful judgements.</p>
<p>A lot of parents take on the responsibility for all of the feelings and experiences that their kids have… and so knowing that at a time in your life you were hurting so badly that you cut yourself may affect her in ways that she doesn’t even fully understand. She might still be stuck on the fact that she couldn’t help you enough to take away that hurt &#8211; and it might be coming out of her mouth in ways that sound unfeeling and rude… but with conversation you may be able to both get to a place of better understanding. So. Talk to her and talk to her not only about those scars, but about that time in your life. She may need to understand more to be able to forgive herself for your past experiences.</p>
<p>Insofar as your scars go, I understand that they draw a certain amount of attention and conversation, and I think it is wonderful that you are at a place where you feel comfortable enough to allow for those moments, those conversations, and that larger understanding of yourself. One of my very best friends on this earth has an arm covered with scars from her past as a cutter; those scars mark a horribly difficult time in her life that she was able to overcome. Her scars are no longer a source of shame, but rather a marker of her growth and strength. We all have stories and struggles and marks and imperfections that tell our stories. Those are the things that make us human, and that make us beautiful.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-15-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Your Stories: Kai Davis</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/your-stories-kai-davis/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/your-stories-kai-davis/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3216</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Your Stories: Temporary Hiatus Hey beans! For the next month(ISH) we are going to take a… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/your-stories-kai-davis/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/PyRn4eClJQs" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"></iframe></p>
<h6>Your Stories: Temporary Hiatus</h6>
<p>Hey beans! For the next month(ISH) we are going to take a brief pause in our Your Stories project as we gather more footage and think about the best ways to keep it moving forward.</p>
<p>However! We love, love, love featuring your stories and work and such &#8211; so we are going to continue to feature videos of youth who we think are kicking a whole sh*tton of ass in a variety of ways.</p>
<p>This week we are featuring poet Kai Davis. The above was filmed in 2011 when Kai was a senior at Central High School in Philadelphia. Her passion as expressed through her poetry is provocative, moving and inspiring. To youth out there who are afraid that their words do not hold important meaning &#8211; they do, so speak them.</p>
<p>You can find more about Kai <a href="http://locksandglasses.tumblr.com/">on her tumblr.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/your-stories-kai-davis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 13, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-13-2013-2/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-13-2013-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 14:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3224</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think I have a problem. When my girlfriend holds me, she strokes my hair and… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-13-2013-2/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>I think I have a problem. When my girlfriend holds me, she strokes my hair and says things like &#8220;my pretty girl&#8230;&#8221; Which was kind of sweet until I caught her cuddling with her cat and saying the same thing. I mean, am I like a pet to her? Should I be nervous?</h6>
<p><em>- Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3224"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>That is some serious Wizard of Oz wicked witch shit and you need to GET OUT ASAP.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I think you should start scratching the back of the couch and peeing in the litter box. See if it has a positive or negative impact on your relationship and then reassess.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-13-2013-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 12, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-12-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-12-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3208</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I had a friend over and she said something was &#8220;for homos&#8221; while one of my… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-12-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;I had a friend over and she said something was &#8220;for homos&#8221; while one of my roommates, who might be gay, was within hearing distance without us realizing at the time. Neither of us has anything against gay people and I knew she was using the phrase in a completely sarcastic way, so I didn&#8217;t think to call her out on it. But now I&#8217;m worried my potentially gay roommate thinks I&#8217;m a homophobic idiot and won&#8217;t ever come out, esp since we live in a pretty homophobic place. Am I overthinking this?&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>-Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3208"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>I think… If I were you, I’d go up to her and say VERY QUICKLY, “hey, listen, my friend said ‘for homos’ the other day and now I’m terrified that you think we’re homophobic idiots and like, I don’t know your life and maybe your bff is gay or your brother or your mom or whatever and I just, I don’t want you to think that because that’s not true and we love everyone and she was just kidding slash being dumb and you probably didn’t even hear it, but I’ve been obsessing about it and I even asked everyoneisgay.com what to do bc i was so stressed out and so now i’m just blurting out my feelings i’m sorry, i’m not hateful, i swear”</p>
<p>… I dunno if that’ll work, but like, at least your feelings will be out there and you won’t feel like your roomie is uncomfortable anymore, you know? You might feel like she thinks you’re completely weird, but WHO ISN’T COMPLETELY WEIRD, YOU KNOW?</p>
<p>Generally, people aren’t offended if you apologize for something that doesn’t apply to them. Does that make sense? If the tables were turned and your roomie’s friend made a gay joke, you would feel 1000x better if she apologized, even tho you aren’t gay… you know? There are no limits when it comes to being respectful to those around you. You’re doing great.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>Ohhhhhh sarcasm, you tricky little devil, you.</p>
<p>I think this question brings to light the trouble with words and phrases. Saying something is “for homos” is funny to some people whether they or gay or straight or bi or trans or pan or asexual or WHATEVER, without necessarily being an indicator of how they feel when they aren’t trying to make someone laugh. Their brain is like, this is what I know I mean, but this is why I think it is a funny play on words, and then sometimes the brains of other people are like ‘oh hahahaha i know what you mean,’ and everything goes according to plan. The problem, though, is that not everyone is going to agree with their sarcasm, not everyone is going to GET their sarcasm, and some people are going to be truly insulted by what they THINK was meant, or by the fact that NO MATTER WHAT THEY MEANT YOU SHOULDN’T JOKE AROUND WITH A WORD LIKE HOMO.</p>
<p>Do you get what I mean? We all approach these things differently, so I want to just caution all y’all: generally, jokes including words or phrases like homo or gay or {insert other hot button words here} are best left unsaid unless you are with your BFF and you know they know you and you know they will get the MANY LAYERS of your comedy and not understand or misunderstand it as one-dimensional.</p>
<p>Jesus. I am trying so hard to communicate my feelings without pissing you guys off.</p>
<p>SO THAT ALL SAID: 1) Talk to your friend about being more cautious with those kinds of phrases, regardless of her intent. 2) It doesn’t matter the sexuality of your roommate. All you have to do is own the fact that your friend said something that might be offensive to ANYONE. Talking to them is the best move &#8211; just a quick simple apology that your friend was tossing around insensitive words is perfect and will communicate the message clearly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-12-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 11, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-11-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-11-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 15:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3196</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;How am I supposed to &#8216;get over&#8217; something? I feel like I can never control my… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-11-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;How am I supposed to &#8216;get over&#8217; something? I feel like I can never control my emotions and reactions well enough, whenever something upsets me. I cry too easily. I wish so desperately that I didn&#8217;t always worry about stupid things.&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>- Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3196"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says:</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">You know, there are some days where you could say anything awful to me and I would roll my eyes and continue listening to my ultimate TaylorSwift / Kelly Clarkson / Demi Lovato playlist. THEN THERE ARE DAYS where someone makes one snide comment on our post and I burst into tears and feel totally worthless. On those days, NOTHING can help me. No matter how much I remind myself that other people are stupid and I’m the best, I just keep crying. </span></p>
<p>Now, this is not a long-term ‘getting over’ thing, but I want to AT THE VERY LEAST show you that you are not alone and we all feel too many emotions sometimes. I don’t think you’re wrong or weird or that it’s bad.</p>
<p>Me, personally, tho.. I do a lot of pros/cons slash solution lists in my head, like, ‘here are the reasons this makes me feel bad, here are ways it can be fixed, here are the people I need to talk to less bc they make me feel like shit.’ I’m absurdly honest with myself and I talk A LOT. I think that all helps. I really don’t think it’s about ‘getting over’ something, it’s about letting go of that control and realizing sometimes we all have to get through the worst, so we can become the strong individuals we are deep down. You know? You have absolutely no control over how you feel, but you do control what you do about those feelings. Making the right choices and being respectful to YOURSELF will make you feel better. When I say respect yourself, I mean don’t beat yourself up about feeling things. You have to be willing to let those feelings happen, to forgive yourself and to work to a place where you can actually get over them.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>This is basically my life, most days. I am a human that has strengths that can overpower humans in some areas, but who has what seems to be no armor at all protecting this heart of mine.</p>
<p>I cry many times a week. I take things personally. I feel overwhelmed. I am sensitive.</p>
<p>My way of “getting over” things is through a long and often tearful journey through my feelings. It sounds like you take similar journeys. I need you to know that crying and feeling &#8211; even when it is more than the ‘average’ human &#8211; is still a valid way to process your feelings, which is a means of “getting over” something.</p>
<p>Dannielle is right, though, that phrase “getting over” falls very short of the reality of our feelings. When something happens that affects us emotionally, we have to pick it up, turn it over in our hands, examine why it hurts and how that hurt feels, and understand it. We might need to write about it, or talk to a friend, or meditate, or pray, or take a walk around the block.</p>
<p>The more you begin to understand yourself, the easier this gets. I used to cry when someone looked at me the wrong way, but as I grew (and you will grow, too) I explored and learned about myself and my weaknesses. Now I have the tools to say to myself, “Kristin, that person who glared at you might be having a bad day. You do good things. You are a good person. People understand you and know that you are smart and caring. It’s okay.”</p>
<p>Work to understand the things that hurt you. Cry, but explore through those tears. Give yourself time to better understand you. Remind yourself that you are good and kind even if someone misunderstands that. Feelings are really tricky and we are always, forever working. That is also where all the beauty is… in the work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-11-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 8, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-8-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-8-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3191</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I work at a library, and this really cute girl comes in every so often, and… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-8-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;I work at a library, and this really cute girl comes in every so often, and last time I saw her, she was wearing one of your &#8220;make the yuletide gay&#8221; hats. Is it inappropriate to give her my number while I&#8217;m at work?&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>-Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3191"></span></p>
<h2><strong>News Memo:</strong></h2>
<p>Dear readers,</p>
<p>If anyone you have a crush on watches/reads Everyone Is Gay… ask them out. ASK. THEM. OUT.</p>
<p>Literally say &#8220;hey Kristin and Dannielle would punch me in the throat if I didn’t ask you out, so you in?”</p>
<p>You’re welcome for the dates,</p>
<p>Dannielle &amp; Kristin</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/march-8-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
