<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Everyone Is Gay</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 14:31:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.2</generator>
		<item>
		<title>April 15, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-15-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-15-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 14:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3316</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Ok, so. My girlfriend is totally hot. She has the perfect body and the perfect boobs… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-15-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;Ok, so. My girlfriend is totally hot. She has the perfect body and the perfect boobs and i&#8217;m just like, blehhhhh. Is it weird that im kind of jealous of her?! And how do i stop this feeling and just enjoy her body instead of envy it?&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>- Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3316"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>What an AWESOME PROBLEM TO HAVE.</p>
<p>“Hi i’m anonymous and my girlfriend is super hot and i love her body, HEEEELLLLP”</p>
<p>K, I’m done making fun of you.</p>
<p>I think you should talk more out loud about all the things you love about your girlf. AAAANNND talk to her about the parts of your body she loves. BECAUSE HERE IS THE THING, you’re jealous that her body is perfect for you, but your body is probably also perfect for her. Does that make sense? She loves your thighs, your back dimples, your stomach, your clavicle, etc. and you’re not even thinking about how awesome those parts of you are, because you’re too busy loving every part of her.</p>
<p>Look at yourself, appreciate yourself, love yourself. We are all so perfect in our own little ways. BTW if you do have this conversation with her, and the two of you talk about all the things you love about one another’s bodies… YOU WILL FEEL SO GREAT ABOUT YOU… aaaaaand you’ll probably end up making out AND STUFF.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>Hear, hear.</p>
<p>I think that you should absolutely have those above conversations, and I think that your girlfriend’s image of you is crucial to understanding how beautiful you truly are —- but I also think that you should think more about why you are unhappy with your own body.</p>
<p>If you just love the way her waist bends and the way her boobs boob, then you are viewing specific parts of her body’s form which you can’t necessarily achieve for yourself (because you have your own waist bends and your boobs boob in their own unique way), but if you are like, “Man, her waist is a little flatter than mine and I like that,” or “I wish my thighs were a little more firm,” then this might also be about you wanting to start exercising or eating better or becoming more active so that you can feel <em>healthier</em> instead of aiming to look “as good as” your boo.</p>
<p>Does that make sense?</p>
<p>If this is about how your curves and bends make you appealing to her &#8211; then all you need to do is express those feelings you have and use conversation (and making out) to help you build on that confidence for yourself. If you think that part of that jealousy is coming from you wanting to be more motivated in the path toward being healthy &#8211; then this is a combination approach: talk to her about your feelings, and also make positive changes in your own life (and perhaps you can make them together!) so that you begin to also feel more centered for yourself.</p>
<p>Tadaaaaa.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-15-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>April 12, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-12-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-12-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 15:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3310</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I&#8217;ve never had a relationship last this long &#8211; how is it supposed to feel when… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-12-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;I&#8217;ve never had a relationship last this long &#8211; how is it supposed to feel when that initial honeymoon everythingisawesomeandyouaretotallyflawless phase wears off?&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>- Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3310"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I think it feels different for every human? I’ve only made it past the honeymoon phase, like, once in my entire life. I haven’t had many relationships make it past 6 or 7 months, TO BE HONEST.</p>
<p>For me, the one time I got past the honeymoon phase, it didn’t really stop. Sure, things were more routine, we got in a few fights, things were a little more serious, etc. BUT I would still be like ‘omg you’re so cute’ and I would think she was a funny little idiot and I wanted to hear about her day and I wanted to giggle and I loved seeing movies and none of that ever went away.</p>
<p>I think your feelings become deeper and they mean something more, but I don’t think the honeymoon feelings are every supposed to go away? Maybe I’m wrong, but technically it’s an opinion so I CAN’T BE WRONG. BOOM.</p>
<p>Your feelings will mean different things. Instead of thinking your boo is perfect, you love her because of her imperfections. Instead of thinking she does nothing wrong, you talk through the mistakes you’ve both made and come to a compromise that makes you both happy. Instead of going out to dinner, you start to love when she cooks for you. Instead of her watching the shows you love, you watch the stupid shows she loves. Things change, but it’s for the better. The honeymoon phase is over, but everything is still the greatest.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I agree and I think that a lot of people have an opinion of what is “supposed to happen” after the initial falling-in-love-and-getting-googly-eyed part of a relationship is over. A lot of us think it’s okay if some of the magic goes away or if we don’t keep up with date nights or if we start to talk less about our feelings or the love notes taper, etc…</p>
<p>I whole-heartedly disagree.</p>
<p>I think that as the honeymoon stage wears off, a relationship definitely requires more work and more attention &#8211; but I think that those feelings of overwhelming love should remain, and I also think that every effort should remain to keep the little (but huge) elements of care and love present.</p>
<p>What <em>should</em> it feel like? I don’t know how to answer that since we all process things differently, but I can tell you what it has felt like for me and you can take from it what you will. For me, it feels like a love that is so much more nuanced and so much deeper than an initial honeymoon phase, but with those elements of EEEEILOVEYOU woven in to the overall picture. It feels like something that is fragile in places that need care, and strong as hell in the places that keep us together. It feels like a journey that is filled with certainty, though also peppered with doubts and confusions that comes with life’s ups and downs.</p>
<p>It feels good to wake up together and good to go to sleep together and good to make breakfast together and good to buy new shoes together, and sometimes you cry and maybe sometimes you yell… but the overall and underlying feeling should be wonderful, challenging, and ever-changing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-12-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>April 10, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-10-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-10-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 15:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3308</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I do this thing where I date people and make them really happy but then one… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-10-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;I do this thing where I date people and make them really happy but then one day I get bored and walk away. Its not out of malice but I keep on leaving people heartbroken after being treated so well for no better reason than I got bored. I feel like such a shitty person because of this but I don&#8217;t know what to do to change it. HELP?!&#8221;</h6>
<p>- Question submitted by <a href="http://fluffy-noodle.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">fluffynoodle</a></p>
<p><span id="more-3308"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>It’s so weird because my instinct is to let you know you’re not a jerk and you can’t help how you feel. I mean, what are you supposed to do?? You can’t fake feelings and you can’t continue a relationship wherein you’re not happy!</p>
<p>I think, if I were you, I’d be as honest as possible. We all know there’s a point in a new relationship where you talk about past relationships. WHEN THAT MOMENT COMES, BE HONEST. Instead of saying ‘yea it just didn’t work out,’ tell the truth. Your feelings faded and you have no idea why, things weren’t fun and exciting anymore, you didn’t see yourself with the person and it seemed unfair to continue dating.</p>
<p>In some cases, people will be like, “wait, you got bored and gave up” and then they’ll make judgements about you based on your past. Anytime someone makes a judgement about you based on something in the past, things don’t turn out well. In other cases, people will be like, “that’s happened to me before, here’s to hoping we’re not one of THOSE couples” and then you’ll giggle and make out and maybe that relationship will last a lot longer than you thought.</p>
<p>If you’re totally over a relationship and you’re being kind and thoughtful, you’re doing all the right things. If you’re at the beginning of a relationship and you’re being totally honest, you’re also doing all the right things.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I think there might be a little more going on here than just “all of a sudden getting bored.” I mean &#8211; if you had this happen once, then I would have different advice… but you are explaining this as a pattern that continues to happen, so I think that this warrants some self-reflection.</p>
<p>I agree with Dannielle’s advice on what to do when you are <em>in </em>that situation &#8211; be honest, be honest, be honest.</p>
<p>However, what kind of factors lead you into those relationships in the first place? Are you considering the things that you like and want in a relationship when you first enter into one? Are you more concerned with having SOMEBODY to snuggle / makeout / etc with and so therefore putting a little less focus on the longterm things that keep love going? What, exactly, <em>makes</em> you feel bored? Is it the conversations? The sex? The attraction? All of it?</p>
<p>Here’s something to notice: When you described your relationships you said you always “make them really happy,” but… you didn’t say anything about <em>you</em> being happy.</p>
<p>I know that you don’t often turn to an advice site to get asked more questions… so I apologize. However, this is a situation that is bigger than simply being honest with others &#8211; this is a situation where you should challenge yourself to be honest with… yourself. Reflect on things. Journal at the start, the middle, and the end of your next relationship. Pay attention to the specifics and start to really pull them apart.</p>
<p>Relationships are an incredible way to get insight into some of the things happening in your brain and heart and head. Be honest. Be kind. Reflect. Work. You will figure it out and things will become a lot clearer and easier to navigate over time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-10-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>April 9, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-9-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-9-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3305</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Is it really okay to be bi? I almost feel like it&#8217;s cheating :(&#8220; - Question… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-9-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;Is it really okay to be bi? I almost feel like it&#8217;s cheating :(&#8220;</h6>
<p><em>- Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3305"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>Everyoneisbi.com</p>
<p>Ugh… that does not look cute, but you guys, WHATEVER. I would like to, on behalf of the entire community, apologize to you. I am so sorry that ANYONE ON EARTH has made you feel like being who you are is anything less than perfect. I am sorry that people in YOUR OWN community, have made you feel like you must ‘choose.’ I am sorry that the very world which tells you to accept everyone, has made you feel completely unaccepted.</p>
<p>You, my dear friend, are not cheating on anything. You’re not cheating the gays, you’re not cheating the straighties. You’re not cheating.</p>
<p>You’re literally just recognizing a piece of yourself. I think that’s awesome. If anyone looks you in the eye and says something negative about the way you identify, give them a good solid punch in the throat and say it’s from me. ******</p>
<p>You are perfect. You are bi. You are going to fall in love with the greatest human.</p>
<p>******everyoneisgay.com doesn’t want you to punch people.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>Cheating on what?<br />
You know?!</p>
<p>People like people like people like PEOPLE. It’s like… just because I happen to bone ladies and have exclusively mashed mouths with ladies for the past howevermany years doesn’t mean that I don’t think some boys are SUPER FINE, and doesn’t mean that if presented with the right opportunity I wouldn’t have mashed my mouth on another boy’s mouth. So what even makes me gay and not bi or pan or {insert newest term used to describe something that I might be}? Me thinking some boys are cute doesn’t mean that I am any less attracted to ladies. You liking whoever you like doesn’t make you any less of anything.</p>
<p>You aren’t cheating. You are saying that you are attracted &#8211; romantically, sexually, or otherwise &#8211; to various human beings and that those attractions are not solely dependent on one form of gender presentation. You are being honest with yourself and with others about those attractions. You have decided that those attractions align you with the identity known as “bisexual.” You are a real person. Your feelings are real and valid and fucking amazing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-9-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>April 8, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-8-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-8-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3294</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;What should I wear to prom if I reallllyyyy don&#8217;t want to wear a dress?&#8221; -Question… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-8-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;What should I wear to prom if I reallllyyyy don&#8217;t want to wear a dress?&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>-Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3294"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says:</strong></h2>
<p>HI I AM YOUR PROM EXPERT, DANNIELLE, NICE TO MEET YOU.</p>
<p>I think you should wear a nice pair of pants, a fitted button-up, a nice vest OR BLAZER DEPENDING ON WHERE YOU LIVE, a good pair of shoes and a bow tie.</p>
<p>Now, if the bow tie is overboard, go without! You want to feel confident. There are some outfits SLASH clothing items that I really want to wear, but I just can’t because I feel dumb and, YOU GUYS, if you feel dumb, you won’t have a good time and you’ll hate all of the pictures. SO MAKE SURE YOU FEEL GOOD. Wear bright colors and fun ties and just FEEL AWESOME.</p>
<p>Prom is a fancy night, so you want to get in the fancy mood with some fancy clothes (but you guys spending 500$ is a tiny bit silly). Find diff pieces at diff stores. Sign up for email lists so you know when stuff is on sale. Don’t go overboard, get stuff you’ll wear again!</p>
<p>Suggested shops: J Crew Factory, Top Shop, ASOS, THRIFT STORES.</p>
<p>Try to match these looks!! <a href="http://www.x17online.com/zac_efron/Zac_GQ_Cover.jpg" target="_blank">PICTURE ONE</a>, <a href="http://www.thefollowfashion.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/jcrew-spring-summer-2013-1-630x486.jpeg" target="_blank">PICTURE TWO</a>, <a href="http://i702.photobucket.com/albums/ww30/theurbangent/0915016c.jpg" target="_blank">PICTURE THREE</a>,<a href="http://www.ifiwereaguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/jcrew-men.jpg" target="_blank">PICTURE FOUR</a>, <a href="http://images0.chictopia.com/photos/Akudosochim/5537862730/velvet-topman-shoes.jpg" target="_blank">PICTURE FIVE</a></p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I very much feel that Dannielle has advised you properly along your prom non-dress hunt, and so in lieu of further advice I would like to contribute a few pictures of what I would look like as your prom date in some of the above suggested outfits.</p>
<p>You are welcome in advance.</p>
<p><img src="http://media.tumblr.com/a5f3b522e5c296b4e981d29b77fdebc4/tumblr_inline_mkx2eapvjr1qz4rgp.jpg" alt="image" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img src="http://media.tumblr.com/e96f0f5dcf9c9a5f1a53b4a9cbcd409f/tumblr_inline_mkx2etyTkV1qz4rgp.jpg" alt="image" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img src="http://media.tumblr.com/1a100898b61a8f4fcac43531555e3784/tumblr_inline_mkx2f3No7o1qz4rgp.jpg" alt="image" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-8-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>April 5, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-5-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-5-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 15:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3283</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I feel like I&#8217;m always saying no when my friends ask me to go on road… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-5-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;I feel like I&#8217;m always saying no when my friends ask me to go on road trips with them, but I can&#8217;t stand long car rides. They bond and come back closer than I am with them. Should I go on trips with them even though I don&#8217;t really feel like it, just to be a good friend?&#8221;</h6>
<p>-Question submitted by <a href="http://knifefullofknots.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">knifefullofknots</a></p>
<p><span id="more-3283"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>I have two very different answers for this question. My first reaction was NO, you shouldn’t have to do something you hate just to hang out with your friends. I haaaate bars and going out to drink, etc. THEREFORE, I don’t do it, I instead plan other events. I’ll reach out to all my friends and be like “ladies night? dinner and a movie” and they’re almost always like ‘OMG YES’ because we are friends who love each other. Your friends want to hang out with you, they don’t ONLY want to do the things they like, you know?</p>
<p>My second answer has to do with loving your friends and doing whatever they want because you know you’ll get to spend time with them. I’ve been in quite a few situations where my friends are like ‘BAR THE BAR LETS BAR THE BAR’ and I roll my eyes, but I go anyway because I love them so much. What happens, EVERY TIME, WITHOUT FAIL…I have a blast. We get there and it’s horrible and it’s loud and it smells and I hate it. BUT THEN after they get their drinks and we find a place to sit, we end up talking for HOURS, we make stupid jokes and laugh and learn things about one another and leave giggling so hard.</p>
<p>So, this is totally up to you. I would NEVER tell you to do something you hate, but you might have fun. AND, If you’re like ‘nope never’ just be sure to plan a few extra friend times so your friends know how much you want to hang out with them AND SO you don’t feel left out.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I am going to elaborate a little on the “go on getcha some car ride fun” option, because I think there might be a little you can do to try this out one more time. You hate long car rides, fine. Understandable. You don’t want to go on trips. That is your prerogative, and totally fair. HOWEVER, I think that you should try going on one adventure with them <em>without </em>thinking to yourself, “I am going to totally hate this.”</p>
<p>I am not trying to challenge your knowledge of yourself, but I do know that sometimes &#8211; when we allow for it &#8211; life surprises us. The next time they plan a trip, go with them and tell yourself, “You know what, self? We are going to just try this out and see what happens and like THE WORST THING that could happen is I’m not thrilled but it’s a few days and there’s a chance that I’ll laugh so much that I will forget I am in the car.” See what happens!! If you do, in fact, have a blast &#8211; THEN GREAT. If you feel yourself getting edgy, just take a deep breath and be patient with the experience.</p>
<p>If you do discover that you just cannot have fun on trips, then perhaps you can find a way to feel more included. Set up a night when they return where each person recounts their favorite story and re-enact it to see what would have happened if you were there. Skype with them from a different city and when they show you the seashells they collected you can show them your cat sleeping on your pillow. Remember that they want you there, so even if you aren’t present for the making of <em>all</em> the memories, you can certainly still be a part of the experience itself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-5-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Episode 74: April 4, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/episode-74-april-4-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/episode-74-april-4-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 13:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Watch Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3292</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[1. I&#8217;m not as &#8220;out&#8221; as my girlfriend, and it bothers her. What do I do?… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/episode-74-april-4-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/63205882" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
<h6> 1. I&#8217;m not as &#8220;out&#8221; as my girlfriend, and it bothers her. What do I do?</h6>
<h6>2. I am over my ex&#8230; but I can&#8217;t stop having dreams about her. Help!</h6>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/episode-74-april-4-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>April 3, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-3-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-3-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 15:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3281</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;What am I supposed to do when I don&#8217;t even know what I&#8217;m feeling? Ever. I&#8217;ve… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-3-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;What am I supposed to do when I don&#8217;t even know what I&#8217;m feeling? Ever. I&#8217;ve tried writing, but I don&#8217;t even know how to start.&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>-Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3281"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>omg. You are literally me. I have so many journal entries with phrases like “I guess I don’t really feel anything, but that’s the situation” OR “Everyone is making it seem like I should be super emotional right now, but I’m just not” … And I think that’s okay? I guess, I don’t know. I just have always been this way, stuff doesn’t affect me the same way it affects others?!</p>
<p>I’ve been in a situation where someone will say or do something and a friend will ask, “aren’t you so pissed?!” and I will literally be like, “No, I mean, I don’t really care…” and everyone thinks I’m so weird. But I DON’T THINK I AM, I think i just dont get mad/sad/whatever as easily as some people.</p>
<p>HOWEVER, I do think about my experiences and write about them. Regardless of the emotion that comes along with it, writing down what is going on in your life can still be wonderful and peaceful and helpful in figuring out who you are as you grow into the human you will be for the rest of your life. I suggest you continue to write, don’t over think it, just treat your journal like an old friend, say what’s going on in your life and if you feel something SO BE IT, feel it, write it, analyze it, but if you don’t, who cares?! Just keep swimming*</p>
<p>*writing</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>I have to agree on the whole “just keep swimming / writing” part of Dannielle’s advice —- I think that the first part of this is just to stop expecting your writing to be any one thing. Your writing could be a list of facts or events or dates or feelings or thoughts or anything you want it to be, and I think that in allowing it to take any shape it wants you will also find that you get more out of the experience.</p>
<p>Insofar as not quite knowing what you are feeling, well that is a huge part of being a human. I am not sure how old you are, but I can tell you that my progression with feelings has been something like this:</p>
<p>12 &#8211; 17: I AM YELLING I AM CRYING THAT IS SO FUNNY SHUT UP WHY AM I CRYING WHO NEEDS SLEEP SHUT UP MOM DOOR SLAM HAHAHAHAHA CRYING AGAIN LIFE IS AWESOME EVERYTHING IS WHEEEEEEE</p>
<p>17 &#8211; 29: I have a lot of thoughts and a lot of feelings and let’s make out okay sure let’s make out again ugh life is so complicated and confusing now I am crying but I am also thinking and writing and hahahahahahaha who needs a job anyway ughhhhhh i need money i hate everything everything is unfair but life is so beautiful i wonder who i am.</p>
<p>30 &#8211; 32: Oh, well shit. I think I know why I get so upset about this thing and why this bothers me so now I can connect those things sometimes but UGH OMG EVERYTHING IS TOO MUCH AND OVERWHELMING AND I DON’T UNDERSTAND ANYMORE AND WHY IS ohhhhhhh right, that thing happened and so then the other thing happened and that’s why I got overwhelmed. I should save money for the future. Buffy the Vampire Slayer is the best.</p>
<p>What that all means is, as you grow you start to learn and understand more about your feelings and develop a greater appreciation for 90s television. It is okay if you are confused and overwhelmed by your feelings and not quite understanding them… that happens to all of us, and the best thing that you can do is just be aware of yourself and allow that confusion alongside all of the other experiences.</p>
<p>You are already paying attention to what is happening in your brain and heart, and that is the best thing you could ever do. Not unlocking it all is okay. Be patient, and enjoy the ride.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-3-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>April 2, 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-2-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-2-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Read Us]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3279</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I think when people cheat it’s selfish to tell the person they cheated on. If you… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-2-2013/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>&#8220;I think when people cheat it’s selfish to tell the person they cheated on. If you want to stay with them isn’t it just better to shut up and not hurt them?&#8221;</h6>
<p><em>-Question submitted by Anonymous</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3279"></span></p>
<h2><strong>Dannielle Says: </strong></h2>
<p>I think the act of cheating is selfish. Besides, aren’t most cheaters found out anyway?</p>
<p>I mean, really, not telling the person is just kind of cowardly. If you want to be in a relationship with someone, don’t cheat on them. Period. There is no “cheat on them, but don’t say anything” rule because cheating isn’t a thing that should happen in the first place. If you <em>want</em> to be in a relationship with someone and they want to be in a relationship with you, you build a trust that you hope will not be broken. Cheating breaks that trust and lying about it breaks that trust even further.</p>
<p>HOWEVER, if you do cheat on someone, the only way the two of you will be able to work through that is if you tell them. The action was bad, yes, but lying about it is worse. There are second chances in life, people can work through things, but NONE of that is possible if you’re not being honest. Talk about it, be open, admit your mistakes, try to work together. Lying never solves problems, communication does.</p>
<h2><strong>Kristin Says:</strong></h2>
<p>A. GREE.</p>
<p>I certainly do not think it is selfish to be honest with your partner about a mistake that you’ve made. I think the reason that people generally <em>don’t </em>tell their partner about cheating is because they don’t want to lose their relationship… and that, in my opinion, is the selfish act.</p>
<p>I understand that what you are trying to communicate is, “If I know it meant nothing and I know they won’t understand, then why put them through all of the hurt when it won’t happen again,” but… honestly, f**k that. You mess up, you own it. Sure, they might not understand, sure you might lose a relationship or have some serious issues to work through because of those actions &#8211; but if a person goes so far as to <em>take </em>those actions, they need to own them and be honest.</p>
<p>Let me tell you what: if you cheat on a person and you are super upset about it and it was a one time thing and you messed up and you will never do it again and you TALK to your partner, you might lose them, but you might also be able to work through it. If you cheat on a person and never tell them and some day, down the line, they find out… then you aren’t just a cheater. You’re a liar, too.</p>
<p>Short answer: No, it’s not selfish. If you cheat, you own up to that. End of story.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/april-2-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spring Tour Dates!</title>
		<link>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/spring-tour-dates/</link>
		<comments>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/spring-tour-dates/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 14:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>everyoneisgay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.everyoneisgay.com/?p=3285</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[WE ARE COMIN&#8217; AT YOU, GAYBEANS! Six states in two weeks! Virginia! Pennsylvania! Massachusetts! Conneticut! New York! Idaho!… <a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/spring-tour-dates/">Read More &#187;</a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/omgtour.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3286" title="omgtour" src="http://www.everyoneisgay.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/omgtour-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a></strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">
<p><strong>WE ARE COMIN&#8217; AT YOU, GAYBEANS!<br />
</strong><strong style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">Six states in two weeks!<br />
</strong><strong style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">Virginia! Pennsylvania! Massachusetts! Conneticut! New York! </strong><strong style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">Idaho!<br />
</strong><strong style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;">AAAAAHHHHHHH!!!</strong></p>
<p>Wednesday, April 3: <a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/402652166499803/" target="_blank">Virginia Tech, Roanoake, VA</a></p>
<p>Saturday, April 6: <a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/127317427451797/" target="_blank">Haverford College, PA</a></p>
<p>Wednesday, April 9: <a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/152709154890634/" target="_blank">Amherst College, Amherst, MA</a></p>
<p>Thursday, April 10: <a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/171344556349955/" target="_blank">Wesleyan University, Middletown, CT</a></p>
<p>Monday, April 15: <a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/227324587413996/?ref=22" target="_blank">The College of Idaho, Caldwell, ID</a></p>
<p>Wednesday, April 17: <a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/345670465550966/?ref=22" target="_blank">Columbia University, New York, NY</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.everyoneisgay.com/spring-tour-dates/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
