<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0"><channel><title>Jezebel</title><link>http://jezebel.com</link><description>Jezebel is gossip, culture, fashion, and sex for the contemporary woman.</description><language>en</language><item><title><![CDATA[Downton Abbey Creator Basically Calls Dan Stevens a Shit]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/downton-abbey-creator-basically-calls-dan-stevens-a-shi-476394821</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><strong><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l3zkd0mbtdpjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></strong></p>
<p class="first-text"><strong>Downton Abbey </strong>creator <strong>Julian Fellowes </strong>would have liked to give Matthew and Lady Mary Crawley a happier ending, but wasn't able to because <strong>Dan Stevens</strong> bailed so unceremoniously.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;I had no choice. Dan would not stay – he was determined to go. Everyone liked him and thought he was fantastic. I tried to persuade him to come back just for one episode of the next series so we could give Matthew and Mary a happy ending but he wanted to go off to America and now I believe he has a three-movie deal. He’s doing very well!”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When you translate that from Tory peer British it means &quot;Dan Stevens is an ungrateful little douchenugget.&quot; [<a href="http://www.express.co.uk/news/showbiz/392991/Julian-Fellowes-couldn-t-give-Dan-Stevens-a-fond-farewell" target="_blank">Express</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><strong><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l3zebz7t9d5jpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></strong></p>
<p><strong>Justin Theroux </strong>hides behind drapes to scare <strong>Jennifer Aniston. </strong>You heard me. Did I stutter? So no one told you that it's gonna be this way? (Clap clap clap clap.)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;He calls it trickery,&quot; the “Friends” actress said in an appearance on “The Ellen DeGeneres Show.”</p>
<p>“He's constantly hiding behind drapes. And I'm constantly scared. It's like, it doesn't get old on me.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Trickery?? </em>[<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/jennifer_aniston_constantly_scared_VHSO8PfZb8BiFc6CddCaUN" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</p>
<p><strong>Jenreaux </strong>was seated two tables away from <strong>John Mayer </strong>at a restaurant and... wait for it... nothing happened. YAR, news is my job. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/jennifer-aniston-justin-theroux-dine-next-to-her-ex-boyfriend-john-mayer-2013184" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</p>
<p>&quot;Let's just move to France or Italy, open a little antique store, eat pasta, get fat.&quot; When are we going, Jennifer Aniston? I just packed a Longchamp bag full of carbs. [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/409505/jennifer-aniston-talks-moving-to-italy-eating-pasta-and-getting-fat" target="_blank">E!</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l3y756tc5ctjpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></p>
<p>We forget, amidst the <strong>Kristen Stewart </strong>hubbub, that <strong>Mary-Kate Olsen </strong>is actually the O.G. frowner. She looked unhappy in a private Knicks suite with <strong>Olivier Sarkozy, </strong>maybe because she forgot to bring the thimble she takes a nap in.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“She looked annoyed,” said a spy. “She wasn’t smiling . . . he was rubbing her back, kissing her, making all these sweet gestures.” Then, “She perked up to take a photo, and looked grumpy again.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Later, Sarkozy reportedly &quot;entertained&quot; Mary-Kate at the Tribeca Ball by &quot;doing a little dance.&quot; Yep, sounds like these two crazy kids are gonna MAKE IT. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/little_frowny_face_dPXa4BZW7GiwlzmhGvuB6N" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l3yjh4qpz9igif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p>
<p><strong>Kris, </strong>the <strong>Kris Jenner-</strong>hosted talk show you haven't been waiting for all your life, premieres on July 15th and will run for six weeks on &quot;selected Fox-owned stations,&quot; attempting to prove itself for national broadcast. It also has a logo that looks like it belongs on a cereal box. Woot. [<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/kris-talk-show-kris-jenner_n_3112383.html?utm_hp_ref=tv" target="_blank">HuffPo</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><strong><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l3z0100ydj7jpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></strong></p>
<p><strong>Jimmy Fallon </strong>interrupted <strong>Justin Timberlake's </strong>speech to <strong>Jessica Biel </strong>at last year's Timberbiel <a href="http://gawker.com/5954494/" target="_blank">Homeless Video</a> Nuptials to crack some jokes, to J.T.'s surprise. &quot;Interrupting the groom's speech at the wedding reception? Cracking jokes when your buddy is looking desperately for the words to say that he hopes his wife will remember forever?&quot; But he rolled with it, sparking a 10-minute improv that had all the guests &quot;roaring with laughter.&quot; (They were drunk.) And Jimmy Fallon and Justin Timberlake lived happily ever after. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/justin-timberlake-jimmy-fallon-interrupted-my-wedding-speech-2013184" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<ul><li><strong>Marc Anthony, </strong>the ancient Roman emperor who used to be married to <strong>J.Lo, </strong>probably broke up with his girlf, 22-year-old Topshop heiress <strong>Chloe Green. </strong>[<a href="http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/marc-anthony-splits-with-22-year-old-girlfriend-chloe-green/story-fn907478-1226624178479?from=public_rss" target="_blank">News.au</a>]</li><li><strong>Weird Science </strong>will get a remake, and if doesn't star <strong>Christopher Mintz Plasse</strong> I will literally eat my own hand. [<a href="http://www.vulture.com/2013/04/theyre-remaking-weird-science.html" target="_blank">Vulture</a>]</li><li>It turns out that <strong>Edward Norton </strong>married <strong>Shauna Robinson </strong>(who just gave birth to their kid)last year secretly. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/news/edward-norton-and-shauna-robertson-secretly-wed-before-sons-birth-2013184" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><strong>Sir Paul McCartney </strong>and <strong>Non-Sir But Utterly Complacent With That Ringo Starr </strong>had dinner together with their wives. [<a href="http://www.express.co.uk/news/showbiz/392996/Beatles-reunite-for-a-spot-of-dinner-with-their-wives" target="_blank">Express</a>]</li><li><strong>Real Housewife of Atlanta NeNe Leakes </strong>is getting her own wedding spinoff on Bravo called <strong>I Dream of NeNe</strong>. There are sleep disorder clinics for that! [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/tv-movies/nene-leakes-scores-housewives-spin-off-dream-nene-article-1.1321032" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</li><li><strong>Martha Stewart </strong>straight-up napped through a live <strong>Jerry Seinfeld </strong>standup routine because she owns this fuqing joint (=the world). [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/stewart_snoozy_at_seinfeld_9hgcvrkz7U5U4RWSeBMWTL" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li><strong>John Travolta's son </strong>likes Spongebob. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/news/john-travolta-and-son-benjamin-post-2013184" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><strong>Robert Downey Jr. </strong>says he's one of the greatest actors of his generation and will definitely win an Oscar (although &quot;[he] couldn't care less&quot;). Am I the only one who doesn't find him charming? K. [<a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/04/robert-downey-jr-brags-great-actor-win-oscar/" target="_blank">Radar Online</a>]</li><li>May this picture of <strong>Sandra Bullock </strong>and <strong>Melissa McC</strong><strong>arthy</strong> spark a thousand buddy comedies. (Okay, maybe just like two.) [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/hot-pics/they-got-heat-2013184" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li>Anchors on <strong>Good Day Philly </strong>lose it over sex idiot <strong>Ryan Lochte. </strong>[<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/18/olympics-ryan-lochte-reality-show-interview-fox-world-record-stupid-dumb-video/?adid=hero5" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Finch </strong>from American Pie had a knife pulled on him in a one-night stand gone bad. Annnnd, cut. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/18/eddie-kaye-thomas-american-pie-swat-house-standoff-girlfriend-knife/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Jon Krasinski's </strong>beard blah blah blah tl;dr fell asleep with eyes open. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-beauty/news/john-krasinski-grows-full-beard-hot-or-not-2013184" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><strong>Beyonce </strong>had to go to the dentist in Croatia on tour. [<a href="http://www.express.co.uk/news/showbiz/392983/Beyonce-takes-emergency-dentist-trip" target="_blank">Express</a>]</li><li><strong>&quot;Amanda Bynes </strong>is fine,&quot; says <strong>Nikki Blonsky; </strong><strong>Damian from Mean Girls </strong>yells &quot;She doesn't even go here!&quot; from the back of the room. [<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2311127/Nikki-Blonsky-says-Hairspray-star-Amanda-Bynes-having-breakthrough-breakdown.html" target="_blank">Daily Mail</a>]</li><li><strong>Robin</strong> <strong>Roberts</strong>, who recently returned to TODAY after her battle with bone marrow disease,was briefly hospitalized last week in Florida. Feel better, Robin Roberts. [<a href="http://bossip.com/760799/get-well-soon-robin-roberts-suffers-setback-in-recovery/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+bossiprss+%28Bossip.com%29&amp;utm_content=Google+Reader" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Clueless</strong> alums <strong>Donald Faison </strong>and <strong>Stacey Dash </strong>will reunite on a show called <strong>The Exes, </strong>if you think it's worth it/the freeway teaches you just how important love is. [<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/clueless-reunion-donald-faison-stacey-dash-the-exes_n_3111470.html?utm_hp_ref=tv" target="_blank">HuffPo</a>]</li><li><strong>Kate Middleton </strong>gets involved with three new charities at the precise moment which, across the ocean, I consider buying three Diet Cokes just to hit the minimum delivery requirement for a breakfast sandwich. [<a href="http://www.people.com/people/package/article/0,,20395222_20692419,00.html" target="_blank">People</a>]</li><li></li></ul>
<p><small><em>Image via <a href="http://www.gettyimages" target="_blank">Getty</a></em></small></p>]]></description><category domain="">dirt bag</category><category domain="">julian fellowes</category><category domain="">dan stevens</category><category domain="">jimmy fallon</category><category domain="">marc anthony</category><category domain="">jon krasinski</category><category domain="">beyonce</category><category domain="">amanda bynes</category><category domain="">nikki blonsky</category><category domain="">kate middleton</category><category domain="">robin roberts</category><category domain="">donald faison</category><category domain="">stacey dash</category><category domain="">ryan lochte</category><category domain="">beyonce chloe green</category><category domain="">paul mccartney</category><category domain="">ringo starr</category><category domain="">nene leakes</category><category domain="">martha stewart</category><category domain="">jerry seinfeld</category><category domain="">john travolta</category><category domain="">robert downey jr</category><category domain="">sandra bullock</category><category domain="">melissa mccarthy</category><category domain="">edward norton</category><category domain="">weird science</category><category domain="">shauna robinson</category><category domain="">justin theroux</category><category domain="">downton abbey</category><category domain="">jennifer aniston</category><category domain="">kristen stewart</category><category domain="">kris jenner</category><category domain="">kim kardashian</category><category domain="">john mayer</category><category domain="">mary-kate olsen</category><category domain="">olivier sarkozy</category><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">476394821</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Breslaw]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Too Fat to Be in Your Friend's Wedding? Then Your Friend Is a Bitch.]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/too-fat-to-be-in-your-friends-wedding-then-your-frien-476302048</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><em><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l1ppgemoj4yjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></em></p>
<p class="first-text"><em>Welcome to Friendzone, Jezebel's column devoted to dealing with the valuable people in your life who you're not humping. Got an issue and looking for guidance? Email <a href="mailto:friendzone@jezebel.com">friendzone@jezebel.com</a></em></p>
<p><strong>I was married last year and had my close friend (of about 15ish years) in my bridal party.  Now she's engaged.  I found out about her engagement through Facebook, and I found out that I wasn't in her bridal party through an email.  Now, normally not being in a bridal party would not unhinge me, but the email from my friend also included the reason why I wasn't going to be standing with her as she married:  I am too fat and too pale.  Her specific quote:  &quot;I have friends that take pride in they're (sic) appearance.  Our wedding is beach-themed and I want all my girls to look fit and tan.  The dresses I picked are strapless and only look good on thin girls.&quot;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Here's the conundrum:  how do I decline her invitation?  Yes, she actually invited me! Do I go to the wedding and then belly-flop into their cake during the first cut, nomming my fat face through the fondant and plastic bride and groom statues?  We have mutual friends that I don't think know about her email, and if I don't come I'm going to look like a huge asshole.</strong></p>
<p>Note: the following is a rage-filled diatribe. This column will return to its commitment to kind civility in the questions that follow. But holy shit, am I right, you guys? HOLY SHIT.</p>
<p>Ahem.</p>
<p>Usually in this column, I try to give folks the benefit of the doubt. Even when a friend has been a real jerk to the letter-writer, I think to myself, &quot;Well, maybe the friend is a troubled person. Maybe the friend is suffering.&quot; I don't try to excuse the friend's behavior, but I do try to understand it because, you know, compassion and all that jazz. </p>
<p>Not this fucking time.</p>
<p>Your friend is a loser. She is an awful, superficial, stupid person. Are we positive that she is not actually an alien robot creature bent on your extermination? I am sorry you had to be friends with this stinky piece of excrement for 15 years. I am sorry this death-eater was in your bridal party. I am sorry she may be blessed with daughters one day, daughters whom she will undoubtedly raise to hate themselves as much as I hate their mother right this moment. </p>
<p>I could say more terrible things about your friend, but I trust the commenters to help me out with that one. Except for the ones who may write things like, &quot;I'm sorry, but like, I have the right to make sure my bridal party is pretty.&quot; Because those people are terrible also, and should restrict their social media activities to their thinspiration Pinterest boards.</p>
<p>Don't bother with a &quot;no&quot; response card. Simply send a link to this article to your &quot;friend.&quot; And if any of the other gals are curious as to why you won't be at the wedding, send the link along to them, too. Then kick back with a glass of wine, a delicious cupcake and your sexy husband. Be glad you don't have to waste one more ounce of your time on this sewage dump of a human. (Oh, and don't forget to block her on Facebook. Cheers!)</p>
<p><strong>Way back when I was 18, I fell for a guy at work. He was my first true crush and I was excited when he made it clear that my interest in him was mutual.  Suddenly, my wild-child, hard-partying best friend declared that she also liked this guy and that if I had any respect for our friendship I would stop seeing him outside of work.  Two weeks later she told me that she'd slept with him, that it was great, and that she &quot;couldn't wait&quot; to do it again. Ultimately, we fell out over it. A few months ago, we became friends again via Facebook. Turns out she hasn't changed one bit. In fact, age has only made her more boy-crazy and desperate. She emails or texts me at least five times a week, begging me to hang out with her. I do so out of guilt (she seems so lonely) and then I have to listen to her brag or sob (or both!) over tons of men. We do share some great memories and I'd be happy to see this girl once in awhile, but I just can't stand seeing her every week. How do I tell her?</strong></p>
<p>Putting aside what happened when you were younger, I feel kind of bad for this gal. She does sound lonely, and unhappy, and desperate. She's lucky to have found someone willing to spend time with her. However, she's clearly working your last nerve and may need to find a new buddy if she doesn't shape up.</p>
<p>After all, your job isn't to take care of all the little lost bunny rabbits in the world, no matter how sweetly pathetic they may be. I believe your primary job is to take care of yourself and to put energy into good work, good love, and good friendships. Then you'll be a happy, productive citizen and the world will continue to turn on its axis and we'll all get to marry David Tennant, the end.</p>
<p>You may wish to say to this chick, &quot;You've been telling me so much about your man drama that I barely get to hear about <em>you</em>. I'd really like to hear about what else is going on in your life! You were always so good at art/dancing/baking/writing/scrimshaw...do you still do that?&quot; It may help to focus your hangout time on an activity, like a monkey-training class or a day at the Renaissance Fair or a BBC America marathon or something. If she goes back to babbling about men, well, you tried. You have my permission to usually (or always) be &quot;busy&quot; when she wants to hang out. </p>
<p><strong>My ex-boyfriend is not exactly beloved by my roommates. He was a real jerk to me for awhile, and made me cry more times than I can count. A couple years have passed, and things between us are much better. We've begun hooking up again, and it's exactly what I need right now. The problem is that my friends refuse to let him stay over our house. They won't even let me bring him in the house. Yet they insist on bringing over another friend who used to be really nasty to me. It seems unfair. What do I do? </strong></p>
<p>Let's deal with the boyfriend issue and the former friend issue separately. Based on your pals' reactions, I have a feeling that even if this former friend was a real jerk to you, she didn't cause you the same torment that this fella did. Then again, maybe she is actually a malevolent lifeform who seeks to chase you through time and space in order to exterminate you! (But I'm guessing not.)</p>
<p>First, the dude issue. As you know, your friends are trying to protect you. I advise you to sit them down and have a frank talk with them about how you feel and what you &quot;need right now,&quot; as you put it. Speak to them from a place of gratitude for their protective instinct. Don't try to convince them that he's a real prize of a guy now, but do present some reasons why his presence in your life is helpful at this time. Remember, if he fucks up, they're going to have to clean up the mess…again. If they don't relent, I suggest you stay at his house or get a cheap motel room.</p>
<p>On to the next issue. Is the ex-friend's presence actually damaging to you, or just annoying? If it's the latter, you may as well put up with it. If it's the former, tell your roommates that the girl is no longer welcome in your home. Be very clear as to why you cannot stand her being in your house. They ought to comply with your wishes. If they don't, it's time to consider getting new roommates once your lease is up. Perhaps it'd be better for you to live with folks who aren't as invested in your personal choices. You're a grown-up, after all. </p>
]]></description><category domain="">friendzone</category><category domain="">advice</category><category domain="">weddings</category><category domain="">roommates</category><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 22:55:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">476302048</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sara Benincasa]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Desperate College Dean Warns Parents of the Dangers of Franzia]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/desperate-college-dean-warns-parents-of-the-dangers-of-476280431</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l1e6e9lisq4jpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">&quot;Tour de Franzia&quot; is a famed wine-chugging extravaganza celebrated at college campuses across the country; you may recall the name of the event from the great <a href="http://jezebel.com/5946946/attention-butt+chuggers-please-do-not-put-alcohol-up-your-butt">butt-chugging incident</a> of 2012. Wesleyan University's administration has tried its best over the past few years to police what campus blog <a href="http://wesleying.org/2012/05/07/p-safe-drops-franzia-awareness-report/" target="_blank">Wesleying </a>calls a &quot;wine-fueled shit-show of a scavenger hunt,&quot; but undergrads seem hellbent on participating, despite warnings that they'll face judicial consequences and be prohibited from participating in commencement if caught with a box in hand.</p>
<p>This year, Dean Mike Whaley, Vice President of Student Affairs, decided to contact higher authorities: Wesleyan parents. He forwarded every mom and dad the requisite anti-Tour de Franzia email he sent students along with a<a href="http://track.jango.wesleyan.edu/w.aspx?j=282183212&amp;m=72118A30A48549CDAB8D391D35BE68B1" target="_blank"> special note of his own</a>. </p>
<p>&quot;It felt like I was back in high school,&quot; one sophomore told Jezebel. &quot;I felt like I was in trouble at school and the teachers called my parents.&quot;</p>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="255" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l1dgb2xjbjlpng/ku-medium.png" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p>Here's the email:</p>
<blockquote>

<p>Fw: Seeking your help with a problematic campus event</p>
<p>Dear Wesleyan Parents,</p>
<p>We need your help. I am forwarding to you the message (below) that I recently sent to all students. The so-called &quot;Tour de Franzia&quot; has surfaced at Wesleyan in recent years and it has been fraught with dangerous problems. It has been impossible for us to identify the students who organize the event because it is publicized and promoted via an anonymous Facebook account. We need your help in talking with your student about the very real dangers associated with the event, as well as the significant judicial consequences that participants will face. I hope you will help us to discourage participation in this dangerous activity</p>
<p>Many thanks, Dean Mike Whaley</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Unfortunately for Mr. Whaley, &quot;the general student reaction to both emails was not, 'oh shit well there goes tour this year,'&quot; a tipster told us, &quot;it was like 'oh woah tour is coming up? sweet glad they reminded us.&quot;</p>
<p><a href="http://wesleying.org/2013/04/17/dean-whaley-administration-to-ramp-up-tour-de-franzia-charges-whether-or-not-youre-actually-drinking/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=dean-whaley-administration-to-ramp-up-tour-de-franzia-charges-whether-or-not-youre-actually-drinking" target="_blank"><em>Wesleying</em> </a>also documented some surprising parental reactions:</p>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="223" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l1awo389o8ipng/ku-medium.png" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p>
<p>At least they're not butt-chugging it?</p>

<p><em><small>Image via <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/justonlysteve/" target="_blank">justonlysteve</a>/Flickr.</small></em></p>]]></description><category domain="">college</category><category domain="">wesleyan</category><category domain="">franzia</category><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">476280431</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Katie J.M. Baker]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[WTF: Model Scouts Look for New Talent at Eating Disorders Clinic]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/wtf-model-scouts-look-for-new-talent-at-eating-disorde-476140685</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l107l86u8cwjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Sweden's largest eating disorders treatment clinic, the 1,700-bed Stockholm Center for Eating Disorders, says it has an unusual problem: scouts for Sweden's biggest modeling agencies who congregate outside its doors, persistently trying to recruit patients. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;We think this is repugnant. People have stood outside our clinic and tried to pick up our girls because they know they are very thin,&quot; chief doctor Anna-Maria af Sandeberg told the Metro newspaper.<br/><br/>&quot;It sends the wrong signals when the girls are being treated for eating disorders.&quot;  [...]<br/><br/>In one incident, an agent with one of Sweden's largest modelling agencies approached a 14-year-old girl and left a business card.<br/><br/>The girl's mother and care coordinator Chistina Lillman-Ringborg later confronted the agent, explaining that the girl suffered from a serious illness.<br/><br/>&quot;They claimed that they approach healthy, normally slim young people and that they never urge anyone to lose weight; that's how they defended themselves,&quot; Lillman-Ringborg told the TT news agency.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Indeed it seems highly unlikely that an agency would have to waste its time &quot;urging&quot; a girl to lose weight when she is already <em>anorexic to the point of hospitalization</em>. Just pick her up out of that wheelchair, get that girl some five-inch heels, and stick her on the next flight to Paris. What could possibly go wrong!</p>
<p>Over the years, the media has highlighted some pretty outrageous behavior from modeling scouts (who are generally autonomous operators within the modeling economy, traveling widely in search of young talent and getting paid a finder's fee per head by the major agencies with which they are affiliated). Scouts in South America who <a href="http://jezebel.com/5558200/brazilian-blondes-and-exotic-model-exporting">use</a> their knowledge of colonial history and European settlement to search for white models in countries like Brazil, where the population is majority non-white. Scouts in Russia <a href="http://jezebel.com/5891967/the-creepy-world-of-model-scouts">luring</a> impoverished teenagers into modeling with tales of the financial security they will enjoy, but leaving them with interrupted educations and tens of thousands of dollars in debt. But scouts actually recruiting for models outside an eating disorder treatment clinic pretty may be the most despicable of all the horrible model scouting news stories we've ever heard. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.thelocal.se/47404/20130418/#.UXABgitg8yE" target="_blank">Scouts Seek Models At Local Anorexia Clinic</a> [The Local]</p>
<p><small><em>Image via <a href="http://www.gettyimages.com/" target="_blank">Getty</a>.</em></small></p>]]></description><category domain="">awful</category><category domain="">fashion</category><category domain="">eating disorders</category><category domain="">sweden</category><category domain="">model scouts</category><category domain="">modeling</category><category domain="">model behaviors</category><category domain="">model scouts eating disorders</category><category domain="">models eating disorders</category><category domain="">models food</category><category domain="">model scouts targeting anorexic patients</category><category domain="">anorexia</category><category domain="">models anorexia</category><category domain="">anorexic models</category><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 18:50:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">476140685</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jenna Sauers]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[The 31 Best Carbohydrates Ever]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/the-31-best-carbohydrates-ever-474380069</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l0zn3aoci9ujpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">Everyone's so damn afraid of carbs. Over ten years after <em>Dr. Atkins' New Diet Revolution </em>warned dieters worldwide about the fattening power of the potato, the low-carb revolution is still in full effect. This is insane, because carbs are delicious. Fuck a protein shake, am I right?</p>
<p>Even the <em>BBC</em> has <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-22145709" target="_blank">gotten in</a> on the craze; reporting on how low-carb diets are all the rage, they cite Demi Moore and Jennifer Aniston's willowy frames as triumphs of endless nights of never-ending salad bowls filled with skinless, boneless chicken breasts atop beds of lettuce. Yum, yum?</p>
<p>An unnamed British actor even ALLEGEDLY* has his <a href="http://blindgossip.com/?p=52631&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=british-bread-ban" target="_blank">hotel rooms</a> swept for contraband carbs before entering. Maybe he's afraid some stray mini-bar Pringles will bust out of their cage and force feed themselves to him? Perhaps the actor is a she — and the she is Gwyneth Paltrow! Seeing as she thinks she's British, and then there's this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Only last week, actress Gwyneth Paltrow provoked the wrath of the dietetic establishment while she was promoting her new low-carb, gluten-free cookbook, by saying she avoids feeding her children bread, rice and pasta.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The thought of being a childhood without Spaghetti O's makes my fat cells sob.</p>
<p>However, all that I could live with, I cannot waste all my tears on little Apple; girlfriend has it made. However, when I read that one desperate U.K. restaurant is now offering a <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-2307329/Plan-Bread-broccoli-bread-lowest-calorie-loaf-banker-Paul-Shackleton-leaving-JP-Morgan.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490" target="_blank">low-carb bread</a> MADE FROM BROCCOLI, it was the straw that broke the vitamin- and nutrient-deficient camel's back. What fresh hell is this? It's CARBS made from VEGETABLES.** My bread machine weeps.</p>
<p>Fuck. That. Enough!</p>
<p>High-protein diets might still be all the rage, but it’s time for their reign of tyranny to come to an end. You know why? Because nothing will ever beat a carb. Potatoes, rice, and bread will get you every time — and why not? The ultimate point of living isn’t to be as healthy as possible — it’s to have a great fucking time. And what’s a better time than French fries? Possibly sex. Maybe.</p>
<p>Plus, this week has pretty much blown, and so it's probably best for us to carbo-load our troubles away. It's science!</p>
<p>After thirty years of research (eating pounds of every known carb), I’ve come up with the 31 best ones. They are in descending order, and this is not open to debate. (Of course it is.)</p>
<p> 1. The potato in all its forms. Listed here from most to least delicious (not up for debate) (untrue):</p>
<ul><li>Mashed potatoes </li><li>French fries (from most to least delicious: poutine, disco, waffle, shoestring, curly, chili cheese, cheese, wedge, steak, chili, stix) </li><li>Au Gratin </li><li>Scalloped </li><li>Tater tots </li><li>Hash browns</li><li>Home fries </li><li>Potato chips </li><li>Baked potatoes (not sure whether these count as they’re basically a vegetable) </li><li>Sweet potato, anything</li></ul>
<p>2. Bagels <br/> 3. Croissants<br/> 4. Naan <br/>5. Pizza (thin crust) <br/>6. Cereal (all, except fuck Kashi Go Lean) <br/>7. Muffins (all, except fuck bran) <br/>8. Soft pretzels (toppings, any and all) (Super Pretzel allowed)<br/>9. Injera <br/>10. Roti <br/>11. Lasagna <br/>12. Challah<br/> 13. Cinnamon rolls (although list is strictly savory, cinnamon rolls have ability to mingle in savory and sweet world, therefore acceptable.)<br/>14. Mac and Cheese <br/>15. Fry coating (any type) <br/>16. Chapati <br/>17. ALL PASTA SHAPES <br/>18. White rice (any type) <br/>19. Pizza (deep dish) <br/>20. Everything free in an Italian or Mexican restaurant. <br/> 21. Utz pretzel nuggets <br/>22. Bread pudding <br/>23. Bread salad<br/> 24. Potato chip sandwich <br/>25. Dumplings (all varieties)<br/> 26. Focaccia <br/>27. Tamales <br/>28. Triscuits (or Wheat Thins, same diff) <br/>29. Inari <br/>30. Pizza (delivery or Digiorno) <br/>31. Spaghetti mixed with rice and folded into mashed potatoes (it's a thing; try it)  </p>

<p><small>*Gerard Butler??<br/>**I know broccoli has carbs, but that's not the point!</small></p>
<p>[<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-22145709" target="_blank">BBC</a>]</p>
<p><small><em>Image via <a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/gallery-661903p1.html" target="_blank">Penny Hillcrest</a>/<a href="http://jezebel.com/&lt;a href=">http://www.shutterstock.com/</a>&quot;&gt;Shutterstock.</em></small></p>]]></description><category domain="">food</category><category domain="">carbs</category><category domain="">protein</category><category domain="">carbohydrates</category><category domain="">lists</category><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 17:20:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">474380069</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Laura Beck]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[There's Crazy Crap Going on Behind the Scenes at the Today Show]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/theres-crazy-crap-going-on-behind-the-scenes-at-the-to-476048703</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l0q558p57qqjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">After working at NBC for 22 years, one day last month, Ann Curry entered the building at 30 Rockefeller Plaza and couldn't find her employee badge. Remarkably, this was a problem.</p>
<p>According to a <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/21/magazine/who-can-save-the-today-show.html?smid=tw-share&amp;pagewanted=all" target="_blank">piece</a> by Brian Stelter in today's<em> New York Times</em>: </p>
<blockquote>
<p>The guard looked at her quizzically.</p>
<p>“Name?” he asked.</p>
<p>“Ann Curry,” she said.</p>
<p>Then, after a moment. “A-N-N.” Pause. “C-U-R-R-Y.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>True, she was wearing a trench coat and a hat. But still: There's crazy shit going on behind the scenes at the <em>Today</em> show. Brian Stelter's <a data-amazontag="jezebelamzn-20" data-amazonasin="1455512877" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/Top-Morning-Inside-Cutthroat-World/dp/1455512877?tag=jezebelamzn-20&amp;ascsubtag=link">book</a>,<em> Top of The Morning, </em>which takes a look &quot;inside the cutthroat world of morning TV,&quot; hits stores next week. You may consider <em>Today — </em>like many morning progams — to be alternately informative, insipid, cheesy and comforting, but it's not to be taken lightly:  The show rakes in $500 million in annual revenue for NBC. In today's article for the <em>Times, </em>in addition to the Ann Curry/security guard incident, there are a several weird, uncomfortable and bizarre revelations. For instance: Though the show tries very hard to appear a cheerful, fun AM hangout, the truth is darker. For instance, the Ann Curry departure: </p>
<blockquote>
<p>So insistent was [producer Jim Bell] that Curry was the problem — that she was “out of position,” as he put it in an e-mail to his deputies — that he had been talking about it with friends for months. One morning-TV veteran suggested to him that firing Curry, who had been co-hosting for only about six months at that point, would be tantamount to “killing Bambi.” Undeterred, Bell hatched a careful three-part plan: 1.) persuade Lauer to extend his expiring contract; 2.) oust Curry; 3.) replace her with Savannah Guthrie. According to this source, Bell called his plan Operation Bambi.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Stelter points out:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Though it is created largely for women, the business is, even now, managed mostly by men, including those who like to think in terms of war, sabotage and embarrassing James Bond-like names for things they do in the office. It’s also marred by the striking effects of sleep deprivation: paranoia, hot tempers, rash decisions. It probably doesn’t help that morning hosts are, almost by definition, multimillionaires, making far more than the producers they supposedly work for, and far, far more than the staff members who toil for them at 5 a.m. It’s a situation unusually conducive to resentment.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p> Yikes. </p>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="200" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l0rr2sa6ny7jpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p>
<p>Also, when Ann Curry left last year, was there a PR team in place to handle the gossip, rumors and blowback? Well, yes… If by team you mean one person:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>[Curry's] weepy departure on June 28 would have been a P.R. crisis for any network, but it was doubly bad for NBC, which employed just one dedicated P.R. person, Megan Kopf, to oversee all of “Today” — its stars, correspondents and producers. (Kopf was also trying to deal with the fallout while planning her wedding.)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Audiences at home were not the only ones who realized that something was amiss after Curry's awkward ousting. The other <em>Today</em> show hosts felt like the show needed fixing:     </p>
<blockquote>
<p>During this tumultuous period, NBC commissioned Sterling Brands, a consulting firm, to diagnose what exactly had gone wrong at “Today.” Sterling interviewed Lauer, Guthrie, [producer Jim Bell] and nine other senior staff members anonymously, in order to keep their assessments private. The results turned out to be damningly frank. One of them said that “our sense of family is broken.” Another said, “Matt is being blamed, and some in our audience see Savannah as the younger replacement wife.” Another interviewee suggested that Curry wasn’t the only problem, saying, “People were leaving for the content, too.” But the most revealing comment had nothing to do with Curry at all. “If I look at the show,” one of the 12 people said, “I am not sure I’d know what year it is. I want to feel like we are watching 2012.” The staff members also went after “Good Morning America,” but they were honest about the competition’s strengths. “They look like they are having more fun,” the report concluded.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Stelter doesn't even go into the other behind-the-scenes rumors, like the one about Matt Lauer and Natalie Morales having an affair, or the one about how Matt Lauer <a href="http://omg.yahoo.com/news/rumor-resurfaces-matt-lauer-secret-father-natalie-morales-223900313.html" target="_blank">fathered</a> one of Natalie Morales's kids — or the one insisting that Savannah Guthrie <a href="http://www.nationalenquirer.com/celebrity/today-show-sex-scandals-savannah-guthries-twisted-love-life" target="_blank">fell in love with a married TV producer</a> who left his wife for her. Stelter does address the rumor that Anderson Cooper was being considered to replace Matt Lauer — and it was not just a rumor: Pat Fili-Krushel, chairwoman of the NBCUniversal News Group, called Cooper up: </p>
<blockquote>
<p>…Cooper and Fili-Krushel had actually met for coffee and discussed a role for him on “Today” — not this year, but perhaps in 2014. According to one person with direct knowledge, one option called for Cooper to overlap with Lauer for 12 months, allowing for an orderly transition.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Stelter writes that it &quot;seems certain&quot; that the current contract Matt Lauer has with Today is his final one. After Matt signed his most recent contract, Stelter saw his wife at a party, where Annette Lauer's wife snapped, “Two more years, and then he’s mine.” </p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" class="youtube" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/9__i8mx8A80?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0" id="youtube-9__i8mx8A80"></iframe></span></p><p> But Ann Curry remains the saddest part of the story. Was she a problematic cohost? Definitely. But the way NBC let the narrative roll out, the network seemed cruel, she appeared to have been thrown under the bus, and the whole thing was painful and embarrassing. Apparently since getting the boot, she's been stuck in some kind of weird limbo over the past, filing reports for NBC but working from an office on the 26th floor while all of her old coworkers at <em>Today</em> are on the 3rd floor. She cried while reading email and Twitter messages from fans, Stelter writes: </p>
<blockquote>
<p>She was overwhelmed by condolences. “It feels like I died,” she told colleagues afterward, “and I’ve seen my own wake.”<br/><br/></p>
</blockquote>
<p>On <em>Today</em>'s Facebook page, the first comment on a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10151413948061350&amp;set=a.10150616327591350.445876.12566691349&amp;type=1&amp;theater" target="_blank">picture</a> of the current hosts reads &quot;I miss Ann Curry!!!!!!!!!!!!!&quot;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/21/magazine/who-can-save-the-today-show.html?pagewanted=1&amp;_r=0&amp;smid=tw-share" target="_blank">Waking Up on the Wrong Side of a Rating War</a> [NYT]</p>
<p>Earlier: <a href="http://jezebel.com/5990585/everyone-hates-matt-lauer">Everyone Hates Matt Lauer</a></p>
<p><em><small>Images via <a href="https://www.facebook.com/today" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/AnnCurry" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.</small></em></p>]]></description><category domain="">today show</category><category domain="">ann curry</category><category domain="">matt lauer</category><category domain="">today</category><category domain="">tv</category><category domain="">natalie morales</category><category domain="">savannah guthrie</category><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">476048703</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dodai Stewart]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Everyone Thinks Rihanna's Pregnant]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/everyone-thinks-rihannas-pregnant-475834510</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l0c2k1zc6vtjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">As the <strong>Rihanna</strong> bacchanal—Rihacchanal?—known as the Diamonds tour continues to suffer under the weight of four concert cancellations (Boston, March 10; Baltimore, March 12; Houston, April 15; Dallas, April 16) and late publicity appearances, the rumor mill was fed by her paparazzi-snapped exit from a Beverly Hills medical building.</p>
<p>Her reps say that she's suffering from the flu and laryngitis, and her friends add that she's depressed that her sickness is forcing her to let her fans down, but the tabloids persist on providing us with unsolicited Ri-Ri uterus updates that claim she's got <strong>Chris Brown's </strong>bun in the oven.</p>
<p>Nope nope nope nope. A source says: &quot;[Rihanna] is just sick, and that’s really it. I know, that’s not a good enough reason because everybody wants some drama and the rumors that she’s pregnant to make the rounds, but sorry, not this time. She’s not pregnant!” [<a href="http://hollywoodlife.com/2013/04/17/rihanna-pregnancy-rumors-chris-brown-baby-denial/" target="_blank">Hollywood Life</a>, <a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/409053/rihanna-not-pregnant-in-spite-of-speculation-says-source" target="_blank">E!, </a><a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/17/rihanna-on-the-mend-pregnancy-rumors-persist/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><strong><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l0bwd3i27ovjpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></strong></p>
<p><strong>Billy Ray Cyrus</strong> didn't write much about <strong>Miley </strong>and <strong>Liam Hemsworth's </strong>relationship in his memoir <strong>Hilbilly Heart</strong> (LOLZ) because he isn't sure they're gonna get married/she's just being Miley, etc. &quot;I don't know, I really don't. They're young. They're kids. The great news is, they're great friends. They're really, really good friends. If you end up getting married, that's your business too, you know?&quot; Miley's gonna be sooooo maaaaad. [<a href="http://blog.music.aol.com/2013/04/16/billy-ray-cyrus-talks-miley-engagement/" target="_blank">AOL Music</a>]</p>
<p>Furthermore, when Liam asked for Billy Ray's consent after he proposed, Billy Ray made a joke: &quot;I jokingly said, 'Can I be in your brother's next movie?' And then I said, 'No, I'm joking.' It was a good question. He never did answer ... I should have said next two movies! And get me in that film of his too.''&quot; What a funny joke! It's so funny! He totally wasn't joking! [<a href="http://www.tv3.ie/entertainment_article.php?locID=1.803.810&amp;article=101059" target="_blank">TV3ie</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="162" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l0cjxixkazigif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p>
<p>For the first time since 2011, <strong>Britney Spears </strong>is returning to the studio to record a single. It's called &quot;Ooh La La&quot; and it will play over the credits of <strong>Smurfs 2. </strong>My palms might have started bleeding just typing that. Yeah wait no it gave me the stigmata. Cool. [<a href="http://www.latimes.com/entertainment/music/posts/la-et-ms-britney-spears-new-single-ooh-la-la-20130417,0,5338728.story" target="_blank">L.A. Times</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><strong><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l0b7p7sdujmjpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></strong></p>
<p><strong>Russell Brand </strong>informed<strong> Conan O'Brien </strong>that he attempted to get <strong>Tom Cruise</strong> to play Scientology's Pied Pieper on the set of their movie <strong>Rock Of Ages, </strong>but Tom wasn't biting. (Remember, this was around the dissolve of TomKat, so he had other things on his mind. Like aliens.) Brand told Conan:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;Every so often I'd say things like 'oh Tom, sometimes I'm a bit lost in life' to see if he would try and get me in and he'd go 'oh yeh, I dunno, read the bible. Or 'Tom, I wish I had a way of thinking more positively about the future.&quot; [But] that man had no interest in getting me into Scientology at all... If there’s a cult that don't want me, I want to know why!&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ah, Russell. We like you godless and slithery.</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><strong><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18l0b9o8po18mjpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></strong></p>
<p><strong>Bryce Dallas Howard, </strong>who directed one of the <strong>Jennifer Aniston-</strong>produced lifetime shorts that comprise the five-part &quot;Call Me Crazy,&quot; said that mental illness had a special significance to her since suffering from post-partum depression after the birth of her first child in 2007. &quot;It went untreated for eighteen months because I was just so ashamed and frightened. I didn't know what it meant and didn't know what happened to me. Getting to have an opportunity to tell a story that is about mental illness and how it affects one's self and one's community was really something that really meant a lot to me.&quot; [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/news/bryce-dallas-howard-makes-red-carpet-return-talks-post-partum-depression-2013174" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<ul><li>&quot;They'll say, 'Oh, he's sexy,' but women still go for guys who are 6-foot-2. &quot;It's nice that people are thinking outside the box, but I don't believe any of it for a minute.&quot; <strong>Peter Dinklage </strong>calls out your bullshit. [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/game-thrones-star-peter-dinklage-don-sex-symbol-article-1.1319646" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</li><li><strong>Katherine Jackson </strong>fears that <strong>Debbie Rowe's </strong>testimony in the <strong>Jackson </strong>wrongful death suit might expose paternity secrets. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/18/katherine-jackson-prince-paris-debbie-rowe-michael-jackson-paternity-aeg-wrongful-death-lawsuit/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Edward Norton's </strong>fiancee gave birth to their son. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/news/edward-nortons-fiancee-shauna-robertson-gives-birth-to-a-baby-boy-2013174" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><strong>Justin Bieber </strong>put a cartoon of himself in bed with a seemingly-nude &quot;Belieber&quot; on Twitter and everyone went rabid and thousands of parents across America decided, no, they did NOT know their own 14-year-old daughter anymore, now give them a fishbowl full of sauv blanc. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/justin_bieber_posts_cartoon_pic_H5udkydyup92scsy9ZYu7J" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li><strong>Whoopi Goldberg</strong> doesn't give a flying fuckbutt who replaces <strong>Joy Behar </strong>and <strong>Elizabeth</strong> <strong>Hasselbeck </strong>on <strong>The View</strong> at all, like, AT ALL. &quot;Let me tell you this about <em>The View</em>: I take a paycheck every other week. That's all I do. I could give a shit what comes. I do my job — I have a contract. That's where I stand. I don't give a fuck.&quot; But tell us how you really feel, Whoopi. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/entertainment/news/whoopi-goldberg-i-dont-care-who-replaces-elisabeth-hasselbeck-and-joy-behar-on-the-view-2013174" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li>Regarding her potential biopic, <strong>Stevie Nicks </strong>&quot;has told <strong>Reese [Witherspoon]</strong> that she's almost too old.&quot; Zingity zing. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/stevie-nicks-reese-witherspoon-is-almost-too-old-to-play-me-in-a-biopic--2013174" target="_blank">People</a>]</li><li><strong>Sylvester Stallone's </strong>mom shops at the 99 cent store. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/18/sly-stallone-mother-jackie-stallone-99-cent-store-photo/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Gabby Reece</strong> didn't mean women should be <em>submissive, </em>she just meant, um, women should be submissive. [<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/gabby-reece-submissive-comments-video_n_3106341.html" target="_blank">HuffPo</a>]</li><li><strong>Kanye West </strong>will be the musical guest on <strong>SNL </strong>on May 18th. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/kanye_to_snl_NvAYZUSl20SNGj5CkwOOrK" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li>Shortly before <strong>Sharon </strong>and <strong>Ozzy Osbourne's </strong>split, they made a 911 call about a burning candle at 4:45 AM, with Ozzy sounding incoherent. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/17/sharon-osbourne-ozzy-osbourne-911-call/?adid=hero1" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Nicki Minaj</strong> to <strong>Mariah Carey </strong>on <strong>American Idol</strong>:&quot;Simmer down, sir.&quot; A+ [<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/american-idol-feud-nicki-mariah-sir-video_n_3106520.html?utm_hp_ref=tv" target="_blank">HuffPo</a>]</li><li>If you want your <strong>Krysten Ritter </strong>fix, the final episodes from Season 2 of <strong>Don't Trust The B- In Apartment 23 </strong>will be released online soon. [<a href="http://www.vulture.com/2013/04/final-dont-trust-the-b-episodes.html" target="_blank">Vulture</a>]</li><li><strong>Amber Rose </strong>got a big old inking of <strong>Wiz Khalifa's</strong> face on her arm. [<a href="http://bossip.com/760198/amber-rose-gets-wiz-khalifas-face-tattooed-on-her-arm-photos/?utm_source=feedly&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed:+bossiprss+%28Bossip.com%29" target="_blank">Bossip</a>]</li><li>Everyone wants to fuck <strong>Idris Elba. </strong>Not news, but I like that picture of Idris Elba, and this is MY horse and pony show. [<a href="http://bossip.com/760011/vibevixen-counts-down-most-sought-after-celebrities-in-showbiz-with-their-most-lustable-list-do-you-agree-with-their-picks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+bossiprss+%28Bossip.com%29&amp;utm_content=Google+Reader" target="_blank">Bossip</a>]</li><li><strong>Mark Wahlberg </strong>isn't a fan of the spray tan. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/wahlberg_fakes_it_for_film_RL9Ww0nHZNYkOmlrlhPcuN" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li>Dammmmn. <strong>Nick Lachey</strong> on going on a date with <strong>Kim Kardashian </strong>in 2006: &quot;Let’s just say this: We went to a movie. No one followed us there. Somehow, mysteriously, when we left, there were 30 photographers waiting outside. There are certain ways to play this game, and some people play it well.&quot; [<a href="http://bossip.com/760205/put-on-blast-nick-lachey-claims-kimmy-cakes-called-the-paps-during-one-of-their-dates-back-in-the-day/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+bossiprss+%28Bossip.com%29&amp;utm_content=Google+Reader" target="_blank">Bossip</a>]</li><li>Meanwhile, Kim K is getting her karmic comeuppance by growing hair all over her body because she's pregnant (??!) [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/18/kim-kardashian-laser-hair-removal-growth-pregnancy-hormones/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Jennifer Aniston </strong>goes &quot;cupping&quot; (an Eastern medicine procedure involving hot glass bulbs placed on the skin to drain toxins and stress). Stars are still just like us, you guys. [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/408990/jennifer-aniston-shows-off-cupping-marks-on-red-carpet" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li>Here's <strong>Girls' </strong><strong>Jemima Kirke </strong>kissing jewelry designer <strong>Pamela Love,</strong> both in wedding gowns, from the catalogue of Stone Fox Brides. [<a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20692093,00.html" target="_blank">People</a>]</li><li><strong>Will.i.am </strong>is going back to school to study quantum physics, although he already wrote his thesis on the subject, &quot;Boom Boom Pow.&quot; [<a href="http://www.ctvnews.ca/entertainment/will-i-am-is-going-back-to-school-to-study-computer-science-1.1242965" target="_blank">CTV News</a>]</li><li>I guess <a href="http://jezebel.com/leann-rimes-marriage-sitcom-in-the-works-not-that-amer-472407798">that $50,000 pen</a> was just a decoy; <strong>Robert Pattinson </strong>gave birthday girl <strong>Kristen Stewart </strong>his grandmother's opal ring AND THE BLESSING/CURSE OF IMMORTALITY. [<a href="http://hollywoodlife.com/2013/04/17/kristen-stewart-birthday-gift-robert-pattinson/" target="_blank">Hollywood Life</a>]</li><li><strong>Lisa Rinna </strong>may join <strong>The Real Housewives of Beverly Hills. </strong>[<a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/04/lisa-rinna-talks-join-real-housewives-of-beverly-hills/" target="_blank">Radar Online</a>]</li><li>The writers of E!'s <strong>Fashion Police </strong>are officially on strike. [<a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-207_162-57580070/e-s-fashion-police-writers-go-on-strike/" target="_blank">CBS News</a>]</li><li><strong>Jonah Hill </strong>bailed on three blondes to hang out with &quot;an older woman&quot; who happened to be <strong>Arianna Huffington's </strong>sister. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/hill_hits_town_with_huff_sis_FlZ0qXfhM69gF6SoUj8cJM" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li></ul>
<p><small><em>Image via <a href="http://www.gettyimages.com/" target="_blank">Getty</a>.</em></small></p>]]></description><category domain="">dirt bag</category><category domain="">rihanna</category><category domain="">miley cyrus</category><category domain="">liam hemsworth</category><category domain="">billy ray cyrus</category><category domain="">whoopi goldberg</category><category domain="">idris elba</category><category domain="">amber rose</category><category domain="">nick lachey</category><category domain="">mark wahlberg</category><category domain="">jennifer aniston</category><category domain="">william</category><category domain="">kristen stewart</category><category domain="">robert pattinson</category><category domain="">jonah hill</category><category domain="">lisa rinna</category><category domain="">fashion police</category><category domain="">jemima kirke</category><category domain="">pamela love</category><category domain="">kim kardashian</category><category domain="">justin bieber</category><category domain="">joy behar</category><category domain="">sylvester stallone</category><category domain="">gabby reece</category><category domain="">kanye west</category><category domain="">sharon osbourne</category><category domain="">krysten ritter</category><category domain="">idris elba ozzy osbourne</category><category domain="">nicki minaj</category><category domain="">mariah carey</category><category domain="">elizabeth hasselbeck</category><category domain="">stevie nicks</category><category domain="">britney spears</category><category domain="">tom cruise</category><category domain="">russell brand</category><category domain="">edward norton</category><category domain="">conan obrien</category><category domain="">bryce dallas howard</category><category domain="">peter dinklage</category><category domain="">katherine jackson</category><category domain="">debbie rowe</category><category domain="">michael jackson</category><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">475834510</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Breslaw]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fuck Cupcakes]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/fuck-cupcakes-475125988</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18ky2poli3wvtjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">The death of the cupcake is a victory for womankind. </p>
<p>The <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887324345804578425291917117814.html?mod=WSJ_hp_EditorsPicks" target="_blank"><em>Wall Street Journal</em></a> investigated gourmet-cupcake burnout today. <a href="http://online.wsj.com/public/quotes/main.html?type=djn&amp;symbol=CRMB" target="_blank">Crumbs Bake Shop</a> Inc., which once traded at more than $13 a share in mid-2011 (yes, on the real stock market, not in My Little Pony-ville), has sunk to a mere $1.70 — about a fourth of the price of a Crumbs cupcake, believe it or not — and expects sales to drastically slump throughout the year. Even more humble cupcake sellers said customers are &quot;getting tired&quot; of cupcakes, despite stores with names like &quot;Happy Cakes&quot; and &quot;Sweet Thing&quot; continuing to infiltrate our society like diabetes. </p>
<p>There's a Pinterest-worthy bakery in North Berkeley, California, that sells &quot;mini&quot; versions of its matcha green tea and lemon pistachio cupcakes. The store's cupcakes are already significantly &quot;mini&quot; so their diminutive replicas are offensively miniature; a dollhouse couple couldn't gorge themselves on one quarter-sized dessert. When I was in college, I'd often get a mini cupcake after class as a treat, which I'd finish in one gulping bite; in under a second I'd be left with nothing but a cloying, frosted aftertaste. I'd feel both guilty and unfulfilled as I scrunched up the adorable mini-wrapper with my chipped, unworthy fingernails. Weren't cupcakes supposed to make me happy?</p>
<p>The cupcake represents everything I am not but often wish I could be: domestic, meticulous, modest, sweet. Cupcakes represent measured indulgence. They represent capitalism. (More than $13 a share!) They represent prescribed modes of femininity and our cultural fixation on eternal girlhood. (Also, as Dodai <a href="http://jezebel.com/5911208/a-cupcake-is-never-just-a-cupcake-the-psycho+sexuality-of-a-twee-treat">pointed out</a> last year, &quot;a cupcake is a symbol for both a vagina and the female orgasm.&quot;) Therefore, I think I can confidently say that the death of the cupcake is a victory for feminism.</p>
<p>Why did it take this long for the cupcake to fall from its mighty pink throne? The financial crisis hit in 2008; the<em> Sex and the City </em>finale aired in 2004. Yet, the cupcake has remained the lone frilly indulgence we couldn't ditch out of recessionary guilt. And who even likes cupcakes anymore? Girls who tweet &quot;Been craving cup cakes for two days. TWO. DAYS! Must resist!&quot; and Instagram their glittery cupcake nail art. (Cupcakes fit very well on nail beds. This can't be a coincidence.) Also unsurprising: that some idiot made &quot;<a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=keep+calm+and+have+a+cupcake&amp;tbm=isch&amp;tbo=u&amp;source=univ&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=2hFvUfLDGdPI4AP66IGwAQ&amp;ved=0CFIQsAQ&amp;biw=970&amp;bih=617" target="_blank">Keep Calm and Have a Cupcake</a>&quot; into a thing. Cupcakes are tender parcels of meaningless drivel. Cupcakes are a distraction!</p>
<p>I asked Buzzfeed Food's Rachel Sanders how she felt the cupcake had impacted U.S. culture. &quot;This is getting a little deep, but I believe they tap into our American cultural tendency toward selfishness and emotional isolation,&quot; she typed to me via Gchat. &quot;Like, what other culture needs a kind of cake that is literally impossible to share; if you even try it just disintegrates into crumbs and sadness? You are going to be alone forever, so go ahead and carbo-load.&quot;</p>
<p>Let our collective fascination with cupcakes disintegrate into so many tiny sprinkles from this time forth.</p>

<p><em><small>Image via Ivonne Wierink/Shutterstock.</small></em></p>]]></description><category domain="">rant</category><category domain="">cupcakes</category><category domain="">food</category><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 22:45:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">475125988</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Katie J.M. Baker]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Catholic High School Fires Lesbian Coach for Being Gay]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/catholic-high-school-fires-lesbian-coach-for-being-gay-475004417</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18ky0wufrc4t6jpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">The Catholic Diocese of Columbus fired Bishop Watterson High School's much-beloved physical education teacher and coach after learning she was gay and living in sin. Is that even legal? It's unclear, but at least those poor children are safe from the clutches of a devil woman who was plotting to turn them all into lesbians, one soccer goal at a time.</p>
<p>Carla Hale taught at Bishop Watterson for 19 years — the <a href="http://www.bishopwatterson.com/academics/departments/health-and-physical-education" target="_blank">school's website</a> still lists her as Department Chair of Health and Physical Education Department — but was fired in late March after her mother's <a href="http://www.legacy.com/obituaries/dispatch/obituary.aspx?n=Jeanne-Roe&amp;pid=163314539#fbLoggedOut" target="_blank">obituary</a> effectively outed her;  it said she lived with a partner named Julie. (No Catholic men are named Julie.) Neither the Diocese, the school, nor Hale would comment, but Hale's attorney and multiple sources close to the situation confirmed that she would still be teaching kids how to shoot hoops today if it wasn't for her sexual orientation.</p>
<p>More than 7,000 people — including current students, alumni, and teachers — have signed a <a href="http://www.change.org/petitions/diocese-of-columbus-reinstate-faculty-member-carla-hale#share?utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=notification&amp;utm_campaign=new_petition_recruit" target="_blank">Change.org petition</a> urging the Diocese of Columbus to reinstate Hale. </p>
<p>&quot;Discrimination against someone for their sexuality is wrong,&quot; wrote a commenter who identified herself as Courtney Hale, ostensibly Carla's daughter. &quot;It is not our place to judge someone especially based on these terms. She is an amazing mother, friend, teacher, and all around person. That is how people should see her!&quot;</p>
<p>It’s the second time this year that Catholic schools in Ohio have fired educators for supporting gay rights, according to <a href="http://outlookcolumbus.com/2013/04/columbus-diocese-fires-gay-teacher-coach/" target="_blank">Outlook Columbus</a>. In February, an assistant principal at Purcell Marian High School in Cincinnati was fired by the Cincinnati Archiocese after he said he was pro-gay marriage on his personal blog.</p>
<p>On Bishop Watterson High School's website, there's a quote:</p>
<blockquote>&quot;Be it known to all who enter Bishop Watterson High School: Christ is the reason for this school, the unseen, but ever present teacher in the classes, the model of its faculty, and the inspiration of its students.&quot;</blockquote>
<p>It's common knowledge that J.C.  <s>preached tolerance and kindness</s> thought lesbians were icky.</p>]]></description><category domain="">holy crap</category><category domain="">bishop watterson</category><category domain="">lgbtq</category><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 21:40:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">475004417</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Katie J.M. Baker]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Vogue Runs Another Blackface Editorial]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/vogue-runs-another-blackface-editorial-474996107</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><em><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kxhjmvms1jujpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></em></p>
<p class="first-text"><em>Vogue </em>Netherlands has published an editorial featuring blackface makeup. The model in the story is Querelle Jansen, the stylist was Marije Goekoop, and the photographer was Ishi. Both Goekoop and Ishi are frequent contributors to the magazine. </p>
<p>The spread was intended to honor Marc Jacobs' work over the years for Louis Vuitton. For the fall, 2008, and spring, 2009, seasons, Jacobs took inspiration from black beauty icons Grace Jones and Josephine Baker. To represent those seasons — rather than hiring a black model — <em>Vogue </em>Netherlands painted Jansen's face black and had her wear a wig intended to mimic the texture of black hair. </p>
<p><em>Vogue </em>Paris <a href="http://jezebel.com/5379708/oh-no-they-didnt-french-vogue-does-blackface/">pioneered</a> the recent blackface trend in fashion with a 2009 editorial featuring Lara Stone and shot by Steven Klein. Blackface was subsequently copied by <em><a href="http://jezebel.com/5650170/the-latest-in-tasteful-blackface-fashion-shoots/">Numéro</a></em>, <em><a href="http:" target="_blank">L'Officiel Hommes</a></em>, <em><a href="http:" target="_blank">V</a>, <a href="http://jezebel.com/5987856/the-truth-about-using-a-white-girl-in-an-african-queen-fashion-shoot">Numéro</a> </em>(again), and the makeup brand <a href="http://jezebel.com/5963390/makeup-ad-features-particularly-blackface+y-blackface">Ilamasqua</a>. The blackface trend is so old, in fashion terms, that it's even been <a href="http://jezebel.com/5391756/antm-models-in-oh+so+trendy-blackface-shoot/">copied</a> by <em>America's Next Top Model</em>. Even ignoring, for argument's sake, the fact that blackface is offensive to many people, you'd think that fashion's tastemakers would conclude that blackface is, like, <em>totally played out</em>. Can you think of a single other trend from 2009 that's still getting referenced in editorial photography today? I can't. </p>
<p>It's particularly troubling that blackface persists in a fashion industry that continues to display an <a href="http://jezebel.com/5985110/new-york-fashion-weeks-models-are-getting-whiter">overwhelming</a> preference for white models. Models of color — even successful ones — often face discrimination on the basis of their race. Black models are <a href="http://jezebel.com/5991522/chanel-iman-still-hears-the-following-words-we-already-have-one-black-girl-we-dont-need-you">told</a> by clients that they won't be hired because they &quot;already have&quot; a black model, black models talk about <a href="http://jezebel.com/5993312/louis-vuitton-to-finally-stop-making-those-awkward-ads-with-celebrities">encountering</a> makeup artists and hair stylists who <a href="http://jezebel.com/5846472/jourdan-dunn-some-people-in-fashion-dont-know-how-to-handle-black-hair">refuse</a> to work with them, and black models say they have a harder time breaking into an industry that accords them fewer opportunities than white models. Models of color are also sometimes paid less than their white counterparts. It's not possible to argue that, all things being equal, blackface — despite its painful history in, particularly, the U.S. and Europe — <em>could</em> be an appropriate aesthetic reference for a fashion magazine or brand. Because for models of color working today, <em>things</em> <em>are not equal. </em></p>
<p>As Fashionista <a href="http://fashionista.com/2013/04/vogue-netherlands-blackface-editorial/" target="_blank">points out</a>, <em>Vogue</em> Netherlands has — even by the standards of high fashion, an industry where it's <a href="http://jezebel.com/5990201/worlds-top-fashion-weeks-nearly-90-white">normal</a> for 90% of the runway spots to go to white girls — a particularly poor track record when it comes to hiring models of color. The magazine is practically all-white. That, like fashion's apparently endless interest in blackface photos, seems sadly unlikely to change anytime soon. </p>]]></description><category domain="">fashion</category><category domain="">blackface</category><category domain="">black face</category><category domain="">blackface fashion</category><category domain="">vogue</category><category domain="">vogue netherlands</category><category domain="">vogue blackface</category><category domain="">vogue netherlands blackface</category><category domain="">vogue netherlands black face</category><category domain="">race</category><category domain="">racism</category><category domain="">racism in fashion</category><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 20:10:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">474996107</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jenna Sauers]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[This Week in Tabloids: Anne Hathaway Thinks Her Dog Isn't Hip Enough]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/this-week-in-tabloids-anne-hathaway-thinks-her-dog-isn-474983761</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kxj1w8fxbqrjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">Welcome back to your friendly neighborhood Midweek Madness, in which we send Tanisha Love Ramirez to the newsstand to pick up the latest issues of the celebrity weeklies and assist us in cuddling fuzzy gossip from <em>In Touch</em><strong>, </strong><em>Us</em><strong>, </strong><em>Ok!</em><strong>, </strong><em>Life &amp; Style</em><strong>, </strong>and <em>Star.</em></p>
<p><em><br/></em>This week, Kim Kardashian's fetus is ruining her life, Jennifer Aniston is pregnant again but for real this time, and Anne Hathaway wants to kick an old dog to the curb and get a new trick.   </p>
<hr/>

<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="418" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kxhqpemxq2yjpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p>
<p><em><strong>Life &amp; Style</strong></em></p>
<p>“This Baby Is Ruining My Life”</p>
<p>Have you guffawed today? In this week’s cover story, <strong>Kim and Kanye are so over Kim being pregnant. </strong>Poor pregnant Kim is becoming POOR pregnant Kim. Friends estimate that Kim, who used to make millions flaunting her famous figure at parties, book signings, fashion events, etc, has lost over<strong> $2 million in endorsements</strong>, deals and appearances since conceiving. According to a friend: “Nobody wants to see a pregnant woman partying at a nightclub and it’s not like she can shoot an ad campaign right now.” Kim is so desperate to remain relevant and marketable tha<strong>t she’s taken to making free appearances at book and magazine signings.</strong> <em>Free</em>, people. Furthermore, Kim is worried that her pregnancy has driven her baby-daddy away. According to the mag, Kimye have been together only a mere 18 days out of the 108 days since they announced Kim’s pregnancy. Next: Amid rumors of his infidelity, Blake Shelton admitted on <em>CBS This Morning</em> that his marriage to Miranda Lambert hasn’t been all roses and posies. But have no fear, <strong>Miranda is determined to keep her husband’s penis holstered with her new “husband–taming makeover,”</strong> complete with a little black dress that “lets it all hang out.” (Fig 1) You know what they say: If you set your boobs free and your husband comes back to you, he’s yours forever. Next: Jennifer Aniston has allegedly told friends to save yet another date, Adele wants to say “I doo-wop” in a ‘50s-themed wedding, Kristin Cavallari is now in possession of a bridal body, so that’s happening, and Olivia Wilde and Jason Sudeikis want to get married in the woods…er, sorry, wilderness! And lastly, <strong>Nicole Richie was spotted without her 4-carat diamond engagement ring</strong>, so the world is freaking out. Also, her kids weren’t on hand, so maybe she’s divorcing them too. </p>
<p><strong>Grade: F (dead dog)</strong></p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><em><strong><img height="418" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kxjh4qt0ixujpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>Ok!</strong></em></p>
<p>“Pregnant Kim Collapses”</p>
<p>…In <em>tears</em>, you guys. <strong>Kim collapsed into a fit of tears after fighting with Kanye about her looks.</strong> According to an insider—who is not the fetus— Kanye is putting a lot of pressure on Kim to look perfect, but refuses to help her dress her growing baby bump. Adding to her stress is the fact that<strong> Kanye insists recording his album in Paris, forcing Kim to endure her pregnancy alone in L.A.</strong> and travel long distances just to see him. Momager Kris has been trying to cheer Kim up, even joking about what good television Kim’s breakdown would make, because priorities. Meanwhile, Jessica Simpson’s family is stressing her out, with her parents refusing to play nice long enough to plan—and finally go through with—a wedding. Papa/Mama drama! Moving on. <strong>Farrah Abraham hopes to sell her recently debuted sex tape with James Deen for a couple of million</strong>. Yeah, ain’t nobody got time for dat. Finally, <strong>Blake Shelton is expected to preside over Kelly Clarkson’s nuptials</strong>, because who wouldn’t want a man who left his ex-wife for his current wife to join them in holy matrimony? </p>
<p><strong>Grade: F (sick puppy)</strong></p>

<hr/>

<p class="has-media media-300"><em><strong><img height="415" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kxih4fhlimgjpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>In Touch</strong></em></p>
<p>“The Truth at Last”</p>
<p>At last? This the same news and “truth” we’ve been fed for the last four weeks: People still think that <strong>Khloe Kardashian bears an uncanny resemblance to her mother’s hairdresser</strong> of 30 years, Alex Roldan, fueling rumors that Khloe isn’t actually a biological Kardashian. Rather than celebrate the fact that she only got one-half of the loony stick, Khloe is allegedly planning on confronting momager Kris Jenner about her paternity on one of their many reality shows. Dun, dun, duuuunnn! This all comes on the heels of a recent “take back my life” kick Khloe’s been on, complete with a tabloid-celebrated slim down, photographic evidence of her holding hands with her husband Lamar Odom and generally being the least annoying Kardashian. Truth is, we’re over it. Moving on. Call him a porn star, call his member tiny, call him maybe, but <strong>DO NOT call James Deen Farrah Abraham’s boyfriend.</strong> James claims Farrah tried to coerce him into pretending to be her boyfriend, to which he responded, “Absolutely not…I’m not a prostitute, and I’m not going to go on fake dates with people,” because, standards. Farrah, for her part, insists that the tape is only intended to celebrate her body, “So I can look back and remember how great I looked when I was 21.” Don't you wish you could remember how good your labia looked when you were young? Other famous-for-being-famous person Brandi Glanville is taking a break from drinking and tweeting to reveal who she’d like to play her in her ex’s scripted television show based on their divorce and his subsequent marriage to LeAnn Rimes.  Brandi’s pick: Denise Richards. Also in this issue: <strong>Prince Harry once dated a grocery store clerk named “Margaret”</strong>, Perez Hilton thinks that his former bestie Amanda Bynes should be committed and <strong>Russell Brand wants to have an orgy with the Kardashians</strong> because he “thinks pregnant women are radiant and the idea of lactation is an interesting one.” Klassy.</p>
<p><strong>Grade: D- (mean old dog)</strong></p>

<hr/>

<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="413" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kxfrahfvsufjpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p>
<p><em><strong>Us</strong></em></p>
<p>&quot;I'll Stand By My Man&quot;</p>
<p>The day after the Academy of Country Music Awards, <strong>Blake Shelton and his wife Miranda Lambert shot a music video and made out</strong>. They were, according to an eyewitness, &quot;all over each other.&quot; There are tons of infidelity rumors, yet Miranda trusts Blake: &quot;She knows he comes off as flirty,&quot; a source says. They're away from each other a lot, which is tough, but they Skype and text and call. Also, <strong>Miranda is the daughter of two private investigators, so she and Blake know each others' passwords and phone codes</strong>. &quot;I don't have to snoop anymore,&quot; Miranda says, adding that on Twitter: &quot;I like to check his direct messages.&quot; Sounds trusting! And not snoop-y at all. Also inside: Farrah Abraham says she made a porn movie with James Deen because: &quot;When I'm older, I'll have mybest year to look back on. As my young fans should expect, I made sure my partner was tested… and contraception was used.&quot; Um, <a href="http://nyobetabeat.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/markey_mark_wtf.gif" target="_blank">okay</a>. <strong>Kristen Stewart and Robert Pattinson hit Coachella</strong> where she danced to Postal Service. <strong>Amanda Bynes has &quot;snapped,&quot; according to a &quot;pal.&quot;</strong> She has an eating disorder, paranoid thoughts, changes her number and email every two weeks, and is increasingly isolated as she &quot;shuts down anyone who tells her she's not well.&quot; A doctor who has never met her diagnoses: &quot;She may be in the early stages of bipolar disorder.&quot; We skipped the story about Tori Spelling getting her body back and only skimmed the one about Matt Damon and his wife renewing their vows in St. Lucia — although since it was held on the beach, everyone wore ivory, white and cream, Jimmy Kimmel officiated and the kids played around a bonfire as the sun went down, it sounds perfect. But more important is this <strong>2-page spread of hotties from <em>Mad Men</em></strong> (Fig. 2) Everything — from the George Nelson clock to the rotary phone to the UN architecture print — is so delicious. We want to party with Harry Crane and Stan Rizzo.</p>
<p><strong>Grade: B- (loyal but snappy dog)</strong></p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="406" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kxg1hha02iljpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p>
<p><em><strong>Star</strong></em></p>
<p>&quot;Jen: Pregnant Bride!&quot;</p>
<p>HAHAHAHAHAHA. How fresh and new. Never ever heard this rumor before. It feels like being trapped in a groundhog day of a dream of a deja vu of a nightmare in a parallel dimension of infinite Unsolicited Uterus Updates. This time around <strong>Jennifer Aniston and Justin Theroux &quot;recently found out she's expecting a baby&quot;</strong> and that's not all — their wedding is &quot;just weeks away.&quot; Jen had her eggs frozen back in 2005, and the mag absurdly insists she and Justin &quot;talked about having children from day one.&quot; As in, she arrived at work on the movie set of <em>Wanderlust</em> and met her costar who'd been living with a woman for 14 yeas and said, &quot;Should we have a baby together?&quot; Anyway, <strong>Jen has &quot;already switched into mommy mode,&quot;</strong> which is a thing women, with all of our levers and buttons and gears, can do quite easily. J'Anthrax is redoing the house so it will be less swanky LA pad and more family-friendly home. Body expert Alicia Hunter — who recently declared that Kim Kardashian to be seven zillion pounds — insists that <strong>Jen is already showing</strong>: &quot;She appears to be filling out… Her bust looks fuller, and her normally wispy waist looks much less defined. Even her arms look softer!&quot; Hunter calls these &quot;early indications of pregnancy,&quot; and if so, 89% of the women and 82% of the dudes we know are pregnant right now. Anyway, Jen's thrilled to be pregnant and &quot;keeps calling the baby 'my little miracle.'&quot; As in, it will be a miracle if <em>Star</em> is actually correct this time. (Just FYI, Star declared Jen pregnant in <a href="http://jezebel.com/5958554/this-week-in-tabloids-rihanna-queen-of-bad-ideas-is-trying-to-get-pregnant-by-chris-brown">November 2012</a>, claimed she was having twins in <a href="http://jezebel.com/5883401/this-week-in-tabloids-courtney-the-evil-succubus-maneater-will-devour-bachelor-ben">February 2012</a>, and also claimed she was having twins in <a href="http://jezebel.com/5868134/this-week-in-tabloids-jen-anistons-neighbor-saw-her-baby-bump-from-a-kitchen-window">December 2011</a>. This is the longest gestational period EVER. Also inside: Julianne Hough and Leonardo DiCaprio &quot;flirted up a storm&quot; at Coachella. <strong>Anne Hathaway has decided her faithful old Labrador, Esmerelda, isn't cool enough for Hollywood. </strong>&quot;Anne really wants a stylish young puppy she can play and interact with&quot; says an insider who just might be Esmerelda. &quot;She says she just can't bond with a dog that's half dead — it's not quite the glamourous look she's going for now that she's won an Oscar.&quot; You guys, if this cur is  spreading rumors about Annie, she is a bitch.<strong> Rachel Zoe's TV show has been canceled and Cameron Diaz, Kate Hudson, and Eva Mendes have all dumped her as a stylist</strong>, because she's way too expensive. The A-listers are turning to lesser known edgy stylists who are much cheaper and Zoe might go broke. What else? Catherine Giudici from The Bachelor is &quot;a total drunk.&quot; After losing her husband and being attacked politically, <strong>Ashley Judd might have a breakdown</strong>. Lisa Vanderpump was topless in a 1978 British horror flick called Killer's Moon. And finally, why didn't anyone tell us this??!? <strong>Britney's new boyfriend is named David &quot;Lucky&quot; Lucado.</strong> LUCKY. She's a star. But she cry, cry, cries in her lonely heart.</p>
<p><strong>Grade: C- (accidentally knocked-up dog)</strong></p>
<hr/>

<h4>Addendum:</h4>

<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="564" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kxj7hhj5309jpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p>
<p><em>Fig. 1, from Life &amp; Style</em></p>

<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="438" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kxgreqsxogijpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p><em>Fig. 2, from Us</em></p>
]]></description><category domain="">midweek madness</category><category domain="">this week in tabloids</category><category domain="">anne hathaway</category><category domain="">kim kardashian</category><category domain="">ok</category><category domain="">in touch</category><category domain="">life  style</category><category domain="">us</category><category domain="">us weekly</category><category domain="">star</category><category domain="">star magazine</category><category domain="">tabloids</category><category domain="">celebrity</category><category domain="">roundup</category><category domain="">gossip</category><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 19:06:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">474983761</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dodai Stewart]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Children of Ohio, You Are Officially Screwed When It Comes to Sex Ed]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/children-of-ohio-you-are-officially-screwed-when-it-co-474352940</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kxiyntfxl5hjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Apparently being known for <a href="http://jezebel.com/Steubenville">Steubenville</a> isn't enough for Ohio — they're now trying to corner the market on not educating their teens about sex. Yesterday, the Ohio House Finance Committee's Republican members voted to adopt a state budget amendment that mandates an abstinence-only approach to sexual education. Oh, Ohio.</p>
<p>The idiotic measure will &quot;prohibit the teaching of sexual education coursework that endorses non-abstinence as an acceptable behavior or promotes sexual gateway activity.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Sexual Gateway Activity&quot; — what's that? Who's he?: </p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="http://codes.ohio.gov/orc/2907.01" target="_blank">ORC 2907.01(B)</a> “Sexual contact” means any touching of an erogenous zone of another, including without limitation the thigh, genitals, buttock, pubic region, or, if the person is a female, a breast, for the purpose of sexually arousing or gratifying either person.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In addition, teachers can't distribute contraceptives at school, because nothing keeps a teen not pregnant more than not giving them condoms. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>So... educators must pretend that teenager's normal and natural sexual feelings and actions are just not happening. And if they're questioned by students — they just, what? Tell them to put an ice pack on That Which Is Most Sacred and read the bible? Just make sure they skip that sassy Genesis 19:30-36! And forget about Genesis 29: 21-28, too — RAU-NCHY. Actually, maybe just skip that whole section.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Even worse, parents can sue educators if they feel the provisions were violated. &quot;You told my daughter that sex exists — that'll be one million dollars, please!&quot;</p>
<p>Once again, with feeling: Abstinence-only education <a href="http://jezebel.com/5950986/taxpayers-still-giving-millions-of-dollars-to-abstinence+only-education-programs-that-dont-work">DOES NOT WORK</a>. Even more to the point, teenagers who receive comprehensive sex education are <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2008/03/24/AR2008032401515.html" target="_blank">60 percent less likely</a> to get pregnant (or to get someone else pregnant), and teen pregnancies are <a href="http://thinkprogress.org/health/2012/04/10/461402/teen-pregnancy-sex-education/" target="_blank">highest</a> in abstinence-only states. Welcome to the club, Ohio — hope you have lots of extra money in that budget to help with the influx of teen moms. </p>
<p>Unfortunately, Ohio isn't the only state that naively thinks abstinence-only education can save its youth, plenty of other states are peddling this b.s. That said, even Mississippi, the state with the <a href="http://thechart.blogs.cnn.com/2012/04/10/u-s-teen-birth-rate-drops-to-a-record-low/" target="_blank">highest</a> teen birth rate, has significantly <a href="http://jezebel.com/5951817/some-mississippi-schools-rethink-abstinence+only-education">wised up</a>.  </p>
<p>Although <a href="http://jezebel.com/terrifying-public-high-school-speaker-if-you-take-birt-472610594">scaring kids with tales of disease and regret</a> will only get educators so far. According to the Guttmacher Institute's <a href="http://www.guttmacher.org/pubs/FB-Teen-Sex-Ed.html" target="_blank">research</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The majority (86%) of the decline in the teen pregnancy rate between 1995 and 2002 was the result of dramatic improvements in contraceptive use, including an increase in the proportion of teens using a single method of contraception, an increase in the proportion using multiple methods simultaneously and a substantial decline in nonuse. Just 14% of the decline is attributable to decreased sexual activity.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You can terrify a few innocent souls into abstinence with stories of girls who dry humped and then were stricken with a genital warts-herpes hybrid that ate their homework, but the vast majority of teens will still bone. Even if they take the scary messages to heart, they still might end up boning — this time without condoms because they never learned any better. (Or possibly anal so they can still go to heaven. Praise be!)</p>
<p>When it comes to sex, teens have taken a horny version of Alec Baldwin's <em>Glengarry Glen Ross </em>speech to heart: Always Be Boning. And trust — they approach boning with as much passion as Baldwin does closing. </p>
<p>The best we can do as adults is to educate them about their options — and yes, abstinence is one. So is birth control. If we speak openly and honestly with teens, we might even be able to destigmatize sex. We could even teach teens to respect each other's boundaries and to communicate clearly about desires. Invaluable lessons that would yield happier, healthier adults.</p>
<p>But by subscribing to useless, inane, and antiquated abstinence-only education, we cut teens off from the whole truth — they're forced to piece it together on their own from their friends and the media. No wonder our culture has such a fucked up relationship with sex — and a difficult time understanding what does and doesn't constitute consent. </p>
<p>Clear boundaries are never explained or explored, and it's no surprise many teens have backwards ideas of what they are and aren't entitled to. If we pretend sex is something that only happens between married people, we can continue to ignore the painful truth of what's really at stake. If we're unable to speak openly with kids about these things, then we an expect more shitty business as usual. Ohio already knows plenty about <a href="http://jezebel.com/tag/steubenville">that</a>. </p>
<p>[<a href="http://innovationohio.org/2013/04/16/ohio-republicans-propose-restrictions-on-sex-ed-that-promotes-gateway-activity/" target="_blank">Innovation Ohio</a>] </p>
<p><small><em>Image via Lisa F. Young/<a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/" target="_blank">Shutterstock</a>.</em></small></p>]]></description><category domain="">abstinence</category><category domain="">abstinence-only education</category><category domain="">sex ed</category><category domain="">sexual education</category><category domain="">ohio</category><category domain="">laws</category><category domain="">teenagers</category><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 17:50:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">474352940</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Laura Beck]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[New Hampshire State Rep.]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/thoughtful-republican-lawmaker-refers-to-women-as-vagi-474843809</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kxd4h20v673jpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">New Hampshire State Rep. Peter Hansen has pissed off the entire New Hampshire House of Representatives after he sent out an email to the official legislative listserv referring to women as &quot;vaginas.&quot;</p>
<p>Engaging in a debate about a <a href="http://www.gencourt.state.nh.us/legislation/2013/HB0135.html" target="_blank">gun bill</a>, State Rep. Hansen made his offensive comment in response to his colleague's recent speech about the benefits of retreating instead of using deadly force. Hansen sent out an email to everyone on the listserv saying:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What could possibly be missing from those factual tales of successful retreat in VT, Germany, and the bowels of Amsterdam? Why children and vagina's of course. While the tales relate the actions of a solitary male the outcome cannot relate to similar situations where children and women and mothers are the potential victims.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>People, including members of his own party were immediately put off by his &quot;crude catch-all for women,&quot; with State Republican chair Jennifer Horn calling his comment &quot;disrespectful and shameful.&quot;</p>
<p>After being called out on how inappropriate his language was, Hansen tried to turn it around, saying that people's discomfort with the word &quot;vagina&quot; is what's really problematic.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Having a fairly well educated mind I do not need self appointed wardens to A: try to put words in my mouth for political gain and B: Turn a well founded strategy in communication into an insulting accusation, and finally if you find the noun vagina insulting or in some way offensive then perhaps a better exercise might be for you to re-examine your psyche.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Oh, OK. So people who are offended by his use of the word &quot;vagina&quot; to reduce half of the population to nothing but the hole between their legs are actually the sexist ones. Got it.</p>
<p>As the <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/peter-hansen-new-hampshire-vaginas_n_3095135.html" target="_blank">Huffington Post</a> points out:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Hansen's comments are particularly bold in New Hampshire, the only state with a female governor and <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/01/02/us/politics/from-congress-to-halls-of-state-in-new-hampshire-women-rule.html" target="_blank">an all-female delegation</a> to Congress. The speaker of the state House and the chief justice of the state Supreme Court also are both women.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Perhaps that's why he eventually kinda/sorta apologized, weeks later.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Can there be any doubt my comment is being misinterpreted and taken completely out of context? It was not, and is not, my intention to demean women at any time. It is apparent that the intent of my remarks has been misinterpreted, the true goal of the message lost and for that I apologize to those who took offense.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Whatever. Can you really be that surprised by Hansen's comments? If anything, they seem to be an aboveboard indication of what <a href="http://jezebel.com/tag/roe-v-world">his party thinks about women</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/peter-hansen-new-hampshire-vaginas_n_3095135.html" target="_blank">Peter Hansen, New Hampshire Lawmaker, Calls Women 'Vaginas' In Email To Colleagues</a> [HuffPo]</p>]]></description><category domain="">wtf</category><category domain="">vaginas</category><category domain="">peter hansen</category><category domain="">new hampshire</category><category domain="">republicans</category><category domain="">politics</category><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 16:47:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">474843809</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracie Egan Morrissey]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tragedy Is Not a Competition: How to Talk About Boston]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/tragedy-is-not-a-competition-how-to-talk-about-boston-474794161</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><strong><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kwrc4aplffujpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></strong></p>
<p class="first-text"><em>Welcome to a very special episode of Friendzone, Jezebel's column devoted to dealing with the valuable people in your life who you're not humping. </em><em>In this installment, we're tackling<a href="http://jezebel.com/this-is-off-topic-but-how-do-i-deal-with-friends-who-p-473443938"> one</a> from the comments on Boston: dealing with your sanctimonious friend who says we should reallllly be talking about [insert other awful thing here], which is &quot;so much worse&quot; or whatever.  </em></p>
<p><strong>How do I deal with friends who post things like, &quot;Yes, bombing in the US is bad, but what we need to be talking about is the US sending drones to bomb other countries&quot;? The same friend posted an article a few weeks back that said (paraphrasing), &quot;Sure, there are issues with LGBT Americans, but most of them are well enough off that marriage equality shouldn't be a big issue. While you were too busy paying attention to the Supreme Court, Obama signed a bill protecting Monsanto's ability to grow GMO crops, and that's a way bigger problem.&quot; </strong></p>
<p><strong>I have a hard time reading these things and not feeling shitty about everything; they make me feel guilty for some reason. How do I respond? Is it even productive? Why can't this friend just talk about their concern about drones separately from the Boston Marathon? Isn't raising awareness about issues one at a time better than being elitist about the ones you think are more important than others?</strong><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Ah, the pretentious Facebook shit-starter. Convinced she alone truly understands the way things ought to be, she just loves posting opinions and ideas that run counter to what she regards as unenlightened conventional wisdom. Less sophisticated beings may be wasting their time mourning the terrible loss of life in Boston, but <em>she </em>has her eye on the Big Picture. She's wiser. She's more clever. And she can't wait to prove it to you.</p>
<p>Let me be clear. I don't entirely disagree with your friend, at least not politically. She makes some salient points that are perhaps worth discussing in a forum more suited to intellectual and ethical discourse than frigging Facebook. But she's intentionally being a pain in the ass in order to gain attention – as if all 563 of her friends are actually going to say, &quot;Hey, great point you made on the FB, Alicia. Time to march on Washington to demand the end to program X or special cause Y. Wow. You've really changed things.&quot;</p>
<p>If she's a good friend whom you do not care to insult, simply hide her provocative posts from your newsfeed. If she's a &quot;meh&quot; friend about whom you don't actually give much of a rat's patootie, defriend her. You're not going to change her mind, and you're not going to win any heroism points by going off on her on Facebook. What we need to do here is ease your mind, and the best way to do that is to get her purposely pot-stirring posts out of your face.</p>
<p>As for your guilt – I'd say it's entirely unnecessary. You are allowed to feel bad for bombing victims in Boston and drone strike victims in Pakistan. You are even allowed to hold these two thoughts in your head <em>at the same time</em>. Unlike your friend, who seems to see life as an either/or proposition, you seem to grasp the concept that reality is far more complicated than anything one might express in a Facebook status update.</p>

<p><em>Got an issue and looking for guidance? Email <a href="mailto:friendzone@jezebel.com">friendzone@jezebel.com</a>.</em></p>]]></description><category domain="">boston marathon</category><category domain="">friendzone</category><category domain="">advice</category><category domain="">tragedy</category><category domain="">friends</category><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 14:50:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">474794161</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sara Benincasa]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Adele Says Fanks But No Fanks to Seven-Figure Memoir Paycheck]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/adele-says-fanks-but-no-fanks-to-seven-figure-memoir-pa-474712342</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kwoqw359r3ljpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">Although <strong>Adele</strong> and her people have been meeting with Harper Collins to discuss a possible book deal (with a seven-figure offer), it won't be a memoir because, at 24, she thinks she's too young. </p>
<p>&quot;Adele's never been a really showy person. So it was always going to take a lot to get her to write her life story anyway. [...] But even though she received a lucrative offer, her primary concern was that she doesn't want to write a book about just 24 years. She feels she'd rather wait until she has more life experience to write about.&quot; <a href="http://jezebel.com/5988442/adele-saying-fank-you-is-the-best-sound-in-the-world">Fank you</a>. [<a href="http://www.belfasttelegraph.co.uk/entertainment/news/adele-far-too-young-to-write-memoir-29203231.html" target="_blank">Belfast Telegraph</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><strong><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kwnujyuxtlojpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></strong></p>
<p><strong>Baby Goose </strong>is quickly becoming a parody of himself, but in the BEST WAY, and I love it. While filming his onscreen son's baptism scene in <strong>The Place Beyond The Pines,</strong> he started to cry. &quot;I didn't know that was going to happen. I was just sitting in the church watching a baby to be baptised, and I don't know why I was emotional, but I was.&quot; (And furthermore: &quot;The kid who plays my son - his name is Tony Pizza. It's hard not to like a guy named Tony Pizza. We really hit it off.&quot;) [<a href="http://www.entertainmentwise.com/news/111845/Ready-For-Evas-Babies-Ryan-Gosling-Hints-Hes-Broody-After-Getting-Emotional-Over-Baby-Scenes-" target="_blank">Entertainmentwise</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="180" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kwnnx8004qpgif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p>
<p>Like the rest of us,<strong> Amanda Seyfried</strong> did <em>not</em> have ESPN about her former co-star <strong>Lindsay Lohan's </strong>future downward spiral when the two shot <strong>Mean Girls.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>She's been feverishly following news of a possible musical adaptation on Broadway. &quot;I desperately want to be Regina,&quot; she says. When they were shooting, she had a great admiration for the film's lead, Lindsay Lohan, though they weren't really friends. &quot;She's talented.&quot; A pause. &quot;Was.&quot; Another pause. &quot;I mean, I don't know.... She was so bright-eyed.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://www.allure.com/celebrity-trends/cover-shoot/2013/amanda-seyfried#slide=5" target="_blank">Allure</a>]</p>
<p>Meanwhile, back at the ranch, <strong>Lindsay Lohan's </strong>still looking for a rehab that's not too hot, not too cold, but just right. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/where_will_lilo_do_rehab_WuFKiJ8vVwpoPCAcHhCPVJ" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><strong><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kwo8uxwbb48jpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></strong></p>
<p><strong>Jaden Smith </strong>is unclear about his possible romantic relationship with <strong>Kylie</strong> <strong>Jenner</strong>, although he does say she's Pretty Baller and Pretty Awesome: “I went to New York and [Kylie] came too, and then she came here [to London] and surprised me, so that’s pretty baller. She’s one of my best friends. It’s pretty awesome.” [<a href="http://hollywoodlife.com/2013/04/16/jaden-smith-kylie-jenner-dating-best-friends-interview/" target="_blank">Hollywood Life</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<ul><li>Could that <strong>Friends </strong>reunion season rumor you saw floating around Twitter yesterday BE any less true? [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/408723/friends-reunion-report-makes-internet-implode-but-it-s-not-happening-yet" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li>A weird topless photo of <strong>Angelina Jolie </strong>having her breast nibbled by a horse is up for auction and might make up to $33,000. [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/topless-angelina-jolie-photo-hits-auction-block-article-1.1318259" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</li><li><strong>50 Cent </strong>thinks Anne Frank would, indeed, <a href="http://jezebel.com/justin-bieber-hopes-anne-frank-would-have-been-a-belie-472944407">have been a belieber</a>. Namaste. [<a href="http://www.vulture.com/2013/04/50-cent-and-mark-wahlberg-weigh-in-on-bieber.html?mid=twitter_vulture" target="_blank">Vulture</a>]</li><li><strong>Sharon Osbourne </strong>plans on returning to <strong>Ozzy </strong>when he's been clean for months. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/17/sharon-osbourne-ozzy-split-clean-drug-alcohol-sober/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Shakira </strong>and her ex-boyfriend <strong>Antonio de la Rua</strong>, the son of the former Argentine president, are fighting over who created her &quot;brand.&quot; [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/shakira-slams-lawsuit-claims-crafted-brand-article-1.1318716" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</li><li><strong>Rick Ross </strong>is down in the dumps after loosing his Reebok deal for those pesky date rape lyrics. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/17/rick-ross-reebok-apology-date-rape-song-u-o-e-n-o/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Leonardo DiCaprio </strong>says that &quot;being off in Morocco&quot; or whatever for a film doesn't make relationships easy. [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/leonardo-dicaprio-work-isn-best-relationship-article-1.1318372" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</li><li><strong>Debbie Harry </strong>approves of <strong>One Direction. </strong>[<a href="http://www.contactmusic.com/news/one-direction-given-blondie-s-approval_3610886" target="_blank">Contact Music</a>]</li><li><strong>Malin Akerman </strong>had a baby boy named <strong>Sebastian. </strong>[<a href="http://celebritybabies.people.com/2013/04/16/malin-akerman-welcomes-son-sebastian/" target="_blank">People</a>]</li><li><strong>Psy </strong>continues taking over YouTube/the world. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/psy_gentleman_climbs_youtube_charts_dlJSJ7PZyipLQlhAOOMT0N" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li><strong>Lisa Vanderpump </strong>has tits. [<a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/04/lisa-vanderpump-topless-nude-scene-photo/" target="_blank">Radar Online</a>]</li><li><strong>Pamela Anderson </strong>says she's never really felt beautiful. [<a href="http://www.tv3.ie/entertainment_article.php?locID=1.803.810&amp;article=100952" target="_blank">TV3ie</a>]</li><li>She looks great and relatively understated here, incidentally. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-style/news/pamela-anderson-unveils-modest-makeover-looks-breathtaking-at-45-2013164" target="_blank">People</a>]</li><li><strong>Lara Flynn Boyle. </strong>:-| [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-beauty/news/lara-flynn-boyle-looks-unrecognizable-during-outing-2013164" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li>Some pictures of <strong>Matt Damon's </strong>vow renewal ceremony with wife <strong>Luciana. </strong>[<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/matt-damons-vow-renewal-see-pictures-from-the-star-studded-beach-ceremony-2013164" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><strong>Bruno Mars </strong>wants &quot;a weird circus wedding&quot; and &quot;Eye of The Tiger&quot; for the bride's entrance song. Form an orderly queue, laydeez. [<a href="http://tvnz.co.nz/entertainment-news/bruno-mars-would-like-weird-circus-wedding-5409637" target="_blank">TVNZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Hayden Panettiere </strong>likes money. I mean, cotton. [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/408482/hayden-panettiere-goes-country-as-new-face-of-cotton-campaign-mdash-watch-now?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-topstories&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_topstories" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li>NOOO. <strong>Dick Van Dyke's</strong> rep says that he's suffering&quot;fatigue and lack of sleep resulting from symptoms of a yet-to-be diagnosed neurological disorder.&quot; [<a href="http://www.torontosun.com/2013/04/17/dick-van-dyke-has-suspected-neurological-disorder" target="_blank">Toronto Sun</a>]</li></ul>]]></description><category domain="">dirt bag</category><category domain="">adele</category><category domain="">ryan gosling</category><category domain="">amanda seyfried</category><category domain="">mean girls</category><category domain="">lindsay lohan</category><category domain="">jaden smith</category><category domain="">lara flynn boyle</category><category domain="">bruno mars</category><category domain="">dick van dyke</category><category domain="">hayden panettiere</category><category domain="">sharon osbourne</category><category domain="">ozzy osbourne</category><category domain="">shakira</category><category domain="">rick ross</category><category domain="">leonardo dicaprio</category><category domain="">debbie harry</category><category domain="">one direction</category><category domain="">psy</category><category domain="">lisa vanderpump</category><category domain="">pamela anderson</category><category domain="">matt damon</category><category domain="">luciana damon</category><category domain="">malin akerman</category><category domain="">antonio de la rua</category><category domain="">kylie jenner</category><category domain="">friends reunion</category><category domain="">angelina jolie</category><category domain="">50 cent</category><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">474712342</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Breslaw]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[10 Types of Men That Women Definitely Do NOT Want to Marry!]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/10-types-of-men-that-women-definitely-do-not-want-to-ma-473051378</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kuavqc2u10vpng/ku-xlarge.png" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">If there's one thing I know about women, it's that there are 11 types of us: ten types that men do <em>not</em> want to marry, and then the wife type. If you're one of the ten gross unwifeable kinds, WOE BETIDE YOU, because not only are you dumb and annoying and probably love your mom too much, you also can't fulfill your womanly prime directive! Which is to get married. At all cost. To whomever. AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.</p>
<p>At least, that's what I learned from Samantha Daniels's &quot;<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/samantha-daniels/10-types-of-women-a-man-w_b_2911111.html" target="_blank">10 Types of Women That Men Do Not Want to Marry</a>,&quot; a handy personality checklist for women who just want to be married to anyone no matter what and are eager to carve up their personalities into a freakish amalgam of bland woman-tropes so they can land the kind of man who likes women who aren't human beings. In other words...rrrrrrrromance! The 10 types of unmarriageable hags include: Miss &quot;I Have Daddy Issues,&quot; Miss &quot;I Want To Change You,&quot; Miss &quot;Bossy Pants,&quot; Miss &quot;I Live For You And I Have Nothing Else Going On,&quot; Miss &quot;I Speak To My Mother Five Times A Day About Everything,&quot; and Miss &quot;I Don't Eat.&quot;</p>
<p>Because yep. That's what people are like! We just have one personality trait each, like Smurfs. (Be sure to tune in for next week's column: &quot;The One Type of Female Smurf that All the Other Smurfs <a href="http://images1.wikia.nocookie.net/__cb20130104110813/smurfsfanon/images/2/2c/Vanity_Smurf_(Glovey_Story).gif" target="_blank">Except One</a> Totally Want to Bang.&quot;)</p>
<p>But turnabout is fair play—ladies shouldn't have to settle for just any old man, and we shouldn't be the only ones invested in self-improvement in the name of wedlock. So, after thorough scientific research, I've made my own <em>equally sensical</em> list, dividing all the men on earth into the ten types of men that there are. On earth. Make sure you're not any of these men and you will definitely get a whole bunch of wives—guaranteed! It's science like that!</p>
<p><strong>1. Mr. &quot;Oh No! What's My Job? I Don't Have a Job!&quot;</strong></p>
<p>Soooooo typical. The old &quot;I fell off the belltower and got amnesia and now I've reverted to my wise-cracking high school alter-ego 'T-Bone' and I can't remember what my job is&quot; excuse. If I had a nickel for every time I heard that one, I wouldn't have to date guys with jobs! I'd be nickel-rich!!!</p>
<p><strong>2. Mr. &quot;Lives with Parents&quot;</strong></p>
<p>Oh, but not with <em>his</em> parents. Sorry for the confusion. He just got drunk one time, wandered into some random house, went to sleep in the baby's room, and started calling the people who live there Mommy and Daddy. It's like, grow <em>up</em>, Reggie.</p>
<p><strong>3. Mr. &quot;Nyeeehhhhhhh, I Work for the Phone Company and I'm Wearing a Windbreaker&quot;</strong></p>
<p>Yeah, it's pretty cool that you're impervious to wind, but quit being so fucking smug.</p>
<p><strong>4. Mr. &quot;Shipwrecked on a Deserted Island&quot;</strong></p>
<p>That dude is <em>never</em> going to be president.</p>
<p><strong>5. Mr. &quot;I Have Bee Beard and I'm Jealous of Other People with Better Bee Beards&quot;</strong></p>
<p>Obviously not good husband material—he can't even get good bees!</p>
<p><strong>6. Mr. &quot;Pretends to Be a Suit of Armor with a Guy Inside but Instead Is Just an Empty Suit of Armor Animated By a Ghost&quot;</strong></p>
<p>SO TIRED OF MY DATES <del>WALKING OUT ON ME</del> DISSIPATING INTO THE NIGHT AIR WITH A KEENING WAIL JUST BECAUSE I CRACKED OPEN THE VISOR ON THEIR GREATHELM. </p>
<p><strong>7. Mr. &quot;Has a Close Relationship with His Family and Friends and Often Puts Others' Happiness Before His Own but Not in a Destructive Way, Just a Nice Way&quot;</strong></p>
<p>Ugh. Nerd.</p>
<p><strong>8. Mr. &quot;Bag of Hair Who Can't Stand Your Mother&quot;</strong></p>
<p>Not only is he a bag of damp human hair incapable of thought or speech—or much of anything, really, except for accruing mildew and deterring superstitious burglars (try leaving him on your windowsill at night!)—he <em>doesn't even like your mother</em>. Dealbreaker!!!</p>
<p><strong>9. Mr. &quot;Always Makes You Be Both Halves of the Two-Person Horse Costume&quot;</strong></p>
<p>Then he calls you &quot;Mrs. Horse&quot; in front of the neighbors.</p>
<p><strong>10. Mr. &quot;Belvedere&quot;</strong></p>
<p>Been there, done that. YOU BURNED ME ONCE, LYNN BELVEDERE. Never again. Never again.</p>

<p>Look. Here's what this silly joke article means. Marriage for marriage's sake isn't how people become happy. Married you will be no happier than single you. Changing your own unhealthy impulses, for the sake of marriage <em>as an end in itself</em>, is not a healthy impulse. There are no &quot;types&quot; of people that &quot;men&quot; or &quot;women&quot; want to marry, and there's no listicle that's going to heal your loneliness. There are people and then there are other people and sometimes people fall in love with each other despite their faults and they get married or they don't and it works out or it doesn't. So work on yourself, fine—work on your bee beard, work on your clinginess—but do it because it's good for <em>you</em>. Making marriage your goal (instead of, say, happiness! Or compatibility!) is like saving up all your money to buy a really expensive lottery ticket. Quit it.</p>
<p><em><small>Image by Jim Cooke.</small></em></p>]]></description><category domain="">i thee dread</category><category domain="">relationships</category><category domain="">marriage</category><category domain="">dating</category><category domain="">sex</category><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 21:30:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">473051378</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Lindy West]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Get Over In-Flight Anxiety (Without Gobbling Pills or Drinks)]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/how-to-get-over-in-flight-anxiety-without-gobbling-pil-473048690</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18ku17jcnmdfrjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">With almost <a href="http://flyfright.com/statistics/" target="_blank">one in three</a> American adults anxious about flying, the de-stress ritual of a pre-flight cocktail to in-flight glass of wine/quaaludes routine is coming to be everyone's go-to for dealing with flying nerves. Now, ain't nothing wrong with a little booze or a couple of clonazepam to calm your nerves (or maybe there definitely is?), but for longer flights, numbing your anxiety with copious amounts of alcohol and/or pills isn't always the best travel plan, unless you plan on drunkenly finding your luggage and making out with a bag of Doritos while doing so.</p>
<p>Personally, my fear of flying doesn't stem from fear of an airplane crash as much as it does from hating sitting in a tin can for hours on end next to someone who usually smells like a sandwich. Or maybe I'm the one who smells like a sandwich? IDK, something somewhere on all airplanes smells like an old turkey sandwich to me, and me and my nerves don't like it, so I've tried my fair share of attempts to tackle in-flight anxiety.</p>
<p>Now, there's a whole subcategory of self-help books dedicated to getting over your flying anxiety. (Brief aside: SELF-HELP FOR ANXIOUS PEOPLE WILL MAKE YOU MORE ANXIOUS. Unless those &quot;How to Cure Your Anxiety&quot; books are printed on Xanax paper, avoid that shit like it's the anxiety plague. Sorry, everyone who makes money from selling <a data-amazontag="jezebelamzn-20" data-amazonasin="" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Best-Anxiety-Books/lm/R2XJSDDSVUZ0GY?tag=jezebelamzn-20&amp;ascsubtag=link">anxiety books</a> on Amazon.) In my experience, most of the advice is as effective, if not less effective, than rubbing a voodoo amulet and speaking in tongues in the bathroom before getting on the plane. </p>
<p>Here's some of the strange stuff I've tried in the past: </p>
<p><strong>1. Bring a photo of your destination and stare at it: </strong></p>
<p>Did it work? If by &quot;work&quot; you mean &quot;look like someone obsessed with Minneapolis, Minnesota on a plane,&quot; then yes.</p>
<p><strong>2. Pretend like you're not on a plane: </strong></p>
<p>This one has mixed results, and it depends on how into your in-flight entertainment you can get. That one flight that had &quot;Save the Last Dance&quot; as our in-flight movie was a breeze, because pretending to be Julia Stiles in an urban RomCom comes very easily to me, so I was imaging myself dancing in a sports bra/cargo pants combo for the entirety of the flight. That's the opposite of feeling anxious. </p>
<p><strong>3. Talk to your neighbor:</strong></p>
<p>If your neighbor is a grandma or someone's uncle from Georgia on Adderall, this can work. In fact, this can work very well. Several flights have begun with near panic attacks and ended with me explaining what &quot;based&quot; means to a very Midwestern grandma as she hands me a Werther's Original. </p>
<p><strong>4. Memorize very lyric of every song on a Lil Wayne album</strong></p>
<p>Half of the time he's so incomprehensible that you'll become entirely focused on first translating his daunting body of work and ultimately become fixated on whether Lil Wayne leads a life of satire and is a physical embodiment of the state of modern society or if he… wait, I'm on a plane right now?</p>
<p><strong>5. Embrace your anxiety</strong></p>
<p>Don't do this. The one time I decided to let my anxiety take hold, a small French man held my hand and said, &quot;Just pretend she is a biiiiiiig bus&quot; for three hours straight. It was, as they say, in French, <em>trop terrible</em>. </p>
<p>Okay, that's me. You?</p>
]]></description><category domain="">anxiety</category><category domain="">flying</category><category domain="">tips</category><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">473048690</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Meher Ahmad]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fuck Fate and Date Like a Grown-Up]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/fuck-fate-and-date-like-a-grown-up-472976491</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kqnnsj61md8png/ku-xlarge.png" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">You want to believe that if you’re a good girl, the world will deliver unto you the Perfect Guy. That Fate or God is the ultimate matchmaker, pulling the strings of your life to make shit happen. “We’re soul mates!” is the rallying cry of emotional pygmies.</p>
<p>Yeah, it’s time to grow the fuck up.</p>
<p>The real reason you rely on fate, and not action, is this: You’re scared. In fact, you’re fucking terrified. If Fate flings something into your lap, somehow it was “meant to be”—and you like this for two reasons: One, because if the “universe” makes it right, then you can’t be wrong. And when you’re trying to choose someone to spend your life (or at least a lot of time) with, well, that’s a lot of responsibility. Believing the universe made it so is like getting a USDA-certified stamp of love. Bang.   </p>
<p>So, if you walk out your door and end up at this bar instead of that one, where you meet Mark instead of Brian, you may be tempted to say, well, that’s how it was meant to be. It also elevates the mundane (you going to a bar) to a miracle (you meeting the man Jesus set aside just for you). (And if you’re <a href="http://www.howaboutwe.com/date-report/stop-obsessing-how-we-met-relationship-story/" target="_blank">hung up on the how-we-met story?</a> You need to get over that, too—it’s life, not a romcom.) No wonder it’s so heartbreaking later if and when things change; you end up thinking either the universe failed you—or you did. When often it’s neither.</p>
<p>Fate has a pretty sweet job—she gets all the credit and none of the blame. Kind of like God at the Superbowl. Unfortunately, this is bullshit—and puts you in the weakest position of all. And when you blame or wait for Fate to intervene on behalf of your dating life, you renounce your freedom and choice. How…convenient. And how lazy.</p>
<p>I met a woman recently who took no chances with any other aspects of her life. She owned her own business, her own apartment, paid a considerable amount for fitness classes (which is where we met). And yet, when the topic of romance reared its head, she said she wasn’t dating currently, but that she was open to it. “If it happens, it happens,” was her response.</p>
<p>Wait, <em>wha</em>? Is that how she talked about anything else in her life? Do Manhattan apartments just happen to people? Not usually, no. She wasn’t willing to take a chance with anything else—<em>except</em> the one thing she actually wanted but was most afraid to go after (though she denied that, too). </p>
<p>Women are often the biggest Fate-fuckers, but men do it too. I met a 20-something dude recently who asked what advice I had for a man who was ready for a relationship. But he didn’t want to hear what I said, which was, Keep dating. Make an effort. Risk rejection. He didn’t want to online date because he wanted his romance to be “random” (really?). (Subtext: He didn’t want to believe he had to do anything—not a guy you can really help.) He wants God, his mom, or me to just hand him what he thinks he should have, or at least tell him he was doing enough, to approve of his romantic inertia. Sorry.</p>
<p>I’ll tell you what: Nothing in <em>my</em> dating life happened by “accident.” Sure, random shit happens—but I take random situations and turn them in my favor (<a href="http://jezebel.com/5984682/get-rejected-more-youre-not-doing-it-enough">and sometimes I get rejected—which you should be doing, too</a>). I go after what I want or snag it as it passes by, whether it’s someone I meet at a party or the dude who’s teaching me to detach audio in iMovie. I take whatever random situation I’m in and use it to my advantage. (More on <a href="http://territrespicio.com/how-to-happen-to-the-hottest-guy-in-the-room" target="_blank">how to happen to somebody you’re interested in</a>.)</p>
<p>Luck, circumstance—that’s the raw material. Your romantic life is about the choices you make with that. Just because you have a vagina doesn’t mean you need to act like one. So, decide—to be open, engaged, willing to take a risk. Start seeing yourself as the actor in your life, instead of the passive recipient of whatever the tide washes in. Would I leave the skilled work of choosing a partner to some nebulous external force? No way. And neither should you.</p>

<p><em>Terri Trespicio is a media personality &amp; lifestyle expert, and contributor to </em><a href="http://www.thedatereport.com" target="_blank"><em>The Date Report</em></a><em>. Visit her at </em><a href="http://territrespicio.com" target="_blank"><em>territrespicio.com</em></a><em> and follow her </em><a href="http://www.twitter.com/territ" target="_blank"><em>@TerriT</em></a><em>.</em></p>]]></description><category domain="">dating</category><category domain="">relationships</category><category domain="">fate</category><category domain="">men</category><category domain="">single ladies</category><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 17:45:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">472976491</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Terri Trespicio]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[The People Who Watch Marathons]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/the-people-who-watch-marathons-473405924</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18ktbuvlv9o1ajpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">Yesterday, when attacks on the Boston Marathon injured scores of people, mostly spectators, every runner I know spent the day wandering around in a daze, then either going on an angry run or curling up in the fetal position at 9 pm. The spectators — people who show up and cheer with noisemakers and high fives and encouraging cheers and magic-markered tagboard signs that read &quot;YOU ALL ARE CRAZY! KEEP RUNNING!&quot;— are the people who matter most to runners.  Without those people, a marathon would just be an exercise in self-abuse from a large group of crazies. But there is meaning in marathoning: the people who watch. </p>
<p>Running can be a lonely sport — hours on the road solo at times so early people can still be seen stumbling out of bars and hailing cabs home, declined invitations to evening activities, neglected significant others, and truly disgusting feet. In fact, unless a runner trains with a group that doesn't annoy the living daylights out of them, the months leading up to a long race can be profoundly antisocial. But on race day, all of that disappears when, as the marathon runner embarks along a path lined with people — all kinds of people, they're bathed in the encouragement of thousands of people who cheer for them without knowing their names.</p>
<p>It's even common (albeit debatedly cheesy) for marathoners to iron their first names onto their raceday shirts. This isn't so their wasted bodies are easily identifiable in the medical tent when they've run so hard they can no longer speak (that's what race bibs are for). It's so marathon spectators know <em>how to encourage them accurately</em>. When I ran the Chicago marathon in 2010, I didn't iron on my name, but that didn't keep this group of people who had roused themselves from bed and skipped brunch to watch 40,000 carb loaded runners stagger for 26.2 miles from yelling words of encouragement to me, a stranger, on that 80-degree day. &quot;Come on, pink shirt!&quot; &quot;Pink tank top way to be! You're almost there!&quot; Some yelled the  number on my bib. Then, after I'd pass, they'd cheer for the next runner to approach that they'd never met.There's a woman who used to hand out homemade Jello shots to runners at mile 23 along the Chicago course, which sounds gross, but actually turns out to be the perfect combination of cool carbohydrates and enough alcohol to take the edge off the tiniest bit. In Boystown, burly men twirl prop guns on a stage off Broadway, and in Pilsen, a mariachi band plays while ballet folklórico dancers twirl. Spectators even spread out along the lonely stretch between miles 18 and 21, standing in the sun with signs far from any train stations. All for people they've probably never seen, and will probably never see again. </p>
<p>And runners know the feeling of hearing their friends or family shout their name as they race is almost as good as the feeling of crossing the finish line. I once ran an 8K in Chicago after being sick for two weeks, and at about the 5K mark saw my then-boyfriend standing there in all black, looking completely out of place and awkward but coming to life when he saw me. I ran over and high fived him. It kept me going. Another time, during a 15K, a lone man dressed like a cheerleader along the lakefront path in Chicago  was customizing cheers for runners he saw. During the Chicago marathon in 2010, people who lived along the route came outside with garden hoses and sprayed us to keep us cool, and my mother jumped in and ran from miles 21-24 with me. I don't know if I could have finished if she hadn't been there, if all of those people hadn't been there. Very few runners could.</p>
<p>In his <a href="http://www.thenation.com/blog/173851/boston-marathon-all-my-tears-all-my-love#" target="_blank">excellent piece</a> for<em> The Nation</em> yesterday, Dave Zirin invoked a famous quote from women's marathoning pioneer Kathrine Switzer: <em>If you are losing faith in human nature, go out and watch a marathon. </em>As a runner, I know this to be true, but not because of me or my fellow standard issue runners. It's the spectators — who yesterday after the blasts, jumped over barricades to run toward the injured, who helped the few remaining volunteers at the event throw tables out of the way to make room for ambulances. It's the people of Boston who offered their homes to families stranded by the blast — the last I heard, the Google doc of open doors contained 5,000 entries. For strangers. From the people who watch.  </p>
<p> One of the many puzzling aspects of yesterday's attacks was the question of what, exactly, the perpetrators thought they'd accomplish by targeting what basically amounts to a celebration of human tenacity. If anything, the tragedy in Boston will further solidify the bond between runner and spectator. And when the Chicago marathon happens this October, I'll show up to run harder, and they'll show up to cheer louder. If anyone thought this attack would discourage the runners or the watchers, they've clearly never been to a marathon. </p>]]></description><category domain="">boston marathon</category><category domain="">running</category><category domain="">marathons</category><category domain="">terrorism</category><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 15:30:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">473405924</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Erin Gloria Ryan]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Beyoncé's Nipples Launch World Tour]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/beyonces-nipples-launch-world-tour-473201519</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kt23zy4pnmxjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">IT'S ALL HAPPENING. <strong>Beyoncé </strong>launched her Mrs. Carter World Tour in Belgrade, Serbia, wearing what can best be described as an R. Crumb illustration of an outfit.</p>
<p>The glittery bodysuit, just one of the lightning-fast costume changes Bey executed during the spectacle, featured dark contouring around the breasts as well as two nipple inserts like the ones Samantha Jones wore <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gEYXyO1vAxg" target="_blank">that time.</a> [<a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/showbiz/4890055/beyonce-mrs-carter-show-tour-opening-night-belgrade.html" target="_blank">The Sun</a>, <a href="http://theybf.com/2013/04/15/first-look-beyonce-kicks-off-the-mrs-carter-world-show-world-tour-in-belgrade" target="_blank">YBF</a>, screenshot via <a href="http://blip.tv/splashnewstv/beyonce-opens-her-world-tour-in-a-seriously-racy-gold-bodysuit-6571297" target="_blank">SplashNewsTV</a>]</p>
<p><strong>Bey </strong>has been &quot;putting pressure on herself to make sure [her next single] is a classic of 'Single Ladies' caliber.&quot; [<a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/showbiz/bizarre/4889672/beyonce-wants-new-single-to-be-a-hit-like-single-ladies.html" target="_blank">The Sun</a>]</p>
<p><strong>Kid Rock </strong>calls <strong>Bey </strong>and <strong>Jay</strong><strong>'s </strong>high ticket prices &quot;highway robbery.&quot; (Says the man who <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uwIGZLjugKA" target="_blank">jacked the riff from &quot;Sweet Home Alabama&quot;</a> and rhymed &quot;things&quot; with &quot;things.&quot;) [<a href="http://www.entertainmentwise.com/news/111685/Its-Highway-Robbery-Kid-Rock-Slams-Jay-Z-and-Justin-Timberlake-Over-High-Ticket-Prices" target="_blank">Entertainmentwise</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kszj9hsvkzfjpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></p><p>In a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ozzyosbourne?fref=ts" target="_blank">Facebook letter</a> posted this morning, <strong>Ozzy Osbourne </strong>denies the <strong>Sharon </strong>divorce rumors that have been floating around but admits that his relapsed alcohol and drug addiction has made it difficult for everyone around him. (He's a month and change sober now.)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;For the last year and a half I have been drinking and taking drugs. I was in a very dark place and was an a—hole to the people I love most, my family. However, I am happy to say that I am now 44 days sober. Just to set the record straight, Sharon and I are not divorcing. I'm just trying to be a better person. I would like to apologize to Sharon, my family, my friends and my band mates for my insane behavior during this period………and my fans.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/04/16/entertainment-us-ozzyosbourne-divorce-idUSBRE93F0BX20130416" target="_blank">Reuters</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kszkcyf7jxujpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></p><p>Boston native <strong>Mark Wahlberg</strong> was understandably upset at the premiere of his new movie <em>Pain &amp; Gain </em>yesterday.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;I really didn't even want to come tonight. I hadn't really heard much — I spoke to my mom, and most of my family seems to be OK. It's such a big event, there's so many people there. It's horrible man. It's fucking disgusting, man. I just - I'm very upset. You try to put everything in God's hands and whatever happens here is out of our control and there's a bigger picture. But it's still obviously upsetting.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/life/people/2013/04/16/mark-wahlberg-disgusted-by-boston-marathon-bombing/2087069/" target="_blank">USA Today</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kszl6jxykuojpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></p><p><strong> Kristen Stewart </strong>did a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MK6TXMsvgQg" target="_blank">Benny Hill-esque scramble</a> to avoid <strong>Liberty Ross,</strong> who, she was distraught to learn, was also at Coachella. (But really, was she <em>surprised? </em>It's like the 2000s version of the Hamptons.) ''Kristen has tried so hard to put everything from last year behind her - and she still feels incredibly guilty. She and Rob had turned a massive corner in recent months and they were both there to enjoy themselves. The last thing she wanted to do was make Liberty feel uncomfortable, either. She looked pretty upset in the backstage bar later on that evening.'' [<a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/showbiz/bizarre/4889553/kristen-stewart-and-robert-pattinson-next-liberty-ross-at-coachelle.html" target="_blank">The Sun</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" class="youtube" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/yQpuITOZPyo?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0" id="youtube-yQpuITOZPyo"></iframe></span></p><p>Okay, well, <strong>Amanda Bynes </strong>has upped the ante. She posted a video on Twitter with the caption &quot;I'm Sucking On A Sour Patch Kid Listening To Music Getting Ready For Tonight :D&quot; The minute-long clip features her looking nuts and making weird faces to what sounds like a house-ier version of Evanescence. I'm worried. :-| [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/408293/amanda-bynes-posts-a-video-of-herself-getting-ready-watch-it-now" target="_blank">E!</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18ksyjh2paxg2gif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p><strong>Isla Fisher: </strong>&quot;For me, so much about life is acceptance. You can look in the mirror and find a million things wrong with yourself. Or, you can look in the mirror and think, ‘I feel good, I have my health, and I’m so blessed.’ That’s the way I choose to look at it. I don’t need to be perfect. I don’t even own a scale. I have two young daughters and I wouldn’t want them to see me weighing myself all the time. I don’t think it sends the right message.”</p>
<p>Hey, Isla, can you talk to Amanda Bynes for me? [<a href="http://celebritybabies.people.com/2013/04/15/fitness-great-gatsby-isla-fisher/" target="_blank">People</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<ul><li><strong>Miley Cyrus </strong>maybe smoked weed. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/16/miley-cyrus-brazen-blazin-smokin-weed-photos-marijuana-blunt/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li>Related: &quot;<strong>Miley Cyrus </strong>is one of the greatest musicians of all time.&quot; -actual quote, <strong>Snoop Lion. </strong>[<a href="http://www.digitalspy.com/music/news/a473435/snoop-dogg-miley-cyrus-is-one-of-the-greatest-musicians-of-all-time.html" target="_blank">Digital Spy</a>]</li><li><strong>Lindsay Lohan </strong>insists she's not doing drugs or drinking at Coachella. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/15/lindsay-lohan-coachella-denies-drugs-alcohol/?adid=hero5" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Garth Brooks/Chris Gaines </strong>(remember Chris Gaines?!) is being sued by a former business partner. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/15/garth-brooks-sued-lisa-sanderson-employee-fraud-lawsuit/?adid=hero2" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li>Girl, <strong>Tom Cruise's </strong>daughter <strong>Is</strong><strong>abella </strong>will be a woman soon. [<a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/04/isabella-cruise-makeover-photo/" target="_blank">Radar Online</a>]</li><li><strong>Justin Bieber's </strong>response to the Anne Frank controversy: a shirtless picture. I've seen him shirtless more than I've seen myself shirtless. [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/bieber-posts-shirtless-photos-anne-frank-controversy-article-1.1317263" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</li><li><strong>El Beebo</strong> might buy a house in Dubai. [<a href="http://tvnz.co.nz/entertainment-news/justin-bieber-buy-house-in-dubai-5408516" target="_blank">TVNZ.co</a>]</li><li>Umm, NVM: One day after announcing their separation, <strong>Jane Seymour </strong>and her husband got back together. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/jane-seymour-husband-james-keach-reunite-one-day-after-divorce-announcement-picture-2013154" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><strong>Ireland Baldwin </strong>is, for serious, dating a boy named <strong>Slater Trout. </strong>[<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/ireland-baldwin-kisses-boyfriend-slater-trout-at-coachella-picture-2013154" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><strong>Jennifer Aniston </strong>and <strong>Justin Theroux </strong>are having a smallish wedding. [<a href="http://thestir.cafemom.com/entertainment/154163/jennifer_anistons_planner_reveals_what" target="_blank">The Stir</a>]</li><li><strong>Deadmau5 </strong>and <strong>Kat Von D </strong>are having an &quot;underwater&quot; wedding. [<a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20691311,00.html" target="_blank">People</a>]</li><li><strong>LeAnn Rimes </strong>wasn't anorexic when everyone thought she was anorexic, but couldn't sleep, says LeAnn Rimes. [<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2309621/LeAnn-Rimes-opens-anorexia-rumours-explains-OK-gaining-pounds.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490" target="_blank">Daily Mail</a>]</li><li><strong>Michael Douglas' </strong>son <strong>Cameron </strong>lost his appeal and will have to serve his 10-year sentence on a 2010 drug charge. [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/crime/cameron-douglas-sentence-upheld-n-y-court-article-1.1317054" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</li><li><strong>James Deen </strong>stuck up for his penis after <strong>Farrah Abraham </strong>called it small. &quot;It's at least medium-sized.&quot; [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/15/farrah-abraham-james-deen-sex-tape/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Wendy Williams </strong>will appear in &quot;Chicago&quot; on Broadway as Mama Morton. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/wendy_takes_on_chicago_BFwmBI3BNg8gQCWgUAkJ5K" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li><strong>Rihanna's </strong>been cancelling shows on her Diamonds world tour because of &quot;an undisclosed illness.&quot; [<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2309745/Rihanna-cancels-Diamonds-World-Tour-shes-struck-undisclosed-illness-more.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490" target="_blank">Daily Mail</a>]</li><li>Some English guys thought <strong>Macaulay Culkin </strong>was a homeless man. [<a href="http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/home-alone-star-macaulay-culkin-mistaken-for-homeless-man-in-london/story-e6frfmqi-1226621634294?from=public_rss" target="_blank">Digital Spy</a>]</li><li><strong>Naya Rivera, Jennifer Morton </strong>and others stripped down for <em>Allure's </em>&quot;Look Better Naked&quot; issue. Not naked? Cover model <strong>Amanda Seyfried</strong>. [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/naya-rivera-jennifer-morris-strip-allure-better-naked-issue-article-1.1317877" target="_blank">NYDN</a>, <a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/seyfried_tells_naked_truth_qSG8CqkDxMj0SijOuwNHcK" target="_blank">NYP</a>]</li><li></li></ul>]]></description><category domain="">dirt bag</category><category domain="">beyonce</category><category domain="">jay-z</category><category domain="">kid rock</category><category domain="">ozzy osbourne</category><category domain="">mark wahlberg</category><category domain="">boston marathon bombing</category><category domain="">justin bieber</category><category domain="">james deen</category><category domain="">farrah abraham</category><category domain="">wendy williams</category><category domain="">macaulay culkin</category><category domain="">rihanna</category><category domain="">naya rivera</category><category domain="">jennifer morton</category><category domain="">cameron douglas</category><category domain="">leann rimes</category><category domain="">kristen stewart</category><category domain="">miley cyrus</category><category domain="">snoop lion</category><category domain="">lindsay lohan</category><category domain="">tom cruise</category><category domain="">isabella cruise</category><category domain="">el beebo</category><category domain="">jane seymour</category><category domain="">ireland baldwin</category><category domain="">slater trout</category><category domain="">jennifer aniston</category><category domain="">justin theroux</category><category domain="">deadmau5</category><category domain="">kat von d</category><category domain="">garth brooks</category><category domain="">liberty ross</category><category domain="">amanda bynes</category><category domain="">isla fisher</category><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">473201519</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Breslaw]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Game of Boners: One Hand, One Heart]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/game-of-boners-one-hand-one-heart-473000581</link><description><![CDATA[<p class=" class=&quot;has-media media-640&quot; first-text"><em><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe scrolling="no" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.viddler.com/embed/3127b692/?f=1&amp;autoplay=false&amp;player=mini&amp;disablebranding=0" id="viddler-3127b692"></iframe></span> Welcome to Game of Boners, your weekly tally of all the nudity that appears on everyone's favorite fantasy fuck fest, <em>Game of Thrones</em>. Every Monday, we will recap each boob, buttock and sex act that appears on camera, along with some other fun facts from the episode that may or may not have anything to do with sex whatsoever. Keep a box of tissues on hand because Winter is definitely coming.</em></p>
<p>Another week of <em>Game of Thrones</em> and another week of very intense gender commentary. While last week's episode was all about sisterhood and what it means to be a woman in a <em>Game of Thrones</em> world, this week's took great care to point out that being a man, though slightly better, isn't all that great either. It wasn't all a discussion of men, women and how their lives are terrible. The episode was also fraught with another strangely pleasant and optimistic theme — friendship or, to be more specific, that a friend in need is a friend indeed. </p>
<p>Not so friendly — the King's Council in King's Landing where new Hand Tywin is testing everyone with awkward seating arrangements. It's telling to see how everyone reacts. Littlefinger, forever sucking ass, rushes to sit directly at Tywin's lefthand. Varys rolls his eyes and takes the next seat. Cersei, lone woman and the most courageous of them all (I don't know what it it is, but I love that wine-soaked psychopath with all my heart) loudly drags a chair all the way around to her father's other side, making it clear that she's his right hand and Tyrion, noting his sister's move, places his chair at the opposite head of the table and is promptly rewarded by being made Master of Coin, the shittiest job in the kingdom. </p>
<p>On the otherside of the war, Catelyn Stark née Tully is mourning the death of her father alongside her son Robb, her incompetent brother Edmure (who no one is happy with after he blew Robb Stark's defense against the Lannisters all for the sake of a worthless mill) and uncle Brynden Tully (a.k.a Blackfish). Poor Catelyn is naturally out of sorts having lost her father and thinking that she's lost almost all of her children in such a short period of time, but Blackfish tells her that she needs to toughen up for Robb's sake — her motherly fortitude will keep him strong in battle. That stoicism is so annoyingly like the Tully-Starks, isn't it? A girl can't even cry over her dead family for five minutes without a long lost uncle telling her to suck it up. </p>
<p>Dany, far away in Astapor is also being advised by a pair of wizened old men — in her case, on whether or not she should purchase the Unsullied to build her army. Ser Jorah, raspy as ever, points out that it's the kindest thing she can do for the war's innocent bystanders. “Unsullied are not men,&quot; he tells her. &quot;They do not rape. If you buy them, the only men you’ll kill are the ones you want dead.” Ser Selmy feels that an army shouldn't be made up of people forced to fight for you, but rather people who choose to take up arms because they love you. Dany ends up siding with Jorah, not because she agrees with her reasoning, but because she feels sympathy for the slaves of Astapor and wants to give them a better life. One problem — it's an expensive deal that she's attempting to barter and the only way she can afford it is by giving up one of her three dragons. </p>
<p>Jorah and Selmy finally agree on something when they both, in front of the slave trader, voice that a dragon is too high a cost to pay. Dany promptly tells them to shut the fuck up and never disagree with her in public again. It's awesome seeing this young girl, who also happens to be the MOTHER OF DRAGONS, remind these two old bros that she's the one with the power here and that they're job is to help, not to lead. In a further display of One Big Room, Full of Bad Bitches, Dany takes particular interest in one Astapor slave woman and asks whether or not, if free, she would have a family to return to. She doesn't so instead takes a place as Dany's personal attendent, a job that might lead her straight to death's door. &quot;Valar morghulis,&quot; the slave replies when warned of the dangers of her new position. “All men must die,&quot; Dany translates. &quot;But we are not men.” </p>
<p>“All men must die&quot; takes on an even bleaker meaning North of the Wall where the remaining Brothers of the Night's Watch are back at Craster's Keep where Craster himself — threatened by having to compete with any other dick on the dance floor — is the only man allowed permanent residence. The consequences of this rule are made horrifyingly clear as Gilly, apple of Sam's eye, gives birth to a baby boy. Whereas south of the wall, the birth of a male heir is celebrated, here it only means one thing — death. Just as Jon Snow witnessed back in season 2, Gilly's newborn will be left in the snow as a snack for the White Walkers.</p>
<p>Other men who are not doing so swell — Theon Greyjoy and Stannis Baratheon. Things begin to look up for Theon, son of Lucius Malfoy and true master of the Elder Wand, as Simon from <em>Misfits</em> helps him escape his torture chamber. Of course it doesn't take long for his captures to catch up to him (the kid <em>is</em> running away on two feet that have had holes drilled into them) and things then take an even more violent and scary turn. “I’m going to fuck you into the ground,&quot; says one man, preparing to sodomize a bruised and beaten Theon. Luckily, his rapist is stopped short by an arrow through the head. Simon from <em>Misfits</em> saves the day once again.</p>
<p>Stannis, meanwhile, is lookin' rough. His loss at the Battle of Blackwater is clearly weighing on him body and soul and the only way he thinks that he can fix everything is by impregnating Melisandre with another smoke baby. She takes one look at him with his dark under eye circles and and overgrown beard and is like, &quot;Eh, I'd rather ride this canoe into the middle of the ocean&quot; and takes off.  Wise to take a hard pass at that one.</p>
<p>Now let's talk about who we all want to talk about: Jaime Lannister and Brienne of Tarth. Over the course of their journey, this odd couple has grown to begrudgingly enjoy each other's company as is evident after they've been captured by the Boltons, are tied back to back atop a horse and are <em>still</em> playfully smack talking each other. Of course the fun ends very quickly when Jaime warns Brienne of what's about to happen to her. He is the prisoner of worth here, giving him a modicum of protection that doesn't extend to her. Brienne, Jaime tells her, will be raped by the Boltons, probably repeatedly, and he advises her not to fight back. While his warnings seem cold and are laced with that ol' Lannister condescension, there's real worry and regret in his words. “If you were a woman, you wouldn’t resist?” asks Brienne, disgusted at the idea of allowing her own assault. “If I were a woman I’d make them kill me,&quot; Jamie responds. &quot;But thank gods I’m not.”</p>
<p>When the sun sets, it looks as though Jaime's terrible prediction will come true. Brienne is dragged off kicking and screaming by a group of men (ever the warrior, she does not take Jaime's advise by going quietly) and her off-camera screams punch through the air, leading Jaime to do something that once seemed impossible — act for the benefit of someone who's not Cersei, one of their children or himself. He tells Locke (who once looked <a href="http://www.stfimages.com/images/flirtijmj.png" target="_blank">this sweet and innocent</a>) that Brienne, as a noblewoman of Tarth, might not be so worthless a prisoner after all and that returned untouched, she is likely worth her weight in sapphires.</p>
<p>This successfully stops Brienne's rape, but then Jaime, overestimating his charm and skills of manipulation, pushes too far by reminding Locke that his father Tywin would pay even more than that for his own safe return. Locke responds to Jaime's offer by dragging a knife across his very beautiful Lannister face and, for one moment, it looks like he's about to lose an eye, but, no, Locke withdraws and we can all breathe a sigh of relief for the Kingslayer. You know that moment of relief that I was just talking about? PSYCH, just kidding. Everything is still terrible. “You’re nothing without your daddy and your daddy ain’t here,” Locke growls, before lopping Jaime's sword hand off clean at the wrist.</p>
<p>I'm resisting a lot of &quot;lend a friend a hand&quot; puns right now, so, please be appropriately proud.</p>
<p><strong>Onto the skin stats!</strong></p>
<p><strong>Individual Boobs (Female): 7 (Not including Ros' cleavage)</strong></p>
<p>Speaking of helping out a friend, we got our first gratuitous brothel scene of the season when Tyrion paid a group of prostitutes to take his squire Podrick's virginity as a thanks for saving his life at Blackwater. There were boobs everywhere, which was both over the top and a little comforting. This season of <em>GoT</em> had been conspicuously lacking in skin and I was starting to doubt whether or not I even knew this show to begin with. Also the prostitutes reject Podrick's money because apparently he's so good at doing it. Yeah. Sure. Fine.</p>
<p><strong>Individual Boobs (Male): Too many to count.</strong></p>
<p>No one in Astapor wears a shirt!</p>
<p><strong>Butts (Female): Three </strong></p>
<p>Once again, thanks to Littlefinger's brothel.</p>
<p><strong>Butts (Male): One</strong></p>
<p><strong>Vaginas (with merkins): Two</strong></p>
<p><strong>Penises: One</strong></p>
<p>It belonged to a baby.</p>

]]></description><category domain="">game of thrones</category><category domain="">tv</category><category domain="">recaps</category><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">473000581</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Madeleine Davies]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Boston PD:  Marathon Explosions Are an ‘Ongoing Event’ [Update]]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/boston-police-commissioner-says-marathon-explosions-ar-473039257</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kqqlcomgm4tjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Boston Police Commissioner Edward Davis has described the two horrific explosions at the Boston Marathon as part of “an ongoing event” after a third explosion occurred about an hour ago at the John F. Kennedy Presidential library, five miles southeast of the Boston Marathon finish line in Copley Square.</p>
<p>CNN and NBC are reporting that this third explosion came after the explosions that tore through the Boston Marathon finish line, leaving two people dead and at least 49 injured, according to the <a href="http://news.blogs.cnn.com/2013/04/15/explosions-near-finish-of-boston-marathon/?on.cnn=1" target="_blank">most recent figures</a>. On its own Facebook page, the Marathon referred to the blasts as “bombs,” although Comm. Davis, when asked during a recent press conference, stopped just short of characterizing the explosions as an act of terrorism (he added, somewhat wryly, that observers could draw their own conclusions about whether or not the explosions were part of a terror plot). Information is being circulated pretty quickly, and news outlets like CNN, Reuters, and the <em>Boston Globe</em> are frantically live-blogging the event (some of the footage is pretty graphic and, on sites like the <em>Globe</em>'s, video loads automatically). This is what we know so far, in light of the press conference update from Comm. Davis at 4:58 pm ET:</p>
<blockquote>
<ul><li>A third explosion happened at the John F. Kennedy Presidential Library &quot;about a half-hour ago.&quot; The library is about 5 miles southeast of the Boston Marathon finish line.</li><li>Police don't immediately know whether that explosion is related to the two near the Boston Marathon finish line.</li><li>The two blasts near the finish line – along Boylston Street near Copley Square - &quot;happened 50 to 100 yards apart.&quot;</li><li>&quot;We're recommending to people that they stay home ... and that they don'r go anyplace and congregate in large crowds.&quot;</li></ul>
</blockquote>
<p>At approximately 2:50 pm ET today, two explosions hit the Boston Marathon as runners began crossing the finish line. Reuters <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/04/15/us-athletics-marathon-boston-blast-idUSBRE93E0ZF20130415" target="_blank">reported</a> earlier that “two high-profile U.S. law enforcement officials said one or more bombs were responsible for the explosions,” and recounted eyewitness accounts that described the blasts as sounding like “a sonic boom.” According to CNN, “Massachusetts General Hospital said it was treating 19 injured people; Tufts Medical Center reported that some injured were to be treated there as well.” Police are cautioning people to get themselves to safety, and say that it will take a “long time” to clear Copley Square since people attending the marathon dropped bags or “whatever else” they were carrying when the explosions hit, and every discarded bag is being treated with due caution.</p>
<p>Speaking to NBC’s Brian Williams, <em>New York Daily News</em> sportswriter Mike Lupica tried to put the scope of the explosion in perspective for anyone who may not have ever attended the Boston Marathon. He compared Copley Square on marathon day to Times Square in New York on New Year’s Eve, and said that the sight of people fleeing the finish line in terror was “one of the most chilling things” he’s ever seen.</p>
<p><strong>Update</strong>: The <em>Boston Globe</em> has updated the <a href="http://bostonglobe.com/metro/2013/04/15/explosions-rock-boston-marathon-finish-line-dozens-injured/yLhfDT1XC3HXSa8wPiVijL/story.html" target="_blank">injury tally</a> to include at least 125 people.  The paper is also reporting that a &quot;person of interest&quot; was being questioned just before 8:00 pm at Brigham and Women's Hospital in connection with the bombing.</p>
<p><strong>Update</strong>: The latest from <a href="http://news.blogs.cnn.com/2013/04/15/explosions-near-finish-of-boston-marathon/?hpt=hp_t1" target="_blank">CNN</a>: three people are now reported killed in bomb blasts near the Boston Marathon finish line, and area hospitals are saying that at least 132 people have been injured.</p>
<p>[<a href="http://news.blogs.cnn.com/2013/04/15/explosions-near-finish-of-boston-marathon/?on.cnn=1" target="_blank">CNN</a>] [<a href="http://live.reuters.com/Event/Boston_Marathon_Explosion" target="_blank">Reuters</a>] </p>
<p><em><small>Images via <a href="http://www.apimages.com/" target="_blank">AP</a>.</small></em></p>
]]></description><category domain="">boston marathon</category><category domain="">boston marathon explosions</category><category domain="">edward davis</category><category domain="">bombs</category><category domain="">explosions</category><category domain="">tragedy</category><category domain="">crime</category><category domain="">emergency</category><category domain="">terrorism</category><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 21:50:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">473039257</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Barry]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mad Men: Is Don Draper a Sex Addict?]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/mad-men-is-don-draper-a-sex-addict-472996283</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kpzihhujx7rjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p class="first-text">After last week's season premiere served us a <a href="http://jezebel.com/mad-men-new-year-old-you-471298107">two-hour meditation on death</a>, last night's <em>Mad Men</em> was all about sex, which should be a much happier topic as it's the antithesis of death. But with this episode taking place the January after the Summer of Love, the gang is squarely in the winter of their discontent, faced with how sex doesn't just create life, it can also destroy it.</p>
<p>Don Draper was first introduced to us as a man of vices, but over the course of the series it's become quite clear that his bad habits have turned into some hardcore addictions. We know that he's an alcoholic and he's hooked on cigarettes, but his serial cheating was always presented as a byproduct of being trapped in an unhappy marriage to his first wife Betty. Now his sexual behavior—which tends to be socially inappropriate—seems compulsive.</p>
<p>Perhaps &quot;sex addiction&quot; is used a little too much as an excuse for poor behavior in this day and age. But last night we learned a little more about Don's childhood through flashbacks that revealed that after his father's death he and his pregnant stepmother were forced to move into a brothel where she got turned out by &quot;Uncle Mac.&quot; And a 10-year-old Don saw it all. That has to be traumatizing.</p>
<p>Roger Sterling's mother always said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Everything in the world is about sex except sex. Sex is about power.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Psych! That was Oscar Wilde. Still, it's apropos particularly for someone with Don's childhood and lineage—aside from being raised in a brothel during his adolescence, he was also born to a prostitute, impregnated by a john. In every way, Don Draper is the product of transactional sex. It's what he knows. Perhaps that's why he insists on paying for sex, in some form—usually with guilt or other emotional currency—every time. (He gave Sylvia thick wad of bills on last night's episode.) The irony, of course, is that while he's trying to prove his own dominance to himself through sleeping around, he's actually powerless when it comes to sex in the same way that a person is powerless when it comes to any addiction.</p>
<p>But Don is not a sociopath. He knows what he's doing is bad but he just can't seem to stop. (His loyalty to the Heinz Baked Beans guy is demonstrative of his understanding of and ability to be faithful.) It's a lot like smoking. In fact, Don's whole relationship with cigarettes seems to be allegorical for this show. Just like with his marriage and his infidelity, Don's smoking is so hypocritical, considering that full-page ad he took out in <em>The New York Times</em> about no longer accepting cigarette accounts because cigarettes are deadly. It lead to him receiving an award from the American Cancer Society. He contintues to puff away.</p>
<p>As he was in the elevator with his neighbor Dr. Rosen, he realized that he forgot his pack of cigarettes and pressed the button for his floor to go retrieve them. Dr. Rosen said, &quot;You need to stop that nonsense.&quot; (It was the second time in as many weeks that Dr. Rosen brought up how unhealthy Don's smoking is.)</p>
<p>Immediately following this exchange Don continued with the other &quot;nonsense&quot; that he knows he needs to stop: his affair with Sylvia, Dr. Rosen's wife.</p>
<p>Last week we saw Don reading <em>Inferno</em> while on vacation. One of the main themes of that text, of course, is sin. The same could be said for this season of <em>Mad Men</em>. One of the hookers in Don's flashback told him to &quot;find [his] own sins.&quot; And did he ever. We're likely to see Don cycle through all the seven deadly sins. So far he's got Lust, Envy (coveting what belongs to his neighbor, as in, his wife), Gluttony (which is sometimes interpreted as selfishness), and Sloth (sometimes interpreted as love that isn't strong enough) under his belt through his treatment of his marriage.</p>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="170" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kqexgwyrv6igif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p>Meanwhile, Pete Campbell is doing his part of tackling Pride; he wants to be better than everyone else—or at least look like it. (&quot;It's all about what it looks like, isn't it?&quot; he said to Bob Benson.) Sex is certainly about power for Pete. Trudy has always been just as ambitious as her husband, and viewed his career as as something that they worked on together, since there are so many social aspects to being a successful accounts man. (Remember when they charmed everyone with their choreography?) Unlike the more traditional suburban model of marriage of Betty and Don Draper, Trudy and Pete's relationship was a true partnership. And Pete, who is the lesser of the partners at SCDP was also the lesser of the partners in his marriage. (Mostly, it has to do with his own personality and just being a small person in general.)</p>
<p>Pete had some bullshit idea that having a sex life outside of his marriage would give him the upper hand in his marriage. But Trudy isn't Betty. She's not looking to be the victim. Because being victimized would mean failure, and as she said, &quot;I refuse to be a failure.&quot;</p>
<p>In an impassioned speech, she handed Pete his ass and kicked him out, insisting she won't be giving him a divorce. So instead of Pete finding power in his extracurricular sex life, he was basically neutered. Now he has to live in his one bedroom sex flat and worry about things like whether or not he has toilet paper instead of comfortably watching <em>The Tonight Show</em> on a floral print couch.</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe scrolling="no" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.viddler.com/embed/bf4929e9/?f=1&amp;autoplay=false&amp;player=mini&amp;disablebranding=0" id="viddler-bf4929e9"></iframe></span></p><p> Over at her new job, Peggy is dealing with the kind of bullshit sexism that was, unfortunately, inevitably bound to happen to such a tough female boss in that era. (Or probably <em>any</em> female boss.) The <em>really</em> shitty thing wasn't that her employees did that, but that her boss Ted Chaough thought it was funny. I don't think Don would've thought it was funny. Perhaps Peggy thinks that, too. Maybe those thoughts are what makes using her insider info about the Heinz Ketchup account so difficult. She has a loyalty to Don that she's not comfortable betraying.</p>
<p>The ultimate betrayal of last night's episode, though, surrounds <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bob_%26_Carol_%26_Ted_%26_Alice" target="_blank">Don &amp; Megan &amp; Arnold &amp; Sylvia</a>. (Interestingly, <em>Bob &amp; Carol &amp; Ted &amp; Alice</em> will be in theaters within the year, while John Updikes' <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Couples" target="_blank"><em>Couples</em></a>, about a group of promiscuous, married friends, was published in 1968.)With friendships burgeoning between the two men and the two women, Don and Sylvia's affair is getting crueler and crueler.</p>
<p>Here's Megan, opening her heart up to Sylvia about her miscarriage, and her guilt of feeling grateful about it (it was convenient for her career), only to have Sylvia serve Megan some moral judgment on it, making her feel worse. And all the while Sylvia is having an affair with Megan's husband. Megan is the ultimate Soap queen and she doesn't even realize it. These issues will undoubtedly be helpful in her method acting in years to come, though.</p>
<p>When Megan finally shares her secret with Don and asks him what he wants, he tells her, &quot;I want what you want.&quot; It's such a load of crap, since earlier in the evening he told Sylvia, &quot;I want you all the time.&quot; Don is lying to both women, telling them both what they want to hear. Maybe he learned it from the prostitutes he grew up around. For all of Don's attempts to position himself as the john in his sexual relationships, his behavior is much more similar to that of a whore.</p>
<p>At the end of the episode, after being turned away by Sylvia when he knocked on her maid's door, he approaches his own front door, but he doesn't enter. Instead, he slumps down in the hallway, perhaps too tired to go on with the charade. It's like he was living out <a href="http://jezebel.com/mad-men-new-year-old-you-471298107">Roger's therapy rant about doors</a>, and the pointlessness of everything that we do.</p>
<p>Or maybe he's coming to terms with just how unmanageable his life has become, which happens to be the first of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twelve-step_program" target="_blank">Twelve Steps</a> to recovering from addiction.</p>]]></description><category domain="">mad men</category><category domain="">don draper</category><category domain="">sex addiction</category><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 20:45:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">472996283</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracie Egan Morrissey]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Carey Mulligan Says Daisy Buchanan Is 'Like A Kardashian']]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/carey-mulligan-says-daisy-buchanan-is-like-a-kardashia-472964707</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kq43ig2ii2wjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text"><strong>Carey Mulligan</strong> is on the cover of <strong><em>Vogue</em></strong>, in character as <strong>Daisy Buchanan</strong>. <strong>Baz Luhrmann</strong>'s adaptation of <em>The Great Gatsby</em> is <em>finally</em> set to premiere on May 15. Mulligan tells the magazine that she based her characterization of Daisy on two real women from F. Scott Fitzgerald's life: his wife, <strong>Zelda Fitzgerald</strong>, and a girl named Ginevra King whom he wooed as a teenager. Princeton, where Fitzgerald's papers are archived, provided copies of the writer's correspondence with King for Mulligan to read. King once wrote to Fitzgerald, &quot;‘There’s so little to me that I’m not hard to forget quickly.&quot; Zelda said, &quot;I seem always curiously interested in myself, and it’s so much fun to stand off and look at me.&quot; Mulligan says of Daisy:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;It’s that kind of feeling: I’m-so-little-and-there’s-nothing-to-me, watch-me-have-nothing-to-me. She feels like she’s living in a movie of her own life. She’s constantly on show, performing all the time. Nothing bad can happen in a dream. You can’t die in a dream. She’s in her own TV show. She’s like a Kardashian.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://www.vogue.com/magazine/article/great-expectations-carey-mulligan-as-daisy-buchanan-in-the-great-gatsby/#1" target="_blank">Vogue.com</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kq48nwuecomjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p><strong>Beyoncé</strong>'s <strong>H&amp;M</strong> ads are out. [<a href="http://www.vogue.co.uk/news/2013/03/21/beyonce-hm-campaign--collection-confirmed" target="_blank">Vogue UK</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kq4cjzxehfpjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p>The photographer behind<strong> Humans of New York</strong> was asked by <strong><em>Vogue</em></strong>'s Web site to share daily images of people in New York whom he feels embody the ideals of punk ahead of the May 6 opening of the Met Costume Institute show, &quot;Punk: From Chaos to Couture.&quot; [<a href="http://www.vogue.com/vogue-daily/article/humans-of-new-york-catalog-punks-influence/#1" target="_blank">Vogue.com</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kq4dzatj9vvjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p><strong>Hedi</strong> is obviously just doing whatever the fuck he wants now. [<a href="http://www.ysl.com/en_US#!{" target="_blank">YSL</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p> • Just how white are the casts at <strong>Calvin Klein</strong>'s shows, you ask? <strong>Business of Fashion</strong> crunched the numbers and found that the brand's casting directors, Maida Gregori Boina and Rami Fernandes, and found that the brand <em>rarely</em> books black models, and <em>never</em> books Asian or Latina models:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Calvin Klein, in particular, just this past season was entirely Caucasian. And here’s where it gets even worse: in the last eight years there have been only six different black models and zero models of other ethnicities, other than Caucasian, featured in their shows, according to an analysis of imagery on Style.com.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Boina and Fernandes also cast the shows for Jil Sander and The Row, both of which are heavily white. [<a href="http://www.businessoffashion.com/2013/04/op-ed-racism-on-the-runway.html" target="_blank">Bof</a>]</p>
<p>• <strong>J. Crew</strong>'s comeback, 2003-present, is the focus of a new piece in <em>Fast Company</em>. Here, <strong>Jenna Lyons</strong> describes her intense first meeting with<strong> Mickey Drexler</strong>, who became the company C.E.O. in 2003 after being fired by Gap Inc.:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>On Drexler's first day, recalls Lyons, &quot;he sat down, pushed his chair back, put his foot up on the table, and he looked around and he's like, 'You're all interviewing for your jobs.'&quot; On his second day, he asked Lyons to run through the women's collection in front of the entire team, a roomful of 50 people. She presented three pairs of skinny stretch pants. Drexler asked what she thought of them. &quot;At that point I was like, I have to be honest,&quot; recalls Lyons. &quot;I can't lie to him because this is sort of a do-or-die situation.&quot; She said except for one pair, she didn't think the others fit the brand. Drexler told her to throw them on the floor. Then they got to a boucle sweater, which looked like poodle fur. Lyons said she hated it, but it was a million-dollar seller. Drexler told her to drop it on the floor. Then came the cheap cashmere T-shirts, made in China. Onto the floor. &quot;I didn't know if I was going to be fired,&quot; says Lyons. &quot;I was so confused, and I was scared, but I was also a little bit excited, because all the things that I liked and that I thought were brand-right he was leaving up on the wall. And I was like, Is that good, is that bad? I don't know.&quot;</p>
<p>She kept her job. (Many of her colleagues did not.) After two days of reviewing the entire product line, Drexler told Lyons to get on a plane to Hong Kong and design new pieces to fill all the holes. He also asked her where she wanted to source the company's cashmere. A more expensive mill, she said. He told her to call them. This move marked the beginning of Drexler's turnaround strategy—a bet on quality. &quot;You cannot copy high quality, and it takes a long time to get a reputation for quality,&quot; he says. Lyons credits this first encounter as both formative and telling of their future together. &quot;Honestly, I think it was because I didn't bullshit him,&quot; says Lyons. &quot;His bullshit-dar is insane.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3007843/creative-conversations/how-jenna-lyons-transformed-jcrew-cult-brand#6" target="_blank">Fast Company</a>]</p>
<p>• <strong>Condé Nast</strong>'s <strong>College of Fashion and Design</strong> has now welcomed its first students in London. The unaccredited college charges over $30,000 for a year-long <strong><em>Vogue</em></strong> Fashion Foundation Diploma course. [<a href="http://www.wwd.com/media-news/fashion-memopad/style-school-6892671?src=rss/recentstories/20130415" target="_blank">WWD</a>]</p>
<p>• <strong>Prada</strong> is now paying more than $1,000 per square foot in rent for its 10,000-square-foot SoHo flagship store, which was designed by <strong>Rem Koolhaas</strong>. Average commercial rent in the neighborhood is $423/sq. ft. [<a href="http://www.crainsnewyork.com/article/20130414/REAL_ESTATE/304149970" target="_blank">Crain's</a>]</p>
<p>• Swedish model <strong>Tilda Lindstam</strong> says her favorite look from the 76 shows she walked in this past season was &quot;<strong>Alexander McQueen</strong>, but when am I going to wear that? I was so honored to walk in that show. It takes an hour to get dressed and it’s the most painful thing ever. You wear these corsets that are so tight and these giant hip cages — they bring a drill and drill it onto you. It’s insane. It’s the most painful show, but it’s also the most beautiful show.&quot; [<a href="http://www.wwd.com/eye/fashion/tilda-lindstam-most-popular-girl-6887815?module=hp-hero-topstories" target="_blank">WWD</a>]</p>
<p>• The director of the upcoming documentary about <strong>Carine Roitfeld</strong> says he has lots of footage of <strong>Kanye West</strong> &quot;chatting up models.&quot; [<a href="http://fashionista.com/2013/04/carine-roitfeld-documentary-release/" target="_blank">Fashionista</a>]</p>
<p>• <strong>J.C. Penney</strong> won a temporary reprieve in its ongoing legal battle with <strong>Macy's</strong> over the right to sell <strong>Martha Stewart</strong>-designed homewares. The judge in the case ruled that J.C. Penney, for now, can sell all the Martha Stewart spatulas and oven mitts it wants, provided it rebrands them as J.C. Penney's own homewares label. The trial continues today. [<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/13/business/interim-martha-stewart-ruling-favors-jc-penney.html?_r=1&amp;" target="_blank">NYTimes</a>]</p>
<p>• Perhaps the best part of <em>Women's Wear Daily</em>'s long, new interview with <strong>Miuccia Prada</strong> is this passage, where Prada discusses feminism:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>WWD: Why is there a need [for greater femininity now in fashion]?<br/>M.P.: </strong>This is a very complicated question. We are losing the old power and not really knowing what is the new power. I think that you shouldn’t throw away anything, so I always want to keep our power as women or our deep identity that comes from all our history of women. <br/><br/><strong>WWD: What old power are women losing?<br/>M.P.:</strong> It’s the side that pleases men. It’s not a direct power but a power through men, which I hate but we have so much in ourselves. It’s all the feminist discourse. <br/><br/><strong>WWD: Does every collection have a window into feminist discourse?<br/>M.P.: </strong>In a way, always. I’m always trying to do something that is…never to please men in the most banal way.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://www.wwd.com/fashion-news/fashion-features/the-interviews-miuccia-prada-6886165?full=true" target="_blank">WWD</a>]</p>]]></description><category domain="">rag trade</category><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 20:10:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">472964707</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jenna Sauers]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Should Guys Wear Tinted Moisturizer? We Made 'Em Try It.]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/should-guys-wear-tinted-moisturizer-we-made-em-try-it-472554002</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kq5cq8lbyw5jpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text"> Calling it &quot;tinted moisturizer&quot; instead of &quot;makeup&quot; seems to make men more comfortable with the idea of wearing it. But are <em>you</em> comfortable with men wearing it? You should be. In case you needed any convincing of its unisex benefits, we applied tinted moisturizer to the faces of our colleagues at <a href="http://deadspin.com" target="_blank">Deadspin</a>. Check out how beautiful they became.</p>
<p>Here's the thing: tinted moisturizer is magical. A light-weight foundation that evens out skin tone in with a natural look that not only quenches skin but typically contains some level of SPF protection? It's like the makeup equivalent of finding out that Doritos are heart-healthy—except it's <em>real</em>.</p>
<p>I feel bad for anybody who isn't hep to its powers, but particularly bad for guys who are up against the kind of implicit gender biases about makeup, as though wearing tinted moisturizer would somehow make them less manly. It's a stupid concept that isn't fair and doesn't make sense. More and more men are starting to realize that, though, and the stigma around tinted moisturizer is <a href="http://www.menshealth.com/grooming/look-younger-0" target="_blank">gradually</a> being lifted.</p>

<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kq60udxt81bjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p>When I told Deadspin's <a href="http://tom_ley.kinja.com/" target="_blank">Tom Ley</a> [pictured above; bare-faced on the left; with tinted moisturizer on the right] that <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/whitneyjefferson/kourtney-kardashian-calls-scott-disick-out-for-wearing-her-m" target="_blank">Scott Disick wears tinted moisturizer</a> he said, &quot;I don't know who that is.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;He impregnated Kourtney Kardashian. Twice,&quot; I told him, &quot;And he was kind of secretive about wearing tinted moisturizer, but when she found out she was really supportive and said, 'Tinted moisturizer is amazing to use. It's awesome.' And I agree with her.&quot;</p>
<p>I used CK One 3-in-1 Face Makeup with SPF 8 on Tom. Sure, it's actually titled &quot;makeup&quot; instead of &quot;tinted moisturizer,&quot; but CK One is a notoriously unisex beauty brand.</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kc4rw17ctqtjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p>When I asked <a href="http://barryap.kinja.com/" target="_blank">Barry Petchesky</a> about his own personal beauty regimen he laughed at the silliness of my question. </p>
<p>&quot;Do you wash your face?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I mean…no? Sometimes?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;What do you use?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Soap.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;A special face soap? Something with salicylic acid?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Oh, I don't know. If I wash it, I guess I use hand soap.&quot;</p>
<p>(How annoying is that? He didn't have a single pimple on his face <em>and</em> he's a smoker.) I used Laura Mercier Tinted Moisturizer SPF 20 on him. (Bare-faced on the left; with tinted moisturizer on the right.)</p>
<p>I asked Barry what he considers crossing the line between toiletries and makeup and he said, &quot;Anything where the results are immediately seen.&quot;</p>
<p>So I guess, by his definition, Barry is wearing makeup, because the results were immediate—and <em>gorgeous</em>.</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kc4r2flynjpjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p><a href="http://jackdickey.kinja.com/" target="_blank">Jack Dickey</a> was my favorite of the makeovers because the shade (Fair) of CK One I used on him seemed custom-made for his skin. Some women spend <em>years</em> trying to find the perfect color and he happened upon his by accident. The tragedy is that he probably won't even ever wear it again. (Again: He's bare-faced on the left; with tinted moisturizer on the right.)</p>
<p>In fact, none of these guys expressed any interest in wearing tinted moisturizer beyond helping me out for this post. It's not that they disliked it—they all politely told me that they liked their after shots, and Jack later emailed me, &quot;WHATEVER. FELT GREAT&quot;—but they don't even wear regular moisturizer.</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18kc4spmkw7xajpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<p>Although, I don't see how anyone could argue with these results. However, none of them received compliments. But they weren't on the receiving end of any derision either. As far as they could tell, nobody suspected they were wearing makeup. Probably because they looked so natural!</p>]]></description><category domain="">makeovers</category><category domain="">tinted moisturizer</category><category domain="">makeup</category><category domain="">skin</category><category domain="">beauty</category><category domain="">standards of beauty</category><category domain="">guys</category><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 18:20:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">472554002</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracie Egan Morrissey]]></dc:creator></item></channel></rss>