<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0"><channel><title>Jezebel</title><link>http://jezebel.com</link><description>Jezebel is gossip, culture, fashion, and sex for the contemporary woman.</description><language>en</language><item><title><![CDATA[Please Stop Telling Us When to Get Married]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993816/please-stop-telling-us-when-to-get-married</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jwu4ggq2vlmjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Should you get married while you're young and have &quot;peak nubility,&quot; or wait until you're older and have not-as-great boobs but a more emotionally mature attitude toward compromise? Careful, I think it's a trick question. But if you're the sort of person who needs an article or someone else's experience to answer that question (assuming you're among the &quot;lucky&quot; portion of the population who is actually allowed to marry), then rest assured the advice is out there, chomping at the bit for you to put a ring on it either now or never. Hint: Do it now! </p><p>That's right: As if it isn't obviously ludicrous to tell people what to do or when to do it when it comes to crazy, madcap, culturally condoned unions such as marriage, people are out there still telling you when to do it. Mostly, they want you to do it now. Because now is better than later, when you might not be able to do it anymore. I think if you would just do it now, the argument goes, you would see what all the rest of us who already did it have, and you could get in on this, too, like a hotly tipped stock destined for greatness that only other rich people know about.</p>
<p>Why? Are we all just a grandmotherly stereotype of worried fretting over whether all the young ladies are settled yet? Why do we want to tell (mostly) women to get married so soon? Does it just make us feel better? Is this a hookup culture <a href="http://www.nerve.com/love-sex/10-reasons-why-hookup-culture-isn't-leaving-a-generation-unhappy-and-unfulfilled" target="_blank">backlash</a>? Are we afraid that women are reaching peak fulfillment in their lives and careers and finally holding out for the most equitable, manageable arrangement in the history of forever, and it's making us nervous? Do we not know how to deal with new generations of women who might never have kids or find &quot;Mr. Right?&quot;</p>
<p>Newsflash: We know when or if or how we want to get married. We do. And even if we haven't decided, we still know that advice is great and all, but that we will ultimately make this decision for ourselves relative to our situations and lives and desires. Stories about what other women do or did are perfectly interesting but ultimately not really applicable to us and our lives. Please stop pretending that they are.</p>
<p>Take this &quot;marry young&quot; <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/double_x/doublex/2013/04/i_married_young_what_are_the_rest_of_you_waiting_for.single.html" target="_blank">lady</a> who is making the Internet rounds. Message: She married young! And so should you. More specifically, Julia Shaw married at 23, an age when I believe I was literally doing bong hits before original-run <em>Melrose Place</em> came on. Shaw met husband David in college and angels burst through the clouds, so they entered post-haste into the Maturity-Commitment Generator. (<a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/xx_factor/2013/03/29/susan_patton_is_very_concerned_for_women_that_aren_t_trying_harder_to_marry.html" target="_blank">Princeton Mom</a> would be so proud!) And since it worked out so well for Julia Shaw, she wonders why everyone isn't busting down the doors at City Hall to shack up with the quickness:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I'm a married millennial. I walked down the aisle at 23. My husband, David, was 25. We hadn't arrived. I had a job; he, a job offer and a year left in law school. But we couldn't buy a house or even replace the car when it died a few months into our marriage. We lived in a small basement apartment, furnished with secondhand Ikea. We did not have Internet (checking email required a trip to the local coffee shop) or reliable heat.</p>
<p>Marriage wasn't something we did after we'd grown up — it was how we have grown up and grown together. We've endured the hardships of typical millennials: job searches, job losses, family deaths, family conflict, financial fears, and career concerns. The stability, companionship, and intimacy of marriage enabled us to overcome our challenges and develop as individuals and a couple. We learned how to be strong for one another, to comfort, to counsel, and to share our joys and not just our problems.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Great, that's great. I don't mean to diminish in any way the success of her arrangement — applause for everyone who does a thing they like and is happy with the thing. But this argument is deeply flawed as a case for marriage for anyone other than Julia and David Shaw, and it's almost too easy to refute.</p>
<p>One: All kinds of relationships, with lovers and friends, with pets you care for, with yourself, in all varieties, can offer something toward our growth and/or stunting as people. Two: marriage, in and of itself, isn't stable. Or intimate. Nor does it offer companionship. It's a legal/religious agreement. The people inside of it can foster and nurture those things. Or not. A lot of 'em do. A lot of 'em don't. That's what the whole divorce rate is about.</p>
<p>I don't see why people attribute what's good about marriage to marriage as a concept, as opposed to the people in it and the work they are doing. Marriage is just a framework. Everything about the way it goes comes down to the two people in it and how they face the challenges that befall them.</p>
<p>There are things, to be sure, about making it harder to leave a relationship that will influence the way you work on the relationship. Committing for life provides a framework for doing the heavy lifting over the long-term in a way that a casual relationship wouldn't. But in either situation, people can be for the notion of working it out no matter what or not. It's not marriage that creates (or more importantly, keeps) this promise. It's people.</p>
<p>This can also be achieved by living together, tangling up finances, having children out of wedlock, sharing a pet, being in love, buying a very expensive couch. At City Hall, no one hands you your intimacy award. No one delivers a maturity certificate. And nowhere on the marriage license does it grant soul-mate status.</p>
<p>Shaw goes on to itemize the particulars/benefits of their arrangement in a way that suggests they are universally desired goals: jump-started independence, scraping by together, and then a whopper of a heads-up about how soul mates work:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Sometimes people delay marriage because they are searching for the perfect soul mate. But that view has it backward. Your spouse becomes your soul mate after you've made those vows to each other in front of God and the people who matter to you. You don't marry someone because he's your soul mate; he becomes your soul mate because you married him.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Hey, I'm sure that's one way it can go. But I'm willing to bet right now that plenty of people made their vows in front of God and everyone including their 3rd grade teacher and ended up with something far short of the glory of soul mates: divorce.</p>
<p>But ultimately, Shaw just wants everyone to know that you don't have to have a lot of money to be married, &quot;just maturity, commitment, and a desire to grow up together.&quot;</p>
<p>That's fine. But I find it really hard to believe that people who want to get married are waiting and somehow missing out on it because they thought they needed more money or a better job first.</p>
<p>Plus, tons of people in their twenties don't want to punch through the milestones and challenges of this notoriously tenuous decade figuring out who they are and fucking it up magnificently already shackled to someone else inside the Maturity-Commitment Generator. Some of them prefer to make some mistakes during this age, the kind that don't require lawyers to extricate from.</p>
<p>But of course, the ultimate flaw of her argument and all when-to-get married arguments is that she generalizes what is ultimately real specific-like: She was ready to get married, so she did.</p>
<p>Being ready to step inside the tangled web of marriage and make the best of it, fight the good fight, foster decency and harmony and all that jazz, is what makes marriage a good, worth-it thing. If you want it. Not being ready won't produce those results. Which is why, as we all know, lots of marriages end, and lots of people like to wait.</p>
<p>Amanda Marcotte over at <em>Slate</em> <a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/xx_factor/2013/04/02/a_reply_to_julia_shaw_women_marry_later_because_they_don_t_want_to_get_divorced.html" target="_blank">discusses</a> the fact that women wait because they don't want to get divorced.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Not that any of this matters anyway. Watching conservatives desperately try to bully women into younger marriage with a couple of promises and a whole lot of threats is <a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/xx_factor/2013/03/29/susan_patton_is_very_concerned_for_women_that_aren_t_trying_harder_to_marry.html" target="_blank">highly entertaining but clearly not persuasive</a>. Women marry later because it makes sense given their own career aspirations. Even many of those pushing the ideological argument for young marriage, <a href="http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2013/03/26/why-gay-marriage-will-win-and-sexual-freedom-will-lose.html#pq=7zpOxS" target="_blank">like Megan McArdle</a>, tend, when it comes to their own lives, to opt out of the pressure to be young divorcees martyred for the cause. I'm glad young marriage is working out for Shaw, but for the majority of women, dating and cohabitating until they're more sure is working out just fine. If he's good enough to marry, he'll still be around when you're ready to make that leap.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And if he's not? That'll be OK too. Isn't it weird to assume women don't understand the risk of marriage, or not marrying, just as we understand the risk of marrying young, or old? There certainly are all kinds of situations where individuals put off getting married and then don't find a suitable partner so easily. There are situations where people spend their young lives married and regret it, only to finally experience something like freedom or personal growth once the marriage ends.</p>
<p>Marriage is a gamble. Not marrying is a gamble. Life is a gamble. It's all so particular, so multi-layered, so irrational, and given the chances for any relationship's success, to enter into one at all is to take a kind of magical leap off of Logic Cliff. This is why it seems foolish to be evangelical about such things in either direction. Understanding of the kaleidoscope of risk/reward in what it means to pair off will help you make the decision whether to do it or not. Stories — like anyone's, like <a href="http://jezebel.com/5993727/roger-eberts-wife-chaz-says-their-life-together-was-more-beautiful-and-epic-than-a-movie">Roger Ebert's</a>, or especially Julia Shaw's — may give you useful anecdotal evidence or insight into how it works for other people. But not you. You have to get your hands dirty and figure it out on your own dime.</p>]]></description><category domain="">i thee dread</category><category domain="">marriage</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Sun, 7 Apr 2013 17:25:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993816</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Moore ]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[The More Weight I Lose, The More Fat Jokes I Hear: A Dating Story]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993824/the-more-weight-i-lose-the-more-fat-jokes-i-hear-a-dating-story</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jsu9a8wp2kijpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text"> When my first and only long-term relationship ended toward the end of 2012, I was warned that I would likely do one or more of the following at my ex: date at him, eat at him, exercise at him or shop at him.</p>
<p>And though he had no Facebook account and we have very few friends in common for him to find about any of the above, I dove headlong into the dating and exercise variations of imaginary vengeance. I got a Living Social deal to a bootcamp and willingly entered that special circle of Hell where self-esteem goes to either flourish or die: OKCupid. </p>
<p>Bootcamp made me feel and look better almost immediately. Having settled into a work-dinner-Netflix-bed-routine, I had made little time for exercise during my relationship so my new friendship with endorphins and kettlebells was awesome.</p>
<p>OKCupid was...not endorphin-producing. This site has covered OKCupid up and down so I assume people are familiar enough with its many terrors that I don't need to summarize. For me specifically, the horror lay in the &quot;Body Type&quot; section. Like many women, I've felt overweight when I wasn't and felt significantly overweight when I was only slightly.</p>
<p>I settled on selecting &quot;Average&quot; and included pictures that only revealed my head and torso. A steady stream of offers came in that ranged from decent to disastrous. Nothing magical. Par for the course, I assumed.</p>
<p>When a friend insisted on seeing my profile after I complained of the mediocrity of the experience a few months in, she looked at me incredulously when she came to my photos.</p>
<p>&quot;Why are there no full body pictures?&quot;</p>
<p>After much haranguing, I agreed to an impromptu photoshoot in stretch pants and changed my body type to &quot;Fit.&quot;</p>
<p>Having never really recovered from the times when I was called fat explicitly, I failed to notice that my body was transforming into something deemed desirable to a large swath of the population. I was delighted at first. But then it turned out that that large swath of the population that I had been pining over turned out to contain a significant number of sizeist assholes.</p>
<p>As I went on more and more dates, I was suddenly and inexplicably on the receiving end of fat jokes. On dates. First dates. Dates when you're supposedly trying to impress people by being a good person.</p>
<p>I almost excused the first one as typical first-meeting banter. I'm a stickler for punctuality and since lots of my dates are not, I told the guy, &quot;I'm really glad you're on time!&quot;</p>
<p>His reply was, &quot;I'm really glad you're not actually an obese middle-aged divorcee!&quot;</p>
<p>I get that it was a reference to the potential nightmare of being Catfished (do people really say that in real life?) but the heart of that statement is &quot;Lol, good thing you're not fat.&quot;</p>
<p>  During the course of another date, the man with whom I was sharing dinner conversation described a harrowing roommate experience that involved (gasp!) living with two overweight women who (wait for it) kept a lot of food in the refrigerator! Something out of Kafka, truly.</p>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="94" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jpuo8iz5ixojpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p> No, but this question does. TREMENDOUSLY.</p>
<associate></associate>
<p>I considered the possibility that I just had terrible luck and had stumbled onto two jerks that thought fat jokes were just some first date funsies, but the pattern continued. They ranged from snide remarks to explicit jokes but all had the same mean-spirit that lives behind any joke made at the expense of others. The worst offender was someone I'll call Dick.</p>
<p>On a second date with Dick, he asked me about my online dating experience so far. Having some doozies and what I consider a gift for oral storytelling, I was happy to give him a few of the most entertainingly upsetting anecdotes from the growing archive.  </p>
<p>There was the guy that made me cry on the first date by yelling at me for not living up to my full potential (something he determined by my graduate education and my failure to attend law school, despite a good LSAT score). For good measure, he called a lot of things &quot;retarded&quot; as well.</p>
<p>There was a man who I politely declined for a second date that followed up with 11 text messages demanding to know why, including one in which he said, &quot;I know you're uncomfortable right now but I need to know exactly what I did wrong for my own edification!&quot;</p>
<p>He, too, had made a fat joke.</p>
<p>Dick laughed at these and said, &quot;My biggest problem so far has been with the stealth fatties.&quot; Chortle, chortle.</p>
<p>His reference, of course, was to women looking thinner in their picture than in real life. An injustice beyond measure, I would surely agree.   </p>
<p>&quot;That's not nice,&quot; I said, refusing to play it polite till the end of the date and just never see him again. Not only was his joke mean, the man was 35 years old and using the word &quot;fattie.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Well, it's not a nice thing to do to a person!&quot; he said. He looked dead serious as he said that to look one way in a picture and show up looking different is genuinely unkind.</p>
<p>To recap, I had just told him about a date that had deeply hurt my feelings and another whose reaction to rejection had bordered on harassment. His idea of an equivalently mean act was someone showing up on a date at a size he deemed unacceptable.   </p>
<p>He further defended himself by claiming that these women identified as &quot;Thin&quot; in their Body Type section which I must say is the biggest load of horseshit I've seen since I was on the set of &quot;Seabiscuit. &quot;</p>
<p>You never know where a stealth fattie might be lurking.</p>
<p>Overweight women are aware that they are not thin, they are reminded of it every day by &quot;well-intentioned&quot; co-workers and sinisterly intentioned advertisers. The potential for outright ridicule is way too high and I simply can't believe that any overweight woman has actually done this unless as part of some daring social experiment to see just how terribly things would go.</p>
<p>I felt like I was suddenly part of a club that I didn't know existed prior: People who were small enough to not get offended by fat jokes. Was this their roundabout, cruel way of assuring to me that they didn't think I was fat? Was it meant to be some sort of compliment to me, that I was part of an arbitrarily decided weight class that they had deemed acceptable for dating purposes?</p>
<p>I had seen &quot;Mean Girls&quot; and everything, but didn't actually know that losing weight was going to subject me to jokes that a few months prior I would have thought were directed at me.</p>
<p>For full disclosure, I have never been significantly overweight. I fully recognize that the experience of constantly feeling overweight and actually being overweight are completely different, as the latter can often come with a world of legitimate cruelty, particularly when one has the audacity to identify themselves as romantically viable. I can't and won't claim that as my experience.</p>
<p>But having sat close enough to the edge of having a real weight problem and being called fat by enough crushes and personal trainers has given me a lifetime of neuroses about it that I feel earns me at least a partial seat at the table.</p>
<p>Why is it that someone who would never dream of making an offensive joke in another category is so eager to make one about weight? How are they so confident that there is no one overweight in my life, past or present, that I love and care about and don't want to hear reduced to a punchline?</p>
<p>Spoiler alert to these fools: Bodies change. The body in front of you might not have always looked like it does now. Even bigger bummer: it might not always look like that in the future either. This is especially pertinent to those looking for long-term relationships. My body may have changed into something deemed more acceptable than it was in the past, but the sense that something remains of the kind of body that you're ridiculing is still very much alive.</p>
<p>The truth is, the real stealth fatties are not these women who look thinner online than they do in real life. The stealth fatties are women of every size, the ones who have been teased relentlessly for their weight or told by industries and idiots that they are not good enough because of how their bodies look.</p>
<p>They have internalized this message, sometimes forever, regardless of what they look like on the outside. And making a joke about fat people isn't going to make them feel any prettier. It's going to make them think that you're mean. Which you are.</p>
<p>We stealth fatties are lurking behind more sizes than you think. Make a joke about the goddamn weather.</p>
<p><em>This post <a href="http://www.xojane.com/issues/the-more-weight-i-lose-the-more-fat-jokes-i-hear-a-dating-story" target="_blank">originally appeared</a> in <a href="http://www.xojane.com/" target="_blank">XOJane</a>. Republished with permission.</em></p>]]></description><category domain="">weighty matters</category><category domain="">weight loss</category><category domain="">xojane</category><category domain="">dating</category><category domain="">republished</category><category domain="">shutterstock</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Sat, 6 Apr 2013 15:10:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993824</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jessica Coen]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[March Madness: Come as You Are — a Brain, an Athlete, a Basket Case, a Princess or a Criminal]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993838/march-madness-come-as-you-are--a-brain-an-athlete-a-basket-case-a-princess-or-a-criminal</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jq0zyoe5tndjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Whoa. WHOA. Did that really just happen?! Did Gameboy really beat out East Coast vs. West Coast Rap by less than 100 votes?! Important question for all you conspiracy theorists out there — did East Coast vs. West Coast Rap really lose or did it just fake its own death and is now chilling out on some remote island somewhere? Can we expect to see it come back <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TGbrFmPBV0Y" target="_blank">in hologram</a> any time soon?</p>
<p>Over on the 80s side of the bracket, cocaine took out Lisa Frank with 59.86% of the vote, so at least danger is triumphing over childhood innocence somewhere in this competition.</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jq0zey4w4lwpng/ku-xlarge.png" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<associate></associate>
<p>Today in the 80s stadium, the Brat Pack goes up against MTV. Who knows who will win, but we have it on good authority that the Brat Pack sewed its own prom dress for the occasion and looks ravishing. Speaking of looks, I think we can all agree that <a href="http://ia.media-imdb.com/images/M/MV5BNDE2NTMyODkwOV5BMl5BanBnXkFtZTcwMjE1ODcxNw@@._V1._SY314_CR16,0,214,314_.jpg" target="_blank">one of these things</a> has aged much more gracefully than the <a href="http://www.mtv.com/shows/16_and_pregnant/season_4/series.jhtml" target="_blank">other</a>.</p>
<p>Travelling on over to 90s town (give me a break, you guys — I've written a lot of these), we've got the musical showdown of all musical showdowns as Grunge goes against the Spice Girls (i.e. the polar opposite of grunge). Oy vey — no matter what the outcome, this category is bound to create a whole mess of unhappy campers, which for the Grunge kids won't be too much of a difference from how they normally feel.</p>
<p>You have 24 hours before polls close.<br/></p>
<script src="http://static.polldaddy.com/p/7017760.js"></script><br/>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/7017760/" target="_blank">80s: Brat Pack (3) vs. MTV (2)</a></noscript>
<script src="http://static.polldaddy.com/p/7017765.js"></script><br/>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/7017765/" target="_blank">90s: Grunge (2) vs. Spice Girls (6)</a></noscript>]]></description><category domain="">80s vs 90s</category><category domain="">march madness</category><category domain="">tweet</category><category domain="">top</category><pubDate>Fri, 5 Apr 2013 22:20:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993838</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Madeleine Davies]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Your Imaginary Boyfriend: Jon Snow]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993820/your-imaginary-boyfriend-jon-snow</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jpuiv62uhhdjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text"><em>Welcome back to Your Imaginary Boyfriend/Girlfriend, Jezebel's series in which we explore the wild and entirely fabricated world of dating a famous person. As is the risk with most fan fiction, things might get weird and things might get creepy, but the important thing is that we all have a good time.</em></p>
<p><em>Today's Imaginary Boyfriend is Game of Thrones' Jon Snow.</em> </p>
<p>&quot;Well that was — well — that was something,&quot; you say, leaning back into your headboard, trying to make yourself comfortable as if a pillow or two could ease the gnawing worry in your gut that maybe it was all too soon for this.</p>
<p>There's no response from beneath the pile of pelts that sits next to you and you want to assume that Jon Snow, bastard son of Ned Stark and former Brother of the Night's Watch, has drifted off into a blissful sleep, but you know otherwise. His silence soars across the bed like an arrow and sinks itself into your heart with a message. <em>I am a changed man now. I am a ruined man and you are the one who ruined me.</em></p>
<p>&quot;Jon?&quot; you reach over to gently shake the furs and suddenly wonder where they even came from. The rest of your bedroom furnishings come from CB2 and the Ikea MALM line. He must have brought them himself. &quot;Jon.&quot;</p>
<p>No words, but you do hear a sniffle.</p>
<p>&quot;I know you're awake,&quot; you coax. &quot;Did we move to fast for you? I told you, I would have been okay with waiting — &quot;</p>
<p>He jerks up suddenly, pelts falling away to reveal a wild head of messy black curls and a stare so hard and sharp that it could pierce its way through stone.</p>
<p>&quot;I broke my oath,&quot; he says, voice hoarse. His mouth, framed by several days' growth of facial hair, crumbles into a tortured frown.</p>
<p>&quot;Oh.&quot;</p>
<p>Jon Snow childishly flips onto his side so that once again he isn't facing you. You angle around to get a better look at his face to see that he's pouting. You want to feel annoyed at his tempestuousness, but, <em>old gods</em>, what a pout it is.</p>
<p>&quot;Come on,&quot; you say gently. &quot;It's okay. You're not in Westeros anymore. You're here in the now with me. Look — &quot; you gesture towards your television. &quot;We can even watch <em>Maddow</em>.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I don't deserve to watch <em>Maddow</em>. Why can't you understand what I've done?&quot;</p>
<p>You rest your chin on his muscular arm and try to think of how you can better ease his conscience.</p>
<p>&quot;Oaths don't matter that much here. We don't even have a Night's Watch. Besides,&quot; a thought suddenly occurs to you. &quot;Didn't you already break your oath when you went off with the Wildlings?&quot;</p>
<p>This was clearly the wrong thing to say.</p>
<p>&quot;You throw that in my face at a moment like this?&quot;</p>
<p>He stands up suddenly to glare down at you and — despite the pout, despite the stare and beautiful hair — your patience begins to wane.</p>
<p>&quot;You're being manipulative,&quot; you tell him. &quot;You asked to come home with me. I was taking my cues from you.&quot;</p>
<p>His chocolate cow eyes immediately soften as he mutters barely above a whisper, &quot;Don't you understand?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;No.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Try to understand.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;That was your first time.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Yes,&quot; he says, blushing. &quot;But that's not it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;So explain it to me.&quot;</p>
<p>You know you sound harsh, but you're tired, frustrated and starting to feel hurt yourself.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a bastard.&quot;</p>
<p>He turns away from you to stare out the window and you don't have the heart to tell him that it's far less dramatic when he's staring out into an air duct than when he's taking in the vast and expansive tundra that's north of the wall.</p>
<p>&quot;That's it?&quot; You don't mean to be dismissive, but you can't believe that Jon Snow is choosing this moment to be so broken up over his parentage.</p>
<p>&quot;<em>That</em> is everything.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;You know,&quot; you start after a few moments of intense (for him) and awkward (for you) silence. &quot;That's not a big deal here. Lots of people were born out of wedlock or grew up without fathers. Barack Obama, for example —&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Your king?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Um, yeah. Sort of.&quot;</p>
<p>This seems to calm him and he returns to sit next to you on the bed.</p>
<p>&quot;Still, I should have taken you as my wife first.&quot;</p>
<p>He settles his head into your lap and unsure of what else to do, you begin playing with his hair.</p>
<p>&quot;Oh.&quot; <em>Oh</em>. &quot;That's not something you're ever going to have to do.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Of course it is,&quot; he says. &quot;And I am sorry for how I acted before. I know now that it was all worth it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We'll talk about it more in the morning&quot; is what you say, but what you think is entirely different: <em>You know nothing Jon Snow. You really know nothing.</em></p>
<hr/><root>
Previously:</root><br/>
<a href="http://jezebel.com/5989007/your-imaginary-girlfriend-taylor-swift">Your Imaginary Girlfriend: Taylor Swift</a><br/>
<a href="http://jezebel.com/5969978/your-imaginary-boyfriend-jesus-christ">Your Imaginary Boyfriend: Jesus Christ</a><br/>
<a href="http://jezebel.com/5965176/imaginary-boyfriend-kanye-west">Your Imaginary Boyfriend: Kanye West</a><br/>
<a href="http://jezebel.com/5963346/your-imaginary-girlfriend-rachel-maddow">Your Imaginary Girlfriend: Rachel Maddow</a><br/>
<a href="http://jezebel.com/5961800/thanksgiving-with-your-imaginary-boyfriend-joseph-gordon+levitt">Thanksgiving With Your Imaginary Boyfriend Joseph Gordon-Levitt</a><br/>
<a href="http://jezebel.com/5959788/your-imaginary-boyfriend-cory-booker">Your Imaginary Boyfriend: Cory Booker</a>]]></description><category domain="">imaginary boyfriend</category><category domain="">game of thrones</category><category domain="">imaginary girlfriend</category><category domain="">fan fiction</category><category domain="">jon snow</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Fri, 5 Apr 2013 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993820</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Madeleine Davies]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[I Re-Watched Jurassic Park for You Because, Really, Who Has the Time?]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993638/everything-that-happens-in-jurassic-park-in-chronological-order</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jpoanaj4sx0gif/ku-xlarge.gif" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">When I was 12, in 1994, I basically did three things: watch <em>The Fugitive</em>, watch <em>A League of Their Own</em>, and watch <em>Jurassic Park</em>. Oh, and listen to Weird Al's &quot;Off the Deep End.&quot; Four things. Over and over and over. (Oh!!! And play that Yo! Noid Nintendo game! Five things! But this is not relevant.) In that impressionable year and the ones that followed, <em>Jurassic Park</em> burrowed its way into my consciousness like some asshole frog DNA (COMPLETELY interrupting the cellular mitosis, BTW) and it has been there ever since—whispering &quot;hold on to your butts&quot; and &quot;blah blah blah something about a flea circus&quot; whenever I needed it the most. And now, 20 years later, as the cruel noose of Father Time's mustache grows ever tighter around my neck, it is with a mix of excitement and horror that I anticipate the 3D theatrical rerelease of my beloved <em>JP</em>. </p>
<p>On the one hand, fuuuuuuuck 3D (here, strap this headache machine to your face and then try to enjoy these screaming children!). On the other hand, dinos <em>and Jeff Goldblum</em>!!! On the third hand, when did I get so old? On the fourth hand, when will this frog DNA stop making me grow extra hands?</p>
<p>I can't tell you what to do, friend. But in case you don't have 127 minutes and $15 to spare, or if you don't feel like leaving your couch to see a 20-year-old movie, or if you're just easily confused by fake dinosaur science (who do I look like—B.D. WONG!?), or if you just want to pretend like you're watching the movie along with some drunk lady, I've broken it down for you in one handy guide. Herewith, everything that happens in <em>Jurassic Park</em> presented in a handy chronological format.</p>
<hr/>
<p>We open on some bushes. <em>Scary bushes</em>. You can tell the bushes are scary because a bunch of dudes in jumpsuits are standing near them looking scared. The bushes are all, &quot;Rustle, rustle. Rustle, rustle.&quot; There is <em>definitely</em> something in those bushes. Some sort of monster. &quot;Come over here,&quot; the bushes whisper. &quot;Try me, I'm just bushes!&quot; Suddenly, the monster begins to emerge. The leaves part. Is it a bigfoot? Is it a dino?</p>
<p>No!!!</p>
<p>IT'S JUST SOME DUMB FORKLIFT CARRYING A DUMB BOX. The monster, it turns out, isn't a monster at all—it's a machine. The real monster, you see, <em>is man</em>. (Or else the real monster is forklifts. Unsure. TBD.)</p>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="161" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jotp4b7gklcgif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p> Oh, except there totally are legit monsters in the box that the forklift is carrying. They're called velociraptors, and they are the world's biggest bitchez. Right away they wiggle out of the box and eat this dude named &quot;the Gatekeeper,&quot; and then they're like &quot;OM GROM GROMPH. WASN'T EVEN HUNGRY—JUST ATE HIM TO FUCK WITH YOU GUYS #YOLO.&quot; One of the velociraptors makes extended Six-Sigma eye contact with this Great White Hunter dude (let's call him &quot;the Keymaster&quot;) through the bars, like she's thinking, &quot;I'mma bookmark you for later, Keymaster.&quot; And she does. (Clever girl.)</p>
<p><em>Foreshadowing</em>.</p>
<p>Now we're in an amber mine in the Dominican Republic! Try to keep up! A lawyer is there, being annoying. &quot;Waaaahhhhh, I want inspections! Inspections are my food!&quot; yells the lawyer. &quot;Mr. Hammond <em>hates</em> inspections,&quot; says the guy in charge of the mine, all normal as though that isn't the vaguest thing in the world to hate. The lawyer suggests that they get a certain &quot;Dr. Grant&quot; to do the inspection, because of &quot;insurance.&quot; (Not sure why that's the mine guy's call, but bygones.) Mine guy isn't into it. &quot;Grant's like me,&quot; he explains. &quot;He's a digger.&quot; Then the miner, who's been mining this whole time BTW, gets very excited about something he's just mined. It's a piece of amber with a bug in it. The lawyer, feeling less appreciated than an old bug (and still very concerned about inspections), stomps off to sit on a tuffet somewhere and lick an oversized lollipop, probably. That's a lawyer stereotype, right? LAWYERS.</p>
<p>Cut to the Badlands. Dr. Grant is digging (OF COURSE) at a fossilized velociraptor skeleton, which is sort of half-buried in 1-2 inches of soft sand, like the cap to your sunscreen, or Joey in the opening credits of <em>Friends</em>. &quot;I hate computers,&quot; says Dr. Grant. Dr. Grant <em>hates computers</em>. Dr. Grant touches Laura Dern on the buns to establish that their relationship is libidinous and caliente, yet tender. Laura Dern, in double denim, is busy agitating for Dr. Grant to impregnate her with a small paleontological baby. No luck yet.</p>
<p>Wait, who's that talking? UGH, it's a kid. DR. GRANT HATES KIDS. They're like computers, but covered in food and hair! Even worse, this kid is talking talking talking, and he has no respect for dinos. &quot;That doesn't look very scary,&quot; the kid says, eyeing the velociraptor with disdain. &quot;More like a 6-foot turkey.&quot;</p>
<p>:-|</p>
<p>&quot;Oh no,&quot; says Laura Dern, shaking her head. She knows what's coming. Dr. Grant is going to spill the intestines of an innocent child with his 6-inch turkey-claw AGAIN. (The paperwork alone! Major headache.) But in the middle of his super-mean lecture about dino behavior and the fashionable disembowelment theories of the day, Dr. Grant is interrupted by the arrival of a helicopter full of Richard Attenborough's hubris. Richard Attenborough (Mr. Hammond, mentioned earlier, hates inspections, etc.) has <em>ruined the turkey dig</em>. Asshole. But it doesn't matter. He's there to invite Dr. Grant and Laura Dern to inspect his mysterious new theme park. Then this dialogue happens:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Hammond: &quot;There's no doubt our attractions will drive kids out of their minds.&quot;<br/>
Grant: &quot;What are those?&quot;<br/>
Laura Dern: &quot;Small versions of adults, honey.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>SOLID JOKE.</p>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="225" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jotp4beg26rgif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p> Then there's a scene of Newman eating breakfast. Later in the movie, breakfast eats Newman.</p>
<p><em>Foreshadowing</em>.</p>
<p>Dr. Grant and Laura Dern hop into Richard Attenborough's helicopter and point the pilot toward Costa Rica. Also on board is Jeffward Goldblum as mathematician Dr. Ian Malcolm, about whom it is extremely difficult for me not to write in all-caps at all times. It was a feat not to write this <em>review</em> entirely in all-caps, I have to tell you. I have basically no lowercase feelings about <em>Jurassic Park</em>.</p>
<p>Jeff Goldblum explains that he's not a mathemagician so much as a &quot;CHAOTICIAN. Chaotician.&quot; At this point, if you go see <em>Jurassic Park</em> in the theater, you will have the opportunity to watch Jeff Goldblum hit on Laura Dern in 3D. Worth it.</p>
<p>Dr. Grant, being some sort of Flintstone who has never ridden in a motorized vehicle before, fumbles with the seatbelts like a confounded granny in an infomercial. The helicopter descends, and everyone hops into some jeeps. At this point, Richard Attenborough has flown four people <em>all the way to Costa Rica</em> without actually telling them why the fuck they're going to Costa Rica. Presumably they've been sitting in a tiny enclosed space staring at each other in silence for hours and hours. Nobody seems to think this is weird. Nobody is yelling at all.</p>
<p>The jeeps rumble deeper into the jungle. &quot;HEY, RICHARD ATTENBOROUGH, WHAT'S WITH THIS BIG FENCE?&quot; &quot;DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT. IT'S DEFINITELY NOT FOR MONSTERS.&quot;</p>
<p>Finally it's time for the Big Reveal. There's dinos! Dinos everywhere! Dr. Grant pees his own pants, and then he pees Laura Dern's pants too, and then a butterfly pees its pants and it causes a landslide in Calabasas. &quot;We're going to make a fortune with this place,&quot; says the lawyer, who clearly doesn't understand that greedy lines like that get you killed in Steven Spielberg movies.</p>
<p>&quot;Welcome to Jurassic Park!&quot;</p>
<p>Richard Attenborough leads them all into a little movie theater where he has a conversation with a piece of cartoon DNA named &quot;Mr. DNA.&quot; Mr. DNA pronounces &quot;dahnasauwwwer&quot; in this weird Huell Howser drawl, and also I just discovered that the guy who voiced Mr. DNA <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0123354/" target="_blank">is dead now</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>His later career was hampered by acute alcoholism. His career was finished when he was arrested by detectives in May of 2004 after barricading himself inside his Los Angeles home for six hours before surrendering. Initial reports claim that a SWAT team had responded to a call from two of his female roommates that he was inebriated, armed and holding a third female roommate hostage. It was reported that he had been depressed over losing voice over work.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That is an extremely sad story. Think about it when you watch Mr. DNA, in case you were having too much fun enjoying this light popcorn thriller. Sorry.</p>
<p>Turns out, Jurassic Park scientists were able to build their own dahnasauwwwers by extracting blood from the stomachs of dinosquitos, putting the blood in a jar with some frog DNA and glue, and then shaking it. Or something like that. I don't know. Go ask B.D. Wong. He's in charge here.</p>
<p>The dumb lawyer asks if B.D. Wong is &quot;auto-erotica,&quot; but he means &quot;animatronic.&quot; It is offensive how little the lawyer knows about B.D. Wong.</p>
<p>After watching a baby velociraptor hatch (&quot;Poosh! Poosh!&quot;), Dr. Grant starts asking questions about how they control the dino populations. B.D. Wong explains that all of the animals at Jurassic Park are ladies, because B.D. Wong is on top of his shit and he engineered them that way and why must you always question B.D. Wong?</p>
<p>Time to feed the raptors! The Great White Hunter lowers an entire cow into the raptor cage, and they go fucking nuts. (Jurassic Park must go through cow slings like gangbusters.) GWH gives a terrifying PowerPoint (basically) on how smart the raptors are, their SAT scores, their Sudoku speed, their vengeful hunger for human intestines. Richard Attenborough tries to distract everyone with lunch—&quot;Alejandro's prepared a delightful menu for us. Chilean sea bass, I believe!&quot;—but ALAN GRANT DOESN'T GIVE A SHIT ABOUT CHILEAN SEA BASS. He just wants to stand around and worry about raptors. (Dude, Alejandro probably worked really hard on that!)</p>
<p>They all sit down to lunch. Jeff Goldblum is extremely concerned:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;Don't you see the danger, John, inherent in what you're doing here? Genetic power is the most awesome force the planet's ever witnessed, yet you wield it like a kid that's found his dad's gun...What's so great about discovery? It's a violent, penetrative act that scars what it explores. What you call discovery, I call the rape of the natural world.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Laura Dern piles on, warning Richard Attenborough that the park is full of poisonous dino-plants that have &quot;no idea what century they're in&quot; and will defend themselves if necessary. (Devil's Snare, probs.) Attenborough is like, &quot;Yo, Dr. Grant, back me up!&quot; and Dr. Grant is like, &quot;NOPE.&quot;</p>
<p>Okay. Then these kids show up. Disregarding why anyone would bring children to an untested island of monstros, everyone gets back in the jeeps and they head out for a tour.</p>
<p>&quot;Hold on to your butts,&quot; says Samuel L. Jackson (Jurassic Park's chief engineer), demonstrating that he's the type of cool dude who says things like &quot;Hold on to your butts,&quot; possibly even <em>twice in one day</em>. (Foreshadowing.)</p>
<p>They don't see any dinosaurs right away, but that's not really important because Newman is busy fucking up everything on earth. (Wait till you guys see Newman fuck up everything on earth in 3D!) See, Newman figured out a get-rich-quick scheme called &quot;steal the dinosaur embryos and sell them to a shadowy ne'er-do-well,&quot; because that's really who you want to have control of your rogue dinosaur embryos. Just the ne'er-do-welliest fool on earth. In order to get the embryos and get out of the park undetected, Newman shuts down the security system. AGAIN. REALLY PLAYING FAST AND LOOSE WITH THE DINOS HERE.</p>
<p>Over in the jeep region, everyone is irritated that they haven't seen a T-rex yet and Jeff Goldblum is waxing philosophical.</p>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="163" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jow5uqar4jagif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p> Jeff Goldblum: &quot;God creates dinosaurs. God destroys dinosaurs. God creates man. Man destroys God. Man creates dinosaurs.&quot;<br/>
Laura Dern: &quot;Dinosaurs eat man, <em>woman inherits the earth</em>.&quot;<br/>
Dumb Lawyer: &quot;MISANDRY! MISANDRY!!!&quot; (Not really, but I bet he was thinking it.)</p>
<p>Everyone stops to help a Triceratops with a stomach ache and dig through its mammoth dump. (Fun fact: Laura Dern never goes anywhere without her elbow-length dump gloves. Both Laura Dern's character in this movie and the actual Laura Dern.)</p>
<p>Uhhhhh, okay, let's fast-forward. The T-rex gets out. The lawyer tries to hide in a toilet house, but T-rex finds him immediately because <em>T-rexes hate lawyers</em> (and, interestingly, landladies) and can smell one drop of lawyer in 100,000 gallons of Costa Rica. Newman gets eaten by <a href="http://25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m9qg4igPiw1rd27mgo1_400.gif" target="_blank">these fancy lads</a> (GOOD), while everyone else runs around screaming, or holds perfectly still, depending on their prior knowledge of dinosaur eyeballs. They all spend a long time trying to escape dinosaurs and sometimes getting covered in dino-boogers. A dino stampede interrupts Hurley and Jin's golf game. Dr. Grant pulls an extremely hilarious and appropriate prank involving an electric fence and some severely traumatized children. Everything is fucked.</p>
<p>(Cut to the interior of the Jurassic Park gift shop. Foolish humans and your hubristic dinosaur thermoses.)</p>
<p>Richard Attenborough is making a speech about fleas. He just wanted to make something that wasn't an illusion, you know? &quot;I wanted to show them something that wasn't an illusion. Something that was real. Something they could see and touch.&quot; And get dismembered by.</p>
<p>Off in the jungle somewhere, in grave danger of being seen and touched, the boy-child calls the girl-child a &quot;nerd&quot; and she goes: &quot;I'm a hacker! I am not a computer nerd—I prefer to be called a hacker.&quot; Lolololllololoolololll. (That's hacker-speak for, &quot;Oh, 1993. You're adorable.&quot;) Then the boy-child gets fried on an electric fence and Dr. Grant dubs him &quot;Big Tim, the Human Piece of Toast&quot;—which also, coincidentally, is my stripper name. What are the odds.</p>
<p>Samuel L. Jackson decides that he needs to go reset the main power switch to fix all the crap that Newman fucked up. I think you know what that means. It's HOLD ON TO YOUR BUTTS #2.</p>
<p>Please. Hold on to your butts. It's just a thing I say. It's kind of my catchphrase.</p>
<p>Oh, also, this whole time Jeff Goldblum is just doing this:</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="480" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jotmrgwdo3wjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<associate></associate>
<p>So.</p>
<p>When Samuel L. Jackson doesn't come back from his mission, Laura Dern decides it's time to hold on to <em>her</em> butt and go find him. She and Richard Attenborough have this exchange:</p>
<p>&quot;it ought to be me, really, going.&quot;<br/>
&quot;Why?&quot;<br/>
&quot;Well, I'm a...and you're a...&quot;<br/>
&quot;We can discuss sexism in survival situations when I get back.&quot;</p>
<p>BOOM, LAURA DERN. BOOM.</p>
<p>While Laura Dern runs to the switchy-hut (I am literally an engineer, obv), the Keymaster/GWH attempts to give her cover from the marauding velociraptors. It's the perfect job for him, seeing as he is the world's #1 expert on how to not get eaten by velociraptors. He immediately gets eaten by velociraptors. Oh well.</p>
<p>Over the walkie-talkie, Richard Attenborough gives Laura Dern instructions: &quot;You've got to pump up the primer handle in order to get the charge. It's large, flat, and gray. Like my penis.&quot;</p>
<p>Laura Dern manages to get the power back on, but not before being attacked by a raptor and snuggled by Samuel L. Jackson's dismembered arm. (Samuel L. Jackson's dismembered arm was probably the #1 most traumatic thing that happened to me in my entire childhood.)</p>
<p>Hey, hey Samuel L. Jackson, MAYBE YOU SHOULD HAVE HELD ON TO YOUR ARM INSTEAD OF YOUR BUTT, AMIRITE.</p>
<p>I'm sorry. That was out of line.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the raptors are chasing the kids around the kitchen (you guys, Alejandro has to clean all that up!), and they would have gotten <em>so eaten</em> if they hadn't come across science's #1 most effective dinosaur avoidance tool: the ladle. (Laura Dern never goes anywhere without her dump gloves and 17 ladles.)</p>
<p>Everyone is <em>almost safe</em>, but they just need to fix the computer so they can lock the raptors out. The hacker child runs over to help. Fortunately, it is a UNIX system (and/or <a href="http://apcmag.com/images/jurassic-park-unix-1.jpg" target="_blank">Microsoft Entertainment Pack Fuji Golf</a>), and she knows this. So then <a href="http://images.wikia.com/jurassicpark/images/9/95/JP-ControlRoom1.jpg" target="_blank">YAAAAYYY</a>! Except, oh wait, there are still raptors in there for some reason.</p>
<p>Blah blah blah run from the raptors some more, and then OH SHIT, T-REX COMES IN AND SAVES THE DAY AND EATS THE RAPTORS AND IT IS RIGHTEOUS AS HELL. RAAAAAAWWWWWRRRRR!</p>
<p>And Dr. Grant loves the kids now, and Laura Dern's hair looks great, and they're all flying home (um, except for the dead ones), and haaaaaaaaay there are some majestic pelicans! &quot;I <em>pelican't</em> fault you for using so many all-caps, Lindy,&quot; says Samuel L. Jackson who just came back from the dead for the purposes of my fanfic, &quot;This truly is the greatest movie ever.&quot; [<em>All laugh</em>.]</p>
<p>THE END. Now, if you need me, I'll be over here <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EvgNcE-tP4I" target="_blank">doing this</a>. Bye.</p>]]></description><category domain="">movies</category><category domain="">jurassic park</category><category domain="">jeff goldblum</category><category domain="">dinosaurs</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Fri, 5 Apr 2013 17:35:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993638</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Lindy West]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Making It Legal: The Morning-After Pill Is Really, Truly Available for All Ages]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993750/making-it-legal-the-morning+after-pill-is-really-truly-available-for-all-ages</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jp81qkmtuqejpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text"> In a monumentous decision, a federal judge has ordered the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to remove longstanding age and point of sale restrictions that prevent women from easy access to emergency contraception. The FDA has 30 days to comply. It's about damn time. </p>
<p>As it stands, emergency contraceptives are only available to women 17 and older without a prescription; younger teenagers need a prescription from a doctor. But even older women can have a hard time getting their hands on the morning after pill, since it's only for sale at health clinics and pharmacies — and because some pharmacists <a href="http://jezebel.com/5879194/pharmacists-who-either-lie-or-suck-at-their-job-tell-teens-they-cant-have-morning+after-pill?tag=morning_after-pill">take it upon themselves</a> to (very illegally) play moral police.</p>
<p><a href="http://jezebel.com/5984224/just-give-us-our-goddamn-morning+after-pills-already?tag=morning_after-pill">Multiple studies</a> have shown that all kinds of women — old and young, married and single, from all ethnicities and education levels — depend on emergency contraception to prevent unintended pregnancy. Even <a href="http://jezebel.com/5963400/even-pediatricians-think-teens-should-have-unrestricted-access-to-the-morning+after-pill?tag=morning_after-pill">pediatricians think</a> teens should have unrestricted access to Plan B. Near the end of 2011, it looked like things might change for the better when Teva Pharmaceuticals, the manufacturer of Plan B One-Step, filed a supplemental new drug application with the FDA to ensure that the drug would be available OTC for women of all ages.</p>
<p>But U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Secretary Kathleen Sebilius blocked the FDA commissioner's approval of the application, even though it included additional data that confirmed its safety for all-ages use. The next day, President Obama publicly supported Sebelius's decision, &quot;as a father of two daughters.&quot; Blergh.</p>
<p>Thankfully, the Center for Reproductive Rights' renewed its lawsuit against the agency seeking to expand over-the counter access to all brands of the morning-after pill, such as Plan B One-Step and Next Choice, to women of all ages, and now they've won! In his decision today, U.S. District Court Judge Edward Korman called the actions by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Secretary Kathleen Sebilius &quot;politically motivated, scientifically unjustified, and contrary to agency precedent.&quot; He continued: &quot;The decisions of the Secretary with respect to Plan B One-Step and that of the FDA with respect to the Citizen Petition, which it had no choice but to deny, were arbitrary, capricious, and unreasonable.&quot;<br/>
 <br/>
&quot;Today science has finally prevailed over politics,&quot; Nancy Northup, president and CEO for the Center for Reproductive Rights, said in a statement. &quot;This landmark court decision has struck a huge blow to the deep-seated discrimination that has for too long denied women access to a full range of safe and effective birth control methods.<br/>
 <br/>
&quot;Women all over the country will no longer face arbitrary delays and barriers just to get emergency contraception. It's a true victory for all women, especially young women, women without government-issued identification, and those who live in areas with limited pharmacy hours.&quot;<br/>
 <br/>
There are still some crucial unanswered questions — how affordable will it be, for one — and the government hasn't yet said whether it'll file an appeal, but the decision is still cause for instant celebration. It's ridiculous that it's taken this long for the government to OK a totally safe medication, but it's great timing, considering the <a href="http://jezebel.com/5982261/meet-the-18-for+profit-companies-fighting-obamacares-contraception-coverage">growing number of companies</a> that are fighting Obamacare's contraceptive mandate in court. Women of all ages need access to emergency contraception — and, in just 30 days, they should be able to purchase it as easily as aspirin.</p>]]></description><category domain="">pill baby pill</category><category domain="">morning after pill</category><category domain="">plan b</category><category domain="">contraception</category><category domain="">reproductive rights</category><category domain="">health</category><category domain="">abortion</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Fri, 5 Apr 2013 15:30:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993750</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Katie J.M. Baker]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amanda Bynes Informs Twitter That She Has An Eating Disorder]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993738/amanda-bynes-informs-twitter-that-she-has-an-eating-disorder</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jot506ymbdzjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Sigh. <b>Amanda Bynes'</b> repeated insistence on only using her (technically crappy; see above) Twitter selfies comes from a dark place, it looks like. I know: You're totally shocked.</p>
<p>Shortly after Bynes insisted that she was being <a href="http://jezebel.com/5993565/the-one-hot-guy-on-girls-quits-because-he-cant-stand-lena-dunham">impersonated</a> in paparazzi snaps on the streets of New York, she's informed Twitter that she has an eating disorder and that's why she only wants the press to use her Twitter shots.</p>
<div class="twitter-embed">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" width="486">
<p>I'm suing certain blogs and magazines saying I have a mental illness! They take pictures anytime I've gained weight then write a fake story!</p>
— Amanda Bynes (@AmandaBynes) <a href="https://twitter.com/AmandaBynes/status/319995853186150402" target="_blank">April 5, 2013</a></blockquote>
<!-- Removed script --></div>
<div class="twitter-embed">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" width="486">
<p>I have an eating disorder so I have a hard time staying thin.</p>
— Amanda Bynes (@AmandaBynes) <a href="https://twitter.com/AmandaBynes/status/320003701983031296" target="_blank">April 5, 2013</a></blockquote>
<!-- Removed script --></div>
<div class="twitter-embed">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" width="486">
<p>They write a news article about every tweet I write and I hate the pictures they choose. They repeat what I tweet then add a bad photo.</p>
— Amanda Bynes (@AmandaBynes) <a href="https://twitter.com/AmandaBynes/status/320029144513646592" target="_blank">April 5, 2013</a></blockquote>
<!-- Removed script --></div>
<div class="twitter-embed">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" width="486">
<p>Only use photos from my twitter when writing an article about me.</p>
— Amanda Bynes (@AmandaBynes) <a href="https://twitter.com/AmandaBynes/status/320029195470241794" target="_blank">April 5, 2013</a></blockquote>
<!-- Removed script --></div>
<p>Request granted. :-/ [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/405116/amanda-bynes-new-twitter-bombshell-i-have-an-eating-disorder" target="_blank">E!</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/AmandaBynes" target="_blank">Twitter</a>]</p>
<p>Haaaa, wait, this is fucked. I feel dirty. [<a href="http://dlisted.com/node/49451/images/spl517375_001.jpg" target="_blank">D Listed</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18josraxbhq68png/original.png" class="transform-original"/></p><p>While <b>Kristen Stewart</b> is allegedly embracing a new &quot;fun, lighthearted&quot; attitude for the sake of her relationship with <b>Robert Pattinson</b>, she may revert back to Level 5 mopedom after R-Patz's softcore Dior commercials hit the air, says a source who is almost certainly neither animal nor mineral. (I choose to believe that all sources are bored ghosts.)</p>
<p>K-Stew will be &quot;livid,&quot; says the ghost, when she sees Rob shirtless and simulating a foursome with a bunch of models. Later, it continues, &quot;Rob and [a model] are in a swimming pool making out and he's seen giving her a blow back with a cigarette at one stage, too.&quot; BREAK UP ALREADY. FUCK. [<a href="http://www.lifeandstylemag.com/entertainment/news/robert-pattinson-steamy-dior-ad-will-upset-kristen-stewart" target="_blank">Life and Style Mag</a>, <a href="http://hollywoodlife.com/2013/04/03/kristen-stewart-robert-pattinson-relationship-back-together/" target="_blank">Hollywood Life</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18josufe5phpwjpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></p><p><b>Gwyneth</b> &quot;I'm Just Like You Except For My Holistic Acupuncture Sessions With Diamond-Tipped Needles Made of Elvish Silver&quot; <b>Paltrow</b> is a &quot;bad mutha,&quot; according to Gwyneth Paltrow. Not, like &quot;mother.&quot; Just like, &quot;mutha.&quot; You know. The flavorful way!</p>
<p><b>Chris Martin</b>, on the other hand, is not a bad mutha because he needs to cook to silence.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;He can't have background music on: it has to be 100 per cent of his attention. But if he isn't at home, I turn on the hip-hop - I'm like a bad mutha rapping along to every word as I cook.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://www.standard.co.uk/lifestyle/esmagazine/10-minutes-with-gwyneth-paltrow-8559034.html" target="_blank">The Standard UK</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18gnbszk5s4r5gif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p>I feel like the ratio of how much I write about <b>Elton John</b> is really disproportionate to how much you actually <i>care</i> about Elton John, but anyway, tally-ho! <strong>Blur</strong> included a song called &quot;Elton John's Cock&quot; on their box-set <i>Blur 21</i> and it confused Elton John's actual cock, says Blur's bassist Alex James:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;I bumped into Sir Elton and he said, 'What's all this I hear about you and my c**k?' I didn't know him well enough to tell him the proper answer.&quot;<br/>
The 43-year-old musician claimed the track was given the name because it was ''too sentimental''.<br/>
He added to the Daily Star newspaper: &quot;We wrote this song but realised it was too sentimental. One of us muttered, 'That's Elton John's cock.'&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://www.contactmusic.com/news/blur-song-confused-elton-john_3587915" target="_blank">Contact Music</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<ul><li><b>Paris Jackson</b> has re-acquainted herself with her birth mom <b>Debbie Rowe.</b> [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/05/debbie-rowe-paris-jackson-relationship-birthday-michael-jackson/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li>Meanwhile, Paris's brother <b>Prince</b> is dating a (literal) Kuwaiti princess. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/05/prince-michael-jackson-date-princess-kuwait-bowling-pictures/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><b>RIP</b>, Gucci, the <b>Lohan</b> family maltese. [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/confidential/lindsay-lohan-ruff-landing-back-new-york-article-1.1307167?localLinksEnabled=false" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</li><li><b>Lindsay Lohan's</b> friend, hotel magnate <b>Vikram Chatwal</b>, was arrested for smuggling a smorgasbord of pills, plus heroin, ketamine and weed, in the crotch of his pants. [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/crime/lohan-pal-vikram-chatwal-fla-drug-bust-article-1.1307920#commentpostform" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</li><li>During breaks between filming <b>Mad Men</b> seasons, <b>Christina Hendricks</b> worked as a florist for shits and giggles and the love of flowers. [<a href="http://www.myfashionlife.com/archives/2013/04/05/christina-hendricks-bursts-onto-flares-may-issue-in-stella-mccartney/" target="_blank">My Fashion Life</a>]</li><li><b>Macklemore</b> and the cast of <b>Pitch Perfect</b> will perform at this year's MTV Awards. [<a href="http://www.mtv.com/news/articles/1704967/macklemore-pitch-perfect-mtv-movie-awards.jhtml" target="_blank">MTV</a>]</li><li>Does <b>Conan O'Brien</b> have sort of a six pack?! [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/entertainment/news/chelsea-handler-conan-obrien-get-naked-and-fight-in-the-shower-201344" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><b>Ryan Murphy's</b> launching a new show called <b>Open</b>, to be co-written with a <b>Dexter</b> producer: &quot;a modern, provocative exploration of human sexuality and relationships.&quot; [<a href="http://www.deadline.com/2013/04/ryan-murphy-cable-drama-sexuality-relationships/" target="_blank">Deadline</a>]</li><li><b>Kate Middleton's</b> friends keep texting her baby name suggestions. (She has her own &quot;short list.&quot;) [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/news/kate-middleton-on-baby-names-my-friends-keep-texting-me-suggestions-201344" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li>&quot;I joke that I've been on a diet since 1974, and it's basically true.&quot; —<b>Kim Cattrall</b>. [<a href="http://www.express.co.uk/news/showbiz/389568/I-ve-been-on-a-diet-since-1974-says-Sex-and-the-City-star-Kim-Cattrall" target="_blank">Express</a>]</li><li><b>Roger Ebert's</b> wife <b>Chaz</b> says that he smiled shortly before passing away. [<a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20688468,00.html" target="_blank">People</a>]</li><li>When <b>One Direction</b> hangs out during down-time, they play Boggle and watch <i>One Day.</i> [<a href="http://tvnz.co.nz/entertainment-news/ed-sheeran-claims-one-direction-love-rom-coms-5396243" target="_blank">TVNZ</a>]</li><li>Apparently <b>Mike Tyson</b> cameos in a <b>50 Shades of Grey</b> spoof in <b>Scary Movie 5.</b> [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/tyson_in_scary_spoof_d7HWJmCryuM3gP59PqnX9M" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li><b>Warren Beatty</b> = still a flirt. Wouldn't have it any other way. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/beatty_babes_JzuJP14RmtfsdV5XeDADPP" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li><b>Lil Wayne</b> stepped out for the first time since his hospitalization for seizures. [<a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20688260,00.html" target="_blank">People</a>]</li><li><strong>Bey</strong> and <b>Jay</b> are celebrating their fifth anniversary in Havana with their MOMS. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/beyonce-jay-z-celebrate-5th-wedding-anniversary-in-havana-with-their-mothers-201344" target="_blank">People</a>]</li></ul>]]></description><category domain="">dirt bag</category><category domain="">amanda bynes</category><category domain="">kristen stewart</category><category domain="">robert pattinson</category><category domain="">gwyneth paltrow</category><category domain="">elton john</category><category domain="">paris jackson</category><category domain="">dennie rowe</category><category domain="">prince jackson</category><category domain="">lindsay lohan</category><category domain="">vikram chatwal</category><category domain="">ryan murphy</category><category domain="">roger ebert</category><category domain="">chaz ebert</category><category domain="">christina hendricks</category><category domain="">macklemore</category><category domain="">pitch perfect</category><category domain="">conan obrien</category><category domain="">kate middleton</category><category domain="">kim cattrall</category><category domain="">harry styles</category><category domain="">one direction</category><category domain="">mike tyson</category><category domain="">warren beatty</category><category domain="">lil wayne</category><category domain="">beyonce</category><category domain="">jay-z</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><category domain="">tweet</category><category domain="">gettypic</category><category domain="">roundup</category><pubDate>Fri, 5 Apr 2013 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993738</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Breslaw]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[James Franco Wants to Steal Ryan Gosling's Heart From You (And Touch His Abs)]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993712/james-franco-wants-to-steal-ryan-goslings-heart-from-you-and-touch-his-abs</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jmyw3k1aps1jpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">In an article for HuffPo today, <strong>James Franco</strong> &quot;reviewed&quot; the film <em>The Place Beyond the Pines</em>, but spent most of his word count extolling the rippling abs of <strong>Baby Goose</strong>. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;I loved the whole film and was engaged every moment of the way. But what I want to talk about is the first section, the Gosling section; I want to make love to this section,&quot; he wrote.</p>
<p>The Spring Breakers star began to illustrate the opening scene of the movie and noted that the first image audience members see is &quot;Gos's toned six-pack, framed tight so that his head is cut off in order to focus our attention on the full spread of idiosyncratic tattoos and the impressive opening and closing of a butterfly knife, a skill Gosling mastered.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I HAVE NO PROBLEM WITH THIS. [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/405005/james-franco-loves-ryan-gosling-just-like-the-rest-of-us?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-celebritynews&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_celebritynews" target="_blank">E!</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="147" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jmyxgvxqtirgif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p> <strong>Rick Ross</strong> is really, really sorry...that you interpreted his rape lyric as being about rape and were totally uptight about it, <em>jeez</em>. Today in sorry-not-sorry, Ross tweeted a non-apology that seems mainly motivated by his bottom line. Not, you know, social responsibility or concern for rape victims.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>About a week after calling the outcry over a verse in his tune &quot;U.O.E.N.O.&quot; a &quot;misunderstanding,&quot; the rapper finally apologized for the offense via Twitter today.</p>
<p>&quot;I dont condone rape.Apologies for the #lyric interpreted as rape. #BOSS,&quot; Ross tweeted.</p>
<p>He added, &quot;Apologies to my many business partners,who would never promote violence against women. @ReebokClassics @ultraviolet.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Oh, thank you sooooooo much. Here, have a cookie. [Drops cookie in toilet.] Oops, sorry you <em>interpreted</em> that cookie as being in the toilet. [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/405019/rick-ross-tweets-apology-for-date-rape-lyric-quot-i-don-t-condone-rape-quot?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-topstories&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_topstories" target="_blank">E!</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jmyxgvtayr8gif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p> <strong>John Mayer</strong> was totally jealous of <strong>Katy Perry</strong>'s friendship with <strong>Russell Brand</strong>, said a source who is totally a real person.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The lusty Lothario grew tired of Katy's comparisons between him and the Brit comedian, and it created a tension between them that threatened to boil over at any point.</p>
<p>&quot;John and Katy together were like a volcano just about to go off,&quot; a source reveals.</p>
<p>&quot;Their relationship was incredibly volatile, stemming from the jealousy they both harbored deep inside.</p>
<p>&quot;Sure, Katy was unhappy that John constantly flirted with other girls and played up his heartbreaker image, even when she was standing next to him.</p>
<p>&quot;But, Katy gave it back. She knew that she could push John's buttons by comparing his flaws to what she saw was great in Russell, which he hated!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ugh @ all of those words. [<a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/04/john-mayer-dating-split-katy-perry-russell-brand/" target="_blank">Radar</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<ul><li>Picture what you think <strong>Vanessa Hudgens</strong> would wear to Coachella. Now look at this picture of what Vanessa Hudgens wore to Coachella last year. Now high-five yourself because you are literally <strong>Nostradamus</strong>. [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/405006/coachella-s-best-dressed-ever-see-pics-of-vanessa-hudgens-nicole-richie-and-more?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-topstories&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_topstories" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li>Apparently <strong>Kim Kardashian</strong> was nervous to tell her family about her pregnancy, and you can watch that thrilling drama unfold on the next ep of <em>Kourtney and Kim and Khaleesi Kornkob Kardassian Kraftwerk (in Miami)</em>. [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/shows/kourtney_and_kim_take_miami/news/405012/kim-kardashian-struggles-to-tell-family-she-s-pregnant-on-kktm-season-finale-i-m-scared-to-tell-khloe" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li><strong>Lena Headey</strong> (<strong>Cersei Lannister</strong>) is currently in the middle of an awful divorce, and says she has less than $5 in her bank account. She's currently waiting on her tax return so she can pay her debts. Which she <em>always does</em>. [<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/04/lena-headey-broke_n_3013732.html?utm_hp_ref=entertainment&amp;ir=Entertainment" target="_blank">HuffPo</a>]</li><li><strong>Beyonce</strong> and <strong>Jay-Z</strong> went to Cuba for their anniversary. [<a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20688234,00.html" target="_blank">People</a>]</li><li>OH MY GOD. I had read about this <strong>Justin Bieber</strong> tattoo situation, but I hadn't actually SEEN THE TATTOO. OH MY GOD. [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/404714/justin-bieber-turns-tattoo-artist-as-another-shirtless-pic-of-the-singer-surfaces" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li><strong>Ryan Murphy</strong> is currently shopping a &quot;HOT CABLE DRAMA.&quot; [<a href="http://www.deadline.com/2013/04/ryan-murphy-cable-drama-sexuality-relationships/" target="_blank">Deadline</a>]</li><li><strong>Miley Cyrus</strong> and <strong>Liam Hemsworth</strong> are still engaged. According to the words written on this website. [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/405002/miley-cyrus-and-liam-hemsworth-s-engagement-still-on-couple-making-quot-healthy-strides-in-their-relationship-quot?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-celebritynews&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_celebritynews" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li><strong>Richard Roeper</strong> spoke fondly of former partner <strong>Roger Ebert</strong>:<br/>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;The guy you saw on TV, telling all those great stories, and having such great passion for movies and being so passionate about so many things - first and foremost his family - that was the real Roger Ebert. What you saw is what you got. We had a great run together, and I have a lot of memories.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://www.digitalspy.com/movies/news/a470706/roger-ebert-remembered-by-richard-roeper-we-had-a-great-run-together.html" target="_blank">DigitalSpy</a>]</p>
</li><li><strong>Ryan Lochte</strong> says he wants to &quot;be like <strong>Kim Kardashian</strong>.&quot; Mission already accomplished in so many ways, brah! [<a href="http://www.digitalspy.com/tv/news/a470684/ryan-lochte-talks-reality-show-i-want-to-be-like-kim-kardashian.html" target="_blank">DigitalSpy</a>]</li><li><img height="282" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jmyxmszpcungif/original.gif" class="transform-original"/> MORE MORE MORE MORE MORE [<a href="http://faunasworld.tumblr.com/post/46518032360" target="_blank">HERE ARE MORE</a>]</li></ul>]]></description><category domain="">dirt bag</category><category domain="">james franco</category><category domain="">ryan gosling</category><category domain="">baby goose</category><category domain="">rick ross</category><category domain="">rape</category><category domain="">katy perry</category><category domain="">john mayer</category><category domain="">celebrity</category><category domain="">gossip</category><category domain="">roundup</category><category domain="">tweet</category><category domain="">fb</category><category domain="">gettypic</category><category domain="">top</category><pubDate>Fri, 5 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993712</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Lindy West]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roger Ebert's Twenty Best Reviews]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993693/roger-eberts-twenty-best-reviews</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jmm7jssbgtyjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Roger Ebert was anything but your stereotypical snobbish film critic; he was a man who would review anything. He was also what some have called &quot;a stealth feminist&quot;, though perhaps he was less stealth than he appeared. Though he's been praised for his amazing take-downs, Ebert also had a way of delicately lifting up movies that made you feel light inside to read about them. Here are some of his best reviews of the worst and best reviews of the best. </p>
<h4>1. On Gone With the Wind:</h4>
<p>&quot;[Rhett Butler] tells Scarlett in a key early scene, 'You need kissing badly. That's what's wrong with you. You should be kissed, and often, and by someone who knows how.' For 'kissed,' substitute the word you're thinking of.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/19980621/REVIEWS08/401010323/1023" target="_blank">June 1998</a>]</p>
<h4>2. On Dances With Wolves:</h4>
<p>&quot;[It] has the kind of vision and ambition that is rare in movies today. It is not a formula movie, but a thoughtful, carefully observed story. It is a Western at a time when the Western is said to be dead. It asks for our imagination and sympathy. It takes its time, three hours, to unfold. It is a personal triumph for Kevin Costner, the intelligent young actor of Field of Dreams, who directed the film and shows a command of story and of visual structure that is startling; this movie moves so confidently and looks so good it seems incredible that it's a directorial debut.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/19901109/REVIEWS/11090301/1023" target="_blank">November 1990</a>]</p>
<h4>3. On Valentine's Day:</h4>
<p>&quot;Valentine's Day is being marketed as a Date Movie. I think it's more of a First-Date Movie. If your date likes it, do not date that person again. And if you like it, there may not be a second date.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20100210/REVIEWS/100219994" target="_blank">February 2010</a>]</p>
<h4>4. On Pirates of the Caribbean 4:</h4>
<p>&quot;At least no movie has yet been inspired by 'It's a Small World.'&quot; [<a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;ved=0CDMQFjAA&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Frogerebert.suntimes.com%2Fapps%2Fpbcs.dll%2Farticle%3FAID%3D%2F20110518%2FREVIEWS%2F110519968&amp;ei=WPZdUd2DC_St0AHNmoG4BQ&amp;usg=AFQjCNHVa2fzGP2CPlF_kc9tvGBsTQiY0A&amp;sig2=_DN0HXV8yi5BmuDQIIE-Qw&amp;bvm=bv.44770516,d.dmQ" target="_blank">May 2011</a>]</p>
<h4>5. On Almost Famous:</h4>
<p>&quot;Oh, what a lovely film. I was almost hugging myself while I watched it.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20000915/REVIEWS/9150301/1023" target="_blank">September 2000</a>]</p>
<h4>6. On How to Lose a Guy in 10 Days</h4>
<p>&quot;Matthew McConaughey and Kate Hudson star. I neglected to mention that, maybe because I was trying to place them in this review's version of the Witness Protection Program. If I were taken off the movie beat and assigned to cover the interior design of bowling alleys, I would have some idea of how they must have felt as they made this film.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20030207/REVIEWS/302070302" target="_blank">February 2003</a>]</p>
<h4>7. On Tim and Eric's Billion Dollar Movie</h4>
<p>&quot;As faithful readers will know, I have a few cult followers who enjoy my reviews of bad movies. These have been collected in the books I Hated, Hated, Hated, HATED This Movie; Your Movie Sucks, and A Horrible Experience of Unendurable Length. This movie is so bad, it couldn't even inspire a review worthy of one of those books. I have my standards.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20120229/REVIEWS/120229974/1023" target="_blank">February 2012</a>]</p>
<h4>8. On Elephant:</h4>
<p>&quot;The day after Columbine, I was interviewed for the Tom Brokaw news program. The reporter had been assigned a theory and was seeking sound bites to support it. ‘Wouldn't you say,' she asked, ‘that killings like this are influenced by violent movies?' No, I said, I wouldn't say that. ‘But what about Basketball Diaries?' she asked. ‘Doesn't that have a scene of a boy walking into a school with a machine gun?' The obscure 1995 Leonardo Di Caprio movie did indeed have a brief fantasy scene of that nature, I said, but the movie failed at the box office (it grossed only $2.5 million), and it's unlikely the Columbine killers saw it. The reporter looked disappointed, so I offered her my theory. ‘Events like this,' I said, ‘if they are influenced by anything, are influenced by news programs like your own. When an unbalanced kid walks into a school and starts shooting, it becomes a major media event. Cable news drops ordinary programming and goes around the clock with it. The story is assigned a logo and a theme song; these two kids were packaged as the Trench Coat Mafia. The message is clear to other disturbed kids around the country: If I shoot up my school, I can be famous. The TV will talk about nothing else but me. Experts will try to figure out what I was thinking. The kids and teachers at school will see they shouldn't have messed with me. I'll go out in a blaze of glory.'</p>
<p>In short, I said, events like Columbine are influenced far less by violent movies than by CNN, the NBC Nightly News and all the other news media, who glorify the killers in the guise of ‘explaining' them. I commended the policy at the Sun-Times, where our editor said the paper would no longer feature school killings on Page 1. The reporter thanked me and turned off the camera. Of course the interview was never used. They found plenty of talking heads to condemn violent movies, and everybody was happy.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?aid=/20031107/reviews/311070301/1023" target="_blank">November 2003</a>]</p>
<h4>9. On A Lot Like Love:</h4>
<p>&quot;To call A Lot like Love dead in the water is an insult to water.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=%2F20050422%2FREVIEWS%2F50413001%2F1023&amp;AID1=%2F20050422%2FREVIEWS%2F50413001%2F1023&amp;AID2=" target="_blank">April 2005</a>]</p>
<h4>10. On Minority Report:</h4>
<p>&quot;American movies are in the midst of a transition period. Some directors place their trust in technology. Spielberg, who is a master of technology, trusts only story and character, and then uses everything else as a workman uses his tools. He makes Minority Report with the new technology; other directors seem to be trying to make their movies from it. This film is such a virtuoso high-wire act, daring so much, achieving it with such grace and skill. Minority Report reminds us why we go to the movies in the first place.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20020621/REVIEWS/206210304/1023" target="_blank">June 2002</a>]</p>
<h4>11. On Speed:</h4>
<p>&quot;Films like Speed belong to the genre I call Bruised Forearm Movies, because you're always grabbing the arm of the person sitting next to you. Done wrong, they seem like tired replays of old chase cliches. Done well, they're fun. Done as well as Speed, they generate a kind of manic exhilaration.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/19940610/REVIEWS/406100302/1023" target="_blank">June 1994</a>]</p>
<h4>12. On the original Willy Wonka &amp; the Chocolate Factory:</h4>
<p>&quot;Kids are not stupid. They are among the sharpest, cleverest, most eagle-eyed creatures on God's Earth, and very little escapes their notice. You may not have observed that your neighbor is still using his snow tires in mid-July, but every four-year-old on the block has, and kids pay the same attention to detail when they go to the movies. They don't miss a thing, and they have an instinctive contempt for shoddy and shabby work. I make this observation because nine out of ten children's movies are stupid, witless, and display contempt for their audiences, and that's why kids hate them....All of this is preface to a simple statement: Willy Wonka and the Chocolate Factory is probably the best film of its sort since The Wizard of Oz. It is everything that family movies usually claim to be, but aren't: Delightful, funny, scary, exciting, and, most of all, a genuine work of imagination. Willy Wonka is such a surely and wonderfully spun fantasy that it works on all kinds of minds, and it is fascinating because, like all classic fantasy, it is fascinated with itself.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/19710101/REVIEWS/50720001/1023" target="_blank">January 1971</a>]</p>
<h4>13. On The Human Centipede:</h4>
<p>&quot;I am required to award stars to movies I review. This time, I refuse to do it. The star rating system is unsuited to this film. Is the movie good? Is it bad? Does it matter? It is what it is and occupies a world where the stars don't shine.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20100505/REVIEWS/100509982" target="_blank">May 2010</a>]</p>
<h4>14. On Mad Money:</h4>
<p>&quot;I was noodling around Rotten Tomatoes, trying to determine who played the bank's security chief, and noticed the movie had not yet been reviewed by anybody. Hold on! In the &quot;Forum&quot; section for this movie, &quot;islandhome&quot; wrote at 7:58 a.m. Jan. 8: &quot;review of this movie ... tonight i'll post.&quot; At 11:19 a.m. Jan. 10, &quot;islandhome&quot; was finally back with the promised review. It is written without capital letters, flush left like a poem, and I quote it verbatim, spelling and all:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>hello sorry i slept when i got back<br/>
well it was kinda fun<br/>
it could never happen in the way it was portraid<br/>
but what ever its a movie<br/>
for the girls most will like it<br/>
and the men will not mind it much<br/>
i thought it was going to be kinda like how to beat the high cost of living<br/>
kinda the same them but not as much fun<br/>
ill give it a 4 0ut of 10</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I read this twice, three times. I had been testing out various first sentences for my own review, but somehow the purity and directness of islandhome's review undercut me. It is so final. &quot;for the girls most will like it/and the men will not mind it much.&quot; How can you improve on that? It's worthy of Charles Bukowski. ...The bottom line is some girls will like it, the men not so much, and I give it 1½ stars out of 4.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20080117/REVIEWS/801170304" target="_blank">January 2008</a>]</p>
<h4>15. On the remake of Footloose:</h4>
<p>&quot;There's one thing to be said for a remake of a 1984 movie that uses the original's<br/>
screenplay. This 2011 version is so similar - sometimes song for song and line for line - that I was wickedly tempted to reprint <a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/19840101/REVIEWS/401010339/1023" target="_blank">my 1984 review</a>, word for word. But That Would be Wrong.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20111012/REVIEWS/111019994" target="_blank">October 2011</a>]</p>
<h4>16. On Once</h4>
<p>&quot;Once is the kind of film I've been pestered about ever since I started reviewing again. People couldn't quite describe it, but they said I had to see it. I had to. Well, I did. They were right.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20071224/REVIEWS/237678516" target="_blank">December 2007</a>]</p>
<h4>17. On Sex and the City 2:</h4>
<p>&quot;Note: From my understanding of the guidelines of the MPAA Code and Ratings Administration, Samantha and Mr. Spirt have one scene that far, far surpasses the traditional MPAA limits for pumping and thrusting.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=%2F20100525%2FREVIEWS%2F100529986#" target="_blank">May 2010</a>]</p>
<h4>18. On Raise Your Voice:</h4>
<p>&quot;Terri (Hilary Duff)'s new roommate is Denise (Dana Davis), who plans to work hard for a scholarship, and resents [Duff] as a distraction. Sizing up Terri's wardrobe and her smile, she tells her: 'You're like some kind of retro Brady Buncher.' I hate it when a movie contains its own review.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20041007/REVIEWS/40930002/1001" target="_blank">October 2004</a>]</p>
<h4>19. On I Know What You Did Last Summer:</h4>
<p>&quot;The best shot in this film is the first one. Not a good sign... After the screening was over and the lights went up, I observed a couple of my colleagues in deep and earnest conversation, trying to resolve twists in the plot. They were applying more thought to the movie than the makers did. A critic's mind is a terrible thing to waste.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/19971017/REVIEWS/710170304/1023" target="_blank">October 1997</a>]</p>
<h4>20. On Freddy Got Fingered:</h4>
<p>&quot;This movie doesn't scrape the bottom of the barrel. This movie isn't the bottom of the barrel. This movie isn't below the bottom of the barrel. This movie doesn't deserve to be mentioned in the same sentence with barrels....The film is a vomitorium consisting of 93 minutes of Tom Green doing things that a geek in a carnival sideshow would turn down.&quot; [<a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20010420/REVIEWS/104200304/1023" target="_blank">April 2001</a>]</p>
<p><em>And as Ebert said in his last blog post, &quot;So on this day of reflection I say again, thank you for going on this journey with me. I'll see you at the movies.&quot;</em></p>
<p>Related: <a href="http://www.feministe.us/blog/archives/2011/01/21/why-roger-ebert-is-the-best/" target="_blank">Why Roger Ebert is the best</a> [Feministe]</p>]]></description><category domain="">roger ebert</category><category domain="">movies</category><category domain="">movie reviews</category><category domain="">reviews</category><category domain="">best reviews</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Thu, 4 Apr 2013 22:20:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993693</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dodai Stewart]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[March Madness Elite Eight Naturally Includes an Eight Ball]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993677/march-madness-elite-eight-naturally-includes-an-eight-ball</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jmabnyd1yxjjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Welcome the the Elite Eight! Yesterday, voters decided to say no to D.A.R.E and yes to MTV (Daren the Lion would be so disappointed in you) and poor Monica Lewinsky still can't catch a break, having lost to the Seattle Sound by a whopping 3,670 votes. Oh, well. She can always go back to her career as a purse designer.</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jmablzfy8yppng/ku-xlarge.png" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<associate></associate>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" class="youtube" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/udNHsk57f24?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0" id="youtube-udNHsk57f24"></iframe></span></p><p>  For today's 80s vote, the White Pony races the rainbow pegasus as cocaine goes up against school supply designer (and surprise heavy-hitter) Lisa Frank. Will Lady Snow finally be the one to blow Frank right out of the running? It wouldn't be the first time that she brought down someone powerful.</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" class="youtube" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/FWOsbGP5Ox4?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0" id="youtube-FWOsbGP5Ox4"></iframe></span></p><p>  In the 90s conference, East Coast vs West Coast rap sets its crosshairs on the Nintendo Gameboy. Sure, they may seem like polar opposites, but I'm willing to bet that Gameboys and rap cassettes were the two most confiscated items in elementary school classrooms throughout the early 90s. You can get your items back after you vote.</p>
<script src="http://static.polldaddy.com/p/7014884.js"></script><br/>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/7014884/" target="_blank">80s: Cocaine (1) vs. Lisa Frank (13)</a></noscript>
<script src="http://static.polldaddy.com/p/7014893.js"></script><br/>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/7014893/" target="_blank">90s: East Coast vs. West Coast Rap (1) vs. Gameboy (12)</a></noscript>]]></description><category domain="">80s vs 90s</category><category domain="">march madness</category><category domain="">top</category><pubDate>Thu, 4 Apr 2013 21:30:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993677</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Madeleine Davies]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Georgia Teens Fight for Racially Integrated Prom Because It's 2013, for Chrissakes]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993590/georgia-teens-fight-for-racially-integrated-prom-because-its-2013-for-chrissakes</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jlnqhcsbzgmjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Black and white students at Wilcox County High School in south Georgia aren't allowed to go to the same prom. Instead, students and parents sponsor segregated proms — yep, in 2013 — and kids that break the skin-dress code are barred entry from the caucasian rager. A mixed-race group of friends who hang out all of the time but can't wear corsages and dance to Top 40 together are trying to encourage their peers to participate in a radical social experiment called NOT BEING RACIST. </p>
<p>&quot;We're embarrassed, it's embarrassing, yeah it's kind of embarrassing,&quot; Stephanie Sinnot, Mareshia Rucker, Quanesha Wallace, and Keela Bloodworth told <a href="http://www.wsfa.com/story/21866345/georgia-high-school-students-organize-first-integrated-prom" target="_blank">WSFA</a>. &quot;We are all friends, that's just kind of not right that we can't go to prom together.&quot;</p>
<p>Uh, they're embarrassed? Wilcox County High School officials are the ones who should be beyond embarrassed, since, last we checked, Brown v. Board of Education declared segregation unconstitutional in 1954. But since the proms aren't financed by or hosted at the school (they're sponsored by the students and parents), the administration says there's nothing it can do. Officials have offered a resolution to permit an integrated prom — big of them, right? — but won't stop segregated proms or even take a stance on the issue.</p>
<p>A biracial student was actually turned away by police at the white prom last year. And when the school decided to elect only one pair for homecoming queen and king for the first time this school year — mmhmm, homecoming is segregated, too — and one of the integrated prom-organizing students won, she <em>still</em> wasn't allowed to attend the white homecoming. The king and queen took separate pictures for the school yearbook.</p>
<p>&quot;When people around here are set in their ways, they are not too adamant to change,&quot; Rucker said. That's why they're taking charge. &quot;If we don't change it, nobody else will,&quot; Bloodworth said. They're organizing a prom for all on April 27th — If you want to learn more, check out their <a href="https://www.facebook.com/IntegratedProm2013" target="_blank">Facebook</a> — but not everyone is ready for intermingling. &quot;I actually put up posters for the integrated prom and we've had people ripping them down at the school,&quot; Bloodworth said.</p>
<p>My instinctive early morning pre-coffee response to their plight was to 1) yell &quot;FUCKING CHRIST&quot; at my computer and 2) get back into bed. But segregated proms are unfortunately <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/05/24/magazine/24prom-t.html?pagewanted=all" target="_blank">nothing new</a>, and we can do better than swearing at inanimate objects and hiding under the covers in the face of mind-boggling injustice. Internet: donate to the cause by <a href="https://www.facebook.com/IntegratedProm2013/app_208195102528120" target="_blank">clicking right here</a>.</p>
<p><em>Do they throw segregated proms in your area/where you grew up? Email me: katie@jezebel.com.</em></p>
<p>[<a href="http://www.wsfa.com/story/21866345/georgia-high-school-students-organize-first-integrated-prom" target="_blank">WSFA</a>]</p>]]></description><category domain="">racism</category><category domain="">prom</category><category domain="">race relations</category><category domain="">race</category><category domain="">georgia</category><category domain="">wilox country high school</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Thu, 4 Apr 2013 15:55:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993590</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Katie J.M. Baker]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[The One Hot Guy on Girls Quits Because He Can't Stand Lena Dunham]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993565/the-one-hot-guy-on-girls-quits-because-he-cant-stand-lena-dunham</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jl6fjbfwq2djpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Say goodbye to sadsacky-turned-sexier Zuckerbergian Charlie, Marnie's (<b>Allison Williams'</b>) chewtoy on <i>Girls</i> (have you guys even heard of this show? Because like NOBODY talks about it). Actor <b>Christopher Abbott</b> and the <a href="http://25.media.tumblr.com/1bcd366473b6a5219229f58369e17936/tumblr_mkgdvdgrCf1qlgjjro1_500.png" target="_blank">Prince mustache he sports in his downtime</a> have &quot;abruptly&quot; departed from the HBO show shortly after <b>Lena Dunham</b> and co. began working on Season 3.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;Chris is at odds with Lena,&quot; a source said. &quot;He didn't like the direction things are going in, which seems a bit odd since the show put him on the map.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What was the offending storyline for Abbott? Does Charlie live-tweet his own late-term circumcision? Let Marnie attempt to shoot an apple off his head with a bow and arrow? Commit hara-kiri for not inventing Snapchat?  Says his rep:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;[Chris] is grateful for the experience of collaborating with Lena, Judd [Apatow], and the entire ‘Girls' cast and crew, but right now he's working on numerous other projects and has decided not to return to the show.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It's the biggest in some shakeups for the show's next stretch of episodes, among them the shift of the <a href="http://jezebel.com/5989426/the-girls-writers-room-is-now-over-50-male">writers room to over 50% male.</a> [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/cutest_boy_leaving_girls_0IrrLAkGdxV4Nqu1N1JxMI" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jl6g50xmml3gif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p> A tattoo artist named <b>Keith McCurdy a.k.a. Bang Bang</b> inexplicably asked his friend non-tattoo artist <b>Justin Bieber</b> to ink him up last summer. It went how you'd expect.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Bieber, then 18, inked McCurdy's leg with a picture of a muscle-bound mouse, the &quot;Believe&quot; singer's cartoon alter-ego, and the word &quot;Swaggy.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Bieber may be fined up to $2,000 for operating as an unlicensed tattoo artist. Refer above for McCurdy's punishment. [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/justin-bieber-illegally-tattooed-ink-artist-article-1.1307127" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jl5l49ac512jpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></p><p> The day before former Nickelodion teen star, current Twitter-abusing cautionary tale <b>Amanda Bynes</b> turned 27, she was spotted on the streets of New York looking bedraggled with purple hair and those Adidas sandals people wear in public showers. OR WAS SHE.</p>
<p>In a since-deleted Tweet, she informed us that an ersatz Bynes was, in fact, on the loose. &quot;My hair is blonde, I've never been a redhead! Somebody keeps posing as me! Check my photos on Twitter for up to date pictures!&quot;<br/>
[<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/amanda-bynes-claims-she-has-a-redheaded-impostor-picture-201334" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" class="youtube" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XPpmWGaluQU?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0" id="youtube-XPpmWGaluQU"></iframe></span></p>
<p>Holy crap, how long has <b>Topanga</b> been making YouTube dating advice videos? In this episode, <b>Danielle Fishel</b> sits in what looks like a blinged out fake cardboard living room of the <b>Bachelor/ette</b> franchise and doles out tongue-in-cheek advice to a girl who wants to ask her boyfriend to prom. Topanga informs us that she asked <i>her</i> boyfriend <b>Lance Bass</b> to prom, and then they got married and lived happily ever after, as we all know. [<a href="http://www.popsugar.com/Danielle-Fishel-Lance-Bass-Prom-Photo-Video-29022742" target="_blank">Pop Sugar</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jl5lg3i9odfjpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></p><p><b>Martha Stewart</b> went on <b>The Today Show</b> and talked about that time she and <b>Snoop Lion Dogg Cat Lemur Owl Field Mouse</b> made brownies and talked about pot brownies. +1,000 for Natalie Morales awkwardly calling him &quot;the Snoop.&quot;</p>
<blockquote>
<p><b>Natalie Morales:</b> We know how you and the Snoop are tight.<br/>
<b>Willie Geist:</b> Do you hang out a lot?<br/>
<b>Martha Stewart:</b> Oh yeah, I hang out with Snoop, [like] he has time for me. We, uh, like to bake brownies together.<br/>
<b>Willie Geist:</b> I bet you do.<br/>
<b>Natalie Morales:</b> What's in those brownies?<br/>
<b>Martha Stewart:</b> They're green, they're green actually.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://allhiphop.com/2013/04/02/martha-stewart-elaborates-on-baking-relationship-with-snoop/" target="_blank">All Hip Hop</a>]</p>
<p>Please click this. [<a href="http://i.imgur.com/US2cNl1.jpg" target="_blank">I have no idea</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<ul><li>Over at La Guardia High School, <b>Madonna's</b> kid <b>Lourdes Leon</b> is dating <b>Timothée Chalamet</b> (The vice president's son on <b>Homeland</b>.) [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/lourdes_dates_finn_actor_u998YbuToaISnozaWBbeRL" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li>A fan interrupted <b>Jonah Hill</b> on a date to give him the following bizarre news: &quot;I buried my father today, and I just wanted to say you're gonna be one of the greats.&quot; Go ahead back to eating your tapas now. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/hill_on_hell_date_8i4AFmjpsmJsedj43RdGgN" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li>It's clearly Fans Oversharing O'Clock.
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;One woman rushed up to <b>[Cyndi Lauper]</b> and was pushed back by a photographer,&quot; said a spy, &quot;but the lady yelled out, ‘I am not going anywhere! I lost my virginity to this woman's music!'&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I am guessing &quot;True Colors&quot; a la <i>Save The Last Dance.</i> [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/lauper_colony_ybBZp1B2oW9TlCCg0ajMMO" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</p>
</li><li><b>One Directioner Niall Horan</b> got his braces off. Wear your retainer, Niall, or the whole thing was a waste. [<a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/showbiz/bizarre/4872666/Niall-Horan-shows-his-mettle-as-he-flashes-gnashers.html?OTC-RSS&amp;ATTR=Bizarre" target="_blank">The Sun</a>]</li><li><b>Jada Pinkett Smith</b> denies rumors that she and <b>Will Smith</b> have an open relationship, but &quot;Will's his own man.&quot; [<a href="http://www.gossipcop.com/jada-pinkett-will-smith-open-marriage-rumor-huffpost-live-video-huffington-post-interview-relationship/" target="_blank">Gossip Cop</a>]</li><li>&quot;You can't have it all,&quot; says <b>Isla Fisher.</b> [<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2303472/Isla-Fisher-juggling-family-career-new-FASHION.html" target="_blank">Daily Mail</a>]</li><li>And yet! [<a href="http://radaronline.com/photos/hot-pics-10/photo/511822/" target="_blank">Radar Online</a>]</li><li><b>Prince William</b> and <b>Kate Middleton</b> will be Skyping with two homeless people during their trip to the Netherlands. [<a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/prince-william-web-chat-royal-1809801" target="_blank">Mirror UK</a>]</li><li><b>Diana Ross</b> and <b>Lisa Marie Presley</b> will testify in the <b>Michael Jackson</b> wrongful death suit. [<a href="http://music.msn.com/music/article.aspx?news=800145&amp;affid=100055" target="_blank">MSN</a>]</li><li><b>Daddy Yankee's</b> publicist says Daddy Yankee, creator of the bassline-heavy heterosexual touchstone &quot;Gasolina,&quot; is not gay. [<a href="http://www.latimes.com/entertainment/music/posts/la-et-ms-daddy-yankee-reggaeton-king-gay-rumors-20130403,0,6857418.story" target="_blank">L.A. Times</a>]</li><li><b>Ed Sheeran</b> is &quot;Switzerland&quot; when it comes to <b>Taylor Swift</b> and <b>Harry Styles</b> [<a href="http://hollywoodlife.com/2013/04/04/ed-sheeran-taylor-swift-harry-styles-drama-switzerland/" target="_blank">Hollywood Life</a>]</li><li>Meet newly-pregnant <b>Heather Morris's</b> boyfriend <b>Taylor Hubbell.</b> [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/news/heather-morris-pregnant-meet-her-boyfriend-taylor-hubbell-201334" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><strong>Richie Sambora</strong> has bowed out of <b>Bon Jovi's</b> next tour due to &quot;personal issues.&quot; [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/richie-sambora-skipping-bon-jovi-tour-dates-due-to-personal-issues-201334" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li>That time <b>Heidi Klum</b> pulled her 7-year-old son <b>Henry</b> from a strong riptide? There are pictures now. (The one of the nanny's the best though.) [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/heidi-klum-rescues-son-henry-from-drowning-see-the-dramatic-pictures-201334" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><b>Nick Jonas</b> totes isn't hooking up with <b>Miley Cyrus</b>, says <b>Nick Jonas</b>. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/nick-jonas-addresses-miley-cyrus-rumors-201334" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><strong>Jennie Garth</strong> wrote a column on a coupon website about how her family's frugal lifestyle. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/news/jennie-garth-writes-about-her-frugal-life-as-a-single-mom-in-debut-column-for-coupon-website-201334" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><b>Jenny McCarthy</b> masturbates sometimes. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/jenny_mccarthy_solo_sex_confession_QDBXeK134ake9LptIuCKyH" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li><b>Avril Lavigne</b> is naked with a teddy bear on the cover of her upcoming album. [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/music-arts/avril-lavigne-appears-nude-upcoming-single-cover-article-1.1306904" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</li><li><strong>Bradley Cooper's</strong> perm! [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/tv-movies/bradley-cooper-takes-perm-public-article-1.1306441" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</li></ul>]]></description><category domain="">dirt bag</category><category domain="">christopher abbott</category><category domain="">lena dunham</category><category domain="">girls</category><category domain="">keith mccurdy</category><category domain="">justin bieber</category><category domain="">amanda bynes</category><category domain="">danielle fishel</category><category domain="">lance bass</category><category domain="">snoop lion</category><category domain="">snoop dogg</category><category domain="">martha stewart</category><category domain="">willie geist</category><category domain="">natalie morales</category><category domain="">madonna</category><category domain="">lourdes leon</category><category domain="">timothee chalamet</category><category domain="">homeland</category><category domain="">jonah hill</category><category domain="">niall horan</category><category domain="">jada pinkett smith</category><category domain="">isla fisher</category><category domain="">will smith</category><category domain="">prince william</category><category domain="">kate middleton</category><category domain="">diana ross</category><category domain="">lisa marie presley</category><category domain="">daddy yankee</category><category domain="">ed sheeran</category><category domain="">taylor swift</category><category domain="">harry styles</category><category domain="">richie sambora</category><category domain="">taylor hubbell</category><category domain="">heather morris</category><category domain="">heidi klum</category><category domain="">nick jonas</category><category domain="">miley cyrus</category><category domain="">jenny mccarthy</category><category domain="">avril lavigne</category><category domain="">bradley cooper</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><category domain="">tweet</category><category domain="">gettypic</category><pubDate>Thu, 4 Apr 2013 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993565</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Breslaw]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jeremy Irons Is Being Completely Gross Again, Compares Gay Marriage to Incest]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993554/jeremy-irons-is-being-completely-gross-again-compares-gay-marriage-to-incest</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jjf5xz9o8pujpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Ew, <strong>Jeremy Irons</strong>. Ew. Remember <a href="http://jezebel.com/5984130/lena-dunham-lands-cover-of-rolling-stone-discusses-her-childhood-fear-of-sex">the other month</a> when he waxed all creepy about how ladies should really just chill out and let men rub us on our bottoms whenever they feel like it? Well, now Monsieur Humbert is grappling with another social conundrum: <em>Just what is up with gay guys</em>!? Hold on to your butts (especially you, women, where Jeremy Irons can see)—it's about to get weird.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;Could a father not marry his son?&quot; Irons asked HuffPost Live host Josh Zepps. Irons argued that &quot;it's not incest between men&quot; because &quot;incest is there to protect us from inbreeding, but men don't breed,&quot; and wondered whether same-sex marriage might allow fathers to pass on their estates to their sons without being taxed.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to me that now they're fighting for the name,&quot; Irons said of advocates for same-sex marriage as opposed to civil unions. &quot;I worry that it means somehow we debase, or we change, what marriage is. I just worry about that.&quot;</p>
<p>Irons reiterated that he &quot;[doesn't] have a strong feeling either way&quot; on same-sex marriage, and said that he &quot;[wishes] everybody who's living with one other person the best of luck in the world, because it's fantastic.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Living with another animal, whether it be a husband or a dog, is great,&quot; he said. &quot;It's lovely to have someone to love. I don't think sex matters at all. What it's called doesn't matter at all.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>OKEY DOKEY, YOU WEIRD DOODOOHEAD. Maybe if you don't have &quot;a strong feeling either way,&quot; you should just shut the fuck up. [<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/03/jeremy-irons-on-gay-marri_n_3009495.html" target="_blank">HuffPo</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" class="youtube" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/syp3KPrYNV8?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0" id="youtube-syp3KPrYNV8"></iframe></span></p><p>  Uh, I guess <em>Couples Therapy</em> caught fire?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The cast of the VH1 reality show &quot;Couples Therapy&quot; was evacuated from their house this afternoon after a fire broke out inside one of the rooms ... TMZ has learned.</p>
<p>Law enforcement sources tell us, a 911 call was placed around 4:45pm reporting the blaze.</p>
<p>We're told the fire department rushed to the scene, but by the time they arrived ... the crew had already extinguished the flames. Once firefighters determined the situation was all clear, they took off. No one was injured.</p>
<p>Sources connected with the show tell us the fire was caused by a production light which had burned a couch.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Glad everyone's okay. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/03/couples-therapy-fire-emergency-cast-evacuated/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="161" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jjhxqykjjsdgif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p> <strong>Madonna</strong>'s dispute with Malawi's education minister continues.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>After changing her original plan to build a multimillion-dollar all-girls school in Malawi to instead creating 10 primary school and continuing to face obstacles, it turns out Madge didn't build any schools at all-just classrooms.</p>
<p>&quot;She has built classrooms at existing schools...really it's a difference in terminology,&quot; Education Minister, Eunice Kazembe, told the BBC.</p>
<p>&quot;They have said they have built 10 schools in Malawi and on our side, what we know is that she [Madonna] has built classrooms. These are not schools from our side and really that's the essence of the difference between her side and the Malawi government,&quot; Kazembe added.</p>
<p>...&quot;She promised an academy and we agreed on standards but she just changed her mind on the project without consulting us,&quot; Kazembe said. &quot;We'd like them to work with us so that they can be absorbed into the strategy of Malawi's education and that goes not just for Madonna-any group that comes to Malawi to assist us in education.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/404543/madonna-school-controversy-malawi-education-minister-says-she-s-building-classrooms-not-schools?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-celebritynews&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_celebritynews" target="_blank">E!</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jjhvc4zmr2xjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p><strong>Daddy Yankee</strong>'s manager responded to allegations that the artist had come out as gay.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;Once again social networks are the protagonists in spreading false news, which have been replicated by other media involving a public figure. The story that is circulating about Daddy Yankee's homosexuality declaration is a false story written by an Internet portal as many others, dedicated to fabricate and disseminate news through social networks,&quot; said Helga García, president of Perfect Partners Public Relations.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Okey dokey then? [<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/03/daddy-yankee-gay_n_3010220.html?utm_hp_ref=entertainment&amp;ir=Entertainment" target="_blank">HuffPo</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<ul><li><strong>Clark Gable</strong>'s son was arrested for a DUI. [<a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20688006,00.html" target="_blank">People</a>]</li><li>The writers of <em>Fashion Police</em> say that E! owes them more than $1 million in back pay. Jokes about <strong>Adele</strong>'s disgusting giant butt don't grow on trees, you know! [<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/03/fashion-police-writers-unpaid-wages_n_3009477.html?utm_hp_ref=tv&amp;ir=TV" target="_blank">HuffPo</a>]</li><li><strong>Joe Mangianello</strong> reveals a &quot;childhood secret,&quot; which is that he used to steal comic books. AND READ THEM. NERD. [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/404572/true-blood-s-joe-manganiello-reveals-childhood-secret?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-topstories&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_topstories" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li><strong>Frankie Essex</strong> has made her boobs available for your eyeballs. [<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2303655/Frankie-Essex-lets-hang-shows-ample-chest-garish-gown-Olympus-Has-Fallen-premiere.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490" target="_blank">DailyMail</a>]</li><li>Here's a portrait of <strong>Lindsay Lohan</strong> made out of garbage! [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/404570/lindsay-lohan-trashed-see-portrait-of-actress-made-entirely-out-of-garbage?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-celebritynews&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_celebritynews" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li>Here's <strong>Kelly Osbourne</strong> wearing floral pants! [<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2303590/Kelly-Osbourne-Jaime-Winstone-matching-floral-outfits-meet-America.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490" target="_blank">DailyMail</a>]</li><li>Apparently everyone wants <strong>Julia Roberts</strong>'s dress from <em>Pretty Woman</em> all of a sudden. Like, on purpose. To wear as actual clothes. [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/404513/julia-roberts-pretty-woman-dress-is-back-mdash-and-in-high-demand?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-celebritynews&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_celebritynews" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li>Some dumb fucking kid &quot;swatted&quot; <strong>P. Diddy</strong>'s house. At least I hope it was a dumb fucking kid. What a dumb fucking prank. [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/404518/sean-quot-diddy-quot-combs-toluca-lake-home-swatted-steve-carell-in-the-clear?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-celebritynews&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_celebritynews" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li><strong>Richie Sambora</strong> has left the Bon Jovi tour citing &quot;personal issues.&quot; [<a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/04/04/entertainment-us-richiesambora-idUSBRE93212Z20130404?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=entertainmentNews" target="_blank">Reuters</a>]</li><li><strong>Josh Duhamel</strong> says that <strong>Fergie</strong>'s pregnancy is &quot;a beautiful thing.&quot; [<a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/404563/josh-duhamel-talks-wife-fergie-s-pregnancy-quot-it-s-a-beautiful-thing-quot?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-celebritynews&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_celebritynews" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li>Best thing I saw today. [<a href="http://pixel.nymag.com/imgs/daily/intelligencer/2013/04/03/03-biden-daydream-5-armageddeon.o.jpg/a_560x375.jpg" target="_blank">Don'tWannaMissAThing</a>]</li></ul>]]></description><category domain="">dirt bag</category><category domain="">jeremy irons</category><category domain="">madonna</category><category domain="">malawi</category><category domain="">daddy yankee</category><category domain="">couples therapy</category><category domain="">celebrity</category><category domain="">gossip</category><category domain="">roundup</category><category domain="">tweet</category><category domain="">fb</category><category domain="">gettypic</category><category domain="">top</category><pubDate>Thu, 4 Apr 2013 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993554</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Lindy West]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tyler Perry Isn't Just an Artless Hack, He's a Scary Ideologue]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993523/tyler-perry-isnt-just-an-artless-hack-hes-a-scary-ideologue</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jixdclw0wodjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">There are a lot of things to laugh at in Tyler Perry's <em>Temptation</em>: Kim Kardashian's attempts to move and talk at the same time, Vanessa Williams's fake French accent for no reason (hoh-hoh-hohhh!), the alien dialogue, the blunt-force moralizing, the sheer ineptitude of Perry's filmmaking. (Worth noting: None of Perry's actual scripted &quot;jokes&quot; made the list.) But, that said, it is not a funny movie—it's a frightening one. <em>Temptation</em> is a movie about punishing women. Specifically, Perry is obsessed with punishing women who stray from the good woman/bad woman binary dictated by traditional Christian gender roles. That is the film's <em>entire purpose</em>. I watched it 24 hours ago and my skin is still crawling. And I'm starting to believe that Tyler Perry isn't just artless—he's reprehensible. </p>
<p><em>Temptation</em> is framed as a story told by a marriage counselor to her client. The client, some white lady, comes in and is like, &quot;I'm thinking about having an affair! YOLO!&quot; And the marriage counselor is like, &quot;Well, let me tell you a little story, lady. About my, um, '<em>sister</em>.'&quot; (The first of a million spoilers: IT'S REALLY ABOUT HER. SHE IS HER OWN SISTER.)</p>
<p>The &quot;sister&quot; in question is Judith—a nice, pretty, church-going &quot;good woman&quot; who wears ugly high-collared blouses, cooks dinner for her man every night, and only has married-sex in bed with the lamp off. Judith's husband, Brice, is a &quot;good man.&quot; He works hard at a pharmacy all day, wears glasses, and is on great terms with Judith's mother. They are &quot;happy.&quot; Except that they're totally not (spoiler #2: it's Judith's fault).</p>
<p>The first hint of Judith's discontent comes when she and Brice are heading home from a romantic dinner. A group of ne'er-do-well youths on the street cat-call Judith as they pass. Judith flips the fuck out and has to be physically restrained by Brice, who tells her to calm down, ignore it, let it go. They get in the car and go home. Judith refuses to speak to Brice for the rest of the night, because he didn't defend <del>his property</del> her honor by fighting the cat-callers to the death. He didn't do his manful duty. &quot;But honey, they could have had guns!&quot; Brice says. THEN HE APOLOGIZES TO JUDITH FOR NOT FIGHTING THE YOUTHS. I didn't see the rest of the scene because my eyes fell out and rolled away.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, at the Millionaire Matchmaking agency where she works, Judith meets Harley—the &quot;third largest social media inventor since Zuckerberg!&quot; (so, uh, LinkedIn? Christian Mingle?). Harley immediately fixates on Judith and begins scheming about how to get his penis inside her posthaste. Harley is rich, sexually aggressive (his dialogue highlights the inhuman weirdness with which Perry writes about sex: &quot;Sex should be random, like animals!&quot;), he believes in Judith's career (Brice, by contrast, told her that she should stay at the matchmaking agency for 15 years before starting her own practice—!?!?), and he goes jogging with no shirt so ladies will look at his muscles. &quot;I bet you only have sex in a bed with the lamp off,&quot; he tells Judith. (Nailed it!!!) In a clunky counterexample to the cat-calling incident, Harley attempts to murder a doofy bicyclist who accidentally bumped Judith's knee with his bicycle. He is truly the best man ever.</p>
<p>Oh, also Harley is <em>literally the devil</em>. Linemouth.</p>
<p>You can tell he's literally the devil because he says things like, &quot;Let me play devil's advocate,&quot; he drives a sinful red sports car, everything in his apartment is constantly on fire, and every time Judith's churchy mom sees him she starts screaming, &quot;HE'S THE DEVIL. THAT MAN IS LITERALLY THE DEVIL.&quot; He is literally the devil.</p>
<p>And because he's the devil, he manages to &quot;seduce&quot; Judith, lure her away from her good Christian life with Brice, nose-feed her mountains of cocaine, beat the shit out of her, and turn her into a cackling demon who hates Jesus and never, ever cooks dinner. Back at the pharmacy, Brice discovers that Harley has been running around giving HIV to all kinds of fallen women all over town. This discovery finally awakens his dutiful aggro side, so he runs to Harley's apartment to rescue Judith from Satan-AIDS, and then throws Harley through a window. Then Brice gets a new, better, non-HIV-having wife and Judith puts her frumpy clothes back on and goes to church, alone forevermore.</p>
<p>Cut back to this dialogue between the therapist and the white lady:</p>
<p>&quot;How does the story end?&quot;<br/>
&quot;Well, it's still being written.&quot;<br/>
&quot;Did [Judith] get HIV too?&quot;<br/>
&quot;Yes.&quot;<br/>
&quot;Did Brice?&quot;<br/>
&quot;No.&quot;<br/>
&quot;Thank you so much for sharing this story with me  I'm going to end this almost-affair and stay with my husband.&quot;</p>
<p>THE END. OF THE MOVIE.</p>
<p>Okay. Now. Okay. There are three main areas in which Tyler Perry is fucking over the entire human race in <em>Temptation</em>.</p>
<p><strong>1. Men Do Marriage Like This/Women Do Marriage Like This!</strong></p>
<p><em>Temptation</em> is a feature-length Chick tract, only with <em>slightly less</em> artistry and nuance. Watching this film as an atheist, it makes absolutely no sense. If you don't believe in the devil, which I don't, <em>Temptation</em> is simply the story of a 25-year-old woman who got married too young, is no longer compatible with her partner, is frustrated with her stalled career, and is preyed upon by a charismatic sociopath with a drug problem. Then, because of Perry's fixation on Christian moralizing, the film portrays Judith's contraction of HIV (deliberately given to her by an abusive partner) as a fitting punishment for her &quot;sins.&quot; From a godless perspective, this is <em>bonkers</em>.</p>
<p>Outside the confines of traditional gender roles, Judith is just a woman trying to find her place in the world. She is confused, she is sad, she is frustrated. &quot;I feel so dead with you Brice,&quot; she says. In the real world, women are not obligated to cook dinner for their husbands, or eschew casual sex, or put their careers on hold for their partners, or submit sexually to dominant men, or ignore cat-callers, or stand up to cat-callers, or swath their knees in modest hemlines, or be nice to their moms. Women are people. But in Perry's universe, women are women, and a &quot;good woman&quot; is a very specific and important thing to be.</p>
<p>People can have whatever kind of relationships they want—if a traditional Christian marriage works for you, go nuts—but Perry's insistence on punishing women who don't follow his doctrine of subservience is harmful and oppressive. Compliance with gender roles doesn't make anyone a good person. People are good people because they're good people. Church doesn't make you good. Loving your mom doesn't make you good. Even fidelity doesn't make you good. Those are all just excuses, loopholes, cop-outs that signify &quot;goodness&quot; without having to actually do the legwork.</p>
<p>When Judith stops being &quot;good,&quot; she is punished. The moral of the movie is explicit: Stay in your unhappy marriage forever because the alternative is Satan-AIDS.</p>
<p>Which brings me to my second point.</p>
<p><strong>2. People with HIV Are Not Your Toys.</strong></p>
<p>Three people in <em>Temptation</em> have HIV. One of them is literally the devil (see above), and the other two are black women who slept with the devil. That Perry would have the <em>gall</em> to use HIV as a punitive measure against black women who don't fit his idea of &quot;goodness&quot;—black women, by the way, account for <a href="http://womenshealth.gov/minority-health/african-americans/hiv-aids.cfm" target="_blank">2/3 of new HIV infections among women</a>—betrays a frightening selfishness and lack of empathy. It echoes, very plainly, the old Fundamentalist rhetoric that AIDS is a punishment from god for the sins of the gays. Perry expands that rhetoric, sure—now dirty, filthy women can sin just like gays do!—but the message is the same. Casual sex is a sin and sinners deserve HIV. That. Is. Crazy.</p>
<p>The other woman infected by Harley is named Melinda (played by <em>the Brandy</em>), a saintly gal who works at the pharmacy with Brice. &quot;I'm accepting my part in it,&quot; she says. She chose to stay with Harley even though he was abusive and she knew he was sleeping around. Besides, the film takes care to point out, she totally took Harley's private jet for granted—so <em>of course</em> he cheated! <em>Temptation</em> isn't a movie about Harley—who, after all, can't help his sin seeing as he is a demon from hell. It's a movie about Harley's victims. Only they're not portrayed as victims—they're <em>sinners</em>. They're to blame. And in the end, Melinda and Judith wind up alone, repentant and meek, while Brice finds himself a new, untainted wife.</p>
<p>Apparently this needs to be said: People with HIV are people. People with HIV are not a rhetorical device that Tyler Perry gets to exploit to keep women in line. People with HIV have healthy relationships with other people, regardless of HIV status. Tyler Perry is a bad person.</p>
<p><strong>3. Harley Rapes Judith.</strong></p>
<p>Here are all of things that Judith says immediately before Harley has sex with her in his private plane: &quot;No.&quot; &quot;Stop it.&quot; &quot;I don't want to.&quot; &quot;Get off of me.&quot; Judith does not want to have sex with Harley. (There's another layer of nuance here—one reason Judith doesn't want to have sex with Harley is that she's deeply invested in Perry's beloved gender roles. But the reason for her &quot;no&quot; is irrelevant. Her spiritual weakness betrays her, Harley can tell she wants it, and she's punished for that weakness.)</p>
<p>He does not stop. He just tries harder. He knows what she <em>really</em> wants, no matter what her mouth and body are saying. She never says yes. He says, smugly, &quot;Now you can say you resisted.&quot; He has sex with her anyway. This is a rape scene. But, in Perry's universe, <em>Harley is right</em>. She <em>did</em> secretly want it. And that's the real problem.</p>
<p>Afterwards, for a minute, Judith is disgusted with Harley and with herself. She pushes him away. She tells him never to contact her again. But then! Then! She's back on the phone with him almost immediately (while Brice is caught up in the football game—doofy doofy dur dur!), telling Harley he's the best she's ever had, begging him to have sex with her again. Judith, it seems, is addicted to what the dick did. And now she's like, &quot;OMG I NEED MORE OF YOUR SATAN BONER AND ALSO COCAINE.&quot; Because that's how us fickle ladies work.</p>
<p>This idea—that men know what women really want, that resistance can be fucked out of us (or consent fucked into us)—is DEEPLY NOT OKAY. It's not okay to telegraph this to young men or young women or victims of sexual violence or potential perpetrators of sexual violence or lawmakers or anyone. It's a paradigm that I was hoping had died out with Pepe LePew. It is frightening.</p>
<p>I'm amazed at how efficiently Perry was able to roll back discourse, human rights, the basics of consent, and storytelling itself in just one shitty movie. Perry has done a lot for the visibility of black voices in popular culture, but that doesn't make his moralistic subtext in <em>Temptation</em> any less repellant and irresponsible. The world should demand better than Tyler Perry.</p>]]></description><category domain="">tyler perry</category><category domain="">temptation</category><category domain="">movies</category><category domain="">gender roles</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Wed, 3 Apr 2013 22:06:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993523</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Lindy West]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[March Madness: D.A.R.E to Say No to the Seattle Sound]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993527/march-madness-dare-to-say-no-to-the-seattle-sound</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jipqzd9tybqjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">There wasn't too much of a contest yesterday as the Brat Pack knocked <em>The Cosby Show</em> clean out of March Madness with 60% of the vote (I'm sorry, Theo! Judd Nelson is just too damn tough!) and the Spice Girls sank <em>Titanic</em> with one swift Girl Power kick to James Cameron's nards. Safe to say that while <em>Cosby</em> and <em>Titanic</em> are out of the running, their hearts will go on and on.</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jipqxecjgj0png/ku-xlarge.png" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<associate></associate>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" class="youtube" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/odKmFHoy0n0?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0" id="youtube-odKmFHoy0n0"></iframe></span></p><p>  Today stepping into the 80s ring, we have two of the most important parts of 80s youth culture, MTV and D.A.R.E. One was an anti-drug and alcohol education program and the other devoted most of its hours airing videos depicting drugs and alcohol as totally awesome. Vote with your conscious! (Or vote with Downtown Julie Brown.)</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" class="youtube" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Y21VecIIdBI?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0" id="youtube-Y21VecIIdBI"></iframe></span></p><p>  In the 90s courtroom, Monica Lewinsky takes the stand to face off against Grunge. What's more your cup of Seattle brewed fair trade coffee: Kenneth Starr or &quot;Super Star&quot; as covered by Sonic Youth?</p>
<script src="http://static.polldaddy.com/p/7012487.js"></script><br/>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/7012487/" target="_blank">80s: MTV (2) vs D.A.R.E. (7)</a></noscript>
<script src="http://static.polldaddy.com/p/7012503.js"></script><br/>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/7012503/" target="_blank">90s: Grunge (2) vs. Monica Lewinsky (7)</a></noscript>]]></description><category domain="">80s vs 90s</category><category domain="">march madness</category><category domain="">top</category><pubDate>Wed, 3 Apr 2013 21:40:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993527</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Madeleine Davies]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[This Week in Tabloids: Angelina Thinks Her Giant Engagement Ring Is Tacky]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993491/this-week-in-tabloids-angelina-thinks-her-giant-engagement-ring-is-tacky</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jidxmaby7x3jpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Welcome back to Midweek Madness, in which Tanisha Love Ramirez assists us in analyzing the &quot;news&quot; in <em>In Touch</em>, <em>Us</em>, <em>Ok!</em>, <em>Life &amp; Style</em>, and <em>Star</em>. This week, Kardashian weight is news again: Kim is fat, Khloe is hot. Also? &quot;Real&quot; &quot;Housewives&quot; get liquid nose jobs; Ryan Gosling's dogs need their privacy; and the real reason Angelina hasn't worn her engagement ring in a while. Let's do this.</p>

<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="413" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jididroo7l5jpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p><strong><em>Ok!</em></strong><br/>
&quot;Yes, We're Married&quot;<br/>
First she stole Brad, and <strong>now Angelina is totes stealing Jennifer Aniston's fake marriage and pregnancy headlines</strong>. Though neither half of Brangelina have confirmed a wedding, Angie was recently spotted wearing a simple gold ring on the finger where her engagement ring once resided, prompting unnamed sources to come out and share stories of a supposed secret sunset wedding ceremony held for their children's benefit. <strong>A &quot;pal&quot; claims that Angie wore a simple white shift dress from L'Wren Scott and recited her own vows</strong>. People cried tears of joy, children ate burgers of beef, Jon Voight managed to stay awake throughout the entire thing — it was a good night. And now that they are all ceremonied, Angie will, no doubt, &quot;call Brad and say she found a child she just can't leave behind&quot; and we'll be reading about their ever-expanding brood next week. Can't wait. Speaking of expanding broods: <strong>Kate Middleton is hoping that once she pops, she just won't stop</strong>. She and Wills want to make sure her womb isn't vacant very long after she blesses the world with a gift from her uterus. According to a source, Kate's mother Carole has been telling Kate that once she gets into &quot;baby-making mode&quot; she'll be able to handle an expanding brood, no problemo. Next: <strong>Kim Kardashian and her ex-boyfriend Reggie Bush have been calling each other</strong>, talking about babies, and generally making Kanye jeallies. And finally, Carrie Underwood didn't even know that she was supposed to be feuding with Taylor Swift. Now that she knows, she's totes over it, because &quot;if anything, we should all be supportive.&quot;<br/>
<strong>Grade: F (wedding news)</strong></p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="413" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18ji95sodverjjpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p><strong><em>Star</em></strong><br/>
&quot;I'll Eat As Much As I Want!&quot;<br/>
Yet another Kim Kardashian tear-down. Talking about her <a href="http://jezebel.com/5988950/this-week-in-tabloids-kim-kardashians-famous-ass-is-now-a-sagging-dimply-blob">ass</a> wasn't enough; now the mag attacks her very character; the title of the story inside is &quot;Selfish Kim Defies Her Doctors.&quot; <strong>She's described as greedy, bingeing, indulgent, defiant</strong>. An eyewitness saw her — gasp — <em>eating</em> with Kanye West at Atlanta's South City Kitchen Midtown. &quot;<strong>Kim ate like it was her last meal on earth</strong>, wolfing down fried chicken and waffles, buttermilk biscuits, mashed potoates, mac 'n cheese, collard greens with bacon and friend green tomatoes with goat cheese. She knew people were watching, but she just didn't care!&quot; SIGH. Imagine all the eyes on her as she and Kanye dined. If you don't eat, you're being rude to the restauranteurs; if you do, someone calls <em>Star</em>. Anyway, apparently <strong>Kris Jenner is pushing Kim to gain weight so she can land a multi-million-dollar deal with Weight Watchers or Jenny Craig</strong>. The thing goes on for a while, with words like &quot;reckless bingeing&quot; &quot;audacious&quot; &quot;slacking on fitness&quot; &quot;arms are flabby&quot; &quot;embarrassing&quot; and so on. It also claims she's scheduled her C-section for right after the 8-month mark so she can &quot;get her life and body back as soon as possible.&quot; Fucking hell, the way we treat women and women who are carrying around another human inside of them! Moving on. <strong>Angelina Jolie doesn't wear her enormous $500,000 diamond engagement ring because she thinks it's tacky</strong> to flash her wealth when she's always going to struggling countries on charity missions. Also, now that you mention it, she <em>hates</em> the ring. It's not her style at all — way too big and gaudy — but she does feel bad, because Brad spent a lot of time designing it for her. (<a href="#footnote1" target="_blank">Fig. 1</a>) <strong>Lena Dunham wants to lose weight and be pretty like other actresses her age</strong>. Leonardo DiCaprio has told Bradley Cooper to fuck as many models as he can before he turns 40. <strong>Liam Hemsworth has told Miley Cyrus they should be seeing other people and will only stay with her if they have an open relationship</strong>. Jessica Alba has told husband Cash Warren to get off the couch, stop getting fat, and get a job. Kyle Richards's husband Mauricio Umansky is &quot;the biggest flirt in Beverly Hills&quot; and cheats on her often and gave a busty former escort sitting at a hotel bar his phone number. He also did that smooth move of leaving his black American Express card on the table, so she'd <em>have</em> to call. Finally, <strong>Adrienne Maloof has a secret first husband</strong> and arrest warrant filed in 1988.<br/>
<strong>Grade: D- (food recall news)</strong></p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="414" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jidibsuhapjjpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p><strong>In Touch</strong><br/>
&quot;Dumped at 200 Lbs&quot;<br/>
<strong>Kim Kardashian is still &quot;eating her feelings&quot;</strong>, random doctors are still guestimating how much gestational weight Kimmy has gained and society has made a blood pact to never let Kim forget that time when she wore that Lanvin babydoll dress. Added twist: <strong>Kanye might be cheating on Kim with Aussie singer Iggy Azalea</strong>. While Kim's been spotted in dark corners of restaurants, ordering double desserts, Iggy has been publicly talking about her trips to Kanye's Parisian house to listen to his latest &quot;scriptures&quot; about McDonalds' fries. Krist. Next, <strong>Kristen Stewart has figured out the key to making Robert Pattinson happy: Smiling.</strong> Millionaire Matchmaker Patti Stanger admits that she's always wanted to be a 1950s housewife because &quot;women were way more cherished back then.&quot; Ummmm… Okay. (<a href="#footnote2" target="_blank">Fig. 2</a>) Finally, escorting celebrities down the red carpet is a legitimate job, you guys: Some dude named Chris Gaida has made his living as a celebrity red carpet escort for the last 14 years and has written a book about it. Forget <em>Lean In</em>!<br/>
<strong>Grade: D (old news)</strong></p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="413" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jididrse863jpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p><strong>Life &amp; Style</strong><br/>
&quot;I'm the Hot Sister Now!&quot;<br/>
Apparently, <strong>there can only be one sexy Kardashian</strong>, and Khloe has at long-last been krowned the kween of sexy. For now. Her recent slim down has earned her a lot of positive attention… and backhanded compliments. In a rampant case of quote abuse, this story twists old and made-up quotes in an attempt to spin an &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot; story. Khloe, who has never actually called herself ugly, sexy or hot in any of the interviews cited, is made out to be a default beauty queen, since Kim Kardashian is pregnant and Kourtney's busy with motherhood. The mag suggests that <strong>as Khloe becomes thinner — and therefore happier, according to the mag — Kim Kardashian drinks more and more haterade</strong>. &quot;It makes matters worse that Khloe is looking amazing. It's hard for Kim to be happy for her.&quot; Meanwhile: <strong>Britney Spears has already told her new beau that she loves him</strong> and her entire family is all, that's just our Britney — always rushing into relationships. Bachelor Sean Lowe's dance partner Peta Murgatroyd &quot;couldn't think of a single person better to be stuck in a room with, sweating.&quot; Also, <strong>Angelina Jolie has been talking to Billy Bob Thornton behind Brad's back</strong>, but it's totes cool because no bodily fluids have been exchanged — or worn. Lastly, a paparazzo stood by and caught these action-packed pics of Heidi Klum putting the &quot;super&quot; in super model, as she rescued her son Henry and two nannies from a riptide in Hawaii — dude, you could have <em>helped</em>. (<a href="#footnote3" target="_blank">Fig 3</a>).<br/>
<strong>Grade: D+ (vague weather report)</strong></p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="410" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18ji9fhwyzeajjpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p><strong><em>Us</em></strong><br/>
&quot;My Best Body Ever&quot;<br/>
It's so weird how this is phrased: It's not &quot;this is the best shape my body's ever been in&quot; or &quot;I feel very fit right now&quot; or even &quot;healthy feels great!&quot; It's as though she's been collecting corpses in varying states of decay and she wants to show us the best one she's ever had. Anyway. In an actual interview with the mag, <strong>Khloe spills that she lost 20 lbs. by boxing</strong>. &quot;I love to box!&quot; she says. Later, the copy reads, &quot;If only she had gotten into the ring sooner.&quot; Every morning, 5-foot-ten Khloe does 20 minutes of cardio to &quot;spike her metabolism&quot; and then goes to Gunnar Peterson's Beverly Hills gym four to five days a week where she gets on the elliptical or treadmill and then boxes for 12 rounds, punching the mitts and so on. She also does 55 minute Pilates classes twice a week. Exhausted just typing about it. One thing that's helped change her body? She no longer takes the hormones she was taking to ovulate, which made her bloated. Any more details and they might as well just print her medical charts. Also inside: <strong>Ryan Gosling's dog is too famous</strong>, so he needs his face blurred (<a href="#footnote4" target="_blank">Fig. 4</a>) The Bachelor's fiancée, Catherine Giudici, is &quot;bored and lonely&quot; in LA and stays in watching TV. <strong>Cory Monteith's rehab stint will be dealing with his heavy drinking, but his &quot;biggest issue&quot; is his cocaine habit.</strong> &quot;He drinks too hard and then he can't say no to other things,&quot; a source explains. &quot;The house party scene in LA is dangerous for him.&quot; Next, there's an amazing four-page piece called &quot;Real Housewives Plastic Surgery Confidential,&quot; (<a href="#footnote5" target="_blank">Fig. 5</a>, <a href="#footnote6" target="_blank">Fig. 6</a>) in which we get to see old pictures of Kyle Richards and the gang. For those keeping count, Vicki Gunvalson as had two breast augmentation, fat injections on her face, nose work and a chin inplant. Kyle Richards had a nose job and liposuction. <strong>NeNe Leaks had a breast lift, nose job and lipo</strong>; Lisa Hochstein has implants and a nose job; Tamara Barney had two different sizes of implants, then had them removed; <strong>Brandi Glanville had implants, liquid rhinoplasty and vaginal rejuvenation</strong>, and Teresa Giudice got C cups in 2008. <em>Liquid</em> rhinoplasty! You can smooth out a bump with injectables. We learned something new today. Finally, the &quot;Secrets of Man Men&quot; story tells us that in season 6, Don Draper's past as Dick Whitman will be the focus and Harry Crane's wardrobe will be <em>Scooby-Doo</em>-esque.<br/>
<strong>Grade: C+ (dog news)</strong></p>
<hr/>
<h4>Addendum</h4>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="898" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jii44dathnrjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p><a id="footnote1" name="footnote1" target="_blank">Fig. 1</a>, from Star</p>
<associate></associate>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="451" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jidibssuls4jpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p><a id="footnote2" name="footnote2" target="_blank">Fig. 2</a>, from In Touch</p>
<associate></associate>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="377" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jididrpb228jpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p><a id="footnote3" name="footnote3" target="_blank">Fig. 3</a>, from Life &amp; Style</p>
<associate></associate>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="478" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jiarma78pdvjpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p><a id="footnote4" name="footnote4" target="_blank">Fig. 4</a>, from Us</p>
<associate></associate>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="237" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jiarkb1qajwjpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p><a id="footnote5" name="footnote5" target="_blank">Fig. 5</a>, from Us</p>
<associate></associate>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="166" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jiarkb1jk6jjpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p><a id="footnote6" name="footnote6" target="_blank">Fig. 6</a>, from Us</p>
<associate></associate>]]></description><category domain="">midweek madness</category><category domain="">this week in tabloids</category><category domain="">star</category><category domain="">ok</category><category domain="">ok</category><category domain="">in touch</category><category domain="">life  style</category><category domain="">us</category><category domain="">us weekly</category><category domain="">us magazine</category><category domain="">celebrity</category><category domain="">roundup</category><category domain="">tabloids</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Wed, 3 Apr 2013 19:40:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993491</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dodai Stewart]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[The First African-American Spokeswoman for DNC Isn't Black Enough, Says Idiot White Guy]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993443/the-first-african+american-spokeswoman-for-dnc-isnt-black-enough-says-idiot-white-guy</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18ji9p37gebhqjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">One of the great things about being biracial is being stopped on the street by strangers demanding to know your racial and ethnic heritage. &quot;What are you?&quot; they ask, refusing to take &quot;get away from me, weirdo&quot; for an answer. Or, you know, when you're at work and a customer grabs your arm, leans in close, and whispers, &quot;My daughters and I pay a lot of money for skin as beautiful as yours. You have the type of skin we would <em>kill for</em>.&quot; </p>
<p>But it's not just white ladies threatening to turn your <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ed_Gein" target="_blank">skin into a suit</a> — there are lots of benefits to being biracial! Like never feeling like you fit in, or feeling like a traitor to your mother's race because all your friends are white, or being mocked by your elementary school classmates when your mother lovingly puts your hair into braids so that you cry and take them out in the bathroom. <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/karen-finney/virginia-shame_b_529210.html" target="_blank">Karen Finney</a> is having even more fun — did you know that if you're biracial and get hired at MSNBC, <em>other people</em> get to decide your racial identity for you? It's true!</p>
<p>MSNBC <a href="http://tv.msnbc.com/2013/04/02/karen-finney-named-new-msnbc-weekend-host/" target="_blank">recently announced</a> that Finney, former deputy press secretary for Hillary Clinton, will host a new show airing on weekends from 4-5 p.m. Finney is described as &quot;the first African-American spokeswoman for the Democratic National Committee.&quot; But how African-American is she? Newsbusters' <a href="http://www.newsbusters.org/blog/16" target="_blank">Tim J. Graham</a>, an expert in determining who is black and who is not, recently did us all a solid and used his male gazin' skills to posit that Finney is simply not tan enough to be black. &quot;MSNBC touting Karen Finney as another African-American host,&quot; <a href="https://twitter.com/TimJGraham/status/319180589049724929" target="_blank">tweeted</a> Graham. &quot;Would the average viewer be able to guess that? Or is Boehner a shade more tan?&quot; Yes. John Boehner's glistening man flesh is &quot;more tan&quot; than Finney's. By this logic John Boehner is blacker than Malcolm X, my grandpa, and Coretta Scott King <em>combined</em>. But Graham didn't stop at melanin — he later implored his followers to &quot;<a href="https://twitter.com/TimJGraham/status/319190014498062337" target="_blank">judge pic here</a>,&quot; linking to an article about Finney with a photo so that they could also weigh in on her true racial identity.</p>
<p>Yes, white dude. Do tell us more about what it means to look black. It sure is good to know that Finney only qualifies as black as long as the average viewer thinks she does. My skin tone is roughly identical to Finney's — I guess I'm out of the club, too. I'm not sure how to break this to my black mom. Sorry, mom. We had a good run. It was fun while it lasted. Can anyone recommend some sort of &quot;Chicken Soup for the Formerly Black Soul&quot; type book that can guide me through this process of having my racial identity stripped from me by some white conservative jerk who probably still thinks that <a data-amazontag="jezebelamzn-20" data-amazonasin="0415963095" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/Irish-Became-White-Routledge-Classics/dp/0415963095?tag=jezebelamzn-20&amp;ascsubtag=link">racism against Irish people</a> is &quot;a thing&quot;?</p>
<p>I'm tired of this. The fact that Graham felt qualified to wade into these waters speaks not only to the state of race relations in this country, but to his deep-seated white male privilege. Guess what? &quot;Tim J. Graham&quot; does not get to have a say in this conversation about women and race. Tim J. Graham doesn't get to decide whether Karen Finney's skin tone meets his standards of blackness because Tim J. Graham <em>doesn't get to maintain blackness standards</em>. Graham acts as if he's doing us all some great service by questioning the legitimacy of Finney's diversity bona fides, but this is just the same old tired racism dance. For Graham to minimize the importance of Finney's hire because her race is not &quot;<a href="https://twitter.com/TimJGraham/status/319206320639184896" target="_blank">self-evident</a>&quot; suggests that us biracial folks ought to pick a distinct category before we can be taken seriously.</p>
<p>Karen Finney gets to be black if she wants because <em>she is black</em>. Regardless of my olive-toned skin suit, I'm still black. Half of my family is black. These are the people who gave me black Barbies and took my brother and me to sit on Black Santa's lap (no line for Black Santa, y'all). I am biracial, and I am black, and Tim J. Turdface Graham doesn't get to take that away from me, or Karen Finney, or anyone else.</p>
<p>This issue is deeply personal for me, but Graham's attitude has broader implications for women of color. For a white man to say, categorically, &quot;you are not black, because you don't look black to me,&quot; denies women of color the right to take ownership of our bodies and our identities. It evokes deeply painful stereotypes of what is or isn't black and it denies that there is anything unique or diverse about being biracial. Graham's comments explicitly state what many biracial people (myself included) struggle with every day: <em>you don't look like me, you don't look like them, you don't belong anywhere</em>.</p>
<p>Graham thinks our choice of identity should be based entirely on outward appearance. The thought of having to &quot;choose&quot; is absurd in and of itself — it is possible to identify and fit in with more than one cultural, racial, or ethnic group. Graham picked a category for Finney (and people who look like her) by ignoring her own statements of self-identification and substituting them with his own flawed judgment. He ejected Finney from a community that he himself does not inhabit. Even more problematically, Graham's tweets reinforce the notion of some sort of monolithic &quot;black culture&quot; that is devoid of nuance, made up of people who look and act the same, and who agree on everything. For Graham, if you don't fit into his preconceived ideas of racial identity, you don't belong. But there's no singular way to &quot;be black.&quot; Finney represents one of a zillion ways — even if she doesn't have a standing weekly appointment at her local tanning salon.</p>
<hr/>
<p><em>Meagan Hatcher-Mays is a third-year law student at Washington University in Saint Louis. She teaches &quot;Women &amp; the Law&quot; to a group of brilliant undergraduates. She yells a lot on <a href="https://twitter.com/ohmeags" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.</em></p>
<em></em>]]></description><category domain="">race</category><category domain="">racism</category><category domain="">karen finney</category><category domain="">tim j graham</category><category domain="">shut up whitey</category><category domain="">gettypic</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Wed, 3 Apr 2013 17:43:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993443</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jessica Coen]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[We've Seen the Future, and You're Freelancing]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993227/weve-seen-the-future-and-youre-freelancing</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jhxy4xvaptrjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Freelancing can be tons of fun. You create your own hours, accept the jobs you want, and take shit from no boss. Plus, many freelance and contract jobs come with the enormous perk of working from the comfort of your own <strike>home office</strike> stinky bed. I'm writing this post laying on my couch wearing an XXL t-shirt as a Comfort Dress; I'm using a Red Vine as a straw to sip Dr. Pepper, and my dog is laying behind me acting as a warming bolster. It's the best. </p>
<p>According to a study conducted by Intuit in 2010, more than forty percent of the US workforce — so, sixty million people — will be contractors, temps, and the self-employed by 2020. That's great for those of us who want to trade business casual for an all day pajama party, but is it good news for everybody?</p>
<p>Jeremy Neuner, founder of the coworking space <a href="http://nextspace.us/" target="_blank">NextSpace</a>, <a href="http://qz.com/65279/40-of-americas-workforce-will-be-freelancers-by-2020/" target="_blank">writes at <em>Quartz</em></a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Following the recent economic downturn, the employment rate has recovered at a frustratingly slow pace, except in one area: temporary, contingent, and independent workers. Between 2009 and 2012, according the Bureau of Labor Statistics, the number of temporary employees rose by 29%. A survey of the 200 largest companies found that temporary workers represented, on average, 22% of their workforce, and that percentage is growing. Workers from all different industries (not just tech) are discovering that they're able to be productive outside of the corporate office and without a long-term employer.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is true, and that's fantastic for many people. There are tons of benefits to not being tied down to a corporate job.</p>
<p>I've contracted and freelanced with companies from a place that rhymes with Shmoogle (not sure what I can and cannot say via my NDA!) to newspapers and magazines. In fat times, contract and freelance work can be a smörgåsbord of choice — you make your own hours, you're usually compensated fairly decently, and there's the delicious freedom to not being tied to a 9-to-5.</p>
<p>However, Neuner takes the benefits of freelance and contract work one step further:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The forces behind this sea-change are many: the rapid adoption of mobile technology, ubiquitous internet access, and a general sense of malaise powered by the vague yet nagging notion that we're just not meant to work all day sitting in a cubicle. Add to that the waste of time, energy and brainpower that commuting engenders, and it becomes apparent that our definition of &quot;workplace&quot; will never be the same. It may seem like a tug of war between companies and workers, but in fact they share common goals: using technology and mobility to maximize productivity, innovation, and well-being.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But do workers and employees <em>really</em> have the same goals? I'm not so sure. Because while it can rule to be a &quot;contingent worker&quot; — it can also SUCK DONKEY BALLS.</p>
<p>First, freelance and contract work usually means no benefits — no matter how much you're working. No healthcare, dental care, and no 401K. While your peers are saving for retirement, you can't afford to replace all the teeth you lost due to your Red Vines and Dr. Pepper addiction.</p>
<p>There's also no job security, and that's fucking stressful. Hustling for freelance assignments can take years off your already shortened life (see above about health insurance). Further, if you're a contract worker, knowing you can be easily discarded with no reflection on the company's numbers (and no severance package!) really blows. Many companies in Silicon Valley hire multitudes of contract workers to do jobs that aren't originally envisioned as temporary. Then, if they need to cut the fat somewhere, they're able to lay those people off and not worry about explaining it to their boards or investors.</p>
<p>And although many contract workers are financially compensated a bit better than employees, their paychecks aren't taxed. Come April 1st, you're furiously adding up 1099s and shoveling out insane amounts of cash to Uncle Sam.</p>
<p>Less obviously, there's a certain divide between staff members and freelance/contract workers at many companies. For contractors, it might mean you're not included in certain meetings, not invited to staff parties, and excluded from important decisions. Even if you're given the same responsibilities (or more!), are working the same hours (or more!), or are bringing equal value to the company — it just doesn't matter. You're not an employee, and you're not treated as one in many of the ways that matter.</p>
<p>If you're in office, that can have an affect on all sorts of things, from work morale to company loyalty. One tech company I worked at, fulltime employees were given white badges and contract workers had the dreaded red badge. We all had access to the same facilities and many of the same perks — free food, gym, bus ride to and from work — but the difference in badge color created a feeling of discontent amongst the red badges. I'm still not one hundred percent sure what the need for separate colors was, but I <em>can</em> tell you that there wasn't a contract worker I met who wasn't fully aware of our lower status.</p>
<p>If you don't work in the same space as where you contract or freelance, there are other issues. Sure, it's great to roll over and start working in your own filth, but it's also pretty fucking lonely. When you're not in the same office as the people you are working for, you miss out on the day-to-day friendships, collaborations, and idea exchanges that lead to better ideas, and general excitement about your shared endeavor.</p>
<p>Companies like <a href="http://nextspace.us/" target="_blank">NextSpace</a> set up coworking spaces that mimic office life — but, like, cool office life with couches for lounging and hot entrepreneur coworkers. They're interesting because you get to be around other people and their energy, and when you've been hibernating in your gross cave of body fluids and funk, that's invaluable. However, it's not quite the same as being in an office with people working toward the same goal or vision — or even in the same field. I've hung out in the San Francisco location, and maybe it's because I'm not a regular, but I wasn't able to find a buddy to brainstorm headlines or stories with. Also, you're paying for your drop-in faux office space; at $20 for a visit, it can add up.</p>
<p>All things considered, I'd choose freelancing over a 9-to-5 corporate job almost every time, but the choice part is key. Piecing together a career is wonderful when it's an opportunity, but it sucks if you're forced into it. For many contract workers, it's not their decision, it's something they're pushed into because a company doesn't want to hire them for whatever reason. The company receives all of the benefits of a fulltime employee, without shelling out for many of the things that make being a fulltime employee worth it.</p>
<p>Not everyone wants to live in the freewheeling life of a freelancer, many people want (and need) benefits and security. Here's hoping this worker revolution doesn't leave them behind.</p>
<p>[<a href="http://qz.com/65279/40-of-americas-workforce-will-be-freelancers-by-2020/" target="_blank">Quartz</a>] [<a href="http://http-download.intuit.com/http.intuit/CMO/intuit/futureofsmallbusiness/intuit_2020_report.pdf" target="_blank">Intuit</a>]</p>]]></description><category domain="">work</category><category domain="">contract workers</category><category domain="">freelance</category><category domain="">working</category><category domain="">corporate</category><category domain="">corporate america</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Wed, 3 Apr 2013 15:35:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993227</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Laura Beck]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Beyonce Doesn't Like Labels But 'I'm a Modern-Day Feminist, I Guess']]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993428/beyonce-doesnt-like-labels-but-im-a-modern+day-feminist-i-guess</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jhhoaogk2sdjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text"> While she's been a lightning rod for claims of both feminism and anti-feminism (particularly since announcing her Mrs. Carter World Tour), <b>Beyoncé</b> has tended in the past to steer clear of the F-word that's put so many <a href="http://jezebel.com/5953879/dont-go-calling-taylor-swift-a-feminist-says-taylor-swift">female celebrities</a> in the <a href="http://jezebel.com/5964727/katy-perry-billboards-woman-of-the-year-is-not-a-feminist">hot seat</a>. Until now, at least. Bey tells <i>Vogue UK</i> in a cover interview for the April 2013 issue that she's a feminist—but not without a disclaimer.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;I feel like Mrs Carter is who I am, but more bold and more fearless than I've ever been. It comes from knowing my purpose and really meeting myself once I saw my child. I was like, 'OK, this is what you were born to do'. The purpose of my body became completely different.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;I guess I am a modern-day feminist. I do believe in equality. Why do you have to choose what type of woman you are? Why do you have to label yourself anything? I'm just a woman and I love being a woman… I do believe in equality and that we have a way to go and it's something that's pushed aside and something that we have been conditioned to accept.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://news.sky.com/story/1073257/beyonce-im-a-modern-day-feminist" target="_blank">Sky News</a>; lede images via <a href="http://www.vogue.co.uk/news/2013/04/beyonce-makes-british-vogue-cover-debut---may-issue-vogue" target="_blank">Vogue UK</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="150" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jhj7bnm2hqigif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p><p> <i>Glee</i> star (and former <b>Bey</b> backup dancer!) <b>Heather Morris</b> is pregnant with her first child. She's three months along already, and the father is her high school sweetheart <b>Taylor Hubbell.</b> It was &quot;totally unexpected.&quot; [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/news/heather-morris-is-pregnant-glee-actress-expecting-first-child-201334" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jhi90iaorfkjpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></p><p>Elmo puppeteer <b>&quot;Tickle Me&quot; Kevin Clash</b> has been slammed with a fifth underage sex lawsuit by a now-25-year-old man who claims to have met Clash on a &quot;gay telephone chat line&quot; in 2004, when he was just 16.</p>
<p>According to the suit, Clash invited the boy to come over, sent a luxury car to pick him up, and once he arrived, plied him with &quot;alcohol and groomed him with attention and affection&quot; until the two engaged in sexual contact. The boy didn't come forward until now, say lawyers, because he wasn't immediately aware of the mental, psychological and emotional trauma of the experience. [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/crime/elmo-puppeteer-hit-5th-sex-allegation-article-1.1305743" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jhi96f6cjrljpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></p><p>Three years since the birth of <b>Kate Hudson</b> and <b>Matt Bellamy's</b> son <b>Bingham Hawn Bellamy</b>, Hudson told <i>Elle</i> that they got tapas or whatever like twice and then she got knocked up by accident.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;It was all very old-fashioned and proper and we went on lovely dates, but two months later I was pregnant... I knew it would take a strong man to deal with it. You know that with a relationship things can go either way when you have a child. Everything becomes a big decision. He was there and that was that, but things happen for a reason.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/kate-hudson-pregnant-article-1.1306011" target="_blank">NYDN</a>, <a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/3am/celebrity-news/kate-hudson-talks-lover-matt-1806288" target="_blank">Mirror UK</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="169" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jhi9k8gfyjojpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></p><p><b>Rebecca Hall</b>, best known for being the one who wasn't <b>Scarlett Johansson</b> in <b>Vicky Cristina Barcelona</b>, has been dating <b>Sam Mendes</b> since his split with <b>Kate Winslet</b> (and, some suspect, before they separated).</p>
<p>Hall doesn't discuss their relationship: &quot;It's what happens when you start going out with a famous person and are a bit famous yourself, I guess. It's their problem though. Everyone can be interested but I'm still not going to talk about it.&quot; However, back when the still-married Mendes cast Hall in two of his plays after meeting her on the set of <i>Starter For Ten</i>, Winslet was supposedly &quot;infuriated.&quot; [<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2303147/Rebecca-Hall-opens-romance-Sam-Mendes.html?ITO=1490&amp;ns_mchannel=rss&amp;ns_campaign=1490" target="_blank">Daily Mail</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<img height="165" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jhj7flhovu1gif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/><root> This one time, </root><b>Ke$ha.</b>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;Me and <b>Johnny Depp</b> had eyeball sex at the benefit concert for Superstorm Sandy in Los Angeles. We never really talked - we just had eyeball sex.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/ke-ha-johnny-depp-eyeball-sex-article-1.1305642#ixzz2PP00JtcO" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<ul><li><b>Justin Bieber's</b> recent troubles may stem from his <b>Selena Gomez</b> breakup. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/03/justin-bieber-selena-gomez-breakup-acting-out-anger/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><strong>Lindsay Lohan</strong> wears a bikini, reveals hella bruises. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/02/lindsay-lohan-brazil-bikini-photo/?adid=hero5" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li><b>&quot;Tanning Mom&quot; Patricia Krentcil</b> agrees with the new law instituted by <b>Chris Christie</b> that prohibits anyone under 17 from hitting a tanning salon without parental approval. [<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/03/tanning-mom-tan-law-ban-governor-chris-christie/" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</li><li>This picture of <b>Jack</b> and <b>Shaq.</b> (<b>Nicholson</b> and <b>O'Neal.</b>) [<a href="http://www.express.co.uk/news/showbiz/389004/Little-and-large-Jack-Nicholson-overshadowed-by-Shaquille-O-Neal-on-basketball-court" target="_blank">Express</a>]</li><li><strong>Jane Henson</strong>, widow (and business partner) of the late <b>Muppets</b> creator <b>Jim Henson</b>, has passed away at 78. [<a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/04/02/showbiz/muppets-jane-henson-dies/" target="_blank">CNN</a>]</li><li><strong>Will Arnett</strong> joins the cast of <b>Teenaage Mutant Ninja Turtles.</b> [<a href="http://www.vulture.com/2013/04/will-arnett-ninja-turtles.html" target="_blank">Vulture</a>]</li><li><b>Tom Cruise</b> wants to go into space. (In spirit, buddy, you already live there.) [<a href="http://www.belfasttelegraph.co.uk/entertainment/news/tom-cruise-wants-space-adventure-29172196.html" target="_blank">Belfast Telegraph</a>]</li><li><strong>Hilary Duff</strong> will appear as a love interest for <b>Ashton Kutcher</b> on that <b>Two and A Half Men</b> episode you're totally gonna watch. [<a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/entertainment/news/hilary-duff-set-to-play-love-interest-for-ashton-kutcher-on-two-and-a-half-men-finale-201324" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li>This is <b>Holly Madison</b> and her newborn daugher <b>Rainbow Aurora</b> (guhhh). [<a herf="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-moms/news/holly-madison-debuts-daughter-rainbow-aurora-in-beautiful-first-baby-portrait-201324" target="_blank">Us Weekly</a>]</li><li><b>Tom Hanks</b> reflects on the life of his friend <b>Nora Ephron</b> after his first Broadway performance in <b>Lucky Guy.</b> [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/tom_tears_for_beloved_nora_YXRDAbg08nebZfVkLDqvEP" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li><b>Matt Damon</b> and <b>Luciana Baroso</b> are set to renew their wedding vows in St. Lucia. Stars are just like us! [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/belated_blowout_U9BnbHG3yIP9ynZcPHd2OJ" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li><b>Jimmy Fallon's</b> extended his NBC contract and gives credence to the rumors that he'll be taking over <b>Jay Leno's</b> job. [<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/03/business/media/jimmy-fallon-said-to-have-extended-nbc-contract.html?_r=0" target="_blank">NYT</a>]</li><li><b>Matt Lauer's</b> slammed by Southampton offiicals for trying to expand his 40-acre horse farm. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/hold_your_horses_Sshz9AiHmVHZQNlKGUmNnK" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li>Porn god/American treasure <b>Ron Jeremy's</b> back to work after his health scare. [<a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/04/01/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/ron-jeremy-returns-to-work/index.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed:+rss/cnn_showbiz+%28RSS:+Entertainment%29" target="_blank">CNN</a>]</li><li><b>Jay-Z's</b> launched Roc Nation Sports. [<a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/pagesix/jay_forming_sports_agency_yankee_vnBUtVq5zO1a7rQqnofaBM" target="_blank">Page Six</a>]</li><li><b>Roger Ebert's</b> cancer returns, he takes some time off writing to battle it. [<a href="http://todayentertainment.today.com/_news/2013/04/03/17583335-roger-eberts-cancer-recurs-critic-takes-leave-of-presence-from-writing-duties?lite" target="_blank">TODAY</a>]</li><li><b>Janelle Monae</b> covers next month's <i>Essence.</i> [<a href="http://www.thelifefiles.com/2013/04/02/hello-janelle-monae/" target="_blank">The Life Files</a>]</li><li>After a motorcycle accident, subsequent leg amputation and eight months of recovery, <b>Wynonna Judd's</b> husband <b>Cactus Moser</b> walked to her. [<a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/judd-husband-cactus-walking-stunned-article-1.1305697" target="_blank">NYDN</a>]</li><li><b>Nicki Minaj</b> truthbombs. &quot;I am lyrically better than most of the male rappers out there - yes, I'm gonna say it. I don't get the credit that I deserve.&quot; [<a href="http://www.missinfo.tv/index.php/nicki-minaj-on-high-school-video-wayne-is-still-so-sexy/" target="_blank">Missinfo.tv</a>]</li><li><b>Jon Hamm's</b> penis is out. <a href="http://jezebel.com/5991466/amc-begs-jon-hamm-to-put-his-penis-away">Still.</a> [<a href="http://www.dlisted.com/2013/04/02/jon-hamm-takes-hammaconda-walk" target="_blank">D-Listed</a>]</li></ul>]]></description><category domain="">dirt bag</category><category domain="">beyonce</category><category domain="">heather morris</category><category domain="">kevin clash</category><category domain="">kate hudson</category><category domain="">matt bellamy</category><category domain="">rebecca hall</category><category domain="">sam mendes</category><category domain="">kate winslet</category><category domain="">kesha</category><category domain="">johnny depp</category><category domain="">justin bieber</category><category domain="">selena gomez</category><category domain="">lindsay lohan</category><category domain="">patricia krentcil</category><category domain="">chris christie</category><category domain="">jack nicholson</category><category domain="">shaquille oneal</category><category domain="">roger ebert</category><category domain="">nicki minaj</category><category domain="">courtney love</category><category domain="">jane henson</category><category domain="">jim henson</category><category domain="">will artnett</category><category domain="">tom cruise</category><category domain="">hilary duff</category><category domain="">holly madison</category><category domain="">tom hanks</category><category domain="">nora ephron</category><category domain="">matt damon</category><category domain="">luciana baroso</category><category domain="">jimmy fallon</category><category domain="">jay leno</category><category domain="">matt lauer</category><category domain="">ron jeremy</category><category domain="">jay-z</category><category domain="">janelle monae</category><category domain="">wynonna judd</category><category domain="">cactus moser</category><category domain="">jon hamm</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><category domain="">tweet</category><category domain="">gettypic</category><pubDate>Wed, 3 Apr 2013 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993428</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna Breslaw]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[Khloe Kardashian and Lamar Odom Raise Millions for Charity, Don't Give a Dime to Charity]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993386/khloe-kardashian-and-lamar-odom-raise-millions-for-charity-dont-give-a-dime-to-charity</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="418" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jfhqqkcjqp0jpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text"> Cathy's Kids, the charity <strong>Lamar Odom</strong> founded in honor on his mother to &quot;help underprivileged kids and raise money for cancer research&quot;, has raised over 2.2 million dollars. Excellent news! The not so excellent news? Not a single penny of that money has gone to underprivileged kids or to fight cancer.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Lamar established the charity — Cathy's Kids — in memory of his mother, who died from cancer when he was 12 ... and initially stated that the purpose of the charity was to help underprivileged kids and raise money for cancer research.</p>
<p>But according to official records — obtained by ESPN's &quot;Outside the Lines&quot; — there is no evidence any of the money ever went to fight cancer.</p>
<p>There is proof, however, $1.3 million of the $2.2 million that was raised went toward funding two &quot;elite&quot; youth basketball teams — the insinuation is that the kids on the teams were so good, they were already on college radars for scholarships and other financial help.</p>
<p>Of the remaining $900k, there is no evidence based on available documentation that any of it went to cancer research. In fact, according to OTL, there's no evidence whatsoever of where the money went.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Further, <a href="http://radaronline.com/2013/04/khloe-kardashian-lamar-odom-no-longer-selling-ebay-cancer-charity-scandal/" target="_blank">they've removed</a> all the items from the charity's eBay page.</p>
<p><strong>UPDATE</strong>: Kardashian's people say <a href="http://radaronline.com/2013/04/lamar-odom-was-target-of-attack-charity-scandal-says-khloe-kardashian-camp/" target="_blank">Odom was duped</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;It is unfortunate that Lamar Odom has been the target of an attack on athletes' charities, although he has personally contributed approximately $2.2 million to his foundation, Cathy's Kids, to fulfill its charitable purposes that include helping underprivileged inner-city youth,&quot; Khloe's reps told Radar in a statement on Tuesday.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Whatever went down, it clearly sucks the most for the kids and the charities; here's hoping this is all gets resolved fast.<br/>
[<a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/04/02/lamar-odom-charity-cancer-khloe-kardashian-espn-outside-the-lines/#ixzz2PLrVqpA0" target="_blank">TMZ</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jfbri9rg1dejpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p>Justice Beaver is at it again! Doing what? Nobody knows, exactly. Mainly it appears he's hitting on Victoria Secret model Jourdan Dunn with lines like &quot;You got nice tits,&quot; and &quot;You flashed me and my dancers and made my day.&quot; How did Dunn react? &quot;I kind of felt a bit awkward because he's this little boy.&quot; Lol, biebs.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>[Jourdan Dunn], 22, revealed on &quot;The Jonathan Ross Show,&quot; that the Canadian pop star had flirted with her at a rehearsal for the Victoria's Secret Fashion show last November. Dunn apparently received a compliment from the singer after accidentally flashing her chest at him.</p>
<p>&quot;He said to me, 'You're really cute. You got nice tits. You flashed me and my dancers and made my day,'&quot; Dunn said. &quot;I kind of felt a bit awkward because he's this little boy. I laughed after it because he was 18 at the time and I was like, 'why not, flirt with the models, do your thing.'&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>[<a href="http://celebslam.celebuzz.com/2013/04/jourdan-dunn-justin-bieber.php" target="_blank">Celebslam</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="427" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jfaau51q2g3jpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p><strong>Michael Fassbender</strong> and <strong>Rosario Dawson</strong> are apparently an item.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Rosario Dawson and Michael Fassbender were spotted together in his neighbourhood in London a couple of times this weekend. (Thanks MK!) No confirmation as to whether or not it was more than just a meeting. Or two meetings. And no body language indications either.</p>
<p>Still, the prospect is intriguing. On a purely physical level, their combination would be hot. And it might be interesting politically too. Because Dawson stars in the upcoming Trance, directed by Danny Boyle, opening this weekend. And Fassbender was initially in talks to play the part that eventually went to Vincent Cassel but had to drop out due to scheduling conflicts. Boyle and Dawson just ended their relationship. If Boyle and Fassbender intend to work together eventually, does a potential Dawson-Fassbender hookup screw that up?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That's great and all, but I'm still confused about the <a href="http://www.thefrisky.com/2012-04-03/about-those-michael-fassbenderdomestic-assault-rumors/" target="_blank">abuse charges</a> from Fassbender's ex. She dropped them, but women don't always drop charges because they're not true. That said, it's not fair to condem him if they actually aren't true. Whatever it is, it makes me a little less excited about him. Is that fair? What do you guys think?</p>
<p>Annnd speaking of Rosario Dawson, <a href="http://filmdrunk.uproxx.com/2013/04/rosario-dawson-is-fully-shaved-full-frontal-in-trance?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+uproxx%2Ffilmdrunk+%28Film+Drunk%29&amp;utm_content=Google+Reader" target="_blank">here's</a> James Mcavoy on her pubic hair — &quot;Where were we? Ah, shaving the vagina, as people do.&quot;</p>
<p>[<a href="http://www.laineygossip.com/Rosario-Dawson-and-Michael-Fassbender-spotted-together/26414" target="_blank">Lainey Gossip</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" class="youtube" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/_SFs761eEFk?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0" id="youtube-_SFs761eEFk"></iframe></span></p><p>  <strong>Courtney Love</strong> is doing ads for electronic cigs.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In the ad, a stodgy older woman catches the controversial performer smoking indoors at a chic party.</p>
<p>&quot;Excuse me, you know you can't smoke in here,&quot; the elderly woman tells the Hole lead singer, while looking at her in utter disgust.</p>
<p>Never one to be intimidated by anyone, Love responds with her trademark foul language.</p>
<p>&quot;Relax, it's a f**kin NJOY,&quot; she says before sauntering away as her song Celebrity Skin plays in the background.</p>
<p>NJOY Kings promote their product as the &quot;look, taste and feel of traditional (cancer sticks).&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Adorable. [<a href="http://radaronline.com/2013/04/courtney-love-smoking-video-electronic-cigarettes-ad/" target="_blank">Radar</a>]</p>
<hr/>
<ul><li><strong>Victoria Justice</strong> wears short shorts. [<a href="http://www.popoholic.com/2013/04/02/victoria-justice-unleashes-her-wicked-stems-and-uber-hotness/" target="_blank">Popoholic</a>]</li><li><strong>Tom Daley</strong> and a tiny piglet LET'S GET MARRIED. [<a href="http://www.queerty.com/pop-brownies-tom-daley-teen-wolf-barbara-walters-20130329/" target="_blank">Queerty</a>]</li><li><strong>Molly Ringwald</strong> can totally pull off red lipstick [<a href="http://yeeeah.com/molly-ringwalds-red-hair-and-red-lips/" target="_blank">Yeeeah</a>]</li><li><strong>Tom Hanks</strong> and <strong>Rita Wilson</strong> are grandparents again! I bet they're awesome grandparents. [<a href="http://celebritybabies.people.com/2013/04/02/colin-hanks-expecting-second-child/?xid=rss-topheadlines&amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+people%2Fheadlines+%28PEOPLE.com%3A+Top+Headlines%29&amp;utm_content=Google+Reader%3EPeople%3C/a%3E]%3Cli%3E%3Cstrong%3ENeil%20Patrick%20Harris%3C/strong%3E%20got%20a%20scavenger%20hunt%20for%20his%2040th%20birthday,%20and%20you%20know%20it%20was%20hella%20fun.%20[%3Ca%20href=" target="_blank">People</a>]</li><li><strong>Bradley Cooper</strong> got a perm. [<a href="http://stylenews.peoplestylewatch.com/2013/04/02/bradley-cooper-perm-curly-hair/?xid=rss-topheadlines&amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+people%2Fheadlines+%28PEOPLE.com%3A+Top+Headlines%29&amp;utm_content=Google+Reader" target="_blank">People</a>]</li><li><em>Game of Thrones</em> is the stallion who mounts the fourth season. (Ugh, I don't know; GoT is getting a fourth season is what I was going for.) (Also, isn't <a href="http://www.etsy.com/listing/107642262/game-of-thrones-dothraki-onesie-the?ref=exp_listing" target="_blank">this adorable</a>??) [<a href="http://www.deadline.com/2013/04/hbos-game-of-thrones-renewed-for-fourth-season/" target="_blank">Deadline</a>]</li><li>Last year, <strong>Betty White</strong> got a hug from First Dog <em>Bo</em> at the White House. I have no picture, but I just saw her telling <strong>Anderson Cooper</strong> about it on his show earlier today. And then he gave her a tour of the White House. Is there any better thought than Betty White hanging out with Bo? She also talked about how she wanted to do a <em>Golden Girls</em> movie, but <strong>Bea Arthur</strong> wanted to quit while they were ahead. I see both points, but really DAMMIT BEA. (Please note, this might be slightly old news, but it's still exciting, OK?)</li><li><em>Finding <strong>Dory</strong></em> is coming!! [<a href="http://www.slashfilm.com/finding-nemo-sequel-officially-called-finding-dory-releases-november-25-2015/" target="_blank">Slash Film</a>]</li><li><strong>Melissa Joan Hart</strong> is the new Nutrisystem spokeswoman. Not sure what the diet is about these days, but when my mom put me on it about twenty years ago, I ate small portions of gross microwave dog food and starved. But it's probably better, now — at least food quality wise? [<a href="http://radaronline.com/2013/04/melissa-joan-hart-weight-loss-nutrisystem-spokesperson/" target="_blank">E!</a>]</li><li><img height="225" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jfet8dqw9nqgif/ku-medium.gif" class="transform-ku-medium"/> <strong>That kid</strong> CANNOT pour the milk into the cereal! (And other <a href="http://imgur.com/a/YET5a" target="_blank">awesome infomercial gifs</a>)
<associate></associate>
</li></ul>]]></description><category domain="">dirt bag</category><category domain="">khloe kardashian</category><category domain="">lamar odom</category><category domain="">justin bieber</category><category domain="">michael fassbender</category><category domain="">rosario dawson</category><category domain="">betty white</category><category domain="">neil patrick harris</category><category domain="">melissa joan hart</category><category domain="">bea arthur</category><category domain="">bradley cooper</category><category domain="">colin hanks</category><category domain="">tom hanks</category><category domain="">courtney love</category><category domain="">rita wilson</category><category domain="">molly ringwald</category><category domain="">celebrity</category><category domain="">gossip</category><category domain="">roundup</category><category domain="">tweet</category><category domain="">fb</category><category domain="">gettypic</category><category domain="">top</category><pubDate>Wed, 3 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993386</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Laura Beck]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Misguided Campaign to 'Bring Back the Afro']]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993349/the-misguided-campaign-to-bring-back-the-afro</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jf9wj5yua05jpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">When is a compliment not really a compliment? When is praise not really praise? Here's a hint: When you're a white man reminiscing about the good old days, when black people wore Afros. Yeah...no. Talk about reducing something complex to something simple. </p>
<p>Yesterday on Slate, Simon Doonan <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/life/doonan/2013/04/pam_grier_s_afro_let_s_bring_it_back.html" target="_blank">posted</a> a piece titled &quot;Bring Back the Afro.&quot; He'd recently spent time watching Pam Grier movies on YouTube in advance of interviewing her, and felt a mix of nostalgia, admiration and awe for her hairdo, writing:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In Scream, Blacula, Scream, Pam's 'fro is short and tight and neat as a pin. In Coffy, it's longer and more dandelion-shaped. In both instances it is an object of beauty, even when there are razor blades nestling in its recesses.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Doonan went on to mention '70s icons like Marsha Hunt, Angela Davis and Kathleen Cleaver, and waxed longingly:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The afro had it all: It was natural, symbolic, regal, unisex, and glamorous. Liberated from the costly and time-consuming burden of trying to make their hair resemble that of white folk, black chicks-and dudes-had found the perfect marriage of style and practicality. And yet … styles change, and fashion evolves, and the afro has-with the exception of occasional retro-hipster sighting on Broadway below Eighth Street-become as rare as a dodo.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>RECORD SCRATCH. Doonan lives in New York, where a veritable <em>ton</em> of people are embracing natural hair, be it a TWA (<a href="http://pinterest.com/maneandchic/twa-hairstyles/" target="_blank">teeny weeny afro</a>) or a larger, fluffy 'fro. From Harlem to Clinton Hill and Fort Greene and beyond, natural hair is all over this town. Not to mention being celebrated on <a href="http://www.npr.org/2012/06/14/154512570/my-kinky-relationship-with-the-teeny-weenie-afro" target="_blank">NPR</a> and online, on sites like <a href="http://lecoil.com/" target="_blank">Le Coil</a>, <a href="http://www.curlynikki.com" target="_blank">Curly Nikki</a>, <a href="http://naturalblkgirlsrock.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Natural Hair Rules</a>, and <a href="http://blackgirllonghair.com/" target="_blank">Black Girl Long Hair</a>. Hell, there was a <a href="http://madamenoire.com/266278/going-natural-and-making-money-sxsw-panel-talks-natural-hair-and-social-media/" target="_blank">SXSW panel</a> about natural hair. And if you're not paying attention to the regular people around you, what about the famous folks?</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jexmq5v04xojpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jetc24v4deijpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p>Fairly well-known: philosopher/academic/activist/author Cornel West, who graduated from Harvard in 1973 and earned his PhD. at Princeton. Grammy-award winning musician Esperanza Spaulding, personally selected by President Obama to play the Nobel Peace Prize Concert. Solange, DJ/singer/sister of Beyoncé. Ahmir Khalib Thompson, aka Questlove, drummer/music journalist/producer who plays with The Roots on TV every damn night. All with afros. Rare as a dodo? The dodo is <em>extinct</em>. So not quite. Doonan also bragged that he'd bought a box of Afro picks. How exotic.</p>
<p>The post generated quite a bit of noise on Twitter, with NPR's Gene Demby <a href="https://twitter.com/GeeDee215/status/319126289653055488" target="_blank">sighing</a> that Doonan was &quot;describing human beings like David Attenborough on [the] Nature channel.&quot; Demby took a <a ref="https://twitter.com/GeeDee215/status/319124072397148160" target="_blank">few jabs</a> at Doonan, while insisting</p>
<div class="twitter-embed">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" width="486">
<p>There's no way you can live in NYC and not see little/big/colored/lush 'fros everywhere. Like, this cat has NEVER been to Brooklyn? Ever?</p>
— Gene Demby (G.D.) (@GeeDee215) <a href="https://twitter.com/GeeDee215/status/319118913222889473" target="_blank">April 2, 2013</a></blockquote>
<!-- Removed script --></div>
<div class="twitter-embed">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" width="486">
<p>As far as I can tell, going natural and growing your hair out is some kind of college-educated Negress rite of passage.</p>
— Gene Demby (G.D.) (@GeeDee215) <a href="https://twitter.com/GeeDee215/status/319118703327342592" target="_blank">April 2, 2013</a></blockquote>
<!-- Removed script --></div>
<div class="twitter-embed">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" width="486">
<p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/therealsheba" target="_blank">therealsheba</a> In Brooklyn's middle-class Negro set, it's probably safe to say that natural styles are the default.</p>
— Gene Demby (G.D.) (@GeeDee215) <a href="https://twitter.com/GeeDee215/status/319120974870097920" target="_blank">April 2, 2013</a></blockquote>
<!-- Removed script --></div>
<div class="twitter-embed">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" width="486">
<p>Hell, over at the Root —- in Slate's office —- @<a href="https://twitter.com/ko_616" target="_blank">ko_616</a> has the biggest Afro in the world.</p>
— Gene Demby (G.D.) (@GeeDee215) <a href="https://twitter.com/GeeDee215/status/319116810358235138" target="_blank">April 2, 2013</a></blockquote>
<!-- Removed script --></div>
<p>Akoto Ofori-Atta also responded:</p>
<div class="twitter-embed">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" width="486">
<p>Hey, @<a href="https://twitter.com/simondoonan" target="_blank">simondoonan</a>! FYI. Nearly every black girl in Brooklyn, Philly, DC etc. has an afro. Including two blk girls at the @<a href="https://twitter.com/slate" target="_blank">slate</a> NY office.</p>
— Akoto Ofori-Atta (@KO_616) <a href="https://twitter.com/KO_616/status/319119963430453248" target="_blank">April 2, 2013</a></blockquote>
<!-- Removed script --></div>
<p>But above and beyond quibbling about how popular natural hair is now (because the answer is: VERY, and there are Afros EVERYWHERE, even the <em>Sports Illustrated</em> <a href="http://sportsillustrated.cnn.com/2013_swimsuit/models/adaora/13_adaora_1.html" target="_blank">swimsuit issue</a>), the problem with Doonan's piece is that he genuinely thinks he's being nice by praising the afro. Is he allowed to think it's a cool hairstyle? Absolutely. But a white man asking black people to wear their hair in a way that pleases him? That's not right. Doonan is unaware of his privilege, and not taking into account how deeply political and culturally charged black hair is.</p>
<p>When he writes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It is impossible to imagine Beyoncé or Kerry Washington or Michelle Obama rocking a Pam Grier afro today (though Beyoncé paid a retro-camp tribute to the style in the 2002 Austin Powers movie). The alternatives-$2,000 weaves, time-consuming blowouts, and scalp-searing chemical processing-seem infinitely less desirable, and yet, African-Americans have largely turned their backs on the freaky 'fro. But what does this honky know?</p>
</blockquote>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="300" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jf23r2u2owjjpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></p><p>Beyoncé wore an Afro wig. And she has done <a href="http://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/actress-recording-artist-beyonce-knowles-attends-the-film-news-photo/1155706" target="_blank">big, curly hair</a>. Kerry Washington had a pseudo-fro in <em>Save the Last Dance</em>. Michelle Obama has been <a href="http://jezebel.com/5895697/if-michelle-obama-had-natural-hair">discussed</a> and <a href="http://jezebel.com/5352094/keeping-michelles-hair-in-perspective">discussed</a> and <a href="http://jezebel.com/5347059/combing-through-the-deeply-rooted-politics-of-black-hair-issues">discussed</a>, and you know what? It's fair to doubt that the President would win an election if his wife had an afro. Imagine the headlines, the conservatives, the speculation. She's been called militant the way she is and her <em>bangs</em> are news. The truth is that hair sends a message. What it comes down to is this: While black people have made great strides, we are still dealing with a lot of deep racism, discrimination and intolerance. Black women have been <a href="http://www.clutchmagonline.com/2012/07/dreadlocks-are-unacceptable-for-employment-at-six-flags-and-many-other-companies/" target="_blank">denied jobs</a> for having dreadlocks. There is still an unspoken consensus that straight hair is seen as more professional. It's easy and understandable that a man who deals mainly with aesthetics would want to gush about Afros, he's right: They're awesome. But what a black woman does with her hair is deeply personal and fraught with meaning.</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" class="youtube" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/1m-4qxz08So?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0" id="youtube-1m-4qxz08So"></iframe></span></p><p>  Ultimately, the problem is that when Simon Doonan wants black people to &quot;bring back the Afro,&quot; he's ignoring the fact that it never really went away, and also acting as though an Afro is an accessory you can pick up in a boutique, like a turban or some platform heels. It's not. It's not even just a hairstyle. It's so much deeper than that. For many, the process of going natural — from the <a href="http://www.naturallycurly.com/topics/view/big-chop-transitioning" target="_blank">tough</a> decision to do <a href="http://www.essence.com/2013/01/10/hot-hair-celebrities-rocking-big-chop/" target="_blank">The Big Chop</a> to <a href="http://www.delux-mag.com/should-i-transition-or-big-chop/" target="_blank">transitioning</a> is daunting, especially in a culture that fetishizes long, silky-straight (or ever-so-slightly wavy) tresses. In Western society, our standards of beauty remain rather narrow, and the examples we hold up in magazines and on movie screens generally have straight or straightened hair. Black women who opt for natural hair do so with while being bombarded with messages that straight is better, and that black hair, in its natural state, needs fixing. Let's not forget how Don Imus infamously called the Rutgers women's basketball team &quot;nappy-headed hos,&quot; making a connection between hair and promiscuity; you'll also hear stuff like her hair is wild, unruly, she needs to &quot;tame&quot; that frizz, etc. While Gabby Douglas was competing in the Olympics, viewers <a href="http://jezebel.com/5930785/haters-need-to-shut-the-hell-up-about-gabby-douglass-hair">criticized her hair</a>'s lack of smoothness. Consciously or unconsciously, black hair is considered savage by those who don't have it and those who have been taught to hate it. Chris Rock's documentary <em>Good Hair</em> shed some light on how black women have been convinced that their hair is not good enough the way it is. Is it any wonder that blow-outs and flat-irons and weaves are popular when women who are considered the epitome of beauty — Victoria's Secret models — all have <a href="http://vsallaccess.victoriassecret.com/supermodels/" target="_blank">long, shiny hair</a>?</p>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="300" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jf23p3qo067jpg/original.jpg" class="transform-original"/></p><p>It's fantastic when black women decide to go natural and/or wear an Afro, but Doonan should realize that for many, it's not simple and it's not easy. Picking out a fro is not for everyone, and not every hair type can <em>make</em> a good Afro. Even after Pam Grier tells him how difficult the upkeep was for her — &quot;You go to sleep looking gorgeous, and you wake up and it's all flattened on one side like a brick wall… No amount of picking is going to pull it out. You need to take a garden rake to that shit&quot; — Doonan remains insistent that &quot;the current global obsession with pin-straight hair will run its course.&quot; That would be nice. But you know, in the '70s, the Afro was a statement, linked to the civil rights movement and a reaction to oppression and the pressure to assimilate. Today's true ideal situation should not be about one particular style coming back, but about black women (and men) feeling free to do whatever they choose with their hair — and not being pressured to conform or doing it because a white man approves and thinks it's cool.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/life/doonan/2013/04/pam_grier_s_afro_let_s_bring_it_back.html" target="_blank">Bring Back the Afro</a> [Slate]</p>]]></description><category domain="">hair</category><category domain="">tress tests</category><category domain="">simon doonan</category><category domain="">afros</category><category domain="">afro</category><category domain="">black hair</category><category domain="">black people</category><category domain="">race</category><category domain="">racism</category><category domain="">shut up whitey</category><category domain="">gettypic</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Tue, 2 Apr 2013 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993349</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dodai Stewart]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[March Madness: Don't You Forget About Being King of the Spice World]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993380/march-madness-dont-you-forget-about-being-king-of-the-spice-world</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jf5myljovfkjpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">If you ever had any doubt about the legitimacy of our March Madness voting system, know this: If I was rigging these brackets, I would have never <em>ever</em> let what happened yesterday happen. Sure, the Gameboy beat the Rachel. This I can let go, but Lisa Frank beating Valley Girls? Gag me with a spoon — now I finally know how real sports feel.</p>
<p>But now on to Day 11!</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jf5ln8uoo65png/ku-xlarge.png" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p>
<associate></associate>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" class="youtube" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/e30ec_UxGFE?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0" id="youtube-e30ec_UxGFE"></iframe></span></p><p>  Today we have another couple of remarkable toughies as over in the 80s conference, the Brat Pack pits itself against the adorable pack of Huxtables from <em>The Cosby Show</em>. Sure, the Brat Pack came prepared having brought their own lunch (sushi, a bag of Matt's cookies, a quart of milk, a thermos full of soup and a pixie stick sandwich), but <em>The Cosby Show</em> has Phylicia Rashā and Rudy so it is <em>not</em> to be underestimated.</p>
<p class="has-media media-640"><span class="flex-video widescreen"><iframe mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitAllowFullScreen="webkitAllowFullScreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" class="youtube" height="360" width="640" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/lGJqhoX1WHM?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0" id="youtube-lGJqhoX1WHM"></iframe></span></p><p>  Meanwhile, over on the 90s side of the tracks, 1997 is being torn apart as <em>Titanic</em> embarks on a voyage to defeat British Girl Power quintet the Spice Girls. What do you choose? Spicing up your life or the first half of the biggest movie of the decade? (I can't be the only person who would only watch the first cassette so that things ended while Jack and Rose were both still alive and happy, can I?) This might honestly be the hardest decision that some of us will ever make.</p>
<script src="http://static.polldaddy.com/p/7009925.js"></script><br/>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/7009925/" target="_blank">80s: Brat Pack (3) vs. Cosby Show (11)</a></noscript>
<script src="http://static.polldaddy.com/p/7009930.js"></script><br/>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/7009930/" target="_blank">90s: Titanic (3) vs. Spice Girls (6)</a></noscript>]]></description><category domain="">80s vs 90s</category><category domain="">march madness</category><category domain="">top</category><pubDate>Tue, 2 Apr 2013 21:45:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993380</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Madeleine Davies]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[What to Do When the World Gets Crazy and No One Knows How to Act Anymore]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993211/what-to-do-when-the-world-gets-crazy-and-no-one-knows-how-to-act-anymore</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="363" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jeyuwgwley1jpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Interacting with humans, as someone I know pointed out recently, is &quot;gross and hard.&quot; You try your best while mitigating your own circumstances, conditions and predispositions, but nobody really knows what's going on, how they're coming off, or what delicate sensibility in someone else they've deeply offended. It's gotten harder now that we all move constantly between on- and offline worlds, so the story goes. </p><p>Being alive in the world today means navigating a fresh crop of social conundrums. This is the Wild West of socializing, so we're told, and as political correctness evolves, as more enhanced civil rights are fought for and won, as habits once considered oddities or fetishes are normalized, the newfound intersections create more and more opportunities for new-fangling, confusion, and questions as to how a person should be. In response, a flood of digital gurus has risen to help us to meet this new need and find answers. But perhaps they're revealing something deeper about our anxieties.</p>
<p>Nowadays at least, civility is less class-oriented and exclusive, and more about gestures of politeness. Things that maintain the social fabric. Etiquette is ostensibly here to make all that easier, right? Sure, if we all know the rules. But since we don't, we're left with a void in the etiquette instruction library to rival post-fire Alexandria.</p>
<p>As this <em>New York Times</em> trend piece called &quot;<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/31/fashion/etiquette-returns-for-the-digital-generation.html?ref=customsetiquetteandmanners" target="_blank">Etiquette Returns for the Digital Generation</a>,&quot; we learn that there's a slew of advice-givers coming out of the woodwork to help serve this unique need:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Are manners dead? Cellphones, Twitter and Facebook may be killing off the old civilities and good graces, but a new generation of etiquette gurus, good-manner bloggers and self-appointed YouTube arbiters is rising to make old-fashioned protocols relevant to a new generation.</p>
<p>Their apparent goal: to help members of Generation Y navigate thorny, tech-age minefields like Paperless Post invites, same-sex weddings and online dating — not to mention actual face-to-face contact with people they encounter in the offline world.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But first: Manners never died, OK? They changed. Etiquette advice of previous decades <a href="http://www.southcoasttoday.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/19970504/LIFE/305049945" target="_blank">offered</a> instruction in the newest and latest ways to embarrass and offend that were relevant then, from videoconferencing to divorce etiquette to sex in the AIDS era to how to send a legible fax.</p>
<p>Nowadays, the hot probs are different. It may be rude to stand around at a party texting on your phone ignoring your guests, but it's just as rude to ignore the text from a friend you just got asking if you can pick them up from the other party they're at, where they happen to be too drunk to drive home from that night. Something's gotta give.</p>
<p>Understanding our new modern world is certainly useful. And some of the dilemmas the <em>Times</em> chronicles are distinctly modern and useful, such as limiting one's baby photos on Instagram (and, apparently, everywhere), but others, such as how to shake hands (&quot;two or three times up and down — from the elbow and not the wrist&quot;) or how to order fast food at the drive-thru (hint: without screaming) seem obvious, the sort of thing one gleans from merely existing in the world with a human head.</p>
<p>And so in the same way products in a capitalist marketplace are designed to create a need, so does etiquette advice often inadvertently add to the very anxiety it purports to help eliminate, by filling us with example after example essentially of ways to fuck it up, many of which we'd never even considered, much less realized we were guilty of.</p>
<p>Over the course of the piece, one is left with the feeling that we are a truly anxious bunch — especially about our bodies — as offenses like farting during yoga and grunting at the gym get some play. Others require fretting over the kind of minutia only reserved for people with the kind of free time worry about stupid shit: like whether, when you're at a dinner party, and your 4-year-old is at home sick with a babysitter, you can say out loud that you're taking this incoming phone call because you have a sick kid at home. Answer: Don't.</p>
<p>Really? This kind of persnickety correctness about manners is pretentious, a kind of snobbery that defeats the purpose of actual good manners, which is making people feel comfortable and welcome no matter what predispositions or limitations they bring to the (literal) table. Surely any decent host, if you stopped to say, as your cellphone rang at dinner — <em>Sorry, have to grab this, sick kid at home</em> — would not find you rude for saying so, but perfectly polite to let people know why you'd take a call at the dinner table. Are you a human or dinner guest bot?</p>
<p>Likewise, in a viral vid (3 million views) called &quot;Don't Be That Guy at the Gym&quot; we discover that just being a noob — a person who is obviously experiencing his first time working out in public and is Doing it Wrong — is rude as fuck. Whatever shall the long-suffering noob do? Pay for private instruction first so as to avoid looking inexperienced? I genuinely don't get it.</p>
<p>Etiquette is perfectly helpful until it demands that we put more effort into perception than reality among people we allegedly want to actually be around, who allegedly actually want to be around us. Sure, try not to fart it up at yoga, but if you do have to let one go, wouldn't all be forgiven? There's no app to stop farts yet, people. No matter what we invent or dream of, the farting never goes gently into that good night.</p>
<p>Due to the ridiculousness of some of the instruction mentioned in the piece, I have to wonder whether this insurgence of etiquette &quot;help&quot; is about more than a whole crop of new people desperate not to grunt at the gym. We have an obsession with other people's foibles that the Internet feeds, the ways in which people violate the social contract, unspoken or otherwise, that we can sit back and play judge and jury about, and I think in many ways the digital influx of advice-givers exists merely because there's always more room on the Internet for another opinion. But it's also about tapping into a hive-mind solution for disconnectedness.</p>
<p>Hear me out: It speaks to our craving for the kind of order and gossip-driven policing of behavior we once got from more tightly knit communities and neighborhoods, where people knew our business, where people who knew our parents could shame us for our rebellions, our indiscretions, our wild goofs. In other words, maybe we are all just dreaming of home, of the institutions that use to finger-wag us that we have all but escaped.</p>
<p>As adults, we often move away from that nest on purpose, and recreate our own communities, but often without anywhere near the familiarity or intimacy of our families of origin. Plus, we feel — whether it's really true or not, grand scheme — that we are living in a time of truly rapid change. Rules and their constant reinforcement alleviates that anxiety about the ambiguity of these new intersections and helps order our world again.</p>
<p>Sometimes, it orders our sense of class, or satisfies our curiosities about other classes, as in this &quot;useful&quot; advice from Randi Zuckerberg, sister of Mark, that is bound to come up for everyone at some point or another:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;Many of these emerging etiquette issues are complicated because there are no clear-cut, black-and-white answers,&quot; Ms. Zuckerberg said. A recent post on Dot Complicated dealt with how to respond to a request for money, something that Ms. Zuckerberg, C.E.O. of Zuckerberg Media, said she has had to deal with quite frequently. (Her advice: &quot;Say no and say it quickly.&quot;)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Noted! It can also order our sense of gender. Women have historically been the guardians and enforcers of etiquette. From Emily Post to the mostly female advice columnists of the previous handful of decades, women have been considered the foremost authority on what to do, how to do it, and who it's OK to do it with.</p>
<p>And while they are still at the forefront of the trend — the piece says women have shown a &quot;new interest in manners,&quot; and there's a Jane Austen descendent quoted in there somewhere among many other lady advice-givers— that men are finally joining this tidal wave of unspoken anxiety over implied expectation with advice on gentlemanly behavior at least speaks to our ever-growing equality as genders.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;We're living in an age of anxiety that's a reflection of the near-constant change and confusion in technology and social mores,&quot; said Steven Petrow, an author of five etiquette books including &quot;Mind Your Digital Manners: Advice for an Age Without Rules,&quot; to be published in 2014. (Mr. Petrow is a regular contributor to <em>The New York Times</em>, writing an advice column on gay-straight issues for the Booming blog.)</p>
<p>&quot;Whether it's wondering how many times it is acceptable to text a date before being seen as a stalker, or what the role of parents is at a same-sex wedding,&quot; he said, &quot;etiquette gurus are popping out from under tablecloths everywhere to soothe all those living in fear of newfangled faux pas.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>All this direction IS helpful, to a point. But the only rule you can count on is that there really are no rules. My friend said you can never wear a tube top to a funeral, but I bet you could if the funeral was being held for the creator of the tube top.</p>
<p>And therein lies the rub: just as we need to be reminded of manners, we need to be reminded of their fluidity and situational application. Just don't get too tangled in the newfangled. Underneath the hermetically sealed correctness of how to act among strangers and friends in our modern crazy world, there should always be room for the well-meaning goofs of our guests, who are, after all, just people.</p>
<p>Sure, we can all be nicer and less offensive. That would help. But we also all know that the Internet has made everyone a big bunch of bumbling, distracted people in many ways, and that it's unlikely to get anything but worse. And so collectively, we can all try to be better, but we can also recognize that at worst, we all stand guilty of the same thing: trying to tend to both worlds simultaneously when no one is actually a good multitasker. This understanding — this space to be the people we all are now doing the things we do, acknowledging we're all guilty — is also a form of etiquette. Just one that rarely gets mentioned.</p>]]></description><category domain="">etiquette</category><category domain="">digital etiquette gurus</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Tue, 2 Apr 2013 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993211</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Moore ]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Ruthless Kiss-and-Tell World of College Hookup Websites]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5992952/the-ruthless-game-of-kiss+and+tell-on-college-hookup-websites</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jemp9f01gz4jpg/ku-xlarge.jpg" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Thanks to humankind's fondness for both talking and humping, we've been gossiping about sex from the moment we were socially able to do so. But — as we know — the internet changes everything, including campus culture, where gossiping about sex has become a dedicated online pastime. Judging by the rising popularity of college hookup websites, Consent 2.0 might have to go beyond &quot;this is what I'm comfortable doing, physically,&quot; to include, &quot;please don't brag about my oral sex skills — or lament my lack thereof — on Facebook to thousands of my peers.&quot; That seems unlikely. </p>
<p>UC Berkeley Hookups is a Facebook page that allows students to anonymously dish about their sexual exploits — it's received some <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/07/uc-berkeley-hook-ups_n_2791550.html" target="_blank">media attention</a> as of late, since sex + coeds will always = googly-eyed readers. But there are tons of other colleges with similar Facebook pages and Twitter feeds to their name: UCSB Hookups has over 8,000 likes (UC Berkeley's page has around 3,000) while USC Hookups has nearly 1,700. All &quot;Hookups&quot; pages have a fair number of racist, sexist and homophobic posts, most comments detail how blacked-out one or both parties were at the time, and some of the people being discussed seem rather identifiable.</p>
<p>From <a href="https://www.facebook.com/SBhookups" target="_blank">UCSB Hookups</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To the girl named Yiselle that I've met once and have seen at the sueno frat house quite a few times. I think you are one of the most beautiful girls I have ever met and you have a set of amazing boobs. Every time I see you, you are dancing with your girl friends. I would do anything to not only dance with you but to fuck you all night long while I suck on your huge titties. Let me know if you're interested ;)</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Dear marissa (i think thats what it was... ik it started with an m),<br/>
You crazy motherfucker. We were both at DP and im pretty sure i saw you hookup with a few other dudes earlier that night, but once i saw your sexy ass body i knew you were mine. We were both beyond gone when we started hooking up.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I met this guy named Cal at a party a few weeks back. He was really shy but had a really great sense of humor and he liked the same music as me. We went back to his apartment, and right as we were about to fuck, we walk in on his roomate giving his black girlfriend what she referred to as his 'strong seven'. i was quite frightened and ran all the way back to my apartment. Cal, will you contact me somehow?</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>This past Friday I was shit faced and looking to fuck. I plucked this cute little drunk girl from a party to come back to my place. We started making out on my deck then as I was fingering her I realized I had gotten blood all over me. At this point she was falling over and being a sloppy mess so I carried her into my house, threw her on my couch and went to grab a burrito. In her drunken slumber she started moaning and screaming so loud-it was so funny they started filming her for their enjoyment. We all went to bed and in the morning she was gone and all I had to remember her by was a puddle on my couch. She left her purse, phone &amp; keys and the next day we were anticipating her royal arrival but she was too embarrassed and sent her roommate instead. Random girl: I'm not asking you clean my couch, just come back and claim your dignity.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>From <a href="https://www.facebook.com/UCBhookups?ref=ts&amp;fref=ts" target="_blank">UC Berkeley Hookups</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To the Norwegian chick i met at FIJI, doing blow off each other was great....especially when you did it off my dick with your mouth following by giving me the best head Ive had in past weekends. I think your name was Line.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Dear DKE boy,<br/>
You were the only guy around so I agreed to dance with you even though I was towering over you. I didn't even mind when you started grabbing my ass in a pretty sexual way. But what the hell were you doing when you reached up my dress?! Your finger felt like a spastic shovel digging through my vag. And when I pulled away, it wasn't because I felt violated it was because I felt like your jagged nails were going to ruin by precious puss you petite prick! Please learn how to properly finger fuck, you're giving yourself and your frat a bad rep.<br/>
Never yours,<br/>
Girl in dress.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>From <a href="https://www.facebook.com/UscHookUp?fref=ts" target="_blank">USC Hookups</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>...lotta of shots deep. As I am rising in the elevator, thoughts in my head were confused. Its not that I didnt get any pussy, I just didnt find the right opportunity to get my shit innnn. Entering my friends dorm, girls in the bathroom ya know puking and shit.. I go to sit on the couch by one of the girls that was supposably passed out. In the middle of a drunk convo, the girl would not stop pushing me with her feet, so I grabbed her ankle like a BOSS, letting her know that I noticed her noticing me. I tell my friend &quot;get out of the room right now.&quot; as he lays on the ground he mumbles &quot;handle it bro, handle it.&quot; once i told him hes a dick, I cuddling behind the girl.. well you know the rest ;) #ThatJustHappened #TurnUp</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Gwen, you absolutely made my night at the Beta registered. It was damn hot in there but we made it so much hotter; my neck was sore the next day from constantly tilting to the left. I think most people prefer the right, but I'm left handed you see.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>To the short Chinese guy in the cinematic school, you gave me the worst sex ever. SERIOUSLY. practice... Also, shave your beard please.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Outraged students are fighting back via a variety of tactics, from launching <a href="https://www.facebook.com/UCBConsent/info" target="_blank">UC Berkeley Consent</a>, which features &quot;anonymous consensual stories about hooking up&quot; (uh, but did both people consent to the telling that followed the kissing?) to pressuring the administration to take action.</p>
<p>USC's Undergraduate Student Government <a href="http://dailytrojan.com/2013/03/26/usg-urges-end-to-usc-hookups/" target="_blank">unanimously voted</a> last week &quot;to pass a resolution that mandates the university administration to actively investigate the Facebook page USC Hook-Ups and determine what further action is needed to address the negative impacts of the page.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;One of my problems with this page is that the negative material posted is celebrated and rarely contested,&quot; Assistant Director of the Women's Student Assembly Anh Phan told <em>The Daily Trojan</em>. &quot;This page contains the most horrific conversations between students and other Facebook users and paints a negative portrait of our university.&quot;</p>
<p>The resolution argues that &quot;the derogatory and explicit nature of the posts on the page is detrimental to the image of the university&quot; since it's publicly viewable, and that the page doesn't support the USC Code of Conduct's Policy and Procedures on Sexual Misconduct and Sexual Assault since a startling number of posts describe possible sexual assault (and underage drinking/super drunken sex).</p>
<p>The core problem with these sites is that they discourage actual communication between sexual partners in favor of bragging (and, let's be real, probably lying) to strangers. But since most universities are too busy battling allegations that they <a href="http://jezebel.com/5986693/college-rape-survivor-faces-potential-expulsion-for-intimidating-her-rapist">mishandled sexual assault reports</a> or <a href="http://jezebel.com/5988325/princeton-buries-rape-survey-report-only-to-have-it-leaked-later?tag=princeton">burying rape surveys</a> to tackle unsavory Facebook pages — and given the typical, disappointing administrative response — or lack thereof — to similar issues (<a href="http://jezebel.com/5965733/oberlin-has-a-nasty-anonymous-message-board-problem">Oberlin's message board drama</a> and <a href="http://jezebel.com/5992821/towson-university-says-its-unofficial-white-student-union-is-protected-by-free-speech">Towson University's &quot;White Student Union&quot;</a> come to mind) — we wouldn't hold our breath waiting for officials or Facebook (ha!) to try and protect students' privacy. Changing campus culture is hard enough; asking anonymous people to be less crappy is near impossible.</p>]]></description><category domain="">college</category><category domain="">sex</category><category domain="">uc berkeley hookups</category><category domain="">facebook</category><category domain="">usc</category><category domain="">ucsb</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Tue, 2 Apr 2013 17:50:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5992952</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Katie J.M. Baker]]></dc:creator></item><item><title><![CDATA[He Has OCD and Aspergers, and He Wants to Fall in Love With You]]></title><link>http://jezebel.com/5993284/he-has-ocd-and-aspergers-and-he-wants-to-fall-in-love-with-you</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="has-media media-640"><img height="360" width="640" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18jeanodkg8m7png/ku-xlarge.png" class="transform-ku-xlarge"/></p><p class="first-text">Everyone has baggage. Some of us have heaps and heaps of matching luggage we tote with us everywhere we go; some of us have suitcases of issues that seem small but weigh us down; many of us have quirks and idiosyncrasies that swing between annoying and charming. And then there are those of us who have mental and psychological diagnoses that are no fault of our own, but impact relationships. Take Dan, who recently applied to take part in the <em>New York Post</em>'s Meet Market dating column. Right away, he disclosed his situation: He has OCD and Aspergers. </p>
<p>Jozen Cummings, who runs the Meet Market column, has a personal site, Until I Get Married, where he wrote about <a href="http://untiligetmarried.com/2013/02/24/everyone-deserves-a-date-including-a-guy-named-dan/" target="_blank">his first encounter</a> with Dan:</p>
<p class="has-media media-300"><img height="471" width="300" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/18je5rmudts9djpg/ku-medium.jpg" class="transform-ku-medium"/></p>
<blockquote>
<p>He was nerd-ish, badly dressed, with thick, black-rimmed eye glasses. He looked like a shorter version of Adam Levine if Adam Levine had a Forrest Gump-like haircut. None of this seemed out of the ordinary. What did seem peculiar was his slow, very slow, walk. I never waited so long for someone to get through the security gate. I felt rude for walking at a normal pace.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Dan informed Cummings about his situation right away, explaining:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>My condition makes it really hard for me to make even the easiest decisions. And I know some women are dominant, but they still want a man who takes charge. I'm not that kind of guy. It takes me forever to make a decision.</p>
<p>I wanted to sign up for this because it's pretty hard for me to meet women the normal way… I don't like clubs or places with loud music and approaching a girl doesn't work too well for me either. I will try to say this in the questionnaire, but I want you to tell whoever you set me up with about my condition. Oh, and I haven't been in a relationship since I was 19.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Dan also specified that he thinks a younger woman would be best: &quot;I know I'm 36 years old, but I might need someone who is around 23,&quot; he told Cummings. &quot;My therapist says since I have such inexperience with love and relationships, a woman that age might be better suited for me.&quot; Plus: &quot;I just want someone who isn't going to run if they see me reacting to my OCD or the Asperger's. I want someone who believes I can get better.&quot;</p>
<p>Cummings appreciated Dan's candor, and felt moved to help him. Usually the Meet Market dates are not about matchmaking — it's just about fun. But &quot;Dan is different,&quot; Cummings wrote.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>After he left, it was hard for me to shake the look on his face when he was telling me about all the problems he's had with dating and meeting women. He told me everything without a trace of self-pity, in a very-matter-of-fact tone, and the more I thought about his story the more I wanted to help him. Here was a guy who knew he had real mental challenges, but no longer wanted to be imprisoned by them.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This all happened weeks ago, but Cummings still hasn't found a woman for Dan. Since today is <a href="http://www.autismspeaks.org/what-autism/world-autism-awareness-day" target="_blank">World Autism Day</a>, Cummings has <a href="https://twitter.com/jozenc/status/319056136412200960" target="_blank">tweeted</a> that he is still trying to make a match.</p>
<p>Dan's situation stirs up mixed emotions: On the one hand, novels, romcoms and the Vows section of the <em>Times</em> can convince you that love is best when it's serendipitous. We're hooked on the meet cute: Reaching for the same book in the bookstore, bumping into each other on the bus. Does disclosing Asperger syndrome (or depression, or bulimia, or commitmentphobia, or other various challenges) right off the bat mean you give up on some of the magic? Falling in love is often marked by discovery and surprise, the lightning bolt or Cupid's arrow <em>thwack</em> of suddenly overwhelming emotions. The heart-fluttering pleasure of bonding, getting to know someone. Matchmakers and online dating sites can get you face to face with a potential mate, but whether or not you click — the chemistry — is all about peeling away layers and admiring the person more and more with each reveal. On the other hand, by getting the Asperger's out of the way, Dan can meet someone interested in his <em>other</em> aspects. (For instance, he holds a Master's in Education and has a certification to teach Social Studies.)</p>
<p>Maybe we should all be more honest about who we are and what we want when it comes to finding romance. Being open with your issues may mean that some people don't want to date you. That's fine. After all, Dan — like any single person searching for love — doesn't need a swarm of potential dates. Just one really good one will do. There's a lesson here, about being open-minded, open-hearted, and comfortable with the fact that <em>any</em> relationship has challenges, obstacles, compromises…and rewards. As Dan puts it:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I see all these people get to experience love, and it's like this chocolate bar, but I can't have it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Yet.</p>
<p><a href="http://untiligetmarried.com/2013/02/24/everyone-deserves-a-date-including-a-guy-named-dan/" target="_blank">Everyone Deserves A Date, Including a Guy Named Dan</a> [Until I Get Married]<br/>
<a href="http://untiligetmarried.com/2013/03/14/i-still-need-help-getting-dan-a-date/" target="_blank">A Picture of Dan to Help me #GetDanADate</a> [Until I Get Married]<br/>
<a href="http://www.nypost.com/dating" target="_blank">Meet Market</a> [NY Post]</p>
<p><em><small>Top illustration by Jim Cooke, Photo of Dan by Jennifer Polixenni Brankin/NY Post</small></em></p>]]></description><category domain="">dating</category><category domain="">autism</category><category domain="">aspergers</category><category domain="">ocd</category><category domain="">adhd</category><category domain="">meet market</category><category domain="">ny post</category><category domain="">love</category><category domain="">top</category><category domain="">fb</category><pubDate>Tue, 2 Apr 2013 15:50:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5993284</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dodai Stewart]]></dc:creator></item></channel></rss>