<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >

<channel><title><![CDATA[&nbsp; www.theamendment.net &nbsp; - HOME]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/index.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[HOME]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 08:29:25 -0600</pubDate><generator>Weebly</generator><item><title><![CDATA[ Work & Downloads]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/work-downloads.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/work-downloads.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 17:57:41 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/work-downloads.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I heard a rumour that some spirits incarnate to earth to do less work. Because life in the afterlife is so busy, compared to living a human life on earth? 2) What roles and responsibilities do spirits usually have in the afterlife? 3) Are there schools of education in the afterlife where one would go for example to learn how to communicate with humans?&n [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="font-size: 18px; line-height: 18px;">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I heard a rumour that some spirits incarnate to earth to do less work. Because life in the afterlife is so busy, compared to living a human life on earth? 2) What roles and responsibilities do spirits usually have in the afterlife? 3) Are there schools of education in the afterlife where one would go for example to learn how to communicate with humans?&nbsp;</em><em style="font-size: 18px; line-height: 18px;">Or is the information downloaded from source 'Johnny Mnemonic' style? </em><span style="font-size: 18px; line-height: 18px;">(</span><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johnny_Mnemonic_(film))" style="font-size: 18px; line-height: 18px;">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johnny_Mnemonic_(film))</a><em style="font-size: 18px; line-height: 18px;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</em><div><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;Work, as you understand, is activity. Activity as work includes a perception of time; your days and the cycles limit activity; essentials for bodily function such as food and rest and the common but not vital, such as bathing and maintenance of dwellings, these serve to limit activity humans deem &lsquo;work&rsquo;.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  There is no time defined by daylight, darkness and their cycles, what activity is chosen is not measured in these segments or subunits. The concept of less by incarnation applies not.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  There are incarnations to change activity in a related area, the activity on Earth to serve a purpose chosen and pursued in Heaven as the purpose relates to human life and this is common a purpose to assist humanity, very common.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  The notion of busy as it compares to relaxed is not a Heavenly relation; these two things do not define and separate in the on or off, up or down, left &amp; right way many things on Earth are seen by all of you.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  2) The afterlife of your true home is so much more complex and intricate than Earth, we do say we cannot this answer. Allow us to say there are many, many more souls related to you, and of you and knowing of you on Earth than are located in body on the surface with you. Your Earth population many, many times over is what the immediacy of Heaven is, as it could apply to Earth. There is no limit to activity, no constraint of resource as you would say; there are not social classes, races, geographical limits and no political understandings in any way that limit activity and with certainty we say, the distinct and categorized types of activity are, in addition to the vastly greater number of souls, vastly more varied, nuanced and diverse by comparison to Earth.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  3) Schools of all types there are; and frequent is the lecture, the conference and the presentation. These have the nature of a concert or show as you understand them. No tedium is there in them; popularity of such concert allows as many shows, episodes or permutations as there appear viewers desiring to attend. There can be one hundred thousand attending yet the closeness and intimacy felt by each will be as you on Earth would feel in a presentation to fifty show goers.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  There is no need to learn to communicate with humans; you are us and we are you and we both do this automatically and naturally. The difference is Earth recognition of the communications sent; all that you think, think to us and say to us, write to us and aim our way, we hear. We hear it all. We love it as we love you.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  Yes, information can be &ldquo;downloaded&rdquo; as you say, yet this implies a repository of data then copied or given access from the destination location. The information you create, store and transmit for Earth use is this way, yet no download need there be from Heaven; the information is permanent and available to anyone interested, and this includes all of you. Your Guardian Angel Guides will provide to you all you might need or want, no download necessary. You gain access and use directly.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  Good day!&rdquo;&nbsp;<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span></div></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ TUNING IN]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/tuning-in.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/tuning-in.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 20:20:25 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/tuning-in.html</guid><description><![CDATA[  [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class='imgPusher' style='float:left;height:0px'></span><span style='z-index:10;position:relative;float:left;;clear:left;margin-top:0px;*margin-top:0px'><a><img src="http://www.theamendment.net/uploads/8/0/3/0/8030819/4165433.jpg?165" style="margin-top: 5px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 10px; border-width:1px;padding:3px;" alt="Picture" class="galleryImageBorderBlack" /></a><div style="display: block; font-size: 90%; margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: 10px; text-align: center;"></div></span> <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;display:block;"><em style="">Q: &nbsp; &nbsp;What do I need to do to become more in tune with the universe and my guides? I want to receive communication from them, but don't know if it is not allowed, or if I am just not able to tune in properly? Is there anything specific to me that you can impart?&nbsp;</em><br /><br />A: &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;You are in tune with the universe; perfect tune. You do receive information from them; they do not supply it like a person walking down the street and do not appear (<em style="">not often anyway</em>) like a teacher before a class, but the information comes by&nbsp;bucketfuls.<br /><br />Specifically you can separate your thoughts from your GAGs (<em style="">Guardian Angels and Guides; Guardian Angels as permanent caretakers, Guides as linked to a specific task, project or undertaking</em>)<br /><br />To listen you concentrate; your thoughts and the information must be sifted apart; imagine just this: a screen type sifter out of which falls the flour into two piles. They look the same, they seem the same but they are not. How do you know they are not the same; by RECOGNIZING they are not the same. Understanding they are different; baking soda, powdered salt, bleached flour and confectioner's sugar might all look the same, even close up. Mixed together, does not them the same make.<br /><br />Once you recognize your information comes to your mind just as that same mind - YOU - use the brain to process down to the body YOUR ideas and thoughts; that these things are all together - but - are - different; THEN the&nbsp;differences&nbsp;will be seen.<br /><br />Practice slowly and steadily; no deadline exists. There is no exam, no test and no grade for speed. The separation is there and it will become open and obvious as you practice looking for it.<br /><br />Often, when you have a quiet moment, think of the split, consider the spread, ask for the question to appear in your head (<em>The Committee is in a rhyming, poetic mood today</em>) The answer will occur to you like your own thought. It is NOT; this is communication and information from the universe. Look not upon a psychic or medium or channel of talent to expect to be this way; you are NOT that person any more than they are you; so you can be different. You are.<br /><br />Have you ever started out the door and&nbsp;suddenly&nbsp;had a hard thought of leaving behind keys/pen/purse/letter/package/cup/lunch/hat/what-have-you? We all have. This sudden and clear recall of something you would forget, this is INFORMATION coming from your GAGs. This sensation is an example we all know and have. When this sensation comes with ease and along with any&nbsp;questions&nbsp;you have asked, you have just heard your GAGs loud and clear.<br /><br />Start with quick answers; soon the longer answers will come automatically and just as easily. Long complex answers will arrive just as does the thought "house key".<br /><br />Good cake making, bakers!&nbsp;<br /></div> <hr style="width:100%;clear:both;visibility:hidden;"></hr>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ Awakened People]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/awakened-people.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/awakened-people.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 19:42:47 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/awakened-people.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Could The Committee be asked about "awakened" people. I use the term awaken to describe understanding, more or less, of what the big picture is all about, that might know about truths of the soul and reincarnation, spirit guides, etc. There are those "asleep" their whole lives and remain unaware of these topics. Could they be described as bei [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="font-size: 18px; line-height: 18px;">Q: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Could The Committee be asked about "awakened" people. I use the term awaken to describe understanding, more or less, of what the big picture is all about, that might know about truths of the soul and reincarnation, spirit guides, etc. There are those "asleep" their whole lives and remain unaware of these topics. Could they be described as being atheist, religious, agnostics or anyone who doesn't believe or consider the true nature of the soul? We incarnate for experiences, lessons, soul contracts, etc. People "asleep" for the course of a lifetime learn and have experiences, none the wiser of their soul's nature. Those who "awaken" at some point I would liken to playing a game, suddenly realizing they are playing while the rest believe it real. What is the purpose - if any - for those who "awaken" compared to others who remain "asleep?" Is it part of a life plan to awaken?&nbsp;</em><br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;We say, we do see your vibrations; no pulling clothes up or down to cover them, we see them always. Worry not they are beautiful. Even you who read these words, your vibrations are seen. We ask you to imagine a universe of voyeurs and thus Heaven you do see.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We thank you for so cutting an insight and say, you nearly answer your questions as you pose them. We expand; thank you.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  All of your surroundings are real; your life on Earth a subset. Creation of these surroundings is by your doing, but you do not remember the collective effort. You are a part of it, by your presence on Earth alone and for many of you, as active creators of the Earth as she was brought into existence as you now have her. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  As we say often, you are standing behind a thick yet transparent veil; to be unaware of your place is well described by your word &ldquo;asleep&rdquo; but this break in your conscious state is not so sharp. Awake and asleep are distinct; separate. Divided. Your sensations of sleep as adventure and relief and a place to go, and its permanent need and use as you live in a body; this is an intentional unawareness but it is only a relative disconnect; it can be modified and for this you have done many things, such as come here.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Acceptance and rejection of Earth religions is all awareness; we say rejection of the concept of an afterlife, as would be understood by the atheist idea, is recognition of religion as an Earth body of ideas and traditions with a basis in what awaits. Many of this way of belief see the twist of interpretation a religion asks followers to believe. By stating there is no afterlife, correctly this recognizes the afterlife could be as a religion might depict but is far greater and not as the religion portrays. True, it is not as the religion portrays and so rejection is correct. Observance of the smile of joy and glee as these rejectors pass on to rediscover, this is a true visit to the candy store of Heaven for all of us to see.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Adherents to organized religions of popularity also see a truth yet accept the portions a system offers. This is also accurate but the joy is also seen upon discovery of the size, depth width and weight of Heaven as compared to the human offered version of ideas.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The purpose of awakening is to broaden your understanding of your life; you awaken not to be anything other than more efficient at achieving what you planned; there is no greater mystery and no formula, no method of a magician in this.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  To make others aware is not and never to proselytize; that is what a religion or cult or tribe could want. We see never to point, direct, command and instruct for you to follow, obey and comply. We hold out flashlights and torches with love for you all and each shall see what is shown. You shall decide what you might. Success is view; progress is thought. There is no correctness of idea, wrongness of thought. We hope to always make this understood; as your knowledge and awareness of who you truly are &ndash; for it is vastly more rich and complex than the body standing before the mirror you see &ndash; you enjoy more the place you now fill. No desire to leave do we want; happiness of challenge we hope to see, for in these things you shall and do grow and become ever greater.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We like this idea of playing a game but differ in the result. The winning of prizes the games might supply is good yet quite small by the size of the goal you will always achieve by your life where you are. In this we say no game there is, for serious and fun is what life is for you.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Know we are here and ask for our help; smell all good roses and never the kelp. Poetry opens the door to the knowledge of the Heavens, the song of the tune the sound of your soul.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Your life plan can include this rise in the awareness yet we say, this is one thing possible in all lives; all plans. No detour would there be for a divergence to awareness of Heaven and your true self; to the contrary, these things can only assist.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We know what awaits and some of you, too. Earth will now change, it&rsquo;s not overdue. Knowing what&rsquo;s here and helping all others will lift you up high as each other&rsquo;s brother. Sibling we&rsquo;d say but it rhymed not so well, yet we know you do think what we wished to you tell.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Ask for our presence request all the signs; gladly we&rsquo;ll sell and all of the time. No price will be charged your soul is yours free, we invest our great riches as we follow your spree. Your days blend together, your life they do form, awareness lifts up it&rsquo;s truly the norm. Know you&rsquo;re with friends, there is no alone, we follow your travels, around every stone.&nbsp; Play the game well, cheat at the rules, gain what you can, behave like a fool. Creation offends, compliance does not, following others fills not your pot. We say there is structure, it provides certainty but live your ideas, please watch where you pee.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We&rsquo;ve blathered a bit, spoken too long, we bid all farewell from this paper song.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Be open!&rdquo; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ Productive Earth]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/productive-earth.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/productive-earth.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 16:14:27 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/productive-earth.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How can I make the best use of this incarnation? Do you read the vibration of the asker as you answer?    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;You already make best use of the incarnation; there is no qualification. No grades, standards, criteria or minimums apply. We say,  [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="font-size: 18px; line-height: 18px;">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How can I make the best use of this incarnation? Do you read the vibration of the asker as you answer?</em><br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;You already make best use of the incarnation; there is no qualification. No grades, standards, criteria or minimums apply. We say, imagine yourself before a store filled with objects of your liking; it could be jewelry, clothing, motorcycles or tools; musical instruments any things of your interest and enjoyment. As you peer through the windows, you are suddenly given an enormous sum of money to enter and buy as many of these things you see, under one condition, you must spend all of it in this store. You may not leave until you have done this, and you may only take these things when there is too little money remaining to buy anything else. How would you consider your choices to be &ldquo;best use&rdquo;? Why would a fine wristwatch of rose colored gold be better than its twin of white? A red car better than yellow? These would be your preferences; and no self judgment of better or less would there be.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Cast aside earthly ideas of money; as you stand before this store coming from elsewhere, on your way to wherever, you stopped a moment to gaze; the store likes this and has windows for just as you do, does it not? The money given suddenly, without warning, expectations or conditions other than be spent in this store, this was not requested; it has no requirement. You have no obligations; you may take your purchases and enjoy them.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Is there a review, a qualification and a standard to be applied to qualify your spree as &lsquo;best&rsquo;? Or not to top standard, but nearly good enough or just satisfactory?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  This is your life. Your adventure on Earth is far greater a pleasure to your soul than one thousand of purchases in as many stores, with as much money as imagined. Believe us.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Yes, vibrations we sense as you sense a person&rsquo;s eyes. We say, a close look into the eyes is intense for you the many, as it a glimpse into a soul it provides. Light best enters your human awareness through this organ, as you all know and because of this, your gaze into the eyes of another provides this to you as it gives the observed a gaze into yours of equal intensity and understanding. Imagine having done this, as you might have? Recall this sensation, do you? This is what we sense of your vibration and yes, it is of this closeness as it is among us all.&rdquo;&nbsp;<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ USA Political Trends]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/usa-political-trends.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/usa-political-trends.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 18:12:52 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/usa-political-trends.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Esteemed Committee, press reporting is loaded with detail about partisan squabbles, national debt, excess spending and economic difficulty involving the USA federal government. What is true, what is advocacy journalism and most importantly, what is coming? Where is all of this leading?  C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&ldquo;There is a combination of c [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Esteemed Committee, press reporting is loaded with detail about partisan squabbles, national debt, excess spending and economic difficulty involving the USA federal government. What is true, what is advocacy journalism and most importantly, what is coming? Where is all of this leading?</em><br /><br /><span style=""></span>  C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&ldquo;There is a combination of choice and destiny in these matters. As we have said several times, the national leader rises to this role for purpose as part of destiny, a lesson and insight to be gained. This component of the situation you describe in your question is not being seen yet, as is expected. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We shall be specific; the purpose of this leader of the USA is to gain introspection by supporter and opposer alike; to cause a great look within expectations and ideas about central authorities.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  These institutions and the formation of sovereign nations are a humanity choice; there are alternatives and we can say these different ways will slowly, incrementally be shown through key individuals having incarnated to live on Earth as is done now. These are brave, experienced souls doing this work, as they must withstand the onslaught of opposition.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  This leader of the USA has the specific purpose to show a government that attempts a role which causes distortion of activity by its actions; we use the concept of a large ship in a river; as this vessel passes, its hull will water displace, the level of the river can be lifted in the immediate vicinity of the ship and there can be disturbances to the surface, waves as they are called, the wake of this large watercraft. Is this good or bad? We can say, it is both. The utility of transport provided is one aspect and this large floating container is built for purpose. Is the wake that reaches the banks good? Possibly, if the water movement produces a good effect. Does the disturbance of other boats by this wake cause enjoyment, damage or other effects? It is the speed of the vessel and the existence of certain things along its route. Human governments are similar in this way; they have been built to achieve what effects? As with the boat of our example, the size and reach and swiftness of course will determine effects.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Have the people choosing government looked closely at effects of today and tomorrow? This is the lesson to be understood, the knowledge to be gained, the wisdom to be developed.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The general effect around the world is similar; tax, debt and expense are a challenge of human creation. We say this commonality is not coincidental and there is certainly a component of destiny in these trends, however choice remains; it is not foregone to do what happens now upon Earth.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The discussion and reporting on these trends are a good thing, disagreement is natural as it occurs by the nature of your soul; the more the better. Our only suggestion is look upon the disagreement, not only the preference, as this is better way for all. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Events of humanity&rsquo;s choosing have brought the Earth to where she now finds herself; soon physical events beyond control of physical beings on Earth will give rise to greater difficulty. These events have come to pass with local effect many times and are understood; as events and economic conditions come together and the latter cause more challenge to the former, effects and reactions will become general, spreading across Earth.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  This plan was always expected; the degree and occurrence along Earth time lines of sequence are entirely and remain a collective choice, by your individual actions.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  There will be blame offered; we ask that you step above it. There will be frustration, even despair and anger; these are expected and normal but we say, what will be solved by anger and fury? <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  This the great lesson is, to define your destination and choose the path; what place will anger, resentment, retribution, bitterness and frustration best fill? <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We have great faith in you all, as we see where humanity will choose to take itself. A great uplifting will there be; the notion of a shift in society is great and we can say, as you would about the gearbox of a vehicle, humanity will upshift as you decide upon your path.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is frustratingly general; we all want specifics so we can avoid trouble. We want to know on what date we should sell our stock to get the best price before it collapses, where to live to avoid the earthquake and what to say to make others like us and say back to us the things we like. We want to know how to make others that do harm to themselves and others just stop and we want pressure and frustration and challenges to go away and we want to know what we can or should do. We do not want general overviews!</em><br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you not appreciation for the ability to first invest? If you no longer wish this investment, dispose of it, concern yourself not for your money. We see the relative importance placed upon this concept but we say with certainty, what you see as money and its worth can and will be changed very quickly. If certainty to its value were possible, that situation would also eliminate money as a medium of exchange. Your individual freedoms are what supply opportunity and risk for its movement. This is far more valuable than a number on a sheet; for as the number can be crossed off and rewritten so can your money be deleted, burned or taken and then where will you be for it? <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Your desire for specifics is product of your environment; you knew you might encounter this challenge and so you have it now. Consider yourself never a victim or unwitting participant in something you dislike but for the failure of others to not see it your way, for this would have resolved everything and avoided what occurs to you now. Look this way not. Look at opportunity; your challenge is a choice; what shall you do? <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You shall compel others to your preferences in the exact proportion you want others to compel you; no more and no less. Your willingness to allow others to force you will provide to you the same power in an opposite and exact proportion. The instant you feel you would like to change something in others, look closely at that thing in yourself you would have others force you to change. Newton&rsquo;s Law of your early physics, every action producing an equal, opposite reaction, this is spirituality in its essence.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You would stop harm done by good example. This is the only way, we guarantee it is effective. The acts of attack and murder are learned; the circumstance to visit such influence can be part of a timeline yet the soul will always be given a choice to act or not act, to accept or reject, to adopt or turn away. Always. The best solution is good example.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  It is easy to want answers yet it is easier to find them but the pleasure of encountering a solution is only felt upon appearance, as you all know from these instances in your own lives. Look not for answers to troubles only, look to outcomes. Where do you want to be? Then move in this direction, in steps. The choice will appear and the better will be told to you; listen inside and you shall hear.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Good day!&rdquo;<br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ Fear]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/fear.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/fear.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 03:03:03 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/fear.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What individual effect and what collective, group effects are created by the emotion of fear? How do these compare to excitement and joy?    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We aim for understanding; we say, everything we say in this place, all is for understanding, comprehension, interpretation and awareness. [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What individual effect and what collective, group effects are created by the emotion of fear? How do these compare to excitement and joy?</em><br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We aim for understanding; we say, everything we say in this place, all is for understanding, comprehension, interpretation and awareness.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  These are the qualities that bring peace to you, what we want incessantly for the people of the planet you all love, your Earth.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Infectious laughter, a phrase known well, has its counterpart. Just as the chuckle will ignite this reaction in your surroundings, so will its opposite. The good news is happiness trumps this opposite; there are no equal values by the two; any amount of happy overrides the fear, the fright and the scare.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The unknown creates a sensation of fear where the eventualities are not understood and thus we communicate with you all this way, to provide you with the stop.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Even a slowing of fear places it far behind all other emotions, yet its manifestation, its emergence and its spread have equal ability to contaminate.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Eliminate it you can, reduce it you will; by loss of fear great joy will be gained. Satisfaction rises from the basis of what was previously unknown when truth is understood; we wish to give this to you.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Acceptance of the previously unknown will not reduce fear, will not deduct it from the now and will not prevent its growth and rise. Fear must be overcome with contentment, satisfaction and peace and these, beloved readers, come from knowing.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Where fear befalls you, look first at what you fear and its loss you will see. This has no other way; a fear faced is a fear erased. This is immutable in the universe; this holds fast and true every place.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Fear is caused by loss of money; but only the loss of your own. Examine this effect; if all were to lose by proportion to their amount the same money, there would be no loss at all. If all money disappeared in an instant, there would not be a fear, there would be an opportunity. Soon a new medium of exchange would rise, the efficiency of the money restored with more of it.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The fear is truly the expected inability to obtain, not what it is.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  If all money disappeared in one instant, would the sun go dark, the planet go dead and all people wrinkle away into Heaven? &nbsp;<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  If all money were quadrupled in amount as prices were halved, what would truly change? More wealth some would feel yet more carrots could you eat? More houses could you fill? More clothes could you wear, in any one instant?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Would hunger be doubled or air twice demanded? Could more water be drunk, more eye blinks produced? &nbsp;Would more sleep be now needed, more sheets for a bed?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Would clouds be expensive, rubbish now scarce?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Would food not be sold, no crops ever grown, if money as given, disappeared from the fold?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Would beauty be greater, bad hair ever banished, winks free of charge, no bugs ever famished?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  But fear you might feel, for practice has shown, to lose all one&rsquo;s money means nothing you&rsquo;d own?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  So think of the cause, ponder the sight, of cash wealth all gone and no banker-like fright.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Kick debts away, kill off what is owed, enjoy newfound balance, finance to unload.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We practice your words, arrange them as speech, offer them up with meaning for each.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Poems make sense, pennies make pounds, you life is not cash, you&rsquo;re all still around.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Fear not what will change, flip that coin over, under its top you shall find a new clover.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The emotion might spread and make itself grow, unless you agree, you all shall say no.<br /><span style=""></span><br />Collude to be happy, concur with good hope, now come all together, even slow pokes.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Smiles will spread, even butter might envy, the way you all cover, the effect once so heavy<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Lightness of joy and levity now, will make progress quick and amazing is how<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Poetry touches, the heart of your soul, sounds by all science, harmonic will grow<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Energy expanded, power increased, this is what happens with good humor grease.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Fear makes dark clouds, worry brings night, kick it away and make things more bright<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Face what concerns, look straight in its eye, tell it to go, a kite it can fly<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Your life on Earth yours, your trip going well, so all the bad things, can just go to hell<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Strong is your will, mighty your love to make yourself happy and soft as a dove.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We know it&rsquo;s not simple, to cast it aside, that worrisome bitch, superficial pride<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The answer&rsquo;s within, the key is inside, to unlock your power, your force gone outside<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Look up to the Heavens, ask always for help, we love you today, no need to now yelp.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Do unto others what you want for yourself, scare off the fright, knock down its old shelf<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Kill what is heavy, give birth to the light, for worry can&rsquo;t stand the brightness of right<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Faith in your soul, pleasure with life, cuts fear into bits like a sharp and hot knife<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Choose not to worry, bake happiness cakes, your love is what matters, that's all that it takes.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You came to be born and you grow to the sky, with greatness inside and a gleam in your eyes.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The Heavens are yours, and you own the Earth too, so always be happy, as we are with you!<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Be well!<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ Spirituality is Science]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/spirituality-is-science.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/spirituality-is-science.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 22:43:06 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/spirituality-is-science.html</guid><description><![CDATA[What is an alien?We are all "aliens" by our understanding; a physical being from another planet, star, solar system or place in this galaxy, another one or someplace else in the universe.To be alien is to show abilities we all have; set well aside for the moment (remember, moment and momentum are the same thing) as we live on Earth.Examples come from time to time; here we have one: [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;">What is an alien?<br /><br />We are all "aliens" by our understanding; a physical being from another planet, star, solar system or place in this galaxy, another one or someplace else in the universe.<br /><br />To be alien is to show abilities we all have; set well aside for the moment (remember, moment and momentum are the same thing) as we live on Earth.<br /><br />Examples come from time to time; here we have one:<br /><br /><a title="" target="_blank" href="http://biertijd.com/mediaplayer/?itemid=25540" style="">http://biertijd.com/mediaplayer/?itemid=25540</a><br /><br />A demonstration of our mind, the power of our thoughts. Remember you create always effects as strong and clear as seen in this video, the difference is how we are accustomed to the effects we create; our movement of the arm and hand begin with thought; the design of the house begins by thinking and the cure for disease begins this way also. We are trained to see a pattern of thought then to movement then to result; here we have thought to result with movement we are TEMPORARILY not used to seeing.<br /><br />Does anybody ever wonder how and why tarot cards work? Wonder no more.<br /><br />Does this seem foolish, like trickery and to not be believed? Then your veil you designed well but assume not that your veil is like that of the every, because it is resembles that of the many.<br /><br />Is this "true"? Is is "real"? &nbsp;Your feelings will tell.<br />&nbsp;</div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ Saint Malachy - Prophecy of Popes]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/saint-malachy-prophecy-of-popes.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/saint-malachy-prophecy-of-popes.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 23:01:22 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/saint-malachy-prophecy-of-popes.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q1. The alleged prophecies were first published by Benedictine monk Arnold Wion in 1595. Wion attributes the prophecies to Saint Malachy, a 12th&#8209;century Archbishop of Armagh, Ireland. Can you ask St. Malachy, if these prophecies were his or were they fabricated by Arnold Wion or Someone else? How did these prophetic visions come to him? Q2. Is there truth in the predic [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="font-size: 17px; line-height: 18px;">Q1. The alleged prophecies were first published by Benedictine monk Arnold Wion in 1595. Wion attributes the prophecies to Saint Malachy, a 12th&#8209;century Archbishop of Armagh, Ireland. Can you ask St. Malachy, if these prophecies were his or were they fabricated by Arnold Wion or Someone else? How did these prophetic visions come to him?</em><br /><em style=""> Q2. Is there truth in the prediction that this Pope Francis of 2013, will be the last Pope? If not, will he be one of the last?</em><em style=""><br /> Q3. Is the Pope Francis same as Peter the Roman mentioned as the 112th pope in the prophecy?<br /> Concerning the 112th pope, this is St. Malachy's purported prediction. "In the final persecution of the Holy Roman Church, there will sit [i.e., as bishop]. Peter the Roman, who will pasture his sheep in many tribulations, and when these things are finished, the city of seven hills [i.e. Rome] will be destroyed, and the dreadful judge will judge his people. The End.[13]"<br /> Q4. Will Rome be destroyed at some point in future?&nbsp;<br /> Q5. What does it mean when it says "dreadful judge will judge his people"? Who is this dreadful judge, God? HigherSelf of every individual?<br /> Q6. Will there be an apocalypse? Will many people die? Definition of Apocalypse from Merriam Webster online : one of the Jewish and Christian writings of 200 BC to AD 150 marked by pseudonymity, symbolic imagery, and the expectation of an imminent cosmic cataclysm in which God destroys the ruling powers of evil and raises the righteous to life in a messianic kingdom<br /> Q7. The outgoing pope Benedict says "God told me to go"&nbsp;Does that sound like God wants to connect the change of papacy with this prophecy of Peter the Roman and a upcoming days of judgment and tribulations ?<br /> Q8. What can we do to be the best during the apocalypse or time of great change and tribulations and judgment? Any advice for humanity to prepare for the change?<br /> Q9. Have you reincarnated anywhere on earth currently? Do you plan to in future? What do you do in afterlife nowadays?</em><br /><br /><span style=""></span>  C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;Great appreciation we have for your nine questions and we hope to disappoint terribly with our response, for so good and representative these questions are, and we thank you as much as can thanks be offered for so ideal an opportunity of illustration such questions provide. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  These things ask about religion, human bodies of thought about Home. Heaven. Reality. Existence. Permanence. The journey of a life to Earth, so long and done so quickly, once it is done. Your longing for the explanation you all know already, but for its very brief, yet permanently appearing place to where you have set it, sits just outside your life and yet is a part of it always.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  All notions of religion grow in appeal on Earth as they touch upon detail and memory you carry within, a deep part of your soul. Religion is an idea of man; it is memory of the Heavens seen through the limits of humanity.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  What this Saint suggested bore great meaning in the organization of his life. Great vision was he able to express and much certainty did he speak. He is, in your Earth time, long gone and has come and gone again several times hence. The accuracy and meaning of his prophecy are not just what is offered in them yet also what is seen in them and chosen to be true. This soul saw importance in this story, as he returned to live a life as Pope centuries later, that life also finished.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We suggest, for comparison, another phase of human life, as an example of the meaning of a prophecy; slavery. In the large nation of the US of A, no longer do there live enslaved peoples, enslavers or their children. The lives that made it are done, all of them; your life knows now, knows it not, but for stories; you are not a part. Does the idea of restitution live on? Why?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  These church leaders, long ago mentioned, have come and gone in the same way, their life lived and purpose given to their growth from the lives experiened.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The latest person to assume this role; he will have great meaning where and how it is chosen to be provided; there is no influence or strength or power over humanity where humanity supplies it not; accuracy of the prophetic detail assumes your choices and will cannot be changed from the place where they were said; if true were this, your will and choice would not be yours, you would not be human.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Yes, this man who lives as Pope now has done so previously in this role. God did not tell the departed one to abdicate his position; this choice made as he decided. God would never tell any of you how to live; only suggest what will help you and then show you where and how a benefit is found. There are other ways for benefit and God&rsquo;s love and blessing for your choices will follow you always, as it has followed this man just resigned.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  There will be no apocalypse as your question describes it; these things said many a century of your time ago, are as you call them, allegories which allude to events now happening and soon to come, but there is no apocalypse to befall Earth.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  There is no dreadful judge for a dreadful people; this saying arises from an Earth thought of religion, damnation and punishment as explanation for what was not understood. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  There will be Popes as Popes are desired; if the choosers lose interest, so will the position. We speculate not upon its likelihood; this question is Earth. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Rome will go on. The organization of a church will see change and to this the phrase refers.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Your question of preparation we like best and so have chosen to speak of it last; we know of the ninth, not directed at us, your typist as he says. Attention is shunned, no importance has it for the many. So you know we have not ignored.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You shall prepare as you have already prepared; your visit to these words and your thoughts upon reading them are evidence and symptom of your preparation. There is nothing more you need do; the concern for preparation arises from the view of tasks, lists of chores and work for progress that permeate your humanity. These are fine, we mean not to criticize it, it is as you have all chosen, and this is good.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Religion is important to you the many and we say, where it supplies comfort, certainty and answers to the things you would know, it is good. It is not bad, nothing on Earth is ever this way; we know great disagreement there could be to this, and we know there is much dislike of many things. All events, all acts, all undertakings and all movement on Earth are good; religion is but one part of the greater hope; where it appeals, seek it. Where it attracts not, go not. Where it repels, you have seen its greatest value of all, in this you have found the greatest purpose of religious thought and you are its champion, you who reject it and dislike it. You give it the life needed to cause its review, its assessment and its audit and in this, great benefit and value does humanity derive, for yourself and all around you, for this you do best on Earth; you QUESTION.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Be happy and chins highest!&rdquo;&nbsp;<br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ Heavenly Tunes]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/heavenly-tunes.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/heavenly-tunes.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 22:06:53 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/heavenly-tunes.html</guid><description><![CDATA[  [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class='imgPusher' style='float:left;height:0px'></span><span style='z-index:10;position:relative;float:left;;clear:left;margin-top:0px;*margin-top:0px'><a><img src="http://www.theamendment.net/uploads/8/0/3/0/8030819/5001610.gif?93" style="margin-top: 5px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 10px; none;" alt="Picture" class="galleryImageBorder" /></a><div style="display: block; font-size: 90%; margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: 10px; text-align: center;"></div></span> <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;display:block;"><em style="">Q:&nbsp; I would surmise that poetry and song are quite popular in the afterlife. Would it be possible to share with us either the lyrics or prose of such.&nbsp;<br /><br /></em><em style="">Also is there a favourite kind of music they enjoy over there or do they get a kick out of watching and listening to the X-Factor.</em><br /><br />C:&nbsp; Music, yes! Song with your words? Poetry of your language? Less so, not common. Ideas with thought are what we communicate, not words of speech as you have.<br /><br />All music and sounds are enjoyed; and we say, just as there is harmony of sounds on Earth, so have we here. The pleasant sounds of notes and chords and groups of them align the frequencies of vibration, as you know well. Our level of vibration much higher also includes all vibrations of slower, in the levels you now fill, and these expand the variety of sound we might use and enjoy here.&nbsp;<br /><br />The music we enjoy the most is the happiness produced by its sounds; upon observation of your Earth, we enjoy most the joy and pleasure and entertainment felt by all of you; where any of the souls of Heaven might look upon just one soul or a great grouping, your concerts, and see many people happy with enjoyment, THIS is the music of Earth we like the best.<br /><br />This enjoyment we have also; we can produce sounds as we like and also we create instruments as you know them for temporary use, which we do often. Your duets, trios, quartets and more, great enjoyment do we derive from this and we say, these things you do as you remember them from Heaven. Your singing groups, what you have named acapella, we enjoy especially as these sounds come from your bodies and the essence of your souls; these sounds are your words and the stories they tell, yes, and they are much more and we love them even more than you know!<br /><br />In Heaven all of these things are expanded; your American jazz, the improvised tunes and random playing of songs both known and invented in the moment, these are wonderful and are a great memory and glimpse into the music of Heaven expanded beyond your imagination. Your church choirs, outstanding and captivating.&nbsp;<br /><br />We enjoy all of your art, be it by your television, radio or any other medium. Until you return to Heaven, enjoy what you have always, as when you rediscover the breadth of music as you will both have and create to compare with the rudimentary way done on Earth, ever with the same value and meaning to your happiness, you will appreciate all the more and the better your time of music upon Earth.&nbsp;</div> <hr style="width:100%;clear:both;visibility:hidden;"></hr>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ Purpose of Existence]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/purpose-of-existence.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/purpose-of-existence.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 21:45:17 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/purpose-of-existence.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the purpose for existence, really? What we basically exist for is to be born from God, then experience lessons, then return and be one with God forever? That's basically what I've been hearing...Also, when we are one with God, all that is and will be, what will we do?     C:&nbsp; &ldquo;Ask we must, how would you describe non-existence? The question assumes y [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><font size="4"><em>Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the purpose for existence, really? What we basically exist for is to be born from God, then experience lessons, then return and be one with God forever? That's basically what I've been hearing...Also, when we are one with God, all that is and will be, what will we do? </em><br /><br /><span style=""></span>    C:&nbsp; &ldquo;Ask we must, how would you describe non-existence? The question assumes your existence implies purpose; a goal, objective and outcome. These things, ending and results, are of time sequence and events. These are of your Earth existence. These concepts are not your reality; notions of your subset of reality, this is what they are.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We suggest your notion of expansion; there is not a place to start, another to end and throughout, steps taken. This approach is human and it supports the purpose, if there were a purpose, a reason, a justification and a motivation, as you know these words of English.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  There are many moments of ecstasy, with certainty yet also complexity of society and the interaction of all souls is vast and varied; the limits of Earth are not found. Ever do you evolve and grow and upon return you will see the great leaps your trip has given, the advance and depth and growth to your understanding. This is not seen from Earth; there is up and down, and left and right. In your true home, there are not these limits, not your movement in the physical way and not in any other way.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You will do things of detail, complexity and interaction as you do not imagine on Earth, as Earth limits these things. This is not to say Earth is limited; Earth is designed, constructed and arranged with reason for placement, as a building could be limited by size, architecture and interpretation of its style and its use, by desires that could be given. Yet a building of great beauty, presence and use is not seen as a limitation; it is seen as a great asset, great shrine, monument and portion of the patrimony of its people. This is Earth.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You are with God now, and you always were and always will be; you do not return to a place you have not departed. You do not learn all of your lessons; <u>much we like this part of your question</u>. It speaks to a successful visit; and it tells of your advance. You have gone to a great place, where you are admired and loved and held in great esteem for just the thing you have said, that you might learn all of your lessons and then have none left to learn. This is not reality and is not your existence. It is not God and is not your source.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Strong is the notion of perfection on Earth, yet as all know, it exists not; as we have said just recently by your timeline, perfection is opinion of limit. It is perception and interpretation of absolutes; this concept is used to great advantage on Earth as an ideal not reached but for the methods, the thoughts and ideas offered, if only you will agree to follow. Religion you this call.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  This is not the way; the notion of perfection implies ending, completion and exhaustion. This happens not on Earth, as you all know well, as it happens not anywhere in the universe. There is no list of tasks to be exhausted, your journey does not end and there is no graduation, with requirements for all to be met by some. No, you know what you want and requirements for these you set for yourself and only for yourself. Help, assistance and love surround you always and progress you make with every breath, but for the veil of humanity that keeps it just beyond your sight and just outside your complete memory of who you are. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You know not when your life on Earth will finish; you do not want to know. You have ideals for your happiness, do you not? Certainly yes, and with good faith in yourself and goodwill to reach this, you live your days with joy where you can find it and faith it will come back, in the moments you feel it not. Your ups &amp; downs, as you say. This is your existence always, in Heaven and on Earth, and there will always be what brings you joy and happiness and love and the accompaniment of the souls who love you.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Be good and be well!&rdquo;</font><br /></div>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>