<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >

<channel><title><![CDATA[&nbsp; www.theamendment.net &nbsp; - HOME]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/index.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[HOME]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 07:26:37 -0600</pubDate><generator>Weebly</generator><item><title><![CDATA[ ufe]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/ufe.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/ufe.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 21:55:21 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/ufe.html</guid><description><![CDATA[For this post The Committee is asked to either bring through information from an entity not yet heard or to supply it through themselves, as they best see the connection; and to ask this entity or being or soul, whomever they ask to come, to deliver relevant and valuable news, of general benefit.    The questions are mine, or at least, start that way, as they always do. The questions that f [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;">For this post The Committee is asked to either bring through information from an entity not yet heard or to supply it through themselves, as they best see the connection; and to ask this entity or being or soul, whomever they ask to come, to deliver relevant and valuable news, of general benefit.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    The questions are mine, or at least, start that way, as they always do. The questions that flow could also be channeled and deliberately interspersed as the source chooses it be sent.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    Q = Questions (I think) &nbsp; &nbsp;C = The Committee&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; UFE = Unidentified flying entity/ies <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>    Q1:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Please, if you could, Esteemed Committee, can you ask another source of good information to give us relevant information, applicable to now and with value for current conditions and circumstances? My thanks in advance.<br /><br /></em><br /><em>Q1a:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are we hearing from you through The Committee?</em><br /><br />C/UFE: You hear from both sources.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q2:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What do you the UFEs offer The Committee does not, will not or cannot?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are here to speak from a new source; as is the case in all the universe, views are different and thus make the circumstances different. Unlike your antiseptic existence, where the concept of set, fixed and continuous is held tightly, independent of your thoughts and interactions, this is not the situation. The same movie or book read multiple times becomes boring; and soon, as soon as the second time and certainly after no more than a few. Your notion of time helps create this feeling. In reality, your mood and emotion and desire create a different experience for each view or read and thus each situation becomes new and different; this is not to say the facts change, they do not. We ask you to consider facts without reaction or perception; what then are facts? Soon your fifth view of the same movie creates a feeling you have spent too much time with it, that another could be seen instead. There is no stead, no placement and no limit to time; all occurs now. Your repetition of view is never boring; it becomes known and your desire to seek what is new is what causes a thing to be discarded for something new, unknown and full of innovations. This is what creates reality; in the oft repeated phrase, thoughts are manifested. As your thoughts turn away from something known, it fades and falls away. It can be recreated, as the arrangement of energetic particles to do this follows the permanence of memory. Memory is thought known and is for ever; it creates substance. Your world is the reverse, where permanence is paramount to thought. It is not, yet so it seems and so you have gone there to feel this reversed, fictitious environment.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why is the repeated view never boring?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You can create multiple circumstances to lead to that which you see just as you can see many courses to follow, many decision trees can be drawn. We suggest mystery novels; these follow many twists and turns. A new book follows other things; and these are created as the author chooses, yes?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You are all your authors; so the place and the event are not the backdrop against which your acts are set; your acts and thoughts, which create them, reconfigure the background and backdrop. These things exist all together and create a new reality by their combination.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Like a situation comedy television program?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, and with the ability to change all things for the same episode. Colors, names, sets, dialogue and endings can be replayed with infinite outcomes.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is this ever done?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, not as you see it on Earth. Off of and away from Earth, where there is no time, any experience or episode can be revisited and replayed at any moment; what involves you now can be suspended and you might return to the exact place to resume it, after you have gone elsewhere. The repeat of a scene or experience or place you make, this is done as it might appeal to you. Time is simply movement; each thing or place is movement and in the permanent moment it occurs. Your words of moment and momentum are the same, by this notion.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This lack of time is unusual and hard to understand.</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, it is simply forgotten and unfamiliar. We give an example; all of you, imagine you hold a wrist timing device, what is your wristwatch. Change all of them to the same time on your clock schedule, on the same date. Each of you push the sun back around the Earth and darken the sky to full night if this corresponds to the time chosen, or all coordinate the wristwatches to the same reading. Move the angle of the sun to the corresponding rise above the horizon for what you say should match this reading. Does this alter time?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Yes, if you choose to see time. No, it does not change time.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is as simple as this?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Certainly; we have no horizon. The angle of light? Simply move yourself and you will change its angle.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have an angle of light and a surface of the planet, neither of which we can move.</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, correct. Move yourself.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The light will still strike the Earth at the same angle.</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Reverse the view; it will go from morning to evening, will it not?<br /><span style=""></span><em><br /><span style=""></span>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Huh?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know not the difference between a morning view of light compared to the afternoon if you see it in a place you have not visited; a photograph of a city you do not know could be either early morning or late afternoon by the angle of sunlight seen in the photo. If you could go to this place, change the reading on this wrist timer, you would be convinced of morning when others would say you are crazy, it is later afternoon.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does this explain mental conditions and disorientation?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, in some cases. The person seen as sick is simply not set to a rhythm of your assumption.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So from where you are, you can create a time and place?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, as you on Earth can, too. You will see.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our notion of time as a resource, an asset of limited size and amount, to be used "wisely" is this valid?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It is, for your Earth and also for the circumstances you create and thus expect. Yet it can also not be. Either is available.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Wasting time is good or bad?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Time wastes not, where time there is not. You also waste no time; you only choose different routes. All time elapsed, by your perception, is a route, course or trajectory. All lead the same.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can Earth be seen as it was long ago?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes; and as it will be. Simply go to this destination, and there it will be.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><em>Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you can see what Earth will become?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, we see what Earth is; it is what its place determines. In a different place you will not be upon it; you are upon it now and your see its existence by its location as this intersects yours. The point can be reached as chosen, as can all other points or places or locations, as you prefer the word.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, if I suggest you consider our calendar, and then if I choose a date upon it, can you look there and tell us what you see?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What do you see in Washington, DC on January 22, 2017? This is the beginning of a term of a new president for the USA?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We see a grid and matrix and this point you fix by your calendar as one point where several matrices of many dimensions intersect. To predict what will be in this place requires you to choose from available approaches. We see several things regarding a new government and leader; we see several males and two females; so far you have chosen two or three to approach this place; we see two approach more closely at this point. Which will be leader? You shall decide.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This isn't enough for some of us; certainty of outcome we must know.</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The universe cannot function this way; certainty is a fiction created by events that are isolated, plucked from their true places and set upon a line, a vector. A facsimile of an event is taken from its place on the matrix and put on a place in the vector; you who agree to live congruently with this vector, and see its alignment only, will fix upon a point as events either precede or follow. Because of this, you see certainty. We see certain approaches and possibilities; the matrix can be rotated and other approaches seen; a different intersection will create this point, the one you have chosen to identify as 2017221, or 2017-22-01, both the same as each adds to 15. Do you see numerology, as you call it, marking the point?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said two females; for president?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, strong contenders for the two parties will each have an approach.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who will win?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You have not chosen this yet.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the winner matter much to Earth?</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, larger things are in play than such person. It will matter to people involved with this process but the greater course of humanity is and always was and always will be above the one person. You are all far greater than one step of process for the role of one person.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Unidentified one, thank you.</em><br />UFE:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ones; we are several and you are welcome. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ dreams]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/dreams.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/dreams.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 16:38:16 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/dreams.html</guid><description><![CDATA[ [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class='imgPusher' style='float:right;height:170px'></span><span style='z-index:10;position:relative;float:right;;clear:right;margin-top:20px;*margin-top:40px'><a><img src="http://www.theamendment.net/uploads/8/0/3/0/8030819/1365179327.jpg" style="margin-top: 5px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-left: 10px; margin-right: 0px; border-width:1px;padding:3px;" alt="Picture" class="galleryImageBorderBlack" /></a><div style="display: block; font-size: 90%; margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: 10px; text-align: center;"></div></span> <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;display:block;"><em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can The Committee speak about dreams? What is the purpose and value? Why do we forget them and how can we better recall and decipher them? </em><br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;To speak to this is more than to speak of what you call a dream. This word you use, it can mean the memory of having been asleep. To answer this well, we discuss what is sleep, and place the dream inside it as a memory of the larger moment.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  A life force and energetic existence permeates, is part of all things on Earth and all things of the Earth; soil, rocks, oceans, mountains, air, rivers and the entire planet. The many animals and plants also, and the more complicated, the animals that sleep, live a life cycle and have a soul from home which departs the body with each cycle. The rotation of the Earth and the light and dark periods created provide the opportunity for linear perception of existence you call time, and sleep is a component.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  When the body enters this phase of brainwave activity, the essence of the soul leaves it until awakened; this your return, a return of the mind, the expression of the soul through the body.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  The phenomena of sleep walking is a physical movement of the body as you are accustomed to seeing when awake, where the mind &ndash; the soul expressing itself through the body &ndash; has not re-engaged. Your body does not require your soul to function. We suggest an automobile; its motor will run without your physical presence, will it not? Its true, proper function will, however, require a driver just as your body, to live your life, requires you.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  Think of the brain as a receptor, antenna and transmitter, for the true and real source of its activity. The perception of the mind and the brain as one is caused by this.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  When the body sleeps, it is because the mind has departed. The dream is but the memory of the last portion of this phase; the dream is as real as your existence in the physical; what happens in the dream uses not the body, so the return to the body leaves the reality of the dream aside.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  Remember an event you know took place; is your memory of this moment different from your dream memory? Yes, because you have attached your memory of the event to the physical experience of your body. Your dream occurs without this burden, without limitations of physical presence on Earth. You do recall the strangeness of the thing in your dreams as being logical and normal when passing and having the experience; only after awakening do these objects, places, interactions and happenings seem unusual, impossible. <br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  Dreams are forgotten as relevance of them fades from your life awake; where you remember a dream for a long time, forever by the timeline of your Earth life, this dream was important to you in both phases. The symbolism of the dream that you remember is placed there by you to nudge you in a direction, at an action, an idea and a thought which shall lead your life towards your plan.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  Your journey to live on Earth requires departure from the body, to gain renewal and relief from each phase; life on Earth for humans is designed as this. Your soul, expressed as your mind when operating through the body, will force itself from the body if denied by physical surroundings. Suspension of sleep will cause psychotic behavior, as your investigation of medicine has shown; this is a life plan forcing itself upon the body. If sleep is stopped, the body soon ceases to function. Dreams are a glimpse, as you recall them, into your true existence. They are recalled as a faded, blurred, sometimes distant memory of things unusual and impossible. This placement of the dream into such perception is by your decision to make it seem obscure and foggy, for we say, clarity of existence and brightness of view are the true reality of your dreams, the fog more truly is cast over life as you live it, but for your decisions to see it as you have it. Thus the idea of life as an illusion.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  Be well.&rdquo;<br><span style=""></span></div> <hr style="width:100%;clear:both;visibility:hidden;"></hr>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ SPACE TRAVEL CONTINUED]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/space-travel-continued.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/space-travel-continued.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 17:21:39 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/space-travel-continued.html</guid><description><![CDATA[ [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class='imgPusher' style='float:left;height:234px'></span><span style='z-index:10;position:relative;float:left;;clear:left;margin-top:20px;*margin-top:40px'><a><img src="http://www.theamendment.net/uploads/8/0/3/0/8030819/9561802.jpg?355" style="margin-top: 5px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 10px; border-width:1px;padding:3px;" alt="Picture" class="galleryImageBorderBlack" /></a><div style="display: block; font-size: 90%; margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: 10px; text-align: center;"></div></span> <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;display:block;"><em style="font-size: 18px; line-height: 18px;">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How does this cloaking device work?</em><br>T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;It is similar to your mirror; light photons, clusters of electromagnetic energy, penetrate, perforate and pass through some substances unimpeded; others allow some transmission, others block these radiations. Your mirror reflects a larger portion of the light striking its surface, by the metallic film affixed to the glass, the silicon based medium which holds it; most substances diffuse the light and reflect a smaller portion yet allow none to pass through. The glass without the metallic reflective film would not reflect much of the light, as you know.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  The cloaking device takes into account all of these effects; and creates an energy field to act as does a mirror with one significant difference; the mirror would reflect; the device used &ldquo;sees&rdquo; as you would say, the image and the light approaching the object to be hidden, to be cloaked. It recreates the same electromagnetic energy and re-transmits it from the otherwise visible side of the object; it &ldquo;copies&rdquo; what would be seen in the absence of the object.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  A similar process occurs with your photography and also your music and electromagnetic waves of transmission in the frequencies of your dimensions; these can be detected and copied, but to an extent too limited to achieve what you will see demonstrated, at some later occasion. <br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  The device reads the light energy that strikes it and re-transmits this; this is easy as your light is limited to your measurements of 300,000 of your kilometers per one of your seconds; in the higher dimensions this is slow, thus easy to replicate; it is conceptually similar to capture and recreation of sound waves, yet the replication is exact, as it is with a mirror image reflected.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  The higher speeds of the dimensions we achieve and in which we exist, allow this.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could we use such device on Earth?&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </em><br>T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Yes, we could give you one; it would require no energy that you yet know and would work perfectly. It would not affect your environment. We would not do this.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why not?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It would be sold for use as a weapon; it would be used to conceal armament and to gain advantage, for financial gain. You remain mired in a dense concept of money and cast aside things of value for it, applying the reverse of truth. The money has no value; it is simply an idea without substance. &nbsp;<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why isn&rsquo;t this device used to conceal presence elsewhere?</em><br>T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;We would never attack and no need for this would there be, in an aggressive or warlike way. Even if this were attempted, our presence could not be cloaked; this device only works inter-dimensionally, from a faster to a lesser speed.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Earth we speak of higher vibrations and ascension into them and many of us would enjoy this, as we understand it.</em><br>T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Certainly, and we say a large attraction is that this ascension represents an elevation above something to which it is compared; some value is placed in the sensation of higher and thus better, by comparison to surroundings. When a rise or ascension to a higher range of vibrations occurs, this notion is cast aside and sensations of this sort, that one has risen and feels elevated, these change significantly from what is perceived now. Yes ascension would occur yet it will be far different and provide greater understanding.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is this the reason no attack would occur?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes; battles and conflicts have already occurred many times as our civilization developed to provide the technology now used to visit your planet. The ability to use technology for destruction has long been established, understood and been seen as futile. All possessors of it understand its use against perceived foes will not work, as they have abilities to detect, defend, repel and destroy by response. Because all possess such ability means it is not considered; its use in this way produces no gain; there is no change to gain. <br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is this aspect of Earth an attraction?</em><br>T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Yes; many aspects of your collective behaviors fascinate us, and much of our visitation revolves around observance.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We hear much commentary you have had contact with leaderships of governments and this is all kept very quiet. Is this true and why?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, many visitors are allowed to visit and make good contact. There has been resistance as your technology developed and our visits were then taken seriously, as the attempts to resist our presence were neutralized. Still your leadership does not know what methods we use and because of this, we are either respected or feared. Humanity remains stuck in a mode of power and its use.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why are we not contacted directly, around governments?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You are, as occurs now.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why governments first?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Governments are you; you create them. They are to represent you, no? Disagreement there might be at this, as we have had this cycle many times, yet you maintain and renew it and thus, we are reluctant to cast it aside as irrelevant. We are now doing both in a larger way, and you are reading contact now.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When are we going to see what we call alien visitors on Earth?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You will not observe us walking about; this would serve only a bad purpose. It is also difficult as existence in your environment is not easy for many of us, for many physiological reasons. We prefer to remain aboard ships. There are other visitors that have and might do more; we speak only of ourselves.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q: &nbsp; &nbsp; So far, distance to the Pleiades star cluster and also the Sirius twins has been mentioned, but only. Where is your home, your base and why are you here?</em><br>T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;We are neither Sirian nor Pleiadean, we are from a star nearby you call Canopus. <br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will humans be given the opportunity to visit your homes?</em><br>T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Not yet; a time will come, generations from now, as you have them upon Earth. Your bodies are fragile away from your atmosphere, as are all bodies and types and this will require some advance planning but most of al, it must be for your purposes and advances. Little in this way would be served.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can any being approach Earth and visit as you do?</em><br>T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;No; permission must be gained and resistance there is to some, who would like to visit and mine your planet. There are others who would disturb life to your collective detriment.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You Canopians, can you be called this? Why do you come?</em><br>T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Observe, study, compare to history and understand development. We like this name for us, we use it not.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let&rsquo;s return, if we might, to space travel. Aboard a vessel, are there windows to look outside?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, this is not necessary. <br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We depict a ship travelling through space as if stars and other visible objects are passed as we might see trees along a roadway; is this accurate?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The speed of light is not a factor; your perception of the spectrum of light at the speeds you are able to recognize and detect is what gives rise to this notion. As there is a spectrum of visible and invisible light to your eyes, so there is also a spectrum of speeds and you are at the lower end; the light you see from a star you deem to be distant and requiring of many of your lifetimes to have its light reach you? This light you see is the residual, cast off which strays into your dimensionality; the light energy traverses the galaxy many times faster, and even our travel does not attain these velocities.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what is seen during the voyage from a star in the Pleiades cluster to Earth? Or from Canopus? </em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Nothing; visible images fade and a grayish fog are all to be observed. As the voyage concludes, we return to the spectrums and see all colors and images again.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the galaxy colorful?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Like a kaleidoscope of a forest; imagine every hue and shade of all colors you might see, all expressed in all the plants and growths and beings of our forest; this is the appearance of the galaxy.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What your vessels made of?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You do not have this material.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it an alloy of anything we have?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, we have some components of metals on your Earth, other you know not. Metals we create and alloys from them you cannot yet produce.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How do you move and propel your ships?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Magnetism.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How do we defy gravity?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As you do now; for example, the way it is suspended inside a space vessel far above your planet&rsquo;s surface or as it can be made to disappear during the trajectory of a flight in your winged craft, these conditions are all able to be replicated with magnetism.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will we be able to defy gravity on Earth?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, you could do this now and have.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why is this not more widespread?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It will change your existence and civilizations and the value of life on Earth would be changed. You have not yet chosen to make this change.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who is the &ldquo;you&rdquo; mentioned in your answer?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You on Earth and all souls and groups who have chosen to visit and know Earth, and the very few courageous ones that live upon it now, such as you who type this and you who read these words. You, the Earth body leaders of these great group, all of you have chosen the course you now follow.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who organizes all this and protects Earth?</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The large hierarchy of all beings throughout the galaxy and universe.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Visitor from Canopus, thank you.</em><br>T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You are all welcome.<br><span style=""></span></div> <hr style="width:100%;clear:both;visibility:hidden;"></hr>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ Exorcism]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/exorcism.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/exorcism.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 15:16:29 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/exorcism.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is going on with this, what is to be learned from it? And how should you perform an exorcism? What is the most successful way to get a negative spirit to leave?     A:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;This is the most extreme form of what is called schizophrenia in your science of psychiatry. It is arranged and  [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is going on with this, what is to be learned from it? And how should you perform an exorcism? What is the most successful way to get a negative spirit to leave? </em><br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>    A:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;This is the most extreme form of what is called schizophrenia in your science of psychiatry. It is arranged and planned; remember Guardian Angels and Guides? [The Committee smiles broadly as this is said] The invasion of a body would not be allowed unless planned. We suggest your sleep; you depart and travel and many things you do; these images of dreams are not images; only this they seem to be as recalled and remembered. Would not the occupation of your body be done best whilst <i>[yes, Erik] </i>you are away? This does not happen; the appearance of the alternate personality is manifested only awake.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  The condition is undertaken as it will provide opportunity and effect for the souls involved, and we say there can be more than one visitor, there can be many. The host soul agrees to allow visitors a short or brief experience in a body, without benefit of having grown and learned; this gives the opportunity to see what a body life in dense matter on Earth would be like. <br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  Great obstacles there are, as these visitors appear without experience of a life in a body and the sensations and feelings are new and difficult to assume; no memory of human interaction has there been and thus behavior appears to those surrounding the visitor, as you who know of this have understood.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  The performance of an exorcism is a human attempt, and we say with kindness and compassion, a feeble one, to gain control over that which you control not. It is done for your purpose, as you feel pressure to assist and remedy, faced with social guilt for standing aside and allowing it, yet this is likely the better course.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  The successful way to have the visitor depart is ask, and this requires recognition and understanding of the process. The negation of the existence of soul presences, in ourselves and others, and a reality beyond human density impedes the understanding that would most efficiently dispatch the perceived invader.&rdquo;<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ Art from above]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/art-from-above.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/art-from-above.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 17:20:55 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/art-from-above.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you tell us specifically which science fictions are channelled if we were to give you a list? I&rsquo;ll begin with one of my favourite authors Ursula K. Le Guin - The lefthand of darkness.    C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;"A larger response we suggest is creativity and art; that which you create  [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="font-size: 18px; line-height: 18px;">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you tell us specifically which science fictions are channelled if we were to give you a list? I&rsquo;ll begin with one of my favourite authors Ursula K. Le Guin - The lefthand of darkness.</em><br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;"A larger response we suggest is creativity and art; that which you create for entertainment. Your art, your expression. You have many things in this category; that not a function serve beyond stimulation of your thoughts.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  All of these things have a portion, a part and a component channeled to you all. Paintings, novels, poems and statues; sculptures and drawings and music and dance; song and lyrics and the words before you now, there is part of them from the Heavens, the place which surrounds you all, just behind the thick, impenetrable yet transparent and temporary veil of existence on Earth.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We suggest the portion created by the humans not be discounted, for contribution you make is always the greatest; it can be of the life you lead now and it often derives from this art created by thought, later delivered to use by and through the soul, once s/he has grown and reached the stage for its issuance. &nbsp;<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  It is always of the artist and creator but there is channeling in all of it, and glad we are to see it loved and enjoyed and criticized and disliked, for it expresses again the reality of the Heavens, manifested on your Earth.&rdquo;<br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ Raise the Vibration]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/raise-the-vibration.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/raise-the-vibration.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 17:10:50 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/raise-the-vibration.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Raise the Vibration    Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the planet Earth need our help in raising her vibrations?C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &ldquo;You are your planet and it is you; all of you, all together. You form a team and you are the one and the many. Your lift each other; as does the one, so does the other.&rdquo; [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;">Raise the Vibration<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>    <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the planet Earth need our help in raising her vibrations?</em><br>C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &ldquo;You are your planet and it is you; all of you, all together. You form a team and you are the one and the many. Your lift each other; as does the one, so does the other.&rdquo;<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>    <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you were standing in our physical shoes, what changes would you begin to make in our world right now?</em><br>C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&ldquo;None; we are not you. We cannot suggest a decision for you; your place is a creation of your planning and it is yours; you shall do with it as you choose, as you please and you desire. The arrogance of suggestion that a change we might like? This is not our thinking. We do not own your planet; we admire it as we admire you. You shall all decide as these decisions are yours, they are your place, your creation and they are your outcome for you to enjoy.&rdquo;<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ Going Home]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/going-home.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/going-home.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 16:33:05 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/04/going-home.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If one has had a difficult life and would like to go home even though it's not their time to go, can they pray for death and will death come?    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;All human life is ended with intention; all of you come to Earth with a plan and desire and expectation to end it. Your time to go is of [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em>Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If one has had a difficult life and would like to go home even though it's not their time to go, can they pray for death and will death come?</em><br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;All human life is ended with intention; all of you come to Earth with a plan and desire and expectation to end it. Your time to go is of your choosing; prayer to whom will be offered and will the request be granted by the recipient of the desire?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  If this you might believe, we ask; have you given away who you are? You have not, yet such desire takes from you control you always have. This you cannot do. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You cannot give away control; it might be temporarily seized from under you on Earth; yet this happening is often a choice made long ago, a choice you choose to recall not.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  If this life you describe as difficult, if it ends now, where will you go? Your hope would be to go where is it less difficult and as you understand, easy. Your expectation of easy will include the circumstances and surroundings of your place now, the difficulties subtracted. The departure will indeed alter the difficulties and the surroundings will be equally modified and often is the case, by a greater or larger effect. We can say with certainty, you will regret the removal of the surroundings that comes with the change in difficulty.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Your plan to live a life path and course cut short but for your frustration, unhappiness and dislike of what you have experienced, this desire is a part of the experience you have planned and encountered; to finish it before completion, to end it before it is done, to terminate before its arrival will cause you regret and repentance as you understand these emotions, in larger effect and amount than you can know on Earth. It will feel to you as if progress made, real and valid and beneficial to you, was wasted, thrown away and disposed. This is not the case yet feel this way, you will. So you will long to reincarnate to repair and re-do the termination so precipitous, as you have before and many of you do now.&rdquo;<br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ SPACE TRAVEL]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/space-travel.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/space-travel.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 16:30:33 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/space-travel.html</guid><description><![CDATA[  [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class='imgPusher' style='float:left;height:0px'></span><span style='z-index:10;position:relative;float:left;;clear:left;margin-top:0px;*margin-top:0px'><a><img src="http://www.theamendment.net/uploads/8/0/3/0/8030819/1365002269.jpg" style="margin-top: 5px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 10px; border-width:1px;padding:3px;" alt="Picture" class="galleryImageBorderBlack" /></a><div style="display: block; font-size: 90%; margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: 10px; text-align: center;"></div></span> <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;display:block;"><em style="">Q = Questioner T = Unidentified Space Traveler Alien Guest Being</em><br /><em style=""><br />Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why and how can beings from physical places, like the Pleiades star cluster, said to be about 425 light years distant, or Sirius at about 8&frac12; light years of travel to Earth, or any other place, come within the lifespan of a being from those places?</em><br /><span style=""></span><br />T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;  The idea of 425 years as Earth measures time is not the &ldquo;time&rdquo; required and this idea of time you hold? It is local. There is &ldquo;time&rdquo; in another physical location and it correlates not to another star. We say, the limit of the speed of light by your dimensional existence applies to your dimension; the distances you would measure by a distance light travels by one year of your time only apply to you as a resident of Earth. The concept of a parsec, the number of degree angles, this is a better measure as it considers the circular nature of the universe and distance and relativity.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So how long does it take, for a traveler from Pleiades, to reach Earth?</em><br />T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; By your time, less than 100 of your minutes.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To cross 425 light years?</em><br />T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; By your measure of it, yes.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To leave, arrive, do a day&rsquo;s work and return to Pleiades can be done in a day?</em><br />T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Yes, by one of your days. You do not have days on Earth; you have a day when combined with a place on Earth; lift yourself off the surface and hover above one spot and your days will end in the lapse of just one, by your clocks.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do the makers of crop circles hover and hang around, planning them? Or do they come from far away?</em><br />T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; These can be done by a more permanent visitor yet often are done by a day visit, as you would call it. It can be planned and done and we the makers then return to origin or travel elsewhere.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why don&rsquo;t we ever see a crop circle being made?</em><br />T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Because you would not believe it; we do say this has happened and the observers have considered themselves crazy in some cases and others simply do not speak of it, also for concern they would be called crazy. So they are often done at night, in your darkness so there will be no observers; humans do not remain in fields of crops at night.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Please explain how such distance can be traveled so quickly.</em><br />T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Each movement occurs along the edge of a circle, ever larger or smaller as a destination is pursued or followed or desired to be visited. There is no distance in a line, which as you would see this on Earth. We take your planet as an example; how many have known, in the western world, that digging a hole deep enough will lead to China? As a round globe is understood, indeed a hole would allow this, from the opposite area. This notion comes from your true understanding of your home of Heaven. The distance across your surface is farther than through the center; this is as it happens in outer space, the area around your planet.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The straight line is shorter, the curved longer but you say space travel is shorter along the curved and longer by what we&rsquo;d call the straight one?</em><br />T: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; The concepts of straight and curved on Earth do not apply away from your planet; you even force yourself into this view inside your solar system, yet as you know, it is a series of circles. On Earth the curved surface and the line through are of the same medium and dimension and so in this way are meaningful to each other; off your Earth, the opposite more true relation exists.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So how does the Pleiadian reach Earth?</em><br />T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The vessel used will reach the edge of the larger circuitous route that will intersect with the larger circuitous route, the time of travel is only long the circumference of the arc, the section of the circle&rsquo;s circumference. We refer to your program of television, Star Trek, which called higher speed travel, &ldquo;warp speed&rdquo;. This is a channeled notion, because true travel through your concept of outer space &ldquo;warps&rdquo; the straight line perception of Earth humanity. In actuality, your straight line view is the warped of the two if it could be said that way.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How is this done?</em><br />T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The destination is planned by comparing destination to origin; once the angles are known the mid-point of the journey is plotted and then steps to reach the midpoint; we suggest a mortar and the trajectory of its missile, its projectile. The movement is to the apogee and then the slug will fall to its target. The vessel will traverse the gap to destination by reach the midpoint, as you might say apogee, of the journey. Unlike a gravity force drawing the ship by mass, a more simple effect is used.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What are the angles?</em><br />T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There is no up or down or left and right; so the location of each end of the journey matter by its relative position; we say, reverse a photograph and then also turn it upside down. If you reverse your view along with the photo, it appears not reversed. So is this travel; so the placement of the destination is set relative to origin and the arrangement is reversed and inverted and moved around you, the traveler, to being destination to your trajectory, as each step of inversion and reversal take place, your ship switches arc of movement and follows a different trajectory.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How are these calculated?</em><br />T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; By your concepts of minutes of angle or parsecs in space; the parallax of intersection. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What propels a vessel so fast?</em><br />T: &nbsp; &nbsp;Speed as you comprehend it, this is not what occurs; density of matter to create rearrangement applies not. The movement of relativities around you can create this; we suggest a wind tunnel; does the air move and you remain stationary? Is the effect upon you the same as your movement through stationary air? Yes, and thus the notion of propulsion is the relation of movement.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When a ship reaches Earth, how does it move and propel itself?</em><br />T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Magnetism; your Earth is highly magnetic and makes this task easy. All planets have this.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  <em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How does an alien ship visiting Earth disguise itself?</em><br />T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You would call this a cloaking device; as your cloak blocks light form touching you and thus light must touch the cloak and that is what you the observer see, so exactly does the device; it blocks light from touching the vessel not by covering and interception of similar dimension but rather lifting the exterior electromagnetic field above your dimension&rsquo;s limits and so light passes through.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span><em>  Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wish to come back to this space travel subject.</em><br />T:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We will do so happily, be well.&rdquo;&nbsp;<br /><span style=""></span></div> <hr style="width:100%;clear:both;visibility:hidden;"></hr>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ REAL PERSONALITY]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/real-personality.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/real-personality.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 15:07:19 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/real-personality.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is our soul&rsquo;s real personality? I mean we incarnate to this planet as differing humans, each with a different set of experiences, surroundings, influences, nature and nurturing. So as we live and seek to live a harmonious life, who and what are we really like without this dense matter of flesh to shackle us? We come here many times and I understand our souls remain the same. Bu [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is our soul&rsquo;s real personality? I mean we incarnate to this planet as differing humans, each with a different set of experiences, surroundings, influences, nature and nurturing. So as we live and seek to live a harmonious life, who and what are we really like without this dense matter of flesh to shackle us? We come here many times and I understand our souls remain the same. But how do we know what our soul is really like as a personality. For example, for one lifetime we might wish to experience being a murderer and by the next lifetime we may choose to experience being a housewife or a domestic pet. These are all experiences but not truly who we are as soul beings. </em><br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;You do not experience this role as a murderer for your benefit; you do this as a sacrifice and by request. Great sacrifice is made. This risk and investment are enormous. To have done it from anger, rage, bitterness or evil desire are learned on Earth and likely you will provide yourself an opportunity to relive and avoid this.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The reality of your soul IS your life and you are, on Earth, who you are; you are a subset while here. We suggest places and roles of Earth as a comparison; does a father of family assume this role at a place of work, of employment? Does a husband treat a woman he barely knows at a store as he might his wife at home? So you see, your personality here, it is your personality. A smaller portion in many circumstances, the memories of lives past and plans forward set aside as if these were just files to be consulted later, as needed. This is all; you remain who you are and you will this always be. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The dense matter of flesh shackles you not; it liberates you into the wonderful experience of Earth and all this density of existence offer. Does a new and expensive car enclose and limit you? Certainly, as you choose to see this.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Your personality is as it is; this changes not.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Your return to Heaven reopens the files you have put up, put away and put aside; that is all.&nbsp;<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ physical body]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/physical-body.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/physical-body.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 14:50:40 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/physical-body.html</guid><description><![CDATA[  [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class='imgPusher' style='float:right;height:12px'></span><span style='z-index:10;position:relative;float:right;;clear:right;margin-top:20px;*margin-top:40px'><a><img src="http://www.theamendment.net/uploads/8/0/3/0/8030819/2842509.jpg?94" style="margin-top: 5px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-left: 10px; margin-right: 0px; border-width:0;" alt="Picture" class="galleryImageBorderBlack" /></a><div style="display: block; font-size: 90%; margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: 10px; text-align: center;"></div></span> <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;display:block;"><em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I often read the phrase "You are more than your physical body" and my imagination runs the gamut of what my physical mind could conjure up. It's not a lot as you know (being physical and all) Can you be a bit more specific with the &ldquo;more&rdquo;?&nbsp;</em><br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;Gladly we respond. Your body is your shell, your vehicle and your suit. Your mind is your essence and is the solidity of your existence. You express through the body you have designed and come to occupy in this life; the feeling given is one of solidity and substance and this is intentional, as the sensations and feeling the body provides create the integration with surroundings. These are your life experiences; you are not this body. You existed quite solidly and substantially before this body and will remain the same substantial and solid person after the body is no longer.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    We would take the physical remains of a person known well; known well to you as a relative or friend or to the general public. This person dies and as we know, the physical remains of the body disappear, in several ways. Do the memories of the person likewise disappear? So the memories remain where the body has gone. Consider yourself; why will all people who knew you well forget you after you pass on? You know, they will not as you will also remember, as you already have, all people who passed on that you did know. The memories of all of us remain with the people who will pass on after we return to our home of Heaven. In all cases, the bodies fade from existence and the memories persist; is this not true?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span></div> <hr style="width:100%;clear:both;visibility:hidden;"></hr>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>