<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >

<channel><title><![CDATA[&nbsp; www.theamendment.net &nbsp; - HOME]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/index.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[HOME]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 09:16:04 -0600</pubDate><generator>Weebly</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Fear]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/fear.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/fear.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 03:03:03 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/fear.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What individual effect and what collective, group effects are created by the emotion of fear? How do these compare to excitement and joy?    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We aim for understanding; we say, everything we say in this place, all is for understanding, comprehension, interpretation and awareness. [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What individual effect and what collective, group effects are created by the emotion of fear? How do these compare to excitement and joy?</em><br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We aim for understanding; we say, everything we say in this place, all is for understanding, comprehension, interpretation and awareness.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  These are the qualities that bring peace to you, what we want incessantly for the people of the planet you all love, your Earth.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Infectious laughter, a phrase known well, has its counterpart. Just as the chuckle will ignite this reaction in your surroundings, so will its opposite. The good news is happiness trumps this opposite; there are no equal values by the two; any amount of happy overrides the fear, the fright and the scare.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The unknown creates a sensation of fear where the eventualities are not understood and thus we communicate with you all this way, to provide you with the stop.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Even a slowing of fear places it far behind all other emotions, yet its manifestation, its emergence and its spread have equal ability to contaminate.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Eliminate it you can, reduce it you will; by loss of fear great joy will be gained. Satisfaction rises from the basis of what was previously unknown when truth is understood; we wish to give this to you.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Acceptance of the previously unknown will not reduce fear, will not deduct it from the now and will not prevent its growth and rise. Fear must be overcome with contentment, satisfaction and peace and these, beloved readers, come from knowing.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Where fear befalls you, look first at what you fear and its loss you will see. This has no other way; a fear faced is a fear erased. This is immutable in the universe; this holds fast and true every place.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Fear is caused by loss of money; but only the loss of your own. Examine this effect; if all were to lose by proportion to their amount the same money, there would be no loss at all. If all money disappeared in an instant, there would not be a fear, there would be an opportunity. Soon a new medium of exchange would rise, the efficiency of the money restored with more of it.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The fear is truly the expected inability to obtain, not what it is.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  If all money disappeared in one instant, would the sun go dark, the planet go dead and all people wrinkle away into Heaven? &nbsp;<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  If all money were quadrupled in amount as prices were halved, what would truly change? More wealth some would feel yet more carrots could you eat? More houses could you fill? More clothes could you wear, in any one instant?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Would hunger be doubled or air twice demanded? Could more water be drunk, more eye blinks produced? &nbsp;Would more sleep be now needed, more sheets for a bed?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Would clouds be expensive, rubbish now scarce?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Would food not be sold, no crops ever grown, if money as given, disappeared from the fold?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Would beauty be greater, bad hair ever banished, winks free of charge, no bugs ever famished?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  But fear you might feel, for practice has shown, to lose all one&rsquo;s money means nothing you&rsquo;d own?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  So think of the cause, ponder the sight, of cash wealth all gone and no banker-like fright.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Kick debts away, kill off what is owed, enjoy newfound balance, finance to unload.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We practice your words, arrange them as speech, offer them up with meaning for each.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Poems make sense, pennies make pounds, you life is not cash, you&rsquo;re all still around.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Fear not what will change, flip that coin over, under its top you shall find a new clover.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The emotion might spread and make itself grow, unless you agree, you all shall say no.<br /><span style=""></span><br />Collude to be happy, concur with good hope, now come all together, even slow pokes.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Smiles will spread, even butter might envy, the way you all cover, the effect once so heavy<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Lightness of joy and levity now, will make progress quick and amazing is how<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Poetry touches, the heart of your soul, sounds by all science, harmonic will grow<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Energy expanded, power increased, this is what happens with good humor grease.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Fear makes dark clouds, worry brings night, kick it away and make things more bright<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Face what concerns, look straight in its eye, tell it to go, a kite it can fly<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Your life on Earth yours, your trip going well, so all the bad things, can just go to hell<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Strong is your will, mighty your love to make yourself happy and soft as a dove.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We know it&rsquo;s not simple, to cast it aside, that worrisome bitch, superficial pride<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The answer&rsquo;s within, the key is inside, to unlock your power, your force gone outside<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Look up to the Heavens, ask always for help, we love you today, no need to now yelp.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Do unto others what you want for yourself, scare off the fright, knock down its old shelf<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Kill what is heavy, give birth to the light, for worry can&rsquo;t stand the brightness of right<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Faith in your soul, pleasure with life, cuts fear into bits like a sharp and hot knife<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Choose not to worry, bake happiness cakes, your love is what matters, that's all that it takes.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You came to be born and you grow to the sky, with greatness inside and a gleam in your eyes.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The Heavens are yours, and you own the Earth too, so always be happy, as we are with you!<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Be well!<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spirituality is Science]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/spirituality-is-science.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/spirituality-is-science.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 22:43:06 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/spirituality-is-science.html</guid><description><![CDATA[What is an alien?We are all "aliens" by our understanding; a physical being from another planet, star, solar system or place in this galaxy, another one or someplace else in the universe.To be alien is to show abilities we all have; set well aside for the moment (remember, moment and momentum are the same thing) as we live on Earth.Examples come from time to time; here we have one: [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;">What is an alien?<br /><br />We are all "aliens" by our understanding; a physical being from another planet, star, solar system or place in this galaxy, another one or someplace else in the universe.<br /><br />To be alien is to show abilities we all have; set well aside for the moment (remember, moment and momentum are the same thing) as we live on Earth.<br /><br />Examples come from time to time; here we have one:<br /><br /><a title="" target="_blank" href="http://biertijd.com/mediaplayer/?itemid=25540" style="">http://biertijd.com/mediaplayer/?itemid=25540</a><br /><br />A demonstration of our mind, the power of our thoughts. Remember you create always effects as strong and clear as seen in this video, the difference is how we are accustomed to the effects we create; our movement of the arm and hand begin with thought; the design of the house begins by thinking and the cure for disease begins this way also. We are trained to see a pattern of thought then to movement then to result; here we have thought to result with movement we are TEMPORARILY not used to seeing.<br /><br />Does anybody ever wonder how and why tarot cards work? Wonder no more.<br /><br />Does this seem foolish, like trickery and to not be believed? Then your veil you designed well but assume not that your veil is like that of the every, because it is resembles that of the many.<br /><br />Is this "true"? Is is "real"? &nbsp;Your feelings will tell.<br />&nbsp;</div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Saint Malachy - Prophecy of Popes]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/saint-malachy-prophecy-of-popes.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/saint-malachy-prophecy-of-popes.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 23:01:22 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/saint-malachy-prophecy-of-popes.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q1. The alleged prophecies were first published by Benedictine monk Arnold Wion in 1595. Wion attributes the prophecies to Saint Malachy, a 12th&#8209;century Archbishop of Armagh, Ireland. Can you ask St. Malachy, if these prophecies were his or were they fabricated by Arnold Wion or Someone else? How did these prophetic visions come to him? Q2. Is there truth in the predic [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="font-size: 17px; line-height: 18px;">Q1. The alleged prophecies were first published by Benedictine monk Arnold Wion in 1595. Wion attributes the prophecies to Saint Malachy, a 12th&#8209;century Archbishop of Armagh, Ireland. Can you ask St. Malachy, if these prophecies were his or were they fabricated by Arnold Wion or Someone else? How did these prophetic visions come to him?</em><br /><em style=""> Q2. Is there truth in the prediction that this Pope Francis of 2013, will be the last Pope? If not, will he be one of the last?</em><em style=""><br /> Q3. Is the Pope Francis same as Peter the Roman mentioned as the 112th pope in the prophecy?<br /> Concerning the 112th pope, this is St. Malachy's purported prediction. "In the final persecution of the Holy Roman Church, there will sit [i.e., as bishop]. Peter the Roman, who will pasture his sheep in many tribulations, and when these things are finished, the city of seven hills [i.e. Rome] will be destroyed, and the dreadful judge will judge his people. The End.[13]"<br /> Q4. Will Rome be destroyed at some point in future?&nbsp;<br /> Q5. What does it mean when it says "dreadful judge will judge his people"? Who is this dreadful judge, God? HigherSelf of every individual?<br /> Q6. Will there be an apocalypse? Will many people die? Definition of Apocalypse from Merriam Webster online : one of the Jewish and Christian writings of 200 BC to AD 150 marked by pseudonymity, symbolic imagery, and the expectation of an imminent cosmic cataclysm in which God destroys the ruling powers of evil and raises the righteous to life in a messianic kingdom<br /> Q7. The outgoing pope Benedict says "God told me to go"&nbsp;Does that sound like God wants to connect the change of papacy with this prophecy of Peter the Roman and a upcoming days of judgment and tribulations ?<br /> Q8. What can we do to be the best during the apocalypse or time of great change and tribulations and judgment? Any advice for humanity to prepare for the change?<br /> Q9. Have you reincarnated anywhere on earth currently? Do you plan to in future? What do you do in afterlife nowadays?</em><br /><br /><span style=""></span>  C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;Great appreciation we have for your nine questions and we hope to disappoint terribly with our response, for so good and representative these questions are, and we thank you as much as can thanks be offered for so ideal an opportunity of illustration such questions provide. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  These things ask about religion, human bodies of thought about Home. Heaven. Reality. Existence. Permanence. The journey of a life to Earth, so long and done so quickly, once it is done. Your longing for the explanation you all know already, but for its very brief, yet permanently appearing place to where you have set it, sits just outside your life and yet is a part of it always.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  All notions of religion grow in appeal on Earth as they touch upon detail and memory you carry within, a deep part of your soul. Religion is an idea of man; it is memory of the Heavens seen through the limits of humanity.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  What this Saint suggested bore great meaning in the organization of his life. Great vision was he able to express and much certainty did he speak. He is, in your Earth time, long gone and has come and gone again several times hence. The accuracy and meaning of his prophecy are not just what is offered in them yet also what is seen in them and chosen to be true. This soul saw importance in this story, as he returned to live a life as Pope centuries later, that life also finished.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We suggest, for comparison, another phase of human life, as an example of the meaning of a prophecy; slavery. In the large nation of the US of A, no longer do there live enslaved peoples, enslavers or their children. The lives that made it are done, all of them; your life knows now, knows it not, but for stories; you are not a part. Does the idea of restitution live on? Why?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  These church leaders, long ago mentioned, have come and gone in the same way, their life lived and purpose given to their growth from the lives experiened.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The latest person to assume this role; he will have great meaning where and how it is chosen to be provided; there is no influence or strength or power over humanity where humanity supplies it not; accuracy of the prophetic detail assumes your choices and will cannot be changed from the place where they were said; if true were this, your will and choice would not be yours, you would not be human.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Yes, this man who lives as Pope now has done so previously in this role. God did not tell the departed one to abdicate his position; this choice made as he decided. God would never tell any of you how to live; only suggest what will help you and then show you where and how a benefit is found. There are other ways for benefit and God&rsquo;s love and blessing for your choices will follow you always, as it has followed this man just resigned.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  There will be no apocalypse as your question describes it; these things said many a century of your time ago, are as you call them, allegories which allude to events now happening and soon to come, but there is no apocalypse to befall Earth.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  There is no dreadful judge for a dreadful people; this saying arises from an Earth thought of religion, damnation and punishment as explanation for what was not understood. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  There will be Popes as Popes are desired; if the choosers lose interest, so will the position. We speculate not upon its likelihood; this question is Earth. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Rome will go on. The organization of a church will see change and to this the phrase refers.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Your question of preparation we like best and so have chosen to speak of it last; we know of the ninth, not directed at us, your typist as he says. Attention is shunned, no importance has it for the many. So you know we have not ignored.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You shall prepare as you have already prepared; your visit to these words and your thoughts upon reading them are evidence and symptom of your preparation. There is nothing more you need do; the concern for preparation arises from the view of tasks, lists of chores and work for progress that permeate your humanity. These are fine, we mean not to criticize it, it is as you have all chosen, and this is good.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Religion is important to you the many and we say, where it supplies comfort, certainty and answers to the things you would know, it is good. It is not bad, nothing on Earth is ever this way; we know great disagreement there could be to this, and we know there is much dislike of many things. All events, all acts, all undertakings and all movement on Earth are good; religion is but one part of the greater hope; where it appeals, seek it. Where it attracts not, go not. Where it repels, you have seen its greatest value of all, in this you have found the greatest purpose of religious thought and you are its champion, you who reject it and dislike it. You give it the life needed to cause its review, its assessment and its audit and in this, great benefit and value does humanity derive, for yourself and all around you, for this you do best on Earth; you QUESTION.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Be happy and chins highest!&rdquo;&nbsp;<br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Heavenly Tunes]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/heavenly-tunes.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/heavenly-tunes.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 22:06:53 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/heavenly-tunes.html</guid><description><![CDATA[  [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class='imgPusher' style='float:left;height:0px'></span><span style='z-index:10;position:relative;float:left;;clear:left;margin-top:0px;*margin-top:0px'><a><img src="http://www.theamendment.net/uploads/8/0/3/0/8030819/5001610.gif?93" style="margin-top: 5px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 10px; none;" alt="Picture" class="galleryImageBorder" /></a><div style="display: block; font-size: 90%; margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: 10px; text-align: center;"></div></span> <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;display:block;"><em style="">Q:&nbsp; I would surmise that poetry and song are quite popular in the afterlife. Would it be possible to share with us either the lyrics or prose of such.&nbsp;<br /><br /></em><em style="">Also is there a favourite kind of music they enjoy over there or do they get a kick out of watching and listening to the X-Factor.</em><br /><br />C:&nbsp; Music, yes! Song with your words? Poetry of your language? Less so, not common. Ideas with thought are what we communicate, not words of speech as you have.<br /><br />All music and sounds are enjoyed; and we say, just as there is harmony of sounds on Earth, so have we here. The pleasant sounds of notes and chords and groups of them align the frequencies of vibration, as you know well. Our level of vibration much higher also includes all vibrations of slower, in the levels you now fill, and these expand the variety of sound we might use and enjoy here.&nbsp;<br /><br />The music we enjoy the most is the happiness produced by its sounds; upon observation of your Earth, we enjoy most the joy and pleasure and entertainment felt by all of you; where any of the souls of Heaven might look upon just one soul or a great grouping, your concerts, and see many people happy with enjoyment, THIS is the music of Earth we like the best.<br /><br />This enjoyment we have also; we can produce sounds as we like and also we create instruments as you know them for temporary use, which we do often. Your duets, trios, quartets and more, great enjoyment do we derive from this and we say, these things you do as you remember them from Heaven. Your singing groups, what you have named acapella, we enjoy especially as these sounds come from your bodies and the essence of your souls; these sounds are your words and the stories they tell, yes, and they are much more and we love them even more than you know!<br /><br />In Heaven all of these things are expanded; your American jazz, the improvised tunes and random playing of songs both known and invented in the moment, these are wonderful and are a great memory and glimpse into the music of Heaven expanded beyond your imagination. Your church choirs, outstanding and captivating.&nbsp;<br /><br />We enjoy all of your art, be it by your television, radio or any other medium. Until you return to Heaven, enjoy what you have always, as when you rediscover the breadth of music as you will both have and create to compare with the rudimentary way done on Earth, ever with the same value and meaning to your happiness, you will appreciate all the more and the better your time of music upon Earth.&nbsp;</div> <hr style="width:100%;clear:both;visibility:hidden;"></hr>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Purpose of Existence]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/purpose-of-existence.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/purpose-of-existence.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 21:45:17 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/purpose-of-existence.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the purpose for existence, really? What we basically exist for is to be born from God, then experience lessons, then return and be one with God forever? That's basically what I've been hearing...Also, when we are one with God, all that is and will be, what will we do?     C:&nbsp; &ldquo;Ask we must, how would you describe non-existence? The question assumes your  [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><font size="4"><em>Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the purpose for existence, really? What we basically exist for is to be born from God, then experience lessons, then return and be one with God forever? That's basically what I've been hearing...Also, when we are one with God, all that is and will be, what will we do? </em><br><br><span style=""></span>    C:&nbsp; &ldquo;Ask we must, how would you describe non-existence? The question assumes your existence implies purpose; a goal, objective and outcome. These things, ending and results, are of time sequence and events. These are of your Earth existence. These concepts are not your reality; notions of your subset of reality, this is what they are.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  We suggest your notion of expansion; there is not a place to start, another to end and throughout, steps taken. This approach is human and it supports the purpose, if there were a purpose, a reason, a justification and a motivation, as you know these words of English.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  There are many moments of ecstasy, with certainty yet also complexity of society and the interaction of all souls is vast and varied; the limits of Earth are not found. Ever do you evolve and grow and upon return you will see the great leaps your trip has given, the advance and depth and growth to your understanding. This is not seen from Earth; there is up and down, and left and right. In your true home, there are not these limits, not your movement in the physical way and not in any other way.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  You will do things of detail, complexity and interaction as you do not imagine on Earth, as Earth limits these things. This is not to say Earth is limited; Earth is designed, constructed and arranged with reason for placement, as a building could be limited by size, architecture and interpretation of its style and its use, by desires that could be given. Yet a building of great beauty, presence and use is not seen as a limitation; it is seen as a great asset, great shrine, monument and portion of the patrimony of its people. This is Earth.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  You are with God now, and you always were and always will be; you do not return to a place you have not departed. You do not learn all of your lessons; <u>much we like this part of your question</u>. It speaks to a successful visit; and it tells of your advance. You have gone to a great place, where you are admired and loved and held in great esteem for just the thing you have said, that you might learn all of your lessons and then have none left to learn. This is not reality and is not your existence. It is not God and is not your source.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  Strong is the notion of perfection on Earth, yet as all know, it exists not; as we have said just recently by your timeline, perfection is opinion of limit. It is perception and interpretation of absolutes; this concept is used to great advantage on Earth as an ideal not reached but for the methods, the thoughts and ideas offered, if only you will agree to follow. Religion you this call.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  This is not the way; the notion of perfection implies ending, completion and exhaustion. This happens not on Earth, as you all know well, as it happens not anywhere in the universe. There is no list of tasks to be exhausted, your journey does not end and there is no graduation, with requirements for all to be met by some. No, you know what you want and requirements for these you set for yourself and only for yourself. Help, assistance and love surround you always and progress you make with every breath, but for the veil of humanity that keeps it just beyond your sight and just outside your complete memory of who you are. <br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  You know not when you life on Earth will finish; you do not want to know. You have ideals for your happiness, do you not? Certainly yes, and with good faith in yourself and goodwill to reach this, you live your days with joy where you can find it and faith it will come back, in the moments you feel it not. Your ups &amp; downs, as you say. This is your existence always, in Heaven and on Earth, and there will always be what brings you joy and happiness and love and the accompaniment of the souls who love you.<br><span style=""></span><br><span style=""></span>  Be good and be well!&rdquo;</font><br></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[droW fo tsiwT]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/drow-fo-tsiwt.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/drow-fo-tsiwt.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 16:57:58 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/drow-fo-tsiwt.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Confused you am  [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<span class='imgPusher' style='float:left;height:0px'></span><span style='z-index:10;position:relative;float:left;;clear:left;margin-top:0px;*margin-top:0px'><a><img src="http://www.theamendment.net/uploads/8/0/3/0/8030819/3066122.jpg?142" style="margin-top: 5px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 10px; border-width:1px;padding:3px;" alt="Picture" class="galleryImageBorderBlack" /></a><div style="display: block; font-size: 90%; margin-top: -10px; margin-bottom: 10px; text-align: center;">Confused you am are I think you not as; understand?  Good.</div></span> <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;display:block;"><ul><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">Day care police charged a three-year-old with resisting a rest.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">A broken pencil is pointless.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">A short, fugitive psychic is a small medium at large.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">Doubts about earthquake science placed it on shaky ground.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">Depleted batteries are always distributed free of charge.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">Even backward poets write inverse.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">An historic grenade fell onto a French kitchen floor; linoleum blown apart.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">A calendar's days are numbered.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">A boiled egg is hard to beat.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">Bakers operate on a knead to know basis</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">A hungry clock goes back four seconds.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">You are stuck with debt if you can't budge it.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">A good plateau is high flattery.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">Those too big for their britches are exposed in the end.</span><br /></li><li><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 16px;">Seen one shopping center, you've seen a mall.</span><br /></li></ul></div> <hr style="width:100%;clear:both;visibility:hidden;"></hr>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Predictions]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/predictions1.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/predictions1.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 21:44:34 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/predictions1.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What challenges await humanity? What&rsquo;s in store for us? What&rsquo;s coming and what do we do?  C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;Ask we must, how will you all react? What will you do? Say? Believe? Respond? These are more important than events you have not caused, what shall be the things of importance to you.  You [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><font size="4"><em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What challenges await humanity? What&rsquo;s in store for us? What&rsquo;s coming and what do we do?</em><br /> <br /> C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;Ask we must, how will you all react? What will you do? Say? Believe? Respond? These are more important than events you have not caused, what shall be the things of importance to you.<br /> <br /> Your life on Earth was not designed to be a free-for-all, where each of you roams adrift in the circumstances completely the result of human creation.<br /> <br /> The impression upon the many of you is this; a good thing as so you have chosen it. The feeling that acts have results, choices turn into outcomes and decisions become effects, this feeling is what drives your life and provides for you what you seek and gain from life on Earth.<br /> <br /> All of you receive these things; there is no exception, no exclusion and no separation from this. All of you exist in the environment of the circumstances you have created. Your ability to decide is complete and the greater things to come, the larger events not controlled by you individually, you have chosen to participate. There is no compulsion, no force. You have not chosen your place now on Earth to be hurt by world events; you have come to feel them, be them and form them, by your responses and reactions. It is not what happens, it is what you feel and decide to do, to help yourself and those around you.<br /> <br /> There will be great change on Earth, upheaval of the physical and effects upon you all. These are all a great opportunity and with joy and glee we await your participation, as you have decided you will have. Great honor, pride and admiration we feel, as we have not, the many of us, chosen to be where you are. The opportunity was and is, yet the takers &ndash; you, all of you, our beloved brothers and sisters &ndash; you did, where we have not. The changes and effects to be felt will alter the pattern of Earth society in ways not known by your memories on Earth. Upheaval of the Earth has not happened in the history of your surface, yet we can say, it has occurred and this time, a great step forward will be taken. A re-set of humanity and development was the result of past tumult and many lives were ended. This time far less; as you have chosen.<br /> <br /> There is not blame, anger, frustration or disappointment and no shame, guilt or unease should anyone feel for imperfection you see. Perfection was never a goal and will never be reached, and you do not want this.<br /> <br /> Perfection is opinion of limit; what is its meaning and who defines it? Can the standard never be changed? Why is the idea of perfection something to be set and forgotten? It is but an ideal, a concept and a thought but it is not and never has been reality in the universe.<br /> <br /> Do your best; react swiftly when the chance presents and do what you would like others to do for you, in their place. In the honesty of your mind, where no other human might go as you believe, you know what you would like for yourself. Simply this you supply to others and the greatest of reward shall you have.<br /> <br /> Volcanoes&nbsp;will erupt; ice will melt, seas will rise. Change will come to commerce, trade and business. Authoritarian functions will not cope with these events and as they attempt it, calmly observe yet fret not at failure. This is the change that you have all come to experience.<br /> <br /> Opportunity there will be to create anew, and a great challenge will be offered, for the ideals of today will not be available tomorrow. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    Money's role will&nbsp;change, employment and its remuneration will change, there will be unrest and chaos by the reactions of the few. Worry not and hold your mind high, for hardship to hurt humanity is not what happens.<br /> <br /> When great change comes to the many, it will not be felt as a loss; we understand this will be seen as troublesome, for experience in these tumults you remember not. The seizure of a house for debt requires sale to another; when sales there cannot be, seizures there also will not be, yet this will take some of your time to manifest. The media of exchange in your commerce and trade, your money and currencies, hold value by you only as you see them to represent your ability to trade. This will diminish.<br /> <br /> Reliance on central leadership will be forced from day to day life and the role of this function will fade.<br /> <br /> Great help and assistance comes to you from your cousins, your brothers and sisters of the galaxy; hints, ideas and suggestions will flow and much of it could seem coincidental, arbitrary and haphazard. Your way will be as you choose it; where general effects might threaten the&nbsp;well-being&nbsp;of humanity, intervention there will be. Technology has presented opportunity for gain and risk for destruction, yet this will be, as it has been on many&nbsp;occasions, prevented.<br /> <br /> Love the things that bring you joy, hope and contentment, the things of value in your life. What you might lose or buy or gain or sell, these not so important a role they take in your life&rsquo;s joy. Fret not at forces beyond your control; it is good to understand them, to be aware but know that change comes to humanity and the forces of the negative seen to hurt goodwill and good cheer are not as strong as they sometimes seem and they will soon matter very little.<br /> <br /> Nations will break up; blame will be offered. Accept the actions taken to preserve what you might have and remember with joy the good feelings of the place you fill where its role is different.<br /> <br /> Europe as we know it will return to her past, localized and focused not on worldly matters, the US of A will also go through great change and development, to be characterized negatively. It is not and worry little for the changes to that which your life did not rule.<br /> <br /> Political leaders, as you admire or dislike, have come not to provide and support and create for you, for this they never did. By promise and failure you will come to see that you never depended upon an organization you created and came to see as necessary. Its role will shrink and the dependence will be seen far smaller than now; we understand your time and your perception of it, for the many of us have lived this dense existence you have now. In not so much time, starting soon in these next two years and over a period of fifteen to twenty, societies on Earth will steadily evolve into something difficult to imagine, as could be extrapolated from history of the last two of your centuries. This is true progress and advance and it will involve the perceived loss of many distractions, soon to be seen as little loss at all. Embrace and enjoy the opportunities to arise, listen not to the talk that says otherwise.<br /> <br /> Allow us a return to what we said at the start; your response, reaction and answer are always yours and you always have the way to go forward and see the positive and this is the choice you should make always.<br /> <br /> Seek never to cause the need for protection in another, remain always ready to protect yourself and by this approach, the need shall pass you by.<br /> <br /> Be generous always, for the generosity you would need will be offered by your acts.<br /> <br /> Be friendly when you can, be gracious when you are able and be yourself always, always true to your hopes and desires and the benefit of humanity.<br /> <br /> Be well and good day!&rdquo;</font><br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Akashic Records]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/akashic-records.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/akashic-records.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 17:45:49 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/akashic-records.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q1: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;What benefit can we as humans gain from the Akashic Records?  C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&ldquo;We believe a diversion to vocabulary is helpful, it will provide some understanding of the human view of records and history, the way these are used in human society. Human language is universal; all societie [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="font-size: large; line-height: 17px;">Q1: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;What benefit can we as humans gain from the Akashic Records?</em><br /><font size="4"><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&ldquo;We believe a diversion to vocabulary is helpful, it will provide some understanding of the human view of records and history, the way these are used in human society. Human language is universal; all societies have this principal means of communication to construct complex thought from simple sounds, the pieces and parts of the thoughts to so identify. These are your names, for everything separate. Names to identify ourselves with you, to fit this approach. Where communication disposes of language, because it is not your natural way, naming also falls away. Identification is not by label, language used not. Akhasic is another of names to identify and we understand it means past times and lives on Earth, events complete, lives fulfilled, civilizations evolved and gone.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Understanding is what you gain; recognition of development as it has always been and continues now. It is a view into your true nature. Essence and spirits, as lived on Earth.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The concept of time and events occurring in sequence; this is the greatest difference between life on Earth and your true home; timelines create a past, your memories wrapped in it, temporarily. Memory is experience, records one way to hold them. This is the purpose they serve to you.&rdquo;<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    <em style="">Q2: &nbsp; &nbsp; Is there anything we can tap into during our human life to help us with our challenges?</em><br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&ldquo;Yes, as challenges have always been part of life, the reason it exists. The steps to overcome them or fall under their weight are not new, these have always been and will always be. There is not a library to visit, these records are available inside you. What you call your intuition and gut feelings are these records as you consider memories and past times.&rdquo;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>    <em style="">Q3: &nbsp; Is it possible to tap into alternate realities that might be available to us to change our &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; lives, the lives of others, and the planet for the better?</em><br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &ldquo;Generally no, and we say, alternate realities is not a good way to describe this. All is real and all is reality, there is no alternate. You wish to say other courses, other lives, other circumstances. This you do not do in the one life; the saying that grass is always greener on the other side is a part of this. The other course of life brings not just differences with the life you have now, it also brings circumstance and opportunity and challenge. Once assumed, you would have all of these things together in that alternative and again you could feel the need to change and explore.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Alternatives you will explore certainly, as you have in many past lives and lives to come again for the many of you.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  There is not an alternative to which you will connect, where methods, ideas and practices will be learned to make things &ldquo;better&rdquo; as you understand it. All of the betterment is already within you all, as you understand and want better to be.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Look at the skin of your arm or leg; do you wish it to be green or blue? You came to have it as you see it; all parameters of your surroundings you came to have as you find them; some of these can be changed, others not. The limits are all known and chosen and for many purposes that, once abandoned would become more obvious as to why you chose them and needed them.&rdquo;</font><br /><br /><em><span style="line-height: 17px;">Q</span><span style="font-size: large; line-height: 17px;">4: &nbsp; &nbsp; Who is the keeper of the Akashic Records?</span></em><br /><font size="4"><br />C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;"Records of your existence on Earth are kept with all of you and all of the universe; the existence of energy and its solidity above all things, its permanence and finality are the medium, the holding and the placement of the records of all things. Allow us a moment of diversion to this topic; what is solid upon Earth is a ghostly image of no substance, yet it is real and solid to you. Records and information are permanent, fade not and come back with instant recall and clarity, not as an Earth existence allows them to fade and become dim. Think of your solid Earth, rock, stone, concrete and mountain as frozen light. Unfreeze ice and the energy of the water strong it becomes; the liquid as gas yet stronger, consider the power of steam to turn and rotate. So is this the way memories and records exist in the lightness of your true existence, and fade not, diminish not. Just as liquid or frozen air has less or no effect upon surroundings, yet gaseous air will destroy as strong wind, so the existence of information as memory and record enable its quick recall and use in the higher dimensions.&nbsp;</font><br /><br /><font size="4">All of you are the keeper of the records of all of you."<br /></font><br /><font size="4"><em>Q5: &nbsp; &nbsp; What is the purpose of it?</em><br /><br /></font><font size="4">C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; "The purpose of records and memories are the purpose of your soul; the blocks and pieces that construct you are your memories and experiences. You are what you have experienced, what you have done and what you have been a part of, in all dimensions, on Earth and everyplace else."</font><br /><br /><font size="4"><em>Q6. &nbsp; &nbsp; Is it unalterable?</em><br /><br /></font><font size="4">C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; "Yes, experience is. Other experience also is. Alternatives to one experience are. All of them are. They do not change; this means erasure, expulsion, disappearance and replacement. This is not possible; all that is will be. You do not expunge what is; it is expanded, the combinations of all to benefit all."&nbsp;</font><br /><br /><font size="4"><em>Q7. &nbsp; &nbsp; How can we tap into it ourselves?&nbsp;</em><br /><br /></font><font size="4">C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;"This quite simple is; ask and listen. What you need and what benefits you will be for you and you shall have it. If you think you get not what you have requested, believe not that you cannot hear, do not understand and will not receive. You do understand and know, all of you, without exception. This is not what operates with your memories and records and histories. You will not have what you need not,&nbsp;curiosity&nbsp;of your Earth life no matter."</font><br /><br /><font size="4"><em>Q8. &nbsp; &nbsp; Paramahamsa Nithyananda (Swamiji) initiates Akashic Readings on crucial life subjects. He reads it in English. How does the channel download this so that we can understand it?</em><br /><br /></font><font size="4">C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;"We enjoy this term of 'download' as Earth computer function mimics the universe in a basic way and yes, this is what occurs. The source of the information is interpreted from thought to word by the person supplying it among humans; this is as happens now with what you read in this moment. We type not, we speak not and we use no words; we give the thought and idea and concept and choose the few words we believe better express the pieces and parts to build what we say, and the human brain data assembles the blocks of letter, word, sentence and paragraph for them to be understood."</font><br /><br /><font size="4"><em>Q9. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Is he accurately interpreting info from the Akashic Records?</em></font><br /><br /><font size="4">C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; "Yes, all information is accurate by your belief of it, which derives from your feeling. Accuracy is a two sided equation; issuance and receipt, dispatch and arrival,&nbsp;commencement&nbsp;and completion. The two parts combined produce the&nbsp;accuracy, the truth and the precision of what you hear. Where you doubt and disagree, there is inaccuracy yet this implies not a shortage of truth; it means this truth for you fits not and so inaccurate it is, or truthful and certain also it will be."</font><br /><br /><font size="4"><em>Q<span style="line-height: 17px;">10. &nbsp; &nbsp;Are the Akashic Records the same as Jung's "collective&nbsp;</span>unconscious<span style="line-height: 17px;">"?</span></em><br /></font><br /><span style="line-height: 17px;"><font size="4">C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; "Smile we do, as a good name to this you suggest and yes, it is just as was said. It is a collective body of knowledge and experience of which humanity is not immediately aware or does not speak where awareness there is.&nbsp;</font></span><br /><br /><span style="line-height: 17px;"><font size="4">It is not so completely unconscious; all that would need to be known is there for use; recall and remember your life on Earth; you did not travel to be where you are now to remain what you truly are in your home, in the completeness of your existence. If you were, no reason would you have to be where you are now.</font></span><br /><br /><span style="line-height: 17px;"><font size="4">You have taken your place as you have chosen and this is separate, for the experience you shall have.</font></span><br /><br /><font size="4"><span style="line-height: 17px;">Time on your Earth is what you should&nbsp;</span>understand<span style="line-height: 17px;">&nbsp;from observations of your solar system. Park yourself where you can observe your beautiful Earth rotate and revolve; the surface will rotate and light will come and go to the surface and the planet will trace a circle about the star, your sun. As you observe a person upon the surface, you will see changes as you will see in all things. The person will start a life and grow and learn and changes will there be to the body and experience gained. The Earth might rotate twenty, twenty five, thirty or thirty five thousand times as this body lives, and the globe will lap the star&nbsp;</span>many<span style="line-height: 17px;">&nbsp;</span>dozens<span style="line-height: 17px;">&nbsp;of times as it rotates. It goes nowhere; it remains in this place and vibrates within its space always where it is. There is no&nbsp;</span>passage<span style="line-height: 17px;">&nbsp;from a place to a place and the life upon it ends where started. The soul that has gone there came from one or many places and can observe, alongside the observer in this example, before going into a body on the surface and can return to this place when done. The experiences of the many laps about the star, these are the permanence of the soul and appear not to be; they show up not as a library, not as an archive and have no&nbsp;</span>catalog,<span style="line-height: 17px;">&nbsp;no listing, no map, no guide for their access, as you all know from your life on Earth.</span></font><br /><font size="4"><span style="line-height: 17px;"><br /></span></font><font size="4"><span style="line-height: 17px;">These are always and exist permanently and all souls that might want or need to see the 'unconscious collective' can do it, as they choose. You choose what you believe you will need to know, before you go, and when the need does go, the detail always will show."</span></font></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Heavenly Clocking]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/heavenly-clocking.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/heavenly-clocking.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 22:02:48 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/heavenly-clocking.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If there is no time in heaven, can a soul incarnate into the past date in human history? Like say, 1500 A.D instead of 2013? Can this incarnated soul alter history by doing something, like say, kill a king or some important person before he could create history? If that happens, which historical continuity is altered, the one we are living now in 2013 o [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><em style="font-size: large; line-height: 17px;">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If there is no time in heaven, can a soul incarnate into the past date in human history? Like say, 1500 A.D instead of 2013? Can this incarnated soul alter history by doing something, like say, kill a king or some important person before he could create history? If that happens, which historical continuity is altered, the one we are living now in 2013 or a parallel one will follow from events of 1500 AD?</em><br /><font size="4"><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  C: &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; "Yes, there are no past and future dates where there is no time, as you measure on Earth. Examine your example; a return to your fourteenth or fifteenth century to assassinate a king and alter the course of history.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You assume the power of your concept of king, to believe the killing of one alters the course of history. Would he or she that might do this be a king because of it? We say no, and know you agree.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The course of history is not arbitrary by the choice of the one to affect the life of the many; reckless and haphazard you would this call, and we return again to what we have said many times; your life is real, as your existence of permanence is real and the life you live is a subset of the reality of your being. The word illusion common is, for the separation you feel as your true existence waits for your return, the understanding of illusion as false, as appearance only without substance, this idea is also of your Earth. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  All of the events of the sequence of time on Earth are available around you; visualize each place and each record this way; look up straight above and look straight down below. Look forward to the distance; turn around and look behind you, this becoming your new forward. Look to your right at an angle halfway between straight ahead and directly up; reverse your gaze 180 degrees from this point. Do you see the interior of a globe in which you have no up, down, left or right? Curiously and strangely, you have complete orientation of position and know precisely where you are yet a position relative to your Earth ideas of up and down, forward and back and left and right &ndash; the expression of three dimensions &ndash; is not. This is a description of what existence is without time; without sequence where the next event follows the prior and the now precedes the next which converts the now into the past.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  This globe, this sphere which surrounds you has proximity that you might touch and reaches out an infinite distance also; you make contact with the inner surface by your will of thought. <br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Choose a moment, a time, a place of the many centuries ago on your Earth line of series, events sequenced and before you, it shall be available; a thin sliver of a sheet, ever thinner and ever finer is this moment; the closer you look, the thinner it is; its thickness increases not as you draw yourself closer to it, and it is drawn to you also. Think of this as a data file and image, infinitely thin yet visible to your awareness and known to you certain. Draw this thin file out from the surrounding view, and draw it to you by your thoughts, and then see it rotate to present its wide and flat surface to your view.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  You gaze upon it and within you see the animated dance of the many people, places and events that attach to this sequence of things that happened inside this moment you again wish to see, alter, view and re-create. Think of a painting upon the wall, whose figures and objects and faces and things, any one and all of them, move alive upon its surface and they see you; all that is around you as you would see them, yet they remain upon the painting. A three dimensional cinematic view you have.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Think of the event you wish to see, to alter, to review and wish to change and quickly, the swirling mass of faces, places and things of its happening will expand and emerge, coming forward as the others of the moment, the place, fade back; the one of which you have thought comes forth and alive, and you see it open up. The flat imagery arranges and between the things you see, the events and the timing expand like an accordion, like paper with many even folds and strips, becoming flat, and arranged and logical. You see the place and spot within and you go to it and then it envelops and surrounds you and you become part of the events and see them again as they happened and the sensation is just as it was when lived; it IS lived again.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  There is your king, your target your object and all the circumstance of the history before and after; do you now still wish to end that life? All of the other souls and their life courses and yours and all that fit within the decisions and the effects such act would feel, these all appeal to you as you consider this decision and then the act, as if done or not done.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The course of history with the king goes off one way upon this flat, shiny living image and the course of history composed of all the lives goes another way. Which choice do you prefer to see?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  So here you choose, and we do say, haphazard is not what is preferred. Your understanding of the serious effect upon the lives is complete, it is unlimited. You are not within the series of daily events life on Earth offers between your moments of sleep, each awake cycle attached, tethered to the next like string. Your understanding of the life on Earth is complete; you disturb it but for yours and the greater good of all humanity.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Selfishness of purpose comes to you; your choice to your life is sacred and you know this must be the same for others, for you to have it. This is your will, your desire and choice operated as it truly exists and your awareness of your action reigns, as this does for all souls.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  No limit to permutation of events exists; parallel are all to the one, and the one to all and agreed and understood from your home are these things.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  So would you travel and change the course of Earth history? Yes, with the agreement and blessing and understanding of all involved and they will also do this always themselves, with your agreement."</font><br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[No Cost Decisions]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/no-cost-decisions.html]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/no-cost-decisions.html#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 21:03:07 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.theamendment.net/6/post/2013/03/no-cost-decisions.html</guid><description><![CDATA[Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Don't we always have the free will decision to not experience the life-review once we become aware of the fact that we have one? Can't I change my mind right now and choose not to go through it if I really wanted to?   C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;Free will is redundant; an Earth term of your ideas of const [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph" style="text-align:justify;"><font size="4"><em style="">Q:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Don't we always have the free will decision to not experience the life-review once we become aware of the fact that we have one? Can't I change my mind right now and choose not to go through it if I really wanted to? </em><br /><br /><span style=""></span>  C:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &ldquo;Free will is redundant; an Earth term of your ideas of constraint, Earth society. Choices you have, not limits. The barriers you perceive are individual and collective choices; they are not permanent and your will is your desire. Free it is not; it is, simply.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Curious is your Earth language, your English, and the use and meaning of word blocks, so curious for us to see the understanding you might give them.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Yes, you can delay, avoid and pursue understanding of your life trip to Earth as you desire, in any way. Your view and memory are unlikely to do this for you; they will give you great reason to know again your experience.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  We suggest a painting; a large impressionist work, composed of the many spots and flecks created by the many strokes of a brush. Close to the surface, what could be seen? As the observer backs away from this picture, the image will emerge; the pieces will begin to form up, the pattern will be revealed. Would you the artist, the actor and the maker of this picture undertake the toil of its creation, passing from spot to spot, place to fleck, mark to point and then shield your eyes as you depart, to never look upon the creation of your effort?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  This is the sensation of life review you would feel, if the chance &ndash; which you have given yourself &ndash; is not taken.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The emotions, ideas, impressions and feelings of your life on Earth, with no matter for what they are, will be changed when a time for a review of life comes to you. This we say with certainty and with guarantee, for we know you have chosen this way. Great effort and courage you have shown by your choice of voyage, and for arrival to not be taken, for your ship to sail again from your port of destination, the voyage unused, the place not visited, for the view of the sea you could have had from the shore, with no voyage ever, why would you do this? It might be done because you have decided to not disembark, to return to origin or to some other place, not where your voyage has taken you.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Your voyage went where you chose; your arrival in Heaven IS your return; the earth voyage&rsquo;s return to a port of origin as you understand a return to be; THIS is your review of life. Why would you set it aside?<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  There is no place to go as there is every place to go; you can go anywhere at any moment you choose and you can reconvene all of the things and people at any time, for there is no time. Simply ask the people and arrange the places and again the encounter you shall create, so you might do it when you believe it best, for you. Gladly will you do this for others who request your coming to their place of review of encounter, for your desire of togetherness for them will be as great as is theirs for you and so it shall be shared by you all.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  The reason for your steps of life you often see not; upon return and for a life&rsquo;s review, you will see this. You will like to see it; you will enjoy it as will all who were with you. Your generosity is such, you will gladly share your review with those who watch it with you and speak to you of their experience along your side and in your moment. You will do this with others and love them for it, as they will love you.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Think not and think never of yourself and your experiences and the memories and reactions of your mind, as you know them to be secret to you but for your desire to share; this you need not share for you need not cover it, for all is known by shared experience of all involved and to whom knowledge of the experience was made.<br /><span style=""></span><br /><span style=""></span>  Your review is a group activity; the opportunity for sharing and understanding it offers is the greatest of sensations your soul might have, for this sharing is the purpose and reason for your trip to the surface of your beautiful, beloved and unique planet.&rdquo;</font><br /><span style=""></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>