<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	
	<link>http://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>TechCrunch is a group-edited blog that profiles the companies, products and events defining and transforming the new web.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 15:51:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain="techcrunch.com" port="80" path="/?rsscloud=notify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
<image><link>http://www.techcrunch.com</link><url>http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/themes/techcrunchmu/images/techcrunch_logo.png</url><title>TechCrunch</title></image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://techcrunch.com/osd.xml" title="TechCrunch" />
	
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" /><feedburner:info uri="techcrunch" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://techcrunch.com/?pushpress=hub" /><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://add.my.yahoo.com/rss?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://us.i1.yimg.com/us.yimg.com/i/us/my/addtomyyahoo4.gif">Subscribe with My Yahoo!</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.newsgator.com/ngs/subscriber/subext.aspx?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.newsgator.com/images/ngsub1.gif">Subscribe with NewsGator</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://feeds.my.aol.com/add.jsp?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://o.aolcdn.com/favorites.my.aol.com/webmaster/ffclient/webroot/locale/en-US/images/myAOLButtonSmall.gif">Subscribe with My AOL</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.bloglines.com/sub/http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" src="http://www.bloglines.com/images/sub_modern11.gif">Subscribe with Bloglines</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.netvibes.com/subscribe.php?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.netvibes.com/img/add2netvibes.gif">Subscribe with Netvibes</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://fusion.google.com/add?feedurl=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://buttons.googlesyndication.com/fusion/add.gif">Subscribe with Google</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.pageflakes.com/subscribe.aspx?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.pageflakes.com/ImageFile.ashx?instanceId=Static_4&amp;fileName=ATP_blu_91x17.gif">Subscribe with Pageflakes</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item>
		<title>As Obama Visits The West Bank, Palestinians Reach For Their Tech Startup Future</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/brL9ub4tINU/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/as-obama-visits-the-west-bank-palestinians-reach-for-their-tech-startup-future/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 15:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mike Butcher</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=784103</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/p3.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="p3" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Sitting in <a target="_blank" href="http://al-snowbar.com/news">Snobar</a>, a cool bar shaded by fir trees in deepest Ramallah, <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/redprince">George Khadder</a> is practically thumping the table as he speaks. A Palestinian who has worked in Silicon Valley, he talks passionately about his desire for Palestinian entrepreneurs to control their own destiny. "I came back from Silicon Valley because I believed I could affect change," he tells me. It's a sentiment that has been echoed during President Obama's visit to Israel and the West Bank. This week Obama specifically spoke about programs designed to stimulate the Palestinian technology ecosystem and build bridges with the large and well-developed Israeli tech community. "Over 100 high-tech companies have found a home on the West Bank, which speaks to the talent and entrepreneurial spirit of the Palestinian people," he said. 

Back in Snobar, you could easily mistake my conversation with a group of tech entrepreneurs to be happening in some hip part of Europe - perhaps a Berlin 'beach' bar by the river Spree. But this is no ordinary party of the world, and these are no run-of-the-mill entrepreneurs shooting the breeze about raising VC or launching a startup. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/p3.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="p3" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Sitting in <a target="_blank" href="http://al-snowbar.com/news">Snobar</a>, a cool bar shaded by fir trees in deepest Ramallah, <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/redprince">George Khadder</a> is practically thumping the table as he speaks. A Palestinian who has worked in Silicon Valley, he talks passionately about his desire for Palestinian entrepreneurs to control their own destiny. &#8220;I came back from Silicon Valley because I believed I could affect change,&#8221; he tells me. It&#8217;s a sentiment that has been echoed during President Obama&#8217;s visit to Israel and the West Bank. This week Obama specifically spoke about programs designed to stimulate the Palestinian technology ecosystem and build bridges with the large and well-developed Israeli tech community. &#8220;Over 100 high-tech companies have found a home on the West Bank, which speaks to the talent and entrepreneurial spirit of the Palestinian people,&#8221; he said. </p>
<p>Back in Snobar, you could easily mistake my conversation with a group of tech entrepreneurs to be happening in some hip part of Europe &#8211; perhaps a Berlin &#8216;beach&#8217; bar by the river Spree. But this is no ordinary party of the world, and these are no run-of-the-mill entrepreneurs shooting the breeze about raising VC or launching a startup. </p>
<p>Even amidst the enormous political and cultural difficulties created by the ongoing conflict between Israelis and Palestinians &#8211; consider the huge &#8216;Peace Wall&#8217; and tight security that make it very hard for anyone, let alone entrepreneurs, to move around &#8211; you can find technology companies plying their wares.</p>
<p></p>
<p>But I hadn&#8217;t had to simply catch a taxi from the airport to visit these entrepreneurs. Weeks earlier, I&#8217;d had to make contact with a local NGO that could get me into the West Bank, arrange to be driven through armed Israeli check-points, spend only a few hours meeting startups and then get back out. In such an environment, you could forgive a Palestinian tech entrepreneur for not being as boosterish as their Silicon Valley counterparts.</p>
<p>Ironically, the difficulties of the security situation make technology potentially the ideal industry for Palestinians. The &#8216;exports&#8217; online, like web sites and apps, are not subject to the usual rules and regulations associated with Israeli security. </p>
<p>The frustration and impatience of Palestinian tech entrepreneurs is palpable. They are champing at the bit to energize their own tech ecosystem, despite the difficulties of day to day life. How do you develop smartphone apps when so few in the population have smartphones and there are no 3G networks available? Palestinians don&#8217;t have the unfettered broadband and 3G connectivity their Israeli neighbors only a short drive away have. How do you meet potential investors if you can&#8217;t get out of the Gaza Strip because of restriction on travel both for you and the investors? How do you organize a simple hackathons? With security being a major concern of the Israeli government mobile phone towers are limited by height to prevent them from being used as firing positions.  </p>
<p>What&#8217;s at stake is an industry which could bring enormous economic benefit to the Palestinians, greater stability and perhaps even positively better relations with Israel. </p>
<p></p>
<p>In this part of the world, creating a tech startup doesn&#8217;t involve Valley-style cash out for the founders, an earn-out and then on the next startup. A thriving Palestinians tech industry could actually transform an entire, economically deprived, area. Tech could actually end up meaning peace. </p>
<p>But there is frustration amongst Palestinian entrepreneurs over the pace of growth amongst home-grown, product based startups.</p>
<p>Around a low table strewn with coffee and drinks, I discuss tech trends and the local movement to launch a tech revolution amongst Palestinians with a group that calls itself the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/peeks.fb/">Peeks</a>. Standing for &#8216;Palestinian Geeks&#8217;, this 2,500-strong membership, was built <a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/peeks.fb/">largely on a Facebook group</a> but has become a vehicle for a new generation hungry to emulate the culture of Silicon Valley. </p>
<p>Unlike many of the more established trade bodies, Peeks is all about something any TechCrunch reader will be aware of: entrepreneurs, startups and geeks.</p>
<p>Started in 2010, Khadder and his fellow Peeks founders set out to create a sustainable economy of entrepreneurs for Palestinians residing in the West Bank and the Gaza strip. </p>
<p>In the Peeks community, members will post events and news, debate and look for people to help. It&#8217;s a grass roots community of entrepreneurs to support each other, engage with students, industry, and the wealth of Palestinian expats working in tech around the world. </p>
<p>They realised there was a lack of entrepreneurial culture, no &#8216;trust culture&#8217;, and a fear of failure. There was also a lack of research, a lack of links between the private culture of startups and education and little private sector skills in the education system. So they plan to develop &#8220;sustainable knowledge based resources&#8221; and do offline events like meet-ups and hackathons.</p>
<p>As Khadder &#8211; who works with solar startup <a target="_blank" href="http://www.yafaenergy.com/">Yafa Enerrgy</a> &#8211; says: &#8220;What we need is a vision to bring this together. There has not been such a vision in Palestine.&#8221;</p>
<p></p>
<p>Whether a vision exists of not, Peeks appears to be pushing at a gradually opening door. Already Gaza has seen its first incubator open up, the Business and Technology Incubator (BTI), and product-based startups in the West Bank <a target="_blank" href="http://www.wamda.com/2012/12/gaza-s-first-incubator-ramps-up-giving-new-hope-to-local-entrepreneurs">are starting to appear</a>.</p>
<p>Palestinian entrepreneur Mohammad Kilany <a target="_blank" href="http://www.synergos.org/bios/mohammedalkilany.htm">co-founded Souktel</a> a &#8216;LinkedIn over SMS&#8217; which matches employees with employers and was designed. <a target="_blank" href="http://ArtTech.ps">ArtTech</a> is a studio producing apps like the <a target="_blank" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.arttech.xbugs&amp;hl=en">X-Bugs game on Android</a>.</p>
<p>George Halabi created <a target="_blank" href="http://SafqaOnline.com">SafqaOnline</a> a classifieds site trying to be the CraigsList for Palestinians.   <a target="_blank" href="http://FinJANi.com">FinJANi</a> is an iGoogle-like start page startup. <a target="_blank" href="http://Steadypoint.net">Steadypoint</a> is a Ramallah-based company working to produce an RFQ platform. <a target="_blank" href="http://Jeeran.com">Jeeran</a> is a startup attempting to beime the &#8220;Yelp of the Middle East&#8221; and now has 8m users in 5 countries.  <a target="_blank" href="http://idevator.com/">Idevator</a>  is a Zynga-like startup producing games for the Middle East.  Yousef  Ghandour is founder of <a target="_blank" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.anabasalli.AnaBasalli&amp;hl=en">Anabasalli</a>, an Android application to assist Muslims during prayer.</p>
<p></p>
<p>It&#8217;s a varied list of startups, but the formation of the Peeks group reflects a growing desire amongst a number of Palestinans in the tech community to break away from what has traditionally been an IT outsourcing industry, and one which was frequently subsidised by donors and outside NGOs. </p>
<p>Indeed, even some Israeli tech companies have used engineers based in Ramallah. Sometimes they&#8217;ve gone further &#8211; the (now defunct) G.ho.st startup (which created a virtual desktop environment for PCs) was <a target="_blank" href="http://kafee.wordpress.com/2008/06/23/ghost-between-ramallah-and-modiin/">started by Zvi Schreiber British-born Israeli CEO</a> who joined with Tareq Maayah, a Palestinian businessman, to start a Ramallah office for the startup in parallel to the Modiin office in Israel.</p>
<p>That said, pure IT outsourcing has been a successful industry for Palestinians. </p>
<p>According to a white paper commissioned by Cisco in July last year the Palestinian IT sector grew over five times from 2008 to 2010 and now accounts for more than 5% of Palestine’s gross domestic product. The paper also noted that the European Investment Bank has put $78 million into the Palestinian high tech sector in the past three years and that Cisco itself has put $15 million into the West Bank since 2008.</p>
<p>Other informal estimates put the size of the ICT industry in Palestine at $350 million, with about $150m spread across telecommunications, and another $20m software development. The majority of that is thought to be in outsourcing companies.</p>
<p>There has also been plenty of outside interest and investment from the likes of Cisco, Google and USAID. All have brought their resources to bare on the emerging Palestinian tech scene. The multinationals clearly trust Palestinians companies to do the work. That&#8217;s important to note.</p>
<p>But it&#8217;s  product-based startups, not outsourcing, that the Peeks and other Palestinian entrepreneurs like them are so desperate to promote and nurture.</p>
<p></p>
<p>It&#8217;s estimated that only about 5-10% of the tech market is considered &#8220;exportable&#8221; &#8211; a code word for home-grown startups building product which can be used internationally. It is from these, according to Khadder,  &#8220;where momentum will come.&#8221; </p>
<p>&#8220;For Palestine to develop it has to develop tech which is IP based not just outsourcing,&#8221; he says. The Peeks group is acutely aware that remaining reliant on outsourcing work is, as one Peeks member put it to me, &#8216;the bottom of the barrel.&#8221;</p>
<p>The irony of the situation is that Palestinian entrepreneurs realise &#8211; as Israel did many years ago &#8211; they will have to produce startups and their own Intellectual Property. For it doesn&#8217;t take a genius to work out that everyone in this region is in the same boat. There are few natural resources, there is political instability and &#8216;exporting&#8217; product can be difficult.</p>
<p>Sustainability to the Peeks means not having to rely on handouts, and building long term, viable technology products which are created by their own people, not working for someone else in another part of the world. </p>
<p>Khadder (pictured below) believes entrepreneurship is the key: &#8220;The [Palestinian] Government, the private sector and academia have been incompetent in their approach to entrepreneurship. We need to see visionaries to promote entrepreneurship.&#8221; </p>
<p></p>
<p>You can tell he&#8217;s passionate about the subject by the language he uses: &#8220;We&#8217;re not bloody India either in terms of code or scale or cost. We need to create our own niche in terms of IP and innovation. I don&#8217;t care what it is &#8211; gaming, social media, anything &#8211; the issue is that&#8217;s the only way we can build a sustainable tech sector in Palestine,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>Part of the issue is that business groups like the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.pita.ps/">Palestinian Information Technology Association of Companies</a> (PITA) tend give voice to established IT companies not startups. And an aligned organisation, the Palestinian ICT Incubator (PICTI), has had less than sterling success, despite a seven track year record.</p>
<p>&#8220;The KPIs have been &#8216;let&#8217;s spend the aid money&#8217; not &#8216;let&#8217;s create a value proposition&#8217;,&#8221; says Khadder. It&#8217;s the fault of both the Aid money plus Palestinians ourselves who have accepted those agendas and not  challenged them. The focus has been outsourcing, outsourcing and more outsourcing &#8211; nothing to empower tech entrepreneurs. That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re trying to change with Peeks, at least from a grass-roots perspective.&#8221;</p>
<p>Mohammed Musleh, business development lead at PITA, says the situation is more complex: &#8220;Peeks is designed to come from the community but PITA is about the companies as they grow. We see ourselves as a second stage, as the companies emerge from organisations like the Peeks. We look at our relationship as symbiotic. We can&#8217;t work against each other, we need to work together to ensure that the community grows. When they need things like advocacy and legal advice and more hard core stuff, PITA can be there for them.&#8221;</p>
<p>But the lack of &#8216;smart&#8217; investors, a highly regulated economy, an old fashioned banking system, creaky corporate laws (mostly inherited from Jordan) is not helping. For instance, there is no structure in Palestine for different classes of stock or convertible loans.</p>
<p>And Peeks members roll their eyes when you ask them about the activity of NGOs. </p>
<p></p>
<p>Privately, these tech entrepreneurs couldn&#8217;t hold back their deep disappointment that aid money and NGO efforts in the  Palestinian tech sector has been spent  &#8211; according to them &#8211; &#8220;very badly&#8221;. As one put it, the money has gone on &#8220;splashy events&#8221; that achieve little long term value. What money there was has been short lived, and &#8220;the KPIs did not stretch beyond a year.&#8221;</p>
<p>But not all NGOs come in for criticism. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.mercycorps.org.uk/">Mercy Corps</a> is one singled out for praise by local Palestinian startups.</p>
<p>The NGO has been working with the Palestinian ICT sector in West Bank/Gaza since 2008, working with universities, TVET institutions and others to try and gear students to what&#8217;s called &#8220;market-driven subjects&#8221; and the softer skills like marketing which are harder to come by in this region.  It&#8217;s sponsored four Startup Weekends in Nablus and Gaza over the last two years, bringing together Palestinian tech people in a more casual environment. They also helped support a SUW in Nazareth, which was organized by Arabs inside Israel. The NGO is backed by the European Union, Source of Hope Foundation, Google Foundation, and USAID among others.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/tova_s">Tova Scherr</a>, program manager with Mercy Corps says: &#8220;I have been working with the tech community in Palestine for the last four and a half years, and it&#8217;s exciting to see the changes that have been happening. When I first started the environment was very company-focused. People from different companies did not meet each other much outside of work, and share what kinds of projects they are working on. Now, partly through our efforts at Mercy Corps, Peeks and others, young developers are seeing the value in sharing and helping each other.&#8221;</p>
<p>She says recent funding stories are inspiring Palestinian entrepreneurs and &#8220;Palestinians abroad are thinking of coming home.&#8221;</p>
<p>However, she counsels caution over the view that tech can cure all ills: &#8220;There has been a lot of hype about Palestinian technology and its potential to support the Palestinian economy. We are now having a major reality-check and need to be more realistic in our approach of what is and isn&#8217;t possible. While there is a lot of potential, computer science graduates in Palestine are not coming out of University with the skills needed to start their own companies or to be strong employees, just out of school. While startups create new jobs and opportunities, I believe startups are not for everyone, and people need to work in established companies as well.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It can often take 6-8 years to build a new entrepreneurship ecosystem in the best conditions. On the ground in Gaza and the West Bank, Palestinians face a different reality than Boulder or Silicon Valley. The political realities, movement and access restrictions faced by Palestinians cannot be completely ignored, even if the cloud makes it easier to export virtual goods …but the grassroots efforts coming out to the Palestinian Geek community, combining local efforts and connecting the Palestinian diaspora and interested supporters for help, is taking Palestine to the next level,&#8221; she says.</p>
<p>Indeed, despite all the obvious drawbacks and barriers, I don&#8217;t hear much griping from the Peeks. Their thoughts are more concerned with trying to support and promote a new culture of entrepreneurialism and acceptance of failure. Indeed, it&#8217;s exactly the same culture that helped Israel become a &#8216;startup nation&#8217; which stands to help Palestine.</p>
<p>To achieve that, the Peeks have &#8220;set out to encourage collaboration, foster entrepreneurs, create links to universities. We&#8217;ve tried to rediscover volunteerism,&#8221; says Khadder.</p>
<p>In saying that he admits that some aspects of business amongst Palestinians has been too fostered by outside aid and what he calls &#8220;hand-outs&#8221; &#8211;  and when he speaks you realise that he&#8217;s talking like many entrepreneurs talk: they don&#8217;t want special favours. In the main they want the restrictions on creating startups, be they legislative or political, to just get out of the damn way. </p>
<p>So far Peeks has managed to punch above their weight. Such as inviting Walid Abu-Hadba, VP of Microsoft, one of the highest-ranking sitting VP’s to ever visit Palestine. Others who have visited include  Ossama Hassanein, chairman of Rising Tide Capital; Paul Fullerton, Senior Manager, Cisco, among others.</p>
<p>Then there are other signs of a growing local ecosystem, and, crucially, investors.</p>
<p>Sadara Ventures, the newly established VC aimed at Palestinian tech startups was founded by Palestinian Saed Nashef and Israeli Yadin Kaufmann. Kaufmann founded helped start Veritas Venture Partners in 1990 and funded Accord Networks, a videoconferencing company that went public in 2000, and Ubique, an instant messaging pioneer that was bought by AOL in 1995. Sadara plans to invest exclusively in Palestinian technology start-ups and aims to take stakes in about 15 companies over 10 years.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s already put $1 million into Souktel (mentioned above) and hotel booking platform <a target="_blank" href="http://www.yamsafer.me/en/home">Yamsafer</a>.</p>
<p>Sadara has raised around $29.5 million and is joining a number of new investors putting into Palestinian tech companies, including a specific Palestinian fund from Rasmala Investment Bank in Dubai, the $60 million private equity-backed Siraj Palestine Fund and Abraaj Capital&#8217;s $36 million Palestine Growth Capital Fund. </p>
<p>VCs are being being joined by other new initiatives. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.fastforward.ps/">FastForward</a> is a brand new accelerator in Ramallah modeled on the Startup Weekend “SWNext” five weeks program.</p>
<p>Sadara&#8217;s Nashef says he and Yadin &#8220;set out to raise our Fund because we both believed that there&#8217;s an opportunity to make profitable investments in Palestine, while at the same time creating social impact. The real big deal is founding the first venture capital fund to invest in early-stage tech companies in Palestine, and having it backed by such top-tier investors as EIB, Cisco, Soros (SEDF), and Skoll, among others.&#8221;</p>
<p>Although says the ecosystem is &#8220;still on the ground-floor, and &#8220;there&#8217;s a lot of work to be done before we can mature as a tech ecosystem&#8221; he expects to invest in two product-based startups per year in Palestine. </p>
<p>While he admits that many short-term opportunities will simply be locally adapted clones of startups that succeeded in the West, he hopes they will start seeing deep tech innovation, though &#8220;this is probably several years down the road. You have to understand that what Sadara is doing here is effectively jumpstarting an ecosystem. We&#8217;re in this for the longterm, and I&#8217;m optimistic on that.&#8221;</p>
<p>He says groups like Peeks are &#8220;a good start, but not enough. I&#8217;d like to see a critical mass of entrepreneurial activities on the ground, taking place regularly, and over a long period before I can comfortably say that entrepreneurs are taking charge of their own destiny in Palestine. We still need more leadership in the community by actual founders.&#8221;</p>
<p>He also thinks &#8220;outsourcing will be with us for a while, and that&#8217;s not necessarily a bad thing. It builds capacity, and creates a cluster that may support IP-based startups. I believe we will need to have our first successful exit story before the local industry landscape undergoes a significant change.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not possible at this early stage to discern quite what reaction this rise of grass roots Palestinian tech activism will have on the Israeli side. However, there may be hope that this entrepreneur-led approach could pay dividends in relations. </p>
<p>There are even some promising signs from one or two Israeli investors. High profile Tel Aviv/New York angel investor Jeff Pulver recently told tech magazine Informilo that he would be &#8220;looking for Israeli/Arab led start-ups,” in 2013. He recently participated in the first hackathon in Nazareth with Arabs living in Israel and Palestinians, and <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/jeffpulver/status/304646623051526144/photo/1">meet entrepreneurs in Ramallah</a>. Initiatives like the <a target="_blank" href="http://Meet.mit.edu">Middle Eastern Education Through Technology</a>,an MIT programme, brings together young Israelis and Palestinians to learn technology and business skills. </p>
<p>Even at the highest echelons of the Israeli technology establishment, there are signs that a thaw might some day develop between the fast-moving world of Israeli technology and the Palestinian side. Even Yossi Vardi, who exited ICQ to AOL back in 1998 for $407m and now commands Godfather-like status in the Israeli scene, <a target="_blank" href="http://new.livestream.com/websummit/DWS12Main/videos/5872006">said on stage at Dublin Web Summit last last year</a> that he hoped there would be greater cooperation and interaction in the future between technologists in Israel and Palestine.</p>
<p>But for his part Nashef does not see more Arab/Israeli cooperation tech: &#8220;It is rare and not very popular given the current tensions. A lot is riding on progress on the political front, and until that happens, this will continue to be a very sensitive issue.&#8221;</p>
<p>There&#8217;s the rub. One cannot escape the politics on the ground. There remain obvious practical hurdles to Palestinian entrepreneurialism on the ground. Across the West Bank and the Gaza strip unemployment is high and mobility restricted. The restriction on movement means the senior management talent you would normally source from abroad for a start is a very big challenge.</p>
<p>But, like entrepreneurs in any parts of the world outside of Silicon Valley, some of the biggest barriers remain in the mind. Talking to Palestinians and Arabs living inside Israel you&#8217;ll find they freely admit, that the age-old risk-averse business culture continues to be one of the biggest hurdles to the development of startups. Then again perhaps this is understandable when so much of daily life is risky and hard to predict enough as it is. </p>
<p>Of course, there is an enormous irony here.</p>
<p>The very technology industry that Israel relied on to pull it out of economic isolation in the 80s and 90s and 2000s is the very same industry that many Palestinian entrepreneurs are looking to to pull them out of a similar predicament. </p>
<p>It&#8217;s an irony of such proportions that it is not lost on the small gathering I met in the Snobar in Ramallah. </p>
<p>&#8220;Palestine is where Israel was 20 years ago in terms of tech,&#8221; admits Khadder. But however long it takes, he, the Peeks and others plan to start the journey towards a new era of Palestinian tech startups.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/784103/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=brL9ub4tINU:GUffNn-HQl4:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=brL9ub4tINU:GUffNn-HQl4:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=brL9ub4tINU:GUffNn-HQl4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=brL9ub4tINU:GUffNn-HQl4:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=brL9ub4tINU:GUffNn-HQl4:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=brL9ub4tINU:GUffNn-HQl4:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=brL9ub4tINU:GUffNn-HQl4:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=brL9ub4tINU:GUffNn-HQl4:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/brL9ub4tINU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/as-obama-visits-the-west-bank-palestinians-reach-for-their-tech-startup-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/p3.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/p3.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">p3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ef4a4ab87c72738ed187e21de55b2fc6?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mike-butcher</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/p3ram.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/p4ram.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/p3.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/p1.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/p2.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/p1george.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/p5ram.jpg" medium="image" />
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/as-obama-visits-the-west-bank-palestinians-reach-for-their-tech-startup-future/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Report: CA Technologies To Buy Enterprise App Deployment And Management Company Nolio For Over $40M</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/dQsM1_rFoGY/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/report-ca-technologies-to-buy-enterprise-app-deployment-and-management-company-nolio-for-over-40m/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 14:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leena Rao</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ca technolgies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=784214</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/nolio.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Nolio" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />According to Israeli publications <a target="_blank" href="http://technation.themarker.com/1.1975787">The Marker</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.calcalist.co.il/internet/articles/0,7340,L-3598639,00.html">Calcalist</a>, IT software giant CA Technologies will purchase Israeli app deployment and management company <a target="_blank" href="http://www.noliosoft.com/">Nolio</a>. The acquisition price has been reported between $40 and $42 million.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/nolio.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Nolio" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>According to Israeli publications <a target="_blank" href="http://technation.themarker.com/1.1975787">The Marker</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.calcalist.co.il/internet/articles/0,7340,L-3598639,00.html">Calcalist</a>, IT software giant CA Technologies will purchase Israeli app deployment and management company <a target="_blank" href="http://www.noliosoft.com/">Nolio</a>. The acquisition price has been reported between $40 and $42 million.</p>
<p>Nolio&#8217;s software automates application deployment and allows IT staff to maintain, manage and recover these enterprise applications. The platform offers application service workflow design, testing and execution with centralized management to control application services across data center application teams, application environments and distributed data center infrastructures.</p>
<p>Nolio has raised $7 million from Cedar Fund, Blumberg Capital and Iris Capital.</p>
<p>Calcalist reports that this will be CA&#8217;s 11th acquisition of an Israel startup. In 2011, CA <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/07/29/ca-buys-website-and-app-monitoring-startup-watchmouse/">acquired</a> website monitoring startup WatchMouse.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve contacted CA Technologies for confirmation and will update when we hear back.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/784214/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dQsM1_rFoGY:Nr0JEIAH7TA:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dQsM1_rFoGY:Nr0JEIAH7TA:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dQsM1_rFoGY:Nr0JEIAH7TA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dQsM1_rFoGY:Nr0JEIAH7TA:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=dQsM1_rFoGY:Nr0JEIAH7TA:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dQsM1_rFoGY:Nr0JEIAH7TA:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=dQsM1_rFoGY:Nr0JEIAH7TA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dQsM1_rFoGY:Nr0JEIAH7TA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/dQsM1_rFoGY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/report-ca-technologies-to-buy-enterprise-app-deployment-and-management-company-nolio-for-over-40m/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/nolio.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/nolio.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Nolio</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bbce6c3c48f821c81c019600a5589ae6?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">leena</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/report-ca-technologies-to-buy-enterprise-app-deployment-and-management-company-nolio-for-over-40m/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Recent YouTube, Veoh Copyright Infringement Rulings Help To Unpack Safe Harbor Guidelines</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/Oix3q6rN0ko/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/some-rules-of-the-road-for-user-uploaded-content-platforms/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 14:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sid Venkatesan and James Freedman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dmca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safe harbor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=783735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/online-content-creation.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="online-content-creation" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><b>Editor's note:</b> <em>Sid Venkatesan is an IP partner at Orrick, Herrington &#38; Sutcliffe LLP. James Freedman is an associate in Orrick’s IP group and a recent Stanford Law School graduate.</em>

Online content providers and aggregators are well aware of the potential penalties that can result from a copyright infringement lawsuit. In addition to being expensive to litigate, a copyright lawsuit can result in statutory damages (which can range between $750 to $30,000 for each infringing work found on a website), some or all of an infringer’s profits and even steeper penalties for willful infringement. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/online-content-creation.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="online-content-creation" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em><a target="_blank" href="http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=2843793&amp;authType=name&amp;authToken=yMSI&amp;locale=en_US&amp;pvs=pp&amp;trk=ppro_viewmore">Sid Venkatesan</a> is an IP partner specializing in high stakes IP disputes and IP counseling for technology companies in the Silicon Valley office of Orrick, Herrington &amp; Sutcliffe LLP. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/jifreedman">James Freedman</a> is an associate in Orrick’s IP group and a recent Stanford Law School graduate. </em></p>
<p>Online content providers and aggregators are well aware of the potential penalties that can result from a copyright infringement lawsuit. In addition to being expensive to litigate, a copyright lawsuit can result in statutory damages (which can range between $750 to $30,000 for each infringing work found on a website), some or all of an infringer’s profits and even steeper penalties for willful infringement. A peer-to-peer platform relying on user-uploaded content, for example, can face <a target="_blank" href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/223431/riaa_thinks_limewire_owes_75_trillion_in_damages.html">nearly unlimited liability</a> under this regime. Clearly, a copyright suit can have a crippling effect on an early-stage tech company.</p>
<p>One of Congress’ goals when it passed the Digital Millennium Copyright Act in 1998 was to insulate certain digital content providers (called “service providers” in the statute) as long as they promptly took down infringing works on notice from the copyright holder of those works.</p>
<h3 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:640px;float:center;color:#0a9400;">Multi-part safe statutory tests are often a litigator’s delight, but they do not always provide clarity for businesses trying to comply with the law.</h3>
<p>This protection is called a “safe harbor” and can be used as a defense to a copyright infringement claim. There are several safe harbors in the DMCA (they are contained in <a target="_blank" href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/17/512">Title 17 of the United States Code, Section 512</a>). One important one, set forth in Section 512, subpart (c), protects service providers that offer “storage at the direction of a user” on the provider’s network, i.e. a platform for user-uploaded content. These service providers can rely on the safe harbor as long as they:</p>
<ul>
<li>Promptly take down allegedly infringing material upon receipt of a statutory compliant notice;</li>
<li>Do not have “actual knowledge” of copyright infringement;</li>
<li>Are unaware of “facts or circumstances from which infringing activity is apparent” (this is called “red flag” knowledge in case law);</li>
<li>Remove or disable access to infringing material upon learning about it (whether or not a takedown notice has been received);</li>
<li>And do not receive a “financial benefit directly attributable to the infringing activity” where the “service provider has the right and ability to control the activity.</li>
</ul>
<p>Multi-part safe statutory tests are often a litigator’s delight, but they do not always provide clarity for businesses trying to comply with the law. Indeed, Section 512(c) raises a number of questions. For example, what are “facts and circumstances from which infringing activity is apparent”? Does an online ad-supported content-hosting platform “receive financial benefit directly attributable to the infringing activity”? Does a service provider that processes or tags user-uploaded content perform “storage at the direct of a user” or something else?</p>
<h5>Unpacking Safe Harbor</h5>
<p>The boundaries of the safe harbor have been tested in litigation and as a result, some recent federal Court of Appeals decisions have cleared up some of the questions around Section 512(c). Most recently, the Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals – which covers nine states, including the west coast – ruled that the video streaming site Veoh was <a target="_blank" href="https://www.eff.org/document/9th-ct-umg-v-veoh-03142013">protected by the safe harbor in a case brought by Universal Music Group</a> (though Veoh’s successor won, the original company went <a target="_blank" href="http://allthingsd.com/20100211/veoh-finally-calls-it-quits-layoffs-yesterday-bankruptcy-filing-soon/">bankrupt</a> following a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/04/07/qlipso-veoh/">fire sale</a> in 2010).</p>
<p>The reasoning of the Ninth Circuit was aligned with a 2012 decision in the Second Circuit (which covers Connecticut, New York and Vermont) in <a target="_blank" href="http://www.ca2.uscourts.gov/decisions/isysquery/ad840309-cbc2-47e1-95bb-73e8784e413c/1/doc/10-3270_10-3342_opn.pdf">Viacom v. YouTube</a>, meaning there is agreement as to some of the rules of the road for courts covering the largest media and technology hubs in the country.</p>
<p>Specifically, the Veoh and YouTube cases make clear that:</p>
<ul>
<li>“Storage at the direction of a user” includes more than simply storing user-uploaded content. Veoh and YouTube both automatically processed uploaded videos for hosting and converted them to Flash. These activities were found to be protected as they were logically related to “storage.” On the other hand, YouTube’s alleged practice of syndicating clips to third parties might not fall within the safe harbor, and this issue was sent back to the trial court for further litigation.</li>
<li>Neither “actual knowledge” nor “red flag” knowledge can be based on a general awareness that infringing works may be on the service provider’s system. For example, there were news articles in 2007 indicating that Veoh had been lax in policing infringing code, but the Ninth Circuit found that such general awareness was not tied to the allegedly infringing UMG works at issue in the case. In reaching this conclusion, the Ninth Circuit appeared to rely on Veoh’s policy of promptly taking down infringing content on notice and the absence of internal emails or documents showing that Veoh knew of specific infringing works on its system.</li>
<li>There is no affirmative duty by the service provider to continuously monitor for potentially infringing copyrighted material. This conclusion is consistent with the statutory notice and takedown scheme, which places the burden of identifying infringing material on the copyright holders.</li>
<li>That being said, a service provider is not allowed to simply sit back and wait for a takedown notice if it is aware of specifically infringing material. Some emails presented in the YouTube case suggested that the YouTube founders may have been aware that infringing material on the site yet elected to wait for a takedown notice before removing the material. This was one of the reasons the YouTube case was <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/05/youtube-vs-viacom-again/">sent back to the trial court</a> for further proceedings, whereas Veoh had obtained a summary judgment victory [the lesson here as always: bad evidence can rarely be covered up with legal doctrine]. Also, on Thursday, the Ninth Circuit concluded that the BitTorrent site isoHunt was <a target="_blank" href="http://cdn.ca9.uscourts.gov/datastore/opinions/2013/03/21/10-55946.pdf">not entitled to safe harbor protection</a> because its operator “actively encourag[ed] infringement,” including by “urging his users to both upload and download” works, actions that showed he had at least red flag knowledge of infringing works.</li>
<li>Finally, the safe harbor does not apply where a service provider receives a financial benefit where the provider “exerts substantial influence on the activities of the users.” Veoh’s model of letting users decide what should be uploaded and retaining the right to take down content in its discretion was found to not “exert substantial influence on its users” and therefore fell within the safe harbor.</li>
</ul>
<p>Generally, these cases show that a platform that leaves content uploads to the discretion of its users, performs processing specifically related to the display of and access to that content, promptly abides by DMCA takedown requests, and does not close its eyes to specifically infringing works can probably take comfort from Section 512(c).</p>
<p>Less clear is how business models that use user uploaded content for purposes other than general ad-supported storage and viewing or models that limit or direct what users upload will fare. Moreover, though affirmative monitoring is not required under these cases, we can reasonably expect that what constitutes “red flag” knowledge may change over time as technology improves and service providers are more easily able to identify and analyze content on their platforms.</p>
<p>[<em><i>This column reflects Sid’s and James’ general views and does not constitute legal advice or the views of Orrick or its clients</i>.]</em></p>
<p>[Image: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.shutterstock.com/index-in.mhtml">Shutterstock</a>]</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/783735/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Oix3q6rN0ko:b-ShdU2xbWM:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Oix3q6rN0ko:b-ShdU2xbWM:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Oix3q6rN0ko:b-ShdU2xbWM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Oix3q6rN0ko:b-ShdU2xbWM:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Oix3q6rN0ko:b-ShdU2xbWM:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Oix3q6rN0ko:b-ShdU2xbWM:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Oix3q6rN0ko:b-ShdU2xbWM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Oix3q6rN0ko:b-ShdU2xbWM:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/Oix3q6rN0ko" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/some-rules-of-the-road-for-user-uploaded-content-platforms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/online-content-creation.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/online-content-creation.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">online-content-creation</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2a014e70509390133a9b9073671a2e8d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tcbucket</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/suitcases.jpg?w=199" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">suitcases</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/some-rules-of-the-road-for-user-uploaded-content-platforms/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>What Games Are: ‘Twas The Night Before GDC</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/5EV1yJ4guWE/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/what-games-are-twas-the-night-before-gdc/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 13:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tadhg Kelly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GDC 2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game Developers Conference]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microconsole]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ouya]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=784039</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gdc13_logo1.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="gdc13_logo1" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />The annual Game Developer's Conference rolls into San Francisco next week. The event is always worth attending if only to see what the future will bring. This year's, more than most, will be a real bellwether for what shape the industry will take over the next five years. And perhaps that shape will have much to do with microconsoles.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gdc13_logo1.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="gdc13_logo1" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><strong>Editor’s note: </strong><em>Tadhg Kelly is a veteran game designer, creator of leading game design blog <a target="_blank" href="http://www.whatgamesare.com/">What Games Are</a> and creative director of Jawfish Games. You can follow him on Twitter <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/tiedtiger">here</a>.</em></p>
<p>According to the Internet, <a target="_blank" href="http://blog.gaiam.com/quotes/authors/theodore-zeldin/61971">Theodore Zeldin said this</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Conversation is a meeting of minds with different memories and habits. When minds meet, they don&#8217;t just exchange facts: they transform them, reshape them, draw different implications from them, engage in new trains of thought. Conversation doesn&#8217;t just reshuffle the cards: it creates new cards.</p></blockquote>
<p>And that sounds like a great place to start talking about the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.gdconf.com">Game Developers Conference</a>, which is on all next week in San Francisco&#8217;s Moscone Center. Although at first it seems like just another of <a target="_blank" href="http://www.gameconfs.com">many events on the gaming calendar</a>, GDC is the one that people travel from halfway around the world to attend. The folks who can&#8217;t afford it or can&#8217;t convince their companies to send them look on wistfully. To those of us going, on the other hand, it&#8217;s game-dev Christmas.</p>
<p>There are several reasons the event is considered so special. One is the people. Games are a far-flung kind of industry where you make a lot of friends at various companies but don&#8217;t actually see them very often, so the conference is a great place to reconnect, share war stories and celebrate. Aside from catch-ups you also meet people whom you admire from afar and those who likewise admire you.</p>
<p>Another reason is the lack of a specific agenda and the high degree of cross-pollination. Most industry events tend to either center around one topic (such as social, monetization, gambling, casual, education, etc.) or function as consumer shows like E3 in LA or Gamescom in Cologne. However, at GDC you can float from talks about <a target="_blank" href="http://developers.kongregate.com/news/kongregate-gdc-talk">monetizing on the Kongregate platform</a> to round tables about the successes and failures of AI design, and on to something else. It&#8217;s a big tent full of ideas and game makers who want to share them.</p>
<p>And while the industry certainly loves to get together and party, there&#8217;s more going on at GDC than just drinks, schmoozing and biz-dev (of which there is a lot). For example this year one of the big summits (mini-collections of talks) is about narrative. There are also panels covering issues, such as the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/11/29/1reasonwhy-reveals-sexism-gaming-industry_n_2205204.html">#1reasonwhy meme</a> regarding women in the games industry, and less serious sessions, including the Experimental Gameplay Workshop.</p>
<p>GDC talks are also often very open and forthright. At many games events the talks tend to be more about advancing agendas or essentially doing PR by pivoting every question back to how awesome your company is. Not so much at GDC though. One example that really stood out for me was a talk about a game called <a target="_blank" href="http://kotaku.com/shadow-physics/">Shadow Physics</a>, which had been highly anticipated in the community for a startling concept but then fell apart as a project. The talk was blunt, honest and open rather than suave or trying to manage a message.</p>
<p>Finally there is the sensation of being on the frontline of the future. GDC tends to be less the place where ideas crystalize into marketing stories. Considering how many of the major gaming news outfits are present at the event, and the quality of the content, GDC tends to be the launch point for new movements in the industry. Streaming cloud games from Onlive are one example, as was the genesis of the book <a target="_blank" href="http://realityisbroken.org">Reality is Broken</a>.</p>
<p>As Zeldin said, it&#8217;s all about creating new cards.</p>
<p>This year&#8217;s GDC will perhaps be more important than those of the last five years. While last year&#8217;s centered around ideas of general transition, few could say what the shape of the next phase of the industry might be. Kickstarter had only just started to be influential thanks to Double Fine, and new console platforms were still mostly ideas rather than emerging realities. Social games had yet to have Draw Something rise and fall, Retina display iPads were announced over the course of the show and gamification had yet to be told that it was 85 percent unsuccessful. Nobody had ever heard of Supercell, seen a local game like <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/05/what-games-are-are-local-mobile-games-incoming/">Spaceteam</a> or really realized how big Skylanders would become.</p>
<p>A year later, so much has changed. Where platform transition was more an idea last year, this year it&#8217;s becoming and bruising reality. For many big game publishers, 2012 was not a good year and sales of even some of the biggest franchises were markedly down. One publisher (THQ) has already gone into total meltdown, and another (EA) has just seen its <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/18/ea-ceo-john-riccitiello-steps-down-larry-probst-becomes-executive-chairman/">CEO resign over poor performance</a>. With Sony having recently <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/20/sony-official-unveils-the-playstation-4-x86-cpu-and-8gb-memory-but-about-experiences-not-specs/">announced their PS4</a> and Wii U having launched and then gone through a very tough patch, many eyes are on Microsoft to see what (if anything) they&#8217;ll have to say. Many are wondering whether social games are tapping out, what future directions they may take and even whether the PC will survive in the wake of Windows 8.</p>
<p>However it could also be a conference where the biggest idea of the year starts to take wing and fly. Microconsoles, those small, mostly Android-powered consoles that want to turn your TV into an app platform, are likely to make a strong showing. I remain very hopeful that microconsoles are going to shape the future for the next five years. Whether it&#8217;s Ouya, Gamestick, Steamboxes or some other as-yet unannounced entrant, there is something very disruptive about the idea of the console that costs $99 and distributes free-to-play or cheaply priced games. Many in the industry are dubious, but then again many in the industry were dubious about the whole Facebook gaming thing and then ended up scrambling to try and get their piece.</p>
<p>Either way, the future is coming to the Moscone Center very soon. Sleep tight.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/784039/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5EV1yJ4guWE:yIn3nC-lleU:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5EV1yJ4guWE:yIn3nC-lleU:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5EV1yJ4guWE:yIn3nC-lleU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5EV1yJ4guWE:yIn3nC-lleU:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=5EV1yJ4guWE:yIn3nC-lleU:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5EV1yJ4guWE:yIn3nC-lleU:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=5EV1yJ4guWE:yIn3nC-lleU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5EV1yJ4guWE:yIn3nC-lleU:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/5EV1yJ4guWE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/what-games-are-twas-the-night-before-gdc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gdc13_logo1.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gdc13_logo1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gdc13_logo1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/06916aaa92c89987b419c3d21fdacfe6?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tadhgk</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gdc13_logo1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gdc13_logo1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/what-games-are-twas-the-night-before-gdc/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Sony Patent Reveals Google Glass Competitor With A Head Mounted Display For Each Eye</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/464dSiRBmrI/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/sony-glass/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 12:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Matt Burns</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sony glass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google glass]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=784197</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sony-glass-1.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="sony-glass-1" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Watch out, Google. A recently published <a target="_blank" href="http://appft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO1&#38;Sect2=HITOFF&#38;d=PG01&#38;p=1&#38;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsrchnum.html&#38;r=1&#38;f=G&#38;l=50&#38;s1=%2220130069850%22.PGNR.&#38;OS=DN/20130069850&#38;RS=DN/20130069850">patent application</a> reveals that Sony's head mounted display glasses are progressing down the evolutionary path rather nicely. What once amounted to just wide-eyed concepts, this latest patent filing, a continuation patent filed on November 14, 2012, shows that Sony, with perhaps a bit of inspiration for <a href="http://techcrunch.com/tag/google-glass">Google Glass</a>, is nearing a practical model. And unlike Google's take on HMDs, Sony's has information displays for both eyes.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sony-glass-1.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="sony-glass-1" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Watch out, Google. A recently published <a target="_blank" href="http://appft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO1&amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;d=PG01&amp;p=1&amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsrchnum.html&amp;r=1&amp;f=G&amp;l=50&amp;s1=%2220130069850%22.PGNR.&amp;OS=DN/20130069850&amp;RS=DN/20130069850">patent application</a> reveals that Sony&#8217;s head mounted display glasses are progressing down the evolutionary path rather nicely. What once amounted to just wide-eyed concepts, this latest patent filing, a continuation patent filed on November 14, 2012, shows that Sony, with perhaps a bit of inspiration for <a href="http://techcrunch.com/tag/google-glass">Google Glass</a>, is nearing a practical model. And unlike Google&#8217;s take on HMDs, Sony&#8217;s has information displays for both eyes.</p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t the first patent to reveal Sony&#8217;s HMD aspirations. A <a target="_blank" href="http://www.engadget.com/2012/06/22/sony-patent-filing-for-glasses-would-share-data-face-to-face/">patent published</a> in the summer of 2012 shows a futuristic device &#8212; it looks like something from a made-for-TV sci-fi movie. The device in that patent has two lens, not connected by a traditional bridge, with each lens acting also serving as a display. There are cameras and battery packs and the works. This is, after all, just a concept. </p>
<p>Sony&#8217;s most recent patent is a more practical take on HMD glasses. They&#8217;re built on a traditional glasses frame in a sort of Google Glass fashion. The actual pop-up display sits behind the glasses&#8217; lenses and, as previously mentioned, there are two displays along with ear buds mounted on little arms.</p>
<p></p>
<p>The patent doesn&#8217;t reveal any information on the displayed content, but it does state it&#8217;s a 2D interface. The screens are also movable by several millimeters, allowing the wearing to fine tune the placement. </p>
<p>Sony has long history with head mounted displays and augmented reality units including commercially available home entertainment devices like the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.sony.co.uk/product/personal-3d-viewer/hmz-t2">HMZ-T2 Personal 3d Viewer</a>. This recent filing is a continuation on patents filed in 2008 and 2009; Sony has been working on this particular device for a significant amount of time.  A <a target="_blank" href="http://www.faqs.org/patents/app/20130044042">bunch</a> <a target="_blank" href="http://www.faqs.org/patents/app/20130038511">of</a> <a target="_blank" href="http://www.faqs.org/patents/app/20130038510">recent</a> <a target="_blank" href="http://www.faqs.org/patents/app/20130050065">patent</a> <a target="_blank" href="http://www.faqs.org/patents/app/20130021374">filings</a> show the company is committed to these devices. Google is not alone in this space. </p>
<p>The war for your eyes is about to take on a whole new meaning.</p>
<p>This is a brand new market. There is enough room for Sony, Google and likely several companies quietly building their own head mounted displays. Each company has unique strengths. Google has the advantage of its all-knowing, always-connected services. Sony has been building world-class hardware for 50 years &#8212; and has a dynamic new CEO in Kazuo Hirai.</p>
<p>Now about that bar in Seattle. <a target="_blank" href="http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2013/03/seattle-bar-bans-google-glass-still-loves-beer-goggles/">They only banned</a> Google&#8217;s model, right?</p>
<p></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/784197/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=464dSiRBmrI:VQXoj1ksnyY:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=464dSiRBmrI:VQXoj1ksnyY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=464dSiRBmrI:VQXoj1ksnyY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=464dSiRBmrI:VQXoj1ksnyY:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=464dSiRBmrI:VQXoj1ksnyY:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=464dSiRBmrI:VQXoj1ksnyY:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=464dSiRBmrI:VQXoj1ksnyY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=464dSiRBmrI:VQXoj1ksnyY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/464dSiRBmrI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/sony-glass/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sony-glass-1.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sony-glass-1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sony-glass-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c921fdee122025b0436360dc6bb7322d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mjburnsy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sony-glass-3.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sony-glass-3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sony-glass-2.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sony-glass-2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/sony-glass/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>The Crowd's Money Can Dominate Early-Stage Investing, But Only If The VCs Get Their Cut</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/5-Anlq6fnFc/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/781442/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 10:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Zach Noorani</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crowdfunding]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781442</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/willywonkacane.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="WillyWonkacane" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><b>Editor’s note:</b> <em>This is the second part of a two-part guest column by Zach Noorani.</em>

Is angel capital an attractive asset class? Is the crowd capable of being good investors, willing to spend 20-40 hours doing due diligence per investment? These are critical questions to help determine just how big equity crowdfunding will become, right? I say no.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/willywonkacane.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="WillyWonkacane" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Editor’s note:</strong> <em>This is the second part of a two-part guest column by <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/zachary-j-noorani">Zach Noorani</a>. <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/17/is-software-eating-the-venture-capitalists-too-part-i/">Part one</a> examined whether equity crowdfunding is a threat to VCs. Zach <b></b>is a former VC and current second-year MBA student at MIT Sloan. Follow him on Twitter <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/znoorani">@znoorani</a>.</em></p>
<p>Is angel capital an attractive asset class? Is the crowd capable of being good investors, willing to spend 20-40 hours doing due diligence per investment? These are critical questions to help determine just how big equity crowdfunding will become, right? I say no.</p>
<p>Successful startup investing is way too hard, and the wisdom of the crowd is way too useless if not destructive (in this case at least). For equity crowdfunding to become a mainstream activity, these questions don’t need to be answered, they need to be removed from the equation.</p>
<p>That’s why the crowdfunding platforms themselves prospect the deals, decide whether they’re attractive, and negotiate the terms. The crowd only sees investment in committee-approved, neatly packaged and pre-negotiated deals.</p>
<ul>
<li><b>FundersClub</b> advertises that <a target="_blank" href="https://thefundersclub.com/site/vetting/">fewer than 5 percent</a> of applicant companies get listed on its site.</li>
<li><b>CircleUp’s</b> acceptance rate is <a target="_blank" href="https://circleup.com/investor-education/faq/">less than 2 percent</a>.</li>
<li><b>AngelList’s </b>approval rate barely registers given that just 15 companies can be invested in online out of the 15K or so they have access to.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can call that simple curation, but it’s the same process with largely the same ratios that institutional VCs undertake. In essence, crowdfunding platforms are the <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Limited_partnership">general partner</a> venture capitalist and have made the crowd their limited partner investors. Their economic models might differ from normal VCs, but their path to success is the same: Build an investment portfolio that makes their LPs an attractive return.</p>
<p>In terms of what constitutes an attractive return, crowdfunding has some advantages over traditional VCs.</p>
<p>In many cases, investors aren’t charged management fees or carried interest, and the “2 and 20” fee structure of most VC funds is expensive as hell. Rather than trust my math, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2008/08/venture-fund--1.html">Fred Wilson</a> calculated the difference between gross (what the crowd gets) and net (what regular VC LPs get) returns on a fund that nominally did a 4x: 39.2 percent (gross) vs. 28.6 percent (net). Big difference.<b></b></p>
<p><b></b>Another advantage is that crowd investors get to pick and choose when to participate. While hard to quantify, there should be some economic value associated with this option.</p>
<p>Taken together, returns as low as break-even (per annual vintage) could be enough to entice the masses. Either by luck or successful cherry-picking, a large portion of the crowd would then be able to make money. But how feasible are break-even returns and at what level of scale? To answer, let’s examine the three models of equity crowdfunding: VC pledge funds; online private placement; and loss leaders.</p>
<h5><b>Venture Capital Pledge Funds</b></h5>
<p>Think <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/fundersclub">FundersClub</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/ourcrowd">OurCrowd</a>. Much like traditional asset managers, the model requires a combination of management fee on capital invested and carried interest on profits. But rather than having committed capital, investors come in on a deal-by-deal basis.</p>
<h3 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:250px;float:right;color:#0a9400;">fee structures matter but not nearly as much as deal quality.</h3>
<p>FundersClub, for example, charges a one-time fee (<a target="_blank" href="https://thefundersclub.com/site/faq/">$300 for a $2.5K investment</a>) to cover transaction costs and will eventually institute a carried interest fee – meaning they make money when investors do, aligning them well with investors generally.</p>
<p>One disconnect, however, is that crowdfunding carry on good investments won’t be affected by the bad, which implies little direct incentive to avoid them. Depending on the return profile, this can also make VC pledge funds quite expensive. Take a very simple example (ignoring management fees):</p>
<ul>
<li>A $50 million VC fund (with 20 percent carry) makes 10 $5 million investments in year one</li>
<li>In year five: Five deals return nothing, three return principal, and two return 3.5x principal</li>
<li>Fund return: 1.0x gross, $0 in carry, 1.0x net</li>
<li>Identical performance from a crowdfunding business (with 20 percent carry) nets 0.86x to the crowd</li>
<li>For the crowd to get 1.0x principal, the portfolio must gross 1.18x (4 percent IRR over the five years)</li>
</ul>
<p>Certainly fee structures matter but not nearly as much as deal quality. While some might view crowd capital with a stigma, to entrepreneurs VC pledge funds are just very public angel groups with perhaps fewer voting rights – overall, not a huge handicap in deal sourcing. And to find deals they use exactly the same tactics as every other professional investor. Therefore success here requires the same caliber of deal sourcing ingenuity and investment acumen as it does for all VCs.</p>
<p>As a result, the sector should develop in some predictable ways:</p>
<p><b>1. </b> To raise a devoted VC fund, you actually have to convince relatively sophisticated investors to bet on you based on your experience and capabilities. Since the crowd largely thinks they’re the general partner, crowdfunding managers face no such scrutiny. Resulting performance should therefore be markedly worse.  Expect most VC pledge fund managers – hundreds maybe – to fall far short of returning investor capital.</p>
<p><b>2.</b>  Some portion will do well by accident.</p>
<p><b>3.  </b>A few will actually prove to be exceptional fund managers.</p>
<p><b>4.  </b>It’ll be hard to tell which is which at least for the first couple of years and there’ll be many bad companies funded and money lost in the process.</p>
<p><b>5.  </b>Given all this uncertainty, the crowd will favor the few that successfully build brands.  But if those players are also good investment managers, their deal volume won’t expand much to meet investor demand.  So the more enthusiasm the Crowd has for the asset class, the more they’ll be pushed to less credible platforms.</p>
<p><b>6.  </b>Speaking of, anyone want to start a Morningstar-like evaluation and performance measurement service for equity crowdfunding platforms? The industry will desperately need one.</p>
<p><b>7.  </b>All this will happen no matter how stringent the SEC’s crowdfunding guidelines end up being. It’s just a tricky asset class.</p>
<h5></h5>
<h5><b>How This Affects Venture Capitalists</b></h5>
<p>We’re basically just talking about a bunch of new angel groups. The more the merrier as far as VCs are concerned. Their money would help more startups get further along before needing a $5 million &#8211; $10 million round. To VCs that means more and less risky investment opportunities to choose from. Maybe Sequoia should send FundersClub some flowers?</p>
<p>But what will happen to the few successful VC pledge fund managers? Undoubtedly they’ll be tempted to move beyond seed rounds and invest larger amounts in later-stage companies, take board seats and invest in stealth companies and follow-on rounds. Perhaps they’ll find a way to do all that through crowdfunding.</p>
<p>And if they do, you can be sure that established VCs would follow suit (<a target="_blank" href="https://www.secondmarket.com/fund/500-startups-ii">500 Startups is already trying</a>). They won’t actually renounce their existing limited partners so this would mean billions of incremental dollars from the crowd gushing into the market. Could this over-capitalize the industry and hurt everyone’s return?  Sure, but so long as the VCs get to manage that capital, they’re happy to take that risk.</p>
<p>More likely, however, is that successful crowdfunding managers raise capital from traditional limited partners themselves or get poached by established VC funds with their famous brands, rich fee structures, and steady streams of committed capital.</p>
<h5><b>Online Private Placement</b></h5>
<p>Private placement agents, deal brokers, bankers, etc. have always played a large offline role in the startup ecosystem. They help companies raise money in exchange for some combination of retainer, percentage of the capital raised, and equity.</p>
<p>With online platforms, deal brokers are extending their services down market, now able to represent many more businesses to many more investors. But at some point “more” investors means the crowd and then their model has to change. To compensate for the crowd’s naiveté and laziness, the placement agent himself has to assume responsibility for maintaining high-deal selection standards. Some dynamics unique to brokers make this problematic:</p>
<p><b>1.</b> <b>Success Fee-Based Compensation –</b> Your real estate agent doesn’t care what house you buy, just that you buy one and that it’s expensive so that he gets a fee and it’s big. If a broker’s thinking is too short-term, what keeps him from offering whatever deals he thinks he can get the crowd to invest in (regardless of objective quality) so as to earn a fee?</p>
<p><b>2. </b><a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adverse_selection"><b>Adverse Selection</b></a> – In a market filled with active and competitive investors, why is it necessary for companies to hire bankers and pay them ~5 percent to 10 percent of the amount raised? Sometimes the decision bears no reflection on the quality of the company for reasons like transaction complexity, geographic remoteness, or esoteric industry focus.  But sometimes it means something is amiss and you’d do well to pass on the opportunity.</p>
<p>Given these distorting incentives, it’ll be even harder for private placement platforms to build break-even portfolios than VC pledge funds. But not impossible.</p>
<p>CircleUp provides an interesting example. They focus on consumer businesses, which CEO Ryan Caldbeck explains are “20 percent of the economy but just 4 percent of angel capital.” Further, consumer startups with annual sales &lt;$20 million are subscale for private equity and not technology-driven enough for most VCs.  That focus perhaps alleviates the negative selection risk.</p>
<p>But are their long-term incentives compelling enough to enforce maniacal deal screening? Here’s my back of the envelope for CircleUp’s model:</p>
<h3 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:250px;float:left;color:#0a9400;">most startups will fail no matter how much capital they raise.</h3>
<p>There are 1.4 million consumer businesses in the U.S. with &lt;$20 million in annual sales. If you buy that the sector’s truly underserved, then it’s not crazy to assume 2 percent are attractive investments. If 10 percent of those companies raise $300K annually through CircleUp, that yields the company $70 million in revenue (assuming 5 percent broker fee). And there are lots of acquirers who’d pay attractive multiples for a value-add transaction processing business (just wait and see what Eventbrite trades at once it goes public). Interesting, right?</p>
<p>VCs are reluctant to admit it, but they regularly work with private placement agents. There’s no reason they wouldn’t patronize the online version for the right deal. In fact, the more effective deal screening and packaging that brokers provide the more of VC analysts’ jobs they&#8217;re doing. Not much threat here.</p>
<h5><b>Loss Leaders</b></h5>
<p>By this I mean <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/angellist">AngelList</a>.</p>
<p>AngelList’s primary goal is to connect startups with investors. Think of them as a private placement platform without the fees – CEO Naval Ravikant has repeatedly said that AngelList will never attempt to monetize fundraising-related activities. Any company can make a listing, most can get introductions, some get recommended to investors, and now a choice few are made available to invest in online.</p>
<p>AngelList wants to help make building companies easier. It’s also a social network, and fulfilling that mission expands the user base and increases engagement, which they&#8217;ll eventually monetize through premium services. But most startups will fail no matter how much capital they raise. AngelList’s essential value, therefore, is not as an indiscriminate fundraising service for private companies, but as a platform that helps discern which companies might actually succeed and make investors money. And to build the type of long-term usage they need, they must be good at this discernment.</p>
<p>Consequently, AngelList is in a unique position to dominate equity crowdfunding. Investors receive full gross returns and are unaffected by perverse deal quality incentives facing pledge funds and brokers. Furthermore, AngelList doesn’t need to deal source; they see the vast majority of early-stage deals automatically – tens of thousands at any given time. If they can just crack the formula of deal selection and demonstrate consistent break-even returns, the volume of online investments they facilitate could become enormous.</p>
<h3 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:640px;float:center;color:#0a9400;">The first few billion dollars of crowd capital will do nothing but de-risk the deals VCs were going to do anyway.</h3>
<p>Who needs VCs then, right?  Some of AngelList&#8217;s most predictive data has to be which investors have committed to participating in a particular round. Said differently, a VC’s vetting process is likely a critical input to AngelList’s approval engine so the crowd could never actually replace professional investors in this model. Not to mention that someone still needs to structure and lead the transactions as well as represent the security’s voting rights.</p>
<p>In that sense, the crowd’s money would only complement professional investor dollars, producing many more and less risky Series A investment opportunities. Perhaps a whole lot of them. Maybe the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nvca.org">NVCA</a> should throw a banquet in AngelList’s honor?</p>
<p>In an end-state where AngelList’s crowdfunding service has proven viable, perhaps they’ll find ways to broaden the Crowd’s investment capabilities to handle larger amounts, follow-on commitments, etc. But the need for VCs to both vet the deal and facilitate the transaction remains unchanged.</p>
<p>One thought, however: The VC’s value in AngelList crowdfunding is likely not correlated with investment amount, meaning that $2 million from the right $50 million fund can mean the same as $20 million from a $500 million fund. Perhaps the crowd would be interested in making up the $18 million difference.</p>
<h5><b>So What’s The Damn Answer?</b></h5>
<p>VCs are the <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Br'er_Rabbit">Br’er Rabbit</a> of the startup ecosystem. They can appear vulnerable and don’t mind playing the woeful underdog. But they invented the rules for the game that I’ve discussed. Any sort of change is rarely more than an opportunity to outcompete one another.</p>
<p>The first few billion dollars of crowd capital will do nothing but de-risk the deals VCs were going to do anyway. In the meantime, all that crowd activity will fund development of deal-screening services that VCs will use to improve their coverage and slim down their teams.</p>
<p>If the crowd is ever going to approach a 40 bps allocation to startups (<a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/17/is-software-eating-the-venture-capitalists-too-part-i/">as discussed in part one</a>), it’ll be because the VCs engineered it and profited handsomely in the process. Their revenue models and fund structures might shift, but they’ll continue to control where the capital goes.</p>
<p><em>[Images: <a target="_blank" href="http://eddieonfilm.blogspot.com/2011_06_01_archive.html">Willy</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/kismihok/2894418909/sizes/z/in/photostream/">shadow crowd</a>]</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781442/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5-Anlq6fnFc:m5OjMUS6_EM:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5-Anlq6fnFc:m5OjMUS6_EM:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5-Anlq6fnFc:m5OjMUS6_EM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5-Anlq6fnFc:m5OjMUS6_EM:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=5-Anlq6fnFc:m5OjMUS6_EM:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5-Anlq6fnFc:m5OjMUS6_EM:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=5-Anlq6fnFc:m5OjMUS6_EM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5-Anlq6fnFc:m5OjMUS6_EM:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/5-Anlq6fnFc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/781442/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/willywonkacane.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/willywonkacane.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WillyWonkacane</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2a014e70509390133a9b9073671a2e8d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tcbucket</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonkacanegif.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WonkaCanegif</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/crowd-shadow.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">crowd shadow</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/781442/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>To Grow Or Die In The Cloud</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/UFwZTvpiXP4/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/grow-to-dominate-in-2013-or-watch-someone-else-do-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 06:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Byron Deeter</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=779671</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/window-washers.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="window washers" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><b>Editor's note:</b> <em>Byron Deeter is the lead cloud specialist at Bessemer Venture Partners.</em>

A few years ago, most people couldn’t tell you what the cloud was, let alone anticipate a market in which the sexy, highly anticipated consumer Internet IPOs were flops while the seemingly nerdy sectors of cloud and enterprise computing ended up driving the technology market returns.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/window-washers.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="window washers" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>Byron Deeter is the lead cloud specialist at Bessemer Venture Partners. Follow him on Twitter <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/bdeeter">@bdeeter</a>.</em></p>
<p>A few years ago, most people couldn’t tell you what the cloud was. They certainly couldn&#8217;t foresee a market in which the sexy, highly anticipated consumer Internet IPOs <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/09/11/zuckerberg-on-facebooks-ipo-stock-performance-has-been-disappointing/">would</a> be <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/05/more-competitors-smarter-gamers-expensive-ads-less-virality-mobile/">flops</a> while the seemingly nerdy sectors of <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/01/hr-software-maker-workday-sets-price-range-for-ipo-at-21-to-24-per-share-valued-at-nearly-4b/">cloud</a> and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/01/hr-software-maker-workday-sets-price-range-for-ipo-at-21-to-24-per-share-valued-at-nearly-4b/">enterprise</a> computing would end up driving returns within the technology markets. For entrepreneurs and investors in cloud computing, market valuations are skyrocketing as acquisition activity heats up, the IPO markets are open, and venture dollars are finally flooding into the segment. Simply put, for participants in the cloud computing market, our time has finally come.</p>
<p>Businesses are moving <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/09/box-stats/">toward cloud-based operations</a> in a permanent way, and the fundamental business metrics of the category leaders are enjoying staggering growth as a result. A few minutes of scrolling through a few pages <a href="http://techcrunch.com/tag/cloud/">here</a> gives a clear sense of the scope and potential of the market.</p>
<p>The IPOs of companies like WorkDay and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/08/02/so-far-so-go-good-for-eloqua-ipo-shares-up-13-in-first-day-of-trading/">Eloqua</a> (then <a target="_blank" href="http://www.thedeal.com/content/tmt/oracle-acquires-eloqua-for-871m.php">acquired</a>), are further evidence of market support for these compelling business models. And private companies such as <a target="_blank" href="http://venturebeat.com/2012/08/29/clearslide-funding/">Clearslide</a>, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/02/bizo-series-b/">Bizo</a> and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/11/09/twilio-raises-12-million-for-powerful-telephony-api/">Twilio</a> all announced significant (even market-moving) news that signaled further growth and opportunity not only for them but also for the industry at large.</p>
<h3 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:640px;float:center;color:#0a9400;">Best-of-breed cloud applications will lead the next wave of innovation.</h3>
<p>How will this play out in 2013 and beyond? Best-of-breed cloud applications will lead the next wave of innovation. The momentum in the enterprise segment and the continued hyper-growth of cloud computing will force legacy suite vendors to attempt to buy their way more deeply into the cloud markets. The leading “next-generation” SaaS vendors, including Salesforce.com, Workday, LinkedIn, NetSuite and Concur, are finding it necessary to aggressively expand into adjacent product offerings or risk being disrupted by newer  applications that are challenging them from all sides.</p>
<h5>Laws Of Cloud Computing</h5>
<p>As a former founder of a cloud-computing startup (and now an investor in the space), I’ve tried to leverage the lessons learned throughout my efforts, as well as those of my partners, our portfolio company executives, and other leading cloud entrepreneurs, to create some best practices with which to thrive in this market. So starting in 2008, the cloud investment team at BVP developed <a target="_blank" href="https://bvp.box.com/10lawsofcloudcomputing">Bessemer’s 10 Laws of Cloud Computing</a>.</p>
<p>One very notable addition is the recent inclusion of a new law: “Grow or Die.” There is currently a land-grab market opportunity around cloud that is a once-in-a-decade (or more) phenomenon. Growth and innovation are critically important to capture the long-term leadership position, because aggressive challengers are lurking close behind the leaders in many cases.</p>
<h5>Grow Or Die Investor-Style</h5>
<p>From an investment standpoint, Grow or Die means recognizing that there are market and company windows of opportunity in which to be aggressive. Aggressive doesn’t mean investing blindly in sales capacity when a product and/or the market isn’t ready. But if there are compelling business economics, then it is actually irresponsible not to invest in growth to capture the full market potential — because if you don’t, someone else will.</p>
<h5>Grow Or Die Entrepreneur-Style</h5>
<p>From an entrepreneurial perspective, Grow or Die means that you need to be extremely proactive in thinking through the right rate and pace of investments, and when to really go &#8220;all in&#8221; on the business. Box CEO Aaron Levie is a great example of this mentality and is an extremely popular speaker on this topic. Box has visibly raised a significant amount of capital and is extremely aggressive at capturing market share – essentially striving to dominate the Microsoft SharePoint ecosystem.</p>
<p>Numerous alternatives existed for them, including organically growing the business at a much slower rate from existing cash flow, raising modest amounts of venture capital to grow at a more measured rate, and/or selling out along the way. Instead they believe (as do the rest of us as investors!) that the opportunity is sufficiently large and the unit economics are sufficiently compelling, that the additional dilution from additional financing is less than the long-term value creation that comes from growing the business at an even faster rate.</p>
<p>Given the tremendous tailwind in the cloud market, the re-platforming opportunity of software overall, and the unique window of time in which startups are actually advantaged relative to the incumbents, many companies have real opportunities to build category-defining products that achieve true market dominance. These factors (along with the huge valuations!) combine to make it a great time to be a cloud entrepreneur, and a really fun time to be a cloud investor.</p>
<p>[Images: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nffcnnr/3727598373/sizes/n/in/photostream/">Washers</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rameshng/6045027221/sizes/m/in/photostream">windows</a>.]</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/779671/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=UFwZTvpiXP4:jUExs9VSyvM:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=UFwZTvpiXP4:jUExs9VSyvM:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=UFwZTvpiXP4:jUExs9VSyvM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=UFwZTvpiXP4:jUExs9VSyvM:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=UFwZTvpiXP4:jUExs9VSyvM:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=UFwZTvpiXP4:jUExs9VSyvM:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=UFwZTvpiXP4:jUExs9VSyvM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=UFwZTvpiXP4:jUExs9VSyvM:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/UFwZTvpiXP4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/grow-to-dominate-in-2013-or-watch-someone-else-do-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/window-washers.jpg?w=120" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/window-washers.jpg?w=120" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">window washers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2a014e70509390133a9b9073671a2e8d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tcbucket</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/cloud-reflection.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cloud reflection</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/grow-to-dominate-in-2013-or-watch-someone-else-do-it/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Backed Or Whacked: Baubles For Your Bike – Part 2</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/pppo_-VPlJc/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/backed-or-whacked-baubles-for-your-bike-part-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 04:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ross Rubin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backed or whacked]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=783028</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/backed-whacked-logo11.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Backed or Whacked logo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><b>Editor’s note: </b><em>Ross Rubin is principal analyst at Reticle Research and blogs at Techspressive. Each column will look at crowdfunded products that have either met or missed their funding goals.</em>

Last week’s Backed or Whacked <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/16/backed-or-whacked-baubles-for-your-bike-part-i/">column</a> looked at a trio of small, easily attached bicycle accessories that could beef up your ride’s horn, assist in toting shopping bags, or add more secure footing to your pedal. This week’s column looks at some larger accoutrements that can help bicyclists with their burdens. Unfortunately, none of them could get over their fundraising hill.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/backed-whacked-logo11.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Backed or Whacked logo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><b>Editor’s note: </b><i>Ross Rubin is principal analyst at </i><a target="_blank" href="http://www.reticleresearch.com/"><i>Reticle Research</i></a><i> and blogs at </i><a target="_blank" href="http://www.techspressive.com/"><i>Techspressive</i></a><i>. Each column will look at crowdfunded products that have either met or missed their funding goals. Follow him on Twitter </i><a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/rossrubin"><i>@rossrubin</i></a><i>.</i></p>
<p>Last week’s Backed or Whacked <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/16/backed-or-whacked-baubles-for-your-bike-part-i/">column</a> looked at a trio of small, easily attached bicycle accessories that could beef up your ride’s horn, assist in toting shopping bags, or add more secure footing to your pedals. This week’s column looks at some larger accoutrements that can help bicyclists with their burdens. Unfortunately, none of them could get over their fundraising hill.</p>
<p><b>Whacked: </b><b><a target="_blank" href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/548672532/roadbug-motorized-bicycle-kit?ref=category">RoadBug</a>.</b><b> </b>One day, mechanical augmentations will have the power to turn us all into bionic super beings. Until the day insurance companies deny coverage on those procedures, though, we can mod our bikes to go farther and faster.</p>
<p>Hudson, NY’s James Brisciana had sought to put his 10 years of experience in the bicycle motorization business to produce the RoadBug, a friction-based moped conversion kit that can accommodate four-stroke engines from the likes of Huasheng and Honda. The kit was also available without the engine at just $99, a $50 discount off the proposed price. Unfortunately, the campaign ran out of gas with Brisciana attracting less than $4,500 of the $20,000 sought.</p>
<p><b>Whacked: </b><b><a target="_blank" href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/loco/instant-cargo-bike-50-mile-ebike-or-moped-thats-lo?ref=category">Loko</a>.</b><b> </b>It may be a coincidence that the bike cargo system dreamed up by Albuquerque-based Loko Bike Products has some verbal similarity to the Lego construction toys, but the bike add-on offers a dizzying array of expansion options nonetheless. Starting with a simple “V-rack” base unit ($99 for early adopters) that quickly attaches to and detaches from a bike, Loko is a modular, convertible, removable cargo bike rack system. The“O-mounts” on its surface can accommodate an impressive array of bags, boxes, banana seats and baby seats, electric or gas conversion options, folding 8&#8243; or 12&#8243; extensions called U-bars, and even ruggedized iPhone cases for capturing video of the ride. With about 15 days left in the campaign, though, only 36 backers have dipped into Loko’s tantalizing alphabet soup of V-racks, O-mounts and U-bars, and the Loko motion has stalled out at just over $4,000 &#8211; a far cry from its $75,000 goal.</p>
<p><b>Whacked: </b><b><a target="_blank" href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1266057078/stemlite-integrated-bicycle-light?ref=category">StemLite</a>.</b><b> </b>&#8220;Ow!&#8221; That&#8217;s the expression heard after you slap your head, forgetting to bring the clip-on bike light. Well, the eventual pain could be much worse if you decide not to turn back for it and go out less-than-gently into that good night. Reasoning that bikes, like cars, should have integrated road lighting, the duet of Nick Sweeney and James Voshell created the StemLite. The product replaces the bike part upon which the handlebar rests with one that integrates an LED light powered by three AA batteries. However, backers failed to deliver in the cold light of day, and the campaign ended with only $3,200 pledged of its $45,000 target.</p>
<p><b>Whacked: </b><b><a target="_blank" href="http://www.indiegogo.com/projects/bike-trailer-with-electric-motor-the-power-to-pedal-with-kids">Ridekick</a>.</b> When you were young and free, you’d scoot around on your two-wheeler dragging nothing but the wind behind you. But then life started weighing you down, becoming a big uphill climb. What if the weight on your shoulders could be placed behind your bicycle? And what if that weight could push you along instead of drag you down?</p>
<p>That’s the idea of Ridekick. It&#8217;s an electric bike trailer that can accommodate two small children and push you to the next destination through the unending series of errands you must run to keep the little ones healthy and engaged. The Ridekick, slated to be produced in Colorado, was to retail for $899, with a $200 discount for Indiegogo backers. However, the campaign didn&#8217;t quite go off without a hitch and ended with just $6,265 of the $165,000 sought.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/783028/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pppo_-VPlJc:YrWXeH3vtfM:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pppo_-VPlJc:YrWXeH3vtfM:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pppo_-VPlJc:YrWXeH3vtfM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pppo_-VPlJc:YrWXeH3vtfM:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=pppo_-VPlJc:YrWXeH3vtfM:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pppo_-VPlJc:YrWXeH3vtfM:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=pppo_-VPlJc:YrWXeH3vtfM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pppo_-VPlJc:YrWXeH3vtfM:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/pppo_-VPlJc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/backed-or-whacked-baubles-for-your-bike-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/backed-whacked-logo11.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/backed-whacked-logo11.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Backed or Whacked logo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/28e1123cb0d96ecdf0a9d854e8c93c14?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rossrubin1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bw-roadbug.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">BW-roadbug</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bw-loko.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">BW-loko</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bw-stemlite.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">BW-stemlite</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bw-ridekick.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">BW-ridekick</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/backed-or-whacked-baubles-for-your-bike-part-2/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>The Evolution Of Google Reader Started With A Crash</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/pVm-av7hWP8/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/the-long-and-storied-history-of-google-reader/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 01:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jason Shellen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google_Reader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=783691</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/reader-melt.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="reader melt" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><b>Editor’s note:</b> <em>Jason Shellen is a former Googler and founding product manager of Google Reader. He is now co-founder at Boxer and advisor at Tapedeck.</em>

As part of Google's recent announcement that it is <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/13/rip-google-reader/">shutting down Google Reader in July</a>, I thought looking back at the history of how our beloved but beleaguered Reader came to be, why we’ll miss it and what we really want in the future.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/reader-melt.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="reader melt" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><strong>Editor’s note:</strong> <em>Jason Shellen is a former Googler and founding product manager of Google Reader. He is now co-founder at <a target="_blank" href="http://getboxer.com/">Boxer</a> and advisor at <a target="_blank" href="http://tapedeck.com/">Tapedeck</a>. Follow him on his <a target="_blank" href="http://shellen.com/">blog</a> and on Twitter <a target="_blank" href="http://twitter.com/shellen">@shellen</a>.</em></p>
<p>As part of Google&#8217;s recent announcement that it is <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/13/rip-google-reader/">shutting down Google Reader in July</a>, I thought looking back at the history of how our beloved, but beleaguered, feed reader came to be, why we’ll miss it and what we really want in the future.</p>
<p>Back in the days on the Blogger team, we spent a lot of time thinking about how to get people blogging after they had signed up. However, when Blogger achieved critical mass, the need to model good blogging seemed less important since great writers, musicians, photographers and journalists were gravitating towards the form and showing the rest of us what made good blog content. The questions we began to hear from users changed from &#8220;How and what do I blog?&#8221; to &#8220;Where do I find the good ones?&#8221; and &#8220;How do I keep up with all of these great blogs?&#8221; Naturally, blog search and a blog reader or aggregator of some sort couldn&#8217;t be too far off.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, there was an ever-increasing number of good Windows and Mac desktop aggregators popping up (<a target="_blank" href="http://feeddemon.com/">Feed Demon</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://newsgator.com/">NewsGator</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://radio.userland.com/">Radio Userland</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://netnewswireapp.com/">NetNewsWire</a>). They were mostly made by great independent developers but didn&#8217;t have a web-app component until a few years later. Then along came <a target="_blank" href="http://bloglines.com/">Bloglines</a>. It was the first feed aggregator that our Blogger team gravitated towards. It was very simple at first and gained more powerful features over time. But my personal frustrations were growing not just with Bloglines, but with some of the social integrations I wanted to see on the web.<br />
I remember a very early version of Firefox had crashed, taking with it my open Bloglines tab and thus losing the 100+ items that it would surely &#8220;mark as read.&#8221; If I went back to Bloglines it would appear as if I had read all of those items, and there would be no way to catch up. I was upset!</p>
<p>I wheeled around in my chair in the Blogger bullpen and complained to Biz Stone: &#8220;I wish there were some sort of eye tracking that would tell which item I had read and saved my state!&#8221; He agreed with my wacky proposal. I continued to stew.</p>
<p>Aside from dreaming up features for products I didn&#8217;t control, I had spent a considerable amount of time at Google helping to form the cross-industry group that ultimately published the Atom feed format and Atom Publishing Protocol. We were pushing Atom to become a recognized Internet standard, with companies such as Six Apart, IBM and Macromedia onboard. When Blogger turned on Atom feeds for all of our millions of users, Blogger single-handedly became the No. 1 producer of feeds in the world. This was huge for aggregators, because for any of them to become mainstream, more content in a subscribable format was needed.</p>
<h3 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:250px;float:left;color:#0a9400;">One beautiful wonderful thing happened along the way to creating Atom.</h3>
<p>Atom was an effort to make feed reading and subscriptions more consumer friendly. If we were really successful with what we had built, we imagined a world where you didn&#8217;t need to market the plumbing of a technology to realize the benefit. Some who embraced RSS-only saw this as an opportunity to latch onto a brewing controversy or, worse, as the window to market RSS to consumers. The next few years would be a boring marketing landscape, as we saw orange and blue chicklets slapped up haphazardly around the web. In hindsight it&#8217;s easy to see that consumers understood words like &#8220;follow&#8221; or &#8220;friend&#8221; for content they wanted delivered regularly rather than &#8220;subscribe,&#8221; &#8220;RSS&#8221; or &#8220;Atom feed.&#8221;</p>
<p>One beautiful wonderful thing happened along the way to creating Atom. For a few years, I had kept a little side-blog right alongside my main blog at <a target="_blank" href="http://shellen.com/">shellen.com</a>. The main view showed larger posts, but I was using some server-side code to read a file I was publishing in another directory and display the second blog on the right-hand column. It was great for shorter posts, but I wondered if there would be a way to display an Atom feed alongside my blog instead of my slapped-together solution.</p>
<p>I wondered this aloud to Chris Wetherell one day in 2004, an engineer on the Blogger team.</p>
<p>&#8220;Say Chris, do you suppose you could display an Atom feed in JavaScript?&#8221; He took the challenge and &#8220;Feedless&#8221; was born. I dropped in a few files on my blog server and pointed it to my new Blogger-created Atom feed. It worked!</p>
<p>However, Chris wanted to show me something else. He quickly modified his first script into something that could display more than one feed into a beast that could blend items together. My mind raced and I saw the value immediately. We could create Blogger Friends, a page on Blogger where you could see all of the blog posts from your friends. LiveJournal had something like this years earlier but maybe you could even follow people who weren&#8217;t on Blogger? Before long this was all Chris and I could talk about, and plans began for Chris&#8217; 20 percent project to become a full-fledged Google project in early 2005.</p>
<p>The &#8220;Goals and Objectives&#8221; section of the product plan for Project Fusion (an early codename for Google Reader) stated &#8220;Our goal is to build a robust web service and best-of-breed user interface for viewing subscriptions. We will be producing an API for read/unread state of individual posts on a per-user basis and will also build our feed viewer on top of this API.&#8221; Pretty geeky stuff. However, we also had a vision statement that was sufficiently less geeky and more jaw-droppingly, ambitious. &#8220;Our vision is to become the world&#8217;s best collaborative and intelligent web content delivery service.&#8221;</p>
<h3 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:250px;float:right;color:#0a9400;">I’m sad to see it go but Google Reader shutting down isn’t a surprise to me.</h3>
<p>As far as we were concerned, the text of blog posts was just the beginning of a content revolution. In fact that early codename, Fusion, was meant to be a hint of the future of how web content would be consumed, fused together perhaps in a new TV-like format.</p>
<p>The future was ripe with possibilities. Our little team was going to launch our product on Google Labs, which meant we could try wild ideas. We knew that Google Video was around the corner and YouTube was still an independent but promising site. We also knew that the Picasa acquisition would help bring fast photo embedding and display to the web. The possibilities were seemingly endless. Our short-term vision included tying all of this together in an easy-to-consume way that also allowed you to easily share it with friends and find or subscribe to more content from a search box powered by Google all from within our app.</p>
<p>In October 2005, Google Reader launched to 100,000 of our closest friends. The team pulled off some amazing feats in a short amount of time. We quickly learned that there was indeed a truly long tail of feed-based content. We experimented with audio, video and photo content displays. We became the relied-upon backend for iGoogle’s feed-based gadgets and had a Reader gadget on iGoogle that became one of my favorite ways to use Reader.</p>
<p>But in early 2006, it was clear to me that, while I was proud of what we were building, we weren’t likely to be that magical fusion of all things digital. I moved on to other projects at Google. Reader was and remains today a great delivery system of content you knew you wanted to see every day.</p>
<p>I’m sad to see it go, but Google Reader shutting down isn’t a surprise to me. The recent hiccups and fact that it remained separate from any other Google social efforts didn’t bode well for its long-term health. I’m certainly overwhelmed by the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.change.org/petitions/google-keep-google-reader-running">petition</a> and public outcry. And who doesn’t love a good “<a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=A25VgNZDQ08">Downfall</a>” parody? But what is it that we’re responding to in Google’s decision to shutter Reader?</p>
<h3 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:640px;float:center;color:#0a9400;">Reader was like TiVo for the web, appealing to completists and skippers alike.</h3>
<p>Reader was an application that felt like you were in control of the programming. You could summon the content you told it to keep track of at your leisure. Reader was like TiVo for the web, appealing to completists and skippers alike. Read everything or read nothing. The choice was yours. When we started Reader, I envisioned something a little more like Google News that knew about your likes and dislikes and would program based on what we thought we knew about you. Indeed recommendations became a part of Reader in the past few years.</p>
<p>But it’s no surprise that Facebook and Twitter (who know an awful lot about what you like) are in a better position to deliver suggested content these days. They don’t explicitly put you in the driver’s seat of programming what you see. We rely on the people (or brands) we follow to act as filters. But it’s not that level of control we came to expect with Reader.</p>
<p>A feed reader lets you subscribe to known content. A feed reader lets you know about content you should subscribe to. A good feed reader lets you know what your friends are reading and gives you the opportunity to share. A smart feed reader displays content in a specific way based on the content and shows you only what you need to know and nothing you don’t. Perhaps the smartest of them all doesn’t need to care whether or not this content comes from a feed at all, toes the line between curating and creating content, and maybe already exists.</p>
<p>I’ve been asked a lot recently if an aggregator or feed reader is even needed these days and what should take Reader’s place. Certainly the folks at <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/22/feedly-winning-on-mobile/">Feedly</a>, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/14/digg-yes-that-digg-is-building-a-google-reader-replacement-complete-with-api/">Digg</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://zite.com/">Zite</a> and others have promising efforts, but my recommendation is to build something that moves beyond the confines of reading or feeds. Just build the world&#8217;s best collaborative and intelligent content-delivery service.</p>
<p><em>[Illustration: Bryce Durbin]</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/783691/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pVm-av7hWP8:CojjyGWDP1Q:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pVm-av7hWP8:CojjyGWDP1Q:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pVm-av7hWP8:CojjyGWDP1Q:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pVm-av7hWP8:CojjyGWDP1Q:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=pVm-av7hWP8:CojjyGWDP1Q:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pVm-av7hWP8:CojjyGWDP1Q:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=pVm-av7hWP8:CojjyGWDP1Q:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pVm-av7hWP8:CojjyGWDP1Q:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/pVm-av7hWP8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/the-long-and-storied-history-of-google-reader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/reader-melt.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/reader-melt.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">reader melt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2a014e70509390133a9b9073671a2e8d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tcbucket</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/started-crash.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">it started with a crash</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/feed-beast.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">feed the beast</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/magical.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">it could have been magical</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beyond1.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">beyond the feed</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/the-long-and-storied-history-of-google-reader/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>August Capital's David Hornik On How To Find ‘Smart Money' For Your Startup [TCTV]</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/JyPpLAimm0A/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/august-capitals-david-hornik-smart-money-video/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 22:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Colleen Taylor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=776904</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-22-at-3-56-35-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="david hornik" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Startup founders just getting their projects off the ground can be so focused on finding money, period, that they don't think about being choosy about who it comes from. But according to <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/august-capital">August Capital</a> partner <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/david-hornik">David Hornik</a>, founders should think just as much about the "who" as they do about the "how much" before inking a VC deal: Finding compatible investors personality-wise is just as important to the success of a startup as the dollar figures on the check, he says.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-22-at-3-56-35-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="david hornik" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><script type="text/javascript" src="http://pshared.5min.com/Scripts/PlayerSeed.js?sid=577&#038;width=640&#038;height=450&#038;colorPallet=%230A9600&#038;hasCompanion=false&#038;relatedMode=2&#038;videoControlDisplayColor=%23000000&#038;playList=517701055&#038;shuffle=0&#038;videoGroupID=133503&#038;autoStart=false&#038;playerActions=16407"></script><br />
Startup founders just getting their projects off the ground can be so focused on finding money, period, that they don&#8217;t think about being choosy about who it comes from. But according to <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/august-capital">August Capital</a> partner <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/david-hornik">David Hornik</a>, founders should think just as much about the &#8220;who&#8221; as they do about the &#8220;how much&#8221; before inking a VC deal: Finding compatible investors personality-wise is just as important to the success of a startup as the dollar figures on the check, he says.</p>
<p>We had the pleasure of spending some time talking to Hornik earlier this month at the <a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/sxsw-2013/">South By Southwest</a> festival in Austin, Texas about what it means to find the proverbial &#8220;smart money&#8221; and how entrepreneurs can go about doing it. Watch the video embedded above to hear about that, why he disagrees with <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/vinod-khosla">Vinod Khosla</a> on whether <a target="_blank" href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/tomiogeron/2013/03/10/vinod-khosla-to-entrepreneurs-venture-capitalists-are-not-your-friends/">entrepreneurs and investors should be friends</a>, the founder personalities he finds himself gravitating towards, whether the pool of startup founders he&#8217;s seen has become more diverse in Hornik&#8217;s 13 year career as a VC, and more.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/776904/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JyPpLAimm0A:WOwBBAokCpY:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JyPpLAimm0A:WOwBBAokCpY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JyPpLAimm0A:WOwBBAokCpY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JyPpLAimm0A:WOwBBAokCpY:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=JyPpLAimm0A:WOwBBAokCpY:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JyPpLAimm0A:WOwBBAokCpY:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=JyPpLAimm0A:WOwBBAokCpY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JyPpLAimm0A:WOwBBAokCpY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/JyPpLAimm0A" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/august-capitals-david-hornik-smart-money-video/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-22-at-3-56-35-pm.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-22-at-3-56-35-pm.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">david hornik</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4978d78871dc3ed1a4264d051e6c9193?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">colleentechcrunch</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/august-capitals-david-hornik-smart-money-video/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Bloomberg: ‘We're Going To Have More Visibility And Less Privacy,' Drones And Surveillance Coming</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/uV8cZfaFdTU/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/bloomberg-were-going-to-have-more-visibility-and-less-privacy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 20:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Gregory Ferenstein</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=784087</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mq-9_reaper_-_090609-f-0000m-77711.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="mq-9_reaper_-_090609-f-0000m-7771" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />&#8220;We&#8217;re going to have more visibility and less privacy. I don&#8217;t see how you stop that,&#8221; admitted New York City Mayor Michael Bloomberg in a surprisingly candid interview about the future of the surveillance state in the Big Apple. While admitting that increased surveillance was &#8220;scary&#8221; and that governments will have to be thoughtful with their laws, he seemed to side with prioritizing radical transparency, especially through the use of automated drones, &#8220;but what’s the difference whether the drone is up in the air or on the building? I mean intellectually I have trouble making a distinction.&#8221; This puts Bloomberg squarely at odds with the growing number of states and congress members either enacting or proposing moratoriums on the use of drones. Indeed, he went on to imply that the fears against drones were somewhat unjustified, especially since security cameras already exist: &#8220;The argument against using automation, it&#8217;s this craziness&#8211; oh, it&#8217;s Big Brother. Get used to it. When there&#8217;s a murder, a shooting, a robbery of something the first thing the police do is go to every single building in the neighborhood and say let&#8217;s see your security camera.&#8221; The NY Daily news notes that the New York Civil Liberties union has identified roughly 2,4000 cameras already affixed on Manhattan buildings&#8211;a presence that is likely to increase if Bloomberg&#8217;s most recent interview is to be believed. Lest Bloomberg be labeled as a surveillience hawk, the interview took on a tone of inevitability, rather than advocacy: &#8220;Everybody wants their privacy, but I don&#8217;t know how you&#8217;re going to maintain it.&#8221; Listen to part of the interview with WOR-AM host John Gambling, below. We&#8217;ll have more analysis soon.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mq-9_reaper_-_090609-f-0000m-77711.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="mq-9_reaper_-_090609-f-0000m-7771" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>&#8220;We&#8217;re going to have more visibility and less privacy. I don&#8217;t see how you stop that,&#8221; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/bloomberg-new-york-eventually-surveillance-city-article-1.1296103">admitted</a> New York City Mayor Michael Bloomberg in a surprisingly candid interview about the future of the surveillance state in the Big Apple.</p>
<p>While admitting that increased surveillance was &#8220;scary&#8221; and that governments will have to be thoughtful with their laws, he seemed to side with prioritizing radical transparency, especially through the use of automated drones, &#8220;but what’s the difference whether the drone is up in the air or on the building? I mean intellectually I have trouble making a distinction.&#8221;</p>
<p>This puts Bloomberg <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/15/congresswoman-proposes-ban-on-armed-drones-in-u-s-regulating-surveillance/">squarely at odds</a> with the growing number of states and congress members either enacting or proposing moratoriums on the use of drones.</p>
<p>Indeed, he went on to imply that the fears against drones were somewhat unjustified, especially since security cameras already exist:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The argument against using automation, it&#8217;s this craziness&#8211; oh, it&#8217;s Big Brother. Get used to it. When there&#8217;s a murder, a shooting, a robbery of something the first thing the police do is go to every single building in the neighborhood and say let&#8217;s see your security camera.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The NY Daily news notes that the New York Civil Liberties union has identified roughly 2,4000 cameras already affixed on Manhattan buildings&#8211;a presence that is likely to increase if Bloomberg&#8217;s most recent interview is to be believed.</p>
<p>Lest Bloomberg be labeled as a surveillience hawk, the interview <a target="_blank" href="http://www.realclearpolitics.com/video/2013/03/23/bloomberg_were_going_to_have_more_visibility_and_less_privacy.html">took on a tone of inevitability</a>, rather than advocacy: &#8220;Everybody wants their privacy, but I don&#8217;t know how you&#8217;re going to maintain it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Listen to part of the interview with WOR-AM host John Gambling, below. We&#8217;ll have more analysis soon.</p>
<iframe src="http://www.wor710.com/player/embed.html?autoStart=false&amp;useFullScreen=true&amp;mid=23013447&amp;osu=null&amp;startButtonColor=0xffffff" height="150" width="590" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/784087/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uV8cZfaFdTU:L3vVOuxbP-Y:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uV8cZfaFdTU:L3vVOuxbP-Y:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uV8cZfaFdTU:L3vVOuxbP-Y:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uV8cZfaFdTU:L3vVOuxbP-Y:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=uV8cZfaFdTU:L3vVOuxbP-Y:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uV8cZfaFdTU:L3vVOuxbP-Y:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=uV8cZfaFdTU:L3vVOuxbP-Y:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uV8cZfaFdTU:L3vVOuxbP-Y:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/uV8cZfaFdTU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/bloomberg-were-going-to-have-more-visibility-and-less-privacy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mq-9_reaper_-_090609-f-0000m-77711.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mq-9_reaper_-_090609-f-0000m-77711.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mq-9_reaper_-_090609-f-0000m-7771</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/36fb0b62cd32125bebf1806040529d3f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ferenstein</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/bloomberg-were-going-to-have-more-visibility-and-less-privacy/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>(Web) Castles Made Of Sand</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/9WXeZoYewwY/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/web-castles-made-of-sand/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sarah Perez</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=782763</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shutterstock_5052592.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="shutterstock_5052592" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />If there is one sliver lining in the Google Reader <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/13/rip-google-reader/">shutdown</a> that has <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/13/googlereaderpocalypse-for-real-this-time/">enraged</a> the blogosphere (OK fine, the <em><a target="_blank" href="http://storify.com/sarahintampa/google-reader-outrage">tech</a> </em>blogosphere), it's the fact that Google offers a way for Reader users to export their RSS subscriptions using its <a target="_blank" href="https://www.google.com/takeout/">Google Takeout</a> service. Actually, Google Takeout lets users of most major Google services remove their data from the Google ecosystem at any time. This is how it should be done.
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shutterstock_5052592.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="shutterstock_5052592" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>If there is one sliver lining in the Google Reader <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/13/rip-google-reader/">shutdown</a> that has <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/13/googlereaderpocalypse-for-real-this-time/">enraged</a> the blogosphere (OK fine, the <em><a target="_blank" href="http://storify.com/sarahintampa/google-reader-outrage">tech</a> </em>blogosphere), it&#8217;s the fact that Google offers a way for Reader users to export their RSS subscriptions using its <a target="_blank" href="https://www.google.com/takeout/">Google Takeout</a> service. Actually, Google Takeout lets users of most major Google services remove their data from the Google ecosystem at any time. This is how it should be done.</p>
<p>As I sat through the demo for yet another mobile/social/data-hungry app this week &#8211; one that probably won&#8217;t make it a year before quietly slinking off into the ether of the <a href="http://techcrunch.com/tag/deadpool/">deadpool</a> &#8211; it struck me how radically the web has changed the disposability of our tools; the tools that allow us to create, interact with and share our data.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve become a bit too naive, blind and trusting in terms of where we&#8217;ve been putting our data lately. Though for all its faults, at least Google has committed to making our RSS subscriptions and other data portable. And Twitter now allows for archive exports.</p>
<p>But everyone else? Who knows?</p>
<p>Our data, our <em>personal</em> data, is what all of today&#8217;s consumer-facing services are building themselves on top of. They&#8217;re our thoughts du jour, our photographs and videos, our daily habits, the places we go or plan to go, our real-world interpersonal connections, our hobbies and interests, our news-reading preferences, each step we take, each emoji-filled message we send, each game we play, our scores, our kids our pets, and so on.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s good and fine and right that the tools we use to interact with all the above change regularly. That we&#8217;re allowed to go through phases and trends with one eye on the horizon for what&#8217;s next.</p>
<h4 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:640px;float:center;color:#0a9400;">Maybe we&#8217;re too caught up in ever-changing trends to have a moment to stop and think about the digital wake we create or what responsibility it is of anyone to manage it.</h4>
<p>For instance, maybe we won&#8217;t <em>always</em> be into photo filters, and will rather look back at pictures from the 2010&#8242;s the way a Gen Xer looks back on stirrup pants and jelly bracelets and popped collars on jean jackets. Or how a Gen Yer looks back on overalls and Blossom hats and t-shirts, knotted to the side.</p>
<p><em>Oh, a photo-filtered picture</em>, we&#8217;ll laugh at our younger selves, shaking our heads. <em>I know when that one&#8217;s from. </em></p>
<p>Maybe we&#8217;ll also laugh about that phase we went through where we hung out in private hidey-holes on mobile like Path, WhatsApp, Viber, Tango and SnapChat, eschewing the drama of lives lived in public on the social backbone that is Facebook.</p>
<p>Or maybe not.</p>
<p>Maybe we&#8217;re too caught up in ever-changing trends to have a moment to stop and think about the digital wake we create or what responsibility it is of anyone to manage it. Maybe all we care about is the <em>new new thing</em>, even as servers shut down, deleting our terabytes of virtual creations. Who needs them anyway? <a target="_blank" href="http://blogs.loc.gov/loc/2013/01/update-on-the-twitter-archive-at-the-library-of-congress/">The Library of Congress has our tweets. What else matters</a>?</p>
<p>I kid, I kid.</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s the thing: It&#8217;s a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.marco.org/2013/03/21/thursday-sandwich">given</a> that almost all apps will come to the end of their independent lives at some point, and often they will come to the end of their <em>actual</em> lives &#8211; whether through &#8220;declining usage,&#8221; <a target="_blank" href="http://googlereader.blogspot.com/2013/03/powering-down-google-reader.html">as cited by Google regarding the Reader shutdown</a>, or because they failed to live up to the hype (see: 95 percent of startups), <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/16/hype/">or because they <em>did</em> live up to the hype</a>, and that hype happened to have a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/15/mailbox-cost-dropbox-around-100-million/">price tag</a> attached <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/09/facebook-to-acquire-instagram-for-1-billion/">that can&#8217;t be resisted</a>.</p>
<p>And there are<strong> just so many startups now.</strong> So many seed-funded. <a target="_blank" href="http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/02/15/digital-diary-are-we-suffering-from-mobile-app-burnout/">So many apps</a>. So many platforms &#8211; web, mobile, tablet, TV, car, body&#8230;<a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/06/the-truth-about-google-glass/">brain</a>?</p>
<h4 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:640px;float:center;color:#0a9400;">Should we be okay with the fact that with a thousand tiny little deaths, our data trails die, too?</h4>
<p>Users who fawned over an app&#8217;s creation, contributing their time and energy into making <em>New-Fangled SOLOMO Photo Sharing InstaBot Checkin Whatnot</em> the &#8220;next big thing,&#8221; don&#8217;t get a portion of the final paycheck when the exit is good. And when things go badly, they sometimes don&#8217;t even get to say goodbye. The app just disappears.</p>
<p>Should we be okay with the fact that with a thousand tiny little deaths, our data trails die, too? Because that&#8217;s what&#8217;s happening. Even Google&#8217;s Takeout solution is not perfect. We might have our subscriptions, but what of our tags, our stars, our custom RSS-based search engines that can pull up blog posts from sites that have long since disappeared from the face of the public Internet?</p>
<p><em>Gone, gone, gone</em> for as much as Google cares.</p>
<p>Startups like <a target="_blank" href="http://www.feedly.com">Feedly</a> and others at least are playing the role of digital EMT &#8211; zapping our dying data back to life. (Pro tip: re-create your exact, case-sensitive Reader tags in Feedly&#8217;s preferences to save your Reader tag history. You&#8217;re welcome.) Similarly, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.posthaven.com/">Posthaven</a> recently launched as <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/22/posthaven-launches-in-public-beta-has-saved-850k-posts-since-posterous-announced-its-shutdown-date-of-april-30th/">a paid service to store Posterous data forever</a>, following its Twitter acquisition.</p>
<p>These kinds of rescue attempts are still rare, though. And for smaller services getting shut down, no one bothers.</p>
<p>Our (web) castles are made of sand, and the tides are regular. <a target="_blank" href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-57415764-93/tim-berners-lee-tell-facebook-google-you-want-your-data-back/">Can we start taking data portability more seriously please</a>?</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/jW5zPy73gWk?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>P.S. From this point forward, and with a nod to Google for the inspiration, I will ask your startup this: <em>What happens to my data when you die?</em></p>
<p>Have an answer ready.</p>
<p><small><em>Image credit: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.shutterstock.com">Shutterstock</a></em></small></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/782763/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9WXeZoYewwY:H3SOjq1y5j8:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9WXeZoYewwY:H3SOjq1y5j8:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9WXeZoYewwY:H3SOjq1y5j8:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9WXeZoYewwY:H3SOjq1y5j8:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=9WXeZoYewwY:H3SOjq1y5j8:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9WXeZoYewwY:H3SOjq1y5j8:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=9WXeZoYewwY:H3SOjq1y5j8:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9WXeZoYewwY:H3SOjq1y5j8:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/9WXeZoYewwY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/web-castles-made-of-sand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shutterstock_5052592.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shutterstock_5052592.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shutterstock_5052592</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5225bb627e112543aa03bf3b2958be3f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sarahintampa</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/web-castles-made-of-sand/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>My Phone And I Are Never Getting Out Of Bed</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/sGju_SrAEcw/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/sent-from-my-phone-in-bed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 17:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Josh Constine</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WTF]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=782648</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/josh-phone-bed.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Josh Phone Bed" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Our beds used to be finite. A limited range of activities took place there. We'd sleep, or try to, make love, eat, and maybe read a paperback. But we could only hide from the world for so long. The nagging puppet strings of our desire to learn and experience would pull taught. Eventually we had to rise. Then we found someone to cuddle with.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/josh-phone-bed.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Josh Phone Bed" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Our beds used to be finite. A limited range of activities took place there. We&#8217;d sleep, or try to, make love, eat, and maybe read a paperback. But we could only hide from the world for so long. The nagging puppet strings of our desire to learn and experience would pull taught. Eventually we had to rise. Then we found someone to cuddle with.</p>
<p>She filled our squinting eyes with wonder. Endless possibility could suddenly curl up in the comforters with us.</p>
<p>Our friends, in our bed.</p>
<p>A library, in our bed.</p>
<p>An office, even, one we could attend naked or hungover or asocial, confined in the cosy confines of where we rest our heads.</p>
<p>The alarm clock&#8217;s red face has turned green with envy. Her function just another replaced by our new mistress. But why even set it when there&#8217;s no place left to go. If I can be anywhere and learn everything whilst luxuriating in linen, reasons to emerge get sparse.</p>
<p>Secretly our beds always long for more of our attention. Those cold mornings when you were sure you could feel the cling of its embrace, tempting you to stay. Now they have our time, even if our affection must be shared.</p>
<p>Meanwhile we slowly wither / legs we&#8217;d stand upon grow thinner / When does seeking turn to sloth? / As we fear to turn them off. The only thing that could convince us to escape our quilted prison? / Percentage points tick down and light goes dark within our prisms.</p>
<p>But if our outlets are located / within reach of where we&#8217;re laying / electrons will continue filling / in the data we keep swilling / So there&#8217;s still a steady stream of infotainment overfed&#8230;</p>
<p>My phone and I are never, ever getting out of bed.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/782648/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sGju_SrAEcw:XrGF0ubLIYo:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sGju_SrAEcw:XrGF0ubLIYo:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sGju_SrAEcw:XrGF0ubLIYo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sGju_SrAEcw:XrGF0ubLIYo:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=sGju_SrAEcw:XrGF0ubLIYo:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sGju_SrAEcw:XrGF0ubLIYo:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=sGju_SrAEcw:XrGF0ubLIYo:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sGju_SrAEcw:XrGF0ubLIYo:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/sGju_SrAEcw" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/sent-from-my-phone-in-bed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/josh-phone-bed.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/josh-phone-bed.jpeg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Josh Phone Bed</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fd3b857e7f0024396cdbd36c4c102a5d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">joshsc</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/sent-from-my-phone-in-bed/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>The Windows Store Crosses 50,000 Available Apps For Windows 8 And Windows RT</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/mzDTs9DmFMs/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/the-windows-store-crosses-50000-available-apps-for-windows-8-and-windows-rt/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Matt Burns</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows rt]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=784043</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/3482-windows-store_thumb.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="3482.Windows Store_thumb" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />It's been said that there aren't many apps available for Windows 8. I've said that <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/14/a-surface-mini-could-wake-up-windows-phone-8/">on occasion</a>. But that's not entirely true. <a target="_blank" href="http://metrostorescanner.com/#/">According to MetroStoreScanner.com</a>, there are now more than 50,000 apps available for Windows 8 and Windows RT, effectively making me a liar.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/3482-windows-store_thumb.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="3482.Windows Store_thumb" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>It&#8217;s been said that there aren&#8217;t many apps available for Windows 8. I&#8217;ve said that <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/14/a-surface-mini-could-wake-up-windows-phone-8/">on occasion</a>. But that&#8217;s not entirely true. <a target="_blank" href="http://metrostorescanner.com/#/">According to MetroStoreScanner.com</a>, there are now more than 50,000 apps available for Windows 8 and Windows RT, effectively making me a liar.</p>
<p>The site aggregates applications available to the Windows Store. If it&#8217;s available on the Windows Store, you can find it listed with pertinent details here. The site also provides basic data for application uploads.</p>
<p>According to the site, there are now 50,304 applications available for Windows 8 but uploads have slowed since Windows 8&#8242;s November launch. In fact, until just this month, the average number of new applications hitting the Store, at least per this source, has declined each month.</p>
<p>Ignoring the inherent differences of targeting different markets, Windows 8&#8242;s cloud application distribution service is growing much more rapidly than Apple&#8217;s counterpart. Apple&#8217;s own Mac App Store launched in 2010 and currently lists only 14,000 apps, according to AppShopper.com. Of course, since Windows 8&#8242;s store also serves tablets, it&#8217;s a little unfair to compare the two (there are 376,144 iPad apps).</p>
<p>But even with a healthy 50K apps, as a Windows 8 user myself, I have yet to find many compelling applications. There&#8217;s Netflix, Plex, and Xbox SmartGlass &#8212; all the rest I&#8217;ve tried are pathetic ports of iOS applications. I tend to stick to traditional applications that run in Desktop.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s clear that Microsoft has succeeded to some degree. 50,000 applications available four months after launch is impressive, but Redmond still needs to incentivize developers to produce compelling applications designed for Windows 8 first and not last.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/784043/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=mzDTs9DmFMs:8Koo83Dkp3E:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=mzDTs9DmFMs:8Koo83Dkp3E:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=mzDTs9DmFMs:8Koo83Dkp3E:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=mzDTs9DmFMs:8Koo83Dkp3E:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=mzDTs9DmFMs:8Koo83Dkp3E:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=mzDTs9DmFMs:8Koo83Dkp3E:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=mzDTs9DmFMs:8Koo83Dkp3E:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=mzDTs9DmFMs:8Koo83Dkp3E:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/mzDTs9DmFMs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/the-windows-store-crosses-50000-available-apps-for-windows-8-and-windows-rt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/3482-windows-store_thumb.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/3482-windows-store_thumb.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">3482.Windows Store_thumb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c921fdee122025b0436360dc6bb7322d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mjburnsy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/the-windows-store-crosses-50000-available-apps-for-windows-8-and-windows-rt/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang: It's Alright, Bob</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/dcdcJEv_wAs/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/gillmor-gang-its-alright-bob/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve Gillmor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gillmor Gang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@stevegillmor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@dannysullivan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@scobleizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@kevinmarks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@tinagillmor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RSS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[notifications]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=783970</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/gillmor-gang-test-pattern_excerpt.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="gillmor-gang-test-pattern_excerpt" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />The Gillmor Gang — Robert Scoble, Danny Sullivan, Kevin Marks, and Steve Gillmor — convened with Gillmor in Boston and the Gang in California. We took another cut at the Google Reader damage, with @dannysullivan hating on notifications and @scobleizer hating on Android's notifications. Did I say I told him so? Yes I did.

But the mere fact we spent so much time on the stream's destruction of Windows and RSS proved the point all along (for me since 2009). Namely, that the new platform is the stream, and the resulting multiplexed meritocracy of the combined social and messaging networks is where the developers will go. As Dylan said, "even the president must stand naked."]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/gillmor-gang-test-pattern_excerpt.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="gillmor-gang-test-pattern_excerpt" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><script type="text/javascript" src="http://pshared.5min.com/Scripts/PlayerSeed.js?sid=577&#038;width=640&#038;height=450&#038;colorPallet=%230A9600&#038;hasCompanion=false&#038;relatedMode=2&#038;videoControlDisplayColor=%23000000&#038;playList=517720261&#038;shuffle=0&#038;videoGroupID=133503&#038;autoStart=false&#038;playerActions=16407"></script>
<p>The Gillmor Gang — Robert Scoble, Danny Sullivan, Kevin Marks, and Steve Gillmor — convened with Gillmor in Boston and the Gang in California. We took another cut at the Google Reader damage, with @dannysullivan hating on notifications and @scobleizer hating on Android&#8217;s notifications. Did I say I told him so? Yes I did.</p>
<p>But the mere fact we spent so much time on the stream&#8217;s destruction of Windows and RSS proved the point all along (for me since 2009). Namely, that the new platform is the stream, and the resulting multiplexed meritocracy of the combined social and messaging networks is where the developers will go. As Dylan said, &#8220;even the President of the United States sometimes must have to stand naked.&#8221;</p>
<p>@stevegillmor, @dannysullivan, @scobleizer, @kevinmarks</p>
<p>Produced and directed by Tina Chase Gillmor @tinagillmor</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://friendfeed.com/realtime-network/2078be41/gillmor-gang-recording-live-today-1pm-pt">Live chat stream</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/783970/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dcdcJEv_wAs:TbqGyjxWqW0:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dcdcJEv_wAs:TbqGyjxWqW0:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dcdcJEv_wAs:TbqGyjxWqW0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dcdcJEv_wAs:TbqGyjxWqW0:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=dcdcJEv_wAs:TbqGyjxWqW0:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dcdcJEv_wAs:TbqGyjxWqW0:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=dcdcJEv_wAs:TbqGyjxWqW0:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dcdcJEv_wAs:TbqGyjxWqW0:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/dcdcJEv_wAs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/gillmor-gang-its-alright-bob/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/gillmor-gang-test-pattern_excerpt.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/gillmor-gang-test-pattern_excerpt.jpeg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gillmor-gang-test-pattern_excerpt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e819990a43a5972b40593cdc6896eef9?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">steve</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/gillmor-gang-its-alright-bob/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Senate Approves Proposed Internet Sales Tax</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/LogmftmORCU/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/u-s-senate-approves-proposed-internet-sales-tax/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 16:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Gregory Ferenstein</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=784045</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/us-senate-logo.gif?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="us-senate-logo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />An Internet Sales Tax is inching its way closer to being the law of the land: The U.S. Senate supported <a target="_blank" href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/23/4138388/us-senate-marketplace-fairness-act-of-2013-symbolic-vote-results-internet-sales-tax">a non-binding vote of approval</a>, 75-to-24, for a law that would allow cities in some circumstances to collect taxes from Internet retailers. If enacted as is, it would allow states to levy taxes on some online retail purchases from businesses with over $1 million in gross receipts. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/us-senate-logo.gif?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="us-senate-logo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>An Internet sales tax is inching its way closer to being the law of the land: The U.S. Senate supported <a target="_blank" href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/23/4138388/us-senate-marketplace-fairness-act-of-2013-symbolic-vote-results-internet-sales-tax">a non-binding vote of approval</a>, 75-to-24, for a law that would allow states to collect taxes from Internet retailers. If enacted as is, it would allow states to levy taxes on some online retail purchases from businesses with over $1 million in gross receipts.</p>
<p>Internet retailers <a target="_blank" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/wp/2012/07/09/the-long-shadow-of-quill-corp-v-north-dakota/">can thank</a> their mostly tax-free existence to a 1992 Supreme Court Case, Quill Corp. v. North Dakota, which declared that companies without a &#8220;substantial nexus&#8221; in a state didn&#8217;t have to pay sales tax. &#8220;Quill became a seminal case for online retailers: It meant, in essence, that they didn’t have to pay state and local sales taxes,&#8221; writes the Washington Post&#8217;s Ezra Klein.&#8221; That’s allowed them to undercut traditional brick-and-mortar stores on price. It’s also meant that state and local governments, which rely heavily on sales taxes, have lost enormous amounts of revenue as more and more commerce has moved online.&#8221;</p>
<p>There are some exceptions: Amazon currently charges California residents sales tax, and will soon charge residents of <a target="_blank" href="http://www.theverge.com/2012/12/11/3754866/amazon-collecting-sales-tax-massachusetts-fall-2013">Massachusetts</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/2/4/3951732/connecticut-residents-to-start-paying-amazon-sales-tax-november-1">Connecticut</a>, after new offices and acquisitions gave it a significant presence in those states.</p>
<p>A score of Internet lobbies, such as Netchoice, representing Facebook, Yahoo, and (TechCrunch&#8217;s parent company) Aol, <a target="_blank" href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13578_3-57575489-38/internet-tax-proposal-up-for-a-vote-in-senate-this-week/">argue</a> that the senate&#8217;s bill &#8220;does nothing to address what the Supreme Court says was an unreasonable burden on interstate commerce,&#8221; explains Steve Delbianco of Netchoice.</p>
<p>An equally self-interested set of lobbies, such as the National Retail Federation, representing the big box likes of OfficeMax, Macy&#8217;s, And Saks, argue that an Internet sales tax ban gives online retailers an unfair advantage and deprives states of billions in revenue.</p>
<p>The current law will give readers a flavor for the sausage factory that is the U.S. Congress. The tax was offered as a non-binding amendment to the Democratic budget by Senators Mike Enzi and Dick Durbin.</p>
<p>&#8220;The strategy of the bill&#8217;s supporters is to offer this general amendment and then claim that all the senators that vote for it support the bill,&#8221; <a target="_blank" href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13578_3-57575489-38/internet-tax-proposal-up-for-a-vote-in-senate-this-week/">explains</a> Brian Bieron, eBay&#8217;s senior director for federal government relations and global public policy, to CNET. &#8220;That is not just a stretch, it is not accurate. But the game plan is to rack up a sizable vote and then make the claim the bill itself should jump over the Finance Committee and go right to the floor.&#8221;</p>
<p>So nothing is law yet, but it&#8217;s getting closer.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/784045/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=LogmftmORCU:f0gBhI0aCbE:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=LogmftmORCU:f0gBhI0aCbE:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=LogmftmORCU:f0gBhI0aCbE:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=LogmftmORCU:f0gBhI0aCbE:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=LogmftmORCU:f0gBhI0aCbE:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=LogmftmORCU:f0gBhI0aCbE:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=LogmftmORCU:f0gBhI0aCbE:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=LogmftmORCU:f0gBhI0aCbE:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/LogmftmORCU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/u-s-senate-approves-proposed-internet-sales-tax/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/us-senate-logo.gif?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/us-senate-logo.gif?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">us-senate-logo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/36fb0b62cd32125bebf1806040529d3f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ferenstein</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/u-s-senate-approves-proposed-internet-sales-tax/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>The TechCrunch Gadgets Podcast: Smartwatches, Apple On The Defensive, And The Nook HD+</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/9pVoXS5t_jg/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/the-techcrunch-gadgets-podcast-smartwatches-apple-on-the-defensive-and-the-nook-hd/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 16:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>John Biggs</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[techcrunch gadgets podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartwatches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pebble]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=783819</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-22-at-5-39-40-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-03-22 at 5.39.40 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />We're back! After a long hiatus, we've started up the TechCrunch Gadgets Podcast, our weekly review of everything hardware. We'll be talking about hardware startups, flagship gadgets, and the wild and wooly worlds of Apple, Samsung, HTC, and all the rest.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-22-at-5-39-40-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-03-22 at 5.39.40 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>We&#8217;re back! After a long hiatus, we&#8217;ve started up the TechCrunch Gadgets Podcast, our weekly review of everything hardware. We&#8217;ll be talking about hardware startups, flagship gadgets, and the wild and wooly worlds of Apple, Samsung, HTC, and all the rest.</p>
<p>Featuring the TC Gadgets team, this weekly audio podcast will bring you the best we have to offer and comment on the news of the week.</p>
<iframe style="border: none" src="http://html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/2261489/height/360/width/640/theme/legacy/direction/no/autoplay/no/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/preload/no/no_addthis/no/" height="360" width="640" scrolling="no"></iframe>
<p>We&#8217;re looking for guests! If you&#8217;d like to be featured, me a line at john@techrunch.com. We aim to make each of these about 20 minutes long &#8211; just right for a commute &#8211; and will bring on a rotating cast of TC writers.</p>
<p>This week we talk smartwatches, Apple on the defensive, and the release of the Nook HD+. Enjoy!</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/techcrunchgadgets/gadgetspodcast1.mp3">Click here to download an MP3 of this show.</a><br />
You can subscribe to the <a target="_blank" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TCGadgetsPodcast">show via RSS</a>. We&#8217;ll a direct iTunes link next week.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/783819/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9pVoXS5t_jg:G5b0EiIMkmw:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9pVoXS5t_jg:G5b0EiIMkmw:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9pVoXS5t_jg:G5b0EiIMkmw:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9pVoXS5t_jg:G5b0EiIMkmw:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=9pVoXS5t_jg:G5b0EiIMkmw:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9pVoXS5t_jg:G5b0EiIMkmw:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=9pVoXS5t_jg:G5b0EiIMkmw:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9pVoXS5t_jg:G5b0EiIMkmw:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/9pVoXS5t_jg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/the-techcrunch-gadgets-podcast-smartwatches-apple-on-the-defensive-and-the-nook-hd/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/techcrunchgadgets/gadgetspodcast1.mp3" length="25511728" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-22-at-5-39-40-pm.png?w=146" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-22-at-5-39-40-pm.png?w=146" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-03-22 at 5.39.40 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c0a943f484a32e62ed3bc81dd0dd25da?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">john</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/the-techcrunch-gadgets-podcast-smartwatches-apple-on-the-defensive-and-the-nook-hd/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Steve Wozniak, Speaking To The Denver Apple Pi Club In 1984, On College Pranks, Building The Apple I &amp; II, And The Apple Pledge Of Allegiance</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/g4BxKL00jEo/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/steve-wozniak-speaking-to-the-denver-apple-pi-club-in-1984-on-college-pranks-apple-ii-features-and-the-apple-pledge-allegiance/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 15:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Matt Burns</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Remove From TC River]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=784014</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/vincepattonvideowoz.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="vincepattonvideowoz" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />"I pledge allegiance to the logo of corporate marketing in Cupertino. And to the computers for which it stands: One notion, under Jobs, indispensable, for hardware and software for all." Steve Wozniak, to the Denver Apple Pi Computer Club in 1984.

And that video above is just a funny anecdotes. TUAW reader Vince Patton pointed the Apple fan site to 14 insightful videos he uploaded to YouTube of Steve Wozniak talking to the Denver Apple Pi Club in 1984. As TUAW notes, they're a treasure trove of first hand accounts into the formation of Apple, the creation of the Apple I and II, and Woz's college antics. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/vincepattonvideowoz.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="vincepattonvideowoz" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/vPssItXt4R4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>&#8220;I pledge allegiance to the logo of corporate marketing in Cupertino. And to the computers for which it stands: One notion, under Jobs, indispensable, for hardware and software for all.&#8221; Steve Wozniak, to the Denver Apple Pi Computer Club in 1984.</p>
<p>And that video above is just a funny anecdotes. TUAW reader Vince Patton pointed <a target="_blank" href="http://www.tuaw.com/2013/03/22/woz-wigginton-videos-surface-in-1984-user-group-talk-treasure-t/">the Apple fan site</a> to 14 insightful videos he uploaded to YouTube of Steve Wozniak talking to the Denver Apple Pi Club in 1984. As TUAW notes, they&#8217;re a treasure trove of first hand accounts into the formation of Apple, the creation of the Apple I and II, and Woz&#8217;s college antics. </p>
<p>Apparently Patton recently discovered his father&#8217;s VHS taping of Woz&#8217;s talk to Denver Apple Pi computer club at the Colorado School of Mines on October 4, 1984. He cleaned up the recording and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/user/PDXtvVince">uploaded 14 clips to YouTube</a>. Two of the best are embedded here but they&#8217;re all worth watching.</p>
<h4>On the Apple II&#8217;s creation</h4>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/5EAMwVkMvbg?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p>&#8220;The computer [the Apple II] was not being design to be a product and it was not being design to be sold, nearly as much as it was being designed to impress and do some very unusual things that had not been seen before.&#8221; Steve Wozniak</p>
<p>Ironically, when speaking about the Apple II&#8217;s integrated hardware, Wozniak brings up a point that Apple still abides by today, &#8220;Whenever you can recognized standards that will prevail, build them in.&#8221; By doing so in the Apple II, this allowed Apple to leave slots open for future hardware, or as Woz says, &#8220;for expansion beyond what we can think of.&#8221; </p>
<p>Looking at Apple&#8217;s past hardware, this is a notion the company still believes in. From the early iMac&#8217;s use of USB over serial to the 10-year life of the Dock Connector, Apple cautiously approaches emerging standards, but tends to invest early and sticks with standards more than most other consumer electronic companies. Apparently it has been that way from the start.</p>
<h4>Steve Jobs on the formation of Apple</h4>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/sTcrSPOsH48?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p>&#8220;Yeah, we&#8217;d lose our money, but at least we would have a company.&#8221; said Steve Jobs according to Woz.</p>
<p>As Wozniak states, this was reason enough to sell bare PC boards and run the possibility of losing money &#8212; just so they would be involved in a company. And so the two, along with Ron Wayne who designed the manual, began selling the Apple I personal computer kit in 1976.</p>
<p>Woz explains there was originally three employees with him and Jobs owning 45% of the company. The remaining 10% went to Ron Wayne, who designed the Apple I manuals. He got cold feet several weeks into the venture and sold his 10% stake in Apple for $800. He received an additional $1,500 later that year in exchange for forfeiting any claims against the company. Given Apple&#8217;s current value, Wayne&#8217;s 10 percent share would have been worth more than $43 billion today.</p>
<p>Brian Heater profiled Wayne for Engadget in 2011. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.engadget.com/2011/12/19/two-days-in-the-desert-with-apples-lost-founder-ron-wayne/">It&#8217;s a fantastic read</a>. </p>
<hr />
<p>All 14 videos are on Vince Patton&#8217;s <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/user/PDXtvVince">YouTube account</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/784014/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=g4BxKL00jEo:5V6AooadZuo:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=g4BxKL00jEo:5V6AooadZuo:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=g4BxKL00jEo:5V6AooadZuo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=g4BxKL00jEo:5V6AooadZuo:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=g4BxKL00jEo:5V6AooadZuo:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=g4BxKL00jEo:5V6AooadZuo:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=g4BxKL00jEo:5V6AooadZuo:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=g4BxKL00jEo:5V6AooadZuo:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/g4BxKL00jEo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/steve-wozniak-speaking-to-the-denver-apple-pi-club-in-1984-on-college-pranks-apple-ii-features-and-the-apple-pledge-allegiance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/vincepattonvideowoz.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/vincepattonvideowoz.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vincepattonvideowoz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c921fdee122025b0436360dc6bb7322d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mjburnsy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/steve-wozniak-speaking-to-the-denver-apple-pi-club-in-1984-on-college-pranks-apple-ii-features-and-the-apple-pledge-allegiance/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>“The Business Of Literature Is Blowing Shit Up”</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/5Pj-cw7lMC8/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/the-business-of-literature-is-blowing-shit-up/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jon Evans</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wattpad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard nash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[invisible armies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=783095</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/booksplosion.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="booksplosion" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />If you love books--heck, if you even <i>like</i> 'em--run, don't walk, and read this <a target="_blank" href="http://www.vqronline.org/articles/2013/spring/nash-business-literature/">magnificent, magisterial essay</a> by Richard Nash on their past, present and future. It's long. Don't be frightened. But even if the Internet has shredded your attention span, at least scroll down to its epic final paragraph. Go on. I'll wait.

It's been a rotten decade for book publishers, newspapers, and anyone else clinging to that 15th century technology called the <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Printing_press">printing press</a>. Marc Andreessen has advised the mighty <i>New York Times</i> to "<a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/03/06/andreessen-media-burn-boats/">burn the boats</a>" and shut down their presses. His partner Ben Horowitz claimed last year that "<a target="_blank" href="http://www.adweek.com/news/press/print-dead-and-other-tough-topics-mpa-conference-144509">babies born today will probably never read anything in print</a>."]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/booksplosion.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="booksplosion" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>If you love books&#8211;heck, if you even <i>like</i> &#8216;em&#8211;run, don&#8217;t walk, and read this <a target="_blank" href="http://www.vqronline.org/articles/2013/spring/nash-business-literature/">magnificent, magisterial essay</a> by Richard Nash on their past, present and future. It&#8217;s long. Don&#8217;t be frightened. But even if the Internet has shredded your attention span, at least scroll down to its epic final paragraph. Go on. I&#8217;ll wait.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s been a rotten decade for book publishers, newspapers, and anyone else clinging to that 15th century technology called the <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Printing_press">printing press</a>. Marc Andreessen has advised the mighty <i>New York Times</i> to &#8220;<a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/03/06/andreessen-media-burn-boats/">burn the boats</a>&#8221; and shut down their presses. His partner Ben Horowitz claimed last year that &#8220;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.adweek.com/news/press/print-dead-and-other-tough-topics-mpa-conference-144509">babies born today will probably never read anything in print</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/02/23/books-without-borders-a-victory-for-amazon-but-also-for-independent-book-stores/">Borders is dead</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.geekwire.com/2012/tablet-killing-ebook-reader-shipments-fall-36-year/">the tablet is killing the e-reader</a>, and Barnes &amp; Noble&#8217;s Nook has gone from <a target="_blank" href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702303916904577375502392129654.html">investor darling</a> to <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/25/business/media/barnes-noble-weighs-its-nook-losses.html">dead-weight albatross</a>. The &#8220;Big Six&#8221; publishers <a target="_blank" href="http://www.wired.com/underwire/2013/03/publishing-industry-next-chapter/all/">may seem to be surviving nicely</a>, but check out <a target="_blank" href="http://evanhughes.tumblr.com/post/45927484006/the-math-on-self-publishing-a-response-to-laura-miller">this graph</a>:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"></p>
<p>If publishers are at war with Amazon, the undisputed king of e-commerce&#8211;and they <a target="_blank" href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2012/06/25/120625fa_fact_auletta">certainly think they are</a>&#8211;then that remarkable trend does not bode well for them.</p>
<p>Authors aren&#8217;t doing so well either. &#8220;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/industry-news/bookselling/article/56284-how-many-copies-does-it-take-to-be-an-amazon-bestseller.html">For large parts of the year it only takes a few hundred copies a day, not a few thousand, to get to the top of Amazon’s daily charts</a>.&#8221; &#8220;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.salon.com/2013/03/15/hey_amazon_wheres_my_money/">My novel shot to the top of the site&#8217;s bestseller list last summer. You won&#8217;t believe how little I got paid</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Nowadays, when authors dream of financial success, they dream more of Hollywood or TV adaptations than slots on the <i>New York Times</i> bestseller list. Movies and television have held up remarkably well under the onslaught of the Internet, thanks largely to ever-more-lucrative foreign markets, while book publishing has quietly become far more hit-and-miss than Hollywood. Last year <i>each</i> book in E.L. James&#8217; <i>Fifty Shades Of Grey</i> trilogy sold <a target="_blank" href="http://publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/industry-news/bookselling/article/56408-the-e-book-explosion-facts-figures-2012.html">more than 15 million e-book copies</a>. Only one other book, Gillian Flynn&#8217;s <i>Gone Girl</i>, broke a million. Which is more than it sold in print, incidentally.</p>
<p>For the last five years, in the face of this spreading transformation, the publishing industry has been caught in a tawdry and depressing spiral of denial and decay, constantly attempting to reject new media, new technologies, and new business models until they can fight back no more. (Disagree? Name some publisher-driven innovations.) Evan Hughes&#8217; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.wired.com/underwire/2013/03/publishing-industry-next-chapter/all/">recent Wired piece</a> is the latest in a long line of eulogies. If it seems incredibly musty and tired to you, you&#8217;re not alone. I&#8217;m faintly amazed that it was published in <i>Wired</i> in 2013; <a target="_blank" href="http://walrusmagazine.com/article.php?ref=2007.09-e-book-publishing&amp;page=">my own contribution to the genre</a> dates back to 2007.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s why Nash&#8217;s essay is such a breath of revolutionary air. The publishing industry will never be the same, but why can&#8217;t it be <em>better</em>? Why can&#8217;t a whole new model of publishing be created, rather than this false dichotomy between &#8220;published&#8221; and &#8220;self-published&#8221;? So the king is dying; well, long live the king!</p>
<p>The Internet opens up new ways of connecting with readers that authors have never dreamed of before&#8230; and that publishers seem to barely even consider. Take <a href="http://techcrunch.com/tag/wattpad/">Wattpad</a>. A few months ago they put a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.wattpad.com/user/JonEvans">couple of my novels</a> up on their site for free. (They did ask permission, even though they didn&#8217;t need to; after the rights to the books in question had reverted from their initial publishers, I released them under a Creative Commons license.)</p>
<p>And I&#8217;m delighted that they did. A cool million chapter-views of my back-catalog hacker thriller <i><a target="_blank" href="http://www.rezendi.com/invisibleArmies.htm">Invisible Armies</a></i> later, I know far more about how people read the book than I ever did before:</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet'><p>One of the fun things about @<a href="https://twitter.com/Wattpad">Wattpad</a> is that you can work out how many readers actually _finish_ your book. In the case of Invisible Armies,&mdash; <br />Jon Evans (@rezendi) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/rezendi/status/308319263377203200' data-datetime='2013-03-03T20:53:35+00:00'>March 03, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet'><p>&#8230;about 50% bounce within the first 2 chapters, but &gt;80% of those who stay to chapter 3 finish the book. Never had numbers before&#8230;&mdash; <br />Jon Evans (@rezendi) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/rezendi/status/308319612334915584' data-datetime='2013-03-03T20:54:58+00:00'>March 03, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet'><p>&#8230;obviously, the next step is for authorial algorithms to data-mine the hell out of all this and build the perfectly addictive book.  &mdash; <br />Jon Evans (@rezendi) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/rezendi/status/308319873140920320' data-datetime='2013-03-03T20:56:00+00:00'>March 03, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Hughes seems to be arguing that authors will choose to self-publish. Charles Stross <a target="_blank" href="http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2013/03/why-i-dont-self-publish.html">disagrees</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Yes, I <em>could</em> do it. But it&#8217;d suck up a huge amount of time I would prefer to spend doing what I enjoy (writing) and force me to do stuff I do not enjoy (reading contracts, accounting, managing other people). The only sane way to do it would be to hire someone else to do all the boring crap on my behalf. And do you know what we call people who do that? We call them <em>publishers</em>.</p></blockquote>
<p>Indeed. But wait: why do all of those people have to work under the same corporate aegis? Why can&#8217;t Stross hire a separate editor, copy editor, publisher and marketer? Why must their end-product be viewed as a thing that is complete and engraved in stone, rather than a living beast amenable to A/B testing and weeks-to-months of optimization, like a Broadway play in previews? If a book isn&#8217;t a sheaf of papers any more&#8211;and given that the bestselling e-books are now outselling the sheaves, it clearly isn&#8217;t&#8211;then what is it?</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll take a swing at that one: a book is a story told in the size and shape that fits most deeply and tightly into the human brain. Everyone keeps waiting for Amazon Singles and short stories to take off, and waiting, and waiting. But I believe novels will remain the dominant form of written storytelling so long as our brains remain substantially unchanged.</p>
<p>Maybe the existing system of publishers and booksellers will collapse. Maybe our collective ability to filter the good from the bad will be challenged. Maybe, as more and more books are written, and more and more made available for free, full-time authors will become an endangered species.</p>
<p>Doesn&#8217;t really matter. Books will remain, and <em>because</em> they&#8217;re books, because they&#8217;re that razor-barbed size and shape, they&#8217;ll remain a genuinely powerful and subversive medium. Richard Nash is right: whatever tidal wave of change comes next, whatever economic system or sociopolitical order, you can bet that books, in one form or another, will be at its disruptive heart.</p>
<p><i>Image credit:</i> Booksplosion, by azrasta, on <a target="_blank" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/azrasta/4622185776/">Flickr</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/783095/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5Pj-cw7lMC8:qbfZilWjfUA:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5Pj-cw7lMC8:qbfZilWjfUA:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5Pj-cw7lMC8:qbfZilWjfUA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5Pj-cw7lMC8:qbfZilWjfUA:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=5Pj-cw7lMC8:qbfZilWjfUA:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5Pj-cw7lMC8:qbfZilWjfUA:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=5Pj-cw7lMC8:qbfZilWjfUA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5Pj-cw7lMC8:qbfZilWjfUA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/5Pj-cw7lMC8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/the-business-of-literature-is-blowing-shit-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/booksplosion.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/booksplosion.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">booksplosion</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/df4f08903b7a5c3d7078165edcf5bcf7?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rezendi</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://media.tumblr.com/62ca8efd0e0366a816c75b5868d85079/tumblr_inline_mk0v16YfzT1qz4rgp.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Transformation amid booksellers</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/the-business-of-literature-is-blowing-shit-up/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Is The Vertical Approach To Enterprise Software Enough To Help You Win The Market?</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/3hCU8nR769c/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/narrow-focus-is-helping-verticals-win-enterprise-software-but-it-challenges-remain/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 09:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Boris Wertz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vertical]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=780773</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/verticals.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="up up up" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><b>Editor's note:</b><em> Boris Wertz is the founder of version one ventures.</em>

We already know that the most profitable companies from the first wave of cloud software were players in the horizontal space. Companies like Salesforce and Workday replaced on-premise solutions and won huge markets. This is old news. What's new is the fact that there’s a second wave of disruption in enterprise cloud computing coming, and it's going to be in the form of vertical SaaS solutions.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/verticals.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="up up up" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong><em> Boris Wertz</em><i> is the founder of </i><a target="_blank" href="http://versiononeventures.com/"><i>version one ventures</i></a><i>, and has invested in over 40 </i><i>early-stage consumer and enterprise companies, including vertical SaaS investments in Clio, Frontdesk, Jobber and Top Hat Monocle. Follow him on his <a target="_blank" href="http://versiononeventures.com/blog/">blog</a> and on </i><i>Twitter <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/bwertz">@bwertz</a>.</i></p>
<p>We already know that the most profitable companies from the first wave of cloud software were players in the horizontal space. Companies like Salesforce and Workday replaced on-premise solutions and won huge markets. This is old news. What&#8217;s new is the fact that there’s a second wave of disruption in enterprise cloud computing coming, and it&#8217;s going to be in the form of vertical SaaS solutions.</p>
<p>When on-premise solutions were first being replaced by cloud software, on-the-ground sales forces drove customer acquisition. As a result, there was a high customer acquisition cost, which made it unsustainable to focus on smaller, long-tail markets.</p>
<p>In the new era of enterprise software, the winners will be purpose-built, vertically sliced tools. Here are four reasons why:</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="background:url('http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/vertical7.png') no-repeat;" width="100"></td>
<td style="padding:0;margin:0;">
<h5>1. Narrow Focus = Better Products</h5>
<p>When your product team is focused on a single market, it’s easier to deliver a solid feature set for that market. You have the freedom to go deep in understanding the specific needs of a user base and customize a solution for them.</p>
<p>Likewise, when your offering isn’t trying to meet the needs of a hundred different user groups, you can streamline the user experience to work for the most common use cases. The result is a more intuitive product that can be incredibly easy to use. That’s the beauty of vertical SaaS businesses like <a target="_blank" href="https://www.styleseat.com/">StyleSeat</a> (business management software for stylists), <a target="_blank" href="http://www.carecloud.com/">CareCloud</a> (health practices), or <a target="_blank" href="http://www.goclio.com/">Clio</a> (law firms). Ultimately, ease of use drives adoption, as even less tech-savvy people can use software products with little to no resistance.</p>
<p>In addition, the cloud lets vertical vendors deliver niche features as specific needs arise. For example, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.getjobber.com">Jobber</a> &#8211; business management software for field services industries &#8211; was able to add a chemical-tracking feature so landscapers and lawn care professionals could meet regulatory requirements by recording any pesticide and chemical usage.</p>
<h5>2. Reach A Category-Leading Position Faster</h5>
<p>The vertical approach helps companies capture a larger market share more quickly than if they were trying to build out a broad, all-things-to-all-people solution. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.mindbodyonline.com/">Mindbody</a>, vertical business management software, is said to have more than 60 percent market share in its core yoga and fitness vertical.</p>
<p>In the cloud, word of mouth drives adoption. Useful products are shared and recommended among employees, colleagues, vendors, etc. For example, Clio saw a rapid increase in its user base through word of mouth, as lawyers from different firms spread the word as they worked on shared cases.</p>
<p>By focusing on a specific vertical, software vendors can more quickly penetrate a certain market and become the de facto industry standard. This can lead to a “winner takes all” (or almost all) dynamic: category leaders do very well, while Nos. 2, 3, 4 and beyond struggle to attract customers and financing.</p>
<h5>3. Better Customer Acquisition Metrics</h5>
<p>With a heavier reliance on word of mouth, the cloud enables a more scalable marketing approach – with social media, search, and email complementing a lean and mean inside sales team. By narrowing their target audience, vertically focused companies enjoy even better customer acquisition numbers. That’s because there are no broad-based or vague marketing messages. These vendors can speak directly to a particular market about their specific needs and challenges. The specificity leads to more effective marketing and better results.</p>
<h5>4. Expansion Into Long Tail</h5>
<p>The economics of vertical SaaS solutions are particularly interesting. Not only are these solutions beating out existing on-premise software products, but they can expand the overall market by driving into the long tail of customers that previously did not have access to affordable software products. The affordability and ease of implementation of vertical SaaS are very attractive to SMBs with limited budgets and IT resources.</p>
<p>While total cost of ownership and ease of implementation were the growth drivers for the first generation of vertical SaaS companies, mobile will be the most important factor for the next generation. First, it opens up completely new use cases. Second, anybody with a smartphone now has access to software. Compare those penetration rates to traditional desktop software that was limited by the number of computers in an office. For example, <a target="_blank" href="https://frontdeskhq.com/">Frontdesk</a> mobile-first business management software helps SMBs schedule classes, book appointments, manage clients, and more from a mobile device.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="padding:0;margin:0;background-color:#3399cc;" colspan="2" width="640" height="6"></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h5>Challenges Lurk For Verticals</h5>
<p>Due to their narrow focus, vertical SaaS vendors enjoy lower customer acquisition costs along with lower capital requirements. They’re able to become the undisputed category leader faster than a horizontal vendor, creating significant barriers to entry in their particular markets.</p>
<p>Yet the vertical approach is not without its own challenges. Vertical markets can be limited in size. In order to scale, companies will need to enter into parallel verticals once they own their first. This is not always an easy undertaking. Fortunately, most enterprise software markets are ripe for disruption from purpose-built, superior solutions.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/780773/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3hCU8nR769c:ql6TRSJvufc:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3hCU8nR769c:ql6TRSJvufc:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3hCU8nR769c:ql6TRSJvufc:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3hCU8nR769c:ql6TRSJvufc:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=3hCU8nR769c:ql6TRSJvufc:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3hCU8nR769c:ql6TRSJvufc:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=3hCU8nR769c:ql6TRSJvufc:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3hCU8nR769c:ql6TRSJvufc:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/3hCU8nR769c" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/narrow-focus-is-helping-verticals-win-enterprise-software-but-it-challenges-remain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/verticals.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/verticals.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">up up up</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2a014e70509390133a9b9073671a2e8d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tcbucket</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/23/narrow-focus-is-helping-verticals-win-enterprise-software-but-it-challenges-remain/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss>
