<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	
	<link>http://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>TechCrunch is a group-edited blog that profiles the companies, products and events defining and transforming the new web.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 12:48:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain="techcrunch.com" port="80" path="/?rsscloud=notify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
<image><link>http://www.techcrunch.com</link><url>http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/themes/techcrunchmu/images/techcrunch_logo.png</url><title>TechCrunch</title></image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://techcrunch.com/osd.xml" title="TechCrunch" />
	
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" /><feedburner:info uri="techcrunch" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://techcrunch.com/?pushpress=hub" /><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://add.my.yahoo.com/rss?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://us.i1.yimg.com/us.yimg.com/i/us/my/addtomyyahoo4.gif">Subscribe with My Yahoo!</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.newsgator.com/ngs/subscriber/subext.aspx?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.newsgator.com/images/ngsub1.gif">Subscribe with NewsGator</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://feeds.my.aol.com/add.jsp?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://o.aolcdn.com/favorites.my.aol.com/webmaster/ffclient/webroot/locale/en-US/images/myAOLButtonSmall.gif">Subscribe with My AOL</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.bloglines.com/sub/http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" src="http://www.bloglines.com/images/sub_modern11.gif">Subscribe with Bloglines</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.netvibes.com/subscribe.php?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.netvibes.com/img/add2netvibes.gif">Subscribe with Netvibes</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://fusion.google.com/add?feedurl=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://buttons.googlesyndication.com/fusion/add.gif">Subscribe with Google</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.pageflakes.com/subscribe.aspx?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.pageflakes.com/ImageFile.ashx?instanceId=Static_4&amp;fileName=ATP_blu_91x17.gif">Subscribe with Pageflakes</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item>
		<title>Peter Thiel's Breakout Labs Funds “Nanostraws” And A Siri-Like Natural Language Processing Startup</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/YzGZE5xs_LQ/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/breakout-labs-skyphrase-stealth-biosciences/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 12:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kim-Mai Cutler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breakout labs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=799924</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-1-24-20-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 1.24.20 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Breakout Labs, a Peter Thiel-backed effort that supports startups doing cutting-edge research that might still be too risky to get traditional venture backing, just put capital into another two companies. They&#8217;re funding a Siri-like natural language processing startup called SkyPhrase and another biotech company called Stealth Biosciences, which is creating &#8220;nanostraws&#8221; that make it easy to insert material into single cells without destroying them. Breakout Labs, which launched last year, gives up to $350,000 to early-stage companies. The motivation behind Breakout is to bridge that gap between the point when a startup is engaging in risky, more capital-intensive research and when they&#8217;ve found something that is commercially viable or that can be made into a product. Breakout is meant to be the first external investor before a startup goes on to find more traditional venture backing. Lindy Fishburne, senior vice president for investments of the Thiel Foundation, said that several of last year&#8217;s companies have gone on to raise angel financing in the $1- to $1.5 million range and two have received additional grants from prestigious institutions like the National Institutes of Health. She said Breakout funded Stealth Biosciences because its technology could help researchers and doctors avoid using viruses or viral vectors to insert material into cells and treat patients. &#8220;This is actually a scalable way to insert material directly inside of cells using nanotechnology,&#8221; Fishburne said. &#8220;They&#8217;ve developed nano-material that allows them to pierce and get what they need into cells, avoiding the use of viruses or viral vectors, a technique which has other issues.&#8221; Stealth developed nanoscale devices called &#8220;Nanostraws&#8221; or &#8220;Stealth Probes&#8221; that can measure and control biological processes at the level of single cells. The two Stanford University professors behind Stealth, Nick Melosh and Craig Garner, say this could be used in personalized medicine, oncology and neuroscience. The second company Breakout is backing is called Skyphrase. There are two schools toward approaching natural language processing; one relies on a brute force statistical approach and the other relies on logical reasoning and language rules. SkyPhrase says it has a technology that marries the strengths of these two techniques. They briefly had a Gmail search app for the iPhone last year that could look for content with rich phrases like “emails that Jane sent me during the holidays containing pictures.&#8221; But it&#8217;s no longer available in the store.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-1-24-20-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 1.24.20 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.breakoutlabs.org/home.html">Breakout Labs</a>, a Peter Thiel-backed effort that supports startups doing cutting-edge research that might still be too risky to get traditional venture backing, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.breakoutlabs.org/recipients.html">just put capital into another two companies</a>.</p>
<p>They&#8217;re funding a Siri-like natural language processing startup called SkyPhrase and another biotech company called Stealth Biosciences, which is creating &#8220;nanostraws&#8221; that make it easy to insert material into single cells without destroying them.</p>
<p>Breakout Labs, which launched last year, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.breakoutlabs.org/recipients.html">gives up to $350,000 to early-stage companies</a>. The motivation behind Breakout is to bridge that gap between the point when a startup is engaging in risky, more capital-intensive research and when they&#8217;ve found something that is commercially viable or that can be made into a product. Breakout is meant to be the first external investor before a startup goes on to find more traditional venture backing.</p>
<p>Lindy Fishburne, senior vice president for investments of the Thiel Foundation, said that several of last year&#8217;s companies have gone on to raise angel financing in the $1- to $1.5 million range and two have received additional grants from prestigious institutions like the National Institutes of Health.</p>
<p>She said Breakout funded Stealth Biosciences because its technology could help researchers and doctors avoid using viruses or viral vectors to insert material into cells and treat patients.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is actually a scalable way to insert material directly inside of cells using nanotechnology,&#8221; Fishburne said. &#8220;They&#8217;ve developed nano-material that allows them to pierce and get what they need into cells, avoiding the use of viruses or viral vectors, a technique which has other issues.&#8221;</p>
<p>Stealth developed nanoscale devices called &#8220;Nanostraws&#8221; or &#8220;Stealth Probes&#8221; that can measure and control biological processes at the level of single cells. The two Stanford University professors behind Stealth, Nick Melosh and Craig Garner, say this could be used in personalized medicine, oncology and neuroscience.</p>
<p>The second company Breakout is backing is called <a target="_blank" href="https://skyphrase.com/index-s.html">Skyphrase</a>. There are two schools toward approaching natural language processing; one relies on a brute force statistical approach and the other relies on logical reasoning and language rules. SkyPhrase says it has a technology that marries the strengths of these two techniques.</p>
<p>They <a target="_blank" href="http://allthingsd.com/20121108/artificial-intelligence-professor-makes-a-search-app-to-outsmart-siri/">briefly had a Gmail search app for the iPhone</a> last year that could look for content with rich phrases like “emails that Jane sent me during the holidays containing pictures.&#8221; But it&#8217;s no longer available in the store.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/799924/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=YzGZE5xs_LQ:3hIo2TyWMwU:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=YzGZE5xs_LQ:3hIo2TyWMwU:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=YzGZE5xs_LQ:3hIo2TyWMwU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=YzGZE5xs_LQ:3hIo2TyWMwU:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=YzGZE5xs_LQ:3hIo2TyWMwU:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=YzGZE5xs_LQ:3hIo2TyWMwU:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=YzGZE5xs_LQ:3hIo2TyWMwU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=YzGZE5xs_LQ:3hIo2TyWMwU:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/YzGZE5xs_LQ" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/breakout-labs-skyphrase-stealth-biosciences/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-1-24-20-pm.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-1-24-20-pm.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 1.24.20 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c4dad53149dd9c712936e1b27c1c1e9f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kimmaicutler</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/breakout-labs-skyphrase-stealth-biosciences/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Foxconn Becomes Largest Microsoft Patent Licensee, Pays Royalty Per Android And Chrome Device</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/KDDjyhWgP-w/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/foxconn-becomes-largest-microsoft-patent-licensee/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 10:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Victoria Ho</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patent litigation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foxconn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hon hai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800435</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/foxconn-pack.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="foxconn" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Microsoft just scored a coup on the patent royalty front, with a new deal with Taiwanese phone maker, Hon Hai, which owns Foxconn. Under the terms of the deal, Microsoft will get paid a flat fee per Android and Chrome-based device that Foxconn makes. And there are a lot of those. A whopping 40 percent of the world&#8217;s phones come from the firm&#8217;s China-based factories. Foxconn is an ODM, or &#8220;original design manufacturer&#8221;, and makes Android devices for clients like Acer and Amazon (it makes the Kindle Fire). It&#8217;s famous for making iPhones and iPads as well. The exact patents licensed were not revealed, but Microsoft has been famously litigious on the patent scene. With regard to the Android OS, legal documents filed in 2010 against Motorola and against Barnes &#38; Noble in 2011 give some clues. One of its patent claims is against a way that long and short file names are implemented, and is linked to the FAT16 file system used by older Microsoft OSes like MS-DOS and Windows. Other patents include data management, across flash drives and another in contact databases. Microsoft&#8217;s user interface patents are also involved. Microsoft said that over 50 percent of the world&#8217;s Android phones come from manufacturers that already have patent agreements in place with it. These include Samsung, LG and HTC, for example. Adding Foxconn to that list will give it a huge boost to these royalty payments, an already huge sum—in 2011, Microsoft was estimated to be making more from patent royalties from phone makers than its own smartphone business. Other behind-the-scenes manufacturers similar to Foxconn such as Quanta and Pegatron also have licensing agreements with Microsoft. Microsoft going after manufacturers has been referred to as &#8220;extortion&#8221; by Google. It made this statement in late-2011 after Samsung and Microsoft decided to cross-license their patents. Probably because Samsung was sick of all the lawsuits with Apple. Hon Hai is the world&#8217;s largest contract electronics manufacturer, and holds some 54,000 patents globally.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/foxconn-pack.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="foxconn" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Microsoft just scored a coup on the patent royalty front, with a new deal with Taiwanese phone maker, Hon Hai, which owns Foxconn.</p>
<p>Under the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/news/Press/2013/Apr13/04-16FoxconnPR.aspx">terms of the deal</a>, Microsoft will get paid a flat fee per Android and Chrome-based device that Foxconn makes. And there are a lot of those. A whopping 40 percent of the world&#8217;s phones come from the firm&#8217;s China-based factories. Foxconn is an ODM, or &#8220;original design manufacturer&#8221;, and makes Android devices for clients like Acer and Amazon (it makes the Kindle Fire).</p>
<p>It&#8217;s famous for making <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/15/apple-partner-foxconn-reportedly-ramps-up-hiring-to-prep-for-next-iphone-launch-this-summer/">iPhones and iPads</a> as well.</p>
<p>The exact patents licensed were not revealed, but Microsoft has been famously litigious on the patent scene. With regard to the Android OS, legal documents filed in 2010 against Motorola and against Barnes &amp; Noble in 2011 <a target="_blank" href="http://www.networkworld.com/news/2011/070611-microsoft-android.html">give some clues</a>.</p>
<p>One of its patent claims is against a way that long and short file names are implemented, and is linked to the FAT16 file system used by older Microsoft OSes like MS-DOS and Windows.</p>
<p>Other patents include data management, across flash drives and another in contact databases. Microsoft&#8217;s user interface patents are also involved.</p>
<p>Microsoft said that over 50 percent of the world&#8217;s Android phones come from manufacturers that already have patent agreements in place with it. These include Samsung, LG and HTC, for example. Adding Foxconn to that list will give it a huge boost to these royalty payments, an already huge sum—in 2011, Microsoft was estimated to be <a target="_blank" href="http://paidcontent.org/2011/05/27/419-android-royalties-exceed-microsofts-windows-phone-7-revenue/">making more from patent royalties</a> from phone makers than its own smartphone business.</p>
<p>Other behind-the-scenes manufacturers similar to Foxconn such as Quanta and Pegatron also have licensing agreements with Microsoft.</p>
<p>Microsoft going after manufacturers has been referred to as &#8220;<a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/09/28/microsoft-samsung-extortion-google/">extortion</a>&#8221; by Google. It made this statement in late-2011 after <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/09/28/samsung-and-microsoft-ink-deal-for-cross-licensing-patents-marketing-windows-phone/">Samsung and Microsoft</a> decided to cross-license their patents. Probably because Samsung was sick of all the lawsuits <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/08/24/apple-wins-patent-ruling-as-jury-finds-samsung-infringes/">with Apple</a>.</p>
<p>Hon Hai is the world&#8217;s largest contract electronics manufacturer, and holds some 54,000 patents globally.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800435/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=KDDjyhWgP-w:ldvNbXX7EqE:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=KDDjyhWgP-w:ldvNbXX7EqE:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=KDDjyhWgP-w:ldvNbXX7EqE:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=KDDjyhWgP-w:ldvNbXX7EqE:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=KDDjyhWgP-w:ldvNbXX7EqE:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=KDDjyhWgP-w:ldvNbXX7EqE:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=KDDjyhWgP-w:ldvNbXX7EqE:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=KDDjyhWgP-w:ldvNbXX7EqE:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/KDDjyhWgP-w" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/foxconn-becomes-largest-microsoft-patent-licensee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/foxconn-pack.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/foxconn-pack.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">foxconn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2730ac85eb6d3f6f7491d176987aab05?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">victoriatc</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/foxconn-becomes-largest-microsoft-patent-licensee/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Jolla Confirms It Will Show Its Debut Handset Next Month &amp; Kick Off “Pre-Sales Campaign” To Take Payments From Fans Ahead Of 2H Launch</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/NDg8hdXJI90/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/jolla-to-show-first-phone-in-may/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 09:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natasha Lomas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jolla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sailfish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MeeGo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800409</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-02-at-19-33-07.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Sailfish" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Jolla, the Finnish startup comprised of ex-Nokians who left to keep the MeeGo fire burning, has confirmed it will be showing off its first handset next month, and kicking off a "pre-sales" campaign to allow fans to register to buy its first phone. Although Jolla has demoed its Sailfish UI in some detail it has not shown off the hardware design so next month will be another big reveal. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-02-at-19-33-07.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Sailfish" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Jolla, the Finnish startup comprised of ex-Nokians who left to keep the MeeGo fire burning, has confirmed it will be showing off its first handset next month, and kicking off a &#8220;pre-sales&#8221; campaign to allow fans to register to buy the phone. Although Jolla has <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/21/jolla-meego-sailfish/">demoed its Sailfish UI</a> in some detail before, it has generally been tight-lipped about its plans for the device&#8217;s hardware design &#8212; so next month will mean another big reveal.</p>
<p>Jolla had <a target="_blank" href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;cad=rja&amp;ved=0CDEQFjAA&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Ftechcrunch.com%2F2013%2F03%2F03%2Fjolla-ceo-interview%2F&amp;ei=VlduUd36CIPYPf7EgLAF&amp;usg=AFQjCNFtxcHfY8glGeFnFaUDY_EYj4uh7A&amp;bvm=bv.45368065,d.ZWU">previously pegged the second half of this year</a> for its debut device launch. Today it has confirmed to TechCrunch that this launch timeframe is not changing, despite its intention to show the phone next month. It provided the following emailed statement confirming the pre-sales campaign and noting that the shipping timeframe remains the same:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote><p>Jolla will showcase its first device in May. The exact timing of the introduction will be announced later. A pre-sales campaign is expected to start after mid-May. The campaign is currently being planned and further details will be available at the time of the product introduction. The sales start of the first Jolla device will take place during the second half of 2013 as earlier announced.</p></blockquote>
<p>The pre-sales campaign was reported earlier in Finnish publication <a target="_blank" href="http://www.digitoday.fi/mobiili/2013/04/16/ennakkotilaajat-saavat-hienomman-jolla-puhelimen/20135494/66">digitoday</a>, which ran an interview with Jolla chairman Antti Saarnio. According to the  interview (translated from the Finnish by Google translate), the pre-sales campaign will be a &#8220;Kickstarter-style&#8221; crowdfunding campaign, whereby early backers can expect to get a device with a few special extras compared to buyers who pile in later.</p>
<p>Jolla told TechCrunch via Twitter that the pre-sales campaign is <em>not</em> a crowdfunding campaign to fund the initial production run, rather &#8220;pre-sales is for the fans to sign up their interest and make sure they get the device first&#8221;. However the distinction between a pre-sales campaign for fans and a crowdfunding campaign to fund production is a minimal one, and mostly a difference of emphasis.</p>
<p>In its interview with digitoday, Saarnio apparently talks about taking &#8220;advance payments&#8221; and &#8220;pre-payments&#8221; from fans who register to buy the device &#8212; payments that &#8220;will not be so great as to constitute a threshold for the fans&#8221; but will be tiered, allowing them to get a more &#8220;tailored&#8221; phone, the more they pay.</p>
<p>Jolla has not, however, confirmed this advanced payment detail separately to TechCrunch. Its statement suggests it is still finalising plans for the pre-sales campaign. <strong>Update: </strong>Jolla has now confirmed <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/JollaHQ/status/324461839880687616">via Twitter</a> that it will be taking payments ahead of the phone&#8217;s launch from fans who intend to buy it. &#8220;Yes, there will be various options to show the support and get something in return. Stay tuned for the announcement in May,&#8221; it said.</p>
<p>The pre-sales campaign is clearly part of Jolla&#8217;s marketing and community-building efforts to spread the word about Sailfish and build momentum behind it. But taking payments ahead of production also makes sense for a startup with limited resources to build hardware and one that is competing in such as fiercely competitive space, against smartphone makers with such huge resources.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800409/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=NDg8hdXJI90:HyQEvsSU7Tk:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=NDg8hdXJI90:HyQEvsSU7Tk:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=NDg8hdXJI90:HyQEvsSU7Tk:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=NDg8hdXJI90:HyQEvsSU7Tk:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=NDg8hdXJI90:HyQEvsSU7Tk:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=NDg8hdXJI90:HyQEvsSU7Tk:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=NDg8hdXJI90:HyQEvsSU7Tk:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=NDg8hdXJI90:HyQEvsSU7Tk:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/NDg8hdXJI90" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/jolla-to-show-first-phone-in-may/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-02-at-19-33-07.png?w=79" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-02-at-19-33-07.png?w=79" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sailfish</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68a02f90ad0a6349a7b852ddce6f93e4?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nelomas</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/jolla-to-show-first-phone-in-may/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Le Camping Alumni Augment Raises €220K To Take Its Augmented Reality Sales Tool To The U.S.</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/TNex0Zo7mRs/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/augment/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve O'Hear</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Augment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=799489</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/augment_screenshot6.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Augment_Screenshot6" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Despite its potential, the jury is arguably still out on the best use-case for Augmented Reality. But one startup, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.augmentedev.com">Augment</a>, thinks it has the answer: helping to sell products by letting customers see what they might look like in the real world.

A graduate of the Paris-based accelerator <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/le-camping">Le Camping</a>, today the company is announcing a €220k (~$289k) funding round -- capital it will use to take its offering to the U.S., where it has recently hired a biz dev and sales person, and incorporated a local subsidiary.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/augment_screenshot6.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Augment_Screenshot6" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Despite its potential, the jury is arguably still out on the best use-case for Augmented Reality. But one startup, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.augmentedev.com">Augment</a>, thinks it has the answer: helping to sell products by letting customers see what they might look like in the real world.</p>
<p>A graduate of the Paris-based accelerator <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/le-camping">Le Camping</a>, today the company is announcing a €220k (~$289k) funding round &#8212; capital it will use to take its offering to the U.S., where it has recently hired a biz dev and sales person, and incorporated a local subsidiary.</p>
<p>Targeting e-commerce sites, catalogs and sales people out in the field, Augment offers a platform where 3D models can be uploaded, and free apps for iOS and Android to let customers <a target="_blank" href="http://agmt.co/demo/furniture/index.html">visualize</a> products/designs embedded in their environment in &#8220;real size&#8221;. So, for example, you might be shopping for a new couch and by using Augment you&#8217;d be able to see how it looks and fits within your actual living room, through the view finder of your iPad.</p>
<p>The advantage of using Augmented Reality as a sales tool is that it increases engagement and conversion rates, and lowers the likelihood of a product being returned because it didn&#8217;t look how the customer had imagined. Or so the pitch goes. &#8220;In short, it removes the uncertainty from buying online or from a catalog,&#8221; says co-founder Jean-François Chianetta.</p>
<p>Competitors in the Augmented Reality platform space include <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/aurasma">Aurasma</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/blippar">Blippar</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/metaio">Metaio</a>. &#8220;Our differentiator is that we provide the easiest platform to visualize your own 3D models in Augmented Reality,&#8221; says Chianetta. &#8220;We let people register to our upload interface, upload their models and share them right away.&#8221;</p>
<p>Furthermore, he says that unlike others Augment doesn&#8217;t do &#8220;games, dancing characters or advertising campaigns&#8221; and is 100% focused on using Augmented Reality to help sell. &#8220;We provide augmented reality as a service so our customers don&#8217;t need to do big upfront investments to benefit from it.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company monetizes in a number of ways including charging to embed the Augment button on e-commerce sites, an &#8220;offline&#8221; mode for sales people taking the iOS or Android app out on the road, and print integration.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s new funding comes from a group of Paris-based angel investors: Tristan Vyskoc, an active investor in startups in the Parisian ecosystem; Laurent Therezien, a web entrepreneur who was part of Lastminute.com and Voyage-Privé; Olivier Mathiot, co-founder and currently VP of Marketing and Communication of PriceMinister; and Nicolas Vauvilliez, who was COO at LeGuide.com and is now owner and CEO of 1001 Maquettes.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/799489/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=TNex0Zo7mRs:9V5AAC9Uba4:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=TNex0Zo7mRs:9V5AAC9Uba4:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=TNex0Zo7mRs:9V5AAC9Uba4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=TNex0Zo7mRs:9V5AAC9Uba4:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=TNex0Zo7mRs:9V5AAC9Uba4:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=TNex0Zo7mRs:9V5AAC9Uba4:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=TNex0Zo7mRs:9V5AAC9Uba4:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=TNex0Zo7mRs:9V5AAC9Uba4:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/TNex0Zo7mRs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/augment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/augment_screenshot6.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/augment_screenshot6.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Augment_Screenshot6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/95b8a6df6d265cf57a4d89ee4856ea98?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve O'Hear</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/augment/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon Expands Its Android Appstore To Nearly 200 Countries; It's All About Scale</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/2QFin-5RPiY/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/amazon-takes-its-android-appstore-global-adding-200-more-countries/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 07:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ingrid Lunden</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800402</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/images-screenshots-captures-amazon-appstore-logo-21032011_00b4000000001978.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="images-screenshots-captures-amazon-appstore-logo-21032011_00B4000000001978" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com">Amazon</a> today took a big step forward in its strategy to take its app distribution business -- and its Kindle Fire hardware business -- global: it announced that its <a target="_blank" href="http://phx.corporate-ir.net/phoenix.zhtml?c=176060&#38;p=irol-newsArticle&#38;ID=1807455&#38;highlight=">Android-based Appstore will expand to cover "nearly 200"  countries</a>, including adding Australia, Latin American countries like Brazil and Mexico, Canada, South Africa and South Korea. Up to now, the only countries where the Appstore was available were the U.S., UK, Germany, France, Italy, Spain and Japan.
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/images-screenshots-captures-amazon-appstore-logo-21032011_00b4000000001978.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="images-screenshots-captures-amazon-appstore-logo-21032011_00B4000000001978" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com">Amazon</a> today took a big step forward in its strategy to take its app distribution business &#8212; and its Kindle Fire hardware business &#8212; global: it announced that its <a target="_blank" href="http://phx.corporate-ir.net/phoenix.zhtml?c=176060&amp;p=irol-newsArticle&amp;ID=1807455&amp;highlight=">Android-based Appstore will expand to cover &#8220;nearly 200&#8243;  countries</a>, including adding Australia, Latin American countries like Brazil and Mexico, Canada, South Africa and South Korea. Up to now, the only countries where the Appstore was available were the U.S., UK, Germany, France, Italy, Spain and Japan.</p>
<p>Developers interested in distributing their apps to these new international users can start <a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/ap/signin?openid.ns=http%3A%2F%2Fspecs.openid.net%2Fauth%2F2.0&amp;pageId=mas_dev_portal2&amp;openid.identity=http%3A%2F%2Fspecs.openid.net%2Fauth%2F2.0%2Fidentifier_select&amp;openid.claimed_id=http%3A%2F%2Fspecs.openid.net%2Fauth%2F2.0%2Fidentifier_select&amp;openid.mode=checkid_setup&amp;openid.assoc_handle=mas_dev_portal&amp;openid.return_to=https%3A%2F%2Fdeveloper.amazon.com%2Fap_login%2F68747470733A2F2F646576656C6F7065722E616D617A6F6E2E636F6D2F686F6D652E68746D6C.html&amp;language=en_US&amp;openid.pape.max_auth_age=1">submitting their apps today</a>, Amazon said. The storefronts themselves will be coming &#8220;in the coming months&#8221; when Amazon officially launches its Amazon Appstore for Android internationally. </p>
<p>Last quarter, Amazon missed on almost all analyst estimates but its stock soared anyway, partly because, as the <a target="_blank" href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2013/01/29/five-takeaways-from-amazons-earnings/">WSJ</a> points out, it was showing improvements in its operating income &#8212; a sign that its business of selling online on a grand scale continues to progress.</p>
<p>Amazon is due to <a target="_blank" href="http://phx.corporate-ir.net/phoenix.zhtml?c=176060&amp;p=irol-newsArticle&amp;ID=1806030&amp;highlight=">announce its next quarterly results on April 25</a>. Putting the news out today that it&#8217;s growing the scale of its digital content business even further helps them continue to sell that message in the lead-up to that.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also an important message to lure more developers to its platform.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Amazon’s platform is a complete end-to-end solution for developers wanting to build, market and monetize their apps and games on Kindle Fire and Android devices,&#8221; said Mike George, VP of Apps and Games at Amazon, in a statement. &#8220;Allowing developers to target distribution of their apps and games in even more international countries is yet another important milestone as we strive to serve consumers and developers globally. Many of our existing developers have localized their apps and games for international consumers, and we look forward to working with new developers that have been waiting to bring their apps to more Amazon customers across the globe.&#8221; </p></blockquote>
<p>Amazon, as we have all <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/27/more-on-amazons-kindle-non-numbers-sales-more-than-double-on-last-year-for-thanksgiving-weekend-cyber-monday-biggest-of-all/">come to expect by now</a>, doesn&#8217;t give out specific numbers on how well apps (or its devices) are selling. (However, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/03/30/amazons-appstore-generates-more-revenue-than-google-play/">Flurry a year ago</a> estimated that the Appstore generated nearly as much as Apple&#8217;s App Store, at 89% of Apple&#8217;s app revenues, with Google Play significantly behind them, making only 23% as much as Apple.</p>
<p>Since first launching the store in 2011, Amazon has gradually been offering different features in the Appstore to give developers more flexibility for how they charge users. </p>
<p>These include single-click purchasing, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/10/amazons-takes-in-app-purchases-out-of-beta-heres-how-theyre-getting-around-that-pricing-issue/">in-app purchasing</a>, A/B testing capability, and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/11/amazon-pumps-up-kindle-fire-gaming-with-gamecircle-opens-apis-to-developers/">GameCircle</a>, launched last year, specifically to promote and use gaming apps. Amazon says that a study of 500 games that utilize in-app purchasing on Amazon found that those enabled to work via GameCircle earned 83% more average revenue per user than non-GameCircle games.</p>
<p>Amazon started as an online bookseller but has since expanded into electronics, home goods, fashion, digital content and much more. With that, it has built a business model around being aggressive on prices for consumers, making up for it with economies of scale. In that sense, taking its Appstore (and probably its hardware) to as wide an audience as possible is an essential move for the company.</p>
<p>But there could be another reason for ramping up Appstore distribution: Because a more powerful app storefront has become a prerequisite for many consumers when considering what mobile hardware to buy, the move is also a sign that Amazon could be gearing up to get more aggressive with its hardware strategy. Amazon currently sells Kindle e-readers and Kindle Fire tablets built on a forked version of Android. Many believe that it will add a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/ewanspence/2012/12/17/the-coming-amazon-kindle-phone-is-not-going-to-be-a-surprise/">smartphone to the lineup</a> soon.</p>
<p>While Amazon has yet to announce a phone, there have been various signals that it does plan to do more with smartphones soon. Included in this is a carrier billing deal it has signed with Bango, which has yet to come into effect but <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/amazons-carrier-billing-deal-with-bango-to-kick-in-this-year-changes-for-the-appstore-and-amazon-ahead/">looks like it might</a> finally this year. Amazon&#8217;s Kindle Fire tablets largely work on WiFi connections (there is one model, the 8.9-inch Kindle Fire HD with LTE access, but so far this is only sold in the U.S.). But a smartphone would be more closely linked with mobile operators, making it more logical for Amazon to look for a way of making it easier for users to pay for content on its Appstore, especially in countries where credit card penetration is low.</p>
<p>Release below.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Amazon Expands Global App Distribution to Nearly 200 Countries – Developers Should Submit Their Apps Soon to Reach Millions More Active Amazon Customers<br />
</strong><br />
Developers around the world reporting high monetization rates with Kindle Fire and Amazon Appstore</p>
<p>SEATTLE&#8211;(BUSINESS WIRE)&#8211;Apr. 17, 2013&#8211; (NASDAQ: AMZN) – Amazon.com, Inc. continued the global expansion of its Appstore today by announcing that developers can now submit their apps for distribution in nearly 200 countries, including Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, India, South Africa, South Korea, and even Papua New Guinea and Vatican City. These apps will be made available in the coming months when the Amazon Appstore for Android launches internationally for consumers. Registered developers who want international distribution will have their apps automatically made available for download, unless they designate otherwise. This international expansion is the latest in a series of Amazon Appstore for Android launches, which have included the UK, Germany, France, Italy, Spain and Japan. Signing up is easy and developers can get started today by visiting the Amazon Mobile App Distribution Portal.</p>
<p>Developers throughout the world are experiencing strong monetization and user engagement through Kindle Fire and the Amazon Appstore. The success is being driven by Amazon’s large customer base and industry-leading e-commerce features like 1-Click purchasing, Amazon’s APIs for In-App Purchasing (IAP) and A/B Testing, and GameCircle, Amazon’s gaming experience for Kindle Fire. A recent study of more than 500 games that utilize in-app purchasing on Amazon found that GameCircle-enabled mobile games earned 83 percent more average revenue per user (ARPU) than non-GameCircle games.</p>
<p>“Amazon’s platform is a complete end-to-end solution for developers wanting to build, market and monetize their apps and games on Kindle Fire and Android devices,” said Mike George, Vice President of Apps and Games at Amazon. “Allowing developers to target distribution of their apps and games in even more international countries is yet another important milestone as we strive to serve consumers and developers globally. Many of our existing developers have localized their apps and games for international consumers, and we look forward to working with new developers that have been waiting to bring their apps to more Amazon customers across the globe.”</p>
<p>Monetization Success<br />
P2 Games is a UK based publisher of interactive games. “We launched our Kindle Fire version of Peppa Pig in January 2013 and within a couple of weeks we saw the sales on Kindle Fire overtake Google Play to a factor of four or five times,” said Peter Sleeman, Director, P2 Games Limited. “Kindle Fire is now a legitimate contender and although our apps have been out much longer on the iOS formats our current rate of sale is close to parity with iOS most days.”</p>
<p>Mobile Deluxe is the creator of popular games like Big Win Slots and Jewel Factory. &#8220;We see superior engagement, retention, and monetization from players who download our games from Amazon,” said Sean Thompson, Vice President of Mobile Deluxe. “The GameCircle integration is helping us achieve 40 percent better per-user monetization rates compared to non-Amazon players. We&#8217;re excited to continue this momentum as the Amazon Appstore grows into more and more international countries.&#8221;</p>
<p>Playmous is a UK mobile games publisher. &#8220;We were excited to see how fast the Kindle Fire install base was growing in the UK and other European countries,” said Anton Volnykh, Playmous. “Our initial launch on the Amazon Appstore in October was targeted to Europe only and we saw 4x growth in paid downloads when we launched the second campaign in just 6 weeks after the initial release. Moreover, our conversion rate from the free version to the paid version of the game has been 30% higher than on other app stores on average with the same product.&#8221;</p>
<p>Anuman Interactive is a French multimedia publishing company. &#8220;With 30 apps released since April 2012, more than 80 percent of the Anuman&#8217;s Android sales were realized on the Amazon Appstore,” said Stephane Longeard, CEO Anuman Interactive. “This store is extraordinarily easy to use with its recommendations system and secure 1-Click payment technology. We are really glad to reach people all over the world, thanks to Amazon Appstore.&#8221;</p>
<p>Developer Support<br />
Big Duck Games is the developer of the popular puzzler Flow Free. &#8220;We&#8217;ve been distributing our games on Amazon since May 2012. Today, we have many hundreds of thousands of daily sessions on Amazon,&#8221; said Sharon Newman, Vice President, Big Duck Games. &#8220;It&#8217;s a great audience that deeply engages with our games, and we&#8217;re excited to reach an even larger audience with the added international launches of the Amazon Appstore.&#8221;</p>
<p>Imangi Studios is the creator of the popular game Temple Run. &#8220;We&#8217;ve integrated with Amazon&#8217;s In-App Purchasing and GameCircle APIs, which was a breeze,&#8221; says Keith Shephard, CEO of Imangi Studios. &#8220;We&#8217;ve seen significantly higher customer engagement with Temple Run since the integration, making the few, short steps worth it. We&#8217;re looking forward to following the Amazon Appstore as it expands into more international countries.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800402/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=2QFin-5RPiY:ok19Esvkll4:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=2QFin-5RPiY:ok19Esvkll4:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=2QFin-5RPiY:ok19Esvkll4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=2QFin-5RPiY:ok19Esvkll4:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=2QFin-5RPiY:ok19Esvkll4:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=2QFin-5RPiY:ok19Esvkll4:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=2QFin-5RPiY:ok19Esvkll4:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=2QFin-5RPiY:ok19Esvkll4:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/2QFin-5RPiY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/amazon-takes-its-android-appstore-global-adding-200-more-countries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/images-screenshots-captures-amazon-appstore-logo-21032011_00b4000000001978.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/images-screenshots-captures-amazon-appstore-logo-21032011_00b4000000001978.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">images-screenshots-captures-amazon-appstore-logo-21032011_00B4000000001978</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6648ec93043f0f368091adece63c6d52?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ingridlunden</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/17/amazon-takes-its-android-appstore-global-adding-200-more-countries/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>China's E-Commerce Market Grew To $190B In 2012, Driven By Mobile Users and Social Media, Says CNNIC</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/yv4gdg8xmMo/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/chinas-e-commerce-market-grew-to-190b-in-2012-driven-by-mobile-users-and-social-media-says-cnnic/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 06:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Catherine Shu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taobao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tmall]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800394</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/hackchina1.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="China flag" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />China&#8217;s e-commerce market racked up a whopping 1.3 trillion RMB ($190 billion USD) worth of transactions in 2012, according to a report by the China Internet Network Information Center (CNNIC) (linked article is in Chinese), an increase of 66.5 percent over 2011&#8242;s total. Last year, 242 million Internet users purchased goods online, and e-commerce transactions accounted for 6.1 percent of total retail sales of consumer goods. The growth was driven in large part by mobile users: during the last half of 2012, 40.7 percent of online shoppers used a mobile device to browse e-commerce merchandise. More than half&#8211;53.6 percent&#8211;browsed a merchandiser&#8217;s mobile app instead of accessing its main Web site through their device&#8217;s Internet browser. 53.3 percent of the respondents who used their mobile devices to shop said they did so while at home, and many stated that their smartphones had begun to replace their home PCs. 26.2 percent said they browsed items on their smartphones while at work or school, and 10.6 percent said they spent their commutes or time waiting in queues to shop. In addition to mobile, social media platforms also drove e-commerce sales. 41.8 percent of shoppers said they had first seen information or promotions for a product on a social media site before deciding to purchase it. Each shopper spent an average of 5,203 RMB (or about $843 USD), an increase of 1,302 RMB ($211 USD), or 25 percent, from the year before. According to the report, the most frequently purchased items were clothing and shoes, which 81.8 percent of online shoppers bought during the last six months of 2012. General merchandise accounted for 31.6 percent of sales, while consumer electronics made up 29.6 percent of the total. While the latest figures from CNNIC are impressive, China&#8217;s e-commerce market still has plenty of room to grow and is set to overtake America&#8217;s. As this Economist story notes, the Chinese e-commerce market is currently dominated by Alibaba, which last year handled 1.1 trillion yuan ($170 billion USD) in sales through two of its portals, Taobao and Tmall, and is on its way to becoming the first online retail company in the world to handle $1 trillion a year in transactions. Taobao is a C2C marketplace with more than 800 million product listings and 500 million registered users, according to Alibaba. B2C platform Tmall counts major international brands like Microsoft, Nike and Unilever among its 50,000 merchants.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/hackchina1.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="China flag" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>China&#8217;s e-commerce market racked up a whopping 1.3 trillion RMB ($190 billion USD) worth of transactions in 2012, according to <a target="_blank" href="http://tech.sina.com.cn/i/2013-04-16/13328244628.shtml">a report by the China Internet Network Information Center (CNNIC)</a> (linked article is in Chinese), an increase of 66.5 percent over 2011&#8242;s total. </p>
<p>Last year, 242 million Internet users purchased goods online, and e-commerce transactions accounted for 6.1 percent of total retail sales of consumer goods. </p>
<p>The growth was driven in large part by mobile users: during the last half of 2012, 40.7 percent of online shoppers used a mobile device to browse e-commerce merchandise. More than half&#8211;53.6 percent&#8211;browsed a merchandiser&#8217;s mobile app instead of accessing its main Web site through their device&#8217;s Internet browser. 53.3 percent of the respondents who used their mobile devices to shop said they did so while at home, and many stated that their smartphones had begun to replace their home PCs. 26.2 percent said they browsed items on their smartphones while at work or school, and 10.6 percent said they spent their commutes or time waiting in queues to shop. </p>
<p>In addition to mobile, social media platforms also drove e-commerce sales. 41.8 percent of shoppers said they had first seen information or promotions for a product on a social media site before deciding to purchase it. </p>
<p>Each shopper spent an average of 5,203 RMB (or about $843 USD), an increase of 1,302 RMB ($211 USD), or 25 percent, from the year before. According to the report, the most frequently purchased items were clothing and shoes, which 81.8 percent of online shoppers bought during the last six months of 2012. General merchandise accounted for 31.6 percent of sales, while consumer electronics made up 29.6 percent of the total. </p>
<p>While the latest figures from CNNIC are impressive, China&#8217;s e-commerce market still has plenty of room to grow and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.economist.com/news/leaders/21573981-chinas-e-commerce-giant-could-generate-enormous-wealthprovided-countrys-rulers-leave-it">is set to overtake America&#8217;s</a>. As this Economist story notes, the Chinese e-commerce market is <a target="_blank" href="http://www.economist.com/news/leaders/21573981-chinas-e-commerce-giant-could-generate-enormous-wealthprovided-countrys-rulers-leave-it">currently dominated by Alibaba</a>, which last year handled 1.1 trillion yuan ($170 billion USD) in sales through two of its portals, Taobao and Tmall, and is on its way to <a target="_blank" href="http://www.economist.com/news/briefing/21573980-alibaba-trailblazing-chinese-internet-giant-will-soon-go-public-worlds-greatest-bazaar">becoming the first online retail company in the world to handle $1 trillion a year in transactions</a>. Taobao is a C2C marketplace with more than 800 million product listings and 500 million registered users, <a target="_blank" href="http://news.alibaba.com/specials/aboutalibaba/aligroup/index.html">according to Alibaba</a>. B2C platform Tmall counts major international brands like Microsoft, Nike and Unilever among its 50,000 merchants. </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800394/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yv4gdg8xmMo:CB9AeeXMCcE:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yv4gdg8xmMo:CB9AeeXMCcE:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yv4gdg8xmMo:CB9AeeXMCcE:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yv4gdg8xmMo:CB9AeeXMCcE:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=yv4gdg8xmMo:CB9AeeXMCcE:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yv4gdg8xmMo:CB9AeeXMCcE:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=yv4gdg8xmMo:CB9AeeXMCcE:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yv4gdg8xmMo:CB9AeeXMCcE:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/yv4gdg8xmMo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/chinas-e-commerce-market-grew-to-190b-in-2012-driven-by-mobile-users-and-social-media-says-cnnic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/hackchina1.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/hackchina1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">China flag</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4b15381361f439f6782de896e29143f1?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">catherineshu</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/chinas-e-commerce-market-grew-to-190b-in-2012-driven-by-mobile-users-and-social-media-says-cnnic/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Tylr Mobile Launches An Email Inbox For Salespeople That Connects To Salesforce.com</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/_WcFgD8dxac/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/tylr-mobile-launches-an-email-inbox-for-salespeople-that-connects-to-salesforce-com/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 05:43:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alex Williams</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tylr mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CRM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doubledutch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crushpath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bluewolf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mailbox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taskbox]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800374</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/tylr.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="tylr" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Tylr Mobile today announced WorkinBox, a new mobile email inbox for salespeople connected to Salesforce.com. WorkinBox matches incoming email with CRM data to help sales people prioritize and focus on messages from customers and prospects, access relevant information and files from CRM, and update CRM systems. The technology has two parts: A native iOS application and contextual engine with connectors to IMAP and the salesforce API. A cloud-based mobile work platform that IT can use to configure the app and add additional data sources, without having to customize. Salespeople can sort their inbox by opportunity size, and access the information and files they need to resolve customer questions. They can turn messages into actionable tasks, and update salesforce.com as they work. It is designed to help bring value to sales organizations that spend $12 billion a year on CRM systems that don’t get used, especially on the go. Mobile systems are changing CRM. CiteWorld recently had a story about Bluewolf CEO Eric Berridge who spent a day on the road with Sysco sales people to see how they work. He learned they do not use their CRM apps. The customers he visited were just as busy. &#8220;They all have five minutes, maximum, to deal with him; they&#8217;re running a business, they have to deal with cash registers and waiters and deliveries. The notion of this guy using a CRM system in front of the client in the five minutes they have for him is a complete disconnect from how his job works.&#8221; The salesman Berridge shadowed told him he was part of the pilot system. &#8220;He didn&#8217;t turn it on once.&#8221; Alan Lepofsky, VP and Principal Analyst for Collaboration Software at Constellation Research saids in a prepared statement: Sales professionals rely heavily on email to engage with prospects, yet there&#8217;s critical information about these prospects in a separate CRM system. Switching context between the two is cumbersome, especially on a mobile device.  If a single app could bring those two worlds together, providing instant access to the information and actions needed to win a deal, companies will be lining up to use it. Co-Founder Ryan Nichols said Tylr competes with two types of startups. Mobile sales tools like Crushpath and Doubledutch that he says would be concerning if they tackled the elephant in the room for mobile productivity: the email inbox.  He said there are a group of startups tackling mobile email, like]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/tylr.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="tylr" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.tylrmobile.com/">Tylr Mobile</a> today announced <a target="_blank" href="http://www.workinbox.com/">WorkinBox</a>, a new mobile email inbox for salespeople connected to <a target="_blank" href="http://salesforce.com/">Salesforce.com</a>.</p>
<p>WorkinBox matches incoming email with CRM data to help sales people prioritize and focus on messages from customers and prospects, access relevant information and files from CRM, and update CRM systems. The technology has two parts:</p>
<ul>
<li>A native iOS application and contextual engine with connectors to IMAP and the salesforce API.</li>
<li>A cloud-based mobile work platform that IT can use to configure the app and add additional data sources, without having to customize.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/tylr-mobile-launches-an-email-inbox-for-salespeople-that-connects-to-salesforce-com/tylrmobile/" rel="attachment wp-att-800387"></a></p>
<p>Salespeople can sort their inbox by opportunity size, and access the information and files they need to resolve customer questions. They can turn messages into actionable tasks, and update <a target="_blank" href="http://salesforce.com/">salesforce.com</a> as they work. It is designed to help bring value to sales organizations that spend $12 billion a year on CRM systems that don’t get used, especially on the go.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Mobile systems are changing CRM. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.citeworld.com/cloud/21708/bluewolf-ceo-sysco-crm">CiteWorld</a> recently had a story about <a target="_blank" href="http://www.bluewolf.com/">Bluewolf </a>CEO Eric Berridge who spent a day on the road with Sysco sales people to see how they work. He learned they do not use their CRM apps.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr">The customers he visited were just as busy. &#8220;They all have five minutes, maximum, to deal with him; they&#8217;re running a business, they have to deal with cash registers and waiters and deliveries. The notion of this guy using a CRM system in front of the client in the five minutes they have for him is a complete disconnect from how his job works.&#8221; The salesman Berridge shadowed told him he was part of the pilot system. &#8220;He didn&#8217;t turn it on once.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p dir="ltr">Alan Lepofsky, VP and Principal Analyst for Collaboration Software at Constellation Research saids in a prepared statement:</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr">Sales professionals rely heavily on email to engage with prospects, yet there&#8217;s critical information about these prospects in a separate CRM system. Switching context between the two is cumbersome, especially on a mobile device.  If a single app could bring those two worlds together, providing instant access to the information and actions needed to win a deal, companies will be lining up to use it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Co-Founder Ryan Nichols said Tylr competes with two types of startups. Mobile sales tools like <a target="_blank" href="http://crushpath.com/">Crushpath</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://doubledutch.me/">Doubledutch</a> that he says would be concerning if they tackled the elephant in the room for mobile productivity: the email inbox.  He said there are a group of startups tackling mobile email, like<a target="_blank" href="http://www.mailboxapp.com/"> Mailbox</a> and<a target="_blank" href="http://taskbox.co/"> TaskBox</a>. &#8221;They&#8217;d be concerning if they started connecting their inbox to enterprise apps and targeting specific enterprise roles,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Tylr has raised more than half of the $1.5M in seed financing it is seeking to build out its mobile work platform and make the app generally available at Dreamforce in November. It has four local employees and one offshore. The company will double its employees by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The company is backed by the Citrix Startup Accelerator, the Alchemist Accelerator, and a group of individual investor/advisors from companies like SAP and salesforce.com.</p>
<p>More effective filters are needed for email. It&#8217;s just a question of how much Tylr can be applied to work passively without too much manual intervention.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800374/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_WcFgD8dxac:LiP5tp80D1I:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_WcFgD8dxac:LiP5tp80D1I:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_WcFgD8dxac:LiP5tp80D1I:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_WcFgD8dxac:LiP5tp80D1I:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=_WcFgD8dxac:LiP5tp80D1I:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_WcFgD8dxac:LiP5tp80D1I:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=_WcFgD8dxac:LiP5tp80D1I:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_WcFgD8dxac:LiP5tp80D1I:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/_WcFgD8dxac" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/tylr-mobile-launches-an-email-inbox-for-salespeople-that-connects-to-salesforce-com/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/tylr.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/tylr.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tylr</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b4e205744ae2f9b44921d103b4d80e54?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Alex Williams</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/tylrmobile.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tylrmobile</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/tylr-mobile-launches-an-email-inbox-for-salespeople-that-connects-to-salesforce-com/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Huawei &amp; ZTE Under Scrutiny Again, This Time By The European Commission For Unfair Competition</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/H-W3pLB_R7s/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/huawei-zte-under-scrutiny-again-this-time-by-the-european-commission-for-unfair-competition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 04:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Catherine Shu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huawei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zte]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european commission]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800373</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/european-commission.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="European Commission" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Another round of headaches for Chinese telecom equipment makers Huawei and ZTE--after previously facing scrutiny over security concerns in the U.S., the two companies are now being targeted by the European Commission. The European Union's executive body is seeking to investigate Huawei and ZTE for undercutting European firms by receiving state subsidies, and wants the backing of EU states to move ahead even without a complaint from domestic manufacturers, according to sources <a target="_blank" href="http://uk.reuters.com/article/2013/04/16/uk-eu-china-telecoms-idUKBRE93F1DC20130416">cited in a Reuters report</a>.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/european-commission.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="European Commission" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Another round of headaches for Chinese telecom equipment makers Huawei and ZTE&#8211;after previously facing scrutiny over security concerns in the U.S., the two companies are now being targeted by the European Commission. The European Union&#8217;s executive body is seeking to investigate Huawei and ZTE for undercutting European firms by receiving state subsidies, and wants the backing of EU states to move ahead even without a complaint from domestic manufacturers, according to sources <a target="_blank" href="http://uk.reuters.com/article/2013/04/16/uk-eu-china-telecoms-idUKBRE93F1DC20130416">cited in a Reuters report</a>.</p>
<p>Reuters reports that European manufacturers Ericsson, Alcatel-Lucent, and Nokia Siemens Networks have refused to cooperate with the Commission or file a complaint because they fear being shut out of the lucrative Chinese telecoms market. In turn, Huawei has denied receiving unfair subsidies and says it complies with international laws and does not engage in espionage. Huawei is the world&#8217;s second largest telecom gear maker after Ericsson.</p>
<p>According to the report, EU Trade Commissioner Karel De Gucht intends to move ahead and bring up the issue with EU trade ministers at a meeting in Dublin this week. An internal EU report last year recommended that EU take steps to limit the growth of Chinese telecoms equipment maker, citing competition against domestic companies as well as threats to security.</p>
<p>The Commission&#8217;s complaints are similar U.S. concerns about the Chinese companies. Last month, Sprint Nextel and SoftBank <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/28/sprint-nextel-and-softbank-agree-not-to-use-huawei-equipment-after-merger/">pledged not to use gear from Huawei if they merged</a>, though that <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/15/dish-makes-25-5b-bid-for-sprint-to-snatch-it-out-of-softbanks-hands/">tie-up is now uncertain after Dish Network launched a $25.5 billion bid</a> to compete with SoftBank&#8217;s previous offer of $20.5 billion. Huawei <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/03/huawei-says-security-concerns-will-hinder-u-s-growth-but-it-still-expects-traction-in-europe-and-asia/">recently said that its U.S. growth prospects will be hindered this year by U.S. security concerns</a> after a U.S. congressional report last October found that U.S. national security interests could be undermined if Huawei and ZTE provide gear for critical infrastructure.</p>
<p>But EU companies have not taken a unilateral stance. In Britain, Huawei has been subject to scrutiny by the government over security concerns, though the company is also seen as a major job provider both there in the Netherlands. Germany, however, stopped Huawei last year from providing infrastructure for a national academic research network.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800373/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=H-W3pLB_R7s:xWwm5ihgJQM:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=H-W3pLB_R7s:xWwm5ihgJQM:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=H-W3pLB_R7s:xWwm5ihgJQM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=H-W3pLB_R7s:xWwm5ihgJQM:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=H-W3pLB_R7s:xWwm5ihgJQM:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=H-W3pLB_R7s:xWwm5ihgJQM:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=H-W3pLB_R7s:xWwm5ihgJQM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=H-W3pLB_R7s:xWwm5ihgJQM:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/H-W3pLB_R7s" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/huawei-zte-under-scrutiny-again-this-time-by-the-european-commission-for-unfair-competition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/european-commission.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/european-commission.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">European Commission</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4b15381361f439f6782de896e29143f1?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">catherineshu</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/huawei-zte-under-scrutiny-again-this-time-by-the-european-commission-for-unfair-competition/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Ventures-Backed Messaging Startup, Just.me, Launches iOS App In 155 Countries/32 Languages, Aiming To Rattle Social's Cage</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/QH_J56stK0I/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/just-me-ios-app-launch/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 04:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natasha Lomas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[just.me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messaging apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[line]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=799780</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/justme_logo_medium.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="justme_logo_medium" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Following its beta launch at the end of January, just.me, the mobile messaging startup from Keith Teare, co-founder of TechCrunch and partner at incubator Archimedes Labs, has launched its first app, available initially for iPhones and iPod Touch. Just.me had planned on an earlier release of the app but said today it held back so it could launch at DEMO Mobile to garner more attention.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/justme_logo_medium.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="justme_logo_medium" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Following its <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/23/741025just-me-ios-beta/">beta launch</a> at the end of January, <a target="_blank" href="http://just.me/">just.me</a>, the mobile messaging startup from <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/keith-teare">Keith Teare</a>, co-founder of TechCrunch and partner at incubator <a target="_blank" href="http://www.archimedeslabs.com/">Archimedes Labs</a>, has <a target="_blank" href="http://www.AppStore.com/justme">launched its first app</a>, available initially for iPhones and iPod Touch. Just.me had planned on an earlier release of the app but said today it held back so it could launch at <a target="_blank" href="http://www.demo.com/ehome/index.php?eventid=50633&amp;">DEMO Mobile</a> to garner more attention.</p>
<p>As with any messaging app, just.me&#8217;s usefulness is commensurate with the number of friends fully on board with the service so getting the word out to drive app downloads is now priority number one for its founders. Just.me does support messaging going outside its bounds, to non-app users, but to access the full suite of features conversation participants need to join in.</p>
<p>Just.me also has a more complex feature-set than the average messaging app, so arguably has more work to do to educate potential users and convince them it&#8217;s worth sticking with it through the learning curve. Rather than focusing on selling itself as just a (free) messaging service, as some of its messaging rivals have, just.me has grander ambitions: it&#8217;s agitating to replace centralised social networks with the contacts in your phonebook plus its tabbed sharing structure.</p>
<p>The app supports private one-to-one messaging; contained group messaging; and public broadcasts, the latter on a public <a target="_blank" href="http://www.just.me/home?feed=public&amp;filter=trending&amp;_t=1366195904984">just.me cloud</a> (similar in concept to Twitter or Google+). It also allows users to talk to themselves by using the app as a private journal and/or storage service, a la Evernote. So it&#8217;s offering a spectrum of messaging types, private and public, all within the same service.</p>
<p>These features make it a lot more &#8216;high concept&#8217; than the average messaging app &#8212; closer, perhaps, to the likes of NHN Japan Corp&#8217;s <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/18/line-100m-users/">Line</a>, which is also styling itself as a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/17/line-the-social-entertainment-platform/">social network replacement</a> and also offers multifaceted sharing options. Unlike Line, though, which is replete with stickers and cartoonish mascots, just.me is not so heavily targeting the youth market.</p>
<p>Just.me has a clean, professional look (see screenshot gallery below) with a focus on displaying users&#8217; own photos that&#8217;s most reminiscent of Path or Facebook Home. Add to that its ability to function as an email-plus-multimedia-attachment replacement and just.me seems most likely to appeal to older, professional power users &#8212; who are seeking to collapse the functions of multiple apps into one low-friction interface.</p>
<h3 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:640px;float:center;color:#0a9400;">Facebook Home is a step forward for mobile software&#8230; We can see the end of single use apps in this move.</h3>
<p>Since just.me&#8217;s beta debut at the start of the year the competitive mobile messaging landscape has shifted a little, with Facebook launching its <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/12/heres-how-to-get-facebook-home-running-on-nearly-any-android-device/">Facebook Home launcher on the Android platform</a>. Home is a skin that sits between the OS and third party apps, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/05/facebook-home-winners-and-losers/">pushing the latter outside</a> the user&#8217;s main sphere of attention. Just.me is not currently competing with Home, since Home is not (<a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/chat-heads-coming-to-ios-facebook-app-via-update-pushing-out-anytime-now/">fully</a>) available on iOS. But Teare &amp; co are working on an Android version of their app &#8212; due in six to eight weeks &#8212; so will be rubbing up against Facebook&#8217;s new-look mobile face soon enough.</p>
<p>Asked whether Facebook Home makes just.me&#8217;s user-acquisition task harder than it might otherwise be, Teare argued the opposite, telling TechCrunch: &#8220;Facebook Home really makes things easier. People will understand a user-centric approach with an app that caters for multiple user needs.</p>
<p>&#8220;Facebook Home is a step forward for mobile software. It represents an attempt to support multiple user goals on a single platform. We can see the end of single use apps in this move. <a target="_blank" href="http://just.me/">just.me</a> shares this vision of a combined messaging and social media app capable of supporting all of a users goals. We are happy to be in the same company as Facebook here.&#8221;</p>
<p>While conceding it&#8217;s an inevitable challenge for a 14-person startup to compete &#8220;in a field that contains giants&#8221;, Teare said just.me&#8217;s distributed openness vs the &#8220;walled garden clubs&#8221;, its range of sharing features and an initial rollout that encompasses &#8220;155 countries from day one, in 32 languages&#8221; (albeit, on only one mobile platform) will help it stand out. And rattle some cages.</p>
<p>&#8220;We do not see ourselves as competing with Facebook Home. We are far ahead feature wise and very different in that we are an open and distributed network, not a centralized one. We rather see ourselves as offering users features and controls that others have yet to build,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We want to be a major player in delivering multi-faceted messaging to users.&#8221;</p>
<p>Just.me <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/12/29/fund-me-mobile-social-network-startup-just-me-raises-2-7-million/">raised a $2.7 million Series A back in 2011</a>. Its investors include Khosla Ventures, SV Angel, Google Ventures, True Ventures, Betaworks, CrunchFund (which is of course tied up with TechCrunch in several ways, including the fact that our parent company AOL is an investor), and individuals including Don Dodge and Michael Parekh.</p>

<a href='http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/just-me-ios-app-launch/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-17-15/' title='just.me'></a>
<a href='http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/just-me-ios-app-launch/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-16-10/' title='Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.16.10'></a>
<a href='http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/just-me-ios-app-launch/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-15-51/' title='Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.15.51'></a>
<a href='http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/just-me-ios-app-launch/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-15-35/' title='Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.15.35'></a>
<a href='http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/just-me-ios-app-launch/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-15-22/' title='Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.15.22'></a>
<a href='http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/just-me-ios-app-launch/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-15-03/' title='Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.15.03'></a>
<a href='http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/just-me-ios-app-launch/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-10-28-2/' title='Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.10.28'></a>
<a href='http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/just-me-ios-app-launch/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-07-53-2/' title='Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.07.53'></a>

<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/799780/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QH_J56stK0I:V_PU5j1rD6g:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QH_J56stK0I:V_PU5j1rD6g:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QH_J56stK0I:V_PU5j1rD6g:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QH_J56stK0I:V_PU5j1rD6g:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=QH_J56stK0I:V_PU5j1rD6g:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QH_J56stK0I:V_PU5j1rD6g:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=QH_J56stK0I:V_PU5j1rD6g:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QH_J56stK0I:V_PU5j1rD6g:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/QH_J56stK0I" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/just-me-ios-app-launch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/justme_logo_medium.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/justme_logo_medium.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">justme_logo_medium</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68a02f90ad0a6349a7b852ddce6f93e4?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nelomas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-17-15.png?w=84" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">just.me</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-16-10.png?w=84" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.16.10</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-15-51.png?w=84" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.15.51</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-15-35.png?w=84" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.15.35</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-15-22.png?w=84" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.15.22</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-15-03.png?w=84" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.15.03</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-10-281.png?w=84" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.10.28</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-22-07-531.png?w=84" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 22.07.53</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/just-me-ios-app-launch/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Instart Logic Raises $17M From Andreessen Horowitz Greylock To Improve Web And Mobile App Performance</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/Kc07T9ysbH8/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/instart-logic-raises-17m-from-andreessen-horowitz-greylock-to-improve-web-and-mobile-app-performance/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 04:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leena Rao</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800272</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="56" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/instart-logic.jpg?w=100&amp;h=56&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Instart Logic" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><a target="_blank" href="http://instartlogic.com/">Instart Logic</a>, a company that provides a cloud-based service for web publishers to improves site performance over both mobile and WiFi networks, has raised $17 million in Series B funding from Andreessen Horowitz, Greylock Partners, Sutter Hill Ventures and Tenaya Capital. This brings the company's total funding to $26 million.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="56" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/instart-logic.jpg?w=100&amp;h=56&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Instart Logic" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://instartlogic.com/">Instart Logic</a>, a company that provides a cloud-based service for web publishers to improves site performance over both mobile and WiFi networks, has raised $17 million in Series B funding from Andreessen Horowitz, Greylock Partners, Sutter Hill Ventures and Tenaya Capital. This brings the company&#8217;s total funding to $26 million.</p>
<p>Manav Mital, CEO and co-founder of the company, explains that Instart solves a major pain point for publishers and site owners, which is having uses be able to access their sites over congested mobile and wifi networks. What Instart Logic offers is a cloud-based, easy to deploy service that can be used by web publishers to improve responsiveness of applications, and create faster load times for pages.</p>
<p>As he says, web applications continue to grow in size and complexity, as static web sites are supplanted by immersive, interactive applications. And more people are accessing these sites and apps from mobile and web. Many sites are suffering from major performance issues. Instart Logic resolves these issues.</p>
<p>“Today’s web and mobile users expect near instant delivery of applications, but the explosion of apps combined with the proliferation of mobile devices has resulted indebilitating performance issues that degrade the user experience,” said Peter Levine, partner at Andreessen Horowitz, in a release. “Enter Instart Logic, which has developed a unique and elegant solution that was built from the ground up to resolve the mobile bottleneck and transform the user experience.”</p>
<p>While the company isn&#8217;t ready to reveal exact numbers yet to the public, Instart Logic says that the load times and performance management of web sites improves dramatically</p>
<p>The founding tea, which includes Mital, Hariharan Kolam and Raghu Venkat, all came from the engineering group at Aster Data, the big data analytics company acquired in 2011 for $263 million by Teradata Corporation. Other early employees hail from Google, Facebook, Amazon, VMware, Citrix, Akamai, Adobe, and Mozilla.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s product, which Mital says takes 15 minutes to deploy, completed its beta program in December 2012. Customers included and NFL team, a Fortune 500 companies and other paying clients in retail, travel and hospitality, enterprise SaaS, online gaming, and media. While the product is still in limited availability, it will be released to the general public later this year.</p>
<p>While there are many on-premise offerings that compete with Instart Logic, Mital says that what&#8217;s disruptive about the company&#8217;s product is the easy of use and deployment. </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800272/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Kc07T9ysbH8:T-6f7iTf2oM:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Kc07T9ysbH8:T-6f7iTf2oM:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Kc07T9ysbH8:T-6f7iTf2oM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Kc07T9ysbH8:T-6f7iTf2oM:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Kc07T9ysbH8:T-6f7iTf2oM:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Kc07T9ysbH8:T-6f7iTf2oM:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Kc07T9ysbH8:T-6f7iTf2oM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Kc07T9ysbH8:T-6f7iTf2oM:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/Kc07T9ysbH8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/instart-logic-raises-17m-from-andreessen-horowitz-greylock-to-improve-web-and-mobile-app-performance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/instart-logic.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/instart-logic.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Instart Logic</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bbce6c3c48f821c81c019600a5589ae6?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">leena</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/instart-logic-raises-17m-from-andreessen-horowitz-greylock-to-improve-web-and-mobile-app-performance/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>HackerEarth Screens Developer Candidates For Startups Through Programming Challenges</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/S0Mo8VyXdG4/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/hackerearth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 03:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kim-Mai Cutler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hackerearth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gsf india]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=798531</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-14-at-8-10-29-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-04-14 at 8.10.29 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />The hunt for great engineering talent is global. It&#8217;s not just in Silicon Valley that the competition is so fierce that there are even agents or auctions for developers. It&#8217;s true in India too, where multi-nationals and emerging startups headhunt for the best engineers. HackerEarth, a startup out of the GSF India accelerator, is looking to make the process of assessing technical talent easier through programming challenges. On the flipside, the startup is also looking to help fresh engineering graduates and more experienced developers become better acquainted with growth-stage startups in India. Over there, startups don&#8217;t quite have the same glamour than they do in the U.S. as college grads feel cultural pressure to find jobs at multi-national companies. &#8220;Engineers are hugely in demand here in India. There&#8217;s a shortage of talent and yet, people don&#8217;t know what kinds of opportunities they have,&#8221; said co-founder Sachin Gupta, who left Google to start the company. &#8220;They often end up working for service companies like Wipro and Infosys. It&#8217;s quite different from the Valley, where you&#8217;re exposed to startups all the time.&#8221; Gupta said HackerEarth has built an online engine that does real-time evaluation of technical skills from programming challenges and problem sets. They either design challenges in-house on skills like front-end development or hire freelancers and professors to design them. Since launch about five months ago, the company has processed about 200,000 code compilations and has registered 20,000 developers on the platform. Of those, about 7 to 8,000 are active. They check for basics like the logic of the programming work &#8212; whether it produces the right output given certain inputs. Then they also look at run-time, memory usage and code size. &#8220;With resumes and traditional sourcing methods, you might end up with thousands of CVs and everyone will say they&#8217;re a Java engineer or Python engineer. But are they really?&#8221; Gupta said. &#8220;We very strongly believe if you know something, you should be able to prove it. Because of all this noise, the conversion rates are very low on these traditional recruiting techniques.&#8221; The company has two models. They either source the candidates, assess them and then directly connect them to companies, earning a recruiting fee. Or they have an enterprise SaaS model, where they provide their assessment engine to companies that are hiring for a fee. They charge about $2 per test taken or about 40,000 Indian rupees (or]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-14-at-8-10-29-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-04-14 at 8.10.29 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>The hunt for great engineering talent is global. It&#8217;s not just in Silicon Valley that the competition is so fierce that <a target="_blank" href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2013-04-10/silicon-valley-goes-hollywood-top-coders-can-now-get-agents">there are even agents</a> or <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/26/developer-auction-racks-up-78-million-more-bids-expands-to-la/">auctions for developers. </a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s true in India too, where multi-nationals and emerging startups headhunt for the best engineers. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.hackerearth.com/">HackerEarth</a>, a startup out of the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.gsfindia.com/">GSF India accelerator</a>, is looking to make the process of assessing technical talent easier <a target="_blank" href="http://www.hackerearth.com/challenges/">through programming challenges</a>. </p>
<p>On the flipside, the startup is also looking to help fresh engineering graduates and more experienced developers become better acquainted with growth-stage startups in India. Over there, startups don&#8217;t quite have the same glamour than they do in the U.S. as college grads feel cultural pressure to find jobs at multi-national companies.</p>
<p>&#8220;Engineers are hugely in demand here in India. There&#8217;s a shortage of talent and yet, people don&#8217;t know what kinds of opportunities they have,&#8221; said co-founder Sachin Gupta, who left Google to start the company. &#8220;They often end up working for service companies like Wipro and Infosys. It&#8217;s quite different from the Valley, where you&#8217;re exposed to startups all the time.&#8221;</p>
<p>Gupta said HackerEarth has built an online engine that does real-time evaluation of technical skills from programming challenges and problem sets. They either design challenges in-house on skills like front-end development or hire freelancers and professors to design them. Since launch about five months ago, the company has processed about 200,000 code compilations and has registered 20,000 developers on the platform. Of those, about 7 to 8,000 are active.</p>
<p>They check for basics like the logic of the programming work &#8212; whether it produces the right output given certain inputs. Then they also look at run-time, memory usage and code size. </p>
<p>&#8220;With resumes and traditional sourcing methods, you might end up with thousands of CVs and everyone will say they&#8217;re a Java engineer or Python engineer. But are they really?&#8221; Gupta said. &#8220;We very strongly believe if you know something, you should be able to prove it. Because of all this noise, the conversion rates are very low on these traditional recruiting techniques.&#8221;</p>
<p>The company has two models. They either source the candidates, assess them and then directly connect them to companies, earning a recruiting fee. Or they have an enterprise SaaS model, where they provide their assessment engine to companies that are hiring for a fee. They charge about $2 per test taken or about 40,000 Indian rupees (or $740) per hire. </p>
<p>HackerEarth has three full-time people and is backed with seed funding from GSF India, which is positioning itself as a TechStars or Y Combinator for India.</p>
<p>They face off against <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/08/06/yc-funded-interview-street-streamlines-the-search-for-great-programmers/">competitors like YC-backed InterviewStreet</a>, which <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/23/interview-street-codesprints/">has CodeSprints or competitions on behalf of employers.</a></p>
<p>Gupta said that HackerEarth is a bit different. &#8220;We&#8217;re structuring our platform as a job or talent discovery platform,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They have kind of pivoted toward a hacker ranking system. We are very clearly a place where people can first discover great companies to work at.&#8221; </p>
<p>He added that the Indian market for talent is much more fractured than it is in the U.S., where developers might congregate on Y Combinator&#8217;s Hacker News or here on TechCrunch. In contrast, he said recruiters have to foster much closer relationships with college campuses around the country.</p>
<p>&#8220;Online media penetration is low and there&#8217;s definitely a communication gap. We have to actively reach out to college students,&#8221; Gupta said. &#8220;Even me &#8212; I didn&#8217;t know about InMobi before coming to Bangalore.&#8221; (The mobile advertising network, InMobi, is one of the flagship startups out of the Indian ecosystem and has gotten around $216 million in funding from investors like Japan&#8217;s SoftBank and Kleiner Perkins.)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/798531/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=S0Mo8VyXdG4:pZxq8SM-kU0:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=S0Mo8VyXdG4:pZxq8SM-kU0:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=S0Mo8VyXdG4:pZxq8SM-kU0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=S0Mo8VyXdG4:pZxq8SM-kU0:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=S0Mo8VyXdG4:pZxq8SM-kU0:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=S0Mo8VyXdG4:pZxq8SM-kU0:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=S0Mo8VyXdG4:pZxq8SM-kU0:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=S0Mo8VyXdG4:pZxq8SM-kU0:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/S0Mo8VyXdG4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/hackerearth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-14-at-8-10-29-pm.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-14-at-8-10-29-pm.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-04-14 at 8.10.29 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c4dad53149dd9c712936e1b27c1c1e9f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kimmaicutler</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/hackerearth/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>HealthKeep Launches An Anonymous Social Network To Let You Share And Track Health Information</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/cUDocBxGbZg/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/healthkeep-launches-an-anonymous-social-network-to-let-you-share-and-track-health-information/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 01:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rip Empson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HealthKeep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HealthTech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800322</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-5-11-19-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen shot 2013-04-16 at 5.11.19 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Services <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/16/healthtaps-qa-service-sees-7-5m-uniques-per-month-with-mds-spending-an-hour-per-session-providing-581m-answers/">like HealthTap have proliferated</a> over the last year as a way to let anyone with questions about their health connect with real, licensed physicians online and avoid the pain of waiting in line at the doctor's office. While HealthTap and others are building up their health information databases to let people quickly find answers to a variety of health questions, the demand for personalized health information continues to grow. 
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-5-11-19-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen shot 2013-04-16 at 5.11.19 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Services <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/16/healthtaps-qa-service-sees-7-5m-uniques-per-month-with-mds-spending-an-hour-per-session-providing-581m-answers/">like HealthTap have proliferated</a> over the last year as a way to let anyone with questions about their health connect with real, licensed physicians online and avoid the pain of waiting in line at the doctor&#8217;s office. While HealthTap and others are building up their health information databases to let people quickly find answers to a variety of health questions, the demand for personalized health information continues to grow. </p>
<p>While we use services like Pinterest, Facebook and Twitter every day, these social networks are far from being the best places to ask health questions and connect with others experiencing similar symptoms, conditions, taking the same medications or receiving similar treatments &#8212; for privacy reasons, among others. That&#8217;s why Lyle Dennis, a practicing physician and neurologist, created <a target="_blank" href="https://www.healthkeep.com/">HealthKeep</a> &#8212; a social network designed to connect people with similar symptoms and conditions and help them better track, manage and understand their health.</p>
<p>HealthKeep provides a forum in which everyday people can post about their health and medical issues and search for potential treatments. Unlike most social networks, i.e. Facebook, the service allows users to register anonymously and does not collect names, which means that its HIPAA-compliant. Once members register on the platform, they can create &#8220;Health Timelines,&#8221; where they can share any new symptom, medication, diagnosis, doctor visit, procedure or test result. A la Facebook, the timeline is updated in realtime, stream-style, allowing users to view updates and graph their health at any point.</p>
<p>Once a user adds an element to their timeline, they are automatically linked to every other member in HealthKeep&#8217;s community that has shared that element. An announcement is made each time a new member is added to that group, whereupon the community can then discuss their symptoms and treatments and share information, all of which takes place within feeds dedicated to those specific items.</p>
<p>Members can create private profiles that can be viewed and searched for identification purposes if they so choose, while doctors have public profiles and can contribute to feeds of interest to them and the patients that follow them. Lyle tells us that, at launch, HealthKeep contains a profile for nearly every U.S. doctor (including name, address, phone number and fax), every FDA-approved medication and thousands of diseases, symptoms, procedures and health goals in its database. [Check out an <a target="_blank" href="https://www.healthkeep.com/joseph-h-willner">example of a physician profile here</a>.]</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-6-08-38-pm.png"></a></p>
<p>These profiles are subject to change when doctors actually claim their profiles, at which point they can change the picture associated with their profile, add custom content, and their profile will display everything they follow and post, and everything that other users are saying about them. As people add their doctors, Lyle hopes that &#8220;follower numbers&#8221; will grown, and once they hit a certain threshold, the startup will reach out to them to help provide more information on how to optimize their profiles.</p>
<p>As to the &#8220;following&#8221; mechanism on HealthKeep, Lyle says, &#8220;as a practicing physician myself, I see the fact that patients often like their doctors, they like to discuss them and recommend them to<br />
others. So, following them on HK gives them a sense of community and they can actually relate and communicate with other patients of that doctor anonymously, through the system. In turn, it gives the doctor a public platform to announce to all his patients news items of interest or importance to them.&#8221; </p>
<p>The founder also said that he thinks that HealthKeep provides an easy way for both everyday people and doctors to stay connected to the latest news, research and findings as they relate to particular diseases or health categories. In the big picture, Lyle says that many doctors and MDs aren&#8217;t particularly active on Facebook, Twitter or other social networks, so he wants to help change that, while giving people their own &#8220;personalized medicine news feed.&#8221; </p>
<p>As to the opportunity going forward, the HealthKeep founder says that he sees the service as another approach to the Quantified Self movement that has taken off over the last few years, as its Health Timelines provide a personal health record through which they can keep track of and follow their health variables, both good and bad. At this point, people can enter and graph any element of their health information manually, but, next, the founder wants to begin connecting the platform with the APIs of fitness-tracking devices like Fitbit, Nike+ and Withings to automatically upload user health information. </p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s easy to forget when and what symptoms we&#8217;ve had in the past, what a test showed and what a<br />
doctor told us a year ago during an appointment. With HealthKeep, we want to give people a realtime, interactive social health dashboard that people can set up for themselves or for their children or grandparents.&#8221; </p>
<p>Up to this point, HealthKeep has been bootstrapped and self-funded, but as the platform begins to scale, the founder says the team will look to begin raising a Series A round later this year. While there&#8217;s plenty of room in the burgeoning online and mobile health space for multiple players, HealthKeep will have to contend with health and doctor-focused professional networking services <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/30/with-25-of-u-s-doctors-on-board-quantiamd-lands-12m-to-become-the-linkedin-for-mds/">like QuantiaMD</a> and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/30/with-30k-doctors-registered-doximity-is-fast-becoming-the-linkedin-for-physicians/">Doximity</a>, as well as health information tools <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2009/10/21/healthguru-raises-3-2-million-for-online-health-video-platform/">like HealthGuru</a>, Quantified Self-style databases <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/12/19/as-google-health-flatlines-drchrono-picks-up-the-slack-with-onpatient-a-health-database-with-a-quantified-self-twist/">like Drchrono</a> and mobile Q&amp;A services like HealthTap &#8212; among many others. It will be an uphill road, but there&#8217;s plenty of opportunity if it can hit scale.</p>
<p>For more, find <a target="_blank" href="https://www.healthkeep.com/">HealthKeep at home here.</a></p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-6-13-50-pm.png"></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800322/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=cUDocBxGbZg:2RF-mLThG_o:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=cUDocBxGbZg:2RF-mLThG_o:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=cUDocBxGbZg:2RF-mLThG_o:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=cUDocBxGbZg:2RF-mLThG_o:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=cUDocBxGbZg:2RF-mLThG_o:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=cUDocBxGbZg:2RF-mLThG_o:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=cUDocBxGbZg:2RF-mLThG_o:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=cUDocBxGbZg:2RF-mLThG_o:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/cUDocBxGbZg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/healthkeep-launches-an-anonymous-social-network-to-let-you-share-and-track-health-information/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-5-11-19-pm.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-5-11-19-pm.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2013-04-16 at 5.11.19 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a94f6b72a8ee7342e862c1c9d6c5b826?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rempson8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-6-08-38-pm.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2013-04-16 at 6.08.38 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-6-13-50-pm.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2013-04-16 at 6.13.50 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/healthkeep-launches-an-anonymous-social-network-to-let-you-share-and-track-health-information/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Japan's KDDI Closes Their Twilio Clone, Partners With Twilio Instead</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/4rRXvvxBwbg/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/japans-kddi-closes-their-twilio-clone-partners-with-twilio-instead/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Greg Kumparak</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800345</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/twilio.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="twilio" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Back in April of 2012, KDDI Web Communications (part of KDDI, Japan's second largest telecoms company) launched <a target="_blank" href="http://boundio.jp/">boundio</a>. Meant to allow developers to build services that ran over phone lines (like, say, a basic call center), it was sort of like a less-awesome Twilio.

One year later, the company is shuttering boundio and replacing it with... wait for it... Twilio.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/twilio.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="twilio" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Back in April of 2012, KDDI Web Communications (part of KDDI, Japan&#8217;s second largest telecoms company) launched <a target="_blank" href="http://boundio.jp/">boundio</a>. Meant to allow developers to build services that ran over phone lines (like, say, a basic call center), it was sort of like a less-awesome Twilio.</p>
<p>One year later, the company is shuttering boundio and replacing it with&#8230; wait for it&#8230; Twilio.</p>
<p>We first noted the budding KWC/Twilio <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/31/twilio-kddi/">partnership back in October </a>, though it was unclear at the time exactly what it meant for the company&#8217;s own competing offering. At a press event in Japan today, the company disclosed that registrations for boundio have been closed, and that all existing boundio customers will be moved over to Twilio&#8217;s platform.</p>
<p>While I tend to be the last person to care about B2B partnerships like this, this one is actually pretty friggin&#8217; huge for Twilio. Here&#8217;s why:</p>
<ul>
<li> As Josh <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/31/twilio-kddi/">pointed out</a> in October (and as Groupon <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/10/31/how-groupon-is-losing-china/">quickly found out</a> after launching in China), breaking into Asia is <em>hard</em>. Like, <em>really</em> hard. It&#8217;s a business culture based on respect and credibility. You don&#8217;t just translate your product, fire off a press release, and call it a day. Partnering with someone as large as KDDI gives them cred, without even requiring a local office.</li>
<li>Most enterprises in Japan already have billing relationships with KDDI. To use Twilio directly, these enterprises would need to go through the process of approving a new vendor. Since KDDI already has those relationships and all billing will go through them, Twilio is instantly inheriting massive new potential customers who are already prepped to work with them.
</li>
</ul>
<p>To step into a bit of a tangent: boundio is just the latest of many carrier-built software efforts to fall. </p>
<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/02/15/wholesale-applications-community-fail/">WAC</a> — a &#8220;unified open platform&#8221; that was being built as a joint effort between AT&amp;T, Verizon, China Mobile, Sprint, and others — imploded <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/17/wac-whacked-telecom-backed-alliance-merges-into-gsma-assets-acquired-by-api-management-service-apigee/">before it even left the gate</a>. Orange quietly killed off all of their API efforts <a target="_blank" href="http://api.orange.com/en/orange-api-closing">last month</a>, and mentions of things like Telefonica&#8217;s <a target="_blank" href="http://bluevia.com/">BlueVia</a> seem to come up once every never. </p>
<p>Developers, it would seem, just don&#8217;t care to work with carriers when they can avoid it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800345/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=4rRXvvxBwbg:PBWeSbqGilA:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=4rRXvvxBwbg:PBWeSbqGilA:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=4rRXvvxBwbg:PBWeSbqGilA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=4rRXvvxBwbg:PBWeSbqGilA:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=4rRXvvxBwbg:PBWeSbqGilA:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=4rRXvvxBwbg:PBWeSbqGilA:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=4rRXvvxBwbg:PBWeSbqGilA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=4rRXvvxBwbg:PBWeSbqGilA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/4rRXvvxBwbg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/japans-kddi-closes-their-twilio-clone-partners-with-twilio-instead/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/twilio.jpg?w=112" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/twilio.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">twilio</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/86f75cc66896ab9b0602715f082803d6?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gregkumparak</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/japans-kddi-closes-their-twilio-clone-partners-with-twilio-instead/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Heyzap Launches An AppData-Like Leaderboard For Mobile Games With User Counts</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/RHMHpDjnJeo/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/heyzap-trends/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kim-Mai Cutler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800101</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/heyzap-logo.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="heyzap logo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />While Apple&#8217;s app store and Google Play have long had leaderboards for the most downloaded and lucrative apps, there hasn&#8217;t been that much transparency around engagement after the download. Heyzap, a Union Square Ventures-backed startup that runs a mobile gaming network, has stepped in and decided to build one. The startup, which was founded about four years ago and originally centered around Flash games, has moved onto mobile platforms (pretty much like every other game developer over the past few years). They have an app on Android with about 10 million installs that lets gamers add friends in their favorite titles and share tips and badges. From those 10 million installs, they say they&#8217;ve been able to gauge the size of different developers&#8217; active userbases. So from that, they&#8217;ve launched Heyzap Trends, a live leaderboard that estimates active usage. The standard iOS and Google leaderboards mainly focus on downloads or installs and then revenue over specific time periods (although Google Play&#8217;s rankings are said to factor in some engagement data). They say they get play data for about 80,000 games on the Android platform, which is shared by people who have the Heyzap app and are logged into it. Even games that aren&#8217;t integrated into Heyzap&#8217;s network get their play data recorded by this, said co-founder Immad Akhund. That&#8217;s partially because of Android&#8217;s open nature. &#8220;The openness of the Android OS is allowing for more unique and interesting experiences for users,&#8221; he said in an e-mail. &#8220;I think this is going to be a trend going forward as mobile apps reach maturity and differentiate through deeper experiences hooked in to the OS layer.&#8221; (As a sidenote, Facebook&#8217;s Home app is a perfect example of this openness.) To me, the data seems reasonable. Heyzap&#8217;s leaderboard, for example, says that King, the European arcade gaming company, has 54.7 million monthly active users. Last month, King said it has 49 million monthly actives on smartphones and tablets, including iOS. Similarly, Storm8, a Silicon Valley-based freemium gaming company that runs a label called TeamLava, has about 14.2 million daily active users, according to the leaderboard. Storm8 said it had 10 million daily actives back in January. Also, Subway surfers apparently has 7.6 million daily actives on Android and its maker, the Danish developer Kiloo, said it had 26.5 million daily actives last month on both iOS and Android. Just to make a note, Heyzap&#8217;s]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/heyzap-logo.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="heyzap logo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/heyzap-trends/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-4-55-42-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-800321"></a></p>
<p>While Apple&#8217;s app store and Google Play have long had leaderboards for the most downloaded and lucrative apps, there hasn&#8217;t been that much transparency around engagement after the download.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.heyzap.com">Heyzap</a>, a Union Square Ventures-backed startup that runs a mobile gaming network, has stepped in and decided to build one. The startup, which was founded about four years ago and originally centered around Flash games, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/10/12/new-heyzap-update-puts-your-favorite-android-games-up-front/">has moved onto mobile platforms</a> (pretty much like every other game developer over the past few years). They have an app on Android with about 10 million installs that lets gamers add friends in their favorite titles and share tips and badges.</p>
<p>From those 10 million installs, they say they&#8217;ve been able to gauge the size of different developers&#8217; active userbases. So from that, <a target="_blank" href="http://trends.heyzap.com">they&#8217;ve launched Heyzap Trends</a>, a live leaderboard that estimates active usage. The standard iOS and Google leaderboards mainly focus on downloads or installs and then revenue over specific time periods (although Google Play&#8217;s rankings are said to factor in some engagement data).   </p>
<p>They say they get play data for about 80,000 games on the Android platform, which is shared by people who have the Heyzap app and are logged into it.</p>
<p>Even games that aren&#8217;t integrated into Heyzap&#8217;s network get their play data recorded by this, said co-founder Immad Akhund. That&#8217;s partially because of Android&#8217;s open nature.</p>
<p>&#8220;The openness of the Android OS is allowing for more unique and interesting experiences for users,&#8221; he said in an e-mail. &#8220;I think this is going to be a trend going forward as mobile apps reach maturity and differentiate through deeper experiences hooked in to the OS layer.&#8221; (As a sidenote, Facebook&#8217;s Home app is a perfect example of this openness.)</p>
<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/heyzap-trends/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-4-55-58-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-800320"></a><br />
To me, the data seems reasonable. Heyzap&#8217;s leaderboard, for example, says that King, the European arcade gaming company, has 54.7 million monthly active users. Last month, King <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/27/king-candy-crush-saga/">said it has 49 million monthly actives on smartphones and tablets, including iOS</a>.</p>
<p>Similarly, Storm8, a Silicon Valley-based freemium gaming company that runs a label called TeamLava, has about 14.2 million daily active users, according to the leaderboard. <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/22/mobile-game-developer-storm8-crosses-10m-users-every-day/">Storm8 said it had 10 million daily actives back in January.</a></p>
<p>Also, Subway surfers apparently has 7.6 million daily actives on Android and its maker, the Danish developer Kiloo, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/09/kiloo-subway-surfers/">said it had 26.5 million daily actives last month on both iOS and Android.</a></p>
<p>Just to make a note, Heyzap&#8217;s numbers are non de-duplicated. That means if the same person plays more than one game from a single developer, they&#8217;re counted more than once. It&#8217;s not an unusual metric: even when Zynga reports daily actives in its quarterly earnings reports, those figures are not de-duped. Instead, they report a separate metric called &#8220;monthly unique users,&#8221; that doesn&#8217;t double count people. </p>
<p>Akhund said they might do non de-duped counts in the future. We &#8220;&#8230;felt for now it made sense to count the user twice as it is double the engagement and monetization opportunity,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Heyzap is backed by $8 million in funding from Y Combinator, Union Square Ventures, Naval Ravikant, Joshua Schachter, Christina Brodbeck, Founder Collective and Qualcomm Ventures. This &#8220;Trends&#8221; project faces off against other companies like Sequoia-backed Onavo, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/08/onavo-insights/">which is trying to do a &#8220;Quantcast for mobile apps&#8221; via active usage data</a> they collect through mobile data compression apps. They are for now, iOS only. Heyzap Trends, in contrast, is games only.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800101/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=RHMHpDjnJeo:J1E6gDrs3NE:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=RHMHpDjnJeo:J1E6gDrs3NE:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=RHMHpDjnJeo:J1E6gDrs3NE:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=RHMHpDjnJeo:J1E6gDrs3NE:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=RHMHpDjnJeo:J1E6gDrs3NE:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=RHMHpDjnJeo:J1E6gDrs3NE:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=RHMHpDjnJeo:J1E6gDrs3NE:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=RHMHpDjnJeo:J1E6gDrs3NE:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/RHMHpDjnJeo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/heyzap-trends/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/heyzap-logo.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/heyzap-logo.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">heyzap logo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c4dad53149dd9c712936e1b27c1c1e9f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kimmaicutler</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-4-55-42-pm.png?w=338" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 4.55.42 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-4-55-58-pm.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-04-16 at 4.55.58 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/heyzap-trends/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook Tests Its First Graph Search Ads, But They Aren't Targeted To Your Queries</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/7hj6a4Q8gOE/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/facebook-graph-search-ads/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Josh Constine</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800291</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/facebook-graph-search-ads.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Facebook Graph Search Ads" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Investors hope Facebook will eventually sell lucrative demand-fulfillment search ads, but it's starting conservatively. Today it begins a small test of its first ads on Graph Search, but they're not targeted to your search queries. Instead, they use standard Facebook targeting and retargeting, look like its sidebar ads, and appear at the bottom of the page, and only if there's over one page of results]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/facebook-graph-search-ads.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Facebook Graph Search Ads" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Investors hope Facebook will eventually sell lucrative demand-fulfillment search ads, but it&#8217;s starting conservatively. Today it begins a small test of its first ads on Graph Search, but they&#8217;re not targeted to your search queries. Instead, they use standard Facebook targeting and retargeting, look like its sidebar ads, and appear at the bottom of the page &#8212; and only if there is more than one page of results.</p>
<p>Mark Zuckerberg <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/15/graph-search-ads/">hinted that ads would come to Graph Search</a> when he answered my question about monetization at the launch event for the new internal search engine for people, places, and interests. He said “You build a good business by building something people want,” but noted that Facebook’s old search typeahead ads “extend quite nicely to this.” Zuckerberg stressed that user experience comes first at Facebook, but admitted search ads “could potentially be a business over time.”</p>
<p>But instead of search typeahead ads that let companies appear above their competitors or related businesses in the drop-down menu of real-time Facebook search results, the first Graph Search ads are really just a new placement. For now they&#8217;ll only appear to a small subset of users who have Graph Search, which itself is only rolled out to a small fraction of Facebook&#8217;s full user base. When people in the test do a Graph Search and wind up on the results page, if there are more results than will fit on one page, they&#8217;ll see two or three ads in a row below the fold and just before the second page of results auto load. The ads look like Facebook&#8217;s sidebar units with a headline, thumbnail image, body text, and that link to an on- or off-Facebook destination.</p>
<p>The Graph Search ads rely on the same targeting techniques as most of Facebook&#8217;s ads: biographical characteristics like age, gender, current city, and employer; Likes, Open Graph activity, and retargeting based on cookies from websites they&#8217;ve recently visited.</p>
<p>If the tests go well and the ads lead to clicks and brand lift, they&#8217;ll likely be rolled out to all Graph Search users.</p>
<p></p>
<p>The question remains whether Facebook will then start letting advertisers target based on the keywords people search. If combined with Facebook&#8217;s other targeting techniques, Graph Search ads could let businesses reach users as they&#8217;re making a decision about what restaurant, retail store, or professional service to go to. Right now Graph Search ads can only be targeted by demographic, interest, and browsing history, but eventually you might get ads for dentists when you search for &#8220;Dentists nearby.&#8221;</p>
<p>This bottom part of the purchase funnel is worth a lot more than the demand generation top of the funnel because the ads can be directly linked to purchases and return on investment. That would let Facebook charge more for them, and gain access to huge budgets reserved for Google and other search advertising. It&#8217;s this new category of ads, rather than subtle improvements to its existing revenue streams, that really get investors excited and could finally pull $FB (which closed today at $26.92) above its $38 IPO price.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800291/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7hj6a4Q8gOE:0wzhGoaokTY:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7hj6a4Q8gOE:0wzhGoaokTY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7hj6a4Q8gOE:0wzhGoaokTY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7hj6a4Q8gOE:0wzhGoaokTY:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=7hj6a4Q8gOE:0wzhGoaokTY:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7hj6a4Q8gOE:0wzhGoaokTY:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=7hj6a4Q8gOE:0wzhGoaokTY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7hj6a4Q8gOE:0wzhGoaokTY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/7hj6a4Q8gOE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/facebook-graph-search-ads/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/facebook-graph-search-ads.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/facebook-graph-search-ads.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Facebook Graph Search Ads</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fd3b857e7f0024396cdbd36c4c102a5d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">joshsc</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/fb-graph-funnel-done-finished-end.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">FB Graph Funnel Done Finished End</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/facebook-graph-search-ads/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Live On 17 Campuses, Endorse.me Launches A Private Platform To Let Students &amp; Employers Connect, Share Confidential Info</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/ATrdL6pr8G4/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/live-on-17-campuses-endorse-me-launches-a-private-platform-to-let-students-employers-connect-share-confidential-info/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 23:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rip Empson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Endorse.me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recruiting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=796746</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-3-43-33-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen shot 2013-04-16 at 3.43.33 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />It's a tough job market out there for college job applicants, and students are looking for any way that can help them stand out from the crowd. While an increasing number of students look to apply to jobs online, the information that might give students at improving their candidacy and landing a job isn't something they want to share publicly, it's confidential. As a result, most of this confidential information -- whether it be recommendations from professors or expiring job offers -- is shared offline.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-3-43-33-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen shot 2013-04-16 at 3.43.33 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>It&#8217;s a tough job market out there for college job applicants, and students are looking for anything that can help them stand out from the crowd. While an increasing number of students look to apply to jobs online, the information that might give students a shot at improving their candidacy and landing a job isn&#8217;t something they want to share publicly, it&#8217;s confidential. As a result, most of this confidential information &#8212; whether it be recommendations from professors or expiring job offers &#8212; is shared offline.</p>
<p>James Ingallinera and Trey Griffith founded <a target="_blank" href="https://endorse.me/employers">Endorse.me</a> last year to give college jobseekers a secure, online platform through which they can share confidential information with prospective employers, and, in turn, give companies a better way to identify and hire top collegiate talent. Endorse.me is officially launching today at 17 campuses across the U.S., including Stanford, Notre Dame, Cornell, Yale, Harvard, Duke, Dartmouth, UVA, Berkeley and Brown, to name a few, with plans to expand to more colleges in the upcoming academic year.</p>
<p>The fundamental idea behind Endorse.me, Ingallinera tells us, came from his years of experience working in the financial sector. Today, with so many students and recent graduates struggling to find work &#8212; and the influx of job applications &#8212; the standard, one-page resume is no longer enough. It&#8217;s the same philosophy behind services <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/03/09/resumes-are-bullshit-hireart-is-better/">like HireArt</a> and many more.</p>
<p>Ingallinera says that, today, students are looking for ways to stand out in applying for their dream jobs, and to share the kind of information that carries more weight than the standard CV. To do this, students are asked to apply to Endorse.me and, once approved, they can add their resume, recommendations from professors and expiring job offers to their confidential profiles. Students can then create a list of their chosen employers and, after reaching out to professors for recommendations, they can choose the companies with which they share that information.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-4-43-41-pm.png"></a>Endorse.me will then notify those companies of the student&#8217;s interest, giving them a complete list of all the students looking to apply to help get their profile information in front of hiring managers. Students can also update their job status on their profile to give employers of interest an opportunity to see interview and job offers they&#8217;re receiving &#8212; the idea being to allow them to unlock further opportunities once companies see that their competitors are interested.</p>
<p>In turn, students can upload their resume and list the firms they&#8217;re interested in, so that they are targeted by them throughout the coming year when new job opportunities arise, regardless of whether the company is actively recruiting at their college.</p>
<p>On the flip side, the more students it attracts, the more value Endorse.me thinks that it can have for employers. Hiring managers can use the platform to view the top-ranked students in their industry, according to their supervisors and professors, which Ingallinera says can be a stronger indicator of on-the-job performance than a one-page resume. By allowing students to express intent and share job offers, Endorse.me allows employers to see where students stand in the hiring process with their competitors, and gain access to and view profiles and resumes year-round.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-4-44-16-pm.png"></a>At launch, the founders tell us, Endorse.me is targeting the financial and technology sectors specifically, but plans to expand its scope in the coming year. That means, at this point, hiring managers from companies like 10gen, Airbnb, Blackstone, Citi, Codecademy, Credit Suisse, Eventbrite, General Catalyst, HubSpot, Indiegogo, Mozilla, Pinterest, Rackspace, Salesforce.com, Spotify, Twitter and Zaarly are currently on Endorse.me and looking for candidates.</p>
<p>Today, Endorse.me is available exclusively as a cloud-based online service, but over the summer, the startup plans to begin developing mobile apps, which it expects to have ready in the fall. The service is currently free for students, employers, and all those intermediaries who choose to write recommendations for students. Again, the service is currently free for employers, but as the startup looks to monetize down the road, it will eventually began charging employers for access to student info.</p>
<p>Endorse.me raised a small round of $300K in seed capital last year, and will look to begin raising its Series A later this fall.</p>
<p>For more, <a target="_blank" href="https://endorse.me/employers">find Endorse.me at home here.</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/796746/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=ATrdL6pr8G4:lD6wPnR8pNQ:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=ATrdL6pr8G4:lD6wPnR8pNQ:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=ATrdL6pr8G4:lD6wPnR8pNQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=ATrdL6pr8G4:lD6wPnR8pNQ:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=ATrdL6pr8G4:lD6wPnR8pNQ:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=ATrdL6pr8G4:lD6wPnR8pNQ:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=ATrdL6pr8G4:lD6wPnR8pNQ:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=ATrdL6pr8G4:lD6wPnR8pNQ:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/ATrdL6pr8G4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/live-on-17-campuses-endorse-me-launches-a-private-platform-to-let-students-employers-connect-share-confidential-info/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-3-43-33-pm.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-3-43-33-pm.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2013-04-16 at 3.43.33 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a94f6b72a8ee7342e862c1c9d6c5b826?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rempson8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-4-43-41-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2013-04-16 at 4.43.41 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-16-at-4-44-16-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2013-04-16 at 4.44.16 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/live-on-17-campuses-endorse-me-launches-a-private-platform-to-let-students-employers-connect-share-confidential-info/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Last GroupSpaces Founder Calls It A Day After 7 Years, Departs To Build Stripe In The UK</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/DrxKPkC7m0w/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/last-groupspaces-founder-calls-it-a-day-after-7-years-departs-to-build-stripe-in-the-uk/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 23:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mike Butcher</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groupspaces]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800288</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/groupspaces.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="GroupSpaces" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Tonight in the UK there came a moment which you might call the end of an era in the UK tech startup scene. One of the first of the 'new wave' of startups from the mid-2000s lost its last founder, as Andy Young (pictured left), co-founder of the group management startup <a target="_blank" href="http://GroupSpaces.com">GroupSpaces</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://insomanic.me.uk/post/48127029333/im-joining-stripe">announced</a> he was leaving to join the payments starts Stripe, and will be a core part of its "expansion into the UK and beyond". Evidently he came to this decision - after seven years of building the startup - that GroupSpaces was not about to fulfil the hopes of its founders as the next big thing in managing group activities, and he has written a <a target="_blank" href="http://insomanic.me.uk/post/48136679276/looking-back-at-7-years-with-my-startup-groupspaces">long post-mortem</a> to that effect.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/groupspaces.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="GroupSpaces" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Tonight there came a moment that you might call the end of an era in the U.K. tech startup scene. One of the first of the &#8216;new wave&#8217; of startups from the mid-2000s lost its last founder, as Andy Young (pictured left), co-founder of the group management startup <a target="_blank" href="http://GroupSpaces.com">GroupSpaces</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://insomanic.me.uk/post/48127029333/im-joining-stripe">announced</a> he was leaving to join the payments startup Stripe to be a core part of its &#8220;expansion into the U.K. and beyond.&#8221; Evidently he came to this decision &#8211; after seven years of building the startup &#8211; that GroupSpaces was not about to fulfill the hopes of its founders as the next big thing in managing group activities, and he has written a <a target="_blank" href="http://insomanic.me.uk/post/48136679276/looking-back-at-7-years-with-my-startup-groupspaces">long post-mortem</a> to that effect.</p>
<p>His co-founder David Langer <a target="_blank" href="http://davidlanger.co.uk/2012/05/14/my-next-chapter/">already departed</a> last May to start a new venture, called <a target="_blank" href="http://invite.gethasty.com/">Hasty</a>, in SF.</p>
<p>GroupSpaces was founded by the two young men in their college dorm and went on to raise money from both U.K. and U.S. institutional investors.</p>
<p>Young says GroupSpaces will continue to operate &#8220;as a sustainable small business&#8221; and while he is &#8220;hugely proud of the contribution and impact we’ve made&#8221; and remains &#8220;dedicated to seeing GroupSpaces continue to thrive and achieve the best it can&#8221; he admits that growth had been &#8220;slower than we hoped in financial returns&#8221; and did not become the &#8220;proverbial billion dollar success&#8221; as they&#8217;d hoped. It will now be managed by existing employees until a new strategy is put in place to partner or exit.</p>
<p>GroupSpaces raised $1.3 million in a Series A round from Index Ventures, 500 Startups and a number of high-profile Angels, including Chris Sacca &#8211; and all this during the <em>last</em> Series A crunch of 2010. However, despite reaching well over half a million users, and being used by many professional associations and sports clubs, it never managed to create that high-growth business required by VC investment. It&#8217;s something Young pores over in detail in his post.</p>
<p>Some highlights include: how they failed to appreciate &#8220;a lack of product-market fit as we moved into new markets,&#8221; insufficient focus, a confused strategy, premature scaling and &#8220;moving too slowly after we raised our Series A.&#8221;</p>
<p>However, they did create a real business that &#8220;provides significant value to our many loyal users, and more continue to sign up as customers each day&#8221; and who &#8220;currently rely on the unhappy marriage of a Yahoo/Google Group coupled with an Excel spreadsheet/google doc for member records, in addition to their own website and other services for events or payments.&#8221;</p>
<p>I think many observers would agree with that statement.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s an interview I did with them two years ago:</p>
<script type="text/javascript" src="http://pshared.5min.com/Scripts/PlayerSeed.js?sid=577&#038;width=640&#038;height=450&#038;colorPallet=%230A9600&#038;hasCompanion=false&#038;relatedMode=2&#038;videoControlDisplayColor=%23000000&#038;playList=517279625&#038;shuffle=0&#038;videoGroupID=133503&#038;autoStart=false&#038;playerActions=16407"></script>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800288/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=DrxKPkC7m0w:m1noQU5pt6I:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=DrxKPkC7m0w:m1noQU5pt6I:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=DrxKPkC7m0w:m1noQU5pt6I:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=DrxKPkC7m0w:m1noQU5pt6I:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=DrxKPkC7m0w:m1noQU5pt6I:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=DrxKPkC7m0w:m1noQU5pt6I:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=DrxKPkC7m0w:m1noQU5pt6I:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=DrxKPkC7m0w:m1noQU5pt6I:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/DrxKPkC7m0w" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/last-groupspaces-founder-calls-it-a-day-after-7-years-departs-to-build-stripe-in-the-uk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/groupspaces.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/groupspaces.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">GroupSpaces</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ef4a4ab87c72738ed187e21de55b2fc6?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mike-butcher</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/last-groupspaces-founder-calls-it-a-day-after-7-years-departs-to-build-stripe-in-the-uk/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Snapchat Experiences Spammy Growing Pains After Passing 150M Snaps Sent Per Day</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/W0HlU0b-sxw/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/snapchat-experiences-spammy-growing-pains-after-passing-150m-snaps-sent-per-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 23:36:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jordan Crook</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snapchat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evan Spiegel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800280</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/snapchat.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="SnapChat" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Picture-messaging sensation Snapchat seems to experiencing some growing pains. CEO and co-founder Evan Spiegel said today that over <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/snapchat-now-sees-150m-images-shared-each-day-but-questions-of-viability-still-linger/">150 million pictures a day</a> flow through the auto-destructing photo-sharing service, but as the service gets bigger and gains more attention, the worst parts of the Internet are sure to follow. 

According to <a target="_blank" href="http://blog.snapchat.com/post/48123758611/snap-spam-ew">a post on the company blog</a>, some Snapchatters experienced a bit of a spam attack this morning from someone who appears to have created multiple accounts and spam to Snapchatters with accounts marked as public. According <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/search?q=snapchat%20naked%20spam&#38;src=typd">to Twitter</a>, that spam seems to be nude-flavored. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/snapchat.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="SnapChat" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Picture-messaging sensation Snapchat seems to experiencing some growing pains. CEO and co-founder Evan Spiegel said today that over <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/snapchat-now-sees-150m-images-shared-each-day-but-questions-of-viability-still-linger/">150 million pictures a day</a> flow through the auto-destructing photo-sharing service, but as the service gets bigger and gains more attention, the worst parts of the Internet are sure to follow.</p>
<p>According to <a target="_blank" href="http://blog.snapchat.com/post/48123758611/snap-spam-ew">a post on the company blog</a>, some Snapchatters experienced a bit of a spam attack this morning from someone who appears to have created multiple accounts and spam to Snapchatters with accounts marked as public. According <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/search?q=snapchat%20naked%20spam&amp;src=typd">to Twitter</a>, that spam seems to be nude-flavored.</p>
<p>Snapchat offers users two security options. You can receive Snaps from &#8220;only friends,&#8221; which means you&#8217;ve accepted them as a friend or added them yourself, or you can accept snaps from everyone.</p>
<p>Snapchat suggests using the private mode for now while the team comes up with a long-term fix for the issue, which is common among social services with quickly growing audiences.</p>
<p>When Snapchat first heard about the spam, the company turned off account creation entirely so that no new users could join the service or create accounts, spam or otherwise. They also shut down snaps sent between public accounts until the problem accounts were terminated.</p>
<p>Obviously, this is a short-term solution to a long-time problem, but Spiegel owns up to that in the blog post.</p>
<blockquote><p>Spam is a problem on many services with large audiences. We know spammers totally suck and we’re working on a long term solution to prevent spam from entering your feed. In the meantime, please adjust your settings to determine who can send you snaps. For a spam-free experience we recommend “Only My Friends”  </p></blockquote>
<p>A few months after Snapchat started to gain traction, many labeled the app as a &#8220;sexting&#8221; service, since the notion of sharing images that don&#8217;t last is relatively new. That general concern has died down though, as <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/12/26/inside-snapchat-the-little-photo-sharing-app-that-launched-a-sexting-scare/">common sense</a> seems to prove that all 150 million messages sent through the service each day (most of which are sent during the day time) can&#8217;t possibly be nudies.</p>
<p>This latest nude spammer, however, does bring up the issue of unwanted sexts as opposed to wanted sexts. And that&#8217;s just the latest in a line of distractions for the company, including incredibly rapid growth, potential revenue streams, and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/27/stanford-grad-files-lawsuit-claiming-he-came-up-with-snapchat-snapchat-calls-lawsuit-devoid-of-merit/">a lawsuit</a> from a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/07/snapchat-lawsui/">former Stanford classmate</a> who claims to have come up with the idea.</p>
<p>But distractions aside, it&#8217;s hard to argue with a service that has users sending <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/snapchat-now-sees-150m-images-shared-each-day-but-questions-of-viability-still-linger/">150 million snaps per day</a>. Consider this: Instagram users post an average of 40 million pictures a day.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800280/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=W0HlU0b-sxw:BKoIJS4Xy40:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=W0HlU0b-sxw:BKoIJS4Xy40:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=W0HlU0b-sxw:BKoIJS4Xy40:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=W0HlU0b-sxw:BKoIJS4Xy40:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=W0HlU0b-sxw:BKoIJS4Xy40:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=W0HlU0b-sxw:BKoIJS4Xy40:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=W0HlU0b-sxw:BKoIJS4Xy40:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=W0HlU0b-sxw:BKoIJS4Xy40:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/W0HlU0b-sxw" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/snapchat-experiences-spammy-growing-pains-after-passing-150m-snaps-sent-per-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/snapchat.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/snapchat.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SnapChat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/123a4c264172746af556b0c74c72b308?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">biggsismyboss</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/snapchat-experiences-spammy-growing-pains-after-passing-150m-snaps-sent-per-day/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Tallygram, OkCupid's Foray Into Friend Finding On Facebook, Hits The Deadpool</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/h1HAGnoSZMY/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/tallygram-okcupids-foray-into-friend-finding-on-facebook-hits-the-deadpool/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 23:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ingrid Lunden</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OKCupid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tallygram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DEADPOOL]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800271</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-17-at-00-35-05.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="tallygram okcupid" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><a target="_blank" href="http://www.tallygram.com">Tallygram</a>, a Facebook-based friend finding app created by dating site <a target="_blank" href="http://www.okcupid.com">OKCupid</a>, has shut down, saying that the community never grew large enough to sustain the site. Tallygram, which originally billed itself as "<a target="_blank" href="http://www.itworld.com/it-management/341058/tallygram-dating-service-people-you-dont-want-sleep-except-those-you-do">a better way to surf Facebook</a>," first opened for business in <a target="_blank" href="http://onlinedatingpost.com/archives/2012/11/okcupid-launches-people-discovery-service-tallygram/">November 2012</a>. 
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-17-at-00-35-05.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="tallygram okcupid" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.tallygram.com">Tallygram</a>, a Facebook-based friend-finding app created by dating site <a target="_blank" href="http://www.okcupid.com">OkCupid</a>, has shut down, saying that the community never grew large enough to sustain the site. Tallygram, which originally billed itself as &#8220;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.itworld.com/it-management/341058/tallygram-dating-service-people-you-dont-want-sleep-except-those-you-do">a better way to surf Facebook</a>,&#8221; first opened for business in <a target="_blank" href="http://onlinedatingpost.com/archives/2012/11/okcupid-launches-people-discovery-service-tallygram/">November 2012</a>.</p>
<p>Now the site, in a note to existing users (below), is referring to itself as an &#8220;experiment.&#8221; Those existing users have an option to <a target="_blank" href="http://tallygram.us6.list-manage1.com/track/click?u=95e4104a778bb042da5bc59d9&amp;id=13e57b608a&amp;e=c6621b3769">export their data</a> from the service by May 15.</p>
<p>With sites like Facebook continuing to build out its own ways of mining its massive database of users and information, such as Graph Search, and many other ways to discover new people (three examples are Badoo, OkCupid and Tinder, which like OkCupid is also owned by IAC) it&#8217;s perhaps not too surprising that Tallygram found it hard to pick up traction.</p>
<p>The service, which came out of OkCupid Labs, had a similar concept behind it as OkCupid, founded by four mathematics grads from Harvard: &#8220;We use math to figure out who your friends or enemies are. See what they really think,&#8221; is how the described itself on its <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/tallygram">Twitter feed</a>.</p>
<p>That process involved helping identify like-minded souls using algorithms combined with some parameters that users set themselves by answering questions about their feelings about things like cats, patent litigation, and their concept of themselves. It then matched this up with other users&#8217; data and their Facebook profiles to find friends of friends &#8212; interesting-enough sounding tech, and relevant to how many interact and meet today, so it may end up somewhere else within the company.</p>
<p>Full statement from Tallygram below:</p>
<blockquote><p>We’re sad to say that, after working on Tallygram for the past year, we’ve decided to put our experiment to rest. We hope you had as much fun using it as we did building it, but the community never grew large enough to sustain the site. We really appreciate you giving the site a shot.</p>
<p>If you want to keep an archive of the answers you&#8217;ve written on Tallygram, we’ve built an exporter so you can <a target="_blank" href="http://tallygram.us6.list-manage1.com/track/click?u=95e4104a778bb042da5bc59d9&amp;id=13e57b608a&amp;e=c6621b3769">download all the questions you’ve answered</a>. The site and archive tool will remain up until May 15, 2013.</p>
<p>While we&#8217;re never happy to shut down a product, <a target="_blank" href="http://tallygram.us6.list-manage2.com/track/click?u=95e4104a778bb042da5bc59d9&amp;id=4971543116&amp;e=c6621b3769">OkCupid Labs</a> soldiers on. We&#8217;re already hard at work on more fun experiments. You can <a target="_blank" href="http://tallygram.us6.list-manage1.com/track/click?u=95e4104a778bb042da5bc59d9&amp;id=73b63b78e6&amp;e=c6621b3769">explore the projects</a> that are already live or sign up to be an <a target="_blank" href="http://tallygram.us6.list-manage.com/track/click?u=95e4104a778bb042da5bc59d9&amp;id=3e94b46eee&amp;e=c6621b3769">OkCupid Labs Alpha Tester</a> and be the first to know about new projects. We need your help to go from potential awesomeness to actual awesomeness.</p></blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800271/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=h1HAGnoSZMY:2JE9SgJwakY:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=h1HAGnoSZMY:2JE9SgJwakY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=h1HAGnoSZMY:2JE9SgJwakY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=h1HAGnoSZMY:2JE9SgJwakY:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=h1HAGnoSZMY:2JE9SgJwakY:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=h1HAGnoSZMY:2JE9SgJwakY:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=h1HAGnoSZMY:2JE9SgJwakY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=h1HAGnoSZMY:2JE9SgJwakY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/h1HAGnoSZMY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/tallygram-okcupids-foray-into-friend-finding-on-facebook-hits-the-deadpool/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-17-at-00-35-05.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-17-at-00-35-05.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallygram okcupid</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6648ec93043f0f368091adece63c6d52?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ingridlunden</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/tallygram-okcupids-foray-into-friend-finding-on-facebook-hits-the-deadpool/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Yahoo CEO Marissa Mayer Unveils The First Results Of Its Hot New Summly Acquisition</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/B1SHMXCr7aM/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/yahoo-ceo-marissa-meyer-unveils-the-first-results-of-its-hot-new-summly-acquisition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 22:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ingrid Lunden</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yahoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Summly]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=800245</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/marissamayer.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="marissamayer" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />In March, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.yahoo.com">Yahoo</a> made a big splash in its already dazzling list of acquisitions when it <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/25/yahoo-acquires-information-gathering-startup-summly/">acquired Summly</a>, a UK-based mobile startup led by 17-year-old founder Nick D'Aloisio that summarizes long texts to make them easier to read on mobile screens. Today, Yahoo CEO Marissa Mayer unveiled the first official fruit of that acquisition: 
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/marissamayer.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="marissamayer" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>In March, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.yahoo.com">Yahoo</a> made a big splash in its already dazzling list of acquisitions when it <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/25/yahoo-acquires-information-gathering-startup-summly/">acquired Summly</a>, a UK-based mobile startup led by 17-year-old founder Nick D&#8217;Aloisio that summarizes long texts to make them easier to read on mobile screens. Today, Yahoo CEO Marissa Mayer unveiled the first official fruit of that acquisition: </p>
<p>A 160-word summary of her hour-long, 2013 Q1 earnings presentation (original length, 2,000+ words). </p>
<p>So for those of you who don&#8217;t have the time or inclination to read the whole results transcript, or one of the many <a target="_blank" href="http://www.techmeme.com/130416/p43#a130416p43">reports covering the earnings</a>, but are still interested in what&#8217;s going on at Yahoo, here it is:</p>
<blockquote><p>I’m pleased with the continued execution I see every day &#8212; our teams have been working very hard, especially in Q1.  As a result of these initiatives and many others, the talent is undeniable &#8212; today, more applicants want to work at Yahoo, and more employees are staying.  These teams bring an incredible mix of engineering and technical talent, which will help us accelerate our efforts in mobile development and contentpersonalization.The teams are already moving quickly to amplify the entrepreneurial spirit that&#8217;s so prevalent at Yahoo right now.<br />
Designed to be more intuitive and personal, the new Yahoo experience is all about users&#8217; interests and preferences. Yahoo is a consumer Internet company, and the consumer Internet is a growth industry. We’re on course to do what we said we would do &#8212; stabilize, and grow with the market.
</p></blockquote>
<p>[Did not make the cut: Yahoo's advertising revenue declines; the fact that search has outstripped display revenues; and that Yahoo currently has 300 million monthly active users on mobile as it gears up for a bigger push on the platform.]</p>
<p>In addition to Summly, which was acquired reportedly for <a target="_blank" href="http://allthingsd.com/20130325/yahoo-acquires-hipster-mobile-news-reader-summly-like-we-said-it-might/">$30 million</a>, Yahoo in the last quarter also bought <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/22/yahoo-buys-snip-it-10-million/">Snip.it</a>, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/12/yahoo-acquires-mobile-nearby-iphone-and-web-app-alike/">Alike</a> and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/yahoo-acquires-jybe/">Jybe</a>, &#8220;accelerating the Company&#8217;s efforts to build world-class technology and engineering teams in mobile and personalization.&#8221; That&#8217;s in addition to the wider push the company has also made to <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/marissa-mayer-on-yahoo-talent/">hold on to its own key talent</a> and appoint a new raft of executives. It now has 11,300 employees on the books.</p>
<p>Read our full Yahoo earnings report <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/yahoo-q1-2013/">here</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/800245/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=B1SHMXCr7aM:wxm4jUmyZBk:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=B1SHMXCr7aM:wxm4jUmyZBk:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=B1SHMXCr7aM:wxm4jUmyZBk:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=B1SHMXCr7aM:wxm4jUmyZBk:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=B1SHMXCr7aM:wxm4jUmyZBk:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=B1SHMXCr7aM:wxm4jUmyZBk:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=B1SHMXCr7aM:wxm4jUmyZBk:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=B1SHMXCr7aM:wxm4jUmyZBk:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/B1SHMXCr7aM" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/yahoo-ceo-marissa-meyer-unveils-the-first-results-of-its-hot-new-summly-acquisition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/marissamayer.jpg?w=105" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/marissamayer.jpg?w=105" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">marissamayer</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6648ec93043f0f368091adece63c6d52?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ingridlunden</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/16/yahoo-ceo-marissa-meyer-unveils-the-first-results-of-its-hot-new-summly-acquisition/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss>
