<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	
	<link>http://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>TechCrunch is a group-edited blog that profiles the companies, products and events defining and transforming the new web.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:29:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain="techcrunch.com" port="80" path="/?rsscloud=notify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
<image><link>http://www.techcrunch.com</link><url>http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/themes/techcrunchmu/images/techcrunch_logo.png</url><title>TechCrunch</title></image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://techcrunch.com/osd.xml" title="TechCrunch" />
	
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" /><feedburner:info uri="techcrunch" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://techcrunch.com/?pushpress=hub" /><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://add.my.yahoo.com/rss?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://us.i1.yimg.com/us.yimg.com/i/us/my/addtomyyahoo4.gif">Subscribe with My Yahoo!</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.newsgator.com/ngs/subscriber/subext.aspx?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.newsgator.com/images/ngsub1.gif">Subscribe with NewsGator</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://feeds.my.aol.com/add.jsp?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://o.aolcdn.com/favorites.my.aol.com/webmaster/ffclient/webroot/locale/en-US/images/myAOLButtonSmall.gif">Subscribe with My AOL</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.bloglines.com/sub/http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" src="http://www.bloglines.com/images/sub_modern11.gif">Subscribe with Bloglines</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.netvibes.com/subscribe.php?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.netvibes.com/img/add2netvibes.gif">Subscribe with Netvibes</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://fusion.google.com/add?feedurl=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://buttons.googlesyndication.com/fusion/add.gif">Subscribe with Google</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.pageflakes.com/subscribe.aspx?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.pageflakes.com/ImageFile.ashx?instanceId=Static_4&amp;fileName=ATP_blu_91x17.gif">Subscribe with Pageflakes</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item>
		<title>Bing Gordon's Founder Checklist: Animal Energy, Blind Confidence, And A Toupee.</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/AbL6vpMk9Ko/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/30/animal-energy-blind-confidence-and-a-toupee-what-bing-gordon-says-your-startup-needs-for-success/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Derek Andersen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788628</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Editor’s note: Derek Andersen is the founder of Startup Grind, a 40-city community bringing the global startup world together while educating, inspiring, and connecting entrepreneurs. As an Electronic Arts&#8217; intern eight years ago, I asked Bing Gordon then the chief creative officer and the only remaining early founding team member, a question about vision. “How can I know where the puck is going to be?” While he delivered a satisfactory response, two weeks later I received an email from Bing saying, “I answered that question poorly a few weeks and I wanted to try again.” A few weeks ago Bing joined me at Startup Grind in Silicon Valley where he delivered some videogame history and founder advice. In 2010 Mark Pincus called KPCB general partner Bing Gordon (look for a bald guy on the front row) one of the world’s “great CEO coaches” supporting founders on the boards of companies like Amazon, Zynga, Klout, and Zazzle. Here are some excepts from our recent interview. Derek: Tell us about your family and where you grew up? BING: So I grew up in a suburb of Detroit.  My dad was a first generation Scotsman and his dad was a janitor.  And he was somebody that believed the grass was always greener and didn’t have, kind of, context or resources.  Thanks, Dad!  We were the first to move in to a subdivision built out of farmlands surrounding Detroit, so I grew up kind of in the creek.  Playing sports with my brother who remembers growing up in the House of Pain.  So I had a good Midwestern upbringing.  I didn’t work in an office before going to Stanford business school, but I did think I was a pretty damn good teenage caddy. I played hockey and lacrosse at the university level and played both, kind of, for most of my adult life. Derek: What was your plan heading to college? BING: Well I went to Yale thinking I was going to be a math major and a writer, and I got there and Yale was lousy at math and it seemed socially irrelevant, so I kind of became an athlete-near-college-dropout.  I realized I was flunking a third of my classes going into the final.  My proud accomplishments in college other than sports achievements was I wrote poetry.  Kind of light verse, in a coffee shop, and Peter Faulk when he was doing Columbo came, and liked it so much he took me out drinking that]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><br />
<a href="http://techcrunch.com/?attachment_id=788646" rel="attachment wp-att-788646"></a>Editor’s note: </strong><a target="_blank" href="http://twitter.com/derekjandersen">Derek Andersen</a><em> is the founder of </em><a target="_blank" href="http://startupgrind.com/about-us/">Startup Grind</a><em>, a 40-city community bringing the global startup world together while educating, inspiring, and connecting entrepreneurs</em><em>.</em></p>
<p>As an Electronic Arts&#8217; intern eight years ago, I asked Bing Gordon then the chief creative officer and the only remaining early founding team member, a question about vision. “How can I know where the puck is going to be?” While he delivered a satisfactory response, two weeks later I received an email from Bing saying, “I answered that question poorly a few weeks and I wanted to try again.” A few weeks ago Bing joined me at <a target="_blank" href="http://startupgrind.com/about-us/">Startup Grind</a> in Silicon Valley where he delivered some videogame history and founder advice.</p>
<p>In 2010 <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G-c8gGZJ-28&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=10m20s">Mark Pincus called KPCB general partner Bing Gordon</a> (look for a bald guy on the front row) one of the world’s “great CEO coaches” supporting founders on the boards of companies like Amazon, Zynga, Klout, and Zazzle. Here are some excepts from our recent <a target="_blank" href="http://startupgrind.com/2013/03/bing-gordon-partner-kpcb-startup-grind-interview-full-transcript/">interview</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Derek: Tell us about your family and where you grew up?</strong></p>
<p><strong>BING</strong>: So I grew up in a suburb of Detroit.  My dad was a first generation Scotsman and his dad was a janitor.  And he was somebody that believed the grass was always greener and didn’t have, kind of, context or resources.  Thanks, Dad!  We were the first to move in to a subdivision built out of farmlands surrounding Detroit, so I grew up kind of in the creek.  Playing sports with my brother who remembers growing up in the <em>House of Pain</em>.  So I had a good Midwestern upbringing.  I didn’t work in an office before going to Stanford business school, but I did think I was a pretty damn good teenage caddy. I played hockey and lacrosse at the university level and played both, kind of, for most of my adult life.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/DL0XW0MBF7s?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p><strong>Derek: What was your plan heading to college?</strong></p>
<p><strong>BING</strong>: Well I went to Yale thinking I was going to be a math major and a writer, and I got there and Yale was lousy at math and it seemed socially irrelevant, so I kind of became an athlete-near-college-dropout.  I realized I was flunking a third of my classes going into the final.  My proud accomplishments in college other than sports achievements was I wrote poetry.  Kind of light verse, in a coffee shop, and Peter Faulk when he was doing <i>Columbo </i>came, and liked it so much he took me out drinking that night.  That was kind of fun.  And my other one is I hitchhiked to 49 states in the U.S. while a college student.  I wasn’t able to hitchhike to Hawaii.</p>
<p><strong>Derek: What did you do coming out of college?</strong></p>
<p><strong>BING</strong>: I was an actor in New York City.  And at the same time I was a busboy at <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Max's_Kansas_City">Max’s Kansas City</a>, kind of the first glitter bar in New York where Iggy Pop and the New York Dolls played…I did that for a year and I realized that professional theater kind of sucks because you don’t get to work when you want, and you make your name in bad plays.  After that I kind of always wanted to be a writer.  I still think that book-writing is the most honorable avocation.  I think it’s a pretty shitty business.  And even though fewer people want to read all the time, I still think that is the product that carries the most honor, in my mind.  So I started doing various odd jobs trying to make enough money that I could afford to write.  After a couple years commercial fishing and tree planting, I got enough money, I had a ’56 pink Pontiac Chieftain and an electric typewriter, and I sat down to write and I realized, I hate writing.  I only did it because teachers needed it for school.  It’s better than doing other stuff in school, but any of you who are writers know it’s like ripping your heart out one word at a time.</p>
<p><b>How did you meet Trip Hawkins and how was Electronic Arts founded?</b></p>
<p><strong>BING</strong>: I’m at Stanford Business School, and I went there because I was good with math, and otherwise I was going to be dead-ended.  And Peter Keane, a decision science professor, asked, “Okay, you Stanford MBAs, let’s have a real decision:  If money were no object, what would you do?”  And I said, “You know that movie <i><a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LcL3eP0Hfy4">Westworld</a>?</i>  I would like to create, inside computers, an adult Disneyland where you play out real stories.” The room went silent, and the MBAs kind of were embarrassed.  The professor comes up to me later and says, “There’s somebody with an answer that sounded like that in one of my other classes, and you should see him.”  That was Trip Hawkins.  I played on the university champion touch football team with him, but I’d never talked with him because he placed out of all the classes I’m in.  He was not the 100 SAT point-deficient MBA.  So we went and talked at Stanford. We ended up living together, played a lot of games together on our free Channel F, and I made so much money fishing that I bought a hot tub, so we had a hot tub and a Channel F.  Let me tell you, we were party central for Stanford Business School!</p>
<p><b>Derek: What did your family think when you joined a videogame company?</b></p>
<p>BING: You know, it wasn’t any worse than what I was already doing.  I left Stanford Business School…I worked half-time at Intel while I was in business school…and the other half of my time I drove to Moor End to date the woman who’s been my wife ever since.  My avowed goal was, in five years to start a consumer tech ad agency to replace Regis McKenna.  Regis McKenna was a great PR guy.  But I thought, okay, whatever, get a couple years of experience and eat their lunch, because they do everything wrong.  And then Trip said, “I’m going to start a software company in five years.”  Well, I actually did start an ad agency six years later – it’s called Goodby-Silverstein, it’s in San Francisco – and I pulled them out of their work and joined them for one day, and then I realized that grown-up businesspeople in advertising give up their self-respect about age 40, and I intended to live past then.  But the game business in the ‘80s was pretty low-creative.  I realized early on that I like being with world-class creative people, and they were not in the video game business in the ‘80s.</p>
<p><b>Derek: At what point did you realize you were onto something big?</b></p>
<p>BING: We did a million-unit seller, and the first time I realized it was different I was getting in a cab in New York.  This is a little later, but it was a cab in New York with an EA sports logo, and the guy turns to me and goes, “EA Sports.  It’s in the game!”  And here I am sheepishly counting the quarters to make sure I’ve got enough to tip the dude – I don’t know if 15% is enough in New York – and he turns to me and loves the logo; kind of gives me an emotional bear hug.  So that was when a million seemed like ubiquity.  Even five years ago when I started a venture – venture capitalists, if you had 500,000 people coming to a web site, that seemed like a tipping point.  The bad news is, the new tipping point’s ten million.  Back then one million was an unheard-of number.  There was so much friction in distribution.</p>
<p><b>Derek: How did the team have such foresight to see 30-years ahead of your time?</b></p>
<p>BING: I talked to you about the kind of blind confidence.  We believed in interactivity, and we believed in learning by doing, as opposed to learning by listening and sitting there.  And we thought there would be this crossover from the magic of movies to games.  And the games had interactivity.  We didn’t know exactly how.  We thought it was going to be based more on visual fidelity and audio fidelity and maybe stories.  But where that started from was that games are going to be a new art form.  You can start with a big vision that electrifies people and let other people around you help invent it, then check in.  If you’ve got a vision, you have to check in:  Are you delivering it in new ways?  Are you still focused on it?  Are you still taking risks to try to get there?</p>
<p><b>Derek: Why does a founder need “animal energy?”</b></p>
<p>BING: You need charisma and animal energy.  Way more important than intellectual savvy and great memory.  Animal energy is the ability to bend the will of other people while standing up.  I think Steve Balmer’s got it.  A lot of leadership is kind of like a tuning fork – getting everybody on the same wavelength. There’s just no substitute for the ability to work hard and be in a good mood.  So when I see somebody in a workplace that can’t help but smile and compliment people, I just tell them, “Don’t ever lose that.”  Startups and the creative process is so hard.  You don’t want Nervous Nellies and Snarky Sams.  Somebody who is uplifting – that’s worth 20 IQ points. And if you’ve got the 20 IQ points, you owe it to yourself to be really happy, because then you get 20 more. I work with John Doer, over at KPCB who kind of runs up and down the Grand Canyon.  Sounds kind of crazy.  I work with Mark Pinkas who surfs every weekend.  Most people that I work with around here who are leaders have extraordinary energy.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZWRZv291_PE?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p><b>Derek: You&#8217;re one of the best CEO coaches in the world. Lay your best advice on us.</b></p>
<p>BING: Most of business can get explained by high school.  If you were a fan of how things worked in high school, whether you were in the middle of how things worked or not, the same kind of, you know, nervousness and vying for attention and having trouble getting your needs met, and being overworked and over social – it’s still what’s driving the people you’re doing business with.  So anytime you run into a complicated situation, imagine it’s <i>Glee</i> and it will all be explainable.  The next thing is – the most important thing for people in their 20s – my experience is everyone in their twenties wastes a year.  You do it from bad choices.  Kind of working in local maxima.  Everyone in their twenties should have a mentor who – all they’ll want from you is thanks and feedback for when it’s working, and they have to believe they have your best interests at heart.  It’s hard to get that from an investor.  It’s hard to believe or even test that an investor will put your needs ahead of theirs.  Most won’t.  Money is very corrupting.  So get a mentor.  Next thing is, I believe that there are a lot of pathways to success.  And the people who succeed have a higher likelihood if they’re doing something they’re passionate about.  In almost all walks of life, opportunities are created.  People who are doing something they like will just pay more attention.  So if you do something – this is kind of a negative for enterprise software – but if you’re doing something that matches a hobby, you’re going to have redoubled time and attention.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788628/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=AbL6vpMk9Ko:wjDSIBct8FY:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=AbL6vpMk9Ko:wjDSIBct8FY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=AbL6vpMk9Ko:wjDSIBct8FY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=AbL6vpMk9Ko:wjDSIBct8FY:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=AbL6vpMk9Ko:wjDSIBct8FY:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=AbL6vpMk9Ko:wjDSIBct8FY:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=AbL6vpMk9Ko:wjDSIBct8FY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=AbL6vpMk9Ko:wjDSIBct8FY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/AbL6vpMk9Ko" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/30/animal-energy-blind-confidence-and-a-toupee-what-bing-gordon-says-your-startup-needs-for-success/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bf060e2d91f7d91edba21efb3dbc8e36?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">derekandersen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-30-at-12-09-31-am1.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-03-30 at 12.09.31 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/30/animal-energy-blind-confidence-and-a-toupee-what-bing-gordon-says-your-startup-needs-for-success/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Big Data Could Cripple Facebook</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/5bqFzyPO95E/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/30/big-data-could-cripple-facebook/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jon Evans</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kredstreet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zuckerberg's law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smogfarm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sentiment analysis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788035</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kredstreet.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="kredstreet" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />So there's this startup called <a target="_blank" href="http://smogfarm.com/">SmogFarm</a>, which does big-data sentiment analysis, "pulse of the planet" stuff. I <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/14/software-metastasis-and-life-3-0/">spotted them last year</a>, and now they've got an actual product with an actual business model up and running in private beta: <a target="_blank" href="http://kredstreet.com/">KredStreet</a>, "The Social Stock Trader Rankings," which performs sentiment analysis on StockTwits data and a sampling of the Twitter firehose to determine traders' overall bullish/bearish feeling. They also compare reality against past sentiment to score and rank traders based on their accuracy, which is more interesting.

It's a first iteration, but it looks pretty nifty, and I like the idea of a ranking system wherein unknowns can leave high-profile loudmouths in their dust by virtue of simply being right more often. Even if I feel slightly uneasy when I imagine such a system being applied to, say, tech bloggers. Actually being held <em><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/05/52-pick-up-or-where-i-went-wrong/">accountable</a></em> for what I've written in the past? Doesn't that just seem terribly <em><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/10/where-i-went-wrong-second-annual-edition/">wrong</a>?</em>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kredstreet.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="kredstreet" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>So there&#8217;s this startup called <a target="_blank" href="http://smogfarm.com/">SmogFarm</a>, which does big-data sentiment analysis, &#8220;pulse of the planet&#8221; stuff. I <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/14/software-metastasis-and-life-3-0/">spotted them last year</a>, and now they&#8217;ve got an actual product with an actual business model up and running in private beta: <a target="_blank" href="http://kredstreet.com/">KredStreet</a>, &#8220;The Social Stock Trader Rankings,&#8221; which performs sentiment analysis on StockTwits data and a sampling of the Twitter firehose to determine traders&#8217; overall bullish/bearish feeling. They also compare reality against past sentiment to score and rank traders based on their accuracy, which is more interesting.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a first iteration, but it looks pretty nifty, and I like the idea of a ranking system wherein unknowns can leave high-profile loudmouths in their dust by virtue of simply being right more often. Even if I feel slightly uneasy when I imagine such a system being applied to, say, tech bloggers. Actually being held <em><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/05/52-pick-up-or-where-i-went-wrong/">accountable</a></em> for what I&#8217;ve written in the past? Doesn&#8217;t that just seem terribly <em><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/10/where-i-went-wrong-second-annual-edition/">wrong</a>?</em></p>
<p>And of course it&#8217;s early days yet for companies like SmogFarm/KredStreet, and sentiment analysis, and natural language processing (such as that which powered <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/25/yahoo-acquires-information-gathering-startup-summly/">Summly</a>), and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/tag/palantir/">Palantir</a>-style data mining. Just imagine what they&#8217;ll be able to do in five years. And when they turn all that big-iron, big-data searchlight power on, say, Facebook timelines &#8212; what <i>won&#8217;t</i> they be able to determine?</p>
<p>A few years ago the EFF <a target="_blank" href="http://panopticlick.eff.org/">discovered</a> that something as simple as your browser settings make you a lot less anonymous online than you might believe. Last week a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nature.com/srep/2013/130325/srep01376/full/srep01376.html">study</a> found that &#8220;human mobility traces are highly unique,&#8221; and when polling allegedly anonymous cell-phone location data, &#8220;four spatio-temporal points are enough to uniquely identify 95% of the individuals.&#8221; Good software can mine a lot of meaning out of apparently sparse and empty data.</p>
<p>So just imagine what happens when next-generation language- and image-processing software, and then the generation after that, and the generation after <i>that</i>, is unleashed on your Facebook timeline. It seems very plausible that all those innocuous things you say, and how you say them, and the pictures you post, and the games you play, will subtly and invisibly add up to a terrifyingly accurate portrait of you, including any and/or all of the things about yourself that you never actually wanted to make public.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s worse is that it will be ridiculously easy. Would-be employers won&#8217;t have to scroll through your Facebook timeline themselves, they&#8217;ll just need to point their profiling software in your direction and 30 seconds later read its high-confidence predictions of your work habits, neuroses, personal failures, emotional instabilities, attitude towards authorities, and sexual proclivities, all expertly extrapolated from the tapestry of subtle-to-invisible nuances accumulated from all of your photos, comments, Likes, upvotes, etc.; all individually meaningless, but collectively highly illuminating. Individual profiling is a huge business just waiting to be tapped by ethically challenged startups.</p>
<p>(This could be mitigated somewhat if you were to keep all your activity friends-only, of course; but even then, every app or distant acquaintance you&#8217;re connected to will be able to learn more about you than you ever intended. And it&#8217;s easy to envision employers requesting that you connect to them on Facebook as part of the job-application process, and filtering out those who refuse&#8230;)</p>
<p>I can imagine what that kind of profiling software would have said about me, early in my career: <i>Hopeless bibliophile. Afflicted with incurable wanderlust. Doesn&#8217;t like being told what to do. Extremely chancy hire: likely to quit any job after six months to travel or try to write the Great Canadian Novel.</i> Which, er, would have been <a target="_blank" href="http://www.rezendi.com/">one thousand per cent</a> <a target="_blank" href="http://www.rezendi.com/tales.htm">true</a>; but obviously I didn&#8217;t want my potential employers back then to know about it.</p>
<p>Doesn&#8217;t matter to me now, of course, now that I&#8217;ve mellowed out some and I&#8217;m pretty well-established. But when people who are still struggling discover that everything they do online says far more about themselves than they know, and will be ceaselessly stored, sifted, mined and measured&#8230;they&#8217;ll inevitably become a whole lot less forthright than they are today.</p>
<p>Most people already know not to publicize individual things that reflect badly on them; once they realize that the <i>totality</i> of what they post can have serious repercussions, too, they&#8217;ll clam up. In the end all public online activity will essentially become an endless ongoing job interview. Doesn&#8217;t that sound great?</p>
<p>You would think all this big-data artillery would be good news for Facebook, so that they can target their ads more effectively. But once everything you share is being watched, filtered, and graded by remorseless, relentless profiling software, you&#8217;ll inevitably begin to share far less. Sure, you can try to use pseudonyms&#8230;but screw up <em>just once</em> and they&#8217;ll be tied to your real identity forever.</p>
<p>&#8220;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.geekculture.com/joyoftech/joyarchives/1594.html">Zuckerberg&#8217;s Law</a>&#8221; states that every year the amount of information shared by Internet users doubles. But KredStreet and the like are only the very beginning of what can be done with this kind of data analysis. It&#8217;s hard to imagine Zuckerberg&#8217;s Law marching on once people realize that everything they do online accumulates into data that reveals far more about them than they know, which can and will be used against them. Instead I can see Facebook slowly turning into a ghost town where everyone is always on their very best fake behavior.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788035/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5bqFzyPO95E:S2KWhTG430U:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5bqFzyPO95E:S2KWhTG430U:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5bqFzyPO95E:S2KWhTG430U:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5bqFzyPO95E:S2KWhTG430U:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=5bqFzyPO95E:S2KWhTG430U:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5bqFzyPO95E:S2KWhTG430U:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=5bqFzyPO95E:S2KWhTG430U:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=5bqFzyPO95E:S2KWhTG430U:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/5bqFzyPO95E" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/30/big-data-could-cripple-facebook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kredstreet.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kredstreet.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kredstreet</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/df4f08903b7a5c3d7078165edcf5bcf7?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rezendi</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/30/big-data-could-cripple-facebook/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Where Have All The Physical QWERTYs Gone?</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/QkLshAsmXHU/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/30/qwerty/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 11:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve O'Hear</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blackberry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[q10]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=787702</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bbq10-5.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="bbq10-5" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />It’s approaching three years since I emailed and got a reply from the late Steve Jobs. The topic of my caffeine-fueled missive that sunny day in June 2010 was the industry’s move towards touch-based interfaces and, specifically, Apple’s one-size-fits-all approach regarding the iPhone’s lack of a physical QWERTY keyboard.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bbq10-5.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="bbq10-5" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>It’s approaching three years since I emailed and got a reply from the late Steve Jobs. The topic of my caffeine-fueled missive that sunny day in June 2010 was the industry’s move towards touch-based interfaces and, specifically, Apple’s one-size-fits-all approach regarding the iPhone’s lack of a physical QWERTY keyboard.</p>
<p>I have a disability that can make touch and other physically demanding interfaces more challenging, I explained to Jobs, and whereas the mouse-driven GUI that he helped usher in with the Macintosh had inadvertently put me on a level playing field, were touch to ever become the dominant mode of input, it had the potential to turn that world upside down.</p>
<p>“That’s obviously a bit dramatic”, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/06/24/steve-jobs-emails-we-will-keep-making-the-best-computers-2/">I wrote on TechCrunch</a> at the time. “There will always be lots of different products on the market, but it’s a possibility nonetheless.” Fast forward to 2013 and what was only a possibility has all but become a reality. Survey the mobile landscape and it’s filled with people fondling their giant slabs of touch, happily typing away on glass.</p>
<p>At this point I know I’ll likely get ripped apart in the comments. In the battle of the physical vs virtual QWERTY, the market has spoken, they’ll say, and those who don’t favour touch are squarely out of touch. And sadly, the evidence is heavily stacked on their side of the argument.</p>
<h3 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:230px;float:right;color:#0a9400;">Survey the mobile landscape and it’s filled with people fondling their giant slabs of touch, happily typing away on glass</h3>
<p>In the first few years of the iPhone’s existence, a ton of hybrid physical QWERTY/touch smartphones from competitors entered the market, ready to differentiate themselves from Apple by talking up their superior typing experience. But they failed to stop the Cupertino juggernaught. Typing on glass, while not ideal, was good enough. Arguably it wasn’t until Android OEMs ditched their, largely, clunky slide-out keyboards and wholesale copied and then supersized Apple’s all touch form-factor, did they begin to turn back the tide.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, continues the argument, the likes of Nokia fell by the wayside, plagued by an antiquated user interface that, in a desperate and confused attempt to respond to the market, tried and failed to crowbar in touch before the company finally jumped onto Microsoft’s Windows Phone platform, sans physical QWERTY.</p>
<p>Furthermore, BlackBerry, which seemingly built its whole business off the back of its physical QWERTY-touting credentials, chose to release its first comeback device as the BB10-powered Z10, another all touch grey slab, rather than the Q10, which combines touch with <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/30/hands-on-blackberry-q10-curious-blend-of-old-and-new/">a physical QWERTY</a> in the best BlackBerry candybar tradition. It’s also been <a target="_blank" href="http://wirelessworker.net/blog/2013/2/blackberry-q10-hands-on">suggested</a> that the Canadian handset maker may even view the Q10’s hybrid approach as a way to wean its traditional customers off a physical keyboard entirely, a gateway device if you will. </p>
<p>So yes, putting aside the fact that the market can only speak to what is put in front of it &#8212; I can’t recall a single candybar QWERTY powered by Android that was anything more than a mid-tier or low end device &#8212; it would seem that the market has indeed spoken.</p>
<p>But it may not have had the final word yet.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s if &#8212; and it&#8217;s a <em>big</em> if &#8212; the BlackBerry Q10, when it finally hits the market next month, surprises everybody and sells in sufficient numbers to smash through the totalitarian all touch screen. And just like the Mac had ensured before it, for this hack and others like me, 2013 <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1984_(advertisement)">won&#8217;t be</a> like 1984 after all.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/787702/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QkLshAsmXHU:SJcx-QTQiqo:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QkLshAsmXHU:SJcx-QTQiqo:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QkLshAsmXHU:SJcx-QTQiqo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QkLshAsmXHU:SJcx-QTQiqo:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=QkLshAsmXHU:SJcx-QTQiqo:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QkLshAsmXHU:SJcx-QTQiqo:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=QkLshAsmXHU:SJcx-QTQiqo:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QkLshAsmXHU:SJcx-QTQiqo:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/QkLshAsmXHU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/30/qwerty/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bbq10-5.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bbq10-5.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bbq10-5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/95b8a6df6d265cf57a4d89ee4856ea98?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve O'Hear</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/30/qwerty/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>After Bootstrapping, Data-Mining Specialist Ondore Closes Million-Dollar Round For Mexican, US Operations</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/-L_fmXKkHWI/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/30/ondore-closes-million-dollar-round-after-years-of-bootstrapping/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 09:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Maria Rocio Paniagua</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=786666</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ondore.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Ondore" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><b>Editor’s note:</b> <em>Maria Rocio Paniagua currently works as a project manager at <a target="_blank" href="http://www.innku.com/">Innku</a>, one of the top mobile and web workshops in Mexico.</em>

Ondore, the leading Latin American big data analysis company that develops online reputation management systems, has closed its first investment round for $1.5 million dollars with Alta Ventures. The company says it will use the capital round to expand sales and marketing efforts in Latin America, as well as Spanish-speaking U.S.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ondore.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Ondore" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><strong>Editor’s note:</strong> <em>Maria Rocio Paniagua currently works as a project manager at <a target="_blank" href="http://www.innku.com/">Innku</a>, one of the top mobile and web workshops in Mexico. Follow her on <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/lachinous">Twitter</a>.</em></p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://web.ondore.com/">Ondore</a>, the leading Latin American big data analysis company that develops online reputation management systems, has closed its first investment round for $1.5 million dollars with <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/alta-ventures-mexico">Alta Ventures</a>. The company says it will use the capital round to expand sales and marketing efforts in Latin America, as well as Spanish-speaking U.S.</p>
<p>Ondore&#8217;s reputation management systems work via data mining: The information obtained is processed, interpreted and sorted automatically. They have different products that target different pains in the market. <a target="_blank" href="http://web.ondore.com/products/ondore-scout/">Scout</a> helps businesses understand and benefit from social media, providing them with deep insights into the conversations that are taking place on the web and interpreting things like sentiment, source and influence. They have also built an <a target="_blank" href="http://web.ondore.com/products/ondore-api/">API</a> that allows the integration of social media and web analytics with apps.</p>
<p>Ondore founder and CTO <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/FernandoLuege">Fernando Luegue</a> started the company eight years ago in Mexico City at the age of 18. During the first three years, Luegue alone conducted scientific research on algorithms that processed information and solved problems for enterprises. Then he developed one that automatically organized information and last year received a patent in the U.S.</p>
<p>With offices in San Francisco, under CEO <a target="_blank" href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/todd-stein/0/308/a0a">Todd Stein</a>, Ondore was bootstrapped until it had a 35-person team on board. “We did data mining in Latin America before we even came across the term,” Luegue says, and now, he added, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/televisa">Televisa</a> (the largest media company in the Spanish-speaking world) and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/ogilvy-mather-interactive">Ogilvy &amp; Mather</a> (one of the largest marketing and PR firms in LATAM) are among Ondore&#8217;s clients.</p>
<p>Finally last year, the company opened its investment round, visiting a plethora of VCs and private investors in both Mexico and Silicon Valley. They received a couple of offers, but decided to go with Alta, which, like Ondore, is based in Latin America and San Francisco. “I don’t want to talk about dumb money,&#8221; Luegue says, &#8220;but I can say that Alta’s technical side is incredibly talented.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">Ondore&#8217;s road has not been an easy one, however. Luegue says that building credibility and assembling a good team was challenging, as was penetrating a B2B market on an international level coming from a Latin American country.</p>
<p>In the next year, Ondore plans to consolidate its already strong lead in the Mexican and Latin American markets on the back of Scout, which the company says has some of the most competitive prices in the market.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/786666/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=-L_fmXKkHWI:Fx72MGFyQRQ:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=-L_fmXKkHWI:Fx72MGFyQRQ:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=-L_fmXKkHWI:Fx72MGFyQRQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=-L_fmXKkHWI:Fx72MGFyQRQ:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=-L_fmXKkHWI:Fx72MGFyQRQ:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=-L_fmXKkHWI:Fx72MGFyQRQ:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=-L_fmXKkHWI:Fx72MGFyQRQ:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=-L_fmXKkHWI:Fx72MGFyQRQ:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/-L_fmXKkHWI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/30/ondore-closes-million-dollar-round-after-years-of-bootstrapping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ondore.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ondore.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ondore</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2a014e70509390133a9b9073671a2e8d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tcbucket</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/30/ondore-closes-million-dollar-round-after-years-of-bootstrapping/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Sequoia Capital In Singapore After A Year, Has Yet To Invest In A Local Startup</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/9RLBrFSLBM8/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/sequoia-capital-in-singapore-after-a-year-has-yet-to-invest-in-a-local-startup/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 06:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Victoria Ho</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequoia capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequoia Capital India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788623</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2008/03/scaledphoto_lg_singapore_cntry.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Singapore skyline" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />When Sequoia Capital India landed in Singapore quietly in 2012, the buzz around town was that a big-name US fund being in the country was going to really jolt the market and provide serious cred to the startups here. The Indian team running operations here, however, appears to have spent the last year of its time in the island state helping startups in its India portfolio expand into Singapore, rather than directly investing in startups here. However, the company just moved into a fancy new co-working space called The Co, and is its anchor tenant, so it could be a sign that it’s trying to get closer to local startups. Previously, it operated out of a service office in High Street. Singapore is a popular choice as a base for foreign companies looking to expand into Southeast Asia, because it&#8217;s a mature market with plenty of infrastructure available. But as a tiny country, it&#8217;s not often the main addressable user base, and startups originating from Singapore are also taught to have expansion plans charted. Early last year, Sequoia Capital India MD, Shailendra Jit Singh, expressed interest in having the fund’s companies expand into the region. Sequoia Cap in the US also appeared to have been eyeing activity in Singapore for a while—it had its first offsite meeting in the country in 2011, and was in discussion with Singaporean Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong about its presence here. The Prime Minister’s Office oversees its R&#38;D arm, the National Research Foundation (NRF), which has been busy backing local venture capital firms here over the past few years. Its Technology Incubation Scheme is a program that distributes seed funding to startups picked by 11 NRF-appointed VCs. The NRF matches investment values in the proportion of 85 percent to 15 percent—the larger portion dished out by the government. This allows the VCs here to provide bigger sums of seed capital to startups, with much of the risk absorbed by the NRF. Former NRF projects head, Yinglan Tan, was also pulled over to Sequoia Capital India’s team in July last year, where he is now a venture partner based in Singapore. When I ran into Tan in Manila a couple of months ago, he was evasive about Sequoia&#8217;s activities in Singapore, but was happy to try to set up meetings with their existing portfolio companies in Singapore—all Indian-based startups, except for Airbnb and Evernote. Some of these companies]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2008/03/scaledphoto_lg_singapore_cntry.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Singapore skyline" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>When <a target="_blank" href="http://www.sequoiacap.com/india">Sequoia Capital India</a> landed in Singapore quietly in 2012, the buzz around town was that a big-name US fund being in the country was going to really jolt the market and provide serious cred to the startups here.</p>
<p>The Indian team running operations here, however, appears to have spent the last year of its time in the island state helping startups in its India portfolio expand into Singapore, rather than directly investing in startups here.</p>
<p>However, the company just moved into a fancy new co-working space called <a target="_blank" href="http://jointhe.co/?q=home">The Co</a>, and is its anchor tenant, so it could be a sign that it’s trying to get closer to local startups. Previously, it operated out of a service office in High Street.</p>
<p>Singapore is a popular choice as a base for foreign companies looking to expand into Southeast Asia, because it&#8217;s a mature market with plenty of infrastructure available. But as a tiny country, it&#8217;s not often the main addressable user base, and startups originating from Singapore are also taught to have expansion plans charted. Early last year, Sequoia Capital India MD, Shailendra Jit Singh, expressed interest in having the fund’s companies <a target="_blank" href="//www.techinasia.com/what-is-sequoia-india-doing-in-singapore-an-interview-with-shailendra-jit-singh/">expand into the region</a>. Sequoia Cap in the US also appeared to have been eyeing activity in Singapore for a while—it had its first offsite meeting in the country in 2011, and was <a target="_blank" href="//www.nrf.gov.sg/nrf/uploadedFiles/News_and_Events/Press%20Release%20For%20Sequoia%20Capital_FINAL.pdf">in discussion</a> with Singaporean Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong about its presence here.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister’s Office oversees its R&amp;D arm, the National Research Foundation (NRF), which has been busy backing local venture capital firms here over the past few years. Its Technology Incubation Scheme is a program that distributes seed funding to startups picked by 11 NRF-appointed VCs. The NRF matches investment values in the proportion of 85 percent to 15 percent—the larger portion dished out by the government. This allows the VCs here to provide bigger sums of seed capital to startups, with much of the risk absorbed by the NRF.</p>
<p>Former NRF projects head, Yinglan Tan, was also pulled over to Sequoia Capital India’s team in July last year, where he is now a venture partner based in Singapore.</p>
<p>When I ran into Tan in Manila a couple of months ago, he was evasive about Sequoia&#8217;s activities in Singapore, but was happy to try to set up meetings with their existing portfolio companies in Singapore—all Indian-based startups, except for Airbnb and Evernote. Some of these companies that are being incubated in Singapore by Sequoia Cap include Via, Druva, Mu Sigma, Idea Device and Practo.</p>
<p>Two months on, those meetings have yet to happen, but word on the street is that Tan has been meeting with some Singapore-based startups that are looking to raise Series A or B rounds, and are looking to expand beyond the island. One that I know of provides Wi-Fi infrastructure.</p>
<p>As for its current startups here, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.via.com">Via</a> is pretty sizable. It operates a flight booking portal similar to Expedia and Zuji, and has about 1,200 employees, the bulk of which are in India, with some in Indonesia and another team in the Philippines. It also lists hotels, and has about 45,000 listings, with plans to add more.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.druva.com">Druva</a> started in Pune, India and is now operationally HQed in Sunnyvale, according to Jaspreet Singh, its CEO and founder. The company provides a backup system for mobile devices in the enterprise.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.mu-sigma.com">Mu Sigma</a> is a Bangalore-based data analytics company. Last month, it struck up a deal with MasterCard that valued the company at $1 billion, according to <a target="_blank" href="//articles.economictimes.indiatimes.com/2013-02-20/news/37200522_1_dhiraj-rajaram-mu-sigma-data-analytics”">The Economic Times</a> in India.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.ideadevice.com">Idea Device</a> is also a Bangalore startup, and makes a runbook automation system. Runbook automation is a set of technologies that helps take out some of the manual system administration tasks for IT departments.</p>
<p>As for the two US-based firms, Airbnb opened its Singapore office late in <a target="_blank" href="http://asia.cnet.com/airbnb-lands-in-singapore-62219424.htm">November</a> last year, and Evernote has been in the country for a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.zdnet.com/evernote-chases-after-asias-user-goldmine-2062302584/">little over a year</a>.</p>
<p>Sequoia Cap US declined to comment further on its plans for Singapore.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788623/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9RLBrFSLBM8:m-4KLhc1FCk:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9RLBrFSLBM8:m-4KLhc1FCk:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9RLBrFSLBM8:m-4KLhc1FCk:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9RLBrFSLBM8:m-4KLhc1FCk:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=9RLBrFSLBM8:m-4KLhc1FCk:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9RLBrFSLBM8:m-4KLhc1FCk:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=9RLBrFSLBM8:m-4KLhc1FCk:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=9RLBrFSLBM8:m-4KLhc1FCk:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/9RLBrFSLBM8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/sequoia-capital-in-singapore-after-a-year-has-yet-to-invest-in-a-local-startup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2008/03/scaledphoto_lg_singapore_cntry.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2008/03/scaledphoto_lg_singapore_cntry.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Singapore skyline</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2730ac85eb6d3f6f7491d176987aab05?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">victoriatc</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/sequoia-capital-in-singapore-after-a-year-has-yet-to-invest-in-a-local-startup/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>The Dash Car Dongle Wants To Make You A Better Driver By Syncing With Your iPhone</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/FMqYoxRAIrQ/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/the-dash-car-dongle-wants-to-make-you-a-better-driver-by-syncing-with-your-iphone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 05:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chris Velazco</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kickstarter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788595</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dash-kickstarter.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="dash-kickstarter" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />I love my tiny little Mazda, but I'll be honest -- I still don't completely understand how it <em>works</em>. That's never really bothered me before (I'd much rather geek out over a phone or something) but a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/shred444/drive-with-dash?ref=recently_launched">Kickstarter project</a> from a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.drivewithdash.com/#">small team in Boston</a> has me itching to pay more attention to what's really going on under the hood. Long story short, Dash combines a Bluetooth 4.0-enabled dongle that plugs into your car's on-board diagnostics port with a smartphone app that gives you up-to-date information how on your car is holding up.
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dash-kickstarter.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="dash-kickstarter" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><iframe width="640" height="480" src="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/shred444/drive-with-dash/widget/video.html" frameborder="0"> </iframe>
<p>I love my tiny little Mazda, but I&#8217;ll be honest &#8212; I still don&#8217;t completely understand how it <em>works</em>. That&#8217;s never really bothered me before (I&#8217;d much rather geek out over a phone or something) but a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/shred444/drive-with-dash?ref=recently_launched">Kickstarter project</a> from a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.drivewithdash.com/#">small team in Boston</a> has me itching to pay more attention to what&#8217;s really going on under the hood. Long story short, Dash combines a Bluetooth 4.0-enabled dongle that plugs into your car&#8217;s on-board diagnostics port with an iPhone app that gives you up-to-date information how on your car is holding up.</p>
<p>Yes, I know that probably sounds very familiar. </p>
<p>We&#8217;ve seen a few startups tapping into that particular port recently &#8212; <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/12/carvoyant-is-ready-to-put-your-car-in-the-cloud/">Carvoyant</a> inked deals with local auto dealers to more broadly distribute its always-on diagnostics and tracking gadget earlier this year, and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/12/automatic-car-app-dongle/">Y Combinator-backed Automatic</a> got plenty of attention for taking a similar concept and combining it with an awfully handsome iPhone app interface. Dash&#8217;s approach seems to resemble the latter slightly more than the former, but at their core they&#8217;re all trying to accomplish the same mission: to improve the driving experience by shining light on data that wasn&#8217;t always easily accessible.</p>
<p>So should you consider Dash over something like the ultra-slick Automatic when both devices are both slated to cost around $69? That all comes down to how you feel about the little tricks that set Dash apart from the oft-hyped California startup&#8217;s service. </p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dash-dashboard.jpg"></a>In addition to tracking fuel usage, passing along notifications when your car&#8217;s components have gone awry and letting people locate their cars on a map, Dash users can use their smartphone as a secondary display of sorts for realtime information like current speed, engine RPM, and fuel economy. The big idea behind latter is that you&#8217;ll be able to find an environmentally-friendly sweet spot while cruising along, though chances are you&#8217;ve already got some sort of indicator telling you how fuel-efficient your driving is if you&#8217;re driving a more recent car. Still, since U.S. cars from as far back as 1996 have ODB ports there are plenty of drivers who could stand to benefit from this sort of info.</p>
<p>Oh, and a side note: if Dash appeals to you because your car&#8217;s built-in speedometer and tachometer don&#8217;t work, you should <em>really</em> get that taken care of first. </p>
<p>In case you were hoping to bring your social fixation into your car too, all that driving data can be automatically uploaded to an associated online Dash account. From there people can compare their own metrics to their fellow Dash users and pick up on best practices for squeezing optimal performance out of their rides (sadly, there doesn&#8217;t seem to be a way to mock them mercilessly for driving like your grandmother). What&#8217;s more, users can also record and share in-car video with speed and engine information overlaid on top of it, well, just because.</p>
<p>Those of you looking to make your iPhone an extension of your car have to consider that the Dash still seems like a long way from fruition. At time of writing the team&#8217;s Kickstarter campaign has raised just over $15,000 from backers, and is ultimately shooting to top $750,000 before May 11. Should the Dash team meet that lofty goal though, they hope to get the first batch of dongles out sometime this June &#8212; just in time for summer roadtrip season. Sadly, just like with Automatic, Android users will have to wait until later in the year to get their mobile car diagnostics on.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788595/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FMqYoxRAIrQ:Ov_6WSsN-tU:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FMqYoxRAIrQ:Ov_6WSsN-tU:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FMqYoxRAIrQ:Ov_6WSsN-tU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FMqYoxRAIrQ:Ov_6WSsN-tU:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=FMqYoxRAIrQ:Ov_6WSsN-tU:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FMqYoxRAIrQ:Ov_6WSsN-tU:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=FMqYoxRAIrQ:Ov_6WSsN-tU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FMqYoxRAIrQ:Ov_6WSsN-tU:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/FMqYoxRAIrQ" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/the-dash-car-dongle-wants-to-make-you-a-better-driver-by-syncing-with-your-iphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dash-kickstarter.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dash-kickstarter.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dash-kickstarter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ec2ac47d9dad53c2ae4f7882ae9bf6b9?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ctvelazco</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dash-dashboard.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dash-dashboard</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/the-dash-car-dongle-wants-to-make-you-a-better-driver-by-syncing-with-your-iphone/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Foursquare's API Is A Pillar Of The Mobile App Ecosystem</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/PY-CQBMneK8/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/the-internet-needs-foursquare-to-succeed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 04:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jonathan Barouch</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foursquare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foursquare api]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=785274</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/4sq-api1.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="api branches" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><b>Editor's note:</b> <em>Jonathan Barouch is the founder and CEO of location-based startup Roamz, developer of social media business product Local Measure.</em>

Foursquare has become entrenched in the fabric of the local web, providing an API that delivers common good for developers. Any destabilization in Foursquare or its developer tools would fundamentally affect the stability of the mobile web.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/4sq-api1.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="api branches" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><strong>Editor&#8217;s note:</strong> <em>Jonathan Barouch is the founder and CEO of location-based startup <a target="_blank" href="http://www.roamz.com/">Roamz</a>, developer of social media business product <a target="_blank" href="http://www.getlocalmeasure.com/">Local Measure</a>. Follow him on Twitter <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/jbarouch">@jbarouch</a>. </em></p>
<p>Foursquare has become entrenched in the fabric of the local web, providing an API that delivers common good for developers. Any destabilization in Foursquare or its developer tools would fundamentally affect the stability of the mobile web.</p>
<p>Now I’m not suggesting that they are so important to the U.S. economy that Ben Bernanke and the Fed should step in to participate in Foursquare’s <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/02/foursquare-looks-into-a-hefty-fourth-round-some-investors-skeptical/">rumored Series D</a>. However, I do think that <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/hunterwalk/status/312962558153871361">Keith Rabois’ comment</a> about Foursquare having a small user base firmly misses the point. Even among all the lovers and haters duking it out on Twitter, no one stopped to consider what the sheer size of Foursquare’s developer base means for the industry.</p>
<p>Dennis Crowley said at the Mobile World Congress that <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/16/foursquare-aims-at-a-moving-target-as-it-tries-to-close-another-round-of-funding/">40,000 developers</a> use Foursquare location data via their API. Let&#8217;s examine the effect on Google, Apple, Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, Foodspotting and many other apps if Foursquare and its API were to no longer exist.</p>
<h5><b>The App Ecosystem</b></h5>
<p>Pick up your smartphone. Search through some of your favorite apps. Do you have Uber? Maybe Foodspotting? Surely you have Instagram. These apps, as well as a significant amount of the most popular apps in Apple’s App Store and Google Play, use Foursquare location data. For developers who have user actions or content tied to Foursquare venue IDs it would be difficult (if not impossible in some cases) to migrate their services off the Foursquare location database.</p>
<p>I would guess that by adding together the unique users of the popular apps that Foursquare powers, you would find that its data touches several hundred million users. Foursquare remaining healthy and maintaining an open API is critically important to Apple given the reliance on Foursquare of so many popular iOS apps.</p>
<p>And while Google has an excellent Places database of its own, it too has an interest in ensuring Foursquare’s longevity. Those same app developers that fill up Apple’s App Store charts are also pumping out apps on Google Play that rely on Foursquare data.</p>
<h3 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:250px;float:right;color:#0a9400;">For the moment Facebook appears to be somewhat dependent on Foursquare’s success.</h3>
<h5><b>Foursquare Over Facebook Places</b></h5>
<p>Almost a year after <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/09/facebook-to-acquire-instagram-for-1-billion/">Facebook acquired Instagram</a>, the photo-sharing app, with its more than 100 million active users, continues to use Foursquare location data rather than Facebook’s own Place API. This would seem to suggest that even Facebook values the location data generated by Foursquare’s 5 million daily check-ins.</p>
<p>For Instagram it would be a significant engineering effort to migrate off Foursquare’s data, given that there isn’t a global harmonized version of the two location data sets. (I have seen first-hand how tricky it is to algorithmically match places across the data sets.)</p>
<p>For the moment Facebook appears to be somewhat dependent on Foursquare’s success. Foursquare also generates a lot of its traffic via Facebook’s open graph and other timeline integrations so there seems to at least be mutual dependence on things not changing.</p>
<h5><b>Twitter&#8217;s Tied</b></h5>
<p>What seems to have been missed in <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/09/if-twitter-gets-into-the-video-hosting-game-it-could-be-a-wonderful-and-horrible-thing/">Twitter’s Vine acquisition</a> was that it was Twitter’s first app that allows users to geo-tag a social media post to a physical place. With Twitter’s own apps, the location feature simply adds a user’s longitude and latitude without reference to the place where it was tweeted. Given that Vine has now set the precedent allowing users to tag their content to a (Foursquare) location, Twitter also seems somewhat tied to Foursquare’s location data.</p>
<p>Location is a huge opportunity for Twitter, and Vine’s use of Foursquare’s API might be the first step for Twitter toward a future of having more granular location data attached to tweets.</p>
<p>These examples illustrate that Foursquare&#8217;s value is less about the size of its active user base and more related to the reach of its location database. Its API is fast becoming the de facto location layer of the mobile web and touches almost every user of location-based apps.</p>
<p>The problem for investors is that they don’t appear to have figured out how to monetize this enviable position. With so many companies dependent on Foursquare’s location data, a lot of people are hoping that they work it out &#8212; and fast.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/785274/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=PY-CQBMneK8:9EIlquEH7Sc:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=PY-CQBMneK8:9EIlquEH7Sc:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=PY-CQBMneK8:9EIlquEH7Sc:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=PY-CQBMneK8:9EIlquEH7Sc:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=PY-CQBMneK8:9EIlquEH7Sc:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=PY-CQBMneK8:9EIlquEH7Sc:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=PY-CQBMneK8:9EIlquEH7Sc:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=PY-CQBMneK8:9EIlquEH7Sc:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/PY-CQBMneK8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/the-internet-needs-foursquare-to-succeed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/4sq-api1.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/4sq-api1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">api branches</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2a014e70509390133a9b9073671a2e8d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tcbucket</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/the-internet-needs-foursquare-to-succeed/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Business Insider's Owen Thomas Is In Talks To Be The New Editor At ReadWrite</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/Aaycjhsnrlo/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/owen-thomas-probably/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Anthony Ha</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[readwrite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Owen Thomas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Say Media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788561</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/8602197952_a344212114.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="owen thomas" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />My old boss <a target="_blank" href="http://www.ditherati.com">Owen Thomas</a> is very close to becoming the new editor-in-chief at the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.saymedia.com">SAY Media</a>-owned tech site <a target="_blank" href="http://www.readwrite.com">ReadWrite</a>, according to sources with knowledge of the company. I'm hearing that it's not quite a done deal, but that it's looking very likely.

Naturally, I called Owen to ask if this was the case, but he declined to comment. A SAY spokesperson told me, "There's obviously a lot of interest in ReadWrite. There are a lot of good candidates in the mix, and no one's been hired yet." (Just to reiterate — I'm not saying he's been hired, just that the discussions are pretty far along.)]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/8602197952_a344212114.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="owen thomas" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>My old boss <a target="_blank" href="http://www.ditherati.com">Owen Thomas</a> is very close to becoming the new editor-in-chief at the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.saymedia.com">SAY Media</a>-owned tech site <a target="_blank" href="http://www.readwrite.com">ReadWrite</a>, according to sources with knowledge of the company. I&#8217;m hearing that it&#8217;s not quite a done deal, but that it&#8217;s looking very likely.</p>
<p>Naturally, I called Owen to ask if this was the case, but he declined to comment. A SAY spokesperson told me, &#8220;There&#8217;s obviously a lot of interest in ReadWrite. There are a lot of good candidates in the mix, and no one&#8217;s been hired yet.&#8221; (Just to reiterate — I&#8217;m not saying he&#8217;s been hired, just that the discussions are pretty far along.)</p>
<p>Owen may still be best known in startup circles as the former editor of Valleywag. He&#8217;s currently the West Coast Editor at Business Insider, and he was also the founding editor at The Daily Dot, executive editor at VentureBeat, editorial director at NBC, and a reporter/editor at Business 2.0. He&#8217;s definitely drawn his share of controversy (I was working for him at VentureBeat when Elon Musk called him &#8220;the Jayson Blair of Silicon Valley&#8221;), but he&#8217;s also a funny, well-connected writer, and an editor who I learned a lot from.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, we got the scoop that then-EIC <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/dan-lyons-leaves-readwrite/">Dan Lyons was leaving for marketing software company HubSpot</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> After the post went up, SAY VP of Social Ted Rheingold called to reiterate that it&#8217;s &#8220;a very open position with lots of interest and lots of candidates.&#8221; It sounds like I may have been a little premature in saying &#8220;probably&#8221; in the headline, so I changed it to &#8220;in talks.&#8221;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788561/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Aaycjhsnrlo:o8UEpnEfB5E:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Aaycjhsnrlo:o8UEpnEfB5E:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Aaycjhsnrlo:o8UEpnEfB5E:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Aaycjhsnrlo:o8UEpnEfB5E:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Aaycjhsnrlo:o8UEpnEfB5E:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Aaycjhsnrlo:o8UEpnEfB5E:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Aaycjhsnrlo:o8UEpnEfB5E:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Aaycjhsnrlo:o8UEpnEfB5E:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/Aaycjhsnrlo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/owen-thomas-probably/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/8602197952_a344212114.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/8602197952_a344212114.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">owen thomas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/72b358648f4587cc2a11895c32b8e979?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">anthha</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/owen-thomas-probably/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>MIT Files Court Papers “Partially” Opposing Release Of Documents About Aaron Swartz Investigation</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/iNxNVcbv3Zo/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/mit-files-court-papers-partially-opposing-release-of-documents-about-aaron-swartz-investigation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alex Williams</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aaron Swartz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MIT]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788536</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/250px-aaron_swartz_profile.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="250px-Aaron_Swartz_profile" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />The Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) is &#8220;partially&#8221; opposing a request by the estate of Aaron Swartz for the release of documents related to the investigation that led to Swartz&#8217;s arrest and prosecution in federal court. In court papers filed today, MIT counsel states that its opposition stems from two factors: its concerns about people in the MIT community named in the documents and the security of its computer networks. MIT has previously stated that it would release the documents with redactions of names and other information. MIT President L. Rafael Reif said in email to the MIT community earlier this month: On Friday, the lawyers for Aaron Swartz’s estate filed a legal request with the Boston federal court where the Swartz case would have gone to trial. They demanded that the court release to the public information related to the case, including many MIT documents. Some of these documents contain information about vulnerabilities in MIT’s network. Some contain the names of individual MIT employees involved. In fact, the lawyers’ request argues that those names cannot be excluded (”redacted”) from the documents and urges that they be released in the public domain and delivered to Congress. The paper filed today reiterates this position, basing it on threats already made to MIT staff and three separate hacking incidents at the university. The information includes &#8220;email, the names, job titles, departments, telephone numbers, email addresses, business addresses, and other identifying information of many members of the MIT community.&#8221; Swartz has become a symbol in the Internet community since his suicide. His supporters have led the debate about the role MIT played in Swartz&#8217;s prosecution and the vigilance of the U.S. Attorney General in the case. MIT claims it is fully cooperating in the investigation that has come since Swartz&#8217;s suicide.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/250px-aaron_swartz_profile.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="250px-Aaron_Swartz_profile" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>The Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) is <a target="_blank" href="https://docs.google.com/viewer?url=http%3A%2F%2Fia600504.us.archive.org%2F29%2Fitems%2Fgov.uscourts.mad.137971%2Fgov.uscourts.mad.137971.114.0.pdf">&#8220;partially&#8221; opposing</a> a request by the estate of Aaron Swartz for the release of documents related to the investigation that led to Swartz&#8217;s arrest and prosecution in federal court.</p>
<p>In court papers filed today, MIT counsel states that its opposition stems from two factors: its concerns about people in the MIT community named in the documents and the security of its computer networks.</p>
<p>MIT has <a target="_blank" href="http://www.boston.com/yourcampus/news/mit/2013/03/mit_agrees_to_release_documents_in_aaron_swartz_case.html">previously stated</a> that it would release the documents with redactions of names and other information. MIT President L. Rafael Reif said in email to the MIT community earlier this month:</p>
<blockquote><p>On Friday, the lawyers for Aaron Swartz’s estate filed a legal request with the Boston federal court where the Swartz case would have gone to trial. They demanded that the court release to the public information related to the case, including many MIT documents. Some of these documents contain information about vulnerabilities in MIT’s network. Some contain the names of individual MIT employees involved. In fact, the lawyers’ request argues that those names cannot be excluded (”redacted”) from the documents and urges that they be released in the public domain and delivered to Congress.</p></blockquote>
<p>The paper filed today reiterates this position, basing it on threats already made to MIT staff and three separate hacking incidents at the university.</p>
<p>The information includes &#8220;email, the names, job titles, departments, telephone numbers, email addresses, business addresses, and other identifying information of many members of the MIT community.&#8221;</p>
<p>Swartz has become a symbol in the Internet community since his suicide. His supporters have led the debate about the role MIT played in Swartz&#8217;s prosecution and the vigilance of the U.S. Attorney General in the case.</p>
<p>MIT claims it is fully cooperating in the investigation that has come since Swartz&#8217;s suicide.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788536/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=iNxNVcbv3Zo:1Q9uLXD66Jc:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=iNxNVcbv3Zo:1Q9uLXD66Jc:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=iNxNVcbv3Zo:1Q9uLXD66Jc:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=iNxNVcbv3Zo:1Q9uLXD66Jc:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=iNxNVcbv3Zo:1Q9uLXD66Jc:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=iNxNVcbv3Zo:1Q9uLXD66Jc:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=iNxNVcbv3Zo:1Q9uLXD66Jc:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=iNxNVcbv3Zo:1Q9uLXD66Jc:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/iNxNVcbv3Zo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/mit-files-court-papers-partially-opposing-release-of-documents-about-aaron-swartz-investigation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/250px-aaron_swartz_profile.jpg?w=108" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/250px-aaron_swartz_profile.jpg?w=108" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">250px-Aaron_Swartz_profile</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b4e205744ae2f9b44921d103b4d80e54?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Alex Williams</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/mit-files-court-papers-partially-opposing-release-of-documents-about-aaron-swartz-investigation/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>With Alternative Offers From Blackstone &amp; Icahn On The Table, Dell Filing Shows It Will Push Ahead With $24.4B Silver Lake Merger</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/vGDXIV-NoCY/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/with-alternative-offers-from-blackstone-icahn-on-the-table-dell-filing-shows-it-will-push-ahead-with-silver-lake-merger/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rip Empson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Dell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silver lake]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788542</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-29-at-5-15-25-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen shot 2013-03-29 at 5.15.25 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Dell <a target="_blank" href="http://www.dell.com/Learn/us/en/uscorp1/secure/2013-03-29-dell-proxy-merger-agreement?c=us&#38;l=en&#38;s=corp&#38;ref=rss&#38;delphi:gr=true">announced today</a> that it has filed its initial proxy materials with the SEC in connection with a merger agreement between Dell, its Chairman and CEO Michael Dell and Silver Lake Partners. Under the terms of the deal, shareholders would received $13.65 in cash for each share of stock, which would be valued at about $24.4 billion. 
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-29-at-5-15-25-pm.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen shot 2013-03-29 at 5.15.25 PM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Dell <a target="_blank" href="http://www.dell.com/Learn/us/en/uscorp1/secure/2013-03-29-dell-proxy-merger-agreement?c=us&amp;l=en&amp;s=corp&amp;ref=rss&amp;delphi:gr=true">announced today</a> that it has filed its initial proxy materials with the SEC in connection with a merger agreement between Dell, its Chairman and CEO Michael Dell and Silver Lake Partners. Under the terms of the deal, shareholders would received $13.65 in cash for each share of stock, which would be valued at about $24.4 billion.</p>
<p>In the rather lengthy filing, some of Dell&#8217;s biggest shareholders like activist billionaire Carl Icahn have urged the company to turn down the deal proposed by Dell and Silver Lake and allow shareholders to stay on as active investors, <a target="_blank" href="http://dealbook.nytimes.com/2013/03/29/what-dell-thought-of-alternatives-to-the-silver-lake-proposal/">according to the New York Times</a>.</p>
<p>The company has essentially been publicly shopping itself around to private-equity firms as part of its negotiated agreement with Silver Lake, during which it received &#8220;two non-binding alternative acquisition proposals,&#8221; including one from <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blackstone_Group">The Blackstone Group</a> and one from investors affiliated with Icahn. Blackstone&#8217;s offer would allow portions of the computer maker to remain a publicly traded company, and Icahn (and JPMorgan&#8217;s supporting review) necessarily indicate that that this agreement would limit Dell&#8217;s financial flexibility and would not be the optimal road to take.</p>
<p>In its letter to shareholders, Dell said that it will continue to work with Silver Lake and Icahn towards what would constitute a more appealing offer for the company and its shareholders, but the letter basically signals that the company will look to move forward with its agreement to merge with Silver Lake. It has yet to see a better alternative.</p>
<p>The letter to shareholders from The Special Committee of Dell&#8217;s board of directors, which was included along with Dell&#8217;s filing today, is included below.</p>
<blockquote><p>March 29, 2013<br />
Dear Shareholders,</p>
<p>Today, at the direction of the Special Committee of the Board of Directors of Dell Inc., the company filed with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission a preliminary proxy statement relating to the proposed acquisition of Dell by affiliates of Silver Lake Partners and Michael S. Dell.</p>
<p>Full Range of Alternatives Evaluated<br />
When the Special Committee was formed last August, we set out to evaluate the full range of strategic and financial alternatives available to the company, including a potential going-private transaction. To assist us in this effort, we hired an experienced group of independent legal and financial advisors and, in addition, retained a top management consulting firm to help us evaluate the risks and opportunities in both the PC business and the company’s effort to transform itself into a more enterprise-centric business. That process, which included more than 25 Special Committee meetings over a period of approximately five and a half months, has highlighted to all of us the significant risks and uncertainties that the company faces as a stand-alone public company. As a result, we as a Committee believe strongly that a transaction that shifts to the buyer the risks associated with Dell’s business, at an acceptable valuation, would be beneficial for Dell’s shareholders.</p>
<p>Silver Lake/Michael Dell Transaction Shifts Risks While Providing Attractive and Certain Cash Premium<br />
The current Silver Lake and Michael Dell transaction delivers $13.65 per share in cash – a 37% premium to Dell’s 90-day average price and a 25% premium to the unaffected price prior to reports in the media about the proposed deal. We believe that this significant, immediate and certain premium offers superior value to owning Dell as a stand-alone entity today.</p>
<p>As part of our agreement with Silver Lake and Michael Dell, we negotiated a robust “go shop” process, which included a 45-day period during which the Special Committee actively sought alternative acquisition proposals as well as a period thereafter in which interested parties can assemble and negotiate acquisition proposals. We are pleased to report that our process has generated two non-binding alternative acquisition proposals, one from a group affiliated with Blackstone Management Partners, L.L.C. (“Blackstone”) and the other from entities affiliated with Carl C. Icahn (“Icahn”). We intend to work diligently with both of them to assist them in their respective due diligence reviews of the company and to seek definitive proposals that would constitute a superior proposal to the current Silver Lake and Michael Dell transaction. Michael Dell has confirmed his willingness to explore participating in alternative acquisition proposals. However, there can be no assurance that either non-binding alternative acquisition proposal will ultimately lead to a superior proposal.</p>
<p>Seeking the Best Outcome for Dell Shareholders<br />
Having conducted a thorough review of Dell’s challenges and opportunities, we remain convinced that the risks and uncertainties of a stand-alone public company are high. While we continue to recommend the current Silver Lake/Michael Dell transaction, and to work toward completion of that transaction, we will also work with Blackstone and Icahn to seek to develop a definitive alternative proposal that provides an even more compelling value proposition for Dell’s shareholders. Our goal was, and remains, to ensure that whatever transaction is consummated is the best possible outcome for Dell’s shareholders.</p>
<p>We are pleased to be serving the Dell shareholders during this important process and we urge you to carefully consider the materials in the preliminary proxy statement.</p>
<p>Sincerely yours,</p>
<p>THE SPECIAL COMMITTEE OF THE<br />
BOARD OF DIRECTORS OF DELL INC.</p></blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788542/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=vGDXIV-NoCY:GGosXlyLzUA:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=vGDXIV-NoCY:GGosXlyLzUA:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=vGDXIV-NoCY:GGosXlyLzUA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=vGDXIV-NoCY:GGosXlyLzUA:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=vGDXIV-NoCY:GGosXlyLzUA:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=vGDXIV-NoCY:GGosXlyLzUA:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=vGDXIV-NoCY:GGosXlyLzUA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=vGDXIV-NoCY:GGosXlyLzUA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/vGDXIV-NoCY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/with-alternative-offers-from-blackstone-icahn-on-the-table-dell-filing-shows-it-will-push-ahead-with-silver-lake-merger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-29-at-5-15-25-pm.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-29-at-5-15-25-pm.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2013-03-29 at 5.15.25 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a94f6b72a8ee7342e862c1c9d6c5b826?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rempson8</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/with-alternative-offers-from-blackstone-icahn-on-the-table-dell-filing-shows-it-will-push-ahead-with-silver-lake-merger/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Bonobos' SF Engineers Split Between NY Relocation And New Company Led By CTO Mike Hart</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/MoBbuzWxx0A/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/bonobos-sf-engineers-split-between-ny-relocation-and-new-company-led-by-cto-mike-hart/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 22:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jordan Crook</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bonobos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mike hart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andy Dunn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cory hicks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788290</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bonobos.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="bonobos" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/bonobos">Bonobos</a>' newly hired San Francisco engineering team is fracturing, but there's no disaster. Bonobos CTO <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/michael-hart">Mike Hart</a> has departed the company to become a co-founder, along with Cory Hicks, of a brand-new business.

After cooking up some hot new personalization technology at Bonobos, Hart and five other engineers from the team will be spinning out that technology into a standalone company separate from Bonobos.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bonobos.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="bonobos" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/bonobos">Bonobos</a>&#8216; newly hired San Francisco engineering team is fracturing, but there&#8217;s no disaster. Bonobos CTO <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/michael-hart">Mike Hart</a> has departed the company to become a co-founder, along with Cory Hicks, of a brand-new business.</p>
<p>After cooking up some hot new personalization technology at Bonobos, Hart and five other engineers from the team will be spinning out that technology into a standalone company separate from Bonobos.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, half of the remaining engineers at Bonobos will be relocating to New York, while the other six have left the company. To be clear, everyone in Palo Alto was offered a relocation package, but some chose New York, while others chose to stay and work on the Hart/Hicks venture, and the rest decided to leave. There were zero layoffs.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the story:</p>
<h3>Cross-Coastal Dilemma</h3>
<p>In late January, Bonobos CEO and founder <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/andy-dunn">Andy Dunn</a> began to realize that the bi-coastal situation wasn&#8217;t working out — the Bonobos brand and retail teams worked out of New York, while the engineering arm remained in Silicon Valley. Not only was traveling back and forth all the time financially taxing on the company, but it was also physically exhausting.</p>
<p>&#8220;It was a different world in 2011, when we were looking to build out our engineering team,&#8221; said Andy. &#8220;We got the impression that NY was light on engineering talent.&#8221; For that reason, Bonobos built out an engineering office in Palo Alto and staffed it with 18 amazing engineers, including Hart and Hicks from Netflix.</p>
<p>But after seeing the cross-coastal offices play out, Andy soon realized that Bonobos required co-located employees, and decided to relocate the Palo Alto engineers to New York.</p>
<p>As Andy worked through this dilemma, Hart was also coming to a realization. He and his PA team were working on a new personalization product for Bonobos based on his years of experience at Netflix handling the same type of curation issues.</p>
<h3>The Split</h3>
<p>After a little A/B testing on the site using the new personalization tech, Bonobos saw a &#8220;really strong revenue lift,&#8221; according to Dunn. Within a few weeks, a decision had been made: Hart would stay in Palo Alto with a handful of developers from Bonobos who were truly passionate about this new venture, and Dunn would try to persuade the remaining engineers to head out to NY.</p>
<p>According to Dunn, the relocation package was a &#8220;meaningful one,&#8221; including a few five-figure checks. However, not everyone wants to pick up their life and move to New York, especially once they&#8217;re entrenched in the Valley, so the 18 developers in Bonobos Palo Alto office split three ways.</p>
<p>Six, including Hart and Hicks, will be working on the mysterious personalization product. Six product team members will come to New York, and the remaining six are no longer with the company.</p>
<p>But that&#8217;s not to say that Bonobos is reducing its engineering efforts — the opposite, in fact. The company plans to have 20 full-stack engineers on the team by the end of this year, and from there grow the engineering team to 30 over the course of the next two years.</p>
<p>Bonobos has also promoted Jon Czaja from VP of Operations to Chief Operating Officer. He was formerly Director of Supply Chain Operations at Walmart, and is the first COO at Bonobos.</p>
<p>&#8220;We just raised a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/bonobos">$30 million round</a>, with which we will become fully profitable,&#8221; said Dunn. &#8220;We want to make this shift at a time when we&#8217;re financially healthy and ready.&#8221;</p>
<h3>The Hart/Hicks Venture</h3>
<p>As for this new personalization product, Mike is keeping pretty mum about the whole thing. So far very little is known about the new company. According to Hart, this product is actually in A/B testing on Bonobos right now, though you&#8217;d be hard-pressed to notice it. It works a lot like personalization on Netflix, but &#8220;far more subtly,&#8221; says Hart.</p>
<p>The team is currently focused on product development, but Hart mentioned that he&#8217;ll probably start looking to raise very soon, and Dunn said that Bonobos would love to be a shareholder, considering the project is Bonobos-bred technology. Hart confirmed that Bonobos will most likely be a participant in upcoming funding rounds, and that Bonobos will probably be the first real customer on the platform if all goes as planned.</p>
<p>The Hart/Hicks Venture will be a platform-as-a-service company, handling the personalization algorithms for its clients.</p>
<p>The product is quite a ways away from a launch — the Hart/Hicks venture (as I like to call it) doesn&#8217;t even have an official name yet — but you should certainly expect to hear more out of Hart <em>and</em> Bonobos in the future.</p>
<p><em>Additional reporting by <a href="http://techcrunch.com/author/josh-constine/">Josh Constine</a> and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/author/john-biggs/">John Biggs</a></em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788290/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=MoBbuzWxx0A:xHXNce5LvYk:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=MoBbuzWxx0A:xHXNce5LvYk:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=MoBbuzWxx0A:xHXNce5LvYk:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=MoBbuzWxx0A:xHXNce5LvYk:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=MoBbuzWxx0A:xHXNce5LvYk:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=MoBbuzWxx0A:xHXNce5LvYk:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=MoBbuzWxx0A:xHXNce5LvYk:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=MoBbuzWxx0A:xHXNce5LvYk:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/MoBbuzWxx0A" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/bonobos-sf-engineers-split-between-ny-relocation-and-new-company-led-by-cto-mike-hart/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bonobos.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bonobos.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bonobos</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/123a4c264172746af556b0c74c72b308?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">biggsismyboss</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/bonobos-sf-engineers-split-between-ny-relocation-and-new-company-led-by-cto-mike-hart/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Stranded In SF? Corral Rides Shows Uber, Lyft, Sidecar And Muni In One App</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/_Hd2nGoA2H4/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/stranded-in-sf-corral-rides-shows-uber-lyft-sidecar-and-muni-in-one-app/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 21:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Greg Kumparak</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788275</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/uber.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="uber" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Super Awesome Party A has just ended, and you need to figure out how to get to Super Awesome Party B <em>stat</em>... and preferably by spending as little money as possible. 

So what do you do? Muni? Uber? Lyft? Sidecar? Hoof it? You could switch between half a dozen different apps and try to figure out which of the options is cheapest and fastest... 

Or you could just open Corral Rides.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/uber.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="uber" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p></p>
<p>Super Awesome SF Party A has just ended, and you need to figure out how to get to Super Awesome SF Party B <em>stat</em>&#8230; and preferably by spending as little money as possible. </p>
<p>So what do you do? Muni? Uber? Lyft? Sidecar? Hoof it? You could switch between half a dozen different apps and try to figure out which of the options is cheapest and fastest&#8230; </p>
<p>Or you could just open Corral Rides.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.getcorral.com/">Corral Rides </a>(&#8220;Corral&#8221; as in the thing that holds a bunch of cows, not &#8220;Coral&#8221; as in the amazing ocean animals) is a transportation aggregator. You punch in where you are and where you wanna go, and it breaks down the prices and times for each of your options. Walking? It&#8217;ll take you a while, but it&#8217;s free. Bus? The next one leaves in 10 minutes. Need to get there fast? There&#8217;s an Uber driver 2 minutes away, but it&#8217;ll cost you about $40 bucks.</p>
<p>(<strong>Note:</strong> Because of the services the app focuses on, it really works best in San Francisco at the moment.)<br />
<br />
&#8220;But wait!&#8221; shouts a developer back at home. &#8220;Uber and Lyft and Sidecar don&#8217;t have public APIs! How are they getting this information?&#8221;</p>
<p>Yeah&#8230; about that.</p>
<p>In a nutshell: it&#8217;s a bit of a hack. But don&#8217;t panic! It&#8217;s the good kind of hacking. Or, at least, the not-terrible kind of hacking. The Corral guys had to sniff out the APIs that Uber and co. are using to grab data in their own apps, and use those. They stop short of tapping any private APIs that require user authentication for security reasons, which means that the app has to switch you over to the appropriate app when you actually try to summon a car.</p>
<p>&#8220;But wait!&#8221; shouts the developer who seems to really enjoy shouting things at his screen. &#8220;Isn&#8217;t there a chance those services will get upset about this?&#8221;</p>
<p>Yeah, of course. But Corral is willing to play friendly:</p>
<p>&#8220;If any of them email us and ask us to stop,&#8221; says co-founder Noam Szpiro, &#8220;we will. The way we see it though, we&#8217;re just sending them free traffic and customers. If they want to be the option <em>not</em> listed, that&#8217;s up to them.&#8221;<br />
<br />
Corral Rides was built in about a month by Noam and his co-founder Snir Kodesh, both ex-Ooyala engineers. Corral Rides is actually a spin-off — a pivot, if you will — from a project they&#8217;d started a few months prior, which was meant to do a similar sort of aggregation across a broader array of apps (including things like restaurant reviews and reservations, movie times, etc.) When they looked at the data and realized that the vast majority of their test users were looking for transportation info, they decided to slim down.</p>
<p>Corral is thus far entirely bootstrapped, and they&#8217;re not searching for funding just yet (though they mention that they might look into joining an accelerator or incubator in the upcoming season).</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that this one app isn&#8217;t their entire long-term vision — it just plays a small part in it. They&#8217;d only fill me in on the big picture off-the-record, so I can&#8217;t say much — but what I <em>can</em> say is that if it all comes together, it&#8217;s going to be pretty great. These two guys are ones to watch.</p>
<p>You can find <a target="_blank" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/corral-rides/id615865417">Corral Rides in the iOS App Store here</a>, with an Android app being the next thing on the team&#8217;s to-do list.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788275/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_Hd2nGoA2H4:zra4a7dUSak:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_Hd2nGoA2H4:zra4a7dUSak:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_Hd2nGoA2H4:zra4a7dUSak:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_Hd2nGoA2H4:zra4a7dUSak:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=_Hd2nGoA2H4:zra4a7dUSak:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_Hd2nGoA2H4:zra4a7dUSak:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=_Hd2nGoA2H4:zra4a7dUSak:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=_Hd2nGoA2H4:zra4a7dUSak:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/_Hd2nGoA2H4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/stranded-in-sf-corral-rides-shows-uber-lyft-sidecar-and-muni-in-one-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/uber.jpg?w=99" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/uber.jpg?w=99" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">uber</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/86f75cc66896ab9b0602715f082803d6?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gregkumparak</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/corral-logo.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Corral logo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/uber.jpg?w=199" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">uber</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-29-at-2-34-14-pm.png?w=200" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-03-29 at 2.34.14 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/stranded-in-sf-corral-rides-shows-uber-lyft-sidecar-and-muni-in-one-app/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Kicking Off Our Flip Off - Meet The "TechCrunch Weekly" Magazine On Flipboard</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/phBWG7gvDoc/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/kicking-off-our-flip-off-meet-the-techcrunch-weekly-magazine-on-flipboard/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 21:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Drew Olanoff</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flipboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[techcrunch weekly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magazine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Publishing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788295</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/techcrunch-weeklyfb.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="techcrunch-weeklyfb" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Flipboard this week announced a new version of its app that allows anyone to make a &#8220;Magazine,&#8221; which is a curated collection of stories based on any topic that you can think of. The company has shared that over 100,000 magazines have been created since the feature launched. We&#8217;ve decided to put together our own magazine called &#8220;TechCrunch Weekly,&#8221; which will be full of the best TechCrunch stories from the past week, refreshed every Friday afternoon. As you know, our staff works hard to write about every technology topic imaginable, and it&#8217;s hard to keep up with all of it. Along with the really great &#8220;flipping&#8221; experience of Flipboard on mobile devices, using the app is one of the best ways to catch up on news that you missed because you were checking Facebook working, or to give yourself a chance to re-read something that you only skimmed the first time. Just to give you an idea of what you&#8217;ll find in this week&#8217;s edition, there&#8217;s possibly a Facebook Android OS coming out, Bitcoin&#8217;s worth a billion, Google Glass explorers got the boot, BlackBerry did things wrong, OUYA is a real product and paying for things with fingerprints is a thing. We&#8217;ll also be sharing some of our more interesting guest posts from the weekend. That&#8217;s a pretty full week of news, and now you can sit back, relax and flip through all of the stories with Flipboard and TechCrunch Weekly on your iOS or Android device. Click or tap here to check it out, or search for TechCrunch on Flipboard. Under the main navigation up top, find the magazine, subscribe, read and wait for a new edition to show up with new content every Friday afternoon. This is the future of publishing and it&#8217;s fun to be involved.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/techcrunch-weeklyfb.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="techcrunch-weeklyfb" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Flipboard this week <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/26/the-new-flipboard-lets-you-create-your-own-mobile-magazine-adds-search-etsy-and-more/">announced a new version of its app</a> that allows anyone to make a &#8220;Magazine,&#8221; which is a curated collection of stories based on any topic that you can think of. The company has shared that over <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Flipboard/status/317713050637586432">100,000 magazines have been created</a> since the feature launched.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve decided to put together our own magazine called &#8220;<a target="_blank" href="http://flip.it/ZmA0V">TechCrunch Weekly</a>,&#8221; which will be full of the best TechCrunch stories from the past week, refreshed every Friday afternoon.</p>
<p>As you know, our staff works hard to write about every technology topic imaginable, and it&#8217;s hard to keep up with all of it. Along with the really great &#8220;flipping&#8221; experience of Flipboard on mobile devices, using the app is one of the best ways to catch up on news that you missed because you were <del datetime="2013-03-29T20:34:15+00:00">checking Facebook</del> working, or to give yourself a chance to re-read something that you only skimmed the first time.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-41.png"></a></p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-51.png"></a>Just to give you an idea of what you&#8217;ll find in this week&#8217;s edition, there&#8217;s possibly a Facebook Android OS coming out, Bitcoin&#8217;s worth a billion, Google Glass explorers got the boot, BlackBerry did things wrong, OUYA is a real product and paying for things with fingerprints is a thing. We&#8217;ll also be sharing some of our more interesting guest posts from the weekend. That&#8217;s a pretty full week of news, and now you can sit back, relax and flip through all of the stories with Flipboard and TechCrunch Weekly on your iOS or Android device.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://flip.it/ZmA0V">Click or tap here</a> to check it out, or search for TechCrunch on Flipboard. Under the main navigation up top, find the magazine, subscribe, read and wait for a new edition to show up with new content every Friday afternoon.</p>
<p>This is the future of publishing and it&#8217;s fun to be involved.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788295/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=phBWG7gvDoc:j8ekLex7FSI:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=phBWG7gvDoc:j8ekLex7FSI:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=phBWG7gvDoc:j8ekLex7FSI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=phBWG7gvDoc:j8ekLex7FSI:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=phBWG7gvDoc:j8ekLex7FSI:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=phBWG7gvDoc:j8ekLex7FSI:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=phBWG7gvDoc:j8ekLex7FSI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=phBWG7gvDoc:j8ekLex7FSI:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/phBWG7gvDoc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/kicking-off-our-flip-off-meet-the-techcrunch-weekly-magazine-on-flipboard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/techcrunch-weeklyfb.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/techcrunch-weeklyfb.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">techcrunch-weeklyfb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b0be7dc9dffd2413ec89e6ebb54da179?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thatdrew</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-41.png?w=480" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo-4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-51.png?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo-5</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/kicking-off-our-flip-off-meet-the-techcrunch-weekly-magazine-on-flipboard/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Ask A VC: AngelList's Naval Ravikant On The Currency Of Silicon Valley And More</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/G4xpuIXalL8/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/ask-a-vc-angellists-naval-ravikant-on-the-currency-of-silicon-valley-and-more/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 21:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leena Rao</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788291</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/naval-1.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="naval-1" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />AngelList&#8217;s Naval Ravikant joined us in the TechCrunch TV studio for our Ask A VC series, where we put VCs in the hot seat. Ravikant talked about the currency of Silicon Valley, which he says is deals shared, talent referred, and acquirers introduced. He explains that AngelList, a service he co-founded that matches early-stage startups with investors, puts these transactions online. We also chatted about his secret to picking the right startups for angel investments (Ravikant invested in Twitter, Foursquare, BranchOut, Codecademy, Uber, Heyzap and Disqus). Check out the video above for more!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/naval-1.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="naval-1" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><script type="text/javascript" src="http://pshared.5min.com/Scripts/PlayerSeed.js?sid=577&#038;width=640&#038;height=450&#038;colorPallet=%230A9600&#038;hasCompanion=false&#038;relatedMode=2&#038;videoControlDisplayColor=%23000000&#038;playList=517690133&#038;shuffle=0&#038;videoGroupID=133503&#038;autoStart=false&#038;playerActions=16407"></script>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://angel.co/">AngelList&#8217;s</a> <a target="_blank" href="https://angel.co/naval">Naval Ravikant</a> joined us in the TechCrunch TV studio for our Ask A VC series, where we put VCs in the hot seat.</p>
<p>Ravikant talked about the currency of Silicon Valley, which he says is deals shared, talent referred, and acquirers introduced. He explains that AngelList, a service he co-founded that matches early-stage startups with investors, puts these transactions online. We also chatted about his secret to picking the right startups for angel investments (Ravikant invested in Twitter, Foursquare, BranchOut, Codecademy, Uber, Heyzap and Disqus).</p>
<p>Check out the video above for more!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788291/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G4xpuIXalL8:j1GN3KeBUFY:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G4xpuIXalL8:j1GN3KeBUFY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G4xpuIXalL8:j1GN3KeBUFY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G4xpuIXalL8:j1GN3KeBUFY:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=G4xpuIXalL8:j1GN3KeBUFY:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G4xpuIXalL8:j1GN3KeBUFY:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=G4xpuIXalL8:j1GN3KeBUFY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G4xpuIXalL8:j1GN3KeBUFY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/G4xpuIXalL8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/ask-a-vc-angellists-naval-ravikant-on-the-currency-of-silicon-valley-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/naval-1.jpeg?w=127" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/naval-1.jpeg?w=127" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">naval-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bbce6c3c48f821c81c019600a5589ae6?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">leena</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/ask-a-vc-angellists-naval-ravikant-on-the-currency-of-silicon-valley-and-more/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook's Home On Android Could Give You A Sixth Sense For Your Social Life</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/yLqy1CElVkY/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/facebook-home/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 21:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Josh Constine</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788218</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/facebook-heads-up-display.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Facebook Heads Up Display" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Constant, close contact with your friends. That's the promise of a "Facebook phone". The modified Android OS and mobile homescreen replacement sources tell us Facebook will unveil April 4th pushes your social life to you so fetching it isn't interruptive. The News feed brought us ambient intimacy, but Facebook's homescreen could turn that social graph awareness into a sixth sense.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/facebook-heads-up-display.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Facebook Heads Up Display" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Constant, close contact with your friends. That&#8217;s the promise of a &#8220;Facebook phone.&#8221; The modified Android OS and mobile homescreen replacement that sources tell us <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/28/facebook-android-phone/">Facebook will unveil April 4th</a> pushes your social life to you so fetching it isn&#8217;t interruptive. The news feed brought us ambient intimacy, but Facebook&#8217;s homescreen could turn that social graph awareness into a sixth sense.</p>
<p>While it only takes a quarter of a minute each time, reaching for your phone, waking it from sleep, firing up the Facebook app, and loading your latest notifications does pull you out of the present. Checking the news feed for the latest photos and stories from your friends is a conscious decision. You&#8217;re either living your life or reading Facebook. The social network would surely prefer those to be one and the same.</p>
<p>If that data automatically fed right into your homescreen, every time you opened your phone you&#8217;d be instantly up to date on conversations with friends and get a peek into their lives. And if Facebook can pipe this content into the lock screen, it&#8217;d be even more immersive, like a true heads-up display. It&#8217;s a deeper way to plug in, where the shell disappears and you gain a more visceral connection to the people you care about.</p>
<p>This is the purpose of what Facebook plans to launch next week, which <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/28/facebook-android-phone/">my sources got me the scoop on right when the big press event was announced yesterday</a>. It&#8217;s a Facebook-ified homescreen that will be shown off on an HTC handset running a version of Android modified by Facebook, similar to what Amazon did to create the Kindle operating system.</p>
<p>Making Facebook an indigenous resident of your phone&#8217;s homescreen could accelerate your social life. It might reduce the time it takes you to respond to messages or continue a comment thread. If a friend is down the street, Facebook could have a better chance of advising you to join them. Giving Facebook a way to tell you more directly about what&#8217;s going on in your immediate vicinity could be important as it focuses more on <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/12/17/facebook-nearby/">local discovery</a>.</p>
<p>If this all seems like Facebook overload to you, you probably won&#8217;t buy the HTC phone just to sport this new homescreen. In the past, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/28/fast-track-to-a-facebook-phone-buy-inq-mobile/">sales</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://bgr.com/2012/02/17/forget-the-facebook-phone-survey-finds-consumers-want-an-amazon-phone/">surveys</a> of sentiments about a Facebook-integrated handset have shown little demand of a &#8216;Facebook Phone&#8217; with a capital P.</p>
<p>But if it didn&#8217;t interfere with or detract from your other apps and overall smartphone experience, but just augmented it with live social info, a &#8216;Facebook phone&#8217; with a lowercase &#8216;p&#8217; and its social homescreen could become something you wouldn&#8217;t mind having. Maybe it wouldn&#8217;t be a priority when buying a handset, but &#8220;Facebook Home-enabled&#8221; could be another feature in a device&#8217;s &#8220;Pros&#8221; column. And if Facebook made a more basic version of the homescreen replacement available as a traditional app download for all Android phones, I think a fair amount of hardcore social networkers would install it.</p>
<p>After  all, it would put you on the cutting edge of Facebook&#8217;s technology. Similar to how Facebook uses its <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/09/standalone-guinea-pigs/">standalone apps</a> like Messenger and its new <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/17/its-alive-mwa-ha-ha-ha/">Android beta club</a> to field test new features with a set of guinea pig early adopters, Facebook Home could let people experience the next wave of social before it trickles down to iOS and the rest of the world.</p>
<p>That, combined with the immersive, non-interruptive experience I describe above are why I see Facebook&#8217;s new &#8220;Home On Android&#8221; as its version of the iWatch or Google Glass. It might not appeal to everyone just yet, but some will want to experience Facebook&#8217;s vision for the future of friendship.</p>
<p><em>[Image Credit: <a target="_blank" href="http://marvel.com/ironman3">Iron Man / Marvel / Disney</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://haxterslab.blogspot.com/2010/08/how-to-use-facebook-places-on-your.html">Haxters Lab</a>]</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788218/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yLqy1CElVkY:k3S5tfIMWWg:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yLqy1CElVkY:k3S5tfIMWWg:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yLqy1CElVkY:k3S5tfIMWWg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yLqy1CElVkY:k3S5tfIMWWg:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=yLqy1CElVkY:k3S5tfIMWWg:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yLqy1CElVkY:k3S5tfIMWWg:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=yLqy1CElVkY:k3S5tfIMWWg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yLqy1CElVkY:k3S5tfIMWWg:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/yLqy1CElVkY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/facebook-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/facebook-heads-up-display.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/facebook-heads-up-display.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Facebook Heads Up Display</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fd3b857e7f0024396cdbd36c4c102a5d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">joshsc</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/facebook-homescreen-notifications-done.png?w=394" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Facebook Homescreen Notifications Done</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/facebook-home/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>LivingSocial Co-Founder And CTO Aaron Batalion To Leave The Company</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/U1I2YqP8dNA/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/livingsocial-co-founder-and-cto-aaron-batalion-to-leave-the-company/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 20:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Colleen Taylor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788296</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/aaronbatalion.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Image of Aaron Batalion via his LinkedIn profile" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/aaron-batalion">Aaron Batalion</a>, the co-founder and CTO of daily deals site <a target="_blank" href="http://www.livingsocial.com">LivingSocial</a>, is leaving the company. He announced his departure in <a target="_blank" href="http://aaronbatalion.com/post/46617716711/moving-on-to-new-adventures">a post on his personal blog</a> published Friday afternoon.

We've reached out to Batalion for more details on his exit and his plans for the future, and will update with anything we hear. For now, here is the full text of his blog post:]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/aaronbatalion.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Image of Aaron Batalion via his LinkedIn profile" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/aaron-batalion">Aaron Batalion</a>, the co-founder and CTO of daily deals site <a target="_blank" href="http://www.livingsocial.com">LivingSocial</a>, is leaving the company. He announced his departure in <a target="_blank" href="http://aaronbatalion.com/post/46617716711/moving-on-to-new-adventures">a post on his personal blog</a> published Friday afternoon.</p>
<p>Here is the full text of his blog post:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Moving on to new adventures…</p>
<p>What an incredible journey it has been since June of 2007, when the four of us knew only our direction, but definitely not our destination. After much soul searching, I have decided to leave LivingSocial to pursue some new ideas. No new adventure to announce yet, just a urge to go create… that there is more to do.</p>
<p>As I look back today, we have processed billions in commerce transactions and have sent tens of billions of emails on technology we created. We took a simple two-week prototype and scaled it to an international business with thousands of fellow employees around the world. We built a culture I am proud of and millions of consumers around the world have experienced their local cities because of our products. More importantly, we created an incredible team with many more strong moves yet to come. Knowing this makes me confident in LivingSocial’s future and the vision of local we have all been fighting for.</p>
<p>I am incredibly proud of what the team has accomplished to date and have been so fortunate to play a role in this amazing journey. My decision to depart has in no way been easy. The experience and, most importantly, the friendships… have been the best of my career.</p>
<p>Always live hungry,</p>
<p>Aaron&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>And here is the internal memo regarding Batalion&#8217;s departure from LivingSocial&#8217;s CEO <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/tim-oshaughnessy">Tim O&#8217;Shaughnessy</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
&#8220;Hey folks,</p>
<p>I wanted to pass along an update.</p>
<p>Over the last few years, I&#8217;ve had the pleasure of working with Aaron Batalion, first at Revolution Health, and then as a co-founder of LivingSocial. Now we&#8217;ll get to see what else is in store for Aaron in the future. He&#8217;ll be moving from a day-to-day role as an employee to an outside advisory role, where he&#8217;ll help me and the company with hiring senior technologists and act on a consultative basis with the technology team, among other things.</p>
<p>Aaron has been an important part of LivingSocial&#8217;s story since there wasn&#8217;t even a LivingSocial, just a Hungry Machine and he&#8217;ll continue to be important moving forward. I&#8217;ve tried to emulate his consistent drive and passion, but with limited success because there is only one &#8220;Tank&#8221;. We owe him a great deal of thanks for the long days, nights and weekends he has given to this company and in helping to grow and scale our technology team. Please wish him the best of luck as he moves on to whatever is next outside of LS and transitions to an advisory role at the company. If you&#8217;re ever in SF, where he&#8217;s been based since last summer, don&#8217;t hesitate to drop him a line.</p>
<p>&#8211; Tim&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Batalion&#8217;s departure comes just one month after LivingSocial <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/20/daily-deals-site-livingsocial-raises-another-110-million/">raised $110 million</a> in a massive new round of funding. The company has raised more than $800 million since it was founded in 2007. It&#8217;s been a complicated road in some ways lately for the company, which <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/29/livingsocial-confirms-layoffs-400-all-but-a-couple-dozen-in-the-u-s-10-of-workforce/">laid off some 400 staffers</a> back in November. While its 2012 revenue was $536 million, the company is not turning a profit, posting a net loss for the year of $650 million.</p>
<p>The fresh funding secured in February (which was raised <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/21/livingsocial-ceo-provides-more-details-on-110-million-funding-round-now-valued-at-about-1-5-billion/">at a $1.5 billion valuation</a>) is sure to kick off some new projects for LivingSocial in the months ahead, but it seems that one core member of LivingSocial&#8217;s team will not be a part of them.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788296/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=U1I2YqP8dNA:2eJq8hyKvkY:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=U1I2YqP8dNA:2eJq8hyKvkY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=U1I2YqP8dNA:2eJq8hyKvkY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=U1I2YqP8dNA:2eJq8hyKvkY:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=U1I2YqP8dNA:2eJq8hyKvkY:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=U1I2YqP8dNA:2eJq8hyKvkY:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=U1I2YqP8dNA:2eJq8hyKvkY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=U1I2YqP8dNA:2eJq8hyKvkY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/U1I2YqP8dNA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/livingsocial-co-founder-and-cto-aaron-batalion-to-leave-the-company/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/aaronbatalion.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/aaronbatalion.jpeg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">aaronbatalion</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4978d78871dc3ed1a4264d051e6c9193?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">colleentechcrunch</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/livingsocial-co-founder-and-cto-aaron-batalion-to-leave-the-company/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft: jQuery 2.0 Will Add Full Support For Windows Store Apps</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/r6_rKm1dzJY/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/microsoft-jquery-2-0-will-add-full-support-for-windows-store-apps/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 20:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Frederic Lardinois</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jquery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jquery 2.0]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788259</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/3007-jqueryonwinrt_196b064b.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="3007.jQueryonWinRT_196B064B" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />The next version of jQuery, the popular JavaScript library, will drop support for Internet Explorer 6, 7, and 8, but that doesn&#8217;t mean Microsoft isn&#8217;t very bullish about getting developers to use jQuery 2.0 and HTML5 to develop &#8220;a new wave of jQuery-based Windows Store applications.&#8221; As Microsoft announced today, Microsoft Open Technologies, the company&#8217;s wholly owned open source-focused subsidiary, and the JavaScript experts at appendTo, have been working with the jQuery community to ensure that the next version of the framework offers full support for Windows Store applications. Developers could obviously already build Windows Store/Metro apps with jQuery, but thanks to this cooperation, the process for developing jQuery 2.0-based Windows Store applications should now be smoother, safer and more streamlined. As appendTo&#8217;s director of support Jonathan Sampson wrote in today&#8217;s announcement, jQuery always met the language criteria for Windows Store applications, but &#8220;Windows 8 exposes all the WinRT APIs within the HTML5 development environment, which comes with a new security model that made some code and common practices of jQuery flagged as unsafe in the context of a Windows Store application. AppendTo reviewed and re-authored portions of jQuery core to bring it into alignment with the Windows security model, as well as identified key areas where alternative patterns would need to be substituted for actually-used conventions.” Even though Microsoft has always stressed this in the run-up to the Windows 8 launch, quite a few developers are still unaware that they can use their web development skills to write desktop apps for Windows 8 and Windows RT. Developers, by the way, can already use a number of other open-source JavaScript frameworks, including backbone.js, Knockout.JS and YUI. As Deve Methvin, the president of the jQuery Foundation noted in a prepared statement today, that&#8217;s also something his organization is interested in. “The jQuery team is excited about the new environments where jQuery 2.0 can be used. HTML and JavaScript developers want to take their jQuery knowledge with them to streamline the development process wherever they work. jQuery 2.0 gives them the ability to do that in Windows 8 Store applications. We appreciate the help from appendTo for both its patches and testing of jQuery 2.0 and MS Open Tech for its technical support.”]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/3007-jqueryonwinrt_196b064b.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="3007.jQueryonWinRT_196B064B" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>The <a target="_blank" href="http://blog.jquery.com/2013/03/01/jquery-2-0-beta-2-released/">next version of jQuery</a>, the popular JavaScript library, will drop support for Internet Explorer 6, 7, and 8, but that doesn&#8217;t mean Microsoft isn&#8217;t very bullish about getting developers to use jQuery 2.0 and HTML5 to develop &#8220;a new wave of jQuery-based Windows Store applications.&#8221;</p>
<p>As Microsoft <a target="_blank" href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/interoperability/archive/2013/03/29/jquery-adds-support-for-windows-store-apps-creates-new-opportunities-for-javascript-open-source-developers.aspx">announced</a> today, <a target="_blank" href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/interoperability/archive/2012/04/12/announcing-one-more-way-microsoft-will-engage-with-the-open-source-and-standards-communities.aspx">Microsoft Open Technologies</a>, the company&#8217;s wholly owned open source-focused subsidiary, and the JavaScript experts at <a target="_blank" href="http://appendto.com/blog/2013/03/windows-store-applications-with-jquery-2-0/">appendTo</a>, have been working with the jQuery community to ensure that the next version of the framework offers full support for Windows Store applications.</p>
<p>Developers could obviously <a target="_blank" href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/Build/2012/3-130">already</a> build Windows Store/Metro apps with jQuery, but thanks to this cooperation, the process for developing jQuery 2.0-based Windows Store applications should now be smoother, <a target="_blank" href="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/javascript-ajax/building-windows-store-applications-with-jquery-2-0/">safer</a> and more streamlined.</p>
<p>As appendTo&#8217;s director of support <a target="_blank" href="http://twitter.com/jonathansampson">Jonathan Sampson</a> wrote in today&#8217;s announcement, jQuery always met the language criteria for Windows Store applications, but &#8220;Windows 8 exposes all the WinRT APIs within the HTML5 development environment, which comes with a new security model that made some code and common practices of jQuery flagged as unsafe in the context of a Windows Store application. AppendTo reviewed and re-authored portions of jQuery core to bring it into alignment with the Windows security model, as well as identified key areas where alternative patterns would need to be substituted for actually-used conventions.”</p>
<p>Even though Microsoft has always stressed this in the run-up to the Windows 8 launch, quite a few developers are still unaware that they can use their web development skills <a target="_blank" href="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/javascript-ajax/building-windows-store-applications-with-jquery-2-0/">to write desktop apps for Windows 8 and Windows RT</a>. Developers, by the way, can already use a number of other open-source JavaScript frameworks, including <a target="_blank" href="http://documentcloud.github.com/backbone/">backbone.js</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://knockoutjs.com/">Knockout.JS</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://yuilibrary.com/">YUI</a>.</p>
<p>As Deve Methvin, the president of the jQuery Foundation noted in a prepared statement today, that&#8217;s also something his organization is interested in. “The jQuery team is excited about the new environments where jQuery 2.0 can be used. HTML and JavaScript developers want to take their jQuery knowledge with them to streamline the development process wherever they work. jQuery 2.0 gives them the ability to do that in Windows 8 Store applications. We appreciate the help from appendTo for both its patches and testing of jQuery 2.0 and MS Open Tech for its technical support.”</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788259/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=r6_rKm1dzJY:3l6sUgzy1AM:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=r6_rKm1dzJY:3l6sUgzy1AM:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=r6_rKm1dzJY:3l6sUgzy1AM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=r6_rKm1dzJY:3l6sUgzy1AM:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=r6_rKm1dzJY:3l6sUgzy1AM:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=r6_rKm1dzJY:3l6sUgzy1AM:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=r6_rKm1dzJY:3l6sUgzy1AM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=r6_rKm1dzJY:3l6sUgzy1AM:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/r6_rKm1dzJY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/microsoft-jquery-2-0-will-add-full-support-for-windows-store-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/3007-jqueryonwinrt_196b064b.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/3007-jqueryonwinrt_196b064b.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">3007.jQueryonWinRT_196B064B</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/55542aa717199728948f628edc1170b1?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fredericlardinois</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/microsoft-jquery-2-0-will-add-full-support-for-windows-store-apps/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillmor Gang Live  03.29.13 (TCTV)</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/yrg7gdKkZo0/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/gillmor-gang-live-03-29-13-tctv/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 20:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve Gillmor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Remove From TC River]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788227</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/gillmore-gang-test-pattern.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Gillmor Gang test pattern" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><strong>Gillmor Gang</strong> - Doc Searls, Robert Scoble, Kevin Marks, and Steve Gillmor. <strong>Recording for today has concluded.</strong>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/gillmore-gang-test-pattern.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Gillmor Gang test pattern" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><strong>Gillmor Gang</strong> &#8211; Doc Searls, Robert Scoble, Kevin Marks, and Steve Gillmor. <strong>Recording for today has concluded.</strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788227/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yrg7gdKkZo0:3FXesb1bzhY:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yrg7gdKkZo0:3FXesb1bzhY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yrg7gdKkZo0:3FXesb1bzhY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yrg7gdKkZo0:3FXesb1bzhY:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=yrg7gdKkZo0:3FXesb1bzhY:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yrg7gdKkZo0:3FXesb1bzhY:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=yrg7gdKkZo0:3FXesb1bzhY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yrg7gdKkZo0:3FXesb1bzhY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/yrg7gdKkZo0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/gillmor-gang-live-03-29-13-tctv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/gillmore-gang-test-pattern.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/gillmore-gang-test-pattern.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gillmor Gang test pattern</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e819990a43a5972b40593cdc6896eef9?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">steve</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/gillmor-gang-live-03-29-13-tctv/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Treasure Data Projects 500 Percent Growth This Year, Launches New “Plazma” Distributed Database</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/xd395rmWfAY/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/treasure-data-projects-500-percent-growth-this-year-launches-new-plazma-distributed-database/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Michael Seo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788149</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tdlogo.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="tdlogo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />It’s only been six months since cloud data warehousing company Treasure Data launched its services, but they’re already reporting some impressive growth figures. Treasure Data achieved month-to-month profitability last year, and they’re well on track to achieve a 500 percent increase in revenue this year. They’ve also amassed 50 high-profile clients, which include a leading social gaming company, a mobile advertising platform based in France, and some other Fortune 500 companies &#8211; unsurprisingly, Treasure declined to name names. Treasure Data is basically a massive warehouse in the cloud for companies to store their data. Big companies like IBM, Oracle, and Teradata offer data services as well, but with their rates going as high as $5 million, that’s not something every business can afford. Treasure Data, on the other hand, costs $1,500 to $2,500 a month with a year-long commitment. That&#8217;s a low enough price point for companies that can&#8217;t afford or do not have the resources to roll out services of their own. They’re also launching a new distributed database called Plazma, which offers significant improvements over HDFS (Hadoop Distributed Files System). Plazma is significantly better than HDFS precisely because it’s more efficient and is able to compile and parse data at a much faster rate. “The reason we did this was for robustness, reliability, and performance,” says Kiyoto Tamura, VP of Product at Treasure Data. “Hadoop distributed several problems around reliability, and we knew we could do better.” With Plazma, Treasure Data boasts that their systems are processing more than 300 billion data points every day.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tdlogo.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="tdlogo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>It’s only been six months since cloud data warehousing company <a target="_blank" href="http://www.treasure-data.com/">Treasure Data</a> <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/09/28/treasure-data-launches-cloud-based-data-warehouse-with-investment-from-ruby-creator-yukihiro-matz-matsumoto/">launched its services</a>, but they’re already reporting some impressive growth figures.</p>
<p>Treasure Data achieved month-to-month profitability last year, and they’re well on track to achieve a 500 percent increase in revenue this year. They’ve also amassed 50 high-profile clients, which include a leading social gaming company, a mobile advertising platform based in France, and some other Fortune 500 companies &#8211; unsurprisingly, Treasure declined to name names.</p>
<p>Treasure Data is basically a massive warehouse in the cloud for companies to store their data. Big companies like IBM, Oracle, and Teradata offer data services as well, but with their rates going as high as $5 million, that’s not something every business can afford.</p>
<p>Treasure Data, on the other hand, costs $1,500 to $2,500 a month with a year-long commitment. That&#8217;s a low enough price point for companies that can&#8217;t afford or do not have the resources to roll out services of their own.</p>
<p>They’re also launching a new distributed database called Plazma, which offers significant improvements over HDFS (Hadoop Distributed Files System). Plazma is significantly better than HDFS precisely because it’s more efficient and is able to compile and parse data at a much faster rate.</p>
<p>“The reason we did this was for robustness, reliability, and performance,” says Kiyoto Tamura, VP of Product at Treasure Data. “Hadoop distributed several problems around reliability, and we knew we could do better.”</p>
<p>With Plazma, Treasure Data boasts that their systems are processing more than 300 billion data points every day.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788149/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xd395rmWfAY:DmkW1Sfeecs:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xd395rmWfAY:DmkW1Sfeecs:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xd395rmWfAY:DmkW1Sfeecs:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xd395rmWfAY:DmkW1Sfeecs:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=xd395rmWfAY:DmkW1Sfeecs:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xd395rmWfAY:DmkW1Sfeecs:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=xd395rmWfAY:DmkW1Sfeecs:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xd395rmWfAY:DmkW1Sfeecs:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/xd395rmWfAY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/treasure-data-projects-500-percent-growth-this-year-launches-new-plazma-distributed-database/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tdlogo.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tdlogo.jpeg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tdlogo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ae07a5f4edc143a76fd9fbd362f9dd65?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mseo2578</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/treasure-data-projects-500-percent-growth-this-year-launches-new-plazma-distributed-database/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch Giveaway: Fitbit One, Aria Smart Scale And A Ticket To Disrupt NY</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/SyQA5OVOeAk/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/techcrunch-giveaway-fitbit-one-aria-smart-scale-and-a-ticket-to-disrupt-ny/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Elin Blesener</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=788221</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fitbit.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="fitbit" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Happy Friday, everyone. As you know, we love giving things away here at TechCrunch, and this week, we have a Fitbit One Wireless Activity + Sleep Tracker and an Aria Wi-Fi Smart Scale to give away. But that&#8217;s not all! TechCrunch Disrupt NY is right around the corner and tickets are going super fast, so we want to give away another ticket to a deserving person who would like to attend (and then party with us). The winner of this giveaway will win all three &#8212; the Fitbit One ($99.95), the Smart Scale ($129.95) and a free ticket to Disrupt NY (valued at $1,995 right now). Want a shot to win all three? Follow the steps below. 1) Become a fan of our TechCrunch Facebook Page: 2) Then do one of the following: Retweet this post (making sure to include the #TCDisrupt hashtag), or Leave us a comment below telling us something fun &#8211; anything! The contest will start now and end April 5th at 7:30pm PT. Please only tweet or comment once, or you will be disqualified. We will make sure you follow the steps above and choose our winner once the giveaway is over. Please note the winner will only receive one (1) free Disrupt ticket, and it does not include airfare or hotel. Our sponsors help make Disrupt happen. If you are interested in learning more about sponsorship opportunities, please contact our sponsorship team here sponsors@techcrunch.com.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fitbit.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="fitbit" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Happy Friday, everyone. As you know, we love giving things away here at TechCrunch, and this week, we have a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.fitbit.com/one">Fitbit One Wireless Activity + Sleep Tracker</a> and an <a target="_blank" href="http://www.fitbit.com/aria">Aria Wi-Fi Smart Scale</a> to give away. But that&#8217;s not all!</p>
<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/disrupt-ny-2013/">TechCrunch Disrupt NY</a> is right around the corner and tickets are going super fast, so we want to give away another ticket to a deserving person who would like to attend (and then party with us). The winner of this giveaway will win all three &#8212; the Fitbit One ($99.95), the Smart Scale ($129.95) and a free ticket to Disrupt NY (valued at $1,995 right now).</p>
<p>Want a shot to win all three? Follow the steps below.</p>
<p>1) <strong>Become a fan of our TechCrunch Facebook Page:</strong></p>
<iframe src="http://www.facebook.com/plugins/likebox.php?id=8062627951&amp;width=300&amp;connections=10&amp;stream=false&amp;header=false&amp;height=250" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" style="border:none; overflow:hidden; width:300px; height:250px;" allowTransparency="true"></iframe>
<p>2) <strong>Then do one of the following:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size:13px;">Retweet this post (making sure to include the #TCDisrupt hashtag), or</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size:13px;">Leave us a comment below telling us something fun &#8211; anything!</span></li>
</ul>
<p>The contest will start <strong>now</strong> and end April 5th at 7:30pm PT. Please only tweet or comment once, or you will be disqualified. We will make sure you follow the steps above and choose our winner once the giveaway is over. Please note the winner will only receive one (1) free Disrupt ticket, and it does not include airfare or hotel.</p>
<p><em>Our sponsors help make Disrupt happen. If you are interested in learning more about sponsorship opportunities, please contact our sponsorship team here <a target="_blank" href="mailto:sponsors@techcrunch.com">sponsors@techcrunch.com</a>.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/788221/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=SyQA5OVOeAk:DVd8s_TMCqg:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=SyQA5OVOeAk:DVd8s_TMCqg:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=SyQA5OVOeAk:DVd8s_TMCqg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=SyQA5OVOeAk:DVd8s_TMCqg:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=SyQA5OVOeAk:DVd8s_TMCqg:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=SyQA5OVOeAk:DVd8s_TMCqg:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=SyQA5OVOeAk:DVd8s_TMCqg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=SyQA5OVOeAk:DVd8s_TMCqg:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/SyQA5OVOeAk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/techcrunch-giveaway-fitbit-one-aria-smart-scale-and-a-ticket-to-disrupt-ny/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fitbit.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fitbit.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fitbit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4354d96606cdd10e2c4ed03f5ae5ff77?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">elinblesener</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/29/techcrunch-giveaway-fitbit-one-aria-smart-scale-and-a-ticket-to-disrupt-ny/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss>
