<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	
	<link>http://techcrunch.com</link>
	<description>TechCrunch is a group-edited blog that profiles the companies, products and events defining and transforming the new web.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 15:05:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain="techcrunch.com" port="80" path="/?rsscloud=notify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
<image><link>http://www.techcrunch.com</link><url>http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/themes/techcrunchmu/images/techcrunch_logo.png</url><title>TechCrunch</title></image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://techcrunch.com/osd.xml" title="TechCrunch" />
	
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" /><feedburner:info uri="techcrunch" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://techcrunch.com/?pushpress=hub" /><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://add.my.yahoo.com/rss?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://us.i1.yimg.com/us.yimg.com/i/us/my/addtomyyahoo4.gif">Subscribe with My Yahoo!</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.newsgator.com/ngs/subscriber/subext.aspx?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.newsgator.com/images/ngsub1.gif">Subscribe with NewsGator</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://feeds.my.aol.com/add.jsp?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://o.aolcdn.com/favorites.my.aol.com/webmaster/ffclient/webroot/locale/en-US/images/myAOLButtonSmall.gif">Subscribe with My AOL</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.bloglines.com/sub/http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" src="http://www.bloglines.com/images/sub_modern11.gif">Subscribe with Bloglines</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.netvibes.com/subscribe.php?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.netvibes.com/img/add2netvibes.gif">Subscribe with Netvibes</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://fusion.google.com/add?feedurl=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://buttons.googlesyndication.com/fusion/add.gif">Subscribe with Google</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.pageflakes.com/subscribe.aspx?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.pageflakes.com/ImageFile.ashx?instanceId=Static_4&amp;fileName=ATP_blu_91x17.gif">Subscribe with Pageflakes</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item>
		<title>Macmillan Buys Late Nite Labs To Help Bring Virtual Science Labs To Higher Ed</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/FUQmM65YsoM/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/macmillan-buys-late-nite-labs-to-help-bring-virtual-science-labs-to-higher-ed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 15:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rip Empson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Late Nite Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edtech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macmillan new ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781284</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-6-24-12-am.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen shot 2013-03-20 at 6.24.12 AM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Another day, another acquisition in the education technology market. As the old, familiar names in publishing and education move to get in line with the digital revolution, they're finding plenty of opportunities amidst today's growing roster of young EdTech startups. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-6-24-12-am.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen shot 2013-03-20 at 6.24.12 AM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Another day, another acquisition in the education technology market. As the old, familiar names in publishing and education move to get in line with the digital revolution, they&#8217;re finding plenty of opportunities amidst today&#8217;s growing roster of young EdTech startups. </p>
<p>Last summer, <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macmillan_Publishers">Macmillan</a>, one of the oldest publishing companies out there, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.edsurge.com/n/macmillan-ventures-sets-aside-100-million-to-acquire-startups">created a $100 million fund</a> to use to scoop up promising EdTech startups. The fund, now known as <a target="_blank" href="http://www.macmillannewventures.com/">Macmillan New Ventures</a>, has been looking to add 10 to 15 companies to Macmillan&#8217;s portfolio before 2015. </p>
<p>Prep U, i-Clicker, and EBI were the first startups to be acquired, followed by <a target="_blank" href="http://pevc.dowjones.com/Article?an=DJFVW00020121107e8b7avncm&amp;cid=32135017&amp;ctype=ts&amp;ReturnUrl=http%3a%2f%2fpevc.dowjones.com%3a80%2fArticle%3fan%3dDJFVW00020121107e8b7avncm%26cid%3d32135017%26ctype%3dts">ABI Sapling Learning in November</a>. Today, TechCrunch has learned that virtual science startup and EdTech veteran, <a target="_blank" href="https://latenitelabs.com/">Late Nite Labs</a>, has become the newest addition to Macmillan New Ventures&#8217; portfolio.</p>
<p>While the terms of the deal were not disclosed, Late Night Labs’ VP of Business Development Harris Goodman tells us that the startup&#8217;s 12 employees will be joining Macmillan and re-locating to MNV&#8217;s offices in Union Square in New York City. Macmillan has been looking to build a portfolio of education startups that can demonstrate product-market fit and actual traction among both end-users and schools &#8212; something that&#8217;s been difficult for many of the new generation of EdTech companies to manage.</p>
<p>Late Nite Labs <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/12/05/late-nite-labs-raises-1-1-million-to-bring-virtual-science-education-to-campuses/">raised $1.1 million in late 2011</a> from a handful of angel investors, which included former Chancellor of New York City&#8217;s public schools and Kaplan EVP, Harold Levy, and Disney Education&#8217;s former head of business development, Don Burton, among others. </p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screenshots_005.jpg"></a>At the time, Late Nite Labs had expanded into 150 schools (a number that has grown significantly since, Goodman says), including Arizona State, Penn State and MIT. More recently, the startup has managed to use this traction to push past a $1 million annual run rate and has been growing steadily since. </p>
<p>But why, you ask?</p>
<p>While there is growing pressure across the country to raise the quality and consistency of STEM in both primary and secondary education, the fact of the matter is that federal funding for public universities and colleges has been in a steady decline over the last two decades. Combined with increased spending and rising institutional debt, many state schools and public universities have been forced to make cuts across the board, from faculty and courses to core, student learning programs. </p>
<p>Science resources, specifically wet labs, are often the first to go &#8212; if they even existed in the first place &#8212; the same laboratories where students learn how to use Bunsen burners, mix chemicals and measure boiling points. Officially launched in 2011, <a target="_blank" href="https://latenitelabs.com/">Late Nite Labs</a> set out to solve this problem by providing schools with a web-based platform that allows students to take part in virtual chemistry and biology labs. </p>
<p>The New York City-based startup has origins that date all the way back to 2001, which make it one of the older and more familiar startups in the EdTech market, though it really began to pick up steam more recently, beginning with its more &#8220;official&#8221; debut in 2011. </p>
<p>Over the years, the startup has grown its virtual lab platform to include several hundred experiment simulations, which allow schools to provide their students with a fully-equipped, virtual science lab &#8212; complete with the same containers, compounds and instruments one would find in a real, live wet lab. Teachers can create and manage their coursework through the platform, distribute assignments and so on, including expository videos and images, while students get to follow along and keep track of progress in their own digital notebooks. </p>
<p>The drag-and-drop, interactive platform now includes microbiology, general organic and biochemistry alongside the basics, and Late Nite Labs is currently in the process of working on a physics lab as well.</p>
<p>While exits can be disappointing conclusions for entrepreneurs, Goodman says that the team as a whole will stay together and is looking forward to continue building and expanding Late Nite Labs, especially with the broad support that Macmillan can now provide. Hopefully that remains true. Because the company (as a whole) owns science education brands like Nature, Scientific American, Sapling and Hayden McNeil, Goodman says that the team wants to help create the &#8220;ultimate digital science company.&#8221;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781284/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FUQmM65YsoM:eTy2eCPgDh8:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FUQmM65YsoM:eTy2eCPgDh8:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FUQmM65YsoM:eTy2eCPgDh8:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FUQmM65YsoM:eTy2eCPgDh8:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=FUQmM65YsoM:eTy2eCPgDh8:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FUQmM65YsoM:eTy2eCPgDh8:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=FUQmM65YsoM:eTy2eCPgDh8:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FUQmM65YsoM:eTy2eCPgDh8:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/FUQmM65YsoM" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/macmillan-buys-late-nite-labs-to-help-bring-virtual-science-labs-to-higher-ed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-6-24-12-am.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-6-24-12-am.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2013-03-20 at 6.24.12 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a94f6b72a8ee7342e862c1c9d6c5b826?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rempson8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screenshots_005.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">screenshots_005</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/macmillan-buys-late-nite-labs-to-help-bring-virtual-science-labs-to-higher-ed/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Postmaster Launches An Easy To Use API To Help Businesses Optimize Their Shipments</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/W9oHo3efaLk/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/postmaster-launches-an-easy-to-use-api-to-help-businesses-optimize-their-shipments/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Frederic Lardinois</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postmaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechStars Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shipping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=780999</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/postmaster_rgb_blue1.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Postmaster_RGB_Blue1" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Postmaster, a TechStars Cloud company based in Austin, TX, just launched a new API in beta that will allow businesses to optimize their small parcel shipments. You&#8217;d think that shipping is pretty much a solved problem at this point, but in reality, it&#8217;s still very hard for developers to easily hook their applications into the APIs of major shippers like FedEx, UPS and the USPS and understand who offers the most efficient and cost-effective shipping options for their specific needs. Postmaster, on the other hand, provides developers with a single, easy-to-integrate REST API that allows companies to quickly compare rates across FedEx, UP and USPS (more coming soon) and optimize their shipments for cost and time in transit. While large companies like Amazon use sophisticated algorithms to optimize their shipments, most small businesses don&#8217;t have access to this data. Amazon, for example, knows when it can use basic ground shipping from one of its warehouses to get a parcel to you in two days instead of using a more expensive service. Postmasters allows anybody to route packages intelligently. As Postmaster CEO and co-founder Jesse Lovelace told me earlier this week, one of the main pain points about integrating with existing shipping solutions isn&#8217;t just that they tend to be very old-fashioned APIs, but also the need to get the labels you print certified by them. This can take a long time and just adds unnecessary complexity for a small business. “Carrier integration can be extremely cumbersome. Postmaster wants to not only make this process easier than ever before, but by harnessing shipping data and analytics, ensure that every shipment is optimized, routed and billed as efficiently and cost-effectively as possible,&#8221; Lovelace also said in the announcement today. In addition to providing businesses with access to rates and shipping labels, Postmaster also provides tracking services over SMS, email and webhooks, as well as address validation. The company currently offers client libraries for Ruby, Python and PHP, with .NET, Java and Go libraries coming soon. For now, the service is squarely focused on developers, but the team is also planning to launch a more consumer-focused product soon that may allow users to quickly compare shipping rates without the ability to print out labels.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/postmaster_rgb_blue1.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Postmaster_RGB_Blue1" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.postmaster.io/">Postmaster</a>, a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.techstars.com/cloud/">TechStars Cloud</a> company based in Austin, TX, just launched a <a target="_blank" href="https://www.postmaster.io/docs">new API</a> in beta that will allow businesses to optimize their small parcel shipments. You&#8217;d think that shipping is pretty much a solved problem at this point, but in reality, it&#8217;s still very hard for developers to easily hook their applications into the APIs of major shippers like FedEx, UPS and the USPS and understand who offers the most efficient and cost-effective shipping options for their specific needs. Postmaster, on the other hand, provides developers with a single, easy-to-integrate REST API that allows companies to quickly compare rates across FedEx, UP and USPS (more coming soon) and optimize their shipments for cost and time in transit.</p>
<p>While large companies like Amazon use sophisticated algorithms to optimize their shipments, most small businesses don&#8217;t have access to this data. Amazon, for example, knows when it can use basic ground shipping from one of its warehouses to get a parcel to you in two days instead of using a more expensive service. Postmasters allows anybody to route packages intelligently.</p>
<p>As Postmaster CEO and co-founder Jesse Lovelace told me earlier this week, one of the main pain points about integrating with <a target="_blank" href="http://www.fedex.com/us/developer/solutions.html">existing shipping solutions</a> isn&#8217;t just that they tend to be very old-fashioned APIs, but also the need to get the labels you print certified by them. This can take a long time and just adds unnecessary complexity for a small business. “Carrier integration can be extremely cumbersome. Postmaster wants to not only make this process easier than ever before, but by harnessing shipping data and analytics, ensure that every shipment is optimized, routed and billed as efficiently and cost-effectively as possible,&#8221; Lovelace also said in the announcement today.</p>
<p>In addition to providing businesses with access to rates and shipping labels, Postmaster also provides tracking services over SMS, email and webhooks, as well as address validation. The company currently offers client libraries for Ruby, Python and PHP, with .NET, Java and Go libraries coming soon.</p>
<p>For now, the service is squarely focused on developers, but the team is also planning to launch a more consumer-focused product soon that may allow users to quickly compare shipping rates without the ability to print out labels.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/780999/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=W9oHo3efaLk:vJ2uqvAZ2jo:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=W9oHo3efaLk:vJ2uqvAZ2jo:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=W9oHo3efaLk:vJ2uqvAZ2jo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=W9oHo3efaLk:vJ2uqvAZ2jo:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=W9oHo3efaLk:vJ2uqvAZ2jo:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=W9oHo3efaLk:vJ2uqvAZ2jo:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=W9oHo3efaLk:vJ2uqvAZ2jo:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=W9oHo3efaLk:vJ2uqvAZ2jo:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/W9oHo3efaLk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/postmaster-launches-an-easy-to-use-api-to-help-businesses-optimize-their-shipments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/postmaster_rgb_blue1.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/postmaster_rgb_blue1.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Postmaster_RGB_Blue1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/55542aa717199728948f628edc1170b1?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fredericlardinois</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/postmaster-launches-an-easy-to-use-api-to-help-businesses-optimize-their-shipments/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Health Tracking Gets More Up-Close And Personal With Tiny Blood Monitor Implant</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/7QhafcmT3vs/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/health-tracking-gets-more-up-close-and-personal-with-tiny-blood-monitor-implant/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 14:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Darrell Etherington</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781289</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-10-11-59-am.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-03-20 at 10.11.59 AM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />I thought it was impressive that Withings now offers an affordable home scale that tracks your body fat percentage and heart rate, but scientists have developed a tiny Bluetooth-capable blood monitoring device that resides comfortably under the skin, according to the BBC this morning. It's likely to go into testing with intensive care patients soon, but it's an example of how intense home health monitoring could get over the course of the next few years.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-10-11-59-am.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen Shot 2013-03-20 at 10.11.59 AM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='360' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/DBa41wej-NE?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>I thought it was impressive that Withings now offers an <a title="Withings Smart Body Analyzer Now Available For $149.95, Here’s How It Performs" href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/withings-smart-body-analyzer-review/">affordable home scale that tracks your body fat percentage and heart rate</a>, but scientists have developed a tiny Bluetooth-capable blood monitoring device that resides comfortably under the skin, according to the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-21841829">BBC this morning</a>. It&#8217;s likely to go into testing with intensive care patients soon, but it&#8217;s an example of how intense home health monitoring could get over the course of the next few years.</p>
<p>The device was created by a team of Swiss medical scientists, and is designed to be installed (that really is the most appropriate term here) in a patient&#8217;s abdomen, leg or arm skin, using only a needle. It can last for months, and reports back information about blood glucose and cholesterol levels, so as you might imagine it would be extremely useful for patients with chronic conditions like diabetes who are used to having to draw blood on a much more regular basis.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not a new idea, but the Swiss team&#8217;s design is unique in that it can track a number of different markers at once. In other words, it&#8217;s the ultimately quantified self device for real internal cues. The immediate benefit of this tech is obviously for those with serious conditions, and that&#8217;s likely who will see the benefits in the immediate future. The team hopes to have it generally available to patients in need within the next four years.</p>
<p></p>
<p>But beyond that, it&#8217;s easy to see similar unobtrusive sub-dermal implants gaining traction with the growing number of people who seem to want to keep close tabs on their bodies and health. Cholesterol levels and other indicators that can be found by this type of close monitoring will also probably become even more interesting to current advocates of the Quantified Self movement as the population ages.</p>
<p>It may seem far-fetched to imagine a future where the general desire to know and track more information about ourselves in real-time extends to devices we wear beneath the skin, but ten years ago who could&#8217;ve predicted the rise of successful startups like Withings who have <a title="Withings scores 3 million euros for the tweeting wifi scale and more" href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/09/02/withings-scores-3-million-euros-for-the-tweeting-wifi-scale-and-more/">built a brand on home health tracking</a>, or the advent of a device like the <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/18/the-basis-b1-fitness-band-is-amazing-but-still-needs-polish/">Basis wristband</a>? Devices like this one might just be the next wave of health monitoring tech ripe for consumerization.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781289/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7QhafcmT3vs:-M87tHowjCU:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7QhafcmT3vs:-M87tHowjCU:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7QhafcmT3vs:-M87tHowjCU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7QhafcmT3vs:-M87tHowjCU:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=7QhafcmT3vs:-M87tHowjCU:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7QhafcmT3vs:-M87tHowjCU:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=7QhafcmT3vs:-M87tHowjCU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=7QhafcmT3vs:-M87tHowjCU:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/7QhafcmT3vs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/health-tracking-gets-more-up-close-and-personal-with-tiny-blood-monitor-implant/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-10-11-59-am.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-10-11-59-am.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-03-20 at 10.11.59 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/188039e12983eb749171a75cfd01378d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">etherin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/implant.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">implant</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/health-tracking-gets-more-up-close-and-personal-with-tiny-blood-monitor-implant/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon Rumored To Be Working On A $99 7-Inch Kindle Fire HD</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/pk0irPnEp6A/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/amazon-rumored-to-be-working-on-a-99-kindle-fire-hd-7/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sarah Perez</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kindle fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=777482</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kindle-fire-web.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="kindle fire web" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />How low will Amazon's tablets go? We're now hearing that a $99 Kindle Fire 7" tablet is in production, and will be shipping this year. At a price that low, the Kindle Fire would be able to more easily compete at the tail end of the Android-based tablet market - an area which is today dominated by low-cost tablets out of China, often sold at the sub-$100 price point.
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kindle-fire-web.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="kindle fire web" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>How low will Amazon&#8217;s tablets go? We&#8217;re now hearing that a $99 Kindle Fire 7&#8243; tablet is in production, and will be shipping this year. At a price that low, the Kindle Fire would be able to more easily compete at the tail end of the Android-based tablet market &#8211; an area which is today dominated by low-cost tablets out of China, often sold at the sub-$100 price point.</p>
<p>According to what we&#8217;ve heard, the $99 Kindle Fire HD will also still sport a TI processor <a target="_blank" href="https://developer.amazon.com/sdk/fire/specifications.html">like the rest of the lineup</a>, and will have a 1280&#215;800 resolution, like today&#8217;s Kindle Fire HD 7&#8243; does.</p>
<p>This report follows <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/13/amazon-drops-kindle-fire-hd-8-9-price-from-299-to-269-releases-it-in-europe-and-japan/">an announcement Amazon made earlier this month</a> about reduced prices on its Kindle Fire HD 8.9&#8243; devices. The Wi-Fi-only version will now cost $269, down from $299, while the LTE version dropped from $499 to $399. It also follows news of <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/amazons-carrier-billing-deal-with-bango-to-kick-in-this-year-changes-for-the-appstore-and-amazon-ahead/">a forthcoming carrier billing deal</a> that&#8217;s about to go live  - something which hints that Amazon is now scaling up and becoming more aggressive with its product line up.</p>
<p>Typically, a price drop signals one of two things &#8211; that the manufacturer or retailer is attempting to clear out inventory ahead of a new model, or that it just wants to sell more of the item, at a faster pace. According to other industry experts with visibility into tablet usage trends we&#8217;ve spoken with, the Kindle Fire HD 8.9&#8243; is not Amazon&#8217;s most popular model &#8211; the 7&#8243; HD tablet is.</p>
<p>Today, <a target="_blank" href="http://amazon.com/kindlefirehd7">that tablet is priced at a reasonable $199</a>, while <a target="_blank" href="http://amazon.com/kindlefire">the older (non-HD, 2nd gen.) Kindle Fire is an even lower $159</a>.</p>
<p>While a $99 price may seem extraordinary, IDC Research Director on tablets, Tom Mainelli, says that such a thing actually sounds reasonable. His firm just put out <a target="_blank" href="http://www.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=prUS24002213#.UUDeXtFATUi">an updated tablet marketshare forecast</a> this week, stating that this year tablets running Google&#8217;s Android operating system <a target="_blank" href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/03/12/us-tablets-idUSBRE92B0MS20130312">would overtake the iPad</a> for the first time. The Amazon Kindle Fire, of course, uses its own forked version of Android.</p>
<p>Mainelli explains that Amazon&#8217;s competition isn&#8217;t just the iPad, it&#8217;s all these low-cost tablets running Android. Over Black Friday and the holidays in particular, you could get a $199 HD tablet from Amazon, the slightly cheaper non-HD version, or you could buy a $99 (or even in some cases $79) Android tablet from relatively unknown manufacturers in places like Walgreens, CVS, Bed, Bath &amp; Beyond, and elsewhere.</p>
<p>&#8220;The infrastructure is definitely in place for Amazon to go even lower,&#8221; Mainelli says. &#8220;If they can sell the product at roughly what it costs to build, that fits their long-term vision to make money selling you content on that device. It&#8217;s entirely possible &#8211; physically possible &#8211; to create a device that costs $99, particularly at the scale that Amazon would do it,&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>Android tablets prices across the board are coming down, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.zdnet.com/acer-readying-99-android-tablet-for-emerging-markets-plus-cheaper-windows-8-tablet-7000009171/">too</a>, which also lends credence to this possibility. For example, even HP recently announced a $169 Android device. Everyone in this space is beginning to attack the sub-$199 price point, given that Apple has staked out the high-end of the market at $329 and up.</p>
<p>So if the game is becoming &#8220;how low can you go?&#8221;, Amazon is in a good position to compete here, as it&#8217;s historically <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/28/turtles-all-the-way-down/">been</a> <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/26/technology/amazon-reports-its-first-quarterly-loss-in-four-years.html?_r=0">a low-margin business</a>. It doesn&#8217;t care what it makes from tablets right now &#8211; it&#8217;s about getting consumers a device which connects them back to the Amazon ecosystem, where they will spend on other Amazon products and services.</p>
<h3 style="clear:both;margin-left:5px;margin-bottom:5px;width:640px;float:center;color:#0a9400;">So if the game is becoming “how low can you go?”, Amazon is in a good position to compete here, as it’s historically been a low-margin business.</h3>
<p>Mainelli also points out that the TI &#8211; the processor brand that Amazon uses in its current Kindle Fire devices &#8211; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.informationweek.com/hardware/processors/ti-cuts-1700-jobs-exits-mobile-chip-mark/240142161">has been getting out of the chip business</a>. It was even <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/15/report-amazon-in-advanced-talks-to-buy-texas-instruments-mobile-chip-business-in-deal-worth-billions/">rumored last fall that Amazon was in advanced talks to buy TI</a>. That never ended up happening, but what that story points to is that Amazon has deep ties with the chip maker, and could have easily cut a deal where it agreed to buy up TI&#8217;s remaining remaining stock for cheap. That could help Amazon now deeply discount its tablets retail prices.</p>
<p>Amazon sold 4.8 million Kindle Fires in 2011 (shipping only in the fourth quarter), and in 2012, it shipped 10.4 million units worldwide, according to IDC&#8217;s estimates. It <a target="_blank" href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2011/11/16/142310104/why-amazon-loses-money-on-every-kindle-fire">has been</a> <a target="_blank" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/11/18/kindle-fire-price_n_1101847.html">widely</a> <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/12/30/amazon-is-not-a-commerce-company/">reported</a> that these tablets are sold at a loss, though <a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-19907546">Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos told the BBC in October</a> that&#8217;s not quite true.</p>
<p>&#8220;We sell the hardware at our cost, so it is break-even on the hardware,&#8221; Bezos said at the time.</p>
<p>Amazon could break even at the $99 price point, and get its tablet into more people&#8217;s hands by doing so, pulling them in to its ecosystem.</p>
<p>For what it&#8217;s worth, Amazon denies that such a price drop will be happening. &#8220;We are already at the lowest price points possible for that hardware,&#8221; a company representative told us.</p>
<p>For <em>that</em> hardware, maybe.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/777482/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pk0irPnEp6A:R7rfrhShBOc:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pk0irPnEp6A:R7rfrhShBOc:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pk0irPnEp6A:R7rfrhShBOc:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pk0irPnEp6A:R7rfrhShBOc:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=pk0irPnEp6A:R7rfrhShBOc:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pk0irPnEp6A:R7rfrhShBOc:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=pk0irPnEp6A:R7rfrhShBOc:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=pk0irPnEp6A:R7rfrhShBOc:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/pk0irPnEp6A" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/amazon-rumored-to-be-working-on-a-99-kindle-fire-hd-7/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kindle-fire-web.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kindle-fire-web.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kindle fire web</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5225bb627e112543aa03bf3b2958be3f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sarahintampa</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/amazon-rumored-to-be-working-on-a-99-kindle-fire-hd-7/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>After Pushing Silent Update To Some, Facebook Releases Updated Android App For All On Google Play</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/062pZ8Cva-k/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/after-pushing-silent-update-to-some-facebook-releases-updated-android-app-for-all-on-google-play/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jordan Crook</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781241</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-20-08-1-52-45.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="2013-03-20 08-1.52.45" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Facebook, in its quest to dominate mobile, has just released an incremental update to its Android app through the Google Play Store. The update lets users change their profile pictures direct from the app (which is something iOS has been able to do for quite some time). Also within the update, Facebookers on Android can more easily manage spam and unwanted stories in their News Feed, and enjoy more streamlined access to group messaging. The update isn&#8217;t all that revolutionary, but it came straight through the Google Play store, which is more than I can say for Facebook&#8217;s last Android update. On Friday, Facebook began testing a new way to roll out updates to Android devices called silent updates, which downloads the update in the background over WiFi and then notifies the user to install it. It&#8217;s a new beta program that&#8217;s meant to push fast updates to a group of beta testers who can review the app before it goes live to everyone. To be a part of the program, you must have your Android phone settings set to allow downloads from outside of Google Play. According to InsideFacebook, some users who received the silent update said the app notified them repeatedly until they installed the app. Facebook says the silent updates help &#8220;make sure everyone is using the best version of our app.&#8221; They also ensure that an update won&#8217;t break anything and that&#8217;s its useful to users before sending the new update to all Android users. Facebook has used HTML5 to let it test features on Facebook&#8217;s website on a handful of users, before pushing it out to the full billion. First the feature hits one percent of users, and if it works well, it goes to ten percent before being pushed out entirely. On mobile, that hasn&#8217;t been the case, since native apps force Facebook to send out a full update to all users at the same time. In the latest update, Facebook asks for permission to &#8220;download files without notification,&#8221; which would allow Facebook to expand its beta program and send out silent updates to the 1 percent of its choosing. The newest version of Facebook&#8217;s Android app is available today through Google Play, so everyone can enjoy it. It would seem that Facebook&#8217;s first run on &#8220;silent updates&#8221; went relatively well.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-20-08-1-52-45.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="2013-03-20 08-1.52.45" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Facebook, in its quest to dominate mobile, has just released an incremental update to its Android app through the Google Play Store.</p>
<p>The update lets users change their profile pictures direct from the app (which is something iOS has been able to do for quite some time). Also within the update, Facebookers on Android can more easily manage spam and unwanted stories in their News Feed, and enjoy more streamlined access to group messaging.</p>
<p>The update isn&#8217;t all that revolutionary, but it came straight through the Google Play store, which is more than I can say for Facebook&#8217;s last Android update.</p>
<p>On Friday, Facebook <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/17/its-alive-mwa-ha-ha-ha/">began testing a new way to roll out updates</a> to Android devices called silent updates, which downloads the update in the background over WiFi and then notifies the user to install it.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a new <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/17/its-alive-mwa-ha-ha-ha/">beta program</a> that&#8217;s meant to push fast updates to a group of beta testers who can review the app before it goes live to everyone. To be a part of the program, you must have your Android phone settings set to allow downloads from outside of Google Play.</p>
<p>According to <a target="_blank" href="http://www.insidefacebook.com/2013/03/18/silent-updates-for-android-download-latest-version-of-facebook-without-google-play/">InsideFacebook</a>, some users who received the silent update said the app notified them repeatedly until they installed the app.</p>
<p>Facebook says the silent updates help &#8220;make sure everyone is using the best version of our app.&#8221; They also ensure that an update won&#8217;t break anything and that&#8217;s its useful to users before sending the new update to all Android users.</p>
<p>Facebook has used HTML5 to let it test features on Facebook&#8217;s website on a handful of users, before pushing it out to the full billion. First the feature hits one percent of users, and if it works well, it goes to ten percent before being pushed out entirely. On mobile, that hasn&#8217;t been the case, since native apps force Facebook to send out a full update to all users at the same time.</p>
<p>In the latest update, Facebook asks for permission to &#8220;download files without notification,&#8221; which would allow Facebook to expand its beta program and send out silent updates to the 1 percent of its choosing.</p>
<p>The newest version of Facebook&#8217;s Android app is available today through <a target="_blank" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.facebook.katana&amp;hl=en">Google Play</a>, so everyone can enjoy it. It would seem that Facebook&#8217;s first run on &#8220;silent updates&#8221; went relatively well.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781241/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=062pZ8Cva-k:fQp0E1wKTUQ:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=062pZ8Cva-k:fQp0E1wKTUQ:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=062pZ8Cva-k:fQp0E1wKTUQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=062pZ8Cva-k:fQp0E1wKTUQ:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=062pZ8Cva-k:fQp0E1wKTUQ:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=062pZ8Cva-k:fQp0E1wKTUQ:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=062pZ8Cva-k:fQp0E1wKTUQ:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=062pZ8Cva-k:fQp0E1wKTUQ:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/062pZ8Cva-k" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/after-pushing-silent-update-to-some-facebook-releases-updated-android-app-for-all-on-google-play/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-20-08-1-52-45.png?w=84" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-20-08-1-52-45.png?w=84" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-03-20 08-1.52.45</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/123a4c264172746af556b0c74c72b308?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">biggsismyboss</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/after-pushing-silent-update-to-some-facebook-releases-updated-android-app-for-all-on-google-play/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Transparent Ad Platform Human Demand Closes $900K Series A</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/RT2bWvO4v9M/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/transparent-ad-platform-human-demand-closes-900k-series-a/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sarah Perez</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human demand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile advertising]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=780767</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/humandemand.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="HumanDemand" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><a target="_blank" href="http://www.humandemand.com/">Human Demand</a>, a mobile ad startup which <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/08/15/targeting-the-long-tail-human-demands-new-platform-lets-you-see-which-apps-are-running-your-ads/">launched last summer</a> targeting the long tail of app developers, has since expanded its focus to brands, and is today announcing having raised an additional $900,000 in new funding. Some of that new investment is founder money, while the others leading the round include the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/dev">DEV fund</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/arc-angel-fund">ARC Angel Fund</a>.
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/humandemand.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="HumanDemand" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.humandemand.com/">Human Demand</a>, a mobile ad startup which <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/08/15/targeting-the-long-tail-human-demands-new-platform-lets-you-see-which-apps-are-running-your-ads/">launched last summer</a> targeting the long tail of app developers, has since expanded its focus to brands, and is today announcing having raised an additional $900,000 in new funding. Some of that new investment is founder money, while the others leading the round include the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/dev">DEV fund</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/arc-angel-fund">ARC Angel Fund</a>.</p>
<p>Incidentally, Human Demand CEO Howie Schwartz, the co-founder of <a target="_blank" href="http://offermobi.com/page/about/">OfferMobi</a>, and an active investor in multiple funds (BHV, ff Venture Capital, Metamorphic), is also involved in ARC Angel, but insists he had to pitch the team like any other startup would, then had to leave the room when they made their decision. (<em>Ha!</em>)</p>
<p>He says that in terms of the lead investment, it was fairly evenly split between the three (DEV, ARC and himself). Also participating in the round were Empire Angels, Blackgate Ventures, and other NY area and angel investors. Until today, Human Demand was basically seed funded by Schwartz himself.</p>
<p>For background, the company <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/08/15/targeting-the-long-tail-human-demands-new-platform-lets-you-see-which-apps-are-running-your-ads/">initially offered a platform</a> that made it easier for indie developers to optimize ad campaigns by introducing transparent metrics which showed exactly what the acquisition price per user is on each app. Human Demand also offered a toolkit for these developers which included something called a &#8220;power level&#8221; &#8211; a simple, color-coded system that allows developers to target or block apps via color codes instead of having to calculate actual dollars and cents.</p>
<p>The idea was not only to simplify the process of media buying, but also to show developers where their ads would run.</p>
<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/transparent-ad-platform-human-demand-closes-900k-series-a/hd-map-hyperlocal-wendys/" rel="attachment wp-att-780869"></a>However, since its launch last August, Human Demand has extended its platform to reach brands and agencies, who have a different set of more sophisticated tools at their disposal. Today, Schwartz says the company has an even mix of brands and indie developers using its platform, and he&#8217;s taking a wait-and-see approach as to where the majority of the startup&#8217;s focus will be going forward.</p>
<p>To date, Human Demand has handled around 400 campaigns from its 150 or so customers. While smaller developers might run one campaign, brands and agencies may run as many as 30 or 40. The company is also partnered with several exchanges, including MoPub, MobClix, Smaato, Nexage, OpenX, Inneractive, LiveIntent, and Amobee, for example.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our reach has probably more than doubled since last August,&#8221; says Schwartz of its reach, which he pegs at around 11,000 or 12,000 publishers. He adds that Human Demand has also recently partnered with TRUSTe, allowing consumers to opt-out of interest-based advertising &#8211; something that Human Demand is fairly passionate about, in fact.</p>
<p>&#8220;Obviously, we don&#8217;t have cookies on mobile, but a lot of the same privacy concerns that we&#8217;re seeing wreak havoc in the desktop advertising world &#8211; I think it&#8217;s going to be even worse on mobile. It&#8217;s a more personal device,&#8221; he says. &#8220;It has location. We&#8217;re sleeping with our devices! So we think it&#8217;s very important to be privacy sensitive from the foundation of our platform.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/transparent-ad-platform-human-demand-closes-900k-series-a/hd-carrier-optimization-output/" rel="attachment wp-att-780870"></a></p>
<p>The company recently hired a new VP of Sales, Brian Cronin, who will help Human Demand with its agency and brand scaling efforts. &#8220;We&#8217;re focusing on hyper-local, audience and brand safety,&#8221; says Schwartz of this expanded focus. &#8220;Since our platform is transparent &#8211; we can actually do what we call &#8216;true brand safety,&#8217;&#8221; he adds.</p>
<p>Schwartz explains that one of the challenges today in ad networks is that they&#8217;re blind. For example, a family friendly advertiser might not want to run ads in violent mobile games. As with the indie developers Human Demand serves, the brands can also use the self-serve platform to be in control of their own targeting and ad buys.</p>
<p>In the second quarter of this year, the company will have a series of product announcements, one of the most notable being the support for mobile video. This will allow developer to run trailers to promote installs via video (a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/04/fiksu-introduces-support-for-facebook-mobile-app-install-ads-as-the-new-ad-format-shows-early-traction-for-top-developers/">fairly</a> <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/09/07/flurry-appcircle-android/">popular</a> <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/10/25/admob-brings-interactive-video-ads-to-android/">alternative</a> <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/19/vungle-creates-dev-fund/">to</a> incentivized installs today) and brands and agencies will be able to run video in a pre-roll setting at scale. These videos will become available in the self-serve platform just like banner ads are now.</p>
<p>The additional funding will allow Human Demand to grow Cronin&#8217;s biz dev and sales teams, ramp up on ad operations and support, and further product development.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/780767/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=RT2bWvO4v9M:iu9Y3Bat2nY:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=RT2bWvO4v9M:iu9Y3Bat2nY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=RT2bWvO4v9M:iu9Y3Bat2nY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=RT2bWvO4v9M:iu9Y3Bat2nY:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=RT2bWvO4v9M:iu9Y3Bat2nY:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=RT2bWvO4v9M:iu9Y3Bat2nY:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=RT2bWvO4v9M:iu9Y3Bat2nY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=RT2bWvO4v9M:iu9Y3Bat2nY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/RT2bWvO4v9M" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/transparent-ad-platform-human-demand-closes-900k-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/humandemand.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/humandemand.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">HumanDemand</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5225bb627e112543aa03bf3b2958be3f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sarahintampa</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hd-map-hyperlocal-wendys.png?w=562" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">HD-map-hyperlocal-Wendys</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hd-carrier-optimization-output.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">HD-carrier-optimization-output</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/transparent-ad-platform-human-demand-closes-900k-series-a/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Gridcase's Reactor Is A $149 iPhone 5 Case With A Battery-Boosting Built In Hand-Crank (Or It Will Be If Gets Crowdfunded)</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/Spk1wfZb0Ds/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/gridcase-reactor/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natasha Lomas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781220</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-12-06-56.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Gridcase" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />One of the criticisms Android fans like to level at the iPhone is its non-get-at-able battery -- meaning you can't carry a spare (or rip the battery out to hard reset). So here's a bit of kit that proposes to help iPhone owners who have run out of juice. Gridcase's Reactor case for the iPhone 5 will include a crank for manually charging the battery to eke a little more juice out of your device.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-12-06-56.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Gridcase" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>One of the criticisms Android fans like to level at the iPhone is its non-get-at-able battery &#8212; meaning you can&#8217;t carry a spare (or rip the battery out to hard reset the phone). So here&#8217;s a bit of kit that proposes to help iPhone owners who have run out of juice. Gridcase&#8217;s Reactor case for the iPhone 5 will include a crank for manually charging the battery to eke a little more juice out of your device when there&#8217;s no wall sockets in sight.</p>
<p>Reactor doesn&#8217;t exist yet &#8212; Gridcase is kicking off a crowdfunding campaign to &#8221;provide the funds for the final industrial design and transition of the prototype into production&#8221; &#8212; with its target goal being a rather hefty $350,000. But it has knocked up the following 3D renders of the Reactor:<a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/gridcase-reactor/gridcase/" rel="attachment wp-att-781223"></a><br />
Details of exactly how the Reactor works are pretty thin on the ground at this point because unfortunately for the company the new crowdfunding site it intends to use for the campaign, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crowdsupply.com/">Crowd Supply</a>, hasn&#8217;t launched yet (instead you get a &#8216;launching soon&#8217; holding page). <strong>Update:</strong> The <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crowdsupply.com/gridcase/reactor-for-iphone-5">Reactor crowdfunding page</a> (and Crowd Supply site) has now launched.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s how Gridcase describes the Reactor in its <a target="_blank" href="http://www.marketwire.com/press-release/gridcase-announces-reactor-for-iphone-5-worlds-first-generator-smartphone-case-1770035.htm">release</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>The Reactor utilizes a patent-pending, ultra-thin generator to enable users to manually charge the battery of their iPhone 5 when wall outlets are unavailable. The Reactor is designed to provide an all-important power boost when critical data must be retrieved or essential communication becomes necessary.</p>
<p>Since the Reactor is embedded into the phone&#8217;s case, there&#8217;s never a circumstance where the phone is without power. A small built-in battery provides enough of a boost to revive a dead phone, while manually cranking the generator can extend the battery life of the iPhone indefinitely.</p></blockquote>
<p>The product specifications on the Reactor crowdfunding page are as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>iPhone 5 Two-Piece Case with Built-in Patented Micro-Generator</li>
<li>400mAh Boost Battery</li>
<li>500mA Manual Generator</li>
<li>8.5mm Thickness</li>
<li>4.5 oz Weight</li>
</ul>
<p>Hand-crank-powered charging is unlikely to generate a huge amount of charge, without a huge amount of effort so manage your expectations accordingly of exactly how practically useful a hand-cranked battery charger will be.</p>
<p>Gridcase&#8217;s wording talks of &#8220;an all-important power boost when critical data must be retrieved or essential communication becomes necessary&#8221;. So think sending a few text messages, rather than being able to finish watching that movie on Netflix. Notably the project page does not include any concrete details on how much charge an hour of cranking will earn you.</p>
<p>While Gridcase is starting with the iPhone 5, it says it plans to expand the range to other smartphones in future. Assuming, of course, it manages to crank up enough interest to get its project funded.</p>
<p>The Reactor for iPhone 5 case is expected to retail for $149, although the first 10,000 Reactors are being offered at an early-bird pledge level of $99. Deliveries are slated to begin in October 2013. As well as hosting the crowdfunding campaign, Crowd Supply will stock the Reactor once/if it&#8217;s available &#8212; acting as Gridcase&#8217;s ecommerce reseller.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781220/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Spk1wfZb0Ds:YHdF1qSscOE:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Spk1wfZb0Ds:YHdF1qSscOE:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Spk1wfZb0Ds:YHdF1qSscOE:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Spk1wfZb0Ds:YHdF1qSscOE:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Spk1wfZb0Ds:YHdF1qSscOE:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Spk1wfZb0Ds:YHdF1qSscOE:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Spk1wfZb0Ds:YHdF1qSscOE:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Spk1wfZb0Ds:YHdF1qSscOE:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/Spk1wfZb0Ds" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/gridcase-reactor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-12-06-56.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-12-06-56.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gridcase</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68a02f90ad0a6349a7b852ddce6f93e4?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nelomas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gridcase.jpg?w=479" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gridcase</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/gridcase-reactor/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Basho Open-Sources Riak CS, Its Big Data Storage Software For Companies That Want Their Own Amazon S3 Cloud</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/niWVr7kB49Y/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/basho-open-sources-riak-cs-its-big-data-storage-software-for-companies-that-want-their-own-amazon-s3-cloud/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alex Williams</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Basho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Riak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[riak cs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781234</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/riakcslogo.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="RiakCSLogo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><a target="_blank" href="http://basho.com">Basho</a> is open-soucing Riak CS, its storage software that integrates with Amazon Web Services. Riak CS will be available under an Apache 2 license.

The move is a smart one for Basho, which has built a reputation for Riak, its distributed high performance database. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/riakcslogo.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="RiakCSLogo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://basho.com">Basho</a> is open-soucing Riak CS, its storage software that integrates with Amazon Web Services. Riak CS will be available under an Apache 2 license.</p>
<p>The move is a smart one for Basho, which has built a reputation for Riak, its distributed high performance database. Riak CS runs on top of Riak and applies the same principles of distributed systems, applying it to the issues that companies have with large-scale storage.</p>
<p>Features include highly available, fault-tolerant storage; large object support; S3-compatible API and authentication; multi-tenancy and per-user reporting; an operational model for adding capacity and a visual interface for monitoring and metrics.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/basho-open-sources-riak-cs-its-big-data-storage-software-for-companies-that-want-their-own-amazon-s3-cloud/riakcs/" rel="attachment wp-att-781247"></a></p>
<p>Open-sourcing Riak CS frees Basho to differentiate Riak Enterprise, which will remain proprietary. It can then also work with the open-source community to build out the storage software and integrate into the enterprise offering. The company launched Riak CS last year. Basho will not open-source the capability it developed to run the storage software across multiple data centers.</p>
<p><span style="font-size:13px;line-height:19px;">Companies increasingly need ways to pass large amounts of data between data centers. Riak CS is meant for files that are 5 gigabytes or larger. The trend is toward companies using public data centers for cheap storage and private data centers for managing data that is core to the enterprise.</span></p>
<p>The growth of open-source efforts such as Cloudstack and OpenStack further demonstrates why Basho has open-sourced its storage software. With these open cloud efforts, the market is demonstrating a growing need for storage software that can run anywhere on any system. Basho can leverage this market with its founding principles based in open-source.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781234/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=niWVr7kB49Y:hEUfelMJppI:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=niWVr7kB49Y:hEUfelMJppI:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=niWVr7kB49Y:hEUfelMJppI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=niWVr7kB49Y:hEUfelMJppI:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=niWVr7kB49Y:hEUfelMJppI:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=niWVr7kB49Y:hEUfelMJppI:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=niWVr7kB49Y:hEUfelMJppI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=niWVr7kB49Y:hEUfelMJppI:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/niWVr7kB49Y" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/basho-open-sources-riak-cs-its-big-data-storage-software-for-companies-that-want-their-own-amazon-s3-cloud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/riakcslogo.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/riakcslogo.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">RiakCSLogo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b4e205744ae2f9b44921d103b4d80e54?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Alex Williams</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/riakcs.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">RiakCS</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/basho-open-sources-riak-cs-its-big-data-storage-software-for-companies-that-want-their-own-amazon-s3-cloud/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Withings Smart Body Analyzer Now Available For $149.95, Here's How It Performs</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/alGa2y0sGfc/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/withings-smart-body-analyzer-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 12:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Darrell Etherington</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781089</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ws-50-front-lb-app1.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="WS-50-front-lb-app" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Withings has built quite a name for itself since launching its first Wi-Fi Body Scale in 2009, and the new Withings Smart Body Scale is perhaps the biggest update yet released for its original connected scale tech. The new hardware monitors and tracks not only weight, but also body fat percentage, blood pressure and environmental air quality. I tested the Smart Body Analyzer over the course of the past week, so if you&#8217;re looking to invest in one of the newly available scales, here&#8217;s how it performs. The Withings Smart Body Analyser (or WS-50, as it&#8217;s known more technically) is a very attractive piece of hardware as far as scales go, which is good because Withings wants you to keep it in the bedroom for maximum effectiveness. That&#8217;s because of the new air quality monitor, which works best when it&#8217;s placed somewhere where you actually spend a lot of time. The air quality meter, combined with the body fat and heart rate measurement are the big selling points here, since they provide the reasons to spend $50 more vs. the standard WS-30 Withings wireless scale. As mentioned, it&#8217;s a good looking scale. It&#8217;s glass-topped, which is also necessary for the sensors to connect with your bare feet to deliver accurate readings. But it also feels very solidly constructed, and the readout is legible and bright, opting for low-res output that&#8217;s probably easier on battery life (the scale should get a full year on just four AAA alkalines) and on the eyes from the distance you&#8217;ll be viewing it at when standing. The bottom line is that the Withings Smart Body Analyzer inspires confidence with its construction, and looks like the type of scale Apple might make were it to produce such a gadget. The Smart Analyzer is pretty simple to set up. There&#8217;s a button on the back (actually more like a pressure sensitive groove) and you hold that down to pair it with your smart phone. A second button controls what units your weight is displayed in on the scale itself (settings within an app control readouts there). The pairing process went smoothly for me on an iPhone 5, and I was then able to transfer Wi-Fi network settings for my home network from the phone, meaning I didn&#8217;t have to reenter (or even remember) my complicated password. The pairing process will also prompt you to install the Withings Health Mate]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ws-50-front-lb-app1.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="WS-50-front-lb-app" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Withings has built quite a name for itself since launching its first Wi-Fi Body Scale in 2009, and the new Withings Smart Body Scale is perhaps the biggest update yet released for its original connected scale tech. The new hardware monitors and tracks not only weight, but also body fat percentage, blood pressure and environmental air quality. I tested the Smart Body Analyzer over the course of the past week, so if you&#8217;re looking to invest in one of the newly available scales, here&#8217;s how it performs.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/basics-subhead.jpg"></a></p>
<p>The Withings Smart Body Analyser (or WS-50, as it&#8217;s known more technically) is a very attractive piece of hardware as far as scales go, which is good because Withings wants you to keep it in the bedroom for maximum effectiveness. That&#8217;s because of the new air quality monitor, which works best when it&#8217;s placed somewhere where you actually spend a lot of time. The air quality meter, combined with the body fat and heart rate measurement are the big selling points here, since they provide the reasons to spend $50 more vs. the standard WS-30 Withings wireless scale.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/hardware-subhead.jpg"></a></p>

<a href='http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/withings-smart-body-analyzer-review/withings-scale-1/' title='withings-scale-1'></a>
<a href='http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/withings-smart-body-analyzer-review/withings-scale-2/' title='withings-scale-2'></a>
<a href='http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/withings-smart-body-analyzer-review/withings-scale-3/' title='withings-scale-3'></a>

<p>As mentioned, it&#8217;s a good looking scale. It&#8217;s glass-topped, which is also necessary for the sensors to connect with your bare feet to deliver accurate readings. But it also feels very solidly constructed, and the readout is legible and bright, opting for low-res output that&#8217;s probably easier on battery life (the scale should get a full year on just four AAA alkalines) and on the eyes from the distance you&#8217;ll be viewing it at when standing. The bottom line is that the Withings Smart Body Analyzer inspires confidence with its construction, and looks like the type of scale Apple might make were it to produce such a gadget.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/setup-subhead.jpg"></a></p>
<p>The Smart Analyzer is pretty simple to set up. There&#8217;s a button on the back (actually more like a pressure sensitive groove) and you hold that down to pair it with your smart phone. A second button controls what units your weight is displayed in on the scale itself (settings within an app control readouts there). The pairing process went smoothly for me on an iPhone 5, and I was then able to transfer Wi-Fi network settings for my home network from the phone, meaning I didn&#8217;t have to reenter (or even remember) my complicated password.</p>
<p>The pairing process will also prompt you to install the Withings Health Mate app on your device. It&#8217;s here that you&#8217;ll create a profile to track your statistics from the scale (and any other Withings devices associated with your account). You can very quickly get up and running with the app, after entering your initial height, weight and age, and you can also set up multiple people to track under a single account if you&#8217;re sharing the scale in the household.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/performance-subhead.jpg"></a></p>
<p>The Withings Analyzer does a great job measuring weight, and communicates with the app seamlessly via Wi-Fi (the Bluetooth connection isn&#8217;t required after your initial setup). And air quality tracking appears to be fairly accurate, in so far as it definitely saw marked increases in CO2 levels when the room was occupied versus when it wasn&#8217;t, and a lot less when no one was home versus when they were.</p>
<p>With body fat percentage and heart rate tracking, I saw some variances since I was lucky enough to be able to test against outside measures. The Withings Smart Analyzer reported both as high compared to tests done on professional measurement tools owned by my local gym. The higher numbers were, however, consistently higher, which means that although they might not have been as accurate as expensive pro-grade hardware, they&#8217;re still very useful as a relative measure over time, which is really the important thing from a home health monitoring device like this anyways. And the convenience of having it right there in your own home for daily measurement outweighs the downsides of it delivering slightly inflated readings.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/bottom-sub.png"></a></p>
<p>The Smart Body Analyzer is an impressive piece of hardware, and builds on the already useful Withings line. Its data can be used by an increasing pool of apps (now at over 80, according to Withings) in addition to the company&#8217;s own, and at $150, you&#8217;re not paying too much of a premium for the added metrics of body fat percentage, resting heart rate and air quality. Data reported may not be 100 percent accurate, but I feel it&#8217;s plenty accurate enough to meet the needs of the vast majority of consumers.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781089/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=alGa2y0sGfc:mHG5H88f49Y:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=alGa2y0sGfc:mHG5H88f49Y:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=alGa2y0sGfc:mHG5H88f49Y:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=alGa2y0sGfc:mHG5H88f49Y:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=alGa2y0sGfc:mHG5H88f49Y:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=alGa2y0sGfc:mHG5H88f49Y:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=alGa2y0sGfc:mHG5H88f49Y:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=alGa2y0sGfc:mHG5H88f49Y:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/alGa2y0sGfc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/withings-smart-body-analyzer-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ws-50-front-lb-app1.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ws-50-front-lb-app1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WS-50-front-lb-app</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/188039e12983eb749171a75cfd01378d?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">etherin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/basics-subhead.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basics-subhead</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/hardware-subhead.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hardware-subhead</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/withings-scale-1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">withings-scale-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/withings-scale-2.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">withings-scale-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/withings-scale-3.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">withings-scale-3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/setup-subhead.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">setup-subhead</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/performance-subhead.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">performance-subhead</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/bottom-sub.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bottom Line</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/withings-smart-body-analyzer-review/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Visa Adds Overstock.com, Its Biggest Retail Catch Yet, To Its V.me Digital Wallet</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/QDZqNOz_6hs/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/visa-adds-overstock-com-its-biggest-retail-catch-yet-to-its-v-me-digital-wallet/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 12:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ingrid Lunden</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[v.me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital wallet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781196</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="54" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/vme_logo.gif?w=100&amp;h=54&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="V.Me" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><a target="_blank" href="http://www.visa.com">Visa</a> today is announcing a key development in its bid to build a ubiquitous digital wallet service to compete against the likes of <a target="_blank" href="http://www.paypal.com">PayPal</a>. It has signed on <a target="_blank" href="http://www.overstock.com">Overstock.com</a> as the lastest retailer to use <a target="_blank" href="https://v.me/">V.me</a>. That service now has 35 online merchants signed up, but Overstock, which makes some $1 billion in online sales annually across categories like furniture, rugs, bedding, electronics, jewelry and cars, and is in the top-five e-commerce sites in the U.S., is by far the biggest. Jennifer Schulz, global head of e-commerce for Visa, tells TechCrunch that there are another 132 online merchants due to go live in the coming weeks.
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="54" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/vme_logo.gif?w=100&amp;h=54&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="V.Me" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.visa.com">Visa</a> today is announcing a key development in its bid to build a ubiquitous digital wallet service to compete against the likes of <a target="_blank" href="http://www.paypal.com">PayPal</a>. It has signed on <a target="_blank" href="http://www.overstock.com">Overstock.com</a> as the lastest retailer to use <a target="_blank" href="https://v.me/">V.me</a>. That service now has 35 online merchants signed up, but Overstock, which makes some $1 billion in online sales annually across categories like furniture, rugs, bedding, electronics, jewelry and cars, and is in the top-five e-commerce sites in the U.S., is by far the biggest. Jennifer Schulz, global head of e-commerce for Visa, tells TechCrunch that there are another 132 online merchants due to go live in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>The deal will mean that &#8212; like existing partners 1-800-FLOWERS, LivingSocial, Newegg and others &#8212; Overstock will use a simplified process to enable payments on the site. Users that pre-register with V.me can then pay on any participating site simply by entering their username and password. </p>
<p>The process of entering payment information when paying has long been seen as a hurdle in e-commerce &#8212; partly because it is time-consuming, and partly because of the security concerns of entering payment details everywhere. Schulz says that the streamlining offered by V.me is a significant step in improving the &#8220;44 fields in the typical checkout process.&#8221; The idea with digital wallets like this one is to circumvent both of those challenges, and help retailers realize what Forrester estimates will be a $327 billion e-commerce opportunity by 2017.</p>
<p>For Overstock, it&#8217;s another step ahead to streamline its service and make it more consumer friendly, and gain more of a competitive edge over the likes of Amazon. </p>
<p>Here it&#8217;s about speeding up the process of payment &#8212; before people change their minds or get distracted by something else online. &#8220;V.me adds yet another quick, simple and safe method to purchase on Overstock.com,&#8221; said Dave Nielsen, co-president, Overstock.com, in a statement. &#8220;Visa is a trusted and reliable brand that reinforces our commitment to our customers.&#8221;</p>
<p>And Overstock is changing elsewhere to evolve the business of online transactions. To drive more engaging discovery, it has <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/pinfluencer-is-now-piqora-as-it-preps-to-add-tumblr-twitter-and-more-to-its-social-marketing-net/">teamed up with Piqora</a> (formerly Pinfluencer) introduce Pinterest-style galleries on its site to highlight items that are trending on social networks (initially, Pinterest and Facebook, but eventually others, too), giving people the ability to buy them right then and there.</p>
<p>And to make it easier to seal the deal and improve after-sales service, it&#8217;s also <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/12/20/overstock-may-take-on-amazon-and-google-with-a-new-locker-delivery-system/">reportedly eyeing up a locker-style system</a>, giving people the ability to select a secure location to deliver purchased goods when they know they may not be at home. This would compete against Amazon Prime, and for all we know could even be something it is working on with a third party such as Google (reportedly testing out <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/04/google-is-building-a-same-day-amazon-prime-competitor-google-shopping-express/">Google Shopping Express</a> for a similar service) or <a target="_blank" href="https://www.shoprunner.com/signup/">Shoprunner</a>.</p>
<p>While 35 retailers does not a ubiquitous service make, what Visa has made sure to line up early on are participating financial institutions. Some 64, include 13 of the top 25 banks in the U.S., are now integrated. This means that consumers whose payment cards are linked up or managed by these banks can use the scheme. And while it is run by Visa, the company tells me that in fact you can be a cardholder with MasterCard, American Express and Discover and it would still work.</p>
<p>Schulz also points out that while the service continues to scale out in the U.S., it is also looking to expand internationally, although that can be tricky with different local regulations around online commerce. &#8220;Looking ahead, we’re also working on plans for scaling V.me in additional countries around the globe, while ensuring our digital wallet experience meets Visa’s standards for security, convenience and reliability as it becomes more broadly available,&#8221; she says. &#8220;The wide range of features and functions being developed for V.me will allow Visa to pursue a number of strategies to tailor and/or bundle services to meet local needs.&#8221;</p>
<p>For now, the main focus is online, but you can see how this will also eventually link up with Visa&#8217;s ambitions in mobile payments &#8212; which include a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/25/visa-samsung-ink-nfc-deal-galaxy-s-iv-first-in-line-for-deep-integration-roam-is-visas-first-ready-mobile-payment-partner/">strong emphasis on NFC embedded in mobile devices</a> and a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/22/visa-debuts-new-mobile-payments-and-nfc-partner-program-for-merchants-and-developers-ready/">set of APIs</a> to take its solutions anywhere that commerce happens &#8212; as well.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781196/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QDZqNOz_6hs:wOlKvg6uoFo:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QDZqNOz_6hs:wOlKvg6uoFo:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QDZqNOz_6hs:wOlKvg6uoFo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QDZqNOz_6hs:wOlKvg6uoFo:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=QDZqNOz_6hs:wOlKvg6uoFo:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QDZqNOz_6hs:wOlKvg6uoFo:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=QDZqNOz_6hs:wOlKvg6uoFo:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=QDZqNOz_6hs:wOlKvg6uoFo:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/QDZqNOz_6hs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/visa-adds-overstock-com-its-biggest-retail-catch-yet-to-its-v-me-digital-wallet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/vme_logo.gif?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/vme_logo.gif?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">V.Me</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6648ec93043f0f368091adece63c6d52?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ingridlunden</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/visa-adds-overstock-com-its-biggest-retail-catch-yet-to-its-v-me-digital-wallet/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Mobile Ticketing Solution Masabi Raises $2.8M To Help Transit Agencies Move To The Cloud, Opens New York Office</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/BzxH7Mx07WI/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/masabi/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 12:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve O'Hear</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Masabi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781213</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/35468v2-max-250x250.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="35468v2-max-250x250" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><a target="_blank" href="http://www.masabi.com">Masabi</a>, which develops and deploys mobile ticketing technology for the transport sector, has raised a further $2.8 million in a new round of funding from Detroit-based <a target="_blank" href="http://www.fontinalispartners.com/">Fontinalis Partners</a>, along with London-based <a target="_blank" href="http://www.mmcventures.com/">MMC Ventures</a> and existing investor <a target="_blank" href="http://www.m8capital.com/">m8 Capital</a>. The new capital will be used by the UK company to "accelerate" transit agency deployments in the U.S.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/35468v2-max-250x250.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="35468v2-max-250x250" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.masabi.com">Masabi</a>, which develops and deploys mobile ticketing technology for the transport sector, has raised a further $2.8 million in a new round of funding from Detroit-based <a target="_blank" href="http://www.fontinalispartners.com/">Fontinalis Partners</a>, along with London-based <a target="_blank" href="http://www.mmcventures.com/">MMC Ventures</a> and existing investor <a target="_blank" href="http://www.m8capital.com/">m8 Capital</a>. </p>
<p>The new capital will be used by the UK company to &#8220;accelerate&#8221; transit agency deployments in the U.S. &#8212; in late 2012 it deployed its &#8220;JustRide&#8221; system for Boston’s MBTA &#8212; as well as opening a New York office. Related to its U.S. expansion, Masabi has hired transit industry &#8220;innovator&#8221; Josh Robin as VP of Strategy and Business Development for North American operations.</p>
<p>Described as a leader in transit mobile ticketing and what it calls &#8220;agile fare collection&#8221;, Masabi&#8217;s mobile tech is all about making it easier to book transport tickets (trains, metro etc.) by utilising mobile phones instead of traditional paper tickets or smartcards. Its flagship product, JustRide, which it sells to transit agencies, is a cloud-based, end-to-end mobile ticketing and fare collection system that includes mobile apps for ticket purchase, use, and ticket agent validation. In the future, it plans to support NFC, too.</p>
<p>For the consumer, once deployed, it enables them to book and display tickets on their mobile without having to stand in line, while for transit agencies, Masabi is talking up the speed of deployment and low cost for the system compared to traditional offerings &#8212; the usual cloud promise &#8212; thus its use of the word &#8220;agile&#8221;.  </p>
<p>Along with the Boston roll out, Masabi&#8217;s tech is in use by more than 13 UK transit agencies and retail brands, including: Virgin Trains, First Group, CrossCountry Trains and thetrainline.com.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s new round brings the company&#8217;s total funding to $8.8 million, with m8 Capital having previously participated in Masabi&#8217;s <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/09/28/masabi-secures-2-million-from-m8-capital-for-its-mobile-ticketing-technology-2/">A</a> and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/04/masabi-secures-4-million-b-round-from-m8-capital-2/">B</a> round, totalling $6m.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781213/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=BzxH7Mx07WI:kNMSCNSwf28:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=BzxH7Mx07WI:kNMSCNSwf28:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=BzxH7Mx07WI:kNMSCNSwf28:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=BzxH7Mx07WI:kNMSCNSwf28:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=BzxH7Mx07WI:kNMSCNSwf28:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=BzxH7Mx07WI:kNMSCNSwf28:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=BzxH7Mx07WI:kNMSCNSwf28:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=BzxH7Mx07WI:kNMSCNSwf28:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/BzxH7Mx07WI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/masabi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/35468v2-max-250x250.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/35468v2-max-250x250.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">35468v2-max-250x250</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/95b8a6df6d265cf57a4d89ee4856ea98?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve O'Hear</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/masabi/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>ShareThis Aims For Mobile, With $23M Series C Led By T-Venture, Acquisition Of Social App Platform, Socialize</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/fW0opNmoH_k/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/sharethis-aims-for-mobile-with-23m-series-c-led-by-t-venture-acquisition-of-social-app-platform-socialize/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 11:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sarah Perez</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ShareThis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Socialize]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=780618</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/logo_sharethis.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Logo_ShareThis" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Palo Alto-based publisher platform <a target="_blank" href="http://www.sharethis.com/">ShareThis</a>, the maker of those "social sharing" buttons scattered across the web, is today announcing having closed on $23 million in Series C financing, in a round led by T-Venture, the venture capital arm of Deutsche Telekom. Additionally, in another move signaling its intention to unify its platform across web and mobile, ShareThis has also acquired <a target="_blank" href="http://www.getsocialize.com/">Socialize</a>, a startup whose developer toolkit <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/06/socialize-makes-any-app-social-already-reaches-10m-end-users/">helps make any app social</a>.
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/logo_sharethis.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Logo_ShareThis" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Palo Alto-based publisher platform <a target="_blank" href="http://www.sharethis.com/">ShareThis</a>, the maker of those &#8220;social sharing&#8221; buttons scattered across the web, is today announcing having closed on $23 million in Series C financing, in a round led by T-Venture, the venture capital arm of Deutsche Telekom. Additionally, in another move signaling its intention to unify its platform across web and mobile, ShareThis has also acquired <a target="_blank" href="http://www.getsocialize.com/">Socialize</a>, a startup whose developer toolkit <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/06/socialize-makes-any-app-social-already-reaches-10m-end-users/">helps make any app social</a>.</p>
<p>The new round of funding included new investors Harbourton and corporate funds represented by West Capital investors, as well as participation from existing investors, Blue Chip Venture Company, DFJ, Illinois Ventures, Matthew Pritzker Company, Mercury Fund and RPM Ventures. As a part of the new round, Bernhard Gold of T-Venture will join ShareThis&#8217;s board. ShareThis&#8217;s total raise to date is $54 million.</p>
<p>Today, ShareThis offers <a target="_blank" href="http://sharethis.com/publishers">publishers</a> sharing widgets, developer tools, and an analytics dashboard detailing social sharing trends across sites, and more, as well as <a target="_blank" href="http://sharethis.com/advertisers">tools for advertisers</a> that allow them to run targeted campaigns across the ShareThis network. But while its platform does offer some mobile sharing tools, ShareThis CEO Kurt Abrahamson says that their focus was primarily on mobile web, not apps.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have a fairly large distribution of tools, so Socialize was partially about distribution in the app space, but it was primarily about finding a really strong team that had mobile a little bit more in its DNA,&#8221; he explains. &#8220;They&#8217;re a great team; they&#8217;re based in San Francisco &#8211; culturally, everything was 100 percent.&#8221;</p>
<p>Abrahamson says that although ShareThis had an app solution, it hadn&#8217;t pushed it, and now following this acquisition, Socialize&#8217;s app solution will become the new default.</p>
<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/sharethis-aims-for-mobile-with-23m-series-c-led-by-t-venture-acquisition-of-social-app-platform-socialize/ipad-iphone-android-display-hp/" rel="attachment wp-att-781130"></a>Socialize, for those unfamiliar, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/07/20/socialize-launches-social-sdk-to-let-developers-unleash-communities-hiding-in-mobile-apps/">spun out of the startup&#8217;s earlier efforts</a> with a service called <a target="_blank" href="http://www.appmakr.com/">AppMakr</a> (also now owned by ShareThis), which helped individuals and businesses build their own native iPhone applications. As Socialize, the company put out a &#8220;Social SDK&#8221; (software development kit), which allows app developers to <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/22/ready-for-more-social-apps-socializes-social-action-bar-hits-version-1-0/">quickly add</a> social features to their mobile applications such as likes, comments, shares, an &#8220;activity pane&#8221; showing other users&#8217; in-app activity, and more. The idea is that it can add a social layer to any app, adding not only the ability for users to connect with each other, but a way for the brand to connect with their in-app user base, as well.</p>
<p>As of <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/06/socialize-makes-any-app-social-already-reaches-10m-end-users/">last spring</a>, the company had 150 live apps on its platform, with another 500 or so in testing, and was reaching around 10 million end users. Today, Socialize has grown to 800 apps across 67 million unique devices, and had just this month scored its first enterprise contract with Warner Bros., which will now be integrating Socialize into its various mobile apps, starting with its &#8220;Ellen&#8221; app (the daytime talkshow).</p>
<p>The Socialize platform will remain up-and-running following the ShareThis acquisition, though it might eventually be rebranded. All six members of the current Socialize team will operate out of ShareThis&#8217;s San Francisco office. Former Socialize CEO, now SVP of Strategic Partnerships at ShareThis, Daniel Odio, says that the service won&#8217;t be changed for current users &#8211; in fact, he adds, it will now be actively improved as a part of ShareThis.</p>
<p>Abrahamson also says that Socialize will help give ShareThis a better position in mobile. &#8220;The biggest challenge is that there&#8217;s not consistent metrics across web and mobile. One of the things we&#8217;re going to focus on is figuring out a solution that will allow publishers to see the sharing of their content across multiple platforms, and not just toggling between one and another,&#8221; he says. &#8220;In the world we&#8217;re evolving to, publishers need to optimize content for all devices, and I think they&#8217;ll see different social sharing patterns, depending on the platform.&#8221;</p>
<p>He adds that, today, many web publishers are seeing higher percentages of users coming from mobile than they may have expected. So with the acquisition, ShareThis wants to be able to analyze that traffic and present it back to publishers, letting them see the value on mobile.</p>
<p>The integration of Socialize into ShareThis&#8217;s platform will take around two quarters to complete, with the initial effort focused on developing a version of <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/06/sharethis-sqi-dashboard/">ShareThis&#8217;s SQI measurement</a> (Social Quality Index) for mobile, a proprietary ranking metric that allows publishers to compare themselves to competitors in their same space.</p>
<p>Also reflective of its increased focus on mobile is the new T-Venture investment, which brings a mobile perspective to ShareThis. But more importantly, perhaps, it brings an international angle. Although there are many publishers outside the U.S. using ShareThis, the company hasn&#8217;t really focused on the global market. That will now change, as ShareThis plans to expand internationally in 2013, including establishing European offices, possibly in Germany or the U.K., expanding its head count along the way by two to three dozen.</p>
<p>ShareThis currently has a publisher base of 2.3 million. The company says its tools are seen by 95 percent of the U.S. Internet audience each month &#8211; over 200 million uniques. In 2012, it grew revenues 155 percent, and grew its staff from 50 to 95. On the advertising side, it works with a large number of major brands, including Microsoft, Samsung, Best Buy, Disney, American Express and others.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/780618/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=fW0opNmoH_k:6w15NvNiAr4:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=fW0opNmoH_k:6w15NvNiAr4:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=fW0opNmoH_k:6w15NvNiAr4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=fW0opNmoH_k:6w15NvNiAr4:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=fW0opNmoH_k:6w15NvNiAr4:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=fW0opNmoH_k:6w15NvNiAr4:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=fW0opNmoH_k:6w15NvNiAr4:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=fW0opNmoH_k:6w15NvNiAr4:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/fW0opNmoH_k" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/sharethis-aims-for-mobile-with-23m-series-c-led-by-t-venture-acquisition-of-social-app-platform-socialize/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/logo_sharethis.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/logo_sharethis.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Logo_ShareThis</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5225bb627e112543aa03bf3b2958be3f?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sarahintampa</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ipad-iphone-android-display-hp.jpg?w=466" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ipad-iphone-android-display-hp</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/sharethis-aims-for-mobile-with-23m-series-c-led-by-t-venture-acquisition-of-social-app-platform-socialize/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Ex-Rocket Internet Execs Launch HotelQuickly In Bid To Become The HotelTonight Of Asia</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/tXhChtzkC5k/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/hotelquickly/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 11:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve O'Hear</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HotelQuickly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HotelTonight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Internet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=780898</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screenshots-android.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="screenshots android" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Today, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.hotelquickly.com">HotelQuickly</a>, a Hong Kong-headquarted startup whose team is comprised of a number of ex-Rocket Internet executives, launches its last-minute hotel booking app which not only bears more than a little resemblance to San Francisco-based <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/hoteltonight">HotelTonight</a>, but appears to borrow heavily from the Samwer brothers' playbook, too.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screenshots-android.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="screenshots android" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>If the Samwer Brothers&#8217; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/rocket-internet">Rocket Internet</a> has a blueprint, it goes something like this: Take a proven business model, usually originating from the U.S., and apply it aggressively to new markets. But that blueprint isn&#8217;t immune to being copied in itself.</p>
<p>Today, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.hotelquickly.com">HotelQuickly</a>, a Hong Kong-headquarted startup whose team is comprised of a number of ex-Rocket Internet executives, launches its last-minute hotel booking app which not only bears more than a little resemblance to San Francisco-based <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/hoteltonight">HotelTonight</a>, but appears to borrow heavily from the Samwer brothers&#8217; playbook, too.</p>
<p>￼Available on <a target="_blank" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hotel-quickly/id587697731?mt=8">iOS</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hotelquickly.app">Android</a> &#8212; and launching in Bangkok, Bali, Hong Kong, Singapore, and Melbourne from the get-go &#8212; the HotelQuickly app lets users book &#8220;last minute&#8221; hotel rooms (up to 2am that night) at heavily discounted prices. Specifically, the app presents a list of up to 6 curated offers, based on a user&#8217;s location and divided into 3 categories (prime, design and comfy), which are only available for booking on the same day.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the draw for hotels who partner with HotelQuickly is that it offers an efficient way to shift spare inventory without eating into their existing market or diminishing their brand via overt discounting. At launch, the startup is partnering with over 100 hotels in the region, including the likes of Hotel LKF by Rhombus, Ovolo ￼Group, and East Hotel, with more to be added over the coming months.</p>
<p>So, yes, very HotelTonight. And very Rocket Internet.</p>
<p>Of HotelQuickly&#8217;s five co-founders, two are Rocket alumni. Christian Mischler (COO) previously held the role of COO at Rocket Internet’s Foodpanda, the online food delivery platform, and Raphael Cohen (CSO) was Managing Director of both Foodpanda Vietnam and DropGifts Singapore. Its <a target="_blank" href="http://www.hotelquickly.com/about-us">other</a> co-founders are Tomas Laboutka (CEO), Michal Juhas (CTO), and Mario Peng (CFO), while in total I&#8217;m told that 9 members of HotelQuickly&#8217;s 30-person team are ex-Rocket Internet.</p>
<p>Funding-wise, until as recently as last week, HotelQuickly was bootstrapped at great cost, says co-founder and CEO Laboutka. It&#8217;s in the process of closing an A round, however, thus far raising $500,000 from various investors in Asia, Europe and the U.S.</p>
<p>In comparison, HotelTonight has raised a hefty $36 million since it was founded in 2010, most <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/05/hoteltonight-23-million-series-c/">recently</a> closing a C round last June. However, it operates in the U.S., Canada, Mexico, and Europe only, so for the time being, HotelQuickly gets a head start in Asia, although it already has at least one local competitor in the form of <a target="_blank" href="http://www.checkintonight.asia">CheckInTonight</a>.</p>
<p>(Update: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/hot-2">Hot Hotels</a>, a European HotelTonight competitor, has <a target="_blank" href="http://hot.co.uk/destinations.html">expanded</a> to Singapore, Thailand, Hong Kong, and Vietnam.)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/780898/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=tXhChtzkC5k:xh3Y-YdpLlE:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=tXhChtzkC5k:xh3Y-YdpLlE:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=tXhChtzkC5k:xh3Y-YdpLlE:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=tXhChtzkC5k:xh3Y-YdpLlE:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=tXhChtzkC5k:xh3Y-YdpLlE:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=tXhChtzkC5k:xh3Y-YdpLlE:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=tXhChtzkC5k:xh3Y-YdpLlE:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=tXhChtzkC5k:xh3Y-YdpLlE:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/tXhChtzkC5k" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/hotelquickly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screenshots-android.png?w=84" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screenshots-android.png?w=84" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">screenshots android</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/95b8a6df6d265cf57a4d89ee4856ea98?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve O'Hear</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/hotelquickly/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Singaporean Ad-Matching Platform AdzCentral Gets $3.2M Series A</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/zk70YPzFs6Q/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/singaporean-ad-matching-platform-adzcentral-gets-3-2m-series-a/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 10:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Victoria Ho</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundings & Exits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ad-matching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adzcentral]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781198</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image2.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="adzcentral logo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />AdzCentral, an ad-matching platform from Singapore, has received $3.2 million (S$4 million) in funding from Electric Sheep Capital and Digital Media Partners . The company provides an engine to advertisers that serves up ads based on targeted audience demographics. Companies spell out the parameters of their intended audience and AdzCentral&#8217;s ads are displayed to people based on what sites they&#8217;ve visited (tracked through cookies) or other information shared by partner sites. Some companies call it &#8220;programmatic buying&#8221;, or &#8220;smart media buying&#8221;, or other permutations of the word &#8220;intelligent&#8221;, really, but it&#8217;s basically ad-matching. These providers are also responsible for the ads that seem to chase you around different websites pushing information that seems to be all-too-appropriate, such as previously browsed shop items. The company&#8217;s founder and CEO, Reza Behnam said he industry estimates peg the U.S. market for ad-matching to be worth about $6 billion in 2015, making up about 25 percent of digital display ads in that year. This is up from 13 percent last year, representing some impressive growth, if it happens. And in Asia, digital ad spend is about $25 billion, with only 3 percent of that based on ad-matching. That will become 20 percent in 2015, he said, citing other analyst estimates. It&#8217;s the Asia angle that he&#8217;s counting on. AdzCentral competes with U.S. giants like Rocket Fuel and Acceleration (acquired by WPP), but being in Asia allows it to serve advertisers or Asian subsidiaries of MNCs, said Behnam. It counts brands like SingTel, Standard Chartered, Hyundai and 3M as clients, and has served about 1,000 companies over a base of 100 clients in its three years of operations. The company isn&#8217;t profitable yet, he said, but is planning to spend its Series A money in Southeast Asian expansion efforts. It has &#8220;quietly launched&#8221; in Thailand and Malaysia so far, with people on the ground. It hasn&#8217;t set up offices in those countries, but it is looking to, he said. Vietnam and the Philippines will come later, and it has some advertising partners in India and the Middle East, he said. There are about twenty employees on the ground right now. AdzCentral started in 2010, and won &#8220;seven-digit&#8221; seed funding in August that year from a group of angels that included the Singapore government&#8217;s National Research Foundation (NRF) and Joichi Ito-fronted Neoteny Labs. Behnam was formerly the managing director of Yahoo for Southeast Asia in 2004,]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image2.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="adzcentral logo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.adzcentral.com">AdzCentral</a>, an ad-matching platform from Singapore, has received $3.2 million (S$4 million) in funding from Electric Sheep Capital and Digital Media Partners .</p>
<p>The company provides an engine to advertisers that serves up ads based on targeted audience demographics. Companies spell out the parameters of their intended audience and AdzCentral&#8217;s ads are displayed to people based on what sites they&#8217;ve visited (tracked through cookies) or other information shared by partner sites.</p>
<p>Some companies call it &#8220;programmatic buying&#8221;, or &#8220;smart media buying&#8221;, or other permutations of the word &#8220;intelligent&#8221;, really, but it&#8217;s basically ad-matching. These providers are also responsible for the ads that seem to chase you around different websites pushing information that seems to be all-too-appropriate, such as previously browsed shop items.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s founder and CEO, Reza Behnam said he industry estimates peg the U.S. market for ad-matching to be worth about $6 billion in 2015, making up about 25 percent of digital display ads in that year. This is up from 13 percent last year, representing some impressive growth, if it happens.</p>
<p>And in Asia, digital ad spend is about $25 billion, with only 3 percent of that based on ad-matching. That will become 20 percent in 2015, he said, citing other analyst estimates.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image3.jpg"></a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s the Asia angle that he&#8217;s counting on. AdzCentral competes with U.S. giants like <a target="_blank" href="http://www.rocketfuel.com">Rocket Fuel</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.wpp.com/wpp/companies/acceleration">Acceleration</a> (acquired by WPP), but being in Asia allows it to serve advertisers or Asian subsidiaries of MNCs, said Behnam. It counts brands like SingTel, Standard Chartered, Hyundai and 3M as clients, and has served about 1,000 companies over a base of 100 clients in its three years of operations.</p>
<p>The company isn&#8217;t profitable yet, he said, but is planning to spend its Series A money in Southeast Asian expansion efforts. It has &#8220;quietly launched&#8221; in Thailand and Malaysia so far, with people on the ground. It hasn&#8217;t set up offices in those countries, but it is looking to, he said. Vietnam and the Philippines will come later, and it has some advertising partners in India and the Middle East, he said. There are about twenty employees on the ground right now.</p>
<p>AdzCentral started in 2010, and won &#8220;seven-digit&#8221; seed funding in August that year from a group of angels that included the Singapore government&#8217;s National Research Foundation (NRF) and Joichi Ito-fronted Neoteny Labs.</p>
<p>Behnam was formerly the managing director of Yahoo for Southeast Asia in 2004, and was a venture partner at IDG Ventures. He is the vice-Chairman for the Singapore Chapter of the Interactive Advertising Bureau (IAB), a trade association of digital advertisers.</p>
<p>Electric Sheep Pte Ltd is the name of the Singapore-based investment entity. It doesn&#8217;t seem to have a website, but it has a really strange <a target="_blank" href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Electric-Sheep-Pte-Ltd/230107483670848">Facebook page</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781198/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=zk70YPzFs6Q:XF1tXK4PyUg:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=zk70YPzFs6Q:XF1tXK4PyUg:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=zk70YPzFs6Q:XF1tXK4PyUg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=zk70YPzFs6Q:XF1tXK4PyUg:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=zk70YPzFs6Q:XF1tXK4PyUg:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=zk70YPzFs6Q:XF1tXK4PyUg:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=zk70YPzFs6Q:XF1tXK4PyUg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=zk70YPzFs6Q:XF1tXK4PyUg:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/zk70YPzFs6Q" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/singaporean-ad-matching-platform-adzcentral-gets-3-2m-series-a/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image2.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image2.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">adzcentral logo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2730ac85eb6d3f6f7491d176987aab05?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">victoriatc</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image3.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">adzcentral screenshot</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/singaporean-ad-matching-platform-adzcentral-gets-3-2m-series-a/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon's Carrier Billing Deal With Bango To Kick In This Year – Changes For The Appstore And Amazon Ahead?</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/k4O5CMVI10U/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/amazons-carrier-billing-deal-with-bango-to-kick-in-this-year-changes-for-the-appstore-and-amazon-ahead/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 10:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ingrid Lunden</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appstore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrier Billing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bango]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=780313</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/amazon-apps.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="amazon-apps" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com">Amazon</a> has yet to turn on any services on the back of a <a target="_blank" href="http://paidcontent.org/2011/12/08/419-amazon-may-be-eyeing-up-carrier-billing-for-its-mobile-content-business/">deal it signed</a> with carrier billing specialist <a target="_blank" href="http://www.bango.com">Bango</a> over a year ago, but it looks like we may finally see the first fruits come out later this year, according to a source, with the launch of carrier billing in Amazon's Appstore for Android. This points to a more aggressive push from the tech giant not only on services, but also devices -- which today cover tablets but may also include phones in the near future.
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/amazon-apps.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="amazon-apps" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com">Amazon</a> has yet to turn on any services on the back of a <a target="_blank" href="http://paidcontent.org/2011/12/08/419-amazon-may-be-eyeing-up-carrier-billing-for-its-mobile-content-business/">deal it signed</a> with carrier billing specialist <a target="_blank" href="http://www.bango.com">Bango</a> over a year ago, but it looks like we may finally see the first fruits come out later this year, according to a source, with the launch of carrier billing in Amazon&#8217;s Appstore for Android. This points to a more aggressive push from the tech giant not only on services, but also devices &#8212; which today cover tablets but may also include phones in the near future.</p>
<p>In a statement issued yesterday detailing its not-brilliant earnings for the last <a target="_blank" href="http://www.londonstockexchange.com/exchange/news/market-news/market-news-detail.html?announcementId=11522343">nine months</a> (revenues $11.2m; net loss $3m), Bango notes that the results &#8220;do not include any material income from the agreements signed with Amazon.&#8221; Looking at the future outlook, Bango remains positive on the progress of its relationship with Amazon, describing &#8220;continued adoption of its technology by industry players with partners such as Facebook and Amazon&#8221; in the months ahead. Meanwhile, a note in <a target="_blank" href="http://bango.com/assets/data/investor/bango_annual_report_9m2012.pdf">Bango&#8217;s annual report</a>, also issued yesterday, notes that the company has completed its integration with Amazon, adding it to a roster that already included app storefronts run by Facebook, Google, BlackBerry, Microsoft and Opera &#8212; &#8220;most of the leading app stores,&#8221; the obvious missing piece being Apple&#8217;s App Store.</p>
<p>We reached out to Bango for more clarification; a company spokesperson declined to comment. We also have questions out to Amazon. Meanwhile, a source close to the matter tells TechCrunch that, in fact, both parties are finally preparing for &#8220;this service to go live this year.&#8221;</p>
<p>Amazon&#8217;s Appstore is pre-installed and the default apps storefront on its Kindle Fire tablets, but users of other Android devices can also buy from the store by sideloading, or by <a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/feature.html?ie=UTF8&amp;docId=1000626391&amp;ref_=amb_link_363093842_2">installing the Appstore app</a> on their non-Amazon handsets or tablets. The Bango service is &#8220;directly for Amazon itself,&#8221; notes the source, and not for any third parties that work with the platform.</p>
<p>Although it would certainly be a help to Bango&#8217;s business to have another app store using its payments platform, adding in another payment option for Amazon&#8217;s mobile content could point to several developments for the bigger company, too.</p>
<p><strong>The most obvious one is that it would add carrier billing to Amazon&#8217;s existing Kindle Fire tablet business</strong>. Today, this would have a limited scope: it appears that it is only in the U.S. that Amazon has a direct connectivity deal with a carrier. There, it sells its <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/Kindle-Fire-4G-LTE/dp/B008GFRDL0">8.9-inch Kindle Fire HD</a> with 4G LTE data connectivity provided by AT&amp;T. An announcement last week that Amazon would begin selling the 8.9-inch Kindle Fire HD in <a target="_blank" href="http://phx.corporate-ir.net/phoenix.zhtml?c=176060&amp;p=irol-newsArticle&amp;ID=1795817&amp;highlight=">Europe and Japan</a> did not say whether any of those launches would include LTE services. This could be one signal that Amazon is gearing up to turn on the LTE hose elsewhere.</p>
<p><strong>A second option, related to the first, is that this could be used by Amazon to further extend where and how it markets its digital content business</strong> (apps, books, games, video, music) in other markets outside of the U.S.</p>
<p>Last year saw Amazon launch a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/12/06/amazon-finally-reclaims-its-namesake-launches-in-brazil-with-kindle-store/">Kindle store in Brazil</a>. Emerging markets like Latin America that have become a big target for carrier billing services, because of the low penetration of payment cards &#8212; credit and debit &#8212; among consumers. (It&#8217;s an area that Bango <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/08/bango-raises-10-2m-to-take-its-mobile-payments-service-into-brazil-india-and-other-asian-markets/">specifically raised $10.2 million</a> to better target this year, and it&#8217;s one that its other partners, such as <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/16/bango-adds-telefonica-to-its-list-of-mobile-carrier-billing-partners-for-facebook-and-beyond/">Telefonica</a> and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/27/bango-to-power-payments-in-mozillas-firefox-os-app-store-carrier-billing-by-default/">Mozilla</a>, will also be targeting with carrier billing services for content.)</p>
<p>Combining this with the fact that the Appstore can be used on Android devices other than the Kindle Fire, offering a route for consumers in these places to buy apps, music, video and books by charging the purchases to their operators will give Amazon a window to significantly more digital content revenues internationally. That portfolio of offerings may itself be growing, with <a target="_blank" href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/19/4124702/amazon-talks-to-record-labels-about-subscription-music-service">recent reports of a subscription music service</a>, fuelling the need for quicker and easier ways to pay for that content.</p>
<p><strong>A third option is that Amazon may really be gearing up for another kind of device, a handset</strong>. An Amazon phone ranks up there with the much-fabled <a target="_blank" href="http://www.techmeme.com/search/query?q=%22facebook+phone%22&amp;wm=false">Facebook phone</a> as something that people have been hoping/expecting to see for a while.</p>
<p>But just as there appear to be more smoke signals (actually, let&#8217;s call that smoke <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/08/htc-facebook-phone-specs-leak-outlining-a-solid-mid-range-device-with-fb-and-instagram-pre-loaded/">Myst</a>) around Facebook&#8217;s plans, so too is the Amazon handset getting some recent buzz. In <a target="_blank" href="http://www.engadget.com/2012/12/17/foxconn-reportedly-manufacturing-amazon-smartphone/">February</a>, there were reports that Amazon has put in an order for some 5 million handsets with Foxconn, with the handsets shipping either in Q2 or Q3 this year and priced at between $100 and $200. Some have even <a target="_blank" href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/ewanspence/2012/12/17/the-coming-amazon-kindle-phone-is-not-going-to-be-a-surprise/">started to flesh out that rumor with device specs</a> based on what components are cheap and readily available.</p>
<p>Amazon has been readying <a target="_blank" href="https://developer.amazon.com/post/Tx1FZ1NVQHKUHN/Manage-Bulk-App-Distribution-with-Whispercast-for-Kindle">other services</a> that it could leverage on a larger portfolio of devices. One of the biggest is <a target="_blank" href="https://developer.amazon.com/sdk/mobileads.html?ref_=pe_132830_28453530">its own mobile ad network</a>. As <a target="_blank" href="http://www.businessinsider.com/amazons-new-mobile-ad-network-is-a-huge-threat-to-google-2013-3">BI points out</a>, these ads will appear in any apps that have been downloaded from Amazon&#8217;s Appstore, on any Android device, but creating its own handset will give Amazon potentially a much bigger, guaranteed volume of devices that would help that network scale out.</p>
<p>Going back to Bango and carrier billing, it would be on a handset, too, that a carrier billing service would work most effectively and most obviously. While Amazon&#8217;s tablets mostly today do not connect with carriers, mobile phones certainly will.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/780313/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=k4O5CMVI10U:L1KZHEbZQhI:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=k4O5CMVI10U:L1KZHEbZQhI:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=k4O5CMVI10U:L1KZHEbZQhI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=k4O5CMVI10U:L1KZHEbZQhI:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=k4O5CMVI10U:L1KZHEbZQhI:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=k4O5CMVI10U:L1KZHEbZQhI:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=k4O5CMVI10U:L1KZHEbZQhI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=k4O5CMVI10U:L1KZHEbZQhI:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/k4O5CMVI10U" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/amazons-carrier-billing-deal-with-bango-to-kick-in-this-year-changes-for-the-appstore-and-amazon-ahead/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/amazon-apps.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/amazon-apps.jpeg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">amazon-apps</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6648ec93043f0f368091adece63c6d52?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ingridlunden</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/amazons-carrier-billing-deal-with-bango-to-kick-in-this-year-changes-for-the-appstore-and-amazon-ahead/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Fashion Site Nasty Gal Flirts With Free Shipping To Encourage Shoppers To Splurge</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/FQ4arpQoF4k/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/nasty-gal-free-shipping-offer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 10:18:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natasha Lomas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[eCommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nasty Gal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online fashion shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free shipping]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781160</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nastygal-logo.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="nastygal-logo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />LA-based online fashion outlet Nasty Gal, which picked up almost $50 million in funding last year in two rounds (both from Index Ventures), is now using some of that cash to bankroll a limited time offer of free overnight shipping for customers who spend $150+. The site sells -- in its own words -- “unapologetically sexy” fashions, targeting "fashion-forward, free-thinking girls".]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nastygal-logo.png?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="nastygal-logo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>LA-based online fashion outlet <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nastygal.com/about-us/">Nasty Gal</a>, which picked up <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/08/26/nasty-gal-fashion40m-index-ventures/">almost $50 million</a> in funding last year in two rounds (both <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/03/05/fashion-outpost-nasty-gal-raises-9m-from-index-ventures-with-28m-in-revenue/">from Index Ventures</a>), is now using some of that cash to bankroll a limited time offer of free overnight shipping for customers who spend $150+. The site sells &#8212; in its own words &#8212; “unapologetically sexy” fashions, targeting &#8221;fashion-forward, free-thinking girls&#8221;.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not clear how long the <a target="_blank" href="http://blog.nastygal.com/features-and-shoots/newsflash/2013/03/see-you-tomorrow/">free shipping offer</a>, which is only open to U.S. customers and does not extend to international shipping, will run. Nasty Gal normally charges $29 for an Overnight UPS Service that takes &#8220;one day&#8221; to arrive. We&#8217;ve reached out to the company to ask for more details and will update this story with any response.</p>
<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/12/23/thanks-to-free-shipping-offers-online-holiday-sales-surge-16-percent-to-39b/">Free shipping is a proven tool to get online shoppers clicking</a> &#8211; even more so for online fashion retail which has to deal with the problem of high return rates since buyers aren&#8217;t trying clothes on for size (and style) before buying. UK-based online fashion giant ASOS has offered free standard shipping (and free returns) for years, for example, to keep customers clicking.</p>
<p>The online clothes shopping returns problem may be even more acute for a racy fashions site like Nasty Gals than some of the broader church fashion sites like ASOS which sell a mix of styles to women and men. One girl&#8217;s “unapologetically sexy” is another&#8217;s &#8216;uber tacky&#8217; &#8212; there is, as they say, no accounting for taste. So adding free overnight shipping is one way for Nasty Gal to circumvent any pre-purchase nerves shoppers might have &#8212; about whether those <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nastygal.com/by-nasty-gal_bottoms/coated-garter-leggings">coated garter leggings</a> or <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nastygal.com/by-nasty-gal_bottoms/heavenly-body-shorts">heavenly body shorts</a> will look absolutely awesome or terribly trashy. (Or, as the Nasty Gal <a target="_blank" href="http://blog.nastygal.com/features-and-shoots/newsflash/2013/03/see-you-tomorrow/">blog</a> puts it: &#8220;Now you officially have an excuse to get everything in your tote.&#8221;)</p>
<p>Buyers are encouraged to order several possible items, to reach the $150 threshold, and can then send back the ones that don&#8217;t suit. And with speedy shipping the whole process doesn&#8217;t drag out over the best part of a week (meaning buyers are freed up to spend again if nothing suits).</p>
<p>Add to that, plenty of individual items on Nasty Gal retail for more than $150 (although its own-label items are generally well below that mark) &#8211; so the minimum spend to qualify for the free shipping offer doesn&#8217;t necessarily demand a digital basket stuffed with stuff. The offer may therefore also be aimed at encouraging shoppers to purchase some of the more expensive items on the site &#8212; as they factor in their shipping savings plus the instant gratification of getting the gear the next day.</p>
<p>Free shipping is one way to tackle the problem of online clothing size and fit. But there are of course bags of startups trying to use tech to solve the problem at source &#8212; including <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/22/clothes-horse-wants-to-solve-the-biggest-problem-with-online-shopping-finding-clothes-that-fit/">Clothes Horse</a>, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/07/fits-me-secures-new-funding-to-expand-its-fitting-room-robots/">Fits.me</a>, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/09/10/fitiquette-online-clothing-measurement-never-looked-so-good/">Fitiquette</a> and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/05/metail-the-virtual-fitting-room-startup/">Metail</a>, to name a few.</p>
<p>Another one &#8211; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.virtusize.com/">Virtusize</a> &#8211; is evidently currently being trialled by ASOS, as their &#8220;fit visualiser&#8221; interface appears on a minority of ASOS items. This approach requires buyers to measure a garment they already own that fits them and then offers a comparison with the item that&#8217;s for sale:</p>
<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/nasty-gal-free-shipping-offer/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-09-38-32/" rel="attachment wp-att-781164"></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781160/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FQ4arpQoF4k:DPv6Vh6fdVY:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FQ4arpQoF4k:DPv6Vh6fdVY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FQ4arpQoF4k:DPv6Vh6fdVY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FQ4arpQoF4k:DPv6Vh6fdVY:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=FQ4arpQoF4k:DPv6Vh6fdVY:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FQ4arpQoF4k:DPv6Vh6fdVY:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=FQ4arpQoF4k:DPv6Vh6fdVY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=FQ4arpQoF4k:DPv6Vh6fdVY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/FQ4arpQoF4k" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/nasty-gal-free-shipping-offer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nastygal-logo.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nastygal-logo.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nastygal-logo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68a02f90ad0a6349a7b852ddce6f93e4?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nelomas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-20-at-09-38-32.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Asos size visualiser</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/nasty-gal-free-shipping-offer/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Jawbone Releases Android UP App, Makes Wristband Available In European Apple Stores</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/StfQCVJQYOQ/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/jawbone-android/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 06:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Catherine Shu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jawbone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[up]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781150</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/jawboneupblue.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="jawboneupblue" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Jawbone <a target="_blank" href="http://www.sys-con.com/node/2585634">announced</a> today that its app for <a target="_blank" href="https://jawbone.com/up">UP</a>, the company's movement-tracking wristband, is now available for Android on Google Play. The $129 UP was previously only compatible with iOS. The wristband can also now be purchased in European Apple stores, and will be made available in Asia and Australia next month.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/jawboneupblue.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="jawboneupblue" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Jawbone <a target="_blank" href="http://www.sys-con.com/node/2585634">announced</a> today that its app for <a target="_blank" href="https://jawbone.com/up">UP</a>, the company&#8217;s movement-tracking wristband, is now available as a free download for Android on Google Play. The $129 UP was previously only compatible with iOS. The wristband can also now be purchased in European Apple stores, and will be made available in Asia and Australia next month.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are excited to expand the UP community by introducing support for Android, 11 new languages for iOS, and product availability in more than 25 additional countries around the world,&#8221; said Travis Bogard, Jawbone vice president of product management and strategy, in a statement.</p>
<p>When coupled with its app, the UP wristband allows users to track their sleep, movement, food, and mood. Apple Stores in Asia and Australia will begin carrying the gadget next month, along with other retail locations in Europe, Asia, Australia, and the Middle East.</p>
<p>While Android users can now use Jawbone UP, the company says it currently has no plans to release the UP app to BlackBerry 10 or Windows Phone.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781150/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=StfQCVJQYOQ:ZWeIwafavRM:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=StfQCVJQYOQ:ZWeIwafavRM:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=StfQCVJQYOQ:ZWeIwafavRM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=StfQCVJQYOQ:ZWeIwafavRM:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=StfQCVJQYOQ:ZWeIwafavRM:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=StfQCVJQYOQ:ZWeIwafavRM:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=StfQCVJQYOQ:ZWeIwafavRM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=StfQCVJQYOQ:ZWeIwafavRM:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/StfQCVJQYOQ" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/jawbone-android/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/jawboneupblue.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/jawboneupblue.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jawboneupblue</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4b15381361f439f6782de896e29143f1?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">catherineshu</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/jawbone-android/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>China Telecom's 4Q Earnings Boosted Above Analysts' Estimates Thanks To iPhone Usage</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/vzBpiZ_-1eA/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/china-telecoms-4q-earnings-boosted-above-analysts-estimates-thanks-to-iphone-usage/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 06:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Catherine Shu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china telecom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781143</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2010/11/chinatelecom.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Image (1) chinatelecom.jpg for post 346591" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />China Telecom, the third-largest telecommunications company in that country, reported better-than-expected 4Q profit as customers using the iPhone helped boost sales of wireless data.

Net earnings fell 17 percent to 2.36 billion yuan ($380 million USD) from 2.84 billion yuan a year earlier, but outperformed the 2.04 billion yuan average estimated by analysts asked by Bloomberg. 4Q sales rose 17 percent to 73.1 billion yuan, from 62.6 billion yuan, in-line with the 73.2 billion yuan expected by analysts.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2010/11/chinatelecom.jpg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Image (1) chinatelecom.jpg for post 346591" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>China Telecom, the third-largest telecommunications company in that country, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.chinatelecom-h.com/eng/ir/kpi_quarterly.php">reported</a> better-than-expected 4Q profit as customers using the iPhone helped boost sales of wireless data.</p>
<p>Net earnings fell 17 percent to 2.36 billion yuan ($380 million USD) from 2.84 billion yuan a year earlier, but outperformed the 2.04 billion yuan average <a target="_blank" href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-20/china-telecom-profit-beats-estimates-as-iphone-lifts-data.html">estimated</a> by analysts asked by Bloomberg. 4Q sales rose 17 percent to 73.1 billion yuan, from 62.6 billion yuan, in-line with the 73.2 billion yuan expected by analysts.</p>
<p>China Telecom <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/20/china-telecom-to-get-iphone-in-march/">started selling the iPhone in March </a>as part of its campaign to grab more higher-end 3G users. Up until that point, the larger China Unicom had been the first and only carrier to offer Apple&#8217;s smartphone <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2009/10/30/the-iphone-launches-in-china-today-seems-to-arouse-little-interest-pictures-from-beijing/">since October 2009</a> (China Mobile <a target="_blank" href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/03/13/us-chinamobile-iphone-idUSBRE92C1CQ20130313">has yet to offer customers an iPhone contract</a>).</p>
<p>China Telecom said when it first started carrying the iPhone that the device would increase long-term growth, but put &#8220;short-term pressure&#8221; on profitability. Indeed, since releasing the iPhone, China Telecom has reported <a target="_blank" href="http://www.bloomberg.com/quote/728:HK">three straight declines</a> in quarterly profit. The company&#8217;s focus on <a target="_blank" href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2012/08/22/us-chinatelecom-earnings-idUSBRE87L03N20120822">expanding</a> its 3G coverage means that its selling expenses, including handset subsidies, are higher than usual. Last August the company said that it was acquiring 3G network infrastructure from its parent, China Telecom Corp., for an initial $13.3 billion to cut future costs, and that the final value of the deal would be more than 117 billion yuan.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781143/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=vzBpiZ_-1eA:D6959dIsO7Q:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=vzBpiZ_-1eA:D6959dIsO7Q:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=vzBpiZ_-1eA:D6959dIsO7Q:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=vzBpiZ_-1eA:D6959dIsO7Q:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=vzBpiZ_-1eA:D6959dIsO7Q:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=vzBpiZ_-1eA:D6959dIsO7Q:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=vzBpiZ_-1eA:D6959dIsO7Q:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=vzBpiZ_-1eA:D6959dIsO7Q:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/vzBpiZ_-1eA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/china-telecoms-4q-earnings-boosted-above-analysts-estimates-thanks-to-iphone-usage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2010/11/chinatelecom.jpg?w=135" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2010/11/chinatelecom.jpg?w=135" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image (1) chinatelecom.jpg for post 346591</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4b15381361f439f6782de896e29143f1?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">catherineshu</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/china-telecoms-4q-earnings-boosted-above-analysts-estimates-thanks-to-iphone-usage/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon Launches ‘Send to Kindle' Button For Web Developers &amp; WordPress Blogs</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/ldWcgnsmdbo/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/amazon-launches-send-to-kindle-button-for-web-developers-wordpress-blogs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 02:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Catherine Shu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=781133</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kindle-fam.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Kindle Family" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />Amazon just launched the Send to Kindle button, which clips Web content and saves it to Kindle readers and apps, for <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/sendtokindle/developers/button">Web developers</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/send-to-kindle/">WordPress bloggers</a>. The button is also now available on The Washington Post, TIME, and Boing Boing. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kindle-fam.jpeg?w=100&amp;h=70&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Kindle Family" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>Amazon just <a target="_blank" href="http://www.kindlepost.com/2013/03/send-to-kindle-button.html">launched the Send to Kindle button</a>, which clips Web content and saves it to Kindle readers and apps, for <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/sendtokindle/developers/button">Web developers</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/send-to-kindle/">WordPress bloggers</a>. The button is also now available on <a target="_blank" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/">The Washington Post</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.time.com/time/magazine">TIME</a>, and <a target="_blank" href="http://boingboing.net/">Boing Boing</a>.</p>
<p>The <a target="_blank" href="www.amazon.com/sendtokindle">Send to Kindle suite</a>, which Amazon <a target="_blank" href="http://paidcontent.org/2012/08/15/kindle-read-it-later/">launched last year</a> with its Send to Kindle button for Google Chrome, is being positioned as an alternative to content-clipping services like Pocket and Instapaper, making it easier for users to read content besides e-books on their devices:</p>
<blockquote><p>The Send to Kindle Button lets you easily send that content to your Kindle to read later, at your convenience. Just send once and read everywhere on any of your Kindle devices or free Kindle reading apps for iPhone, iPad and Android phones or tablets. No more hunting around for that website or blog that caught your eye &#8212; just open your Kindle and all the content you sent is right there. The Send to Kindle Button is also great for those who want to collect content from the web to use in work projects, school assignments, or hobbies.</p></blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/781133/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=ldWcgnsmdbo:msDup08SNnU:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=ldWcgnsmdbo:msDup08SNnU:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=ldWcgnsmdbo:msDup08SNnU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=ldWcgnsmdbo:msDup08SNnU:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=ldWcgnsmdbo:msDup08SNnU:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=ldWcgnsmdbo:msDup08SNnU:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=ldWcgnsmdbo:msDup08SNnU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=ldWcgnsmdbo:msDup08SNnU:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/ldWcgnsmdbo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/amazon-launches-send-to-kindle-button-for-web-developers-wordpress-blogs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kindle-fam.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kindle-fam.jpeg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kindle Family</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4b15381361f439f6782de896e29143f1?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">catherineshu</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/amazon-launches-send-to-kindle-button-for-web-developers-wordpress-blogs/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Social Platform Unison Adds Voice And Video Using WebRTC, Features You Won't Find In Yammer, Convo Or Chatter</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/zgpIM9jReas/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/social-platform-unison-adds-voice-and-video-using-webrtc-features-you-wont-find-in-yammer-convo-or-chatter/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:41:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alex Williams</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yammer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web rtc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[convo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=780919</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img width="65" height="64" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/unisonlogo.png?w=65&amp;h=64&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="unisonlogo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" />The news feed is getting increasingly complex. It's evident in <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/18/the-new-salesforce-com-crm-platform-is-chatter-and-its-made-for-mobile/">Salesforce Chatter</a>, which has added a new layer to the feed for sales people to add, edit or complete deals. Unison is breaking through the added confusion of the feed by changing the metaphor and the information architecture with a new capability to leverage <a target="_blank" href="http://www.webrtc.org/">WebRTC</a>.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="65" height="64" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/unisonlogo.png?w=65&amp;h=64&amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="unisonlogo" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /><p>The news feed is getting increasingly complex. It&#8217;s evident in <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/18/the-new-salesforce-com-crm-platform-is-chatter-and-its-made-for-mobile/">Salesforce Chatter</a>, which has added a new layer to the feed for sales people to add, edit or complete deals. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.unison.com/">Unison</a> is breaking through the added confusion of the feed by changing the metaphor and the information architecture with a new capability to leverage <a target="_blank" href="http://www.webrtc.org/">WebRTC</a>.</p>
<p>The new business communications tool connects calls from the app across all three major platforms: in a browser as well as smartphone and desktop apps.</p>
<p>Unison has built a collaboration platform with a backend running on the Amazon cloud. It is architected on Riak, for high availability and data integrity. The client apps for Windows, Mac, Android, iOS and web run on a variety of platforms, as appropriate for the environment.</p>
<p>WebRTC is the open standard developed by Google and Opera. It makes real-time communication native to the browser. No need for stubborn plugins &#8212; apps can be built directly on the browser for a seamless experience, be it with audio, video or chat.</p>
<p>WebRTC with rooms is the metaphor for communication. There are no longer multiple streams running down a page, making you feel like a Matrix cyborg trying to follow along. Instead, the user interface is divided according to a room or different rooms where you are participating in conversations.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/social-platform-unison-adds-voice-and-video-using-webrtc-features-you-wont-find-in-yammer-convo-or-chatter/unisonroom/" rel="attachment wp-att-780994"></a></p>
<p>Rooms have been tried before as a metaphor for virtual groups, but they were not dynamic. Unison syncs the data so everyone can be updated at the same time whether they&#8217;re using the client or web app. People can view the rooms and a general news feed.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/social-platform-unison-adds-voice-and-video-using-webrtc-features-you-wont-find-in-yammer-convo-or-chatter/room-with-news-feed-open/" rel="attachment wp-att-780995"></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve used Yammer and tried Chatter, and at TechCrunch we use Convo. All suffer from latency, which causes it to lack real-time capabilities. Yammer, Chatter and Convo all force you into traditional feeds. None of them have WebRTC. In fact, Yammer CEO David Sacks told me at SXSW that he was not familiar with it. With WebRTC, Unison has developed a real-time way for people to mix conversations over time (posts, files, comments) with real-time conversations via voice and video.</p>
<p>The future is the feed, but we need new metaphors to make the experience better. Unison sets a direction for the way to build an information architecture and the kind of visual representation needed to make working in virtual teams an experience that transcends the noise of traditional feeds. Adding WebRTC makes the experience richer and easier to manage.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, Unison is in a crowded space. Analyst Alan Lepofsky put this <a target="_blank" href="http://www.alanlepofsky.net/alepofsky/alanblog.nsf/dx/enterprise-collaboration-vendors-im-currently-tracking">list</a> together last year, showing how difficult it is to gain traction in a market that has matured to the point where almost everyone can boast some social capability.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/780919/"></a> <div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=zgpIM9jReas:sSb6-3zGK6Y:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=zgpIM9jReas:sSb6-3zGK6Y:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=zgpIM9jReas:sSb6-3zGK6Y:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=zgpIM9jReas:sSb6-3zGK6Y:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=zgpIM9jReas:sSb6-3zGK6Y:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=zgpIM9jReas:sSb6-3zGK6Y:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=zgpIM9jReas:sSb6-3zGK6Y:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=zgpIM9jReas:sSb6-3zGK6Y:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/zgpIM9jReas" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/social-platform-unison-adds-voice-and-video-using-webrtc-features-you-wont-find-in-yammer-convo-or-chatter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/unisonlogo.png?w=65" />
		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/unisonlogo.png?w=65" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">unisonlogo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b4e205744ae2f9b44921d103b4d80e54?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Alex Williams</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/unisonroom.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">unisonroom</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/room-with-news-feed-open.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Room with news feed open</media:title>
		</media:content>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/social-platform-unison-adds-voice-and-video-using-webrtc-features-you-wont-find-in-yammer-convo-or-chatter/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss>
