<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Diary of a Nomad Mom</title>
	<atom:link href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com</link>
	<description>My inner bitch speaks 4 languages</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 05:38:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>THE TODDLER BED</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/the-toddler-bed/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/the-toddler-bed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 05:38:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=555</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Dear genius who invented the &#8220;convertible crib to toddler bed&#8221; concept: You are a giant ass. Seriously. I am sure that you thought that the sun shined out of your ass when you came up with this idea. &#8220;Why charge parents $100 for a crib when we could charge them $500 for a crib with [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/the-toddler-bed/">THE TODDLER BED</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/how-i-spent-my-new-years/' rel='bookmark' title='HOW I SPENT MY NEW YEAR&#8217;S'>HOW I SPENT MY NEW YEAR&#8217;S</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/misery-loves-company/' rel='bookmark' title='MISERY LOVES COMPANY'>MISERY LOVES COMPANY</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear genius who invented the &#8220;convertible crib to toddler bed&#8221; concept:</p>
<p>You are a giant ass. Seriously. I am sure that you thought that the sun shined out of your ass when you came up with this idea. &#8220;Why charge parents $100 for a crib when we could charge them $500 for a crib with one replaceable side? All we have to do is tell them that the bed will &#8220;grow with the child&#8221; and they&#8217;ll buy them by the dozen,&#8221; I&#8217;m sure you explained to your colleagues. And damn you, you were right. I did spend the extra $400 and am now stuck with the pain and misery of that bad decision.</p>
<p>&#8220;Why is the bed such a problem,&#8221; you might ask yourself (that is, if you can stop counting your millions for long enough). Well, let me tell you. </p>
<p>This idea that the toddler bed is a happy medium between the crib and regular bed only exists in the parents&#8217; mind. In the kid&#8217;s mind things are pretty black and white. One side is the fully enclosed crib jail and the other side is everything else. The stupid idea of the toddler bed medium only acts to give us parents the idea that we maintain some modicum of control over the situation, when in reality we have completely lost the battle.</p>
<p>Let me tell you what a child can do in a bed that is enclosed on three and a half sides: whatever she wants. She can jump on the bed. She can stand up in the bed. She can get in and out and in and out and in and out of the bed. She can get out of her bed and go and bang on the bedroom door. She can slowly but surely slide out of the open side and down onto the very thin carpet where her poor mother is lying while pretending to sleep. In other words, she can do everything she could do in a regular bed and MORE thanks to the handy side rails. </p>
<p>The only person that is held in place by the damn sides is the infuriated mother who is lying cramped up against them while begging her child to sleep. That extra-short length gives me just enough space to *think* that I can somehow lie down comfortably if I just try hard enough.  </p>
<p>I bought the convertible bed and now find myself with my nose and mouth pressed up against the half-side of crib rails like one of the poor, unadopted puppies at the pet store. Sometimes, I catch myself scratching the railing and mumbling &#8220;Free me&#8230;free me!&#8221;</p>
<p>And my legs&#8230;where do I put those? If I face in, I have to let everything below the knee dangle off the side of the bed. When I lose all feeling and am forced to roll over, I have to wedge my toes in between the crib slats so that I don&#8217;t fall out.</p>
<p>The final moment of insanity comes when I can finally get up. David Blaine could not extricate himself from a sleeping child&#8217;s convertible toddler bed without waking them up. Between the contorted body position and the partial paralyzation, I am going to make a shit ton of noise when I stand up. That is, if I can stand up again. </p>
<p>So thank you, thank you from the bottom of my heart for coming up with this great idea. I hope you made enough to pay my chiropractor bills.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/the-toddler-bed/">THE TODDLER BED</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/how-i-spent-my-new-years/' rel='bookmark' title='HOW I SPENT MY NEW YEAR&#8217;S'>HOW I SPENT MY NEW YEAR&#8217;S</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/misery-loves-company/' rel='bookmark' title='MISERY LOVES COMPANY'>MISERY LOVES COMPANY</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/the-toddler-bed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>WE ARE MOVING</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/we-are-moving/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/we-are-moving/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 07:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=549</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t know about the rest of you, but I really like to move. I get super excited about new adventure and am ready to go as soon as the announcement is made. Unfortunately, in Nomad Papa&#8217;s line of work, move announcements are usually followed by 9+ months of waiting. It is just like being [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/we-are-moving/">WE ARE MOVING</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kid-listened-and-i-regret-it/' rel='bookmark' title='MY KID LISTENED AND I REGRET IT'>MY KID LISTENED AND I REGRET IT</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t know about the rest of you, but I really like to move. I get super excited about new adventure and am ready to go as soon as the announcement is made. Unfortunately, in Nomad Papa&#8217;s line of work, move announcements are usually followed by 9+ months of waiting. It is just like being pregnant &#8211; you wait and wait, prepare as much as you can and then your life gets turned upside down . You also lose sleep and find yourself pooping either more or less often, and eat copious amounts of calories that you swear &#8220;don&#8217;t count&#8221;. </p>
<p>We have had a whole, never-ending, incessantly long year to prepare for our move. It is now just two weeks away and I still don&#8217;t have an exact move date from the movers. Welcome to my life. I&#8217;ve had a long time to mull over the move and think about the things I want in our new place. Here they are:</p>
<p><strong>NOMAD MOM&#8217;S MUST HAVES</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>A good neighbor &#8211; What the hell am I going to do without my trusty neighbor? The one I can call on when I am moments from tossing the kids into the canal. The one that eats half my batch of brownies so that I can justify making a new set every day. The one who sees my two year old taking her pants off on the bike path behind the house and laughs instead of calling child protective services. The one who is just like me, so hanging out with her is like hanging out with myself, only better. I&#8217;d start to tear up, but that is so not me. or her. shit.</li>
<li>A good grocery store &#8211; I thought all grocery stores were more or less equal. And then I moved to the Netherlands. Now I have some basic requests. I&#8217;d like a grocery store that sells baking soda. I want one that puts the sugar in the baking aisle instead of next to the coffee. I want one that stocks something other than potatoes in the pre-washed ready packages. Is that so much to ask?</li>
<li>Friends &#8211; I am old, married and have two kids. How am I going to make friends if I have to go to work everyday? I am going to be that desperate mom that accosts parents as they pick-up kids from school. Me: &#8220;Do you want to go and grab a pint in the pub?&#8221; Other Mom: &#8220;Um, could you let go of my kid&#8217;s jacket you psycho?&#8221; Maybe I should put an ad in the daycare newsletter&#8230;.</li>
<li>All of you &#8211; you guys travel, right? I am going to need all of you, your comments and your likes more than ever&#8230;or at least until I find a pub I can nip off to when life gets to be too much. So pack up your virtual suitcases and get ready for the UK</li>
</ol>
<p>Here is the scoop. Nomad Papa has a new job at the University of Oxford. Yes, that Oxford. And Nomad Mom also has a new job. (Someone is going to pay me to come to an office&#8230;I still can&#8217;t wrap my head around it.) We are leaving lovely Delft behind after four fun, terror and tear-filled years (we have toddlers, remember). Because we are gluttons for punishment, we are going to do all of it again in another new country we have barely visited. </p>
<p>That, my friends, is how the Nomad family rolls. More fun to follow, guaranteed!</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/we-are-moving/">WE ARE MOVING</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kid-listened-and-i-regret-it/' rel='bookmark' title='MY KID LISTENED AND I REGRET IT'>MY KID LISTENED AND I REGRET IT</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/we-are-moving/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>LET&#8217;S GO TO A PARTY</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/lets-go-to-a-party/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/lets-go-to-a-party/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 13:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=539</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s Friday and that means it is party time. I&#8217;d like to go out to a real party, but I am sitting in 10 year old sweatpants and my pajama top (yes, it is 3pm here. No one likes to be judged) and I am pretty sure I would have to put on nicer clothes. [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/lets-go-to-a-party/">LET&#8217;S GO TO A PARTY</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/momma-needs-a-new-pair-of-shoes/' rel='bookmark' title='MOMMA NEEDS A NEW PAIR OF SHOES'>MOMMA NEEDS A NEW PAIR OF SHOES</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/snowpocalypse-2013/' rel='bookmark' title='SNOWPOCALYPSE 2013'>SNOWPOCALYPSE 2013</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s Friday and that means it is party time. I&#8217;d like to go out to a real party, but I am sitting in 10 year old sweatpants and my pajama top (yes, it is 3pm here. No one likes to be judged) and I am pretty sure I would have to put on nicer clothes. So I have decided to go to a virtual party instead. And you guys get to come along. How fun is that? </p>
<p><a href="http://www.5minutesformom.com/ubp/" ><img src="http://www.5minutesformom.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/UBP-2013_500px.jpg" title="Ultimate Blog Party 2013" alt="Ultimate Blog Party 2013" /></a></p>
<p>Welcome to the Ultimate Blog Party 2013. As your host, I would like to direct you to your own liquor cabinet where you can mix up the drink of your choice. Or just bring over the whole bottle. You are in your yoga pants at your own house, people &#8211; there&#8217;s no need to get out the fancy glassware. </p>
<p>Now that you are comfortably settled with your drink, you are ready to go out and meet some people. Why not start with me? You might as well, you are already here and I am damn freaking awesome, so it would be silly to look for someone else. </p>
<p>Hi. My name is Lynn. I am a 35 year old American married to an Italian and living in the Netherlands&#8230;for three more weeks. Then we are moving to the UK. Because that obviously makes sense. We have two kids and they speak mostly Dutch and English, but throw in some Italian from time to time to show off to their friends. They are 2 and 4, but 2 and 4 nowadays are like 12 and 14 when we were kids. You gotta step up your game early. </p>
<p>This blog is my safe place. It&#8217;s where I come to bitch about things that piss me off or frustrate me. It is where I pull back the curtains on the perfect life I report on my personal facebook page (you know that you do this too, so shut it) and share the gritty details of being a mother to two. This is the place where I grapple with the motherly guilt that causes me to keep my kids at home one workday per week and with the massive frustration that the kids give me on that day. </p>
<p>Some of you might be wondering why I choose to do this in such a public space. The answer is simple. I am obviously an attention whore. If this party were to take place in a real venue, I am sure that you could all pick me out of the room. I&#8217;d be the loud woman bitching in the center to a big group of people.</p>
<p>It makes my day/week/month that you are all here too. I really love to meet people who read the blog and don&#8217;t do it because they know I will ask their opinion about it at next week&#8217;s playgroup meeting. I love that some of you comment on the blog to my husband, mainly because it drives him insane. (He is really private. I have no idea how we ended up together. Must have been laziness.) Most of all, I love hearing your own stories and opinions via the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/NomadMomDiary" title="Nomad Mom Diary - Facebook Page" target="_blank">facebook page</a> and the comments section. Please keep it all coming!</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s it for me. If you feel up to sharing, leave me a comment to tell me about you. If you aren&#8217;t ready to take that step, scroll back up to the image and click the link to find other bloggers at the party. What else have you got to do? Let the laundry/kids/dinner wait for a few minutes and focus on yourself for a change!</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/lets-go-to-a-party/">LET&#8217;S GO TO A PARTY</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/momma-needs-a-new-pair-of-shoes/' rel='bookmark' title='MOMMA NEEDS A NEW PAIR OF SHOES'>MOMMA NEEDS A NEW PAIR OF SHOES</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/snowpocalypse-2013/' rel='bookmark' title='SNOWPOCALYPSE 2013'>SNOWPOCALYPSE 2013</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/lets-go-to-a-party/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>MY KID LISTENED AND I REGRET IT</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kid-listened-and-i-regret-it/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kid-listened-and-i-regret-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 09:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=533</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>(Side note here &#8211; sorry for the long quiet period. Our move to the UK is just three weeks away and I have been completely overwhelmed with job hunting and move management. Hopefully I am now on top of things and can get back to my normal writing schedule. Thanks for sticking with me!) I [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kid-listened-and-i-regret-it/">MY KID LISTENED AND I REGRET IT</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/the-milestones-that-really-matter/' rel='bookmark' title='THE MILESTONES THAT REALLY MATTER'>THE MILESTONES THAT REALLY MATTER</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/i-am-a-bad-mom-episode-552/' rel='bookmark' title='I AM A BAD MOM, EPISODE 552'>I AM A BAD MOM, EPISODE 552</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/colonoscopy-cycle/' rel='bookmark' title='COLONOSCOPY CYCLE'>COLONOSCOPY CYCLE</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>(Side note here &#8211; sorry for the long quiet period. Our move to the UK is just three weeks away and I have been completely overwhelmed with job hunting and move management. Hopefully I am now on top of things and can get back to my normal writing schedule. Thanks for sticking with me!)</em></p>
<p>I have spent roughly 90% of the last four years of my life telling the kids to do something and being ignored in return. In thinking about it, I really have no idea why I continue trying to tell them anything? Must be that parental guilt or something&#8230;or just insanity. Probably #2.</p>
<p>Anyways, I have gotten so used to the kids ignoring me, that it does not begin to cross my mind that they might actually listen every now and again. But you know kids, they like to keep you on your toes. Just when you think it is safe to tell them to do something, they turn around and jump right into action when you least expect it. This is what happened to me, and I totally learned my lesson. From now on, I&#8217;ll stick to my normal nagging or be much more specific in my commands.</p>
<p>We had just gotten back home after some errands and found a parking spot in front of the neighbor&#8217;s house. Addy was begging to play with the neighbor&#8217;s kid and I was telling her that they needed to play in the garden because it was sunny for once and not completely miserably cold. After much haranguing, she finally agreed. I got her out of the car and walked around to get Giorgie out. Thirty seconds later I stood up with kid #2 and found a completely empty sidewalk in front of me. Sidewalk, walkways, doorways, street&#8230;emptiness in every direction.</p>
<p>At that moment, every organ in my body took up residence in my windpipe. I called her name a few times without any answers. Mind racing, I walked over to see if she had gone to our front door. Nope. I began spinning in circles and screaming loudly looking in every possible direction all at once. The only response I got was the little one adding in her own frantic calls for her sister. </p>
<p>I began jogging down the block, trying to cross off all possibilities from my list. Not at our house, not standing in front of the neighbor&#8217;s house, not wandering down the street. My job turned into a sprint and I finally found her standing on the bike path behind our row of houses, waiting to go into the gate to the back garden. i.e. exactly where I had told her to go. She was bawling her eyes out because she could hear my screaming for her and she couldn&#8217;t get the gate to open. </p>
<p>As my organs descended back to their normal homes, my mind cleared up enough for me to remember that I had left the second kid standing on the sidewalk in front of the house. Clearly, I am a top contender for Best Mother 2013. I took the shortest path, running in through the back gate and dumping Addy in the garden with promises to kill her in a minute, through the house, hurdling over the cat and dog and back out the front door. Poor little G was still standing on the sidewalk calling for her sister. </p>
<p>I called my mom later and told her what had happened. She got a giant grin on her face and exclaimed her happiness that my kids were paying me back for all of the times I had done that to her. Her exact quote, &#8220;One down, 999 to go&#8221;.</p>
<p>Thanks mom!</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kid-listened-and-i-regret-it/">MY KID LISTENED AND I REGRET IT</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/the-milestones-that-really-matter/' rel='bookmark' title='THE MILESTONES THAT REALLY MATTER'>THE MILESTONES THAT REALLY MATTER</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/i-am-a-bad-mom-episode-552/' rel='bookmark' title='I AM A BAD MOM, EPISODE 552'>I AM A BAD MOM, EPISODE 552</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/colonoscopy-cycle/' rel='bookmark' title='COLONOSCOPY CYCLE'>COLONOSCOPY CYCLE</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kid-listened-and-i-regret-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>THE MILESTONES THAT REALLY MATTER</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/the-milestones-that-really-matter/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/the-milestones-that-really-matter/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 09:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=522</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday evening I was driving my almost four year old home from dance class. For perhaps the second time ever, she had given me permission to play &#8220;mommy music&#8221; in the car. We were rolling along rocking out to the radio when a pop culture phenomenon came on the radio. One minute into the song [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/the-milestones-that-really-matter/">THE MILESTONES THAT REALLY MATTER</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss yarpp-related-none'>

No related posts.
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday evening I was driving my almost four year old home from dance class. For perhaps the second time ever, she had given me permission to play &#8220;mommy music&#8221; in the car. We were rolling along rocking out to the radio when a pop culture phenomenon came on the radio. One minute into the song a little voice popped up from the back seat saying, &#8220;Mommy, is that the woopagungugsta song?&#8221; I nearly wrecked the car because I was laughing so hard&#8230;50% because she correct identified &#8220;Gangnam Style&#8221; and 50% because she did so with a Dutch accent. If that is the only thing she has learned at daycare in the last four years, I still say that was money well spent.</p>
<p>That night at dinner I could hardly contain myself. I could not wait to share this monumental accomplishment with my husband. To say that he was less than impressed would be an understatement. He said (and I quote),&#8221;We don&#8217;t need to encourage this kind of garbage.&#8221; Um, yes, yes we do. I was so proud I had called my mom, sister and taken the kid over to the neighbors for a command repeat performance. </p>
<p>All of this got me to thinking about those damn milestone charts. If such an accomplishment had been listed on one, he would have been more excited. And shouldn&#8217;t an awareness of the world around her rate just as highly? I would like to propose a new milestone chart:</p>
<p><img src="http://nomadmomdiary.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/milestonechart-1019x1024.png" alt="milestonechart" width="550" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-525" /></p>
<p>Let me take you through these. I didn&#8217;t put an age on them, but most kids seem to hit them by the time they are five. There is an evolutionary reason for this. Conveniently, Mother Nature turns your sweet baby into a giant jerk around the same time you have to send them off to school. This is why moms only cry on the first day of school. After that, they realize that 8 hours without the little assholes is actually pretty nice.</p>
<p>#1 &#8211; Remember when no meant no? Yeah, me either. At some point in the toddler years my kids figured out that I was not going to give in. About a week later, they turned to papa for his permission. </p>
<p>#2 &#8211; We had a long talk about this at playgroup. The lying stage is immediately proceeded by the spinning stage. In the spinning stage, they are very quick to give their version of the events (she ran into the Barbie car), but will eventually &#8216;fess up to their own misdeeds (she ran into it because I kicked it at her). </p>
<p>#3 &#8211; It is suddenly not safe to talk in front of the kids. Your only hope is that your kid will repeat something that they heard the neighbors say before telling the neighbors something embarrassing you said about them.</p>
<p>#4 &#8211; I don&#8217;t care how hard you try, some bastard somewhere will introduce your child to toddler music. The only good news is that after hearing the same song approximately 4,725,912 times, your child will move on to something a bit more hip. </p>
<p>#5 &#8211; This one is really hilarious. My kids aren&#8217;t there yet, but the neighbor&#8217;s kid regularly walks up to me and says things like, &#8220;Lynn, that Giorgie is really crazy&#8221;. She isn&#8217;t ratting her out for being bad, she just wants to share her two cents on the situation. Sometimes she even gives me advice. I usually take it.</p>
<p>#6 &#8211; So your kids have figured out that they can con the grandparents into giving them all of the stuff both you and papa said no to? Don&#8217;t be pissy&#8230;.instead get the kids to ask for the things that you want too (new iPad anyone?).</p>
<p>#7 &#8211; I cook, clean, diaper, wash and generally manage everything in the household. Yet every time my husband shows up late in the evening with no prior warning, my kid says &#8220;Don&#8217;t be mad at papa&#8221;. I know I should have never let him teach her to say, &#8220;Addy and Papa, best friends forever.&#8221;</p>
<p>#8 &#8211; Ahhh, those days of sweet kisses and hugs for no reason quickly fade away as your kid realizes that signs of affection are perhaps the only currency they have. You want a hug for mommy, you better be prepared to pay up in chocolate or horsey rides.</p>
<p>What else should be on my list?</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/the-milestones-that-really-matter/">THE MILESTONES THAT REALLY MATTER</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss yarpp-related-none'>
<p>No related posts.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/the-milestones-that-really-matter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>GIVE MAMA MONEY</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/give-mama-mone/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/give-mama-mone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=516</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Hello blog readers (all six of you)! I want to introduce you to my friend Cordelia. I met her in a facebook group for multicultural bloggers and it was like meeting my soulmate. Seriously, love at first type! When I decided to invite others to come and share their stories with you, I knew that [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/give-mama-mone/">GIVE MAMA MONEY</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/hey-im-done-having-kids-okay/' rel='bookmark' title='HEY, I&#8217;M DONE HAVING KIDS, OKAY???'>HEY, I&#8217;M DONE HAVING KIDS, OKAY???</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Hello blog readers (all six of you)! I want to introduce you to my friend Cordelia. I met her in a facebook group for multicultural bloggers and it was like meeting my soulmate. Seriously, love at first type! When I decided to invite others to come and share their stories with you, I knew that Cordelia had to be on the list. We decided to both write about the cray cray shit we mamas do to try and earn a little pocket money. You can read my story over on <a href="http://multilingualmama.com/2013/03/22/i-am-going-to-sell-my-eggs/" title="I am going to sell my eggs" target="_blank">Multilingual Mama</a>.</em></p>
<p>Greenbacks: the early days.</p>
<p>Once upon a time, long long ago, I earned a decent paycheck. I got paid handsomely to sit at a stylish desk, in a stylish loft, to speak with stylish people and end the day with a nice glass of stylish red wine. The only downside was that my office was in too stylish a neighborhood and I often felt the very un-stylish desire to slap a few hipsters hard upside their heads. They thought they were stylish. They weren’t. I know blind people with a better-coordinated sense of dress. What can I say…nothing is in this world is perfect.</p>
<p>And nothing stays the same.</p>
<p>I decided to have a baby. I waved bye-bye to my lovely wardrobe, to my waistline and of course to my glasses of wine -well for the first 12 weeks anyway. Even my midwife knew better than to take it completely away from me.  Wine was definitely preferable to stress and Xanax. </p>
<p>The new me said goodbye to my stylish ways and hello to spit-up and marker-stained (washable? my arse) tops. Bonjour oatmeal and avocado smeared cords. My life was now spent frantically running between some combination of A: home, B: daycare and C: the office all the while lugging laptops, breast pumps and please god let them not leak before I get them in the fridge milk baggies, among others new necessities now overflowing in my life. My T-shirt, come winter or summer was perpetually sweat-stained from the strain. I was a pack-horse. Wait, who am I kidding. I was a pack-mule.</p>
<p>But I didn’t care. With a supportive office and hubby, for the apple of my eye, the mango of my heart, my gorgeous baby girl, I would do ANYTHING.</p>
<p>Bring on the global economic collapse of 2008.<br />
In truth, I was very lucky as I held on to my job. My LF’s [Loving Father] field was a disaster area and it was a miracle he kept his through the summer of 2009. Then, he became a SAHF and was brilliant at it, especially given our otherwise calm little angel’s borderline psychotic temper tantrums. </p>
<p>Twelve months, baby #2 on the way, top floor of a walk-up, and cloth diapering to save money at the laundromat &#8211; imagine the looks when a week’s worth of soiled diapers went into the machine- was enough to turn any LF to a BARF or Bitter And Resentful Father. We knew things had to change. I could not live with BARF. Bye-Bye Big Apple, Hello Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>Ka-ching! Asia, school fees, round-the-world plane tickets, and mama’s quest for dough<br />
Two years into our stint in Asia on a local contract, I found myself longing and ultimately needing to earn some cash if I hoped to ever make it back to see my family. My rudimentary Thai, aka Taxi Thai, and a country that, despite it’s reputation as the land of smiles, is extremely strict regarding the hiring of foreign workers, was not going to make this easy.</p>
<p>Butcher, Baker, Candlestick Maker.<br />
I’ve always had a desire to be a butcher. Not just any butcher, but a proper butcher, like the French or Italians who respect the animal and know its anatomy thoroughly. Butchery can and should be a well-honed craft, not a bunch of illegals, barely trained, wielding high-powered saws through carcasses. In Thailand, there were few options. People I approached thought I was crazy and why me when they can hire Thais?</p>
<p>Candles? I think not. This left me no choice but baker. I turned my hand to making bread and lucked out. I managed to master one type of artisanal loaf. And so began the next six months, where, like pigpen, a cloud of flour dust followed my every step. With an oven that could only accommodate two loaves and a ravenous French clientele, I spent hours tied to my kitchen baking followed by traveling Thai style, i.e. over loaded.  </p>
<p><img src="http://nomadmomdiary.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/breaddelivery-soi-dogs-300x225.jpg" alt="Multilingual Mama bread delivery" width="300" height="225" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-518" /></p>
<p>As I pedaled with 10 to 12 paper bags swinging off the handlebars, stacked in the front basket, secured in the toddler bike seat, and even hanging off the back of the bike seat, I realized I was expending insane amounts of sweat and energy for a few baths (Thai currency) of profit. No more lugging 20Kg bags of flour to the curb, hoping to find a cab home.</p>
<p>Now I am teaching conversational English, which is funny because I can’t tell you the difference between the past, imperfect, and err… well those other tenses. I am also not a qualified teacher &#8211; well except for dinghy sailing. I do disclose all of the above and so far I’ve had no complaints &#8211; chalking that up to my stellar personality and spiking their coffee when they aren’t looking. I have but one requirement apart from payment, I have to like my student enough to want to get drunk and party all night with them, otherwise I can’t seem to get my arse out the door and on my bike. </p>
<p>Teaching is definitely more lucrative, but still only half of what I’d earn if I could get some freelance research work. In the case of my former work-related contacts, absence has not made the heart grow fonder. In French we say ‘loin des yeux, loin du coeur’, which translates as ‘far from the eyes, far from the heart’ or wallet.</p>
<p>There is the possibility of a job on the horizon, one that would give me a proper paycheck once more. I’ll admit I’m tempted. Mama could use some trousers that aren’t falling off the hips (maternity) or giving me a mega-muffin top (pre-baby). Knickers that aren’t bleached out at the crotch would also be nice. But I worry I won’t find the time to write anymore &#8211;since no one has ever paid me a cent to do it&#8211;and miss out on the magical years with my kids – the ones where they actually want to spend time with me.</p>
<p>I also haven’t totally given up on the idea of becoming my waxer’s sidekick as a henna artist, one of her income streams. Yes even she has cottoned on that I am hard up and brought me a book of designs, some henna and told me to practice for the next three months and she would consider using me. I could make $90 a gig plus a free ticket and accommodation to wherever the wedding takes place. Of course, I’ll never be allowed near the bride, kids only for me, and I’ll double as a side freak show “Look mommy, a farang working as a henna assistant!”</p>
<p>Whatever pays the ballet &#038; swim classes…</p>
<p><em>Born in New York back when subway graffiti was rife, Cordelia Newlin de Rojas mostly spends her time pondering, parenting, and writing. Franco-American, she spent her summers in the Loire indulging in heart-arresting foods. An eclectic background ranging from Japanese art and postal history to environmental social innovations and rigging dinghies has taken her to England, Turkey, Singapore and now Thailand, where she resides with her Mexican husband and their two daughters. They are attempting to raise trilingual kids in Spanish, French and English with some Thai thrown in. She can also be found blogging at <a href="http://multilingualmama.com/category/humor/" title="Multilingual Mama - Humor" target="_blank">multilingualmama.com</a>.<br />
</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/give-mama-mone/">GIVE MAMA MONEY</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/hey-im-done-having-kids-okay/' rel='bookmark' title='HEY, I&#8217;M DONE HAVING KIDS, OKAY???'>HEY, I&#8217;M DONE HAVING KIDS, OKAY???</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/give-mama-mone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>DON&#8217;T LOSE 10 POUNDS</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/dont-lose-10-pounds/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/dont-lose-10-pounds/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 07:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=506</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the Dutch doctor&#8217;s complete unwillingness to give me antibiotics, I recently lost 13lbs with a stomach infection. I now find myself down to a svelte weight I haven&#8217;t seen since 2001. You would think that I&#8217;d have my butt permanently parked in front of the mirror so I could admire my practically nonexistent [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/dont-lose-10-pounds/">DON&#8217;T LOSE 10 POUNDS</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/' rel='bookmark' title='REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH'>REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/can-we-bring-wigs-back-in-fashion/' rel='bookmark' title='CAN WE BRING WIGS BACK IN FASHION?'>CAN WE BRING WIGS BACK IN FASHION?</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/fat-pants/' rel='bookmark' title='FAT PANTS'>FAT PANTS</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the Dutch doctor&#8217;s complete unwillingness to give me antibiotics, I recently lost 13lbs with a stomach infection. I now find myself down to a svelte weight I haven&#8217;t seen since 2001. You would think that I&#8217;d have my butt permanently parked in front of the mirror so I could admire my practically nonexistent backside. Well, you&#8217;d be wrong. You see, all of those bitches and assholes who constantly harp on you to lose those extra ten pounds conveniently forget to mention the downsides. </p>
<p>I, on the other hand, am a great friend. I am going to pull back the curtains on this weight loss bullshit and tell it like it really it. You do not want to lose those last few pounds. They are your best friend. Since this is so contrary to what everyone else says, I&#8217;ll give you some reasons why.</p>
<h2>Reasons why you should not lose 10 pounds</h2>
<ol>
<li>Newsflash ladies. You know how your post-baby belly button has that &#8220;lived in&#8221; look? If you lose the extra weight, you might as well post a giant flashing vacancy sign on your mid-section. No more pulling up the pants a bit higher or rocking the maternity jeans. You now have an unsightly flap that has to be carefully and precisely tucked away. If you make a sudden move, you run the risk that it will come flying out and knock out someone across the room. It turns out those last pounds were helping disguise the fact that your thirty-something skin doesn&#8217;t have the elasticity of before. So do yourself a favor and eat an extra cookie. &#8220;Womanly curves&#8221; sound much more appealing than a drooping vag cover.</li>
<li>Your clothes don&#8217;t fit. Once upon a time shrinking out of your wardrobe would have been a cause for celebration. No so once you have kids. Now all of your pants look like you are wearing a poopy diaper. You *could* go and buy some new ones, but that requires money and time. Do any of you have an overabundance of either or those? I didn&#8217;t think so. Go for a second helping and leave the droopy drawers to your toddler.</li>
<li>This last reason is perhaps the most concerning. Before I lost the weight, I would hide in the bathroom or closet when changing into my pajamas. Regardless of how much alcohol I had after dinner, I did not want the last thing I heard at night to be &#8220;you should go to the gym&#8221;. I lost the weight and damned if I am not right back to hiding in the closet. The newfound delineation between my boobs and belly has put a familiar sparkle in my husband&#8217;s eyes. When I have spent the whole day running behind two kids without a single second to myself, and when I finally make it up to my precious, comfy bed where I can sit down and not talk to anyone, the LAST thing I want is someone sneaking over and groping me from behind. Heaven help you if you say no! It does not go over well, regardless of how solid your excuses are (Aunt Flo, hairy legs, gassy, etc, I have tried them all). Pour yourself another glass and savor it while sitting all alone.</li>
</ol>
<p>So there you have it. The glamourous life of a Skinny Minnie is totally overrated once you have had kids. You are better off holding on to the protective layer that fluff is providing. </p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/dont-lose-10-pounds/">DON&#8217;T LOSE 10 POUNDS</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/' rel='bookmark' title='REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH'>REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/can-we-bring-wigs-back-in-fashion/' rel='bookmark' title='CAN WE BRING WIGS BACK IN FASHION?'>CAN WE BRING WIGS BACK IN FASHION?</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/fat-pants/' rel='bookmark' title='FAT PANTS'>FAT PANTS</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/dont-lose-10-pounds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>MY KID&#8217;S PURSE</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kids-purse/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kids-purse/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 15:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=497</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I am sure that you have all seen those blog posts and articles showcasing the contents of someone&#8217;s purse. I have a news flash for people that write those &#8211; I really hate them. I don&#8217;t want to see what another mom has in her purse. Likely it is the same crap that I have [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kids-purse/">MY KID&#8217;S PURSE</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/guest-posting-gig/' rel='bookmark' title='GUEST POSTING GIG'>GUEST POSTING GIG</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/lies-we-all-tell-our-kids/' rel='bookmark' title='8 LIES WE ALL TELL OUR KIDS'>8 LIES WE ALL TELL OUR KIDS</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/hello-sponsors-are-you-there/' rel='bookmark' title='HELLO, SPONSORS? ARE YOU THERE?'>HELLO, SPONSORS? ARE YOU THERE?</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am sure that you have all seen those blog posts and articles showcasing the contents of someone&#8217;s purse. I have a news flash for people that write those &#8211; I really hate them. I don&#8217;t want to see what another mom has in her purse. Likely it is the same crap that I have in my purse&#8230;a bunch of half-used kleenex, cookie crumbs, hand sanitizer and other random shit my kids give me to shove in there. </p>
<p>Even worse are the posts with single gal purses. Is there anything more depressing as a mom than having your complete lack of coolness validated by the internet? The single gal has fancy lipstick. I have chapstick. She has condoms. I have diaper rash cream. She has concert ticket stubs. I have the Wiggles concert video. Just go ahead and put me out to pasture already.</p>
<p>So I am not going to do that here. Instead, I am going to open up a literal can of worms and showcase the inside of my kid&#8217;s purse. She&#8217;s almost four. She loves pink and princesses. She is a kleptomaniac. And apparently she has a serious problem distinguishing trash from treasure.</p>
<p>See for yourself:</p>
<p><img src="http://nomadmomdiary.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/APurse_Artboard-4-1019x1024.png" alt="The contents of my kid&#039;s purse. If you can&#039;t see this image, then you pretty much missed the whole point of this post. Go and get on a computer that displays images, you lazy butt." width="600" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-501" /></p>
<p>The assorted Princess miniatures I get. My little one just turned two so we are very into the &#8220;birthday party&#8221; concept at the moment. Thus the slice of cake, party table and presents. Ballerina Dora and her dance studio are obvious musts. I mean, what if she were out somewhere and was required to act out Swan Lake and she didn&#8217;t have those. That would be embarrassing!</p>
<p>She does have a few practical items. She just borrowed the princess mobile phone from our neighbor this afternoon. She must have walked straight into the door and hid it in her purse. Nevermind that we already had a Belle phone. This one is pink, so it is obviously better. The two pieces of Cinderella&#8217;s slippers sidewalk chalk should come in handy if she needs to write mommy a note. </p>
<p>And then there is the random shit. Why are the Pinypins disassembled? Why aren&#8217;t there enough pieces for two complete dolls? Why did she steal her sister&#8217;s birthday present matchbox car? It is so new, G is still playing with it. And the mountain of clippings? Should I be checking her closet to see if it looks like a scene from A Beautiful Mind? I tried to throw away an old sticker the other day. That kid has eyes in the back of her head. She did a vocal bitch slap from across the room that left my ears ringing for the rest of the day.</p>
<p>The biggest mystery is how all of this fits into that one purse. I have no f&#8217;ing clue. I blame it on my neighbor. She let her watch Mary Poppins recently and admitted that Addy was wide-eyed and glued to the TV during the unpacking scene. If I find a lamp in there, we are going to have words.</p>
<p>There you are, ladies and gentlemen, the contents of my kid&#8217;s purse. Would you like to share the contents of your kid&#8217;s purse? Just send me a photo to lynn (at) nomadmomdiary.com with a description and I will post it up. Or, post it up on your own blog and send me the link. I&#8217;ll add it here.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kids-purse/">MY KID&#8217;S PURSE</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/guest-posting-gig/' rel='bookmark' title='GUEST POSTING GIG'>GUEST POSTING GIG</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/lies-we-all-tell-our-kids/' rel='bookmark' title='8 LIES WE ALL TELL OUR KIDS'>8 LIES WE ALL TELL OUR KIDS</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/hello-sponsors-are-you-there/' rel='bookmark' title='HELLO, SPONSORS? ARE YOU THERE?'>HELLO, SPONSORS? ARE YOU THERE?</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kids-purse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>MOMMY&#8217;S ANNUAL REVIEW</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-annual-review/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-annual-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 21:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=488</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I just got an email with tips for preparing for my upcoming annual review. It stated: &#8220;Hi Lynn, if your annual review seems like a chore, try remembering that it shouldn’t be a one way street where your boss is doing all the talking – Make the most of your review and get the recognition [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-annual-review/">MOMMY&#8217;S ANNUAL REVIEW</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss yarpp-related-none'>

No related posts.
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just got an email with tips for preparing for my upcoming annual review. It stated:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;Hi Lynn, if your annual review seems like a chore, try remembering that it shouldn’t be a one way street where your boss is doing all the talking – Make the most of your review and get the recognition you deserve with these handy hints.&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>If you have read any other post on this blog, you know that my bosses are real asshats. They frown heavily on things like &#8220;vacation days&#8221; and &#8220;sick leave&#8221; and have even gone so far as to outlaw potty breaks and lunch. The only upside is that I do get to work from home (take that Marissa Mayer).</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve put in a lot of overtime in the last couple of years and I figure I am due for a salary adjustment (or even just a salary in the first place) AND a big fat bonus (no, a used diaper doesn&#8217;t count). So I thought I would trip on over to the recommended website and check out the handy tips.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>#1: Before the meeting: Brush up on your organisation’s performance management system: It might sound obvious, but even if you think you know how the system works there may have been some recent changes. So, at the very least it’s worth having a quick look on your intranet if you have one, or a chat with someone in HR. If you work somewhere where there isn’t a formal system, talk to your manager in advance about what ground they’ll be covering in your meeting.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Hmmm, I think I can safely say that we fall into the second category. I mean the kids have learned how to open the iPhone and email incriminating photos to unsuspecting contacts (sorry old boss), but they haven&#8217;t set-up an official home intranet yet. </p>
<p>The performance management system looks something like this: They tell me to do something and I do it. If I don&#8217;t, they throw a giant screaming fit and potentially also kick and thrash about on the ground. There isn&#8217;t a lot of gray area there. If I follow said command, they wait 10 seconds and ask for something else. Those 10 seconds were my reward for completing the task.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>#2: Gather your evidence: You should have objectives that you’ve been asked to deliver on, so dig them out and make some notes on how you’ve done.<br />
Think about the times when you might have gone beyond your own objectives to help deliver work that wasn’t officially yours to do – if you don’t bring up what you’ve done your helpfulness might be overlooked.<br />
Talk to someone who can help jog your memory about what you’ve done over the whole year.<br />
Have some time to yourself: Immediately before your meeting, keep some time free. You’ll feel much more focused than if you rush straight from another meeting. It’ll also help you to stay calm.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Since we don&#8217;t have a formal system, I think that means I can set my own goals. Here they are: don&#8217;t kill the kids. I just checked and they are sleeping like angels, so I can check that box. </p>
<p>Now about those times I&#8217;ve gone above and beyond&#8230;I&#8217;ve made cookies and cakes for playgroups parties and giftbags for the daycare kids. Let&#8217;s not forget the massive treasure-load of dress-up clothes I brought back from the States. </p>
<p>And things that aren&#8217;t officially mine &#8211; I keep getting stuck with changing the trashbag (a clear Nomad Papa task). That counts, right? I&#8217;d try and talk to someone for more ideas, but all of my friends are as drunk and sleep-deprived as I am and there isn&#8217;t a single one of us that can remember what we did last week. Damn.</p>
<p>Oh, I know, I&#8217;ll just take some free time and focus on remembering. Waahhhaaaaaaaa. Or maybe I&#8217;ll pee and then refill my wine glass.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>#3: In the meeting: Make your case: Many managers will begin by asking you how you think your year has gone, so it’s your chance to give them a summary of what you’ve done well.<br />
Be open to feedback: For many of us any kind of feedback can feel like criticism even when it’s intended to help you improve. Rather than be overly defensive, be open to what you’re hearing.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>I am going to rock out in this meeting by taking control of the when and where. I think I&#8217;ll butter them up with chocolate frosting sandwiches and cookies and ice cream for dessert. Then, in that split second between the full belly feeling and the sugar rush, I am going to say, &#8220;Look at how awesome your mommy is! She gave you chocolate for lunch!&#8221; and list off my greatest hits of accomplishments. (Note to self &#8211; cull list of any items that will cause a distraction, like the zoo. Don&#8217;t mention the zoo unless we can leave immediately to visit it. Otherwise the review will go in a downward spiral.)</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll ask for feedback, but use big words so that they don&#8217;t have any idea what I am talking about. I mean, they are going to spew out nonsense anyways, so I might as well get some entertainment out of it.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>#4: The Final Tip: When you’re busy getting on with the day job it can be tempting to just wing it when it comes to your appraisal meeting but putting some effort into preparing for it should ensure you get a fair report that gives you the recognition you deserve.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Hmmm, so what is the recognition I deserve? A million dollars? A paid vacation to a beach where no kids are allowed? Yes and yes. Unfortunately, I just checked our reward policy and it looks like the most I can hope for is a half-eaten piece of birthday cake that Giorgie no longer wants. </p>
<p>A girl can dream though, a girl can dream.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-annual-review/">MOMMY&#8217;S ANNUAL REVIEW</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss yarpp-related-none'>
<p>No related posts.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-annual-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 12:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=476</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I am having one of those days that is going to end with me either punching someone in the face or flushing my own head down the toilet. I am a mega, mega beeyotch. I was trying to think of the reason why I am so bitchy today, and I came up with quite a [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/">REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/why-my-kids-are-glad-im-home/' rel='bookmark' title='WHY MY KIDS ARE GLAD I&#8217;M HOME'>WHY MY KIDS ARE GLAD I&#8217;M HOME</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/mandatory-make-up-moment/' rel='bookmark' title='MANDATORY MAKE-UP MOMENT'>MANDATORY MAKE-UP MOMENT</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/payback-is-a-bitch/' rel='bookmark' title='PAYBACK IS A BITCH'>PAYBACK IS A BITCH</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am having one of those days that is going to end with me either punching someone in the face or flushing my own head down the toilet. I am a mega, mega beeyotch. I was trying to think of the reason why I am so bitchy today, and I came up with quite a long list. I thought I&#8217;d share it with you, just in case some of you others have a similar problem and don&#8217;t want to have to think all of this up again.</p>
<p>(BTW, if you are feeling bitchy and need something to laugh at, check out Jason Good&#8217;s post <a href="http://jasongood.net/365/2012/12/46-reasons-why-my-three-year-old-might-be-freaking-out/" target="_blank">46 Reasons My Three Year Old Might Be Freaking Out</a>. It kinda inspired this post, but his is funnier. Damn him.)</p>
<p>REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH (valid on any given day)</p>
<ol>
<li>I woke up.</li>
<li>I woke up too early.</li>
<li>The kids kept me up all night</li>
<li>I have kids</li>
<li>I am married&#8230;to a man (maybe it would be different if I had married a woman&#8230;I dunno.)</li>
<li>My pants are too tight</li>
<li>My pants are all dirty</li>
<li>I am wearing my least favorite pair of underwear (the threadbare granny panties that ride up my butt)</li>
<li>I have to go somewhere that I can&#8217;t wear yoga pants</li>
<li>I had to put on a bra AND brush my hair</li>
<li>My bra is too big (why can&#8217;t the weight come out of my belly instead of my boobs?)</li>
<li>It&#8217;s my non shower day but I have to look nice</li>
<li>It&#8217;s my shower day but I don&#8217;t have anywhere to go</li>
<li>I left my house (sometimes, isn&#8217;t that enough?)</li>
<li>I have 400 loads of laundry to do / dishes to wash / etc.</li>
<li>Someone peed on my floor</li>
<li>Someone pooped on my floor</li>
<li>My husband said the word &#8220;gym&#8221; in the house. (Context is irreleant)</li>
<li>Nothing I see, read, hear or think is funny</li>
<li>Everything I think of is funny, but I can&#8217;t get anywhere to write it down</li>
<li>My kids are hanging off of me</li>
<li>My kids prefer Papa (I know that I should be happy about that, but don&#8217;t the little shits know that I do all of the work and therefore deserve all of the credit)</li>
<li>Everyone on facebook is posting up motivational shit. I don&#8217;t need that.</li>
<li>No one is posting anything on facebook. (Come on, refresh already!!)</li>
<li>No one helped me fold the laundry</li>
<li>My husband helped, but did it all wrong and didn&#8217;t put anything away</li>
<li>The kids &#8220;helped&#8221; me fold laundry and now I have to rewash it all</li>
<li>The weather sucks.</li>
<li>The kids are being assholes</li>
<li>I have PMS</li>
<li>My husband has PMS</li>
<li>My kids have PMS</li>
<li>The dog ate my lunch</li>
<li>We ran out of sweets in the house.</li>
</ol>
<p>So those are my reasons&#8230;.or a few of them at least. What are yours?</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/">REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/why-my-kids-are-glad-im-home/' rel='bookmark' title='WHY MY KIDS ARE GLAD I&#8217;M HOME'>WHY MY KIDS ARE GLAD I&#8217;M HOME</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/mandatory-make-up-moment/' rel='bookmark' title='MANDATORY MAKE-UP MOMENT'>MANDATORY MAKE-UP MOMENT</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/payback-is-a-bitch/' rel='bookmark' title='PAYBACK IS A BITCH'>PAYBACK IS A BITCH</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.020 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-19 13:15:36 -->
