<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Diary of a Nomad Mom</title>
	<atom:link href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com</link>
	<description>My inner bitch speaks 4 languages</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:56:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>GIVE MAMA MONEY</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/give-mama-mone/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/give-mama-mone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=516</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Hello blog readers (all six of you)! I want to introduce you to my friend Cordelia. I met her in a facebook group for multicultural bloggers and it was like meeting my soulmate. Seriously, love at first type! When I decided to invite others to come and share their stories with you, I knew that [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/give-mama-mone/">GIVE MAMA MONEY</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/hey-im-done-having-kids-okay/' rel='bookmark' title='HEY, I&#8217;M DONE HAVING KIDS, OKAY???'>HEY, I&#8217;M DONE HAVING KIDS, OKAY???</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Hello blog readers (all six of you)! I want to introduce you to my friend Cordelia. I met her in a facebook group for multicultural bloggers and it was like meeting my soulmate. Seriously, love at first type! When I decided to invite others to come and share their stories with you, I knew that Cordelia had to be on the list. We decided to both write about the cray cray shit we mamas do to try and earn a little pocket money. You can read my story over on <a href="http://multilingualmama.com/2013/03/22/i-am-going-to-sell-my-eggs/" title="I am going to sell my eggs" target="_blank">Multilingual Mama</a>.</em></p>
<p>Greenbacks: the early days.</p>
<p>Once upon a time, long long ago, I earned a decent paycheck. I got paid handsomely to sit at a stylish desk, in a stylish loft, to speak with stylish people and end the day with a nice glass of stylish red wine. The only downside was that my office was in too stylish a neighborhood and I often felt the very un-stylish desire to slap a few hipsters hard upside their heads. They thought they were stylish. They weren’t. I know blind people with a better-coordinated sense of dress. What can I say…nothing is in this world is perfect.</p>
<p>And nothing stays the same.</p>
<p>I decided to have a baby. I waved bye-bye to my lovely wardrobe, to my waistline and of course to my glasses of wine -well for the first 12 weeks anyway. Even my midwife knew better than to take it completely away from me.  Wine was definitely preferable to stress and Xanax. </p>
<p>The new me said goodbye to my stylish ways and hello to spit-up and marker-stained (washable? my arse) tops. Bonjour oatmeal and avocado smeared cords. My life was now spent frantically running between some combination of A: home, B: daycare and C: the office all the while lugging laptops, breast pumps and please god let them not leak before I get them in the fridge milk baggies, among others new necessities now overflowing in my life. My T-shirt, come winter or summer was perpetually sweat-stained from the strain. I was a pack-horse. Wait, who am I kidding. I was a pack-mule.</p>
<p>But I didn’t care. With a supportive office and hubby, for the apple of my eye, the mango of my heart, my gorgeous baby girl, I would do ANYTHING.</p>
<p>Bring on the global economic collapse of 2008.<br />
In truth, I was very lucky as I held on to my job. My LF’s [Loving Father] field was a disaster area and it was a miracle he kept his through the summer of 2009. Then, he became a SAHF and was brilliant at it, especially given our otherwise calm little angel’s borderline psychotic temper tantrums. </p>
<p>Twelve months, baby #2 on the way, top floor of a walk-up, and cloth diapering to save money at the laundromat &#8211; imagine the looks when a week’s worth of soiled diapers went into the machine- was enough to turn any LF to a BARF or Bitter And Resentful Father. We knew things had to change. I could not live with BARF. Bye-Bye Big Apple, Hello Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>Ka-ching! Asia, school fees, round-the-world plane tickets, and mama’s quest for dough<br />
Two years into our stint in Asia on a local contract, I found myself longing and ultimately needing to earn some cash if I hoped to ever make it back to see my family. My rudimentary Thai, aka Taxi Thai, and a country that, despite it’s reputation as the land of smiles, is extremely strict regarding the hiring of foreign workers, was not going to make this easy.</p>
<p>Butcher, Baker, Candlestick Maker.<br />
I’ve always had a desire to be a butcher. Not just any butcher, but a proper butcher, like the French or Italians who respect the animal and know its anatomy thoroughly. Butchery can and should be a well-honed craft, not a bunch of illegals, barely trained, wielding high-powered saws through carcasses. In Thailand, there were few options. People I approached thought I was crazy and why me when they can hire Thais?</p>
<p>Candles? I think not. This left me no choice but baker. I turned my hand to making bread and lucked out. I managed to master one type of artisanal loaf. And so began the next six months, where, like pigpen, a cloud of flour dust followed my every step. With an oven that could only accommodate two loaves and a ravenous French clientele, I spent hours tied to my kitchen baking followed by traveling Thai style, i.e. over loaded.  </p>
<p><img src="http://nomadmomdiary.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/breaddelivery-soi-dogs-300x225.jpg" alt="Multilingual Mama bread delivery" width="300" height="225" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-518" /></p>
<p>As I pedaled with 10 to 12 paper bags swinging off the handlebars, stacked in the front basket, secured in the toddler bike seat, and even hanging off the back of the bike seat, I realized I was expending insane amounts of sweat and energy for a few baths (Thai currency) of profit. No more lugging 20Kg bags of flour to the curb, hoping to find a cab home.</p>
<p>Now I am teaching conversational English, which is funny because I can’t tell you the difference between the past, imperfect, and err… well those other tenses. I am also not a qualified teacher &#8211; well except for dinghy sailing. I do disclose all of the above and so far I’ve had no complaints &#8211; chalking that up to my stellar personality and spiking their coffee when they aren’t looking. I have but one requirement apart from payment, I have to like my student enough to want to get drunk and party all night with them, otherwise I can’t seem to get my arse out the door and on my bike. </p>
<p>Teaching is definitely more lucrative, but still only half of what I’d earn if I could get some freelance research work. In the case of my former work-related contacts, absence has not made the heart grow fonder. In French we say ‘loin des yeux, loin du coeur’, which translates as ‘far from the eyes, far from the heart’ or wallet.</p>
<p>There is the possibility of a job on the horizon, one that would give me a proper paycheck once more. I’ll admit I’m tempted. Mama could use some trousers that aren’t falling off the hips (maternity) or giving me a mega-muffin top (pre-baby). Knickers that aren’t bleached out at the crotch would also be nice. But I worry I won’t find the time to write anymore &#8211;since no one has ever paid me a cent to do it&#8211;and miss out on the magical years with my kids – the ones where they actually want to spend time with me.</p>
<p>I also haven’t totally given up on the idea of becoming my waxer’s sidekick as a henna artist, one of her income streams. Yes even she has cottoned on that I am hard up and brought me a book of designs, some henna and told me to practice for the next three months and she would consider using me. I could make $90 a gig plus a free ticket and accommodation to wherever the wedding takes place. Of course, I’ll never be allowed near the bride, kids only for me, and I’ll double as a side freak show “Look mommy, a farang working as a henna assistant!”</p>
<p>Whatever pays the ballet &#038; swim classes…</p>
<p><em>Born in New York back when subway graffiti was rife, Cordelia Newlin de Rojas mostly spends her time pondering, parenting, and writing. Franco-American, she spent her summers in the Loire indulging in heart-arresting foods. An eclectic background ranging from Japanese art and postal history to environmental social innovations and rigging dinghies has taken her to England, Turkey, Singapore and now Thailand, where she resides with her Mexican husband and their two daughters. They are attempting to raise trilingual kids in Spanish, French and English with some Thai thrown in. She can also be found blogging at <a href="http://multilingualmama.com/category/humor/" title="Multilingual Mama - Humor" target="_blank">multilingualmama.com</a>.<br />
</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/give-mama-mone/">GIVE MAMA MONEY</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/hey-im-done-having-kids-okay/' rel='bookmark' title='HEY, I&#8217;M DONE HAVING KIDS, OKAY???'>HEY, I&#8217;M DONE HAVING KIDS, OKAY???</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/give-mama-mone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>DON&#8217;T LOSE 10 POUNDS</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/dont-lose-10-pounds/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/dont-lose-10-pounds/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 07:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=506</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the Dutch doctor&#8217;s complete unwillingness to give me antibiotics, I recently lost 13lbs with a stomach infection. I now find myself down to a svelte weight I haven&#8217;t seen since 2001. You would think that I&#8217;d have my butt permanently parked in front of the mirror so I could admire my practically nonexistent [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/dont-lose-10-pounds/">DON&#8217;T LOSE 10 POUNDS</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/' rel='bookmark' title='REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH'>REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/can-we-bring-wigs-back-in-fashion/' rel='bookmark' title='CAN WE BRING WIGS BACK IN FASHION?'>CAN WE BRING WIGS BACK IN FASHION?</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/fat-pants/' rel='bookmark' title='FAT PANTS'>FAT PANTS</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the Dutch doctor&#8217;s complete unwillingness to give me antibiotics, I recently lost 13lbs with a stomach infection. I now find myself down to a svelte weight I haven&#8217;t seen since 2001. You would think that I&#8217;d have my butt permanently parked in front of the mirror so I could admire my practically nonexistent backside. Well, you&#8217;d be wrong. You see, all of those bitches and assholes who constantly harp on you to lose those extra ten pounds conveniently forget to mention the downsides. </p>
<p>I, on the other hand, am a great friend. I am going to pull back the curtains on this weight loss bullshit and tell it like it really it. You do not want to lose those last few pounds. They are your best friend. Since this is so contrary to what everyone else says, I&#8217;ll give you some reasons why.</p>
<h2>Reasons why you should not lose 10 pounds</h2>
<ol>
<li>Newsflash ladies. You know how your post-baby belly button has that &#8220;lived in&#8221; look? If you lose the extra weight, you might as well post a giant flashing vacancy sign on your mid-section. No more pulling up the pants a bit higher or rocking the maternity jeans. You now have an unsightly flap that has to be carefully and precisely tucked away. If you make a sudden move, you run the risk that it will come flying out and knock out someone across the room. It turns out those last pounds were helping disguise the fact that your thirty-something skin doesn&#8217;t have the elasticity of before. So do yourself a favor and eat an extra cookie. &#8220;Womanly curves&#8221; sound much more appealing than a drooping vag cover.</li>
<li>Your clothes don&#8217;t fit. Once upon a time shrinking out of your wardrobe would have been a cause for celebration. No so once you have kids. Now all of your pants look like you are wearing a poopy diaper. You *could* go and buy some new ones, but that requires money and time. Do any of you have an overabundance of either or those? I didn&#8217;t think so. Go for a second helping and leave the droopy drawers to your toddler.</li>
<li>This last reason is perhaps the most concerning. Before I lost the weight, I would hide in the bathroom or closet when changing into my pajamas. Regardless of how much alcohol I had after dinner, I did not want the last thing I heard at night to be &#8220;you should go to the gym&#8221;. I lost the weight and damned if I am not right back to hiding in the closet. The newfound delineation between my boobs and belly has put a familiar sparkle in my husband&#8217;s eyes. When I have spent the whole day running behind two kids without a single second to myself, and when I finally make it up to my precious, comfy bed where I can sit down and not talk to anyone, the LAST thing I want is someone sneaking over and groping me from behind. Heaven help you if you say no! It does not go over well, regardless of how solid your excuses are (Aunt Flo, hairy legs, gassy, etc, I have tried them all). Pour yourself another glass and savor it while sitting all alone.</li>
</ol>
<p>So there you have it. The glamourous life of a Skinny Minnie is totally overrated once you have had kids. You are better off holding on to the protective layer that fluff is providing. </p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/dont-lose-10-pounds/">DON&#8217;T LOSE 10 POUNDS</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/' rel='bookmark' title='REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH'>REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/can-we-bring-wigs-back-in-fashion/' rel='bookmark' title='CAN WE BRING WIGS BACK IN FASHION?'>CAN WE BRING WIGS BACK IN FASHION?</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/fat-pants/' rel='bookmark' title='FAT PANTS'>FAT PANTS</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/dont-lose-10-pounds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>MY KID&#8217;S PURSE</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kids-purse/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kids-purse/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 15:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=497</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I am sure that you have all seen those blog posts and articles showcasing the contents of someone&#8217;s purse. I have a news flash for people that write those &#8211; I really hate them. I don&#8217;t want to see what another mom has in her purse. Likely it is the same crap that I have [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kids-purse/">MY KID&#8217;S PURSE</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/guest-posting-gig/' rel='bookmark' title='GUEST POSTING GIG'>GUEST POSTING GIG</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/lies-we-all-tell-our-kids/' rel='bookmark' title='8 LIES WE ALL TELL OUR KIDS'>8 LIES WE ALL TELL OUR KIDS</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/hello-sponsors-are-you-there/' rel='bookmark' title='HELLO, SPONSORS? ARE YOU THERE?'>HELLO, SPONSORS? ARE YOU THERE?</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am sure that you have all seen those blog posts and articles showcasing the contents of someone&#8217;s purse. I have a news flash for people that write those &#8211; I really hate them. I don&#8217;t want to see what another mom has in her purse. Likely it is the same crap that I have in my purse&#8230;a bunch of half-used kleenex, cookie crumbs, hand sanitizer and other random shit my kids give me to shove in there. </p>
<p>Even worse are the posts with single gal purses. Is there anything more depressing as a mom than having your complete lack of coolness validated by the internet? The single gal has fancy lipstick. I have chapstick. She has condoms. I have diaper rash cream. She has concert ticket stubs. I have the Wiggles concert video. Just go ahead and put me out to pasture already.</p>
<p>So I am not going to do that here. Instead, I am going to open up a literal can of worms and showcase the inside of my kid&#8217;s purse. She&#8217;s almost four. She loves pink and princesses. She is a kleptomaniac. And apparently she has a serious problem distinguishing trash from treasure.</p>
<p>See for yourself:</p>
<p><img src="http://nomadmomdiary.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/APurse_Artboard-4-1019x1024.png" alt="The contents of my kid&#039;s purse. If you can&#039;t see this image, then you pretty much missed the whole point of this post. Go and get on a computer that displays images, you lazy butt." width="600" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-501" /></p>
<p>The assorted Princess miniatures I get. My little one just turned two so we are very into the &#8220;birthday party&#8221; concept at the moment. Thus the slice of cake, party table and presents. Ballerina Dora and her dance studio are obvious musts. I mean, what if she were out somewhere and was required to act out Swan Lake and she didn&#8217;t have those. That would be embarrassing!</p>
<p>She does have a few practical items. She just borrowed the princess mobile phone from our neighbor this afternoon. She must have walked straight into the door and hid it in her purse. Nevermind that we already had a Belle phone. This one is pink, so it is obviously better. The two pieces of Cinderella&#8217;s slippers sidewalk chalk should come in handy if she needs to write mommy a note. </p>
<p>And then there is the random shit. Why are the Pinypins disassembled? Why aren&#8217;t there enough pieces for two complete dolls? Why did she steal her sister&#8217;s birthday present matchbox car? It is so new, G is still playing with it. And the mountain of clippings? Should I be checking her closet to see if it looks like a scene from A Beautiful Mind? I tried to throw away an old sticker the other day. That kid has eyes in the back of her head. She did a vocal bitch slap from across the room that left my ears ringing for the rest of the day.</p>
<p>The biggest mystery is how all of this fits into that one purse. I have no f&#8217;ing clue. I blame it on my neighbor. She let her watch Mary Poppins recently and admitted that Addy was wide-eyed and glued to the TV during the unpacking scene. If I find a lamp in there, we are going to have words.</p>
<p>There you are, ladies and gentlemen, the contents of my kid&#8217;s purse. Would you like to share the contents of your kid&#8217;s purse? Just send me a photo to lynn (at) nomadmomdiary.com with a description and I will post it up. Or, post it up on your own blog and send me the link. I&#8217;ll add it here.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kids-purse/">MY KID&#8217;S PURSE</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/guest-posting-gig/' rel='bookmark' title='GUEST POSTING GIG'>GUEST POSTING GIG</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/lies-we-all-tell-our-kids/' rel='bookmark' title='8 LIES WE ALL TELL OUR KIDS'>8 LIES WE ALL TELL OUR KIDS</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/hello-sponsors-are-you-there/' rel='bookmark' title='HELLO, SPONSORS? ARE YOU THERE?'>HELLO, SPONSORS? ARE YOU THERE?</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-kids-purse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>MOMMY&#8217;S ANNUAL REVIEW</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-annual-review/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-annual-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 21:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=488</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I just got an email with tips for preparing for my upcoming annual review. It stated: &#8220;Hi Lynn, if your annual review seems like a chore, try remembering that it shouldn’t be a one way street where your boss is doing all the talking – Make the most of your review and get the recognition [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-annual-review/">MOMMY&#8217;S ANNUAL REVIEW</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss yarpp-related-none'>

No related posts.
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just got an email with tips for preparing for my upcoming annual review. It stated:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;Hi Lynn, if your annual review seems like a chore, try remembering that it shouldn’t be a one way street where your boss is doing all the talking – Make the most of your review and get the recognition you deserve with these handy hints.&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>If you have read any other post on this blog, you know that my bosses are real asshats. They frown heavily on things like &#8220;vacation days&#8221; and &#8220;sick leave&#8221; and have even gone so far as to outlaw potty breaks and lunch. The only upside is that I do get to work from home (take that Marissa Mayer).</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve put in a lot of overtime in the last couple of years and I figure I am due for a salary adjustment (or even just a salary in the first place) AND a big fat bonus (no, a used diaper doesn&#8217;t count). So I thought I would trip on over to the recommended website and check out the handy tips.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>#1: Before the meeting: Brush up on your organisation’s performance management system: It might sound obvious, but even if you think you know how the system works there may have been some recent changes. So, at the very least it’s worth having a quick look on your intranet if you have one, or a chat with someone in HR. If you work somewhere where there isn’t a formal system, talk to your manager in advance about what ground they’ll be covering in your meeting.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Hmmm, I think I can safely say that we fall into the second category. I mean the kids have learned how to open the iPhone and email incriminating photos to unsuspecting contacts (sorry old boss), but they haven&#8217;t set-up an official home intranet yet. </p>
<p>The performance management system looks something like this: They tell me to do something and I do it. If I don&#8217;t, they throw a giant screaming fit and potentially also kick and thrash about on the ground. There isn&#8217;t a lot of gray area there. If I follow said command, they wait 10 seconds and ask for something else. Those 10 seconds were my reward for completing the task.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>#2: Gather your evidence: You should have objectives that you’ve been asked to deliver on, so dig them out and make some notes on how you’ve done.<br />
Think about the times when you might have gone beyond your own objectives to help deliver work that wasn’t officially yours to do – if you don’t bring up what you’ve done your helpfulness might be overlooked.<br />
Talk to someone who can help jog your memory about what you’ve done over the whole year.<br />
Have some time to yourself: Immediately before your meeting, keep some time free. You’ll feel much more focused than if you rush straight from another meeting. It’ll also help you to stay calm.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Since we don&#8217;t have a formal system, I think that means I can set my own goals. Here they are: don&#8217;t kill the kids. I just checked and they are sleeping like angels, so I can check that box. </p>
<p>Now about those times I&#8217;ve gone above and beyond&#8230;I&#8217;ve made cookies and cakes for playgroups parties and giftbags for the daycare kids. Let&#8217;s not forget the massive treasure-load of dress-up clothes I brought back from the States. </p>
<p>And things that aren&#8217;t officially mine &#8211; I keep getting stuck with changing the trashbag (a clear Nomad Papa task). That counts, right? I&#8217;d try and talk to someone for more ideas, but all of my friends are as drunk and sleep-deprived as I am and there isn&#8217;t a single one of us that can remember what we did last week. Damn.</p>
<p>Oh, I know, I&#8217;ll just take some free time and focus on remembering. Waahhhaaaaaaaa. Or maybe I&#8217;ll pee and then refill my wine glass.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>#3: In the meeting: Make your case: Many managers will begin by asking you how you think your year has gone, so it’s your chance to give them a summary of what you’ve done well.<br />
Be open to feedback: For many of us any kind of feedback can feel like criticism even when it’s intended to help you improve. Rather than be overly defensive, be open to what you’re hearing.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>I am going to rock out in this meeting by taking control of the when and where. I think I&#8217;ll butter them up with chocolate frosting sandwiches and cookies and ice cream for dessert. Then, in that split second between the full belly feeling and the sugar rush, I am going to say, &#8220;Look at how awesome your mommy is! She gave you chocolate for lunch!&#8221; and list off my greatest hits of accomplishments. (Note to self &#8211; cull list of any items that will cause a distraction, like the zoo. Don&#8217;t mention the zoo unless we can leave immediately to visit it. Otherwise the review will go in a downward spiral.)</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll ask for feedback, but use big words so that they don&#8217;t have any idea what I am talking about. I mean, they are going to spew out nonsense anyways, so I might as well get some entertainment out of it.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>#4: The Final Tip: When you’re busy getting on with the day job it can be tempting to just wing it when it comes to your appraisal meeting but putting some effort into preparing for it should ensure you get a fair report that gives you the recognition you deserve.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Hmmm, so what is the recognition I deserve? A million dollars? A paid vacation to a beach where no kids are allowed? Yes and yes. Unfortunately, I just checked our reward policy and it looks like the most I can hope for is a half-eaten piece of birthday cake that Giorgie no longer wants. </p>
<p>A girl can dream though, a girl can dream.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-annual-review/">MOMMY&#8217;S ANNUAL REVIEW</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss yarpp-related-none'>
<p>No related posts.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/my-annual-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 12:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=476</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I am having one of those days that is going to end with me either punching someone in the face or flushing my own head down the toilet. I am a mega, mega beeyotch. I was trying to think of the reason why I am so bitchy today, and I came up with quite a [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/">REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/why-my-kids-are-glad-im-home/' rel='bookmark' title='WHY MY KIDS ARE GLAD I&#8217;M HOME'>WHY MY KIDS ARE GLAD I&#8217;M HOME</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/mandatory-make-up-moment/' rel='bookmark' title='MANDATORY MAKE-UP MOMENT'>MANDATORY MAKE-UP MOMENT</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/payback-is-a-bitch/' rel='bookmark' title='PAYBACK IS A BITCH'>PAYBACK IS A BITCH</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am having one of those days that is going to end with me either punching someone in the face or flushing my own head down the toilet. I am a mega, mega beeyotch. I was trying to think of the reason why I am so bitchy today, and I came up with quite a long list. I thought I&#8217;d share it with you, just in case some of you others have a similar problem and don&#8217;t want to have to think all of this up again.</p>
<p>(BTW, if you are feeling bitchy and need something to laugh at, check out Jason Good&#8217;s post <a href="http://jasongood.net/365/2012/12/46-reasons-why-my-three-year-old-might-be-freaking-out/" target="_blank">46 Reasons My Three Year Old Might Be Freaking Out</a>. It kinda inspired this post, but his is funnier. Damn him.)</p>
<p>REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH (valid on any given day)</p>
<ol>
<li>I woke up.</li>
<li>I woke up too early.</li>
<li>The kids kept me up all night</li>
<li>I have kids</li>
<li>I am married&#8230;to a man (maybe it would be different if I had married a woman&#8230;I dunno.)</li>
<li>My pants are too tight</li>
<li>My pants are all dirty</li>
<li>I am wearing my least favorite pair of underwear (the threadbare granny panties that ride up my butt)</li>
<li>I have to go somewhere that I can&#8217;t wear yoga pants</li>
<li>I had to put on a bra AND brush my hair</li>
<li>My bra is too big (why can&#8217;t the weight come out of my belly instead of my boobs?)</li>
<li>It&#8217;s my non shower day but I have to look nice</li>
<li>It&#8217;s my shower day but I don&#8217;t have anywhere to go</li>
<li>I left my house (sometimes, isn&#8217;t that enough?)</li>
<li>I have 400 loads of laundry to do / dishes to wash / etc.</li>
<li>Someone peed on my floor</li>
<li>Someone pooped on my floor</li>
<li>My husband said the word &#8220;gym&#8221; in the house. (Context is irreleant)</li>
<li>Nothing I see, read, hear or think is funny</li>
<li>Everything I think of is funny, but I can&#8217;t get anywhere to write it down</li>
<li>My kids are hanging off of me</li>
<li>My kids prefer Papa (I know that I should be happy about that, but don&#8217;t the little shits know that I do all of the work and therefore deserve all of the credit)</li>
<li>Everyone on facebook is posting up motivational shit. I don&#8217;t need that.</li>
<li>No one is posting anything on facebook. (Come on, refresh already!!)</li>
<li>No one helped me fold the laundry</li>
<li>My husband helped, but did it all wrong and didn&#8217;t put anything away</li>
<li>The kids &#8220;helped&#8221; me fold laundry and now I have to rewash it all</li>
<li>The weather sucks.</li>
<li>The kids are being assholes</li>
<li>I have PMS</li>
<li>My husband has PMS</li>
<li>My kids have PMS</li>
<li>The dog ate my lunch</li>
<li>We ran out of sweets in the house.</li>
</ol>
<p>So those are my reasons&#8230;.or a few of them at least. What are yours?</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/">REASONS WHY I AM A BITCH</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/why-my-kids-are-glad-im-home/' rel='bookmark' title='WHY MY KIDS ARE GLAD I&#8217;M HOME'>WHY MY KIDS ARE GLAD I&#8217;M HOME</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/mandatory-make-up-moment/' rel='bookmark' title='MANDATORY MAKE-UP MOMENT'>MANDATORY MAKE-UP MOMENT</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/payback-is-a-bitch/' rel='bookmark' title='PAYBACK IS A BITCH'>PAYBACK IS A BITCH</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/reasons-why-i-am-a-bitch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>MISERY LOVES COMPANY</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/misery-loves-company/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/misery-loves-company/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 10:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=469</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Nomad Papa and I had always planned on having three kids. Anytime I met someone who had three kids, I would grill them relentlessly about their lives. &#8220;Is it a lot more work? How do you manage it? Do you feel outnumbered?&#8221; and 500 other questions that my inquiring mind wanted to know. Do you [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/misery-loves-company/">MISERY LOVES COMPANY</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/misery-is-key-to-stress-reduction/' rel='bookmark' title='MISERY IS KEY TO STRESS REDUCTION'>MISERY IS KEY TO STRESS REDUCTION</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/i-am-a-bad-mom-episode-552/' rel='bookmark' title='I AM A BAD MOM, EPISODE 552'>I AM A BAD MOM, EPISODE 552</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/how-i-spent-my-new-years/' rel='bookmark' title='HOW I SPENT MY NEW YEAR&#8217;S'>HOW I SPENT MY NEW YEAR&#8217;S</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nomad Papa and I had always planned on having three kids. Anytime I met someone who had three kids, I would grill them relentlessly about their lives. &#8220;Is it a lot more work? How do you manage it? Do you feel outnumbered?&#8221; and 500 other questions that my inquiring mind wanted to know.</p>
<p>Do you know that every single parent of three I spoke to swore up and down that 3 kids were hardly any more work than 2! I would walk away breathing out a huge sigh of relief. Three wouldn&#8217;t be hard, we could do it!</p>
<p>Now that I am older, wiser and less sleep-deprived, I have come to a massive realization. Parents LIE. They lie all the time and, most importantly, they lie to each other. Kids are a fuck ton of work. I don&#8217;t care if you have one kid or ten kids, you are busy 24/7. And a big chunk of that time (aka the entirety of the toddler years) you are also miserable. Why? Because, I repeat, kids are a fuck ton of work. So why do we perpetuate this vicious cycle of lies? Let me explain.</p>
<p>Say you have one kid. You eventually get less sleep-deprived and manage to see glimpses of your former life. You can do this because you and your spouse can take turns holding the kid. You might never sit down to a meal or drink a beer together, but you can still do these things without holding a kid. Then people start nagging you to have a second kid. Other parents say, &#8220;no, it is much easier with the second kid because you have all of the knowledge from the first one.&#8221; You don&#8217;t question their motives. You just buy into it.</p>
<p>Since you only have one kid at this point, you can find time to bump uglies with your spouse (or go to 100 different fertility treatments, or however you get the second one). Everyone keeps on perpetuating the myth that #2 is so much easier than #1. Then you have #2 and discover that you have spent 9+ months eating spoonfuls of bullshit. </p>
<p>#2 is twice as much work as #1. First off, they are the total opposite of #1 in every way possible. So whatever little tricks you used on #1 do not work on #2. Then you realize that the combination of sleep deprivation and pregnancy brain have caused you to completely black out the first 18 months of your first child&#8217;s life. You are pretty sure that you were all together during the time, but you can&#8217;t come up with any specifics to save your life. &#8220;Did he/she start teething that early? Did I start with fruits or veggies? When did he/she start to sit up?&#8221; No fucking clue. So you gotta dig the books back out again and relearn the basics.</p>
<p>Somewhere in the midst of this turmoil (likely the moment when you find yourself sitting on the toilet with two screaming children in your lap while trying to convince your bladder that now is not the moment to have performance anxiety), you begin to hate everyone that told you that 2 kids were no more work than 1. You make a pact with yourself that you will never tell anyone that kids are &#8220;not too much work&#8221; or that having 2 kids &#8220;isn&#8217;t that much harder than having 1&#8243;.</p>
<p>Fast forward a week or so to your next playgroup outing. You will be there in stained clothing and will spend the entire time chasing one child or the other. During one of your 100 trips with a kid to the snack table, you will pass a group of moms who are (gasp) sitting down and having a conversation. Combed hair, pressed jeans and a tea cup in hand. Bitches. And what do they all have in common? They only have ONE kid. </p>
<p>Then one of them will innocently mention that they are thinking about having a second kid. At that moment, all pacts with yourself will go flying out the window. You suddenly see your opportunity to bring those perfectionists down to your level. You will hear yourself say the words you swore never to say, &#8220;Oh, you should definitely do it. Going from one kid to two is hardly any more work. You already know everything and it is much, much easier.&#8221; And then you walk away quickly so that they don&#8217;t notice the smirk on your face.</p>
<p>So now you know why this multi-kid myth continues. It is because, in the end, misery loves company. I would much rather hang out with the moms who are just as frazzled as I am, than be reminded of my own stupidity in believing the more kids didn&#8217;t equal more work. That&#8217;s why, if you meet me in real life, you should not be surprised to hear my say, &#8220;2 Kids are great. You should do it!&#8221; Really, it is flattery at it&#8217;s best. I don&#8217;t do it because I hate you. I do it because I need a new bitching buddy. So get on out there and procreate, people!</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/misery-loves-company/">MISERY LOVES COMPANY</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/misery-is-key-to-stress-reduction/' rel='bookmark' title='MISERY IS KEY TO STRESS REDUCTION'>MISERY IS KEY TO STRESS REDUCTION</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/i-am-a-bad-mom-episode-552/' rel='bookmark' title='I AM A BAD MOM, EPISODE 552'>I AM A BAD MOM, EPISODE 552</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/how-i-spent-my-new-years/' rel='bookmark' title='HOW I SPENT MY NEW YEAR&#8217;S'>HOW I SPENT MY NEW YEAR&#8217;S</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/misery-loves-company/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NOPE, THAT&#8217;S NOT EXERCISE</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/nope-thats-not-exercise/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/nope-thats-not-exercise/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 20:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=457</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week my not quite 2 year old decided to give up her afternoon naps. By 8pm I was EXHAUSTED in the way that only mothers can be. I had finally gotten the kids to bed and made it back downstairs for a little me time. I checked my email and there was a message [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/nope-thats-not-exercise/">NOPE, THAT&#8217;S NOT EXERCISE</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/sweatpants-are-new-black/' rel='bookmark' title='SWEATPANTS ARE THE NEW BLACK'>SWEATPANTS ARE THE NEW BLACK</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week my not quite 2 year old decided to give up her afternoon naps. By 8pm I was EXHAUSTED in the way that only mothers can be. I had finally gotten the kids to bed and made it back downstairs for a little me time. I checked my email and there was a message from my husband. The subject line: LINK. </p>
<p>Hmmm, I was intrigued. I opened it up and saw that the link was to an article in the Italian newspaper. Even more intriguing. La Repubblica publishes everything from breaking news to soft-core porn on its site so there was no telling what the article was going to be. Having nothing better to do, I clicked through.</p>
<p>Was I met with a pair of perfectly shaped boobs and an advertisement for bottled water? Nope. He had sent me an article about some new health discovery that recommended people do a sweat-inducing work out for at least 2-3 hours per week. I can read between the lines here, people. The message here wasn&#8217;t &#8220;Oh what an interesting discovery!&#8221;. It was &#8220;Get yo lazy ass to the gym&#8221;. I wish he had sent the boobs instead.</p>
<p>Apparently my husband thinks that I lead a sedentary life. (I&#8217;ll pause here so that all of you moms can catch your breath after laughing yourselves silly.)</p>
<p>In his world, if it doesn&#8217;t happen in the gym or while out running, it doesn&#8217;t count. Let me just give you a few examples of our she said / he heard battles over the bulge.</p>
<p>Example 1: The Mommy Triathlon</p>
<p>I SAY: I took Addy to dance class today.</p>
<p>HE HEARS: Blah blah dance blah.</p>
<p>I MEAN: I rushed out the door, biked across town to the daycare, ran up and down the stairs to her classroom, threw her on the bike, biked across town again to dance class, rushed her inside and somehow shoved her tutu and tights on before hussling her into the classroom 2 minutes late. Then I sat down with the other dance moms and passed around the communal paper bag as we all tried to catch our breath again.</p>
<p>HE SAYS: Hey, did you go to dance class today? You should really go to the gym.</p>
<p>Example 2: The Mommy Marathon</p>
<p>I SAY: Giorgie didn&#8217;t nap today.</p>
<p>HE HEARS: (Who the hell knows&#8230;he claims he has gone deaf from listening to the kids cry&#8230;I have my doubts.)</p>
<p>I MEAN: I chased her around the house 27 times trying to get clothing and/or a diaper back on her. I pulled out and then cleaned up the same set of toys 15 times. I tossed her into the air, slung her around, carted her butt up and down the stairs, cooked lunch while holding her, ate lunch with her in my lap, peed with her in my lap, broke up 6 arguments, danced to the aurora song 5 times in a row, and made countless trips back and forth between the couch and the snack cabinet. And that was just between 12-1pm.</p>
<p>HE SAYS: Hey, are you going to ever go to the gym? You promised me that you would get a membership.</p>
<p>Clearly he is not going to take my word for it that motherhood is a workout routine all on its own. That is why so many of us wear yoga pants on a daily basis. It isn&#8217;t laziness or the elastic waistband (wait, yes it is&#8230;whatever&#8230;overlook that for a minute) it is because we are working our butts off trying to keep up with the kids.</p>
<p>I need help here, Internet world. There must be some study out there that says &#8220;Wow! Moms burn through a shitload of calories each day and should absolutely be allowed to eat whatever the hell they want anytime they want.&#8221; So can one of you internet peeps find this and send me the link? I will share it with everyone, for the good of all motherkind. </p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/nope-thats-not-exercise/">NOPE, THAT&#8217;S NOT EXERCISE</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/sweatpants-are-new-black/' rel='bookmark' title='SWEATPANTS ARE THE NEW BLACK'>SWEATPANTS ARE THE NEW BLACK</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/nope-thats-not-exercise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>FAT PANTS</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/fat-pants/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/fat-pants/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 09:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=444</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week I went to London to visit my glamourous friend. You know, the friend you aspire to become when you grow up. (If you don&#8217;t have one of those, get one!) I put a lot of thought into what I should wear. I needed to appear perfectly put together but still maintain an air [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/fat-pants/">FAT PANTS</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss yarpp-related-none'>

No related posts.
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week I went to London to visit my glamourous friend. You know, the friend you aspire to become when you grow up. (If you don&#8217;t have one of those, get one!) I put a lot of thought into what I should wear. I needed to appear perfectly put together but still maintain an air of casualness so that it didn&#8217;t seem like I was trying to hard. The solution: blown out hair, make-up, cute jeans and a v-neck tee. </p>
<p>As usual, I was running late so the first chance I had to really sit down was on the airplane. I climbed in and slid down into my designated spot. And then I immediately arched back up so that I could adjust my jeans and tuck the muffin top down below the belt line. Shit. I did not see that coming. I suddenly realized that my seemingly well-thought out wardrobe plan had a fatal flaw: I did not wear my fat pants. </p>
<p>I spent the flight wondering why someone can&#8217;t invent a cute pair of fat pants. My personal pair of choice are some &#8220;Not Your Daughter&#8217;s Jeans&#8221; that no one under the age of 75 would proudly wear in public. The butt sags down below my inner thighs and the waistband is large enough to fit me and my daughter into at the same time. In short, all the reasons why I LOVE those pants are the same reasons why my husband goes running in the opposite direction when he sees them coming. (Hmmm, note to self: wear fat pants when trying to avoid husband&#8217;s attention.)</p>
<p>I came back home thoroughly frustrated with clothing designers. WTF people? Don&#8217;t any of you have kids? I bet if just one of you hosted a mommy summit and asked for our help in designing a cute pair of fat jeans, you&#8217;d win the Nobel Peace prize and make a gazillion dollars. Think about it, ok?</p>
<p>But something happened to pull me out of the deep dark depths of depression. My friend Molly pinged me on facebook to let me know about an ad she just saw:</p>
<p><a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Overalls-Convo.jpg"><img src="http://nomadmomdiary.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Overalls-Convo.jpg" alt="Sexy Overalls? Send me that link!" width="400" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-445" /></a> </p>
<p>Sexy overalls? It was like a light from heaven shot through the clouds and shined down directly on my laptop screen. Could this be the solution to all of our fat pants problems? TOTALLY! Let me introduce you to my new wardrobe:</p>
<p><img src="http://nomadmomdiary.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/DressyMeeting-03-1024x614.png" alt="I bet that huge wrap belt could tuck in even the biggest muffin top." width="600" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-452" /></p>
<p><img src="http://nomadmomdiary.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/innerJLo-03-1024x614.png" alt="I&#039;m bringing out my inner JLo even if we are only going to TGIFridays" width="600" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-451" /></p>
<p><img src="http://nomadmomdiary.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/weekendwear-03-1024x614.png" alt="No waistband, no bra, just pure fun." width="600" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-450" /></p>
<p><img src="http://nomadmomdiary.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/offtoplaygroup-03-1024x614.png" alt="Do you know how many tissues I could keep in those pockets?" width="600" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-449" /></p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/fat-pants/">FAT PANTS</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss yarpp-related-none'>
<p>No related posts.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/fat-pants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>SO LONG, THONG-A-LONGA-DING-DONG</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/so-long-thong-a-longa-ding-dong/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/so-long-thong-a-longa-ding-dong/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 17:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=440</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I got out of the shower this morning and just like every other day, I pulled on my giant pair of granny panties. They are the antithesis of everything sexy, from the full butt coverage to the high elasticized waist panel that tucks in the muffin top. Put on a pair of these and the [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/so-long-thong-a-longa-ding-dong/">SO LONG, THONG-A-LONGA-DING-DONG</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss yarpp-related-none'>

No related posts.
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I got out of the shower this morning and just like every other day, I pulled on my giant pair of granny panties. They are the antithesis of everything sexy, from the full butt coverage to the high elasticized waist panel that tucks in the muffin top. Put on a pair of these and the thrice daily plumber butt shows become a thing of the past. In short, granny panties are a mommy&#8217;s best friend.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, my path to enlightenment was fraught with horrors and mishaps. I had a brief fling with boxer briefs (shudder). Try stripping down in front of your significant other in a pair of undies that showcase your best features: a bulging waistline and thunder thighs. It&#8217;s almost enough to put off even the most sex-deprived spouse.</p>
<p>Most of my 20&#8242;s was spent in a long love/hate relationship with the whale tail&#8230;the butt floss&#8230;the thong-a-longa-ding-dong. With a name like g-string it seems like something that should cause auto-orgasms with each step. If only!</p>
<p>Those sexy scraps of lace looked like a wrought iron fence around an abandoned park if I wasn&#8217;t &#8220;landscaped&#8221; to perfection. The sporty version with its masculine cotton panels and &#8220;comfort&#8221; strip in the back rubbed blisters where the good lord split me but the sun doesn&#8217;t shine. Not a situation I cared to explain to co-workers as I hobbled along.</p>
<p>One day I realized that the only truly comfy pair of thongs I owned consisted of three strings and a minuscule cotton panel with snoopy on the front. (No, I am not making that up.) I felt like a five year old prostitute.</p>
<p>That day I abandoned all pretense of the sex kitten, afternoon quickie, mile-high club identity that I wasn&#8217;t backing up anyways. I embraced my spit-up stained, sippy-cup carrying, sleep-deprived outer image and slipped on a pair of granny panties. </p>
<p>And I have never looked back.</p>
<p>So long, thong-a-longa-ding-dong. May you forevermore chafe someone else&#8217;s butt.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/so-long-thong-a-longa-ding-dong/">SO LONG, THONG-A-LONGA-DING-DONG</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss yarpp-related-none'>
<p>No related posts.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/so-long-thong-a-longa-ding-dong/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>HEY, I&#8217;M DONE HAVING KIDS, OKAY???</title>
		<link>http://nomadmomdiary.com/hey-im-done-having-kids-okay/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadmomdiary.com/hey-im-done-having-kids-okay/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 09:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadlynn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadmomdiary.com/?p=433</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>My husband and I have this funny routine we like to do. I say that I am done having kids. He says that we might have one more someday. Then I say that he can have another kid with his second wife. I&#8217;m not quite sure that he has understood that I am dead serious. [...]</p><p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/hey-im-done-having-kids-okay/">HEY, I&#8217;M DONE HAVING KIDS, OKAY???</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/raising-our-husbands/' rel='bookmark' title='RAISING OUR HUSBANDS'>RAISING OUR HUSBANDS</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/lies-we-all-tell-our-kids/' rel='bookmark' title='8 LIES WE ALL TELL OUR KIDS'>8 LIES WE ALL TELL OUR KIDS</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/how-to-know-if-you-are-ready-to-travel-with-kids/' rel='bookmark' title='HOW TO KNOW IF YOU ARE READY TO FLY WITH KIDS'>HOW TO KNOW IF YOU ARE READY TO FLY WITH KIDS</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My husband and I have this funny routine we like to do. I say that I am done having kids. He says that we might have one more someday. Then I say that he can have another kid with his second wife. I&#8217;m not quite sure that he has understood that I am dead serious.</p>
<p>Maybe some of the rest of you are in the same position, and are wondering whether you are really done having kids. Read my checklist and find out for yourself.</p>
<h2>SIGNS YOU ARE DONE HAVING KIDS</h2>
<ol>
<li>When you hear a newborn baby crying, you run in the opposite direction.<br />(I was out walking the dog one day and caught myself running past the house where I could hear a new baby crying inside. I didn&#8217;t even know the family, but I wasn&#8217;t taking any chances.)</li>
<li>When you use four forms of birth control on a regular basis, even though you haven&#8217;t had sex in three months.<br /> (My mama always said that the best form of birth control was abstinence. She was wrong. The best form of birth control is toddlers.)</li>
<li>When a woman in the group announces that she is pregnant, you express your condolences instead of congratulations.<br />(By the way, pregnant women don&#8217;t take that very well&#8230;fyi)</li>
<li>Every time your youngest child masters a new skill, you think, &#8220;thank god we won&#8217;t have to go through that again&#8221;.<br /> (Catching yourself mid-swing throwing the baby walker into the canal is a clear indicator.)</li>
<li>You can admit that every minute of pregnancy sucks.<br />(Only women in denial can convince themselves that packing on thirty some-odd pounds and having an alien invader in their body is a beautiful and amazing experience.)</li>
<li>When someone jokes that you will be the next to have a baby, you seriously debate punching them in the face and/or not speaking to them ever again.<br />(Is there anything more frustrating than trying to defend yourself against that kind of attack? The more you say no, the more they laugh and say yes. Punching them in the face is totally justified.)</li>
<li>When you sell all of your baby stuff and use the money to buy wine and condoms.<br />(I haven&#8217;t done this yet, but I am definitely going to do it now that I thought it up. Local moms, hang in there for a yard sale date.)</li>
<li>When the wine glass is an extension of your hand (sorta like Capt. Hook) and you find yourself standing in front of the wine bottle at 4:59pm.<br />(Give alcohol up for at least 9 months? I can barely go for a day. I don&#8217;t need kids that badly.)</li>
</ol>
<p>So how did you do? Anyone else interested in a uterus retirement party?</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/hey-im-done-having-kids-okay/">HEY, I&#8217;M DONE HAVING KIDS, OKAY???</a> appeared first on <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com">The Diary of a Nomad Mom</a>.</p><div class='yarpp-related-rss'>
<h3>Related posts:</h3><ol>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/raising-our-husbands/' rel='bookmark' title='RAISING OUR HUSBANDS'>RAISING OUR HUSBANDS</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/lies-we-all-tell-our-kids/' rel='bookmark' title='8 LIES WE ALL TELL OUR KIDS'>8 LIES WE ALL TELL OUR KIDS</a></li>
<li><a href='http://nomadmomdiary.com/how-to-know-if-you-are-ready-to-travel-with-kids/' rel='bookmark' title='HOW TO KNOW IF YOU ARE READY TO FLY WITH KIDS'>HOW TO KNOW IF YOU ARE READY TO FLY WITH KIDS</a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadmomdiary.com/hey-im-done-having-kids-okay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.700 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-26 07:11:23 -->
