<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/" xmlns:creativeCommons="http://backend.userland.com/creativeCommonsRssModule" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>internetmonk.com</title>
	
	<link>http://www.internetmonk.com</link>
	<description>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 04:01:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
<!-- podcast_generator="Blubrry PowerPress/4.0.7" -->
	<itunes:summary>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:author>The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer</itunes:author>
	<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/monkposterx3.jpg" />
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer</itunes:name>
		<itunes:email>michael@internetmonk.com</itunes:email>
	</itunes:owner>
	<managingEditor>michael@internetmonk.com (The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer)</managingEditor>
	<copyright>2006-2009</copyright>
	<itunes:subtitle>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</itunes:subtitle>
	<image><link>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</link><url>http://creativecommons.org/images/public/somerights20.gif</url><title>Some Rights Reserved</title></image>
	<itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
		<itunes:category text="Christianity" />
	</itunes:category>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/internetmonk/SWqj" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="internetmonk/swqj" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license><feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">internetmonk/SWqj</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>The Problem with “Safe, Legal” Abortion</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-problem-with-safe-legal-abortion</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-problem-with-safe-legal-abortion#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 04:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Public Issues]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40366</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This absolutely horrifying story from The Atlantic about Dr. Kermit Gosnell, now standing trial for murder in Philadelphia, gives the lie to the traditional argument that making and keeping abortion legal ensures that it will be done safely and with concern for the health and well being of the mother. As the grand jury report states: [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/t1larg.kermit.gosnell.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40370" alt="t1larg.kermit.gosnell" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/t1larg.kermit.gosnell.jpg" width="512" height="288" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/national/archive/2013/04/why-dr-kermit-gosnells-trial-should-be-a-front-page-story/274944/"><strong>This absolutely horrifying story from <em>The Atlantic</em></strong></a> about Dr. Kermit Gosnell, now standing trial for murder in Philadelphia, gives the lie to the traditional argument that making and keeping abortion legal ensures that it will be done safely and with concern for the health and well being of the mother. As the grand jury report states:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">&#8220;This case is about a doctor who killed babies and endangered women. What we mean is that he regularly and illegally delivered live, viable babies in the third trimester of pregnancy &#8211; and then murdered these newborns by severing their spinal cords with scissors. The medical practice by which he carried out this business was a filthy fraud in which he overdosed his patients with dangerous drugs, spread venereal disease among them with infected instruments, perforated their wombs and bowels &#8212; and, on at least two occasions, caused their deaths.&#8221;</p>
<p>I encourage you to go and read the entire article, if you can stomach it. It is a true American horror story. It also reveals issues of racism, mistreatment of the poor, the exploitation of women, and the failures of government and journalistic institutions.</p>
<p>I will simply re-post here some of the grand jury&#8217;s conclusions about the appalling lack of oversight with regard to this doctor and clinic.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Pennsylvania is not a third-world country. There were several oversight agencies that stumbled upon and should have shut down Kermit Gosnell long ago. But none of them did&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">The first line of defense was the Pennsylvania Department of Health. The department&#8217;s job is to audit hospitals and outpatient medical facilities, like Gosnell&#8217;s, to make sure that they follow the rules and provide safe care. The department had contact with the Women&#8217;s Medical Society dating back to 1979, when it first issued approval to open an abortion clinic. It did not conduct another site review until 1989, ten years later. Numerous violations were already apparent, but Gosnell got a pass when he promised to fix them. Site reviews in 1992 and 1993 also noted various violations, but again failed to ensure they were corrected.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">But at least the department had been doing something up to that point, however ineffectual. After 1993, even that pro form a effort came to an end. Not because of administrative ennui, although there had been plenty. Instead, the Pennsylvania Department of Health abruptly decided, for political reasons, to stop inspecting abortion clinics at all&#8230; The only exception to this live-and-let-die policy was supposed to be for complaints dumped directly on the department&#8217;s doorstep. Those, at least, would be investigated. Except that there were complaints about Gosnell, repeatedly. Several different attorneys, representing women injured by Gosnell, contacted the department. A doctor from Children&#8217;s Hospital of Philadelphia hand-delivered a complaint, advising the department that numerous patients he had referred for abortions came back from Gosnell with the same venereal disease. The medical examiner of Delaware County informed the department that Gosnell had performed an illegal abortion on a 14-year-old girl carrying a 30-week-old baby. And the department received official notice that a woman named Karnamaya Mongar had died at Gosnell&#8217;s hands.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Yet not one of these alarm bells &#8212; not even Mrs. Mongar&#8217;s death &#8212; prompted the department to look at Gosnell or the Women&#8217;s Medical Society&#8230; But even this total abdication by the Department of Health might not have been fatal. Another agency with authority in the health field, the Pennsylvania Department of State, could have stopped Gosnell single-handedly.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">The Department of State, through its Board of Medicine, licenses and oversees individual physicians&#8230; Almost a decade ago, a former employee of Gosnell presented the Board of Medicine with a complaint that laid out the whole scope of his operation: the unclean, unsterile conditions; the unlicensed workers; the unsupervised sedation; the underage abortion patients; even the over-prescribing of pain pills with high resale value on the street. The department assigned an investigator, whose investigation consisted primarily of an offsite interview with Gosnell. The investigator never inspected the facility, questioned other employees, or reviewed any records. Department attorneys chose to accept this incomplete investigation, and dismissed the complaint as unconfirmed.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Shortly thereafter the department received an even more disturbing report &#8212; about a woman, years before Karnamaya Mongar, who died of sepsis after Gosnell perforated her uterus. The woman was 22 years old. A civil suit against Gosnell was settled for almost a million dollars, and the insurance company forwarded the information to the department. That report should have been all the confirmation needed for the complaint from the former employee that was already in the department&#8217;s possession. Instead, the department attorneys dismissed this complaint too&#8230; The same thing happened at least twice more: the department received complaints about lawsuits against Gosnell, but dismissed them as meaningless&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Philadelphia health department employees regularly visited the Women&#8217;s Medical Society to retrieve blood samples for testing purposes, but never noticed, or more likely never bothered to report, that anything was amiss. Another employee inspected the clinic in response to a complaint that dead fetuses were being stored in paper bags in the employees&#8217; lunch refrigerator. The inspection confirmed numerous violations&#8230; But no follow-up was ever done&#8230; A health department representative also came to the clinic as part of a citywide vaccination program. She promptly discovered that Gosnell was scamming the program; she was the only employee, city or state, who actually tried to do something about the appalling things she saw there. By asking questions and poking around, she was able to file detailed reports identifying many of the most egregious elements of Gosnell&#8217;s practice. It should have been enough to stop him. But instead her reports went into a black hole, weeks before Karnamaya Mongar walked into the Woman&#8217;s Medical Society.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">&#8230;And it wasn&#8217;t just government agencies that did nothing. The Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania and its subsidiary, Penn Presbyterian Medical Center, are in the same neighborhood as Gosnell&#8217;s office. State law requires hospitals to report complications from abortions. A decade ago, a Gosnell patient died at HUP after a botched abortion, and the hospital apparently filed the necessary report. But the victims kept coming in. At least three other Gosnell patients were brought to Penn facilities for emergency surgery; emergency room personnel said they have treated many others as well. And at least one additional woman was hospitalized there after Gosnell had begun a flagrantly illegal abortion of a 29-week-old fetus. Yet, other than the one initial report, Penn could find not a single case in which it complied with its legal duty to alert authorities to the danger. Not even when a second woman turned up virtually dead&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">So too with the National Abortion Federation.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">NAF is an association of abortion providers that upholds the strict est health and legal standards for its members. Gosnell, bizarrely, applied for admission shortly after Karnamaya Mongar&#8217;s death. Despite his various efforts to fool her, the evaluator from NAF readily noted that records were not properly kept, that risks were not explained, that patients were not monitored, that equipment was not available, that anesthesia was misused. It was the worst abortion clinic she had ever inspected. Of course, she rejected Gosnell&#8217;s application. She just never told anyone in authority about all the horrible, dangerous things she had seen.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>A meaningful discussion about abortion in this country must be honest, open, and complete on all sides. It is not enough to be &#8220;pro-life&#8221; and yet refuse to confess that the movement has been sorely lacking in advocating for a variety of social justice concerns that would make abortion a less attractive alternative, especially for the poor. But neither is it appropriate to take a &#8220;pro-choice&#8221; stance and fail to acknowledge the ugly reality that abortion contributes to the actual harm of people and society, especially when its legality is abused in such unspeakable ways.</p>
<p>The silence of the mainstream media and the &#8220;pro-choice&#8221; movement regarding this case is inexcusable. Many are starting ask why this story hasn&#8217;t received much coverage: see <a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/opinion/opinion-la/la-ol-kermit-gosnell-why-so-little-coverage-20130412,0,4790500.story">LA Times</a>, <a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/weigel/2013/04/12/kermit_gosnell_the_alleged_mass_murderer_and_the_bored_media.html">Salon</a>, <a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/2013/04/10/philadelphia-abortion-clinic-horror-column/2072577/">USA Today</a>, as well as this piece I&#8217;ve referenced from The Atlantic.</p>
<p>Whatever your position on whether or not abortion should remain a legal alternative in our society, for the common good can&#8217;t we all engage in a discussion about working together to do whatever we can to lessen the number of abortions performed and, certainly, to condemn houses of horror like this from every conceivable angle and shut them down immediately?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-problem-with-safe-legal-abortion/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Put the Top Down and Put This On</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/put-the-top-down-and-put-this-on</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/put-the-top-down-and-put-this-on#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 17:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Listening]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40385</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Spring arrived in full glory in Indianapolis today. The long drive home from church required an appropriate soundtrack. What better than one of the greatest albums of all time? It&#8217;s all sunshine and great grooves. It will come back to you.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Spring arrived in full glory in Indianapolis today. The long drive home from church required an appropriate soundtrack. What better than one of the greatest albums of all time? It&#8217;s all sunshine and great grooves.</p>
<p>It will come back to you.</p>
<p><iframe width="480" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/7ETwkwOMJ6A" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/put-the-top-down-and-put-this-on/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>In the Garden</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/in-the-garden</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/in-the-garden#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40339</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I come to the garden alone While the dew is still on the roses And the voice I hear falling on my ear The Son of God discloses. Je­sus said to her, “Mary!” Just one word from his lips, and for­got­ten the heart­aches, the long drea­ry hours….all the past blot­ted out in the pre­sence of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_40340" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 572px"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Christ-appearing-Ryder-e1365896633290.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-40340 " alt="Christ appearing Ryder" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Christ-appearing-Ryder-e1365896633290.jpg" width="562" height="387" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Christ Appearing to Mary (detail), Ryder</p></div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>I come to the garden alone<br />
While the dew is still on the roses<br />
And the voice I hear falling on my ear<br />
The Son of God discloses.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Je­sus said to her, “Mary!” Just one word from his lips, and for­got­ten the heart­aches, the long drea­ry hours….all the past blot­ted out in the pre­sence of the Liv­ing Pre­sent and the Eter­nal Fu­ture.</p>
<p style="text-align: right; padding-left: 30px;"><small>- C. Austin Miles, 1912</small></p>
<p style="text-align: center; padding-left: 30px;">* * *</p>
<p>The hymn <a href="http://cyberhymnal.org/htm/i/t/g/itgarden.htm"><em>&#8220;In the Garden&#8221;</em> </a>has caught a lot of flak over the years for its sentimentality and its &#8220;me and Jesus&#8221; lyrics. One critic who expressed his conviction that the church has forsaken a robust hymnology and replaced it with insipid ditties bewailed it as a &#8220;mawkish little rhyme about someone’s personal experience and feelings.&#8221;</p>
<p>I get the criticism, but I also understand why some people find comfort in a hymn like <em>&#8220;In the Garden.&#8221;</em> It was my grandfather&#8217;s favorite and we sang it at his funeral service years ago. As a hospice chaplain I am asked to include it in such services regularly. I don&#8217;t care for its waltzy tune (especially when played on a bad organ at the wrong tempo), and the refrain tends to distract from the Gospel story on which it is based. Still, it is based on a vivid and memorable resurrection appearance which took place in a garden, and the mood of the biblical narrative is also tender and personal.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>But Mary stood just outside the tomb, and she was crying. And as she cried, she looked into the tomb and saw two angels in white who sat, one at the head and the other at the foot of the place where the body of Jesus had lain.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>The angels spoke to her, “Why are you crying?” they asked. “Because they have taken away my Lord, and I don’t know where they have put him!” she said.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Then she turned and noticed Jesus standing there, without realising that it was Jesus.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>“Why are you crying?” said Jesus to her. “Who are you looking for?” She, supposing that he was the gardener, said, “Oh, sir, if you have carried him away, please tell me where you have put him and I will take him away.”</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Jesus said to her, “Mary!” At this she turned right round and said to him, in Hebrew, “Master!”</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: right;"><em>- John 20:11-16 (Phillips)</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Christ-appearing-Ryder-e1365898863473.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-40340" alt="Christ appearing Ryder" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Christ-appearing-Ryder-e1365898863473-203x300.jpg" width="203" height="300" /></a>The Gospel of John has long been favored by evangelicals and those who emphasize a &#8220;personal relationship&#8221; with Jesus because it is filled with intimate encounters like this one. John portrays Jesus as one constantly engaged in conversation with individuals, speaking words of salvation and peace.</p>
<p>Whatever concerns I have about evangelical<em>ism</em>, I don&#8217;t ever want to lose this. One thing the resurrection means is that Jesus <em>&#8220;walks with me and he talks with me, and he tells me I am his own.&#8221; </em>In the Upper Room, the Savior made promises to his disciples about what the resurrection would mean for them, and he spoke in the most personal and tender of terms:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>&#8220;No, I will not abandon you as orphans—I will come to you. Soon the world will no longer see me, but you will see me. Since I live, you also will live. When I am raised to life again, you will know that I am in my Father, and you are in me, and I am in you. Those who accept my commandments and obey them are the ones who love me. And because they love me, my Father will love them. And I will love them and reveal myself to each of them.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: right;"><em>- John 14:19-21, NLT</em></p>
<p>So then, one of the quiet, unexpected features of Christ&#8217;s majestic victory over the forces of sin, death, and hell is that he applies his great triumph by meeting us individually, in quiet places, whispering our names, and assuring us that we are not alone.</p>
<p>I understand why people might want that sentiment expressed at a funeral.</p>
<p>I can see why I might need that today.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><small><strong>Not What We Might Expect</strong><br />
<em>A Series for Sundays in Eastertide, 2</em></small></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/in-the-garden/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brennan Manning</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/40334</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/40334#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 20:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Noted]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40334</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Brennan Manning April 27, 1934 – April 12, 2013 “Suffering, failure, loneliness, sorrow, discouragement, and death will be part of your journey, but the Kingdom of God will conquer all these horrors. No evil can resist grace forever.” Richard Francis Xavier Manning, better known to legions of faithful readers as author, speaker, and contemplative Brennan [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/b-manning.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40335" alt="b manning" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/b-manning.jpg" width="560" height="573" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://brennanmanning.com/"><strong>Brennan Manning</strong></a><br />
April 27, 1934 – April 12, 2013</p>
<p><i>“Suffering, failure, loneliness, sorrow, discouragement, and death will be part of your journey, but the Kingdom of God will conquer all these horrors. No evil can resist grace forever.”</i></p>
<p>Richard Francis Xavier Manning, better known to legions of faithful readers as author, speaker, and contemplative Brennan Manning, for whom grace was irresistible, completed his earthly journey on Friday, April 12 at 12:10AM.  He is now resting safely in the arms of his Abba.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/40334/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lillian Daniel: Every Spiritual Home (a Riff)</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/lillian-daniel-every-spiritual-home</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/lillian-daniel-every-spiritual-home#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 16:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Riffs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40282</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Excerpt from the chapter, &#8220;Every Spiritual Home&#8221; From: When &#8220;Spiritual but Not Religious&#8221; Is Not Enough: Seeing God in Surprising Places, Even the Church by Lillian Daniel Jericho Books, 2013 * * * These days, very few people who join our church were raised in the denomination or tradition we are a part of, and we are [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/8417820695_8f1d687f5a_z.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40289" alt="8417820695_8f1d687f5a_z" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/8417820695_8f1d687f5a_z.jpg" width="512" height="342" /></a></p>
<p><em>Excerpt from the chapter, <strong>&#8220;Every Spiritual Home&#8221;</strong></em></p>
<p>From: <strong><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1455523089/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1455523089&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=goonewdai-20">When &#8220;Spiritual but Not Religious&#8221; Is Not Enough: Seeing God in Surprising Places, Even the Church</a></strong><img style="border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=goonewdai-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1455523089" width="1" height="1" border="0" /><br />
<em>by Lillian Daniel</em></p>
<p>Jericho Books, 2013</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-40284" alt="When-Spiritual-But-Not-Religious-199x300" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/When-Spiritual-But-Not-Religious-199x300.jpg" width="199" height="300" /></p>
<p>These days, very few people who join our church were raised in the denomination or tradition we are a part of, and we are hardly unique in that. Most of my church members were raised in other forms of Christianity that were less open-minded than ours, and they may have some negative feelings about the church of their childhood. And so they drifted from church and sought to go it alone, without a faith community.</p>
<p>But eventually they hit something that was bigger than private, self-created spirituality. Perhaps it was the death of a parent, the birth of a child, a friend&#8217;s illness, or a lonely patch in life, but suddenly they found themselves remembering some of those childhood Bible lessons. They found themselves recalling the blessings of the Christian faith, and they searched for a church, but they did so very tentatively, not knowing what they would find and afraid of being hurt.</p>
<p>&#8230;A miraculous thing can happen to grown-ups on a faith journey. We come to appreciate moments from our past faith community, as different as it may be from our current one. We may recall a special Sunday school teacher who taught us the &#8220;sacred writings&#8221; in our childhood.</p>
<p>That is why when people join our church, we always say, &#8220;We give thanks for every community that has ever been your spiritual home.&#8221;</p>
<p>I believe that there really is a connection between who we were raised to be and who we are now. It might not be a straight line, but you can connect the dots. God works through all kinds of religious communities at different points in our lives.</p>
<p>&#8230;So give thanks for the small and tender blessings of every place that has ever been your spiritual home, and for lessons you have learned.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span id="more-40282"></span></p>
<p><em>Begin riff&#8230;</em><img class=" wp-image-40302 alignright" alt="8627877255_1c473ecc6c_h" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/8627877255_1c473ecc6c_h-e1365863593209.jpg" width="286" height="306" /></p>
<p>Building on Lillian Daniel&#8217;s gracious words, I would like to give thanks for those along the way who contributed to my spiritual journey&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">To the United Methodists who baptized me into God&#8217;s family, taught me Bible stories in Sunday school, showed me what reverence and beauty looks like in worship and church architecture, planted the seeds of a deep love for church music in my heart, confirmed me in the faith and first fed me the Bread of life in communion, I say, &#8220;Thank you.&#8221;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">To the Southern Baptists who reawakened me when I was a troubled teenager by putting into the hearts of their own flawed yet loving young people a spirit of reaching out to others and saying the name Jesus, then pointing me to the Bible and inviting me to immerse myself in God&#8217;s Story, I say, &#8220;Thank you.&#8221;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">To the various small or non-denominational, fundamentalist, and dispensational churches who supported the Bible college I attended, encouraging and supporting them to train pastors, teachers, and missionaries to learn, love, and live out the Bible&#8217;s teachings, I say, &#8220;Thank you.&#8221; Though I now think that many of those teachings are off-base and cannot be supported by a serious study of the Scriptures, you taught me to study, to love God and his Word, and to seek truth in its words and stories. I&#8217;m studying more than ever today, seeking truth more passionately than ever, and trying to communicate the Message more effectively than ever, and you provided the spark. Thank you.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">To the small Baptist church in the hills, the parish in the mountains, the steeple rising high above the village, the people of the land who welcomed a clueless young pastor and put up with his immaturity and loved back twice for all the love he gave you, I have nothing but thanks.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">To the little city church in the far northern suburbs, the church of refugees where we made life-long friends, among whom we had our children, where I completed my formal education and continued to learn through practice, failure, and the messy process of growing into adulthood, there is little to say but, &#8220;Thank you.&#8221;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">To the Evangelical Free Church in America, whose pastors and teachers led me to a new level of love for Jesus and the Scriptures. You tended me through seminary, when I was struggling to balance the demands of a growing family, work, church involvement, and Masters level study. I tried to develop a life-long relationship with you, and wondered often why it never happened as I thought it should. Now I see that you were another important community along the way that showed me hospitality, grace, and gave me important gifts, only to send me on to other places. That was necessary for my life and my growth, and I say, &#8220;Thank you,&#8221; for playing an essential role in my journey.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">To the non-denominational churches, Wesleyan in spirit, mission-minded, pragmatic and church-growth oriented, in which I served for over fifteen years, I am indebted to you for your hospitality, generosity, and the many friendships I gained while among you. You helped my family settle into the only homes we&#8217;ve ever owned. You sent me around the world on mission trips. You affirmed my teaching and pastoral gifts. And though we ultimately parted and I have often criticized you, I owe you much thanks. You served as the incubator in which God put me through the hardest testings I&#8217;ve ever known. It is not right for me to resent you for that, though sometimes I do. So if my thanks still comes across as emanating from a heart full of mixed feelings, please try to understand. Try to hear the following words, because I do mean them: &#8220;Thank you.&#8221;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">To the Lutheran congregations that are now providing me a home, &#8220;Thank you.&#8221; In some ways, I feel like Dorothy must have felt after having been to Oz and back. I&#8217;m home, but home is different, and I am different too. I&#8217;m still trying to get my bearings; I&#8217;m still learning to walk again. I&#8217;m frightened and have little or no self-confidence. I am not sure I have any idea what I&#8217;m doing or where I am going, but you are providing space for me to figure that out. Your historic teachings, liturgy, and sacraments are like leg braces for me at the moment, providing the support I need to walk forward. And who knows where the future leads? In the meantime, I thank you for grace, for welcome, for guidance, and for showing me the promise of a land beyond the wilderness.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/lillian-daniel-every-spiritual-home/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saturday Ramblings 4.13.13</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-4-13-13</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-4-13-13#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 04:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saturday Ramblings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40294</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is Saturday again? Already? We just had Saturday a week ago. And we will most likely have another one next week. Well, why not? I mean, we have to have Mondays every week. It&#8217;s only fair we have Saturdays as well. As I matter of fact, I propose we have two Saturdays for every [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Rambler21.jpeg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-38060" alt="Rambler" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Rambler21-300x200.jpeg" width="300" height="200" /></a>It is Saturday again? Already? We just had Saturday a week ago. And we will most likely have another one next week. Well, why not? I mean, we have to have Mondays every week. It&#8217;s only fair we have Saturdays as well. As I matter of fact, I propose we have two Saturdays for every one Monday. What do you think? I may just run for emperor on that platform. In the meantime, what do you say we spend this Saturday rambling?</p>
<p>Joel Osteen, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/09/joel-osteen-hoax-discredit-televangelist-lost-religion_n_3044562.html" target="_blank"><strong>former Christian</strong></a>? A web site that looked a lot like the real thing&#8212;although the address was <a href="http://www.joelostenministries.com/">www.joelostenministries.com</a> (don&#8217;t bother&#8212;it has been taken down) which was deliberately misspelled&#8212;featured a <a href="http://www.chron.com/news/houston-texas/houston/article/Joel-Osteen-target-of-elaborate-Internet-hoax-4418266.php" target="_blank"><strong>letter</strong> </a>supposedly from the Houston minister declaring he was leaving Christianity. The man behind the hoax says he&#8217;s a fan of Osteen, he just thinks Osteen is a <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/headlines/2013/04/joel-osteen-too-shallow-for-man-behind-internet-hoax/" target="_blank"><strong>little shallow</strong></a>. Kind of like how the Atlantic Ocean is a little deep.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a rapper by the name of <a href="http://blog.christianitytoday.com/ctliveblog/archives/2013/04/reformed-rapper-shai-linne-false-teachers-joel-osteen-joyce-meyer-td-jakes.html" target="_blank"><strong>Shai Linne</strong></a> has a new song out titled &#8220;Fal$e Teacher$.&#8221; In this song he names names of those he considers false teachers. <em>&#8220;Don’t be deceived by this funny biz, if you come to Jesus for money, then he’s not your God, money is! Jesus is not a means to an end, the Gospel is He came to redeem us from sin, and that is the message forever I yell! If you’re living your best life now you’re heading for hell!”</em> I guess I just don&#8217;t get rap music. Do they always pull their punches like this? I find it very interesting that he laments how the American prosperity gospel is infecting churches in Africa. Your thoughts?</p>
<p><span id="more-40294"></span></p>
<p>I have thought for some time we might need to have a good conversation about Christians and guns. Here is a very good starting place. Perhaps we will visit this topic in more detail at a future date. For now, <a href="http://religion.blogs.cnn.com/2013/04/10/my-take-the-thin-line-between-god-and-guns/" target="_blank"><strong>think on these words</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Just what the world has been waiting for. A <a href="http://www.thenewamerican.com/culture/education/item/15060-ron-paul-announces-phase-2-of-the-revolution-a-new-homeschooling-program" target="_blank"><strong>Ron Paul-branded homeschool curriculum</strong></a>. It is designed to teach our little darlings &#8220;the biblical principle of self-government and personal responsibility, which is also the foundation of the free-market economy.&#8221; And what Bible is he finding this stuff in? Still, you know Christian homeschooling parents will simply hear &#8220;biblical principles&#8221; and eat this stuff up, while forcefeeding it on their children. Do we really need a new generation of Christians schooled in self-government? Discuss.</p>
<p>The Supreme Commander of the Baptist culture wars, <a href="http://www.religionnews.com/2013/04/12/richard-land-controversial-southern-baptist-leader-gets-a-new-job/    " target="_blank"><strong>Richard Land</strong></a>, has a new job. He is soon to take over as head of Southern Evangelical Seminary in Charlotte, North Carolina. His mission?  “My goal is to join with the SES family to produce an ever increasing number of graduates who will be the green berets and paratroopers of God’s army.” Paratroopers? Did he really say paratroopers? We may have a new source of great Ramblings material in Charlotte.</p>
<p>Not that there is any lack of fun stuff coming from the Tar Heel state. First some state legislators wanted to declare an official North Carolina state religion (It was going to be Christianity. Who knew? I thought it would have been NASCAR.). Now a <a href="http://projects.newsobserver.com/node/27309" target="_blank"><strong>state legislator</strong></a> likens Muslims who pray to terrorists. You know how every family has a black sheep? The wool doesn&#8217;t get much darker than what is being knit in North Carolina right now. I think Richard Land is going to fit right in, don&#8217;t you?</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the new president of <a href="http://www.tulsaworld.com/article.aspx/Incoming_ORU_president_talks_broken_generation_with/20130406_18_A1_CUTLIN585244" target="_blank"><strong>Oral Roberts University</strong></a> (full disclosure: my alma mater) seems firmly committed to taking the school back into the 1990s with his culture war rhetoric. It is getting harder and harder for me to think of a reason students should consider many Christian colleges.</p>
<p>A city in Poland has erected a <a href="http://bigstory.ap.org/article/giant-john-paul-ii-statute-readied-unveiling  " target="_blank"><strong>45-foot-tall statue</strong></a> of Blessed John Paul II, with its arms outstretched. What does this remind you of? Are you humming <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Mf2u9VWAhM" target="_blank"><strong>Big Butter Jesus</strong></a> to yourself now?</p>
<p>The Synonymous Rambler brought to my attention a Romanian lawyer who is suing his priest for failing to exorcise <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2304985/Romanian-lawyer-sues-bishop-priests-claiming-failed-properly-exorcise-flatulent-demons-house.html" target="_blank"><strong>flatulent demons</strong> </a>from his house. You know, I wish I could make stuff like this up. I really do. And who doesn&#8217;t think Flatulent Demons wouldn&#8217;t make for a great song title&#8212;it could be the flip side of Shai Linne&#8217;s Fal$e Teacher$. This week&#8217;s Ramblings Challenge: Come up with the lyrics for a song called Flatulent Demons. Then sing it in your worship service tomorrow &#8230;</p>
<p>Before we get to this week&#8217;s birthdays, we note with sadness the passing of three Christian authors and thinkers. <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/local/obituaries/j-david-kuo-onetime-leader-of-bushs-faith-based-initiative-dies-at-44/2013/04/06/24e9cd6a-987e-11e2-97cd-3d8c1afe4f0f_story.html" target="_blank"><strong>David Kuo</strong></a> served as the deputy director of President George W. Bush&#8217;s office of faith-based initiatives. After Kuo left that post, he became a vocal critic of the Bush administration, saying they did not live what they were preaching.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.christianitytoday.com/ct/2013/april-web-only/john-mccandlish-phillips-bright-light-for-christ-in-big-app.html" target="_blank"><strong>John McCandlish Phillips</strong></a> was a star reporter for the New York Times, gaining his fame by writing an article exposing the Orthodox Jewish roots of a leader of the Ku Klux Klan. After the article appeared, the Klansman committed suicide, which Phillips saw as God&#8217;s judgment at work. Phillips left the Times to be a campus preacher in New York.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.nowtheendbegins.com/blog/?p=13658" target="_blank"><strong>Dave Hunt</strong></a> was an author and teacher specializing in end times prophecy. He was not afraid of naming names. Nor was he afraid of bending Scripture to meet his predetermined opinions. Hunt was passionate for Jesus, even though he missed the ocean of God&#8217;s grace by focusing on his Dixie cup of news events he thought were important.</p>
<p>Birthday cards were opened this last week by my beautiful daughter Rebekah Cypert; Merle Haggard; Billy Dee Williams; Walter Winchell; Percy Faith; James Garner; Wayne Rogers; Betty Ford; Ward Bond; Carl Perkins; Cheetah; Harry Morgan; Chuck Connors; David Halberstam; Brian Setzer; Robert Fripp; and David Letterman.</p>
<p>So, I mentioned this rapper named Shai Linne. I am not a fan of rap. (Nor am I a fan of modern country music. Mix the two together&#8212;country and rap&#8212;and what do you get? Right. Crap.) But I kind of like this. And that is saying a lot, coming from this old, white rambler. Enjoy.</p>
<iframe width="640" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/NIjuRfldwTE" frameborder="0" type="text/html"></iframe><div style="text-align:right;"><a style="color:#aaa;font-size:9px" href="http://www.clickonf5.org/" title="IFRAME Embed for Youtube Free WordPress Plugin" target="_blank">IFRAME Embed for Youtube</a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-4-13-13/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>iMonk: Doing the Math</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/imonk-doing-the-math</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/imonk-doing-the-math#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 04:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>iMonk</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Michael Spencer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40277</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A classic Michael Spencer post from April, 2009. I’m not very good at math, and I’m worse at being a Jesus follower, but even a stopped clock is right twice a day. I starting doing some personal math this morning as I started my day, and I made a discovery. I could no longer deny [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/abacus-e1365741828293.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40279" alt="abacus" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/abacus-e1365741828293.jpg" width="508" height="274" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/thoughts-after-doing-the-math"><strong>A classic Michael Spencer post from April, 2009</strong></a>.</p>
<p>I’m not very good at math, and I’m worse at being a Jesus follower, but even a stopped clock is right twice a day.</p>
<p>I starting doing some personal math this morning as I started my day, and I made a discovery.</p>
<p>I could no longer deny that a lot of things add up in my life; they add up to an area where sin has taken a deep root.</p>
<p>The last few months, I keep bumping into the same kind of feedback in my immediate environment from people who know me and observe me. When I first heard it, I was angry and defensive. I should know right away that defensive is a signal all is not well.</p>
<p>That feedback may not have been flawless, but I’m not convinced some of it is true.</p>
<p>A number of relationships changed, and I blamed the other persons. I’m not “unblaming” them entirely now, but I see something I didn’t see before.</p>
<p>I began to notice the interactions I had with other people, and I discerned some patterns. Not random patterns, but intentional patterns. There was something THERE that people were moving around; something that was playing a big role in those interactions. Something that was part of me.</p>
<p>I began to look at the places where my life was going well, and was surprised to find many areas where this kind of sin would be rewarded.</p>
<p>I looked at my ministry, and I saw that this sin serves me pragmatically and allows me to be an effective leader, especially in some aspects of my particular situation.</p>
<p>My personality isn’t always the clearest picture to me, but it became clearer. The established patterns of my life began to show me a kind of person and a pattern of behavior, all held together by the sin that was being revealed to me.</p>
<p>I thought back on my life history, and considered where this sin began to be part of my life and why; I traced its impact from the past to the present.</p>
<p>I began to understand the common thread that held together many separate strands in my life experience: I was protecting a pattern and preference for a sin that I believed defined my life.</p>
<p>Life in Jesus is a life of repentance, but I come from a tradition where sin is always behavior. Doing bad things. Sinning against the example of righteousness. The sins that arise from the components of our own personality- the acceptable, even valued ones- are much deeper to repent of. Some even applaud and reward certain patterns of sin.</p>
<p>How do you repent of what is making your life work?</p>
<p>How do you repent of what people expect you to do and be?</p>
<p>How do you repent of your self-image, your security and your identity?</p>
<p>How do you repent of sins that have grown essential to your being and life?</p>
<p>How do you repent of sins that the very repentance of them will cause you to lose support and encouragement?</p>
<p>When I do the math, when I put on the special glasses of Gospel realism, I see a disease and a man in denial. I see a sin addict in need of a group. I see a person whose engagement in sin and life in ministry are deeply entwined.</p>
<p>Christ forgives. Sin is defeated. We are part of the new creation. But my sin hasn’t left quietly. It’s convinced me that without it, I’m too vulnerable to do without it.</p>
<p>Christ showed me these things. Jesus showed me because he wants to be my security, my identity, my everything. He does not beat me down over this situation, but invites me into repentance in love, kindness and compassion. The wounds of Jesus are to change this situation and to change me. But I need community, because this is a fearful revelation. I wonder what life would be like on the other side of a pattern of living that has become identical with being Michael Spencer.</p>
<p>But that’s the journey with Jesus. That’s the narrow path, the treasure in the field, the dying all day long. It’s the only place to go because he has the words of eternal life.</p>
<p>But I need a community. Maybe you do too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/imonk-doing-the-math/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>When The Pain Becomes Too Much To Bear</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/when-the-pain-becomes-too-much-to-bear</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/when-the-pain-becomes-too-much-to-bear#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 04:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40269</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Just the pain, the excruciating pain, was just too much.&#8221; These were the words of a friend of Matthew Warren when he learned that Warren, the son of Rick and Kay Warren, took his own life last Friday. I know that pain all too well. I have been honest with you about my battle with [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/VanGogh_Depression.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-40270" alt="VanGogh_Depression" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/VanGogh_Depression-798x1024.jpg" width="358" height="459" /></a>&#8220;Just the pain, the excruciating pain, was just too much.&#8221;</p>
<p>These were the words of a friend of Matthew Warren when he learned that Warren, the son of Rick and Kay Warren, took his own life last Friday. I know that pain all too well.</p>
<p>I have been honest with you about my battle with depression. It has not gotten any easier or better. And yes, sometimes the pain, the excruciating pain, just gets too much. I would much rather suffer physical pain than this emotional pain. Matthew Warren, a Christian who came from a loving home and had access to medical and spiritual help, could no longer bear his pain. Statistically, another American ended his/her own life seventeen minutes prior to Warren&#8217;s suicide, and another seventeen minutes after. Eighty six people in the United States take their own lives each day, while another 2,150 attempt to kill themselves. And this does not take into account all of those who walk through their days suffering from depression, feeling as if their soul is in a vice and their life is being slowly suffocated.</p>
<p>But statistics don&#8217;t feel pain, only people do. And mental illness does not avoid those who check the &#8220;Christian&#8221; box on their census forms. I guarandamntee you that at least one person in your pew or row at church this Sunday will be one who is suffering from depression or another mental illness. No matter the size of your congregation, chances are very good that at least one person in worship with you this Sunday has had suicidal thoughts in the last six months. And while we will gladly (and rightly) declare ourselves pro-life and take a stand for the unborn, we cower in ignorance and fear when confronted by someone who has emotional pain that could cause them to take their own life.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>As to mental maladies, is any man altogether sane? Are we not all a little off the balance?</em> C.H. Spurgeon</p></blockquote>
<p>I really don&#8217;t want to join the growing chorus at this time saying that the church needs to do more for the mentally ill in their midst. Yes, that is true in a broad sense, but once again, the &#8220;church&#8221; is not going to be the one to help. It is the people who make up the church that must be God&#8217;s hand extended to those who are hurting. And these human hands are just that, human hands, imperfect and flawed and clueless. Yet it is these hands the Lord uses, or wants to use. So I want to address three people in this mess of life that involves pain so severe it can result in death.</p>
<p><span id="more-40269"></span></p>
<p><strong>First of all, pastors.</strong> You are not a leader, you are not a director, you are not a spokesman. You are a pastor, a shepherd. There is nothing, not one thing, that matters more than your sheep. Nothing. Forget everything else but the sheep in your care. Sheep get sick, and if you don&#8217;t care for them, they will die. Yet since you are most likely not a licensed counselor or medical professional, just how are you going to care for the sick sheep?</p>
<p>Certainly prayer. By all means, prayer. And helping them to know how God sees them is vital. For so many caught in the web of depression, the spider that is closing in on them is doubt and despair. Doubt that God cares, that he even knows who they are or that they are in agony. They may have seen God clearly for much of their lives, but now the clouds are so thick they wonder if he ever existed. Your job is to turn their eyes from themselves to God. This is not easy. It will take time and patience and tender fierceness.</p>
<p>More than anything, you just need to be there for them. Not just once or twice, and not just when you see the on Sundays. Go to them, even if they don&#8217;t want to see you. See them anyway. Sit with them. Listen to their stories. Stay. Be. Care. That is what a shepherd does. And you are a shepherd.</p>
<p><strong>Next, laymen.</strong> You are just as useful to God in bringing healing as the shepherd is. Maybe more. After all, if my pastor were to come see me (which he hasn&#8217;t, but that is another story), I might think that he was just fulfilling his duty. But when my friend Mike calls to tell me he is coming over to watch baseball with me and bringing ice cream, I know it&#8217;s not because he is being paid to do so. It&#8217;s because he knows I am suffering and he wants to help bring healing. (When I told him I was feeling the effects of depression, he said he didn&#8217;t think it was depression, just a recession, and with any luck we&#8217;d get through it without anymore layoffs. I told him to shut up and pass the ice cream.) You won&#8217;t have to look very far to find someone suffering from depression in your workplace, your neighborhood, your school or your church. (And if you can&#8217;t find anyone, you can come be my friend.) And just like the commercials that say you don&#8217;t have to be perfect to be a Big Brother, just willing, the same goes here. You don&#8217;t have to be a medical professional or professional minister to give aid to one suffering from depression. You just have to be willing. I don&#8217;t want someone to come over and try to &#8220;fix&#8221; me.  I just want friends who will love me and be with me.</p>
<p>I wrote earlier about how lousy Christians are at loving one another, even though that is the one mark Jesus said will identify us as his followers. I talked about how few people I have had who are willing to say &#8220;I love you&#8221; or just come be with me. This week I had breakfast with a friend who apologized for not being there for me, and said &#8220;I love you.&#8221; With him, that brings me up to a total of &#8230; three. Three people from my church who have said &#8220;I love you and will walk with you as you go through this.&#8221;  I can count two or three other friends who also are there to encourage me (like Mike, who goes to a different church than I do, and my former coworker Smokey) and show me love. There are others, however, who, for whatever reason, don&#8217;t want to say &#8220;I love you&#8221; or cannot find time to just be with me. There are those who say, &#8220;If you are ever having a bad day, call me,&#8221; not understanding that someone in depression can&#8217;t even pick up the phone and call. So if you are going to be used of God to bring healing, you will have to do the calling. It will most likely be inconvenient and tedious to go sit with someone who is not the life of the party. Do it anyway.</p>
<p><strong>Finally, the one who is depressed.</strong> You are sick, just as someone with diabetes or cancer is sick. You can&#8217;t just &#8220;get over it.&#8221; You need help. You need medical help. You need counseling. Both of these are necessary (and I am receiving help from my doctor and from a professional counselor). You also need spiritual help at this time, and that is going to be more difficult. If you have a true shepherd at your church, one who is willing to tend to sick and lost sheep (which, by definition, is all sheep), then count yourself among the fortunate few. If you attend a church with a leader or a celebrity or someone other than a pastor, you are going to have to look elsewhere. But do look. You don&#8217;t need someone who is a gifted speaker or a noted theologian. You need a patient listener who will help you to see through the clouds to the One who has never left you and never will leave you.</p>
<p>You may find it hard to keep going to church, to face those who smile and seemingly have no cares beyond beating the Presbyterians to Applebees for lunch. Forget them. Instead, find someone else who is hurting and give them a hug. You will know that one when you see him. He will look just like you.</p>
<p>Here are some additional essays/stories to read on this topic.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.christianitytoday.com/ct/2009/march/15.22.html" target="_blank"><strong>The Depression Epidemic</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.haventoday.org/spurgeon-on-depression-gd-434.html" target="_blank"><strong>Spurgeon On Depression</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/articles/D/depression.html" target="_blank"><strong>The Boat In The Backyard</strong> </a>(Michael Spencer)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/when-the-pain-becomes-too-much-to-bear/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>73</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mistakes We Make about Faith</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/mistakes-we-make-about-faith</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/mistakes-we-make-about-faith#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 04:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40260</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We mistakenly understand faith when we&#8230; Confuse having faith with having certainty. Forget Jesus said faith that is only the size of a mustard seed avails much. Fail to recognize how much our fears shape our faith. Think that having a hearty or mature faith means I have strong opinions about lots of different issues. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/tree-of-life-beach.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40262" alt="tree of life beach" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/tree-of-life-beach.png" width="540" height="277" /></a></p>
<p>We mistakenly understand faith when we&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Confuse having faith with having certainty.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Forget Jesus said faith that is only the size of a mustard seed avails much.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Fail to recognize how much our fears shape our faith.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Think that having a hearty or mature faith means I have strong opinions about lots of different issues.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Trust in our faith rather than in the One who is the object of our faith.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Think of faith like currency that can buy us favors from God.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Imagine that having faith will give us &#8220;answers&#8221; to life&#8217;s perplexing questions.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Forget that Jesus helped the one who said, &#8220;I believe; help my unbelief.&#8221;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Fail to recognize how much our personalities, experiences, and relationships affect the way we think about faith and exercise it.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Equate faith with positive thinking and presume that faith and failure cannot go together.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Think that faith is only an individual thing and that I cannot ever be carried by the faith of others.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Conceive of faith only as an inner, &#8220;spiritual&#8221; reality, and divorce it from the sacraments and actual Christian practices we perform in the body.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Imagine that faith enables us to avoid or overcome suffering.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Presume that faith can only grow in religious soil, through influences that are specifically pious or devotional in nature.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>What are your comments on these statements?</p>
<p>Are there any that you would alter or refine?</p>
<p>Do you have some of your own that you would add?</p>
<p>Do you have any examples that might shed light on how we sometimes carry the wrong idea of having faith?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/mistakes-we-make-about-faith/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>61</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>When Asking a Question Is Itself a Problem</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/40240</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/40240#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundamentalisms]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40240</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here is an exceedingly wise word from Samantha Field, in an interview she gave at the her.meneutics blog called, &#8220;Finding Faith after Spiritual Indoctrination.&#8221; I recommend the entire article. However, this part is essential reading, and I pull it out for our consideration and discussion today. * * * Spiritual abuse is so much more [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/follow_the_leader-e1365457525377.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-40242" alt="follow_the_leader" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/follow_the_leader-e1365457525377.jpg" width="400" height="237" /></a></p>
<p>Here is an exceedingly wise word from Samantha Field, in <a href="http://www.christianitytoday.com/women/2013/april/finding-faith-after-spiritual-indoctrination.html?paging=off"><strong>an interview she gave at the her.meneutics blog called, <em>&#8220;Finding Faith after Spiritual Indoctrination.&#8221;</em></strong></a></p>
<p>I recommend the entire article. However, this part is essential reading, and I pull it out for our consideration and discussion today.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Spiritual abuse is so much more common than many people think. It exists in so many forms, and it is incredibly easy to miss. And it happens where people are honestly trying to do the right thing, to follow Christ, to pursue godliness.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">It also happens when people stop asking why. Being handed a list of &#8220;this is what you should believe&#8221; is so very easy, especially when that list is handed to you by someone you respect. But when we stop asking questions, when we even begin to accept that asking questions is in itself a problem, that&#8217;s when we can surrender our faith into the hands of someone who could misuse it.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Many times when I explain my religious environment, the focus is the legalism, when legalism isn&#8217;t really the problem. It&#8217;s the power and control that legalism places in the hands of a select few. Fundamentalism, in my experience, frequently results in the congregation surrendering control over almost every area of their lives to their pastor. In a strange twist, while fundamentalists preach in the complete &#8220;sufficiency of Scripture,&#8221; in reality they practice whatever their pastor hands down from the pulpit.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">I also find it troubling that in discussions about faith, we seem to confuse &#8220;having faith&#8221; with &#8220;being certain.&#8221; I&#8217;m no longer comfortable with feeling certain about anything; certainty, I&#8217;ve found, is dangerous territory. It also bothers me when we frequently resort to statements like &#8220;the Bible is very clear on this issue,&#8221; or that a specific interpretation of a passage is &#8220;plain&#8221; or &#8220;obvious.&#8221; This type of language seems almost designed to shut down conversation, or to dismiss the speaker&#8217;s opposition.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">I think it&#8217;s important for us to stay receptive to new and challenging ideas. To honestly engage with a concept we don&#8217;t agree with, and see where it takes us. Instead of digging in even deeper when our faith system gets confronted, if we took a second to empathetically understand their perspective, we could have a change of heart and a change of mind. Being able to do this, I&#8217;m realizing, is much easier said than done. Most of the time when I&#8217;m challenged, I instantaneously start mounting a defense. It takes me a while to realize that instinctually defending your own idea almost automatically means you&#8217;re not really listening to&#8211; or trying to understand&#8211; another.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/40240/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic
Page Caching using disk: enhanced

 Served from: www.internetmonk.com @ 2013-04-15 07:31:14 by W3 Total Cache -->
