<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/" xmlns:creativeCommons="http://backend.userland.com/creativeCommonsRssModule" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>internetmonk.com</title>
	
	<link>http://www.internetmonk.com</link>
	<description>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 04:12:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
<!-- podcast_generator="Blubrry PowerPress/4.0.7" -->
	<itunes:summary>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:author>The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer</itunes:author>
	<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/monkposterx3.jpg" />
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer</itunes:name>
		<itunes:email>michael@internetmonk.com</itunes:email>
	</itunes:owner>
	<managingEditor>michael@internetmonk.com (The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer)</managingEditor>
	<copyright>2006-2009</copyright>
	<itunes:subtitle>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</itunes:subtitle>
	<image><link>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</link><url>http://creativecommons.org/images/public/somerights20.gif</url><title>Some Rights Reserved</title></image>
	<itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
		<itunes:category text="Christianity" />
	</itunes:category>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/internetmonk/SWqj" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="internetmonk/swqj" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license><feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">internetmonk/SWqj</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>Our Therapist, Who Art in Heaven</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/40465</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/40465#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 04:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theologia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40465</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;When God Is Your Therapist&#8221; By T. M. Luhrmann Published: April 13, 2013 New York Times * * * I have started reading T.H. Luhrmann&#8217;s book, When God Talks Back: Understanding the American Evangelical Relationship with God, and hope to be reviewing it soon. In the meantime, I noticed that she had an op-ed piece [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Psych-Couch.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40466" alt="Psych Couch" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Psych-Couch-e1366338445881.jpg" width="588" height="362" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/14/opinion/sunday/luhrmann-when-god-is-your-therapist.html?hp&amp;_r=0"><em><strong>&#8220;When God Is Your Therapist&#8221;</strong></em></a><br />
<em>By T. M. Luhrmann</em><br />
Published: April 13, 2013<br />
New York Times</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>I have started reading T.H. Luhrmann&#8217;s book, <strong><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0307277275/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0307277275&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=goonewdai-20">When God Talks Back: Understanding the American Evangelical Relationship with God</a></strong><img style="border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=goonewdai-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0307277275" width="1" height="1" border="0" />, and hope to be reviewing it soon. In the meantime, I noticed that she had an op-ed piece in the NYT Sunday Review last week (see link above) and thought it might provide some good grist for discussion.</p>
<p>In both her book and this article, Luhrmann, a professor of anthropology at Stanford University, describes how she spent time among evangelical Christians because of her interest &#8220;in the fact that people like me seemed to experience reality in a fundamentally different manner.&#8221; The piece at hand today describes how the evangelical churches help people deal with anxiety and stress in their lives through prayer.</p>
<p>The author likens what happens in evangelical settings to <a href="http://www.nacbt.org/whatiscbt.htm">cognitive-behavioral therapy</a>, which its practitioners characterize like this:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Cognitive-behavioral therapy is based on the idea that our thoughts cause our feelings and behaviors, not external things, like people, situations, and events. The benefit of this fact is that we can change the way we think to feel/act better even if the situation does not change.</em></p>
<p>Luhrmann cites the methodology of Rick Warren in <strong>The Purpose Driven Life</strong>, who, in her words, <em>&#8220;spells out thoughts he thinks his readers have but don’t want, and then asks them to consider themselves from God’s point of view: not as the inadequate people they feel themselves to be, but as loved, as relevant and as having purpose.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>What she observed in the churches was that congregation members were being encouraged to view their prayers &#8212; their conversations with God &#8212; in these same therapeutic terms. God is portrayed as a kind and welcoming Father and Friend, who invites us to share our concerns and struggles and helps us handle them.</p>
<p>She also notes that she saw this most clearly when tragedy struck and people avoided trying to give &#8220;answers&#8221; to theodicy questions and encouraged simply being with God, who would wrap his arms around them and give them comfort and strength. As a hospice chaplain, it was heartening for me to read that, for I have often seen people move much too quickly to the &#8220;answer bag,&#8221; where they pulled out clichés and pat solutions and unwisely applied them to those in deep pain. In the cases she observed, however, Luhrmann notes, <em>&#8220;for them, God is a relationship, not an explanation.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>She concludes that these churches are offering, in effect, <em>&#8220;a way of dealing with unhappiness.&#8221; </em> Instead of threatening faith, difficulties are presented as situations in which we can strengthen our connection to God because it is then that we feel our need of him most.</p>
<p><span id="more-40465"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/old-movie-psych-e1366342052459.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-40476" alt="old movie psych" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/old-movie-psych-e1366342052459-300x285.jpg" width="240" height="228" /></a>I came away from T.H. Luhrmann&#8217;s editorial with mixed feelings.</p>
<p>On the one hand, any increase in kindness, forbearance, and gentleness in the way our pastors and teachers encourage us to treat one another is welcome. Withholding judgment and pat answers, learning to listen, helping people recognize God and his love in the hidden places of suffering and pain, urging them to talk to him in prayer and to cast their burdens on him &#8212; these are salutary ways of walking with one another in love and compassion.</p>
<p>On the other hand, I can&#8217;t help but suspect that this commendable activity that T.H. Luhrmann is describing may be rooted in shallow soil. For it is not just a &#8220;relationship with a Friend&#8221; that we need when it comes to knowing God, it is faith to embrace the mystery that he doesn&#8217;t always show up as my Friend.</p>
<p>He doesn&#8217;t always appear to wrap his arms around me and speak words of peace. Sometimes the room stays dark and my own voice echoes back when I pray. Occasionally God comes to me with a stern voice, as he did to poor, suffering Job, sitting there in the dirt all pitiful, scratching his sores, and says,</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Why do you confuse the issue?</em><br />
<em> Why do you talk without knowing what you’re talking about?</em><br />
<em> Pull yourself together, Job!</em><br />
<em> Up on your feet! Stand tall!</em><br />
<em> I have some questions for you,</em><br />
<em> and I want some straight answers.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><small>- from Job 38, MSG</small></p>
<p>Or take a saint like Mother Teresa, whose memoirs shocked the world when she confessed that she had lived for years without feeling the conscious presence of God. My theology of the cross tells me that God hides himself in the most unlikely places, and that where we imagine he is, he is not, and where we cannot fathom he would be, there he is.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure God has hung the &#8220;Therapist&#8221; shingle on his door and that he&#8217;s on call 24/7 to fulfill that role.</p>
<p>And by the way, the most important question: where is <em>Jesus</em> &#8212; Christ and Lord, incarnate Son of God, proclaimer of the Kingdom, crucified, buried, risen, ascended into heaven, pouring out the Holy Spirit &#8212; in all of this?</p>
<p>However, apparently many believe in <em>&#8220;Our Therapist, who art in heaven,&#8221;</em> and that is what our churches are offering them. I am sure, as T.H. Luhrmann found, it is comforting and encouraging on one level. And as I said, I&#8217;m all for love and compassion.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m pretty sure, however, that this is not the Gospel.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/40465/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>CM’s Five for the Road</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/cms-five-for-the-road</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/cms-five-for-the-road#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Favorites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Listening]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40430</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[OK, my friend and colleague Jeff Dunn has upped the ante. In honor of his good friend Don Mann, I can understand why. Back in September of 2010, Jeff and I did dueling &#8220;Top Five Albums&#8221; posts here on IM (links below). Being the notorious wafflers we are, at that time we had to list [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/lp1-e1366261596826.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-40437" alt="lp" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/lp1-e1366261596826.jpg" width="421" height="241" /></a></p>
<p>OK, my friend and colleague Jeff Dunn has upped the ante. In honor of his good friend Don Mann, I can understand why. Back in September of 2010, Jeff and I did dueling <em>&#8220;Top Five Albums&#8221;</em> posts here on IM (links below). Being the notorious wafflers we are, at that time we had to list honorable mentions too, because everyone knows you can&#8217;t <em>really</em> just have five favorite albums.</p>
<p>Well, this morning Mr. Dunn took a public stand for five, and five only, essential albums in his collection. He wrote:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">In honor of Don’s homegoing, I want to settle my five selections once and for all. I am planting my flag here, and won’t change my tune (pun intended, if only because it would have gotten an eye-roll from Don). These are the five albums I would listen to repeatedly if I could only have five. Mind you, I’m not saying these are the five best albums of all time. But if I am driving cross-country and can only listen to five, load these up and I will be very happy.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s step back into the Wayback Machine and see how Jeff and I voted a few years ago:</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/my-five-favorite-albums"><strong>Jeff&#8217;s Choices in 2010</strong></a>:</p>
<ol>
<li>Drunkard&#8217;s Prayer, Over the Rhine</li>
<li>Pet Sounds, The Beach Boys</li>
<li>Eat a Peach, The Allman Brothers</li>
<li>The Misfit, Erick Nelson &amp; Michele Pillar</li>
<li>Exile on Main St., The Rolling Stones</li>
</ol>
<p><em>Honorable Mentions:</em> Everybody Knows This Is Nowhere (Neil Young), Shotgun Angel (Daniel Amos), Songs in the Key of Life (Stevie Wonder), Sticks and Stones (77&#8242;s), The Bells of Dublin (Chieftains), Blood on the Tracks (Dylan), Live at the New Earth (Waterdeep).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/and-five-of-my-favorite-albums"><strong>Chaplain Mike&#8217;s Choices in 2010</strong></a>:</p>
<ol>
<li>Love Broke Thru, Phil Keaggy</li>
<li>Blue, Joni Mitchell</li>
<li>Still Life (Talking), Pat Metheny Group</li>
<li>Sky Blue Sky, Wilco</li>
<li>Graceland, Paul Simon</li>
</ol>
<p><em>Honorable Mentions:</em> Sgt. Pepper (Beatles), Blonde on Blonde (Dylan), Pet Sounds (Beach Boys), Thriller (Michael Jackson), Live at Fillmore East (Allman Bros.).</p></blockquote>
<p>Earlier today, Jeff &#8220;settled his selections once and for all&#8221; with these five:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Eat a Peach</strong>, <em>The Allman Brothers</em></li>
<li><strong>Exile on Main Street</strong>, <em>The Rolling Stones</em></li>
<li><strong>Songs in the Key of Life</strong>, <em>Stevie Wonder</em></li>
<li><strong>Troubadour of the Great King</strong>, <em>John Michael Talbot</em></li>
<li><strong>The Misfit</strong>, <em>Erick Nelson &amp; Michele Pillar</em></li>
</ol>
<p>Well, my friend, thanks for allowing me to become part of this discussion today. I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;m ready to take the &#8220;settled once and for all&#8221; position yet, but there is nothing more fun for baby boomers to do than to talk about the music of our generation (and since). You had some great picks, and of course I think mine are better.</p>
<p>And by the way, I&#8217;d love to take a road trip with you &#8212; you play your five and I&#8217;ll play mine. Can&#8217;t think of anything more fun. Of course, we&#8217;ll hit all the ballparks along the way (but that&#8217;s another discussion).</p>
<p>So, fire up the engine and slip on those sunglasses. Time to hit the road, buddy, and here&#8217;s my soundtrack (in alphabetical order):</p>
<p><span id="more-40430"></span></p>
<p>Chaplain Mike&#8217;s &#8220;Five for the Road&#8221; &#8211;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>Aja, <em>Steely Dan</em></strong><br />
Are you kidding me? Nobody, I mean nobody had ever heard sound engineering like this in 1977. It still sounds state of the art today. Plus, when you choose 40 of the best studio players and singers, let Fagen and Becker arrange them in &#8220;bands&#8221; to get the best combinations for each song, and craft each piece to perfection, you end up with one of the greatest collections of jazz-rock-pop ever. <em>&#8220;Peg&#8221;</em> would be the perfect &#8220;up&#8221; road song for our trip, and we&#8217;ll save <em>&#8220;Deacon Blues&#8221;</em> for the long, lonely stretches. Exquisite.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/abbey-road.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-40447" alt="abbey-road" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/abbey-road-300x300.jpg" width="240" height="240" /></a>Abbey Road, <em>The Beatles</em></strong><br />
How to choose which Beatles&#8217; album to include? The obvious choice for critics has been <em>Sgt. Pepper</em> or <em>Revolver</em>, and a few would go against the flow and nominate the <em>White Album</em>. I&#8217;d be happy with any of them, but for my money, the culmination of the genius that was the Beatles is ultimately revealed on <em>Abbey Road</em>. It was actually their last recorded album, though <em>&#8220;Let It Be&#8221;</em> was released later. It features some of the best harmony singing the group ever did (listen to the superb <em>&#8220;Because,&#8221;</em> for example). George Harrison elevated his status and showed his chops with <em>&#8220;Something&#8221;</em> and <em>&#8220;Here Comes the Sun.&#8221;</em> And the feuding Lennon and McCartney were somehow able to <em>&#8220;Come Together&#8221;</em> enough to produce that remarkable tune as well as a 16-minute medley that evokes the spirit of <em>Sgt. Pepper</em>. The cover was an instant classic &#8212; and we sometimes forget how important those album covers were to the whole ethos of listening to popular music then. Though critics were not universally in love with it at the time, in retrospect <em>Abbey Road</em> may be as close to rock music perfection as we&#8217;ll ever hear.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>Still Life (Talking), <em>Pat Metheny Group</em></strong><br />
We need some instrumental music for this road trip, and I have the perfect choice. The climactic album in a &#8220;Brazilian trilogy&#8221; by the jazz guitarist and his group, it features their trademark wordless vocalizing, along with relentless Latin rhythms and crystalline production. <em>&#8220;Last Train Home&#8221;</em> may be the quintessential road song for the last leg of our journey, with its lonesome railroad sound. Pat Metheny sure knows how to make complex music accessible, and this is his best.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>Graceland, <em>Paul Simon</em></strong><br />
The singer-songwriter&#8217;s masterpiece, which sparked criticism for him working in South Africa while the country was under apartheid, nevertheless brought the amazing sounds of that land&#8217;s people to the rest of the world. Mix those harmonies and rhythms with some Cajun Zydeco, fifties acapella group harmonies, Simon&#8217;s witty lyrics, and impeccable arrangements and production values, and the musical stew that emerges is my favorite album of all time. I simply can&#8217;t imagine driving &#8216;cross country if I can&#8217;t sing <em>&#8220;Diamonds on the Soles of Her Shoes,&#8221;</em> or <em>&#8220;You Can Call Me Al&#8221;</em> at the top of my lungs along the way. Besides, <em>&#8220;I&#8217;ve reason to believe we all will be received in Graceland.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>The Lord&#8217;s Supper, <em>John Michael Talbot</em></strong><br />
My CCM choice. I remember how the CCM&#8217;ers had no clue what to do with this one. Awakened spiritually in the Jesus People Movement, John Michael Talbot found the Holy Spirit leading him to become, of all things, a Franciscan, and he began his studies here in Indianapolis. This was his first album as a Catholic and it contained &#8212; gasp! &#8212; a contemporary setting of <em>The Mass!</em> JMT&#8217;s setting and the performance is as fresh and vibrant as the best of the early Jesus music, and what d&#8217;ya know, it actually has substance, historical and theological depth, and a connection to the church in all times and places. A treasure.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>Hey Jeff, if I could smuggle Wilco&#8217;s<em> Sky Blue Sky</em> along, that wouldn&#8217;t hurt. And I probably couldn&#8217;t live without a James Taylor record (probably <em>New Moonshine</em> or <em>JT</em>), although that&#8217;s a matter of personal devotion and not a statement ranking them up with the best of all time. I&#8217;m also sad at the lack of females represented &#8212; Joni Mitchell, I still love you, please forgive me! And if you give me a little time, I will probably remember some other indispensable record, and I&#8217;ll have to come begging for more.</p>
<p>Pretty please? I told you I&#8217;m not ready for this &#8220;settled once and for all&#8221; thing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/cms-five-for-the-road/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Five Albums</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/my-five-albums</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/my-five-albums#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 04:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Listening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40422</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Don Mann was laid to rest this week in Ohio. Don was my brother-in-law&#8217;s brother-in-law. He fought the cancer than claimed a lung, then his voice, as fiercely and bravely as anyone I have known. While he was not a blood relative, Don was a good friend, one I was privileged to know for nearly [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/vinyl-record.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-40424" alt="vinyl-record" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/vinyl-record.jpg" width="400" height="266" /></a>Don Mann was laid to rest this week in Ohio. Don was my brother-in-law&#8217;s brother-in-law. He fought the cancer than claimed a lung, then his voice, as fiercely and bravely as anyone I have known. While he was not a blood relative, Don was a good friend, one I was privileged to know for nearly three decades.</p>
<p>He and I had a running conversation for most of those three decades that centered around this question: &#8220;If you could only have five albums to listen to the rest of your life, what would they be?&#8221; Neither of us ever reached a definitive answer. There was always the &#8220;Yes but what about&#8221; album one of us had forgotten. <em>Yes but what about </em>Leon Live<em>? Yes but what about </em>Low Spark Of High Heeled Boys<em>? Yes but what about &#8230; ?</em></p>
<p>Rule one of our quest was there could be no greatest hits albums included. We both agreed that these were not artistic endeavors, but money-grabs by record labels or lazy artists. Rule two&#8212;multi-disc sets counted as one album. Rule three&#8212;stop making rules and get to the music already.</p>
<p>In honor of Don&#8217;s homegoing, I want to settle my five selections once and for all. I am planting my flag here, and won&#8217;t change my tune (pun intended, if only because it would have gotten an eye-roll from Don). These are the five albums I would listen to repeatedly if I could only have five. Mind you, I&#8217;m not saying these are the five best albums of all time. But if I am driving cross-country and can only listen to five, load these up and I will be very happy.</p>
<p><span id="more-40422"></span></p>
<p><strong><em>Eat A Peach</em>, The Allman Brothers</strong>   Duane Allman is the third-greatest guitarist of all time. Don&#8217;t waste your time arguing that one. He just is, or was. He died at the age of 24 in a motorcycle accident. Following his death, the Allman Brothers scraped together some live and studio recordings featuring Duane, added three tracks without him, and released my favorite album of all time. It is bright and fun and lively. The song Blue Sky, featuring both Duane Allman and Dickey Betts on guitars, may be the most perfect song ever recorded. By the way, the title of the album does not come from the (mistaken) idea that Duane Allman died when he hit a peach truck (it was a flatbed lumber truck). It comes from something he once said in an interview: &#8220;Every time I&#8217;m in Georgia, I eat a peach for peace.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><em>Exile On Main Street</em>, The Rolling Stones</strong>  In a period of three years, the Stones released three of the greatest rock and roll albums of all time: <em>Let It Bleed</em>, <em>Sticky Fingers</em>, and <em>Exile</em>. I mean, most rock groups would be enshrined in the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame for recording just one of these albums, and the Stones tossed these three out one after another. I could just as easily have chosen <em>Let It Bleed</em> or <em>Sticky Fingers</em>. I actually like the songs on <em>Sticky Fingers</em> better, but I like the raw energy on <em>Exile</em>. It is sloppy and loose and has an &#8220;I don&#8217;t give a rip&#8221; feel about the whole thing. Don and I both agreed that this was the last true rock and roll album ever released. Everything since seems a bit plastic.</p>
<p><strong><em>Songs In The Key Of Life</em>, Stevie Wonder</strong>  This is one that makes me want to weep every time I hear it, just for the sheer brilliance of every song. The musicianship is exceeded only by the depth of lyrics which is exceeded only by Stevie Wonder&#8217;s vocals. When I first bought this as a vinyl set, it came with a bonus 45 RPM record with the songs Saturn and Ebony Eyes on it. These were just thrown in for good measure, yet they are two of my favorite songs by Stevie Wonder.</p>
<p><strong><em>Troubadour Of The Great King</em>, John Michael Talbot</strong>  Once upon a time, there were real instruments called violins, cellos, clarinets, flutes&#8212;all part of what was called an orchestra. Then Satan came along and replaced the orchestra with a keyboard that can &#8220;replicate&#8221; (meaning to almost, but not quite, sound totally unlike real instruments) violins, cellos, clarinets and flutes. Then he made the drum machine which brings weeping and wailing and gnashing of teeth. And for some reason, Christian musicians heard these and said, &#8220;It is good enough.&#8221; JMT used a <strong>real orchestra</strong> in recording <em>Troubadour</em>, an album released in 1981 to celebrate the 800th birthday of St. Francis of Assisi. This was my first exposure to what I call &#8220;Catholic cool.&#8221; It is as fresh today as it was thirty years ago.</p>
<p><strong><em>The Misfit</em>, Erick Nelson and Michelle Pillar</strong>   If <em>Exile On Main Street</em> is the last true rock album, <em>The Misfit</em> may be the last true contemporary Christian album. Whereas this album flows easily from beginning to end, most other CCM albums since just seem to try too hard. Michelle Pillar sings the Nazareth song Love Hurts in a way that makes you want to hate the very notion of love. And the Martyr Song could make a marble statue cry.</p>
<p>Ok. There are my five albums. I don&#8217;t know if Don ever settled on his final five, and I won&#8217;t know until he and I meet again. Just think about that: He and I will have all eternity to listen to music. I have my selections picked out. What are yours?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/my-five-albums/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>66</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Simple Man with a Song</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/a-simple-man-with-a-song</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/a-simple-man-with-a-song#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 20:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Listening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noted]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40413</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[George Beverly Shea, the gospel singer best known for singing on Moody Radio and at Billy Graham&#8217;s crusades, died yesterday at the age of 104. You can read the full obituary and tributes HERE. Here is the simple song that became his testimony of faith. Rest well in Jesus, Bev. &#160;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>George Beverly Shea</strong>, the gospel singer best known for singing on Moody Radio and at Billy Graham&#8217;s crusades, died yesterday at the age of 104.</p>
<p>You can read the full obituary and tributes <a href="http://blog.christianitytoday.com/ctliveblog/archives/2013/04/died-george-beverly-shea-billy-graham-crusades-gospel-singer.html"><strong>HERE</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Here is the simple song that became his testimony of faith. Rest well in Jesus, Bev.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/xk9f8zhTwIg" height="360" width="480" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/a-simple-man-with-a-song/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Outline: My Journey from Evangelicalism to the Lutheran Tradition</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/40403</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/40403#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lutheran Tradition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Post-Evangelicalism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40403</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here is an outline from two talks I gave at the church where I am currently learning and serving. It is just an outline, so if you have questions or want clarifications on anything, ask away. My purpose was to describe my personal reasons for why I, as a Christian, have moved from the culture [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/castle_sm-e1366201833253.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40404" alt="castle_sm" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/castle_sm-e1366201833253.jpg" width="614" height="333" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Here is an outline from two talks I gave at the church where I am currently learning and serving. It is just an outline, so if you have questions or want clarifications on anything, ask away. My purpose was to describe my personal reasons for why I, as a Christian, have moved from the culture of evangelicalism to the Lutheran tradition. To do this, I felt it necessary to help my Lutheran brothers and sisters understand what we mean by &#8220;the culture of evangelicalism,&#8221; what its roots are, its characteristics, my opinion of its weaknesses, and how the Lutheran tradition answered many of my concerns when I became a &#8220;post-evangelical.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p><b>From Evangelicalism to the Lutheran Tradition</b></p>
<p><strong>Background</strong></p>
<p>The word <i>“evangelical”</i> (Gk. for gospel) has a long tradition of use in different settings.</p>
<ol start="1">
<li>In the OT, it is used in the prophets to announce the good news of the end of Israel’s exile.</li>
<li>In the NT, it is used to describe the announcement of Jesus and the apostles of the good news that God’s promises are fulfilled in him and God’s Kingdom has been inaugurated through his life and ministry.</li>
<li>In the 16<sup>th</sup>-17<sup>th</sup> centuries, it was used to describe the Reformation churches to distinguish them from Roman Catholicism.</li>
<li>In the 18<sup>th</sup>-19<sup>th</sup> centuries, it was used in connection with the “Evangelical awakenings,” and thus became associated with Puritanism, Methodism, pietism, and revivalism. The emphasis was on a “religion of the heart” and conversion to Christ through personal decision.</li>
<li>In the 19<sup>th</sup> and 20<sup>th</sup> centuries, evangelicals and fundamentalist churches took sides together against “modernism” and the higher critical approach to the Bible.</li>
<li>In the 20<sup>th</sup> century, evangelicals began to separate from fundamentalists, believing that Christians should not abandon the world but remain involved in culture, education, and society. This was the period of “classic evangelicalism” with Wheaton College, Carl F.H. Henry, Billy Graham, Christianity Today, and student missions and parachurch organizations such as Youth for Christ.</li>
<li>From the 1960’s forward, evangelicalism developed into a particularly prominent <i>culture</i> in the U.S. In reaction to social upheaval, various movements developed and grew– the Jesus People movement, charismatic movement, parachurch movements, church growth movement and megachurches, the move away from denominations, the development of Christian media, and the development of the Christian Right in the “culture wars.”</li>
</ol>
<p>It is this “culture” of evangelicalism and the churches (many of them non-denominational), with its roots in the 18<sup>th</sup>-20<sup>th</sup> centuries that we are focusing on in this talk.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/gjon-mili-evangelist-billy-graham-preaching-sermon-at-madison-square-garden-nyc.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-40408" alt="gjon-mili-evangelist-billy-graham-preaching-sermon-at-madison-square-garden-nyc" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/gjon-mili-evangelist-billy-graham-preaching-sermon-at-madison-square-garden-nyc-300x300.jpg" width="240" height="240" /></a>Summary</strong>:</p>
<p><em>Evangelicalism is…</em></p>
<ol start="1">
<li>Rooted in pietism and revivalism.</li>
<li>Forged in defending the Bible.</li>
<li>Related to but distinguished from fundamentalism.</li>
<li>Characterized by missionary zeal, church growth ethos.</li>
<li>Energized by culture wars and conservative moral issues.</li>
<li>Biblicist, cross-centered, conversionist, activist, non-liturgical/sacramental.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Weaknesses</strong></p>
<ol start="1">
<li>Lack of history, tradition.</li>
<li>Lack of appreciation for worship.</li>
<li>Naïve Biblicism.</li>
<li>Inadequate ecclesiology.</li>
<li>Culture war mentality.</li>
<li>Functions better as a mission than a church tradition.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Streams Emerging from Evangelicalism</strong></p>
<ol start="1">
<li><i>Emerging Christians</i>: reacting to institutionalism, conservatism, dogmatism of evangelicalism. Seeking creative, new forms of holding and practicing faith.</li>
<li><i>Neo-reformed Christians</i>: reacting to shallow doctrinal and theological culture of evangelicalism. Seeking intellectual rigor and disciplined practice.</li>
<li><i>Ancient-Future Christians</i>: reacting to absence of worship, liturgy, historical and sacramental perspective. Many returning to historic churches and denominations. Seeking life in community and communion with saints in all times and places.</li>
<li><i>Nones</i>: reacting to many aspects of evangelicalism as a culture. Seeking spirituality without religion, good life in secularized world.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Luther-Preaching-in-Wittenberg_jpg.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-40409" alt="Luther Preaching in Wittenberg_jpg" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Luther-Preaching-in-Wittenberg_jpg-176x300.jpg" width="141" height="240" /></a>How the Lutheran Tradition Answers Many of My Post-Evangelical Concerns</strong></p>
<ol start="1">
<li>A creedal community that sees itself as part of the “one holy apostolic and catholic church.”</li>
<li>The preeminence of Christ.</li>
<li>The centrality of the Gospel and grace.</li>
<li>The theology of distinguishing law and gospel.</li>
<li>The practice of Word and Table worship.</li>
<li>A sacramental theology and perspective on life.</li>
<li>A proper emphasis on pastoral theology and practice.</li>
<li>The doctrine of vocation.</li>
<li>The theology of the cross.</li>
<li>A robust musical tradition.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/40403/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>87</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Great Divide</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-great-divide</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-great-divide#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 04:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sacraments]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40391</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To the bath and the table, To the prayers and the word, I call every seeking soul. - Inscribed on a church bell in Wisconsin * * * I did a couple of talks at my church recently, discussing my transition from evangelicalism to the Lutheran tradition. As I talked, words from several iMonk commenters [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/early-christian-communities.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40392" alt="early-christian-communities" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/early-christian-communities.jpg" width="540" height="360" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>To the bath and the table,</em><br />
<em> To the prayers and the word,</em><br />
<em> I call every seeking soul.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><small>- Inscribed on a church bell in Wisconsin</small></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>I did a couple of talks at my church recently, discussing my transition from evangelicalism to the Lutheran tradition. As I talked, words from several iMonk commenters came into my mind. A number of you have observed that perhaps the greatest divide in Christendom is between those who take a <em>sacramental</em> view of life, faith, and worship, and those who take a <em>non-sacramental</em> view. This struck me with new force as I explained my journey.</p>
<p>Gordon Lathrop writes,</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>This fact [that we need "things" to worship] has often disturbed and offended some Christians. It seems as if we ought to be above such material crutches, as if a gathering come together to speak of God ought to be more spiritual. But that is just the point: for the great Christian tradition, the spiritual is intimately involved with the material, the truth about God inseparable from the ordinary, as inseparable as God was from humanity in Jesus. If these things are crutches, so be it. They will then be for us the very &#8220;ford, bridge, door, ship, and stretcher&#8221; that Luther said we need. These things will show us something about all things.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><small>- <strong><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001DU7MR0/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B001DU7MR0&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=goonewdai-20">Holy Things: A Liturgical Theology</a></strong><img style="border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=goonewdai-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B001DU7MR0" width="1" height="1" border="0" /></small></p>
<p>Once, when I was visiting a woman who had come from an evangelical church to our Lutheran congregation, she complained that we didn&#8217;t talk more about the Holy Spirit. On one level she was probably correct. But her concern was not that we failed to <em>name</em> the Third Person of the Trinity often enough. Rather, she was saying we didn&#8217;t sufficiently emphasize the supernatural work of the Spirit in our midst. Having lived in both worlds, I understood her point. My answer was, &#8220;But remember friend, we experience the supernatural every time we come together for worship. God literally speaks to us from the word. Jesus is present and real when we receive the bread and wine. When we celebrate baptism we are literally witnessing a new birth!&#8221; No church believes in the supernatural more than one that truly practices the sacraments.</p>
<p><strong>Stuff of Life</strong></p>
<p>Lathrop observes that the material things around which the church gathers not only provide a center for our community of faith, they also represent things that have long had a &#8220;centering power&#8221; among human beings. For example, he speaks of the rich imagery of bread: <em>&#8220;&#8230;bread unites the fruitful goodness of the earth with the ancient history of human cultivation. Bread represents the earth and the rain, growing grains, sowing and reaping, milling and baking, together with the mystery of yeast, all presented in a single object. This loaf invites the participation of more than one person. In its most usual form, it is food for a group. It implies a community gathered around to eat together, to share in the breaking open of this compressed goodness.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Bread is the staple food, the fundamental provision that keeps us alive and enables us to overcome famine and death. We pray in humble dependence, <em>&#8220;Give us this day our daily bread,&#8221;</em> to remember that, despite the affluence many of us enjoy, in the end we live by grace from God&#8217;s hands. So with wine, around which we gather in festive joy. And water for washing. And a book filled with words. All invite us to contemplate the essentials of life through the utmost simplicity.</p>
<p><strong>Doorway into the Story</strong></p>
<p>However, there is more. Lathrop, again:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>&#8230; the business of this assembly will look more than a little silly to us unless we know that the bread and wine, water and words are used here with historical intent. Bread and wine are ancient foods in Israel, figuring in many of the ancient stories and coming to frame the Jewish festive meal in the time of Jesus. Water for washing is important in Israel from the time of the crossing of the Red Sea and the washing and appointing of the newly constituted priests down to the apocalyptic expectations of the Qumran community and of the early Christians. And Israel was a community of the word from the time of the exile, when collecting, writing, and reading the stories and poems, oracles and laws became immensely important to Israel&#8217;s very existence. These things at the center of our assembly connect us to that history. The very choice of these things as the communal central symbols arises from that history.</em></p>
<p>By these means we enter the Story. Simple objects engage our senses and stimulate our imaginations and we find ourselves as though we had picked our way the through the wood, fur, and fabric in Lewis&#8217;s wardrobe and entered Narnia. There we remain ourselves and yet we are more, since we are breathing new air, experiencing new adventures, learning new lessons, and becoming what we never thought possible, under the tutelage of that land&#8217;s true Ruler.</p>
<p><strong>Where God Meets Us</strong></p>
<p>Thus, the sacramental elements are those &#8220;thin places,&#8221; those sites in the world where heaven and earth intersect and God himself meets us, inviting us to receive forgiveness and renewal. For these elements all focus on Christ and introduce us to Christ. Where we hear the words, <em>&#8220;for you,&#8221;</em> from our Host&#8217;s mouth, faith awakens within us, faith that reaches out to Jesus to receive a tangible gift of mercy and promise. In the sacraments, God washes us, God feeds us, God&#8217;s promises bring us life. They are not our works to be performed, but his gracious gifts to be received because of the work Jesus already did.</p>
<p>Nothing could be more simple, more earthly, more unexpectedly heavenly. <em>&#8220;Surely the Lord is in this place—and I did not know it! How awesome is this place! This is none other than the house of God, and this is the gate of heaven.&#8221;</em> <em>(Gen. 28:16-17)</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-great-divide/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pete Enns: The scientific consensus is not something to “have faith in”</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/pete-enns-the-scientific-consensus-is-not-something-to-have-faith-in</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/pete-enns-the-scientific-consensus-is-not-something-to-have-faith-in#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 04:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Faith & Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Reading]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40314</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I like what Peter Enns wrote the other day. He points out that creationists badly miss the point when arguing against the scientific consensus about the evolutionary model. They frame the question as &#8220;Do you believe in science, or do you believe in the Bible?&#8221; as though they were equal options in the same epistemological [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/jtot_genesis_cosmology.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40318" alt="jtot_genesis_cosmology" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/jtot_genesis_cosmology.jpg" width="600" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>I like <a href="http://www.patheos.com/blogs/peterenns/2013/04/97-of-scientists-accept-some-form-of-evolution-there-must-be-something-wrong-with-them/"><strong>what Peter Enns wrote the other day</strong></a>. He points out that creationists badly miss the point when arguing against the scientific consensus about the evolutionary model. They frame the question as <strong>&#8220;Do you <em>believe</em> in science, or do you <em>believe</em> in the Bible?&#8221; </strong>as though they were equal options in the same epistemological universe. Not at all. Accepting the consensus of scientists on a matter like this is not giving them a position of &#8220;authority&#8221; equivalent to the &#8220;authority&#8221; of the Bible with regard to our faith.</p>
<p>Here is what Enns had to say:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">A few days ago I posted the main bullet points for the <a title="Framing the Evangelical Discussion of Adam and Evolution" href="http://www.patheos.com/blogs/peterenns/2013/04/framing-the-evangelical-discussion-of-adam-and-evolution/">lecture I gave at the Evangelical Theological Society</a> on April 6. Some of the responses perpetuate common yet unconvincing lines of defense.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">For example, I began my talk by saying that I accept the scientific consensus as a starting point when discussing the question of human origins.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">A response I have heard–more times than I care to recall, and that I knew would likely come again even though I think I was super clear in my lecture–is, “Aha. See! If you start with science, of course you’re going to end up with evolution. And that’s your problem. You put too much faith in science instead of in the Bible.”</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">“Faith in science” suggests that one’s view of scientific matters is on the same sort of playing field as “faith in the Bible,” which then gives a sort of rhetorical oomph to the posed choice. But I don’t have ”faith in science.” I have made a conscious, intellectual decision to accept the <em>overwhelming consensus</em> of demonstrably knowledgable and trained scientists across the world and for several generations.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">I have done this not by ignoring my faith, but by working out my faith. I am not ignoring the Bible and its “plain teachings,” but interpreting the Bible as responsibly as I know how.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">As I see it, the real question isn’t, “Why do you choose science over God?” but, “On what basis do you think you have the right to dismiss the scientific consensus?”</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Pete Enns clarifies the question well, and creationists who answer that question will typically say, &#8220;I dismiss the scientific consensus <em>because I believe the Bible</em> and what it says about how God created the world.&#8221; However, at that point, they have made a leap. When they say, &#8220;I believe the Bible,&#8221; they are really saying,<strong> &#8220;I have accepted a particular interpretation of what the Bible is, and what it teaches about origins.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The issue therefore is not &#8220;believing the Bible&#8221; vs. &#8220;believing the scientific consensus,&#8221; but rather believing a particular conception of the Bible&#8217;s nature and a specific interpretation of what it teaches about science. Once that foundation has been laid, the creationists then give &#8220;the Bible&#8221; authority over what an overwhelming majority (Enns says 97%) of scientists in various fields have come to accept as the best explanation for the evidence gleaned from studying the natural world. In order for them to argue their position, they must conceive of the Bible as a textbook that speaks to science authoritatively and interpret those teachings in certain ways.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">But the leap they take won&#8217;t stand scrutiny. I don&#8217;t tell creationists that I reject their interpretation of Genesis because I became convinced about evolution. Evolution is not my &#8220;authority,&#8221; and I do not interpret the Bible through its lens.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/250px-God_the_Geometer.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-40320" alt="250px-God_the_Geometer" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/250px-God_the_Geometer-218x300.jpg" width="218" height="300" /></a>Not at all. I have never even, in fact, seriously studied biology or the evolutionary model. <strong>I started with and continue to focus on the Bible itself</strong>.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">I simply don&#8217;t think the Bible is to be understood and interpreted the way the creationists would have us accept it. It was not designed to be an &#8220;authority&#8221; with regard to scientific matters. It has little, if anything, to say about the natural scientific processes of the world because it was not written to address those matters.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Given when the Scriptures were written, edited, and compiled, <em>how could it?</em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Given the Bible&#8217;s purpose as Israel&#8217;s story culminating in Jesus the Messiah, <em>why would it? </em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">To say that the Bible has anything to do with &#8220;science&#8221; as we know it requires a particular commitment to the Bible as a divinely inspired &#8220;instruction book&#8221; that is designed to give us a full-orbed &#8220;worldview&#8221; in which we find &#8220;answers&#8221; to all of life&#8217;s questions.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">That may be the Bible we idealize. That is not the Bible we hold in our hands. Nor is it the Bible that will serve as an &#8220;authority&#8221; to compete against the &#8220;authority&#8221; of science. Scientific inquiry and the biblical message do not inhabit the same theoretical universe. They do not compete against one another, they do not speak to the same facts or realities. We need not feel that we must harmonize their teachings or somehow make them agree.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">In saying this, I should also add that the scientific consensus does not support or give ammunition to those who would argue for a strictly naturalistic or atheistic view of life either. Those who hold such views should not appeal to scientific &#8220;authority&#8221; to undergird their metaphysical skepticism or unbelief. Science doesn&#8217;t give them &#8220;answers&#8221; about these things any more than it does to theists and Christians.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The more we focus on this completely bogus war between science and faith, the less energy we will have to give to actually living as people of faith.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/pete-enns-the-scientific-consensus-is-not-something-to-have-faith-in/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>82</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Problem with “Safe, Legal” Abortion</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-problem-with-safe-legal-abortion</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-problem-with-safe-legal-abortion#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 04:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Public Issues]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40366</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This absolutely horrifying story from The Atlantic about Dr. Kermit Gosnell, now standing trial for murder in Philadelphia, gives the lie to the traditional argument that making and keeping abortion legal ensures that it will be done safely and with concern for the health and well being of the mother. As the grand jury report states: [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/t1larg.kermit.gosnell.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40370" alt="t1larg.kermit.gosnell" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/t1larg.kermit.gosnell.jpg" width="512" height="288" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/national/archive/2013/04/why-dr-kermit-gosnells-trial-should-be-a-front-page-story/274944/"><strong>This absolutely horrifying story from <em>The Atlantic</em></strong></a> about Dr. Kermit Gosnell, now standing trial for murder in Philadelphia, gives the lie to the traditional argument that making and keeping abortion legal ensures that it will be done safely and with concern for the health and well being of the mother. As the grand jury report states:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">&#8220;This case is about a doctor who killed babies and endangered women. What we mean is that he regularly and illegally delivered live, viable babies in the third trimester of pregnancy &#8211; and then murdered these newborns by severing their spinal cords with scissors. The medical practice by which he carried out this business was a filthy fraud in which he overdosed his patients with dangerous drugs, spread venereal disease among them with infected instruments, perforated their wombs and bowels &#8212; and, on at least two occasions, caused their deaths.&#8221;</p>
<p>I encourage you to go and read the entire article, if you can stomach it. It is a true American horror story. It also reveals issues of racism, mistreatment of the poor, the exploitation of women, and the failures of government and journalistic institutions.</p>
<p>I will simply re-post here some of the grand jury&#8217;s conclusions about the appalling lack of oversight with regard to this doctor and clinic.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Pennsylvania is not a third-world country. There were several oversight agencies that stumbled upon and should have shut down Kermit Gosnell long ago. But none of them did&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">The first line of defense was the Pennsylvania Department of Health. The department&#8217;s job is to audit hospitals and outpatient medical facilities, like Gosnell&#8217;s, to make sure that they follow the rules and provide safe care. The department had contact with the Women&#8217;s Medical Society dating back to 1979, when it first issued approval to open an abortion clinic. It did not conduct another site review until 1989, ten years later. Numerous violations were already apparent, but Gosnell got a pass when he promised to fix them. Site reviews in 1992 and 1993 also noted various violations, but again failed to ensure they were corrected.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">But at least the department had been doing something up to that point, however ineffectual. After 1993, even that pro form a effort came to an end. Not because of administrative ennui, although there had been plenty. Instead, the Pennsylvania Department of Health abruptly decided, for political reasons, to stop inspecting abortion clinics at all&#8230; The only exception to this live-and-let-die policy was supposed to be for complaints dumped directly on the department&#8217;s doorstep. Those, at least, would be investigated. Except that there were complaints about Gosnell, repeatedly. Several different attorneys, representing women injured by Gosnell, contacted the department. A doctor from Children&#8217;s Hospital of Philadelphia hand-delivered a complaint, advising the department that numerous patients he had referred for abortions came back from Gosnell with the same venereal disease. The medical examiner of Delaware County informed the department that Gosnell had performed an illegal abortion on a 14-year-old girl carrying a 30-week-old baby. And the department received official notice that a woman named Karnamaya Mongar had died at Gosnell&#8217;s hands.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Yet not one of these alarm bells &#8212; not even Mrs. Mongar&#8217;s death &#8212; prompted the department to look at Gosnell or the Women&#8217;s Medical Society&#8230; But even this total abdication by the Department of Health might not have been fatal. Another agency with authority in the health field, the Pennsylvania Department of State, could have stopped Gosnell single-handedly.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">The Department of State, through its Board of Medicine, licenses and oversees individual physicians&#8230; Almost a decade ago, a former employee of Gosnell presented the Board of Medicine with a complaint that laid out the whole scope of his operation: the unclean, unsterile conditions; the unlicensed workers; the unsupervised sedation; the underage abortion patients; even the over-prescribing of pain pills with high resale value on the street. The department assigned an investigator, whose investigation consisted primarily of an offsite interview with Gosnell. The investigator never inspected the facility, questioned other employees, or reviewed any records. Department attorneys chose to accept this incomplete investigation, and dismissed the complaint as unconfirmed.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Shortly thereafter the department received an even more disturbing report &#8212; about a woman, years before Karnamaya Mongar, who died of sepsis after Gosnell perforated her uterus. The woman was 22 years old. A civil suit against Gosnell was settled for almost a million dollars, and the insurance company forwarded the information to the department. That report should have been all the confirmation needed for the complaint from the former employee that was already in the department&#8217;s possession. Instead, the department attorneys dismissed this complaint too&#8230; The same thing happened at least twice more: the department received complaints about lawsuits against Gosnell, but dismissed them as meaningless&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Philadelphia health department employees regularly visited the Women&#8217;s Medical Society to retrieve blood samples for testing purposes, but never noticed, or more likely never bothered to report, that anything was amiss. Another employee inspected the clinic in response to a complaint that dead fetuses were being stored in paper bags in the employees&#8217; lunch refrigerator. The inspection confirmed numerous violations&#8230; But no follow-up was ever done&#8230; A health department representative also came to the clinic as part of a citywide vaccination program. She promptly discovered that Gosnell was scamming the program; she was the only employee, city or state, who actually tried to do something about the appalling things she saw there. By asking questions and poking around, she was able to file detailed reports identifying many of the most egregious elements of Gosnell&#8217;s practice. It should have been enough to stop him. But instead her reports went into a black hole, weeks before Karnamaya Mongar walked into the Woman&#8217;s Medical Society.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">&#8230;And it wasn&#8217;t just government agencies that did nothing. The Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania and its subsidiary, Penn Presbyterian Medical Center, are in the same neighborhood as Gosnell&#8217;s office. State law requires hospitals to report complications from abortions. A decade ago, a Gosnell patient died at HUP after a botched abortion, and the hospital apparently filed the necessary report. But the victims kept coming in. At least three other Gosnell patients were brought to Penn facilities for emergency surgery; emergency room personnel said they have treated many others as well. And at least one additional woman was hospitalized there after Gosnell had begun a flagrantly illegal abortion of a 29-week-old fetus. Yet, other than the one initial report, Penn could find not a single case in which it complied with its legal duty to alert authorities to the danger. Not even when a second woman turned up virtually dead&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">So too with the National Abortion Federation.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">NAF is an association of abortion providers that upholds the strict est health and legal standards for its members. Gosnell, bizarrely, applied for admission shortly after Karnamaya Mongar&#8217;s death. Despite his various efforts to fool her, the evaluator from NAF readily noted that records were not properly kept, that risks were not explained, that patients were not monitored, that equipment was not available, that anesthesia was misused. It was the worst abortion clinic she had ever inspected. Of course, she rejected Gosnell&#8217;s application. She just never told anyone in authority about all the horrible, dangerous things she had seen.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>A meaningful discussion about abortion in this country must be honest, open, and complete on all sides. It is not enough to be &#8220;pro-life&#8221; and yet refuse to confess that the movement has been sorely lacking in advocating for a variety of social justice concerns that would make abortion a less attractive alternative, especially for the poor. But neither is it appropriate to take a &#8220;pro-choice&#8221; stance and fail to acknowledge the ugly reality that abortion contributes to the actual harm of people and society, especially when its legality is abused in such unspeakable ways.</p>
<p>The silence of the mainstream media and the &#8220;pro-choice&#8221; movement regarding this case is inexcusable. Many are starting ask why this story hasn&#8217;t received much coverage: see <a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/opinion/opinion-la/la-ol-kermit-gosnell-why-so-little-coverage-20130412,0,4790500.story">LA Times</a>, <a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/weigel/2013/04/12/kermit_gosnell_the_alleged_mass_murderer_and_the_bored_media.html">Salon</a>, <a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/2013/04/10/philadelphia-abortion-clinic-horror-column/2072577/">USA Today</a>, as well as this piece I&#8217;ve referenced from The Atlantic.</p>
<p>Whatever your position on whether or not abortion should remain a legal alternative in our society, for the common good can&#8217;t we all engage in a discussion about working together to do whatever we can to lessen the number of abortions performed and, certainly, to condemn houses of horror like this from every conceivable angle and shut them down immediately?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-problem-with-safe-legal-abortion/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>117</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Put the Top Down and Put This On</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/put-the-top-down-and-put-this-on</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/put-the-top-down-and-put-this-on#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 17:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Listening]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40385</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Spring arrived in full glory in Indianapolis today. The long drive home from church required an appropriate soundtrack. What better than one of the greatest albums of all time? It&#8217;s all sunshine and great grooves. It will come back to you.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Spring arrived in full glory in Indianapolis today. The long drive home from church required an appropriate soundtrack. What better than one of the greatest albums of all time? It&#8217;s all sunshine and great grooves.</p>
<p>It will come back to you.</p>
<p><iframe width="480" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/7ETwkwOMJ6A" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/put-the-top-down-and-put-this-on/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>In the Garden</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/in-the-garden</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/in-the-garden#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40339</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I come to the garden alone While the dew is still on the roses And the voice I hear falling on my ear The Son of God discloses. Je­sus said to her, “Mary!” Just one word from his lips, and for­got­ten the heart­aches, the long drea­ry hours….all the past blot­ted out in the pre­sence of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_40340" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 572px"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Christ-appearing-Ryder-e1365896633290.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-40340 " alt="Christ appearing Ryder" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Christ-appearing-Ryder-e1365896633290.jpg" width="562" height="387" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Christ Appearing to Mary (detail), Ryder</p></div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>I come to the garden alone<br />
While the dew is still on the roses<br />
And the voice I hear falling on my ear<br />
The Son of God discloses.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Je­sus said to her, “Mary!” Just one word from his lips, and for­got­ten the heart­aches, the long drea­ry hours….all the past blot­ted out in the pre­sence of the Liv­ing Pre­sent and the Eter­nal Fu­ture.</p>
<p style="text-align: right; padding-left: 30px;"><small>- C. Austin Miles, 1912</small></p>
<p style="text-align: center; padding-left: 30px;">* * *</p>
<p>The hymn <a href="http://cyberhymnal.org/htm/i/t/g/itgarden.htm"><em>&#8220;In the Garden&#8221;</em> </a>has caught a lot of flak over the years for its sentimentality and its &#8220;me and Jesus&#8221; lyrics. One critic who expressed his conviction that the church has forsaken a robust hymnology and replaced it with insipid ditties bewailed it as a &#8220;mawkish little rhyme about someone’s personal experience and feelings.&#8221;</p>
<p>I get the criticism, but I also understand why some people find comfort in a hymn like <em>&#8220;In the Garden.&#8221;</em> It was my grandfather&#8217;s favorite and we sang it at his funeral service years ago. As a hospice chaplain I am asked to include it in such services regularly. I don&#8217;t care for its waltzy tune (especially when played on a bad organ at the wrong tempo), and the refrain tends to distract from the Gospel story on which it is based. Still, it is based on a vivid and memorable resurrection appearance which took place in a garden, and the mood of the biblical narrative is also tender and personal.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>But Mary stood just outside the tomb, and she was crying. And as she cried, she looked into the tomb and saw two angels in white who sat, one at the head and the other at the foot of the place where the body of Jesus had lain.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>The angels spoke to her, “Why are you crying?” they asked. “Because they have taken away my Lord, and I don’t know where they have put him!” she said.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Then she turned and noticed Jesus standing there, without realising that it was Jesus.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>“Why are you crying?” said Jesus to her. “Who are you looking for?” She, supposing that he was the gardener, said, “Oh, sir, if you have carried him away, please tell me where you have put him and I will take him away.”</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Jesus said to her, “Mary!” At this she turned right round and said to him, in Hebrew, “Master!”</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: right;"><em>- John 20:11-16 (Phillips)</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Christ-appearing-Ryder-e1365898863473.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-40340" alt="Christ appearing Ryder" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Christ-appearing-Ryder-e1365898863473-203x300.jpg" width="203" height="300" /></a>The Gospel of John has long been favored by evangelicals and those who emphasize a &#8220;personal relationship&#8221; with Jesus because it is filled with intimate encounters like this one. John portrays Jesus as one constantly engaged in conversation with individuals, speaking words of salvation and peace.</p>
<p>Whatever concerns I have about evangelical<em>ism</em>, I don&#8217;t ever want to lose this. One thing the resurrection means is that Jesus <em>&#8220;walks with me and he talks with me, and he tells me I am his own.&#8221; </em>In the Upper Room, the Savior made promises to his disciples about what the resurrection would mean for them, and he spoke in the most personal and tender of terms:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>&#8220;No, I will not abandon you as orphans—I will come to you. Soon the world will no longer see me, but you will see me. Since I live, you also will live. When I am raised to life again, you will know that I am in my Father, and you are in me, and I am in you. Those who accept my commandments and obey them are the ones who love me. And because they love me, my Father will love them. And I will love them and reveal myself to each of them.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: right;"><em>- John 14:19-21, NLT</em></p>
<p>So then, one of the quiet, unexpected features of Christ&#8217;s majestic victory over the forces of sin, death, and hell is that he applies his great triumph by meeting us individually, in quiet places, whispering our names, and assuring us that we are not alone.</p>
<p>I understand why people might want that sentiment expressed at a funeral.</p>
<p>I can see why I might need that today.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><small><strong>Not What We Might Expect</strong><br />
<em>A Series for Sundays in Eastertide, 2</em></small></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/in-the-garden/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic
Page Caching using disk: enhanced

 Served from: www.internetmonk.com @ 2013-04-19 00:13:30 by W3 Total Cache -->
