<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/" xmlns:creativeCommons="http://backend.userland.com/creativeCommonsRssModule" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>internetmonk.com</title>
	
	<link>http://www.internetmonk.com</link>
	<description>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 15:01:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
<!-- podcast_generator="Blubrry PowerPress/4.0.7" -->
	<itunes:summary>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:author>The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer</itunes:author>
	<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/monkposterx3.jpg" />
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer</itunes:name>
		<itunes:email>michael@internetmonk.com</itunes:email>
	</itunes:owner>
	<managingEditor>michael@internetmonk.com (The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer)</managingEditor>
	<copyright>2006-2009</copyright>
	<itunes:subtitle>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</itunes:subtitle>
	<image><link>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</link><url>http://creativecommons.org/images/public/somerights20.gif</url><title>Some Rights Reserved</title></image>
	<itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
		<itunes:category text="Christianity" />
	</itunes:category>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/internetmonk/SWqj" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="internetmonk/swqj" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license><feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">internetmonk/SWqj</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>Holy Week: Dinner with Him Once Dead</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-dinner-with-him-once-dead</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-dinner-with-him-once-dead#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 15:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39874</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Six days before the Passover Jesus came to Bethany, the home of Lazarus, whom he had raised from the dead. There they gave a dinner for him. Martha served, and Lazarus was one of those at the table with him. (John 12:1-2) * * * This story intrigues me. Normally, when reading John 12:1-11, we [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_39879" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 592px"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Giotto-Lazarus-detail.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-39879" alt="Giotto Lazarus detail" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Giotto-Lazarus-detail.jpg" width="582" height="338" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Raising of Lazarus, Giotto</p></div>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Six days before the Passover Jesus came to Bethany, the home of Lazarus, whom he had raised from the dead. There they gave a dinner for him. Martha served, and Lazarus was one of those at the table with him.</em> (John 12:1-2)</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>This story intrigues me. Normally, when reading <a href="http://bible.oremus.org/?ql=231155577"><strong>John 12:1-11</strong></a>, we focus on Mary&#8217;s act of anointing Jesus and Judas&#8217;s objection to what she did. But the narrative about Mary&#8217;s deed is framed with an emphasis on <em>Lazarus</em>. Twice it points out that Lazarus was the one Jesus raised from the dead. To set the stage for the story of the meal, John notes that Lazarus was present at the table with Jesus and that the dinner was given in honor of Jesus &#8212; presumably to thank him for restoring Lazarus to life. Then, following the anointing account, the text ends with these words:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>When the great crowd of the Jews learned that he was there, they came not only because of Jesus but also to see Lazarus, whom he had raised from the dead. So the chief priests planned to put Lazarus to death as well, since it was on account of him that many of the Jews were deserting and were believing in Jesus.</em></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever heard a sermon on what it must have been like to have dinner with someone who had recently been a corpse, dead and buried for four days. But that&#8217;s a genuine curiosity, don&#8217;t you think?</p>
<p><strong>What would American church culture do with this?</strong> Can you imagine? With our technological and marketing skills, Lazarus would have been a religious superstar of the highest order. Book and movie contracts. A tour of appearances and interviews. Given our hunger for the supernatural and the sensational, Lazarus&#8217;s &#8220;experience&#8221; would be first proclaimed and promoted, and then dissected and discussed and debated <em>ad nauseum</em>. I&#8217;m sure there would be a thousand questions about Lazarus&#8217;s &#8220;death experience&#8221; &#8212; what he saw and encountered on the other side. There would, of course, be doubters and those arguing that it couldn&#8217;t have happened as advertised because the experiential claims go against sound doctrine. Some would proclaim the event a clear sign that the last days are upon us.</p>
<p>The text itself (along with <a href="http://bible.oremus.org/?ql=231157980"><strong>John 12:17-19</strong></a>, the last mention of Lazarus in the NT) indicates that Lazarus and what Jesus did for him attracted crowds and generated enthusiasm. If true then, can you conceive of the media blitz that would accompany a happening like this today?</p>
<p><strong>Dinner with him once dead</strong>. Can we even imagine?</p>
<p>And then it struck me: if the Lord&#8217;s Supper is a true sacrament, if Jesus, our crucified and risen Lord is present, and if the baptized who come to the Table are those who <em>&#8220;have been buried with him by baptism into death, so that, just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glory of the Father, so we too might walk in newness of life,&#8221;</em> (Rom. 6:4), then each time we meet together for Communion, we are having dinner among the once dead.</p>
<p>The crowds may not come.</p>
<p>The event may not make the news.</p>
<p>It may, indeed, seem the very opposite of spectacle and enthusiasm.</p>
<p>But his flesh is true food and his blood is true drink &#8212; Jesus&#8217; dying love for the life of the world.</p>
<p>And we who come were once dead, but now live in the risen Christ.</p>
<p>A once in a lifetime experience for Lazarus has now become (at least) an every week event. And you are invited &#8212; Dinner with him once dead! With a whole room of people once dead!</p>
<p>Y&#8217;all come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-dinner-with-him-once-dead/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week with Duccio: Resurrection of Lazarus</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-lazarus</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-lazarus#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 04:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39789</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Source: Web Gallery of Art The Gospel reading for Monday in Holy Week is John 12:1-11. This tells the story of Mary, Lazarus&#8217;s sister, anointing Jesus&#8217; feet at a dinner in their home in honor of Lazarus, whom Jesus raised from the dead. That act of bringing Lazarus back to life is emphasized throughout the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Lazarus.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-39836" alt="Duccio Lazarus" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Lazarus.jpg" width="539" height="510" /></a>Source: <a href="http://www.wga.hu/frames-e.html?/html/d/duccio/maesta/predel_v/pre_v_i.html"><strong>Web Gallery of Art</strong></a></p>
<p>The Gospel reading for Monday in Holy Week is <a href="http://bible.oremus.org/?ql=231131052"><strong>John 12:1-11</strong></a>. This tells the story of Mary, Lazarus&#8217;s sister, anointing Jesus&#8217; feet at a dinner in their home in honor of Lazarus, whom Jesus raised from the dead. That act of bringing Lazarus back to life is emphasized throughout the text and was of such import that the officials decided they should not only kill Jesus, but Lazarus as well. Duccio&#8217;s panel portrays the event itself, which is recorded in the previous chapter, John 11.</p>
<p>Note the vivid colors, the intensity upon the faces of the characters, the depictions of Mary kneeling at Jesus&#8217; feet and Martha making her request, Lazarus himself tightly bound in the grave-cloths, and the lifelike, almost humorous portrayal of the man holding his nose for fear of the stench of death.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-lazarus/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week with Duccio: The Entry into Jerusalem</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-entry</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-entry#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 16:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39823</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Source: Web Gallery of Art &#8220;The scene Entry into Jerusalem is unusual because of the attention given to the landscape, which is rich in detail. The paved road, the city gate with battlements, the wall embrasures, the slender towers rising up above and the polygonal building of white marble reproduce a remarkably realistic layout, both urbanistically and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/duccio-entry.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-39824" alt="duccio entry" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/duccio-entry.jpg" width="562" height="1010" /></a>Source: <a href="http://www.wga.hu/frames-e.html?/html/d/duccio/maesta/verso_1/verso01.html"><strong>Web Gallery of Art</strong></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8220;The scene <em>Entry into Jerusalem</em> is unusual because of the attention given to the landscape, which is rich in detail. The paved road, the city gate with battlements, the wall embrasures, the slender towers rising up above and the polygonal building of white marble reproduce a remarkably realistic layout, both urbanistically and architecturally. The small tree, withered and leafless, that shows behind Christ&#8217;s halo, is the fig-tree that Christ found without fruit. Florens Deuchler has suggested that the literary source is a historical work of the first century A.D., the De Bello Judaico by Flavius Josephus which was well-known in the Middle Ages. The panel by Duccio is a faithful reproduction of the description of Jerusalem in Book V.&#8221; (WGA)</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8220;What made the <em>Maesta</em> so special? First, Duccio&#8217;s representation of space. Not the compact, tightly structured, cubic space we have come to associate with the work of Giotto, in which the architectural setting is invariably conceived to enhance the figural content, but a more pictorial, panoramic spatial setting incorporating a plethora of details culled from the world of everyday life, so that the event relates to the contemporary world of his viewers.&#8221; (Christiansen)</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ducciodibuoninsegna.org/"><strong>Duccio di Buoninsegna</strong></a> (d. 1318) is a seminal figure in Western painting. From Siena, he &#8220;attained a position of prominence in Italy surpassed only by his somewhat younger Florentine contemporary Giotto&#8230;&#8221; (<em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008SLIK3C/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B008SLIK3C&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=goonewdai-20">Duccio and the Origins of Western Painting</a><img alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=goonewdai-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B008SLIK3C" width="1" height="1" border="0" /></em>, Christiansen). His masterpiece, one of the great works of Western art, is the <em><a href="http://www.wga.hu/tours/siena/analysi1.html"><strong>Maesta</strong></a></em>, a large altarpiece. The installation of this altarpiece was one of the most memorable events in Sienese history, <a href="https://docs.google.com/viewer?a=v&amp;q=cache:Ah3cgrSTNKQJ:art.unt.edu/medieval-symposium/2010_papers/Jones_2010.pdf+&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=us&amp;pid=bl&amp;srcid=ADGEESiPnE3xaaibIpokEysBUA7KQdApcWXOfS2BFI3Zo5pqRcbWRRsT15PQNUCBerqehzgxv0DMMG3WQy_LRF6mKOi6Qfh3WapzjqIewFDa48sXbPhuPVmbzAJFQHo7LiswMktAnZus&amp;sig=AHIEtbTL51ZUtaAMLsTTNOyZRgdaQo0LwQ">an event that reveals the close connection in that age between religious and civic life</a>.</p>
<p><em>The Maesta</em> is a double-sided screen nearly fifteen feet tall and more than sixteen feet wide that graced the cathedral in Siena. On the front of the altarpiece is the Virgin (the city&#8217;s patroness) enthroned and surrounded by saints and angels, including four patron saints of Siena. Under the Virgin are panels depicting the early life of Christ. The impression given is that Jesus&#8217; incarnation, birth, and childhood was marked by the motherly care of the Virgin Mary. Above the Virgin are panels depicting scenes from her last days.</p>
<p>The back of the altarpiece tells the Gospel story. It is made up of panels displaying the public life and ministry of Christ and scenes from the Passion and Resurrection accounts. During Holy Week this year, we will post some of these panels, with descriptions, for your viewing and contemplation.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-entry/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week: There is Always a Day Before (iMonk Classic)</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-there-is-always-a-day-before-imonk-classic</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-there-is-always-a-day-before-imonk-classic#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 05:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>iMonk</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Spencer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39776</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[NOTE: As we begin Holy Week, this classic Michael Spencer post from November, 2009 reminds us that each day, each week is a journey into the unknown. We never know if the cross is waiting for us this Friday. Michael wrote these words shortly before he learned that he had a terminal illness. * * [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/oakhilltrail-2011-0423a-e1364056270819.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-39781" alt="oakhilltrail-2011-0423a" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/oakhilltrail-2011-0423a-e1364056270819.jpg" width="550" height="308" /></a></p>
<p><strong>NOTE</strong>: As we begin Holy Week, this classic Michael Spencer post from November, 2009 reminds us that each day, each week is a journey into the unknown. We never know if the cross is waiting for us this Friday. Michael wrote these words shortly before he learned that he had a terminal illness.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>The news story is strange and tragic. Three college softball players go for a night time drive in the country. On an unfamiliar road, they take a wrong turn and drive into a pond…and drown.</p>
<p>There was a day before. A day with no thought of drowning. A day with family and friends. Perhaps with no thought of eternity, God or heaven. There was a day when every assumption was that tomorrow would be like today.</p>
<p>My friend Gary has been the night dean at our school for more than 20 years. His wife has been in poor health, but he has been a workhorse of health. He’s walked miles every day, eaten a vegetarian diet and always kept the rest of us lifted up with his smile and constant focus on the joy he took in his salvation.</p>
<p>Two weeks ago, the doctor turned to him and said leukemia. Today he stands on the crumbling edge of this earthly shadow, looking at the next world, fighting for his life with all that medicine and prayer can offer. Our prayers for him as a school community have been continuous, because we never thought there would be such a day.</p>
<p>There was a day before he heard “leukemia.” A day of work, chores, bills, hopes of seeing a grandchild, prayers for students, love for Suzi. Not a thought that the journey of life contained such a surprising turn for him.</p>
<p>And on that day, Gary was full of faith, full of a servant’s heart, ready for many more days or ready for this to be last one before whatever was around the corner.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/road-into-fog-e1364056568713.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-39783" alt="road into fog" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/road-into-fog-e1364056568713.jpg" width="160" height="177" /></a>We all live the days before. We are living them now.</p>
<p>There was a day before 9-11.</p>
<p>There was a day before your child told you she was pregnant.</p>
<p>There was a day before your wife said she’d had enough.</p>
<p>There was a day before your employer said “lay offs.”</p>
<p>We are living our days before. We are living them now.</p>
<p>Some of us are doing, for the last time, what we think we will be doing twenty years from now.</p>
<p>Some of us are on the verge of a much shorter life, or a very different life, or a life turned upside down.</p>
<p>Some of us are preaching our last sermon, making love for the last time, saying “I love you” to our children for the last time in our own home. Some of us are spending our last day without the knowledge of eternal judgment and the reality of God. We are promising tomorrow will be different and tomorrow is not going to give us the chance, because God has a different tomorrow entirely on our schedule. We just don’t know it today.</p>
<p>Who am I on this day before I am compelled to be someone else? What am I living for? How am I living out the deepest expression of who I am and what I believe?</p>
<p>My life is an accumulation of days lived out of what I believe is true every day.</p>
<p>Gary lived every day with the story of Jesus nearby and the joy of the Lord a ready word to share.</p>
<p>When the day came that “leukemia” was the word he had to hear, he was already living a day resting in the victory of Jesus. That word, above all earthly powers, cannot be taken away. It speaks louder and more certainly the more the surprising words of providence and tragedy shout their unexpected turns into our ears.</p>
<p>Live each day as the day that all of the Gospel is true. Live this day and be glad in it. Live this day as the day of laying down sin and taking up the glad and good forgiveness of Jesus. Live this day determined to be useful and joyful in Jesus. Live this day in a way that, should all things change tomorrow, you will know that the Lord is your God and this is the day to be satisfied in him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-there-is-always-a-day-before-imonk-classic/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Easter as “March Madness”</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/easter-as-march-madness</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/easter-as-march-madness#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laugh or else]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39785</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I won&#8217;t comment on this ad in our paper today for a local church Easter production. I should probably just start a &#8220;Groan or Else&#8221; category for things like this.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I won&#8217;t comment on this ad in our paper today for a local church Easter production. I should probably just start a <em>&#8220;Groan or Else&#8221;</em> category for things like this.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Easter-Ad.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-39786" alt="Easter Ad" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Easter-Ad.jpg" width="601" height="805" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/easter-as-march-madness/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saturday Ramblings 3.23.13</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-3-23-13</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-3-23-13#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 04:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saturday Ramblings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39771</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Pardon me if I am a bit distracted as I ramble today, iMonks. I am celebrating Basketball Christmas as I write this. Yes Virginia (and Washington, D.C.), there is a Santa Claus, and his name is Florida Gulf Coast, my new favorite college basketball team. I love upsets, especially by teams that, before the tournament [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Rambler21.jpeg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-38060" alt="Rambler" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Rambler21-300x200.jpeg" width="300" height="200" /></a>Pardon me if I am a bit distracted as I ramble today, iMonks. I am celebrating Basketball Christmas as I write this. Yes Virginia (and Washington, D.C.), there is a Santa Claus, and his name is Florida Gulf Coast, my new favorite college basketball team. I love upsets, especially by teams that, before the tournament began, I didn&#8217;t even know existed. And have you seen the hideous uniforms worn by Notre Dame? It&#8217;s enough to keep me from ever converting to Catholicism. Of course, we&#8217;ll all be happy as long as someone beats Duke, right? Lace up your Chucks, iMonks. It&#8217;s time to ramble.</p>
<p>First up, let me once again encourage you to check out our newest sponsor, <a href="http://evangelicalbible.com/" target="_blank"><strong>evangelicalBible.com</strong></a>. I was able to check out some of their wares this week, including an ESV and a NKJV Schuyler Bible. Wow. These are things of beauty. I also held in my hands the most beautiful and best-crafted Bible I have had seen: the Allan KJV Longprimer in navy blue. These are investments that you will want to hand down to your kids, and they their kids. No, they are not cheap. But oh are they good!</p>
<p>You know how your friends love to show off baby pictures, and you pretend to be interested so as to not disappoint them? Roving Rambler Adam Palmer showed off some baby pictures he came across this week. <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/03/21/tech/innovation/universe-planck-map/index.html?hpt=hp_c1" target="_blank"><strong>Pictures of the universe</strong></a> when it was not even half a million years old. That, in creation years, makes these pretty much newborn pics of our universe. When the universe was born, do you think God handed out cigars?</p>
<p>An installation service was held for an incoming religious leader this week. You may have heard about it. That&#8217;s right, there is a new <a href="http://www.religionnews.com/2013/03/21/justin-welby-installed-as-105th-archbishop-of-canterbury/" target="_blank"><strong>Archbishop of Canterbury</strong></a>. We have had 266 Catholic popes. Before you click on the link, how many Anglican heads of church do you think there have been? Ok, now you can click. Did you get it right?</p>
<p><span id="more-39771"></span></p>
<p>Oh yeah, there was another installation service this week. Pope Francis is his name. Apparently some <a href="http://www.religionnews.com/2013/03/18/loss-of-papacy-leaves-some-italians-grumbling/" target="_blank"><strong>Italians</strong></a> are a bit upset that Francis is not Italian. Only he is. But he isn&#8217;t. Are you with me on this? Of course, Francis is a born troublemaker. Instead of wanting to hold the traditional Maundy Thursday service in a church, he is going to have it in a <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/religion/the-pope/9945987/Pope-Francis-breaks-the-mould-again-with-ceremony-at-prison-instead-of-St-Peters.html" target="_blank"><strong>prison</strong></a>. How very Jesus-like of him. But then what do you expect from a man who, after elected pope, called back home to Argentina to <a href="http://www.catholicnewsagency.com/news/pope-calls-argentine-kiosk-owner-to-cancel-paper-delivery/" target="_blank"><strong>cancel his newspaper subscription</strong></a>?</p>
<p>Rev. Randy directed my attention this week to this <a href="http://www.charismamag.com/blogs/the-strang-report/17072-why-paul-and-jan-crouch-cant-escape-accountability" target="_blank"><strong>apologetic for TBN</strong></a> by Charisma&#8217;s Steve Strang. Color me not convinced. Or am I wrong? Do we say Paul and Jan are innocent until proven guilty, or do we say where there&#8217;s smoke, there&#8217;s fire?</p>
<p>Did you happen to catch President Obama&#8217;s <a href="http://religion.blogs.cnn.com/2013/03/18/producers-obama-satan-resemblance-is-utter-nonsense/comment-page-40/" target="_blank"><strong>cameo</strong></a> on The Bible mini-series? He played the role of Satan. And no, it wasn&#8217;t just a coincidence. God guided the makeup artist&#8217;s hand to make Beelzebub look like Barak. No, really. So says this <a href="http://www.rawstory.com/rs/2013/03/20/christian-radio-host-god-guided-history-channel-to-prove-obama-is-satan/#.UUpqZ_UPUE8.facebook" target="_blank"><strong>Christian talk show host</strong></a>. And if you can&#8217;t believe a talk show host, who can you believe?</p>
<p>Four words I never thought I would put together in one sentence: <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/03/22/opinion/navarrette-mick-jagger/index.html?hpt=hp_c4" target="_blank"><strong>Mick Jagger, model dad</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, it seems <a href="http://blog.christianitytoday.com/ctliveblog/archives/2013/03/mumford-and-sons-namesake-favors-jesus-not-christianity.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+christianitytoday%2Fctliveblog+%28Christianity+Today+Liveblog%29" target="_blank"><strong>Mumford and Sons</strong></a> are interested in Jesus, but not Christianity or religion. Oh goody. Another cultural icon practicing design-it-yourself religion. But the dude does pick a mean banjo.</p>
<p>Oh my. It seems that for the second year in a row there will be no <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/kosher-coke-california_n_2927282.html?utm_hp_ref=religion&amp;ir=Religion" target="_blank"><strong>kosher Coca-Cola</strong></a> available for Jews in California. That will make it difficult for those who will spend this week wondering in the <a href="http://www.wildernesstorah.org/programs/festivals-general/passover-in-the-desert/" target="_blank"><strong>Mohave Desert</strong></a> leading up to Passover.</p>
<p>Finally, the Synonymous Rambler tells me that no one&#8217;s Holy Week can be complete with a set of <a href="http://www.jewcy.com/religion-and-beliefs/ten-plagues-nail-decals-to-take-your-seder-to-the-next-level?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ten-plagues-nail-decals-to-take-your-seder-to-the-next-level" target="_blank"><strong>Ten Plagues Nail Decals.</strong></a> Sigh. I can&#8217;t wait to get mine.</p>
<p>Installation Week happy birthdays include Pat Nixon; <strong>Jerry Lewis</strong>; Ray Benson; Nat King Cole; John Sebastian; Mia Hamm; John Updike; Earl Warren; Glenn Close; Bruce Willis; Frank Stanton; Bobby Orr; Holly Hunter; Jimmie Vaughan; Erich Kunzel; Chico Marx; Pat Robertson; William Shatner; and Bob Costas.</p>
<p>I never get tired of seeing this. Even though I&#8217;m not a Frenchman, I do like Jerry Lewis. And for those of you under the age of, oh, say, 40, the thing he is pretending to use is called a typewriter. It was a way of putting words on paper. It came between chiseling pictures on rocks and Swype. Enjoy.</p>
<iframe width="640" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/2ozd6W1wyzo" frameborder="0" type="text/html"></iframe><div style="text-align:right;"><a style="color:#aaa;font-size:9px" href="http://www.clickonf5.org/" title="IFRAME Embed for Youtube Free WordPress Plugin" target="_blank">IFRAME Embed for Youtube</a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-3-23-13/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>60</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recommended Reading: Provocative Posts I’ve Spotted around the Web</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/provocative-posts-around-web</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/provocative-posts-around-web#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 04:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Reading]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39732</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tim Gombis ran a most interesting post at his blog this week, discussing a phenomenon he has observed when teaching the Bible to evangelical people in various settings. Gombis remarks that he has become puzzled, for he keeps hearing a particular comment from evangelicals when they learn something new from the Bible. When I began teaching evangelical [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/guy-looking.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-39751" alt="guy-looking" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/guy-looking.jpg" width="480" height="190" /></a></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://timgombis.com/2013/03/20/evangelicals-the-bible/">Tim Gombis ran a most interesting post</a></strong> at his blog this week, discussing a phenomenon he has observed when teaching the Bible to evangelical people in various settings. Gombis remarks that he has become puzzled, for he keeps hearing a particular comment from evangelicals when they learn something new from the Bible.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/gombis.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-39736" alt="gombis" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/gombis.jpg" width="165" height="200" /></a>When I began teaching evangelical undergraduates, it wasn’t long before I heard a student say, <strong>“I’ve never heard this before.”</strong>  My first response was, “I know, and there’s so much more to discover!”</p>
<p>But then I heard another variation: “I’ve never heard this before.  What you’re saying isn’t biblical.”</p>
<p>I asked for clarification.  The student responded by saying, “well, I think there’s a verse somewhere that says something like . . . ,” proceeding to blend together three different passages with the chorus of a praise song.</p>
<p>I figured this sort of thing was just the arrogance of youth, but it began to happen regularly.  Just about three weeks into every semester, a student would raise his or her hand and say, “I’ve never heard this stuff before.”</p>
<p>I began to respond by saying, “you’re welcome!  You or your parents are paying me thousands of dollars to tell you things that you don’t know.  This is what we call ‘education’ and it sounds like I’m doing my job.”</p>
<p>It began to dawn on me, however, that there was something about evangelical culture that was making these students assume that<strong> if something was unfamiliar, it was unbiblical</strong>.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><small><em>(emphasis mine)</em></small></p>
</blockquote>
<p>What surprises and disappoints Tim Gombis is that evangelicals don&#8217;t seem to have the same thrill of discovery that he developed in studying the Bible. They are hesitant about the unfamiliar. He does say these folks from evangelical churches don&#8217;t seem to be <em>challenging</em> him about what he is teaching. Rather, they seem genuinely bewildered about why they don&#8217;t recognize what he is teaching as &#8220;biblical.&#8221;</p>
<p>Is this just an anecdotal observation from a single Bible teacher, or has Tim Gombis uncovered something potentially significant here, a crack in the foundation of &#8220;Bible-believing&#8221; evangelical church life? He thinks it may be significant &#8211;  <em>&#8220;I think this indicates that there’s something warped about how evangelicals regard the Bible.&#8221; </em></p>
<p>I will be following his next few posts to see how he follows up on this initial observation. In the meantime, I thought his comments provocative enough to encourage a good discussion here.</p>
<p>Is it possible that Tim Gombis on to something here?</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/hubble_anniv_adds_01-e1363921016270.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-39752" alt="hubble_anniv_adds_01" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/hubble_anniv_adds_01-e1363921016270.jpg" width="611" height="328" /></a></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.christianitytoday.com/ct/2013/march/bigger-than-we-think.html?paging=off">CT ran a post about creation</a></strong> this week that made my heart sing. <strong>David Wilkinson</strong> encourages us to go beyond the constricted apologetic conflicts that have dominated the subject and move toward <em>&#8220;recapturing the doctrine of Creation in its scriptural fullness.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>And so Wilkinson suggests, for example, that <strong>the Christian doctrine of Creation is never an abstract, academic concept</strong>. We must learn to celebrate creation as the Bible does &#8212; through a rich variety of literary and creative styles and expressions that burst forth with imaginative as well as theological depth. The author notes that these texts are also used for many different purposes in the pages of the Bible: <em> &#8221;to inspire worship, to encourage the weak, to call for holiness, and to offer reassurance in times of trouble.&#8221; </em></p>
<p>We must not forget this and reduce our considerations of this vast and complex theme to opinions and positions to be advanced in culture war debates. To do so is certainly not &#8220;biblical&#8221; &#8212; that is, it does not reflect the inspired witness of Scripture that promotes awe, wonder, and endless adoration of our Creator through exploring his endlessly fascinating creation.</p>
<p>David Wilkinson explores a number of other ways to recapture the fullness of the Bible&#8217;s teaching about creation, including keeping <strong>Christ</strong> at the center of our thinking about creation, and looking at creation through the lens of the <strong>new creation</strong>. In this brief article, he effectively communicates a variety of ways that we can faithfully apply the theology of creation. He commends the value of worship, study, scientific vocations, benevolent care for our environment, and, most of all, pursuing a faith relationship with the personal God who has breathed life into us, his creatures.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Pope-Francis-e1363922233222.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-39755" alt="Pope Francis" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Pope-Francis-e1363922233222.jpg" width="597" height="310" /></a></p>
<p>Finally, I recommend <strong>Matthew B. Redmond&#8217;s</strong> cautionary post on <strong><a href="http://mattbredmond.com/2013/03/15/the-new-pope-luther-and-our-need-to-take-aim-at-ourselves/">how certain evangelicals have greeted the new Pope with various forms o</a></strong><a href="http://mattbredmond.com/2013/03/15/the-new-pope-luther-and-our-need-to-take-aim-at-ourselves/"><strong>f contempt</strong></a>. Matt&#8217;s incisive point is captured in this paragraph:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>And then it landed on me this morning. The reason I was ill at ease about evangelicals making light of the papal process and then using Luther to defend it was this. <strong>Luther was taking aim at his own tradition</strong>. Not the tradition of his neighbor alone. Luther was not trying to start a new religion or denomination or sect. He was trying to reform the church already there. Luther was Roman Catholic, if you will. not Lutheran.</em></p>
<p>Therefore, Redmond suggests, if certain people want to re-fight the Reformation or be like Luther, they ought to take aim at their own traditions, not Roman Catholicism.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Here is what I think, you wanna be like Luther? Set your aim on all the silliness with evangelicalism. The legalism. The celebrity. The concerts disguised as worship. The worship disguised as concerts. The marketing ad nauseum. The legalism. The calls for radical living from pastors with iPads and iPhones who live in the suburbs with 3 bedrooms and 2 baths. Set your aim on the cover-up of sexual abuse. The legalism. Set your aim on a theology that questions everything and stands for nothing. The pastor as CEO. The pastor as rock star. The legalism.</em></p>
<p>You go, Matt. Kudos for calling out those who are sitting in their little neo-reformed bunkers and lobbing bombs at the Catholic Church and its new leader.</p>
<p>Frankly, I heard more wisdom in just a few lines of Pope Francis&#8217;s message at his Installation Mass than I&#8217;ve read in many pages of neo-reformed ranting. <em>“Let us not forget that hatred, envy and pride defile our lives,”</em> he said in his homily. <em>“We must not be afraid of goodness or even tenderness.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>You tell me which is more Jesus-shaped.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/provocative-posts-around-web/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>107</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Difficult Scriptures: The Sermon On The Mount</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/difficult-scriptures-the-sermon-on-the-mount</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/difficult-scriptures-the-sermon-on-the-mount#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 04:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Difficult Scriptures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39731</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I saw it coming, just like you sometimes see a car wreck coming. The preacher used the verses in Matthew&#8217;s account of Jesus&#8217; most well-known sermon dealing with divorce to talk about marriage. He talked about strengthening our marriages and how important marriage is to God. How the family is the first institute ordained by [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/illustrationwrestling3.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-39744" alt="illustrationwrestling" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/illustrationwrestling3-300x266.jpg" width="300" height="266" /></a>I saw it coming, just like you sometimes see a car wreck coming. The preacher used the verses in Matthew&#8217;s account of Jesus&#8217; most well-known sermon dealing with divorce to talk about marriage. He talked about strengthening our marriages and how important marriage is to God. How the family is the first institute ordained by God and how wrong divorce is. All from two verses in Matthew 5. Quite impressive.</p>
<p>But is that what Jesus was trying to get across? Is the Sermon on the Mount Jesus&#8217; life principles for how we are to live in order to please God? If so, they are some very serious life principles to try to live up to. No looking at pretty women. No getting mad at a jerk. Injustice? If you get sued and they take you coat, give them your shirt, too. Enemies? Go over and above to serve them, and don&#8217;t forget to include them in your prayers. And then to top it all off, if you want to make it to heaven, your righteousness has to be greater than the most righteous people on earth. And once you&#8217;re done with that, there&#8217;s one more thing. Be perfect.</p>
<p>Is Jesus really telling us to roll up our spiritual sleeves and get with it? I don&#8217;t think so. Jesus is a shepherd, and he is herding his flock with his staff of words. And his words&#8212;be perfect, for example&#8212;are directing us to his destination: the narrow gate. He leads us to the point where we see we have nothing, absolutely nothing, with which to get us through a gate any larger than a cross will fit through.</p>
<p>So, what is the purpose of the Sermon on the Mount? Are we to take life lessons and apply them so we can try for the &#8220;better righteousness&#8221;? Or is Jesus setting impossible standards so we can see that we have to rely solely on his righteousness? Or is there something else I&#8217;m missing?</p>
<p>Ok iMonks, you know the drill. Wrestle this out. But no eye gouging, and no biting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/difficult-scriptures-the-sermon-on-the-mount/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>86</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Brief Allegory Of The Communion Of Saints</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/a-brief-allegory-of-the-communion-of-saints</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/a-brief-allegory-of-the-communion-of-saints#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 16:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Damaris Zehner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Damaris Zehner]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39726</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From time to time on Internet Monk a commenter will express discomfort with the Orthodox and Catholic tradition of acknowledging the communion of saints.  Someone will object to “praying to Mary” or “worshipping saints.”  Let me offer a parable in response. Imagine a young woman who meets and falls in love with a man – [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/slide-5-communion-of-saints.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-39727" alt="slide-5-communion-of-saints" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/slide-5-communion-of-saints.jpg" width="400" height="254" /></a>From time to time on Internet Monk a commenter will express discomfort with the Orthodox and Catholic tradition of acknowledging the communion of saints.  Someone will object to “praying to Mary” or “worshipping saints.”  Let me offer a parable in response.</p>
<p>Imagine a young woman who meets and falls in love with a man – Let’s call him Josh.  They meet away from each other’s homes, perhaps at work or at college.  When they get engaged, Josh invites her home to get to know his family.</p>
<p>She’s nervous, of course.  Josh is a wonderful guy – far better than she deserves, she thinks.  She’s amazed that he picked her out of all the girls in the world.  Her chief concern everywhere they go is to show Josh how much she loves him and is faithful to him alone.</p>
<p>They pull up to his family’s house.  A surprising number of people are silhouetted against the windows, and the front and back yards are full of clusters of conversationalists.  As they get out of the car, she can hear people young and old talking about other times, other places; about science, and philosophy, and humor.  She feels slightly intimidated and grabs hold of Josh’s hand.  He smiles at her and brings her in to meet his mother and siblings.</p>
<p><span id="more-39726"></span></p>
<p>The story is pretty familiar and predictable up to this point.  Many of us have been through something like this.  But here is where she has a choice – option A and option B.</p>
<p>Option A goes like this:  She gets swept into a noisy crowd of people who all want to meet her; Josh is left behind.  They hug her, ask her questions, laugh, get her a drink – they make her feel at home.  She soon knows that not only has she found a husband, she’s been adopted into a clan.  Some of them, to be honest, seem a bit strange, but she reminds herself that she must seem strange to them.  After an hour or so, she catches Josh’s eye across the room and gives him a wave and a thumbs-up.  He’s delighted.  Eventually he will drive her home, and they can be alone to talk, but right now the music’s starting up and she’s being pulled into a dance.</p>
<p>Option B, on the other hand, looks this way:  Josh brings his fiancée up to his mother, who is sitting on the sofa surrounded by smiling relatives.  But instead of responding to his mother’s greeting, the girl turns back to Josh and holds his hand more tightly.  She does the same thing as aunts and uncles and cousins come to welcome her; she won’t meet their eyes or talk to them.  Though she doesn’t go so far as to stick her fingers in her ears and chant, her posture suggests that she would if she could.  Soon she pulls Josh away to an isolated corner, leaving bewildered and slightly offended people behind her.</p>
<p>“What’s the matter with you?”  Josh asks.  “Why won’t you talk to my family?  They’re important to me, and they were excited about welcoming you.”</p>
<p>“No way!”  she declares.  “I love you and only you.  I’m not going to dilute our relationship or get distracted from you by spending any time with those other people.  If our friends saw me talking to your cousins, they might think I was being unfaithful.”</p>
<p>The allegory is obvious.  The young woman is any Christian, Josh is Jesus, his mother is Mary, and his family represents the communion of saints, alive and dead.  I’ve told the story this way to show how ungracious, at the very least, it is to Jesus and his family to ignore everyone but him.  The girl is not going to marry everyone else in the clan, of course, but she will be a part of them forever.  I’m sympathetic to the girl’s impulse to be exclusively committed to her fiancé, but she needs to ask herself, how does it glorify him to be scornful of everyone else who loves him?</p>
<p>Many people who are uncomfortable with acknowledging the saints raise the point that saints are dead.  It’s one thing, they say, to visit, pray with, eat with or complain to living people – they are happy to do all those things with their fellow (living) Christians.  But conversation with dead people leaves them feeling squeamish.  What are the mechanics of talking to dead people, anyway?  Are we praying to them as if they were gods?  Are we invoking their ectoplasm through a séance?  Or are we just talking to the ceiling like forgetful old people in nursing homes murmuring to lost loved ones?  As a result of this confusion, many people react to the communion of saints like the young woman in the example above and determinedly ignore them.</p>
<p>I have no clue what the mechanics of “talking to the dead” are.  In fact, I don’t think you can talk to the dead.  You can talk to the resurrected, though – the Gospels prove that.  Samuel Wesley, a Protestant of the 19<sup>th</sup> century, wrote in “The Church’s One Foundation” of the “mystic sweet communion” we have “with those whose rest is won.”  It’s not a new idea that those who loved and served the Body of Christ while they were here on earth still do so now (whatever “now” means once one has left the temporal world behind).  The saints in glory are my in-laws, my new family, as are the Christians who are still in this world.  I won’t worship them, and I will only “pray” to them in the seventeenth-century usage of the word meaning to request attention of them.</p>
<p>I should acknowledge that there is one more option that our imaginary young woman has.  She could make such close friends of Josh’s mother or other relatives that she does end up neglecting him.  That would result in a dysfunctional relationship, which is an ugly thing, literally or allegorically.  There are wives who have done so with their husbands and Christians who have done so with their Savior.</p>
<p>But let’s not overcompensate and snub Jesus’ family out of fear of idolatry.  God sets the lonely in families, and our family of “happy ones and holy” is greater than we can imagine.  So let’s take our fingers out of our ears and make eye contact; let’s plunge into the party.  Rejoice, kick your shoes off, and join in the dance.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/a-brief-allegory-of-the-communion-of-saints/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>113</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Swimming The Tiber, Or Just Taking A Quick Dip?</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/swimming-the-tiber-or-just-taking-a-quick-dip</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/swimming-the-tiber-or-just-taking-a-quick-dip#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 05:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39708</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is an understandable lovefest surrounding the new pope, and not only from Catholics. Anglicans, Orthodox, and evangelical leaders are all praising the new servant of the servants of God. Jewish rabbis are looking forward to stronger relations with the Vatican because of Francis. Even Baptists are cautiously optimistic that this new pope will prove [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/tiber-diver-AFP.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-39721" alt="tiber-diver-AFP" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/tiber-diver-AFP.jpg" width="430" height="257" /></a>There is an understandable lovefest surrounding the new pope, and not only from Catholics. Anglicans, Orthodox, and evangelical leaders are all praising the new servant of the servants of God. Jewish rabbis are looking forward to stronger relations with the Vatican because of Francis. Even Baptists are cautiously optimistic that this new pope will prove to be the actual anti-Christ so the rapture can occur and none of them will be left behind. (Kidding, I&#8217;m kidding. Kind of.)</p>
<p>I have made it clear that I am an evangelical. Have been for nearly 40 years, all of the time I&#8217;ve walked with the Lord. I came to faith in an American Baptist church in southwest Ohio where I was taught that anyone who went to any other Protestant church might be a Christian, but barely if that. And that no Catholic could be a Christian. Ever. For any reason. Catholics worshipped dead people and put the pope above Scripture and even above Jesus. I was told that Catholicism was a cult, just like Mormons or Jehovah Witnesses. For years during testimony time I heard the phrase &#8220;I used to be a Catholic, then I got saved and became a Christian.&#8221;</p>
<p>Lately, however, I have been feeling a tug to look more closely at the Catholic Church. Maybe it is just to have a better understanding of Catholicism. Maybe to purge some of my earlier anti-Catholic teachings. Maybe, just maybe, because I feel my time as an evangelical may come to an end. I don&#8217;t know. In any case, I want to spend some time this morning, and again this afternoon, looking at several books I&#8217;ve been browsing lately regarding the Church past and present. These are not meant as in-depth book reviews, merely as jumping off places for discussion.</p>
<p>Where I would really like to start is at the feet of Martha of Ireland, our resident Catholic scholar. I would gladly travel to Ireland and search for her hiding place. Then I would soak up her knowledge of the history of the Church, as well as her insights into where it is headed. Unfortunately, time and money don&#8217;t permit an Irish adventure just now. So I have had to settle for some book learnin&#8217;.</p>
<p><span id="more-39708"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/history-church.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-39720" alt="history church" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/history-church.jpg" width="260" height="371" /></a>My first stop was James Hitchcock&#8217;s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1586176641/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1586176641&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=goonewdai-20"><em>History of the Catholic Church: From the Apostolic Age to the Third Millennium</em></a><img style="border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=goonewdai-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1586176641" width="1" height="1" border="0" />. The 580 page hardcover book was imposing when I received it from Amazon. It is not small, but how could a book covering 2000 years be small if it is to be of any worth whatsoever?</p>
<p>The first thing I realized as I read through Hitchcock&#8217;s work is this is much more than a history of the Catholic Church. It is the history of Western culture. The Church didn&#8217;t exist as today&#8217;s evangelical and mainline Protestant churches do, in a semi-ghetto-like setting, separate from the rest of the world. The Church <em>was</em> the world, at least the Western world.</p>
<p>He starts with the world as it existed just before the incarnation of the Christ, and slowly takes us through the first decades after Jesus&#8217; death and resurrection. You get a feel for just how fragile this new Christian sect was. If persecution from Rome didn&#8217;t threaten them, persecution from Jews did. And how this fledgling faith survived the many heresies that emerged is a miracle unto itself. This story is a rip-roarin&#8217; read, let me tell you.</p>
<p>This is not an academic book, though Hitchcock is a respected professor of history at Saint Louis University. There are no footnotes to be found, which for me is both good and bad. Bad in the sense that I found myself wanting to check his source to see if I could delve deeper into a topic, and good because footnotes are speed bumps for the eyes that make reading much more tedious. There is a suggested bibliography to go with each chapter, so you can get an idea where his thoughts come from.</p>
<p>Hitchcock paints for the most part a very favorable picture of the Catholic Church. Yes, there were some scandals and excesses too grand for him to brush over, but these are eclipsed by all the greatness the Church accomplished. I&#8217;m not trying to say he has painted unfairly; this is his book and his history. And it is not meant as an in-depth critique, or even an in-depth history for that matter. This is a leisurely journey from 30,000 feet. You can see below you, but not in any great detail. Still, this is an extremely enjoyable and informative book, one that I will be referring to again and again.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/popes.jpeg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-39719" alt="popes" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/popes.jpeg" width="128" height="194" /></a>Of course, a great deal of the history of the Catholic Church must, by its very nature, be a look at the various popes, from Peter to Benedict XVI. For that I turned to Fr. John O&#8217;Malley&#8217;s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1580512283/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1580512283&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=goonewdai-20"><em>A History of the Popes: From Peter to the Present</em></a><img style="border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=goonewdai-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1580512283" width="1" height="1" border="0" />. Once again, O&#8217;Malley starts at the beginning, which is not always the best place to start a story, but for a history lesson, it is rather necessary. He gives an apologetic for Peter being the foundation of apostolic succession, which was helpful for this Protestant.</p>
<p>Then O&#8217;Malley takes off on a wild ride throughout the papacy. Once again, we don&#8217;t just learn about the Church, but the world around the Church and how each affected the other. O&#8217;Malley doesn&#8217;t pull any punches. If a certain pope was a stinker, he says so in detail. And there were many more stinkers than I ever suspected. But here is what comes through in this portrait: Yes, there were men who were lecherous, selfish, greedy crooks who wore the pontiff&#8217;s robes. There were some who were incompetent in every way. There were some who had good hearts but surrounded themselves with those with black hearts.</p>
<p>And yet the Church has survived. It has not only survived, but today Pope Francis has a platform to proclaim the Gospel unlike at any other time in history.</p>
<p>From both of these books I see something remarkable: The faithfulness of God. No, I don&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s remarkable that God is faithful. I mean that, in spite of the very best efforts of men and women to muck everything up, God loves us and is merciful beyond measure. This is not a story of a perfect religion with just a few bad apples. This is a picture of a gnarled, worm-ridden apple being held by Someone who says he will give all he has to buy it for it is beautiful in his eyes. My eyes have been opened, however slightly, to the grandness and realness of the Catholic Church. Could there be a home there for me? If St. Malachy is correct in his prophecies, I don&#8217;t have much time to decide.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/swimming-the-tiber-or-just-taking-a-quick-dip/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>163</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic
Page Caching using disk: enhanced

 Served from: www.internetmonk.com @ 2013-03-25 11:02:13 by W3 Total Cache -->
