<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/" xmlns:creativeCommons="http://backend.userland.com/creativeCommonsRssModule" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>internetmonk.com</title>
	
	<link>http://www.internetmonk.com</link>
	<description>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 04:27:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
<!-- podcast_generator="Blubrry PowerPress/4.0.7" -->
	<itunes:summary>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:author>The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer</itunes:author>
	<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/monkposterx3.jpg" />
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer</itunes:name>
		<itunes:email>michael@internetmonk.com</itunes:email>
	</itunes:owner>
	<managingEditor>michael@internetmonk.com (The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer)</managingEditor>
	<copyright>2006-2009</copyright>
	<itunes:subtitle>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</itunes:subtitle>
	<image><link>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</link><url>http://creativecommons.org/images/public/somerights20.gif</url><title>Some Rights Reserved</title></image>
	<itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
		<itunes:category text="Christianity" />
	</itunes:category>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/internetmonk/SWqj" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="internetmonk/swqj" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license><feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">internetmonk/SWqj</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>Recommended Reading: Provocative Posts I’ve Spotted around the Web</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/provocative-posts-around-web</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/provocative-posts-around-web#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 04:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Reading]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39732</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tim Gombis ran a most interesting post at his blog this week, discussing a phenomenon he has observed when teaching the Bible to evangelical people in various settings. Gombis remarks that he has become puzzled, for he keeps hearing a particular comment from evangelicals when they learn something new from the Bible. When I began teaching evangelical [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/guy-looking.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-39751" alt="guy-looking" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/guy-looking.jpg" width="480" height="190" /></a></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://timgombis.com/2013/03/20/evangelicals-the-bible/">Tim Gombis ran a most interesting post</a></strong> at his blog this week, discussing a phenomenon he has observed when teaching the Bible to evangelical people in various settings. Gombis remarks that he has become puzzled, for he keeps hearing a particular comment from evangelicals when they learn something new from the Bible.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/gombis.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-39736" alt="gombis" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/gombis.jpg" width="165" height="200" /></a>When I began teaching evangelical undergraduates, it wasn’t long before I heard a student say, <strong>“I’ve never heard this before.”</strong>  My first response was, “I know, and there’s so much more to discover!”</p>
<p>But then I heard another variation: “I’ve never heard this before.  What you’re saying isn’t biblical.”</p>
<p>I asked for clarification.  The student responded by saying, “well, I think there’s a verse somewhere that says something like . . . ,” proceeding to blend together three different passages with the chorus of a praise song.</p>
<p>I figured this sort of thing was just the arrogance of youth, but it began to happen regularly.  Just about three weeks into every semester, a student would raise his or her hand and say, “I’ve never heard this stuff before.”</p>
<p>I began to respond by saying, “you’re welcome!  You or your parents are paying me thousands of dollars to tell you things that you don’t know.  This is what we call ‘education’ and it sounds like I’m doing my job.”</p>
<p>It began to dawn on me, however, that there was something about evangelical culture that was making these students assume that<strong> if something was unfamiliar, it was unbiblical</strong>.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><small><em>(emphasis mine)</em></small></p>
</blockquote>
<p>What surprises and disappoints Tim Gombis is that evangelicals don&#8217;t seem to have the same thrill of discovery that he developed in studying the Bible. They are hesitant about the unfamiliar. He does say these folks from evangelical churches don&#8217;t seem to be <em>challenging</em> him about what he is teaching. Rather, they seem genuinely bewildered about why they don&#8217;t recognize what he is teaching as &#8220;biblical.&#8221;</p>
<p>Is this just an anecdotal observation from a single Bible teacher, or has Tim Gombis uncovered something potentially significant here, a crack in the foundation of &#8220;Bible-believing&#8221; evangelical church life? He thinks it may be significant &#8211;  <em>&#8220;I think this indicates that there’s something warped about how evangelicals regard the Bible.&#8221; </em></p>
<p>I will be following his next few posts to see how he follows up on this initial observation. In the meantime, I thought his comments provocative enough to encourage a good discussion here.</p>
<p>Is it possible that Tim Gombis on to something here?</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/hubble_anniv_adds_01-e1363921016270.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-39752" alt="hubble_anniv_adds_01" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/hubble_anniv_adds_01-e1363921016270.jpg" width="611" height="328" /></a></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.christianitytoday.com/ct/2013/march/bigger-than-we-think.html?paging=off">CT ran a post about creation</a></strong> this week that made my heart sing. <strong>David Wilkinson</strong> encourages us to go beyond the constricted apologetic conflicts that have dominated the subject and move toward <em>&#8220;recapturing the doctrine of Creation in its scriptural fullness.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>And so Wilkinson suggests, for example, that <strong>the Christian doctrine of Creation is never an abstract, academic concept</strong>. We must learn to celebrate creation as the Bible does &#8212; through a rich variety of literary and creative styles and expressions that burst forth with imaginative as well as theological depth. The author notes that these texts are also used for many different purposes in the pages of the Bible: <em> &#8221;to inspire worship, to encourage the weak, to call for holiness, and to offer reassurance in times of trouble.&#8221; </em></p>
<p>We must not forget this and reduce our considerations of this vast and complex theme to opinions and positions to be advanced in culture war debates. To do so is certainly not &#8220;biblical&#8221; &#8212; that is, it does not reflect the inspired witness of Scripture that promotes awe, wonder, and endless adoration of our Creator through exploring his endlessly fascinating creation.</p>
<p>David Wilkinson explores a number of other ways to recapture the fullness of the Bible&#8217;s teaching about creation, including keeping <strong>Christ</strong> at the center of our thinking about creation, and looking at creation through the lens of the <strong>new creation</strong>. In this brief article, he effectively communicates a variety of ways that we can faithfully apply the theology of creation. He commends the value of worship, study, scientific vocations, benevolent care for our environment, and, most of all, pursuing a faith relationship with the personal God who has breathed life into us, his creatures.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Pope-Francis-e1363922233222.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-39755" alt="Pope Francis" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Pope-Francis-e1363922233222.jpg" width="597" height="310" /></a></p>
<p>Finally, I recommend <strong>Matthew B. Redmond&#8217;s</strong> cautionary post on <strong><a href="http://mattbredmond.com/2013/03/15/the-new-pope-luther-and-our-need-to-take-aim-at-ourselves/">how certain evangelicals have greeted the new Pope with various forms o</a></strong><a href="http://mattbredmond.com/2013/03/15/the-new-pope-luther-and-our-need-to-take-aim-at-ourselves/"><strong>f contempt</strong></a>. Matt&#8217;s incisive point is captured in this paragraph:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>And then it landed on me this morning. The reason I was ill at ease about evangelicals making light of the papal process and then using Luther to defend it was this. <strong>Luther was taking aim at his own tradition</strong>. Not the tradition of his neighbor alone. Luther was not trying to start a new religion or denomination or sect. He was trying to reform the church already there. Luther was Roman Catholic, if you will. not Lutheran.</em></p>
<p>Therefore, Redmond suggests, if certain people want to re-fight the Reformation or be like Luther, they ought to take aim at their own traditions, not Roman Catholicism.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Here is what I think, you wanna be like Luther? Set your aim on all the silliness with evangelicalism. The legalism. The celebrity. The concerts disguised as worship. The worship disguised as concerts. The marketing ad nauseum. The legalism. The calls for radical living from pastors with iPads and iPhones who live in the suburbs with 3 bedrooms and 2 baths. Set your aim on the cover-up of sexual abuse. The legalism. Set your aim on a theology that questions everything and stands for nothing. The pastor as CEO. The pastor as rock star. The legalism.</em></p>
<p>You go, Matt. Kudos for calling out those who are sitting in their little neo-reformed bunkers and lobbing bombs at the Catholic Church and its new leader.</p>
<p>Frankly, I heard more wisdom in just a few lines of Pope Francis&#8217;s message at his Installation Mass than I&#8217;ve read in many pages of neo-reformed ranting. <em>“Let us not forget that hatred, envy and pride defile our lives,”</em> he said in his homily. <em>“We must not be afraid of goodness or even tenderness.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>You tell me which is more Jesus-shaped.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/provocative-posts-around-web/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Difficult Scriptures: The Sermon On The Mount</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/difficult-scriptures-the-sermon-on-the-mount</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/difficult-scriptures-the-sermon-on-the-mount#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 04:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Difficult Scriptures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39731</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I saw it coming, just like you sometimes see a car wreck coming. The preacher used the verses in Matthew&#8217;s account of Jesus&#8217; most well-known sermon dealing with divorce to talk about marriage. He talked about strengthening our marriages and how important marriage is to God. How the family is the first institute ordained by [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/illustrationwrestling3.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-39744" alt="illustrationwrestling" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/illustrationwrestling3-300x266.jpg" width="300" height="266" /></a>I saw it coming, just like you sometimes see a car wreck coming. The preacher used the verses in Matthew&#8217;s account of Jesus&#8217; most well-known sermon dealing with divorce to talk about marriage. He talked about strengthening our marriages and how important marriage is to God. How the family is the first institute ordained by God and how wrong divorce is. All from two verses in Matthew 5. Quite impressive.</p>
<p>But is that what Jesus was trying to get across? Is the Sermon on the Mount Jesus&#8217; life principles for how we are to live in order to please God? If so, they are some very serious life principles to try to live up to. No looking at pretty women. No getting mad at a jerk. Injustice? If you get sued and they take you coat, give them your shirt, too. Enemies? Go over and above to serve them, and don&#8217;t forget to include them in your prayers. And then to top it all off, if you want to make it to heaven, your righteousness has to be greater than the most righteous people on earth. And once you&#8217;re done with that, there&#8217;s one more thing. Be perfect.</p>
<p>Is Jesus really telling us to roll up our spiritual sleeves and get with it? I don&#8217;t think so. Jesus is a shepherd, and he is herding his flock with his staff of words. And his words&#8212;be perfect, for example&#8212;are directing us to his destination: the narrow gate. He leads us to the point where we see we have nothing, absolutely nothing, with which to get us through a gate any larger than a cross will fit through.</p>
<p>So, what is the purpose of the Sermon on the Mount? Are we to take life lessons and apply them so we can try for the &#8220;better righteousness&#8221;? Or is Jesus setting impossible standards so we can see that we have to rely solely on his righteousness? Or is there something else I&#8217;m missing?</p>
<p>Ok iMonks, you know the drill. Wrestle this out. But no eye gouging, and no biting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/difficult-scriptures-the-sermon-on-the-mount/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>72</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Brief Allegory Of The Communion Of Saints</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/a-brief-allegory-of-the-communion-of-saints</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/a-brief-allegory-of-the-communion-of-saints#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 16:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Damaris Zehner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Damaris Zehner]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39726</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From time to time on Internet Monk a commenter will express discomfort with the Orthodox and Catholic tradition of acknowledging the communion of saints.  Someone will object to “praying to Mary” or “worshipping saints.”  Let me offer a parable in response. Imagine a young woman who meets and falls in love with a man – [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/slide-5-communion-of-saints.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-39727" alt="slide-5-communion-of-saints" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/slide-5-communion-of-saints.jpg" width="400" height="254" /></a>From time to time on Internet Monk a commenter will express discomfort with the Orthodox and Catholic tradition of acknowledging the communion of saints.  Someone will object to “praying to Mary” or “worshipping saints.”  Let me offer a parable in response.</p>
<p>Imagine a young woman who meets and falls in love with a man – Let’s call him Josh.  They meet away from each other’s homes, perhaps at work or at college.  When they get engaged, Josh invites her home to get to know his family.</p>
<p>She’s nervous, of course.  Josh is a wonderful guy – far better than she deserves, she thinks.  She’s amazed that he picked her out of all the girls in the world.  Her chief concern everywhere they go is to show Josh how much she loves him and is faithful to him alone.</p>
<p>They pull up to his family’s house.  A surprising number of people are silhouetted against the windows, and the front and back yards are full of clusters of conversationalists.  As they get out of the car, she can hear people young and old talking about other times, other places; about science, and philosophy, and humor.  She feels slightly intimidated and grabs hold of Josh’s hand.  He smiles at her and brings her in to meet his mother and siblings.</p>
<p><span id="more-39726"></span></p>
<p>The story is pretty familiar and predictable up to this point.  Many of us have been through something like this.  But here is where she has a choice – option A and option B.</p>
<p>Option A goes like this:  She gets swept into a noisy crowd of people who all want to meet her; Josh is left behind.  They hug her, ask her questions, laugh, get her a drink – they make her feel at home.  She soon knows that not only has she found a husband, she’s been adopted into a clan.  Some of them, to be honest, seem a bit strange, but she reminds herself that she must seem strange to them.  After an hour or so, she catches Josh’s eye across the room and gives him a wave and a thumbs-up.  He’s delighted.  Eventually he will drive her home, and they can be alone to talk, but right now the music’s starting up and she’s being pulled into a dance.</p>
<p>Option B, on the other hand, looks this way:  Josh brings his fiancée up to his mother, who is sitting on the sofa surrounded by smiling relatives.  But instead of responding to his mother’s greeting, the girl turns back to Josh and holds his hand more tightly.  She does the same thing as aunts and uncles and cousins come to welcome her; she won’t meet their eyes or talk to them.  Though she doesn’t go so far as to stick her fingers in her ears and chant, her posture suggests that she would if she could.  Soon she pulls Josh away to an isolated corner, leaving bewildered and slightly offended people behind her.</p>
<p>“What’s the matter with you?”  Josh asks.  “Why won’t you talk to my family?  They’re important to me, and they were excited about welcoming you.”</p>
<p>“No way!”  she declares.  “I love you and only you.  I’m not going to dilute our relationship or get distracted from you by spending any time with those other people.  If our friends saw me talking to your cousins, they might think I was being unfaithful.”</p>
<p>The allegory is obvious.  The young woman is any Christian, Josh is Jesus, his mother is Mary, and his family represents the communion of saints, alive and dead.  I’ve told the story this way to show how ungracious, at the very least, it is to Jesus and his family to ignore everyone but him.  The girl is not going to marry everyone else in the clan, of course, but she will be a part of them forever.  I’m sympathetic to the girl’s impulse to be exclusively committed to her fiancé, but she needs to ask herself, how does it glorify him to be scornful of everyone else who loves him?</p>
<p>Many people who are uncomfortable with acknowledging the saints raise the point that saints are dead.  It’s one thing, they say, to visit, pray with, eat with or complain to living people – they are happy to do all those things with their fellow (living) Christians.  But conversation with dead people leaves them feeling squeamish.  What are the mechanics of talking to dead people, anyway?  Are we praying to them as if they were gods?  Are we invoking their ectoplasm through a séance?  Or are we just talking to the ceiling like forgetful old people in nursing homes murmuring to lost loved ones?  As a result of this confusion, many people react to the communion of saints like the young woman in the example above and determinedly ignore them.</p>
<p>I have no clue what the mechanics of “talking to the dead” are.  In fact, I don’t think you can talk to the dead.  You can talk to the resurrected, though – the Gospels prove that.  Samuel Wesley, a Protestant of the 19<sup>th</sup> century, wrote in “The Church’s One Foundation” of the “mystic sweet communion” we have “with those whose rest is won.”  It’s not a new idea that those who loved and served the Body of Christ while they were here on earth still do so now (whatever “now” means once one has left the temporal world behind).  The saints in glory are my in-laws, my new family, as are the Christians who are still in this world.  I won’t worship them, and I will only “pray” to them in the seventeenth-century usage of the word meaning to request attention of them.</p>
<p>I should acknowledge that there is one more option that our imaginary young woman has.  She could make such close friends of Josh’s mother or other relatives that she does end up neglecting him.  That would result in a dysfunctional relationship, which is an ugly thing, literally or allegorically.  There are wives who have done so with their husbands and Christians who have done so with their Savior.</p>
<p>But let’s not overcompensate and snub Jesus’ family out of fear of idolatry.  God sets the lonely in families, and our family of “happy ones and holy” is greater than we can imagine.  So let’s take our fingers out of our ears and make eye contact; let’s plunge into the party.  Rejoice, kick your shoes off, and join in the dance.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/a-brief-allegory-of-the-communion-of-saints/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>104</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Swimming The Tiber, Or Just Taking A Quick Dip?</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/swimming-the-tiber-or-just-taking-a-quick-dip</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/swimming-the-tiber-or-just-taking-a-quick-dip#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 05:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39708</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is an understandable lovefest surrounding the new pope, and not only from Catholics. Anglicans, Orthodox, and evangelical leaders are all praising the new servant of the servants of God. Jewish rabbis are looking forward to stronger relations with the Vatican because of Francis. Even Baptists are cautiously optimistic that this new pope will prove [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/tiber-diver-AFP.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-39721" alt="tiber-diver-AFP" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/tiber-diver-AFP.jpg" width="430" height="257" /></a>There is an understandable lovefest surrounding the new pope, and not only from Catholics. Anglicans, Orthodox, and evangelical leaders are all praising the new servant of the servants of God. Jewish rabbis are looking forward to stronger relations with the Vatican because of Francis. Even Baptists are cautiously optimistic that this new pope will prove to be the actual anti-Christ so the rapture can occur and none of them will be left behind. (Kidding, I&#8217;m kidding. Kind of.)</p>
<p>I have made it clear that I am an evangelical. Have been for nearly 40 years, all of the time I&#8217;ve walked with the Lord. I came to faith in an American Baptist church in southwest Ohio where I was taught that anyone who went to any other Protestant church might be a Christian, but barely if that. And that no Catholic could be a Christian. Ever. For any reason. Catholics worshipped dead people and put the pope above Scripture and even above Jesus. I was told that Catholicism was a cult, just like Mormons or Jehovah Witnesses. For years during testimony time I heard the phrase &#8220;I used to be a Catholic, then I got saved and became a Christian.&#8221;</p>
<p>Lately, however, I have been feeling a tug to look more closely at the Catholic Church. Maybe it is just to have a better understanding of Catholicism. Maybe to purge some of my earlier anti-Catholic teachings. Maybe, just maybe, because I feel my time as an evangelical may come to an end. I don&#8217;t know. In any case, I want to spend some time this morning, and again this afternoon, looking at several books I&#8217;ve been browsing lately regarding the Church past and present. These are not meant as in-depth book reviews, merely as jumping off places for discussion.</p>
<p>Where I would really like to start is at the feet of Martha of Ireland, our resident Catholic scholar. I would gladly travel to Ireland and search for her hiding place. Then I would soak up her knowledge of the history of the Church, as well as her insights into where it is headed. Unfortunately, time and money don&#8217;t permit an Irish adventure just now. So I have had to settle for some book learnin&#8217;.</p>
<p><span id="more-39708"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/history-church.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-39720" alt="history church" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/history-church.jpg" width="260" height="371" /></a>My first stop was James Hitchcock&#8217;s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1586176641/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1586176641&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=goonewdai-20"><em>History of the Catholic Church: From the Apostolic Age to the Third Millennium</em></a><img style="border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=goonewdai-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1586176641" width="1" height="1" border="0" />. The 580 page hardcover book was imposing when I received it from Amazon. It is not small, but how could a book covering 2000 years be small if it is to be of any worth whatsoever?</p>
<p>The first thing I realized as I read through Hitchcock&#8217;s work is this is much more than a history of the Catholic Church. It is the history of Western culture. The Church didn&#8217;t exist as today&#8217;s evangelical and mainline Protestant churches do, in a semi-ghetto-like setting, separate from the rest of the world. The Church <em>was</em> the world, at least the Western world.</p>
<p>He starts with the world as it existed just before the incarnation of the Christ, and slowly takes us through the first decades after Jesus&#8217; death and resurrection. You get a feel for just how fragile this new Christian sect was. If persecution from Rome didn&#8217;t threaten them, persecution from Jews did. And how this fledgling faith survived the many heresies that emerged is a miracle unto itself. This story is a rip-roarin&#8217; read, let me tell you.</p>
<p>This is not an academic book, though Hitchcock is a respected professor of history at Saint Louis University. There are no footnotes to be found, which for me is both good and bad. Bad in the sense that I found myself wanting to check his source to see if I could delve deeper into a topic, and good because footnotes are speed bumps for the eyes that make reading much more tedious. There is a suggested bibliography to go with each chapter, so you can get an idea where his thoughts come from.</p>
<p>Hitchcock paints for the most part a very favorable picture of the Catholic Church. Yes, there were some scandals and excesses too grand for him to brush over, but these are eclipsed by all the greatness the Church accomplished. I&#8217;m not trying to say he has painted unfairly; this is his book and his history. And it is not meant as an in-depth critique, or even an in-depth history for that matter. This is a leisurely journey from 30,000 feet. You can see below you, but not in any great detail. Still, this is an extremely enjoyable and informative book, one that I will be referring to again and again.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/popes.jpeg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-39719" alt="popes" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/popes.jpeg" width="128" height="194" /></a>Of course, a great deal of the history of the Catholic Church must, by its very nature, be a look at the various popes, from Peter to Benedict XVI. For that I turned to Fr. John O&#8217;Malley&#8217;s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1580512283/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1580512283&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=goonewdai-20"><em>A History of the Popes: From Peter to the Present</em></a><img style="border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=goonewdai-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1580512283" width="1" height="1" border="0" />. Once again, O&#8217;Malley starts at the beginning, which is not always the best place to start a story, but for a history lesson, it is rather necessary. He gives an apologetic for Peter being the foundation of apostolic succession, which was helpful for this Protestant.</p>
<p>Then O&#8217;Malley takes off on a wild ride throughout the papacy. Once again, we don&#8217;t just learn about the Church, but the world around the Church and how each affected the other. O&#8217;Malley doesn&#8217;t pull any punches. If a certain pope was a stinker, he says so in detail. And there were many more stinkers than I ever suspected. But here is what comes through in this portrait: Yes, there were men who were lecherous, selfish, greedy crooks who wore the pontiff&#8217;s robes. There were some who were incompetent in every way. There were some who had good hearts but surrounded themselves with those with black hearts.</p>
<p>And yet the Church has survived. It has not only survived, but today Pope Francis has a platform to proclaim the Gospel unlike at any other time in history.</p>
<p>From both of these books I see something remarkable: The faithfulness of God. No, I don&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s remarkable that God is faithful. I mean that, in spite of the very best efforts of men and women to muck everything up, God loves us and is merciful beyond measure. This is not a story of a perfect religion with just a few bad apples. This is a picture of a gnarled, worm-ridden apple being held by Someone who says he will give all he has to buy it for it is beautiful in his eyes. My eyes have been opened, however slightly, to the grandness and realness of the Catholic Church. Could there be a home there for me? If St. Malachy is correct in his prophecies, I don&#8217;t have much time to decide.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/swimming-the-tiber-or-just-taking-a-quick-dip/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>159</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quitting Christians</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/quitting-christians</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/quitting-christians#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 06:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39709</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am going to stand in for Chaplain Mike for a few days as he takes a well-deserved breather. I have some observations and questions regarding Catholicism I want to lay out before you the next few days. I thought now, with the installation of Pope Francis, was as good a time as any. But [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/jesus-with-woman-at-the-well.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-39710" alt="jesus with woman at the well" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/jesus-with-woman-at-the-well.jpg" width="378" height="378" /></a>I am going to stand in for Chaplain Mike for a few days as he takes a well-deserved breather. I have some observations and questions regarding Catholicism I want to lay out before you the next few days. I thought now, with the installation of Pope Francis, was as good a time as any. But this morning I want to get something off of my chest. I&#8217;ve touched on this before, but now I want to explore it much more fully. This is an emotional issue for me, though I will try to keep my emotions in check so this doesn&#8217;t just turn into a longwinded rant.</p>
<p><strong>I am through looking to Christians for love.</strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;m not talking about romantic love. I&#8217;m not trying come up with the name of the best Christian dating service. My wife would probably have a thing or ten to say about that. No, I&#8217;m talking about something much deeper than romantic love, which can vary with the wind. I&#8217;m referring to love that causes one to care for another in a giving, unselfish manner. And rather than reinvent the wheel, let&#8217;s just go with Gary Chapman&#8217;s &#8220;love languages&#8221;: gift giving, time spent, encouraging words, acts of service, and physical touch. You might be able to come up with other ways to describe love, but these will do for now.</p>
<p>And, just for fun, let&#8217;s revisit the words of Jesus to his disciples on the eve of his crucifixion.</p>
<blockquote><p>My command is this: Love each other as I have loved you. <sup> </sup>Greater love has no one than this: to lay down one’s life for one’s friends. <sup> </sup>You are my friends if you do what I command. <sup> </sup>This is my command: Love each other. (John 15: 12, 13, 17, NIV)</p></blockquote>
<p>Love each other. <em>This is my command: Love each other.</em> Not a suggestion, not a helpful thought. A command.</p>
<p>Now then.</p>
<p><span id="more-39709"></span></p>
<p>I have also made it clear that I suffer from depression. Most of the time it is under control with the medicine I take, the exercise I make myself do, and the rest I get. But there are times when I am under extreme stress that the depression kicks up to &#8220;11&#8243; (&#8220;The numbers all go to eleven. Look, right across the board, eleven, eleven, eleven and&#8230;&#8221;) and I am basically paralyzed. No, it&#8217;s worse than that. I&#8217;m not paralyzed. I despair of life. At times like these I just hide in bed and hope no one will find me. I don&#8217;t just have a headache. I have a lifeache. And I want it to all go away.</p>
<p>I went thru a very rough patch in November when this &#8220;11&#8243; setting on my depression meter stayed there for most of a month. I didn&#8217;t think I could take much more. I shared my story with a good friend and elder at my church.</p>
<p>&#8220;You? Depressed? No, you couldn&#8217;t be. You&#8217;re the most upbeat person I know.&#8221;</p>
<p>Well, what can I say? I wear a really good mask. I tried again with another friend and elder, pulling him out of a Sunday service to pray for me right then. He did, but didn&#8217;t ask any questions or offer any encouragement. It was pray, then head back into the sanctuary. I headed home.</p>
<p>Three more elders, three more &#8220;I&#8217;ll pray for you&#8221; responses, then nothing. I spoke to our senior pastor, telling him I even had suicidal thoughts (fleeting; but still) in my despair. I stood there crying as I shared what had been going on in my life and how it had stripped me of just about everything. Our pastor told me he was proud of me for hanging in there. <em>Excuse me. Did you hear what I just said? I despair of life so very much I thought about ending it all.</em> That was my unspoken thought. <em>Surely he&#8217;ll call me this week to get together for coffee and talk about this some more.</em> No call. No coffee. No talk. No care.</p>
<p>I talked with four other pastors at our church. One has gotten together with me on a couple of occasions for some good, honest talk. The other three? Nada. A couple of the elders told me to call them if I was having another bad day, as if depression was the same as just feeling blue. Do they not know that those of us with depression could no more pick up the phone, call someone and say &#8220;I&#8217;m having a bad day&#8221; than we could learn to fly?</p>
<p>iMonk writer Adam Palmer, who goes to my church, does care. He will text me out of the blue to check on me. He&#8217;ll hunt me down in church to tell me about some obscure indie group he discovered that he thinks I would like as well. (He&#8217;s almost always right.) Adam doesn&#8217;t coddle me or patronize me. He just loves me.</p>
<p>He loves me. Well, there&#8217;s one.</p>
<p>Do you know what it feels like to have someone love you not for anything you can do for them, but just because of who you are? Even when you are totally messed up and are fighting just to make it one more hour? It is like cold water in the desert.</p>
<p>One person. One person from my church cares enough to show me love when I need it. What about other Christians I know? The short answer is <em>No</em>. A little longer answer is <em>Hell No</em>. One good friend, for instance, refuses to say or show love because it might be inappropriate. Inappropriate? And I suppose Jesus&#8217; love was always appropriate? No, it wasn&#8217;t. Wherever Jesus went he created scandals with his love. His love at a wedding feast created a scandal with the host. His love for sinners he invited to dinner was always getting him in trouble. His love for a man possessed by demons created a scandal when he freed him and sent a herd of pigs&#8212;some person&#8217;s livelihood&#8212;into the sea. And what a scandal he caused by talking to the woman at the well. Not only a woman, but a slut. Not only that, but a Samaritan slut. He loved these and more. Lepers. Bleeding women. Blind and lame men and women. Sinners. Losers. He loved them all, and this caused a great uproar and scandal. But Jesus refused to put his love in a nice, neat box that would be walled in by appropriateness and law and being a good person. He refused to water down his love with rules and regulations and boundaries. His love was full and complete and unconditional and totally scandalous. Of the millions that surrounded Jesus as he walked the roads of Israel, only a handful received his love. And to this day, of the billions who consider themselves Christians, only a handful will really receive his love without adding conditions and codicils and footnotes to it.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve mentioned a coworker I call Smokey. She is a young agnostic tatted-up woman who wants nothing to do with Jesus. But once I explained to her that I was struggling with depression, Smokey has been there daily to tell me she loves me. She asks me what she can do to help me. She gives me little gifts, like a cup of ice water or a handful of yogurt-covered almonds. She volunteers to do extra work, work she wouldn&#8217;t have to do, to take a bit off of my plate. Smokey shows me more love than just about any Christian I know. There is nothing romantic about her love. There is nothing inappropriate. There is only what Jesus told us, his disciples, to do. Love each other.</p>
<p>So why does Smokey, an adamant non-Christian, &#8220;get it&#8221; when it comes to love, but most every Christian I know doesn&#8217;t? Why is it that when I am struggling, like I am right now, I can&#8217;t get my brothers and sisters in Christ to show love without a court order, but those like Smokey and other employees and customers I work with will show love in their words and deeds? How is it that those in whom Love Himself lives bottle up love and refuse to give it while those who do not know Love are very free with their love? I really don&#8217;t get it.  I am ready to quit Christians, or at least quit hoping Christians will do what Jesus commanded and love each other. Christians don&#8217;t get it. Agnostics and atheists do. Something is really screwy here.</p>
<p>Am I wrong? Am I placing too much emphasis on love? Should I really expect my Christian friends to show me love with their words and actions? And when they don&#8217;t, do I have the right to ask them why not? Maybe love is outdated. Maybe I&#8217;m living in a fantasy world, thinking that when I am hurting I can expect others to come alongside of me and not leave. Perhaps wanting someone to say &#8220;I love you&#8221; is a wrong desire. I don&#8217;t know. I know I love others because Jesus tells me to, and because Love lives in me and I can do no less. Is it fair for me to question whether Love really lives in those who refuse to love?</p>
<p>Maybe I should be a Power Ranger Christian male, one who never admits he needs the love of others. One who only gives and receives side hugs. One who would rather wear a skirt than tell other guys, &#8220;I love you.&#8221; But I can&#8217;t do that. I can&#8217;t stop being who my Father made me to be. I can&#8217;t stop loving others as Jesus commanded. I&#8217;m willing to be mocked as long as my words are sincere and are given to those who need them the most. For when I give love, I am reflecting my Father, and that gives him joy, which makes me happy. So if you see me anytime soon, and I tell you or show you in some way that I love you, please know I mean it. Please receive it as from my heart, a heart surrendered to Christ. And if you want to tell me you love me, that will be just fine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/quitting-christians/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>165</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Money and Power: The Elephant in James MacDonald’s Room</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/money-and-power-the-elephant-room</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/money-and-power-the-elephant-room#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 04:01:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Christian Scandals]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39673</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[NOTE: Thanks to Ryan Mahoney and Scott Bryant for this look at one of the prominent scandals in evangelicalism in recent days. James MacDonald graduated from Trinity Evangelical Divinity School in 1988, the same year I did. That year he founded Harvest Bible Chapel in Rolling Meadows, IL. He is also known from his radio [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/james-macdonald-e1363472298376.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-39674" alt="james-macdonald" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/james-macdonald-e1363472298376.jpg" width="540" height="308" /></a></p>
<p><strong>NOTE</strong>: Thanks to <strong>Ryan Mahoney and Scott Bryant</strong> for this look at one of the prominent scandals in evangelicalism in recent days. <a href="http://jamesmacdonald.com/"><strong>James MacDonald</strong></a> graduated from Trinity Evangelical Divinity School in 1988, the same year I did. That year he founded <a href="http://www.harvestbiblechapel.org/"><strong>Harvest Bible Chapel</strong></a> in Rolling Meadows, IL. He is also known from his radio and writing ministry, <em>Walk in the Word</em>. <a href="http://www.harvestbiblefellowship.org/"><strong>Harvest Bible Fellowship</strong></a> is his church planting ministry. MacDonald is part of the neo-reformed movement, and was a member of <a href="http://thegospelcoalition.org/"><strong>The Gospel Coalition</strong></a>, but <a href="http://www.christianitytoday.com/ct/2012/februaryweb-only/james-macdonald-resignation.html">he resigned in Jan. 2012</a> over controversy regarding his conference known as <em>&#8220;The Elephant Room.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>For further reading, check out Ryan and Scott&#8217;s blogs, <a href="http://theelephantsdebt.com/"><strong>The Elephant&#8217;s Debt</strong></a>, and <a href="http://bloodstainedink.wordpress.com/"><strong>Blood Stained Ink</strong></a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>In October 2012, a new website entitled <strong><a href="http://theelephantsdebt.com/executive-summary/" target="_blank">The Elephant’s Debt (TED)</a></strong> was released to the general public.  This site, which was primarily focused upon issues related to money and power struggles at Harvest Bible Chapel (a megachurch located in the western suburbs of Chicago, Illinois), is authored by Ryan Mahoney and Scott Bryant, both of whom were former, long-term congregants within the Harvest system.</p>
<p><strong>What you are about to read is a summary provided by these two men, attempting to assess the issues at Harvest within the context of a larger, evangelical crisis that is looming just over the horizon</strong>.</p>
<p>In the spring of 2010, we became aware of several character issues pertaining to our Senior Pastor, James MacDonald.  While these issues were not yet significant enough (in our minds) to raise questions pertaining to MacDonald’s suitability to fulfill the role of elder within a local church, they were sufficient enough for us to remove our families from the church.   To be clear, our initial concerns were primarily related to: (1) stories surrounding the way he treated staff members, (2) his shift towards eisegeting himself into the biblical text that he was preaching, and (3) what appeared to be a grab for power amidst a reorganization of the elder board structure.</p>
<p>The next step in our journey towards authoring <em>The Elephant’s Debt</em> arrived when MacDonald infamously mishandled a conversation with T.D. Jakes at the <em>&#8220;Elephant Room 2&#8243; (ER2)</em> in January 2012.  In the aftermath of that theological debacle, we each wrote a blog post on our respective websites pertaining to the importance of Trinitarianism and the dangers of the Prosperity Gospel.  More specifically, we talked about MacDonald’s mishandling of Jake’s modalistic responses at ER2 and MacDonald’s failure to even address the question of the Prosperity Gospel.</p>
<p>Interestingly enough, the response to these blog posts was enormous.  As the comments continued to pour in, we both began to receive communication from former and current HBC insiders, suggesting that our concerns should run much, much deeper.  And thus began our inquiry into this matter.</p>
<p>From February 2012 until October 2012, we conducted numerous interviews and acquired significant documentation  pertaining to the growing problems at Harvest Bible Chapel.  What was clear to us in those early days was that all the stories that we were hearing centered around a troubling and disqualifying lack of character in James MacDonald.</p>
<p>For those that have not read <em>The Elephant’s Debt</em> and are thus unaware of the circumstances surrounding Harvest Bible Chapel, please allow us to summarize in brief.</p>
<ul>
<li>At the time of publication, we informed our readers that HBC was approximately $65 million dollars in debt.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Additionally, we reported that James MacDonald was earning in excess of $600,000 in annual compensation from the church and its related ministries.  This figure did not include compensation received from other likely sources of income such as: book royalties, conference fees, etc.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Thirdly, we reported that MacDonald had admitted to a group of Harvest Fellowship pastors that he operated in such a way that he retained 50% of the power within the church, leaving the remaining of power to be divided equally among the suddenly swollen elder board, which had grown from approximately eight men to over 30.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>We then discussed the recent $30 million dollar capital campaign in which MacDonald informed his congregation that he personally knew how much money God wanted them to sacrificially give to the campaign.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Finally, to illustrate our point that we were not alone in our concerns pertaining to MacDonald, we listed a group of former elders and pastors, all of whom left the church for their own reasons and concerns regarding Harvest Bible Chapel and its direction.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-39673"></span></p>
<p><!--more--></p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/elephant-room-e1363575567533.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-39697" alt="elephant room" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/elephant-room-e1363575567533-300x277.jpg" width="240" height="222" /></a>As one might well imagine, following the publication of <em>The Elephant’s Debt</em>, Harvest could no longer ignore our concerns.  Within a few short days, the elders of HBC released a statement in which they attempted to assuage the fears of their congregants.</p>
<p>However, as TED continued to publish updates, more information continued to surface; and new allegations of gambling were brought to the forefront.  Since this issue was relevant to the subject of money, we choose to publish various comments that were left by numerous individuals in the know.  These comments were ultimately verified by a close friend of MacDonald, who publicly acknowledged that MacDonald played poker in the basement of his Inverness mansion and in casinos.  This admission by MacDonald’s friend was confirmed by MacDonald himself in a sermon entitled “My 5G.”</p>
<p>Throughout this season, four churches have seen fit to sever their ties with Harvest Bible Chapel, and a fifth has been thrown out of the Fellowship for their private communications with Harvest leadership pertaining to their concerns related to MacDonald and his handling of <em>The Elephant Room 2</em> debacle.</p>
<p>It should be noted, at this juncture, that in the four months that have followed the publication of <em>The Elephant’s Debt</em>, the leadership of Harvest Bible Chapel has never challenged the underlying facts asserted by our website.  Sadly, however, we did catch Lyn Donald, wife of the long-term Associate Pastor, and other HBC insiders peddling a lie in which they asserted that Joe Stowell had asked to have his name removed from <em>The Elephant’s Debt</em>, only to be rebuffed by these authors.  One can only assume that they are using the name of the Stowell family and their public silence as a means of purposefully misleading congregants who have been disturbed by the evidence put forth by TED.</p>
<p><strong>What is most disconcerting to us is not only the specifics of this local phenomena, but also how this situation highlights several broader problems within conservative evangelicalism at large</strong>.</p>
<p>To begin with, over the past two decades, the church has moved in a direction whereby <strong>entire bodies are being defined by the charismatic presence of their senior pastor</strong>.  As has been discussed numerous times by Michael Spencer, the original Internet Monk, this model of the “pastorate” is a dangerous model that leaves the body unwittingly oriented around the worship of a rock-star mega-pastor.  Moreover, there is a danger for the senior pastor who operates within this model to be overwhelmed in his character by the dark forces of ego and pride.</p>
<p>But the problems go deeper than the rise of the superstar pastor. In many cases, the churches that have been built around such a figure are often <strong>non-denominational in nature</strong>, which ultimately means that they answer to no earthly authority other than that which they have appointed to themselves. So in times of crisis and/or moral failure, as we have seen at Harvest, Sovereign Grace Ministries, and elsewhere, the congregation has no recourse to address its concerns if the self-appointed elder board is unwilling or unable to remove the senior pastor from leadership.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, when so much of the &#8220;Sunday Experience&#8221; and church culture is centered around this charismatic figurehead, <strong>constitutional church structures are no longer capable of limiting the power of the individual in question</strong> because the individual has effectually become &#8220;the church&#8221; for the majority of the congregants.  This is why we see so many megachurch pastor salaries rising to unprecedented heights.  When the pastor is the central draw for the church, and the church fears losing the congregation that comes almost exclusively for his or her teaching, they feel pressured to pay &#8220;competitive rates&#8221; so that other churches can&#8217;t come along and steal &#8220;the talent.&#8221;</p>
<p>One historic strength of evangelicalism has been its willingness to engage the culture for the sake of the Gospel. Indeed, its success in Gospel mission has come about through adopting cultural forms that make the Gospel palatable to the contemporary culture. Historically speaking, we see one significant example of this during the Second Great Awakening when Finney shed the doctrine of election in favor of preaching a message that appealed to experientialism and post-Enlightenment individualism. It wasn&#8217;t important whether or not you were elected by God. It was all about your choice to pursue a fire-insurance policy that gave you the afterlife you desired to secure for yourself.</p>
<p>Of course, the weakness in adopting this course of action is the ease with which contemporary cultural values become the values of the church.  In the case of contemporary American evangelicalism, <strong>values stemming from capitalism</strong> have come to dominate evangelical thinking.  For example, we think of church planters as entrepreneurs, senior pastors as free agent talent, church plants as franchises, sermons as intellectual property, and pastors as brands that can be marketed and exploited.</p>
<p>As <strong><a href="http://theelephantsdebt.com/executive-summary/" target="_blank">Roger Olson</a></strong> has recently pointed out on his blog, evangelicalism as a movement, which began after WWII and continued through the 1970s, is deeply fractured, and perhaps even dead. There is a post-evangelical (left-leaning) wing, a conservative evangelical wing, and a moderate wing.  The conservative wing has unwittingly wed itself to the cultural forms of Modernity and Americanism, and these forms within conservative evangelicalism have calcified as absolutes while the contemporary culture has moved on.  This dynamic has left conservative evangelicalism with a decreased voice and influence in the contemporary culture, losing the very strength it once had, and it is suffering at the hands of the worst elements of the outmoded American cultural forms.</p>
<p>If there is not an awakening and reform within conservative evangelicalism, the last men standing will be the post-evangelical and moderate evangelical camps.  The time is ripe for someone to write,<em>“The Uneasy Conscience of a Conservative Evangelical.”</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/money-and-power-the-elephant-room/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>181</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Even St. Patrick Struggles to Explain the Trinity</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/even-st-patrick-struggles-to-explain-the-trinity</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/even-st-patrick-struggles-to-explain-the-trinity#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Laugh or else]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theologia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39693</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In honor of St. Patrick, we present this bit from Lutheran Satire that is not designed so much to be a knock on St. Patrick as on any attempt to use analogies to &#8220;explain&#8221; the Trinity. It&#8217;s also an overdue apology to Irish snake farmers. Good for a laugh &#8212; especially you&#8217;ve downed your third [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In honor of St. Patrick, we present this bit from <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/TheLutheranSatire?feature=watch"><strong>Lutheran Satire</strong></a> that is not designed so much to be a knock on St. Patrick as on any attempt to use analogies to &#8220;explain&#8221; the Trinity. It&#8217;s also an overdue apology to Irish snake farmers.</p>
<p>Good for a laugh &#8212; especially you&#8217;ve downed your third beer today.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/KQLfgaUoQCw" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/even-st-patrick-struggles-to-explain-the-trinity/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Look: Is This a Church?</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/another-look-is-this-a-church</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/another-look-is-this-a-church#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 04:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelical Issues]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39679</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An excerpt from a post by Chaplain Mike, February 2011 My take on what has happened over the course of the last forty years is as follows. In evangelicalism in particular, we have raised a whole generation of Christians who were discipled not so much by traditional local churches as by parachurch ministries and churches that have [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/diversity.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-39683" alt="diversity" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/diversity.jpg" width="560" height="309" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/is-it-a-church"><strong>An excerpt from a post by Chaplain Mike, February 2011</strong></a></p>
<p>My take on what has happened over the course of the last forty years is as follows. In evangelicalism in particular, we have raised a whole generation of Christians who were discipled not so much by traditional local churches as by <em>parachurch</em> ministries and churches that have become dominated by the parachurch ethos. That ethos is not “Church” but “Mission.” And so what we see today is the fruit of that.</p>
<p><strong>We have many communities of faith that would be better described as “missions” rather than “churches.”</strong></p>
<p>Campus Crusade for Christ, Navigators, InterVarsity, Youth for Christ, and a thousand other parachurch ministries have been the true engines of growth in evangelicalism over the course of my Christian life. Their emphasis on “evangelism and discipleship” influenced those who developed the church growth movement, the Willow Creek movement, the church-planting “community church” type movements, and the more contemporary examples we see today. Traditional Protestantism defined the church as a community where the Word of God was truly preached and the sacraments truly administered. <strong>Today, “church” is defined by many as a community that practices evangelism and discipleship.</strong></p>
<p>I don’t totally disagree, and the emphasis on mission in today’s congregations is likely a reaction to a lack of that emphasis in more traditional congregations.</p>
<p>However, this leads to some problems. What, for example, would Paul say about a “church” that consists wholly of those age 25 and under? Or any “church” that exists primarily to reach a particular demographic? Or a “church” that, for the purpose of outreach, shapes its preaching and “worship” (i.e. music) after a particular culture rather than shaping it around the Gospel? (That is not the same as saying our worship and religious styles will reflect our cultural context.)</p>
<p>I think, frankly, that the Apostle would have problems with this approach. Certainly, in a broad sense, Paul saw himself as an <em>“apostle to the Gentiles,”</em> while others were <em>“apostles to the Jews.”</em> And he did say, in 1Corinthians 9, that he was willing to adapt his approach to reach as many as possible. That was his mission <em>in the world</em>.</p>
<p>However, that was not what he said “church” is about. When Paul gathered people from the various backgrounds he had reached into the church, he brought them <em>together</em>, and insisted that <strong>the ethos of the church was learning to accommodate to one another, accept one another, and become a cross-cultural community in Christ</strong>. Almost every epistle he wrote is designed in part to reinforce this ecclesiological perspective.</p>
<blockquote><p><em><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/circle3.jpg"><img class="alignright" title="circle" alt="" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/circle3-300x249.jpg" width="248" height="197" /></a>For all of you who were baptized into Christ have clothed yourselves with Christ. There is neither Jew nor Greek, there is neither slave nor free man, there is neither male nor female; for you are all one in Christ Jesus. (Gal 3:27-28)</em></p>
<p><em>[you] have put on the new self who is being renewed to a true knowledge according to the image of the One who created him &#8212; a renewal in which there is no distinction between Greek and Jew, circumcised and uncircumcised, barbarian, Scythian, slave and freeman, but Christ is all, and in all. (Col 3:10-11)</em></p>
<p><em>Now may the God who gives perseverance and encouragement grant you to be of the same mind with one another according to Christ Jesus, so that with one accord you may with one voice glorify the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ. Therefore, accept one another, just as Christ also accepted us to the glory of God. (Rom 14:5-7)</em></p>
<p><em>But now in Christ Jesus you who formerly were far off have been brought near by the blood of Christ. For He Himself is our peace, who made both groups into one and broke down the barrier of the dividing wall, by abolishing in His flesh the enmity, which is the Law of commandments contained in ordinances, so that in Himself He might make the two into one new man, thus establishing peace, and might reconcile them both in one body to God through the cross, by it having put to death the enmity. AND HE CAME AND PREACHED PEACE TO YOU WHO WERE FAR AWAY, AND PEACE TO THOSE WHO WERE NEAR; for through Him we both have our access in one Spirit to the Father. So then you are no longer strangers and aliens, but you are fellow citizens with the saints, and are of God’s household, having been built on the foundation of the apostles and prophets, Christ Jesus Himself being the corner stone, in whom the whole building, being fitted together, is growing into a holy temple in the Lord, in whom you also are being built together into a dwelling of God in the Spirit.</em> (Eph 3:13-22)</p></blockquote>
<p><span id="more-39679"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/diversity-II.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-39686" alt="diversity II" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/diversity-II-256x300.jpg" width="205" height="240" /></a>This is an entirely different vision of the church than we see in many congregations, whether traditional or “cutting-edge.” There is a <em>breadth</em> to the church as well as a height, a horizontal element as well as the vertical dimension. It is not just about bringing people into relationship with God through Jesus and providing a place where they may feel “comfortable” because we have accommodated to their cultural expectations. <strong>It is about bringing people into a community that requires that we learn how to relate to all different kinds of people and teaches us to love one another.</strong></p>
<p>It is entirely reasonable to assume that the reason people think we need so many “innovative” mission-oriented “churches” today is because the traditional churches failed to be “the church” in this regard. We isolated ourselves from the world rather than go out in mission with Paul’s gracious, accommodating spirit.</p>
<ul>
<li>We did not welcome the outsider.</li>
<li>We did not show concern for the ones who are unlike us.</li>
<li>We did not love our neighbors when we disapproved of their clothing, the music they liked, or the culture, ethnicity, or socio-economic group they represented.</li>
<li>We ignored and even demonized our straying youth.</li>
<li>We lost our sense of mission, at least when it came to our near neighbors.</li>
<li>We did not go out into the world, as Paul did, willing to adapt our lifestyles and approaches to reach people from various cultures, befriending sinners and sharing God’s love with them in ways they could grasp.</li>
<li>We separated from them instead. We tried to create islands of godliness in a sea of sinful culture. And then we tried to attract outsiders to come in to behold something “different.”</li>
</ul>
<p>Yes, in many ways the traditional churches failed to be the church, participating in God’s mission in the world. <strong>But the ultimate answer is not to create “missions” to particular groups of those who have been left out and then call these missions “churches.”<em> </em></strong>We must distinguish between “church” and “mission.” What happens when we “scatter” into the world differs from what we do when we “gather” together as God’s family.</p>
<p>The “mission” that calls itself a “church” may be a necessary transitional step because of where we’ve been, but ultimately God’s people need to grow up and become adults and listen to what the New Testament says.</p>
<ul>
<li>We are called to create <strong>genuine</strong> <strong>churches </strong>of <em>“Jew and Gentile, slave and free, etc.”</em> united in Christ alone.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>A church is not only a place where the Word is truly proclaimed and the sacraments faithfully served. <strong>It is also a place, according to the consistent and pervasive teaching of the NT, that intentionally strives for inclusion and diversity as a testimony to God’s love for the whole world.</strong></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>A true church is a place where everyone is welcome, and where <strong>one of the chief matters of spiritual formation is learning to love those who are different from me.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>God is creating a community &#8212; a <em>cross-cultural community &#8211; </em>that is, a people which consists of folks who may be very different from one another, but who share a <em>“common unity”</em> in Jesus Christ. That is the NT vision of church. Our unity does not consist in the fact that we all have tattoos or like grunge music or meet in a pub. Nor does it consist in the fact that we are mostly conservative middle-class suburbanites who share a common family-oriented lifestyle. Nor does it consist in our whiteness or blackness or the specific ethnic culture in which we live. Nor is it about organs, hymns, robes, and pews, or praise bands, screens, and &#8220;casual&#8221; worship.</p>
<p>Our only true oneness is in Christ. We accommodate to “where people are” to reach them <em>in the world</em> for Christ, making them disciples. The place we accommodate is in our daily life, relationships, and interactions. But then, when we &#8220;baptize people and teach them to observe all that Christ commanded us,&#8221; we call them into the practice of cross-cultural love within the new family God is creating. What the world needs to see is faith communities made up of people vastly different from one another who have laid hold of that.</p>
<p>That’s church.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/another-look-is-this-a-church/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Commentary by Jesus</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/39666</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/39666#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 16:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laugh or else]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39666</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From today&#8217;s Saturday Ramblings: Andy Stanley met with pastors at some pastors conference in Atlanta. He encouraged them to make their church services “appealing and engaging” in order to keep the customers, er, congregations coming back. Ok, this doesn’t surprise me. Disappoints me, yes. But it doesn’t surprise me. Yet here is the line that really [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From today&#8217;s <a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-3-16-13"><strong>Saturday Ramblings</strong></a>:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong><a href="http://www.christianpost.com/news/andy-stanley-tells-pastors-to-reach-unchurched-people-make-church-appealing-and-engaging-91920/" target="_blank">Andy Stanley</a></strong> met with pastors at some pastors conference in Atlanta. He encouraged them to make their church services “appealing and engaging” in order to keep the customers, er, congregations coming back. Ok, this doesn’t surprise me. Disappoints me, yes. But it doesn’t surprise me. Yet here is the line that really makes me question whether he knows the same God I do: <em>“God is a God of systems and predictability and order, and God honors planning,” </em>he said.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/RadioFreeBabylon"><strong>Commentary by Jesus</strong></a>: (click on image for full size)</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/coffee-strip.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-39667 aligncenter" alt="coffee strip" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/coffee-strip.jpg" width="614" height="219" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/39666/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saturday Ramblings 3.16.13</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-3-16-13</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-3-16-13#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 04:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saturday Ramblings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39659</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Well, iMonks, it has been a very interesting week, has it not? We have a new leader of the church. We also have a new pope. Confused? So were those who selected the Final Four bracket. You ought to see the winner they came up with. And tomorrow&#8212;well, tomorrow is a day we all celebrate [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/w-popedoll-31413.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-39661" alt="w-popedoll-31413" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/w-popedoll-31413-300x166.jpg" width="300" height="166" /></a>Well, iMonks, it has been a very interesting week, has it not? We have a new leader of the church. We also have a new pope. Confused? So were those who selected the Final Four bracket. You ought to see the winner they came up with. And tomorrow&#8212;well, tomorrow is a day we all celebrate by turning Kermit the Frog. It&#8217;s not easy being green. Shall we ramble?</p>
<p>Cardinal Jorge Mario Bergoglio, Archbishop of Buenos Aires, was <a href="http://blog.christianitytoday.com/ctliveblog/archives/2013/03/the-first-pope-from-latin-america-bergoglio.html" target="_blank"><strong>elected</strong></a> the Supreme Pontiff of the Catholic Church on the fifth ballot this week. He then took the name of Francis, the first of 266 such popes, to take that name. One of the first things the new pope did was to <a href="http://www.csmonitor.com/World/Latest-News-Wires/2013/0314/Pope-pays-hotel-bill-Pope-Francis-sheds-luxuries-of-previous-popes" target="_blank"><strong>pay his hotel bill</strong></a>. This would not surprise those in the slums of Argentina where <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/argentines-celebrate-francis-slum-pope-064548438.html" target="_blank"><strong>Bergoglio often visited</strong></a>, even washing the feet of drug addicts. It seems this pope plans to break many traditions. He has many <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/popes-views-tango-art-gay-marriage-163529138.html" target="_blank"><strong>interesting views</strong></a> on many things. I think I&#8217;m really going to enjoy getting to know Pope Francis.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/gty_pope_francis_pays_bill_jef_ssm_130315_wmain.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-39660" alt="gty_pope_francis_pays_bill_jef_ssm_130315_wmain" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/gty_pope_francis_pays_bill_jef_ssm_130315_wmain.jpg" width="640" height="360" /></a></p>
<p>Before the conclave, Cardinal Timothy Dolan wrote to his flock, expressing his hope for a quick vote as he was running short of, well, you can <a href="http://blog.archny.org/index.php/a-few-bloopers/" target="_blank"><strong>find out yourself</strong></a>.</p>
<p>But is Cardinal Bergoglio truly the new head of the Catholic Church? Not according to the results of the <a href="http://www.religionnews.com/2013/03/12/sweet-sistine-winner-cardinal-john-onaiyekan/" target="_blank"><strong>Final Four</strong></a>. In a rout, the winner of the Sweet Sistine tournament was Cardinal John Onaiyekan of Nigeria. So, do we have a new schism?</p>
<p><span id="more-39659"></span></p>
<p>But neither of these men are the leaders of the church, at least not the evangelical church. The new leader of the evangelical church, according to <a href="http://religion.blogs.cnn.com/2013/03/09/the-most-sung-artist-on-the-planet/?hpt=hp_c1" target="_blank"><strong>CNN</strong></a>, is &#8230;</p>
<p>The man many consider the <a href="http://blogs.courier-journal.com/faith/2013/03/14/mohler-catholic-teachings-on-papacy-anathema/" target="_blank"><strong>Baptist Pope</strong></a> has nothing much good to say about Pope Francis, the papacy, or the Catholic Church as a whole. In our next piece of news, we have just received word that the sun is hot.</p>
<p>Oh my. Evangelicalism may be at its end. <a href="http://jonathanmerritt.religionnews.com/2013/03/12/will-god-be-left-behind-an-interview-with-rob-bell-part-one/" target="_blank"><strong>Rob Bell</strong></a> is about to release another book. We know how his last book almost destroyed Christianity as we know it by suggesting God just might love us. Jonathan Merritt sits down with Bell to discuss how we talk about God and why that matters.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.christianpost.com/news/andy-stanley-tells-pastors-to-reach-unchurched-people-make-church-appealing-and-engaging-91920/" target="_blank">Andy Stanley</a></strong> met with pastors at some pastors conference in Atlanta. He encouraged them to make their church services &#8220;appealing and engaging&#8221; in order to keep the customers, er, congregations coming back. Ok, this doesn&#8217;t surprise me. Disappoints me, yes. But it doesn&#8217;t surprise me. Yet here is the line that really makes me question whether he knows the same God I do: <em>&#8220;God is a God of systems and predictability and order, and God honors planning,&#8221; he said. </em>Really?</p>
<p>Well, ministry these days is very difficult. It even comes with its own <strong><a href="http://www.outofur.com/archives/2013/03/the_new_ministr.html" target="_blank">new vocabulary</a></strong>. Do you know of any they left out?</p>
<p>Birthday candles were blown out this last week by Bobby Fischer; Charles Gibson; Robin Trower; Barbie; James Earl Ray; Chuck Norris; Jim Valvano; the Ford Mustang; Edie Brickell; Rupert Murdoch; Wally Schirra; Billie &#8220;Buckwheat&#8221; Thomas; <strong>Bill Payne</strong>; Walter Annenberg; Adam Clayton; Howard Scott; Ry Cooder; and Mike Love.</p>
<p>Bill Payne founded Little Feat with Lowell George in 1969. George has passed away, but the band lives on. And on. And on. Often called the &#8220;hardest working rock and roll band,&#8221; if you are not familiar with Little Feat, you should be. Enjoy.</p>
<iframe width="640" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/VDp3Grz28mE" frameborder="0" type="text/html"></iframe><div style="text-align:right;"><a style="color:#aaa;font-size:9px" href="http://www.clickonf5.org/" title="IFRAME Embed for Youtube Free WordPress Plugin" target="_blank">IFRAME Embed for Youtube</a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-3-16-13/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>97</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic
Page Caching using disk: enhanced

 Served from: www.internetmonk.com @ 2013-03-22 00:28:37 by W3 Total Cache -->
