<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/" xmlns:creativeCommons="http://backend.userland.com/creativeCommonsRssModule" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>internetmonk.com</title>
	
	<link>http://www.internetmonk.com</link>
	<description>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 04:01:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
<!-- podcast_generator="Blubrry PowerPress/4.0.7" -->
	<itunes:summary>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:author>The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer</itunes:author>
	<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/monkposterx3.jpg" />
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer</itunes:name>
		<itunes:email>michael@internetmonk.com</itunes:email>
	</itunes:owner>
	<managingEditor>michael@internetmonk.com (The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer)</managingEditor>
	<copyright>2006-2009</copyright>
	<itunes:subtitle>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</itunes:subtitle>
	<image><link>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</link><url>http://creativecommons.org/images/public/somerights20.gif</url><title>Some Rights Reserved</title></image>
	<itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
		<itunes:category text="Christianity" />
	</itunes:category>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/internetmonk/SWqj" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="internetmonk/swqj" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license><feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">internetmonk/SWqj</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>Holy Week: Music of the Cross on Good Friday</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-music-of-the-cross-on-good-friday</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-music-of-the-cross-on-good-friday#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 04:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Listening]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39966</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have the privilege of serving in a fine congregation in Indianapolis this spring as part of my ordination process. This church is filled with gifted musicians and the entire congregation has bought into the ethos of praising God through excellent music. For Good Friday, I will be joining the choir to sing &#8220;Die Sieben [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have the privilege of serving in a fine congregation in Indianapolis this spring as part of my ordination process. This church is filled with gifted musicians and the entire congregation has bought into the ethos of praising God through excellent music.</p>
<p>For Good Friday, I will be joining the choir to sing <a href="http://www.emmanuelmusic.org/notes_translations/translations_motets/t_schutz_swv478.htm"><strong>&#8220;Die Sieben Worte Jesu am Kreuz,&#8221;</strong></a> by Heinrich Schütz (<em>&#8220;The Seven Last Words of Jesus from the Cross&#8221;</em>).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bach-cantatas.com/Lib/Schutz-Heinrich.htm"><strong>Heinrich Schütz</strong></a>, a German composer and organist, is generally regarded as the most important German composer before J.S. Bach. He studied with both Gabrieli and Monteverdi, and is a figure who bridged the transition from Renaissance to Baroque music.</p>
<p>The following is a recording of the <em>Introitus</em>, or introduction, to <em>Die Sieben Worte</em> by the Ambassador Singers of Columbia International University, Dan Kreider, director.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/YyQcIjWz9Ro" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>While Jesus was on the Cross</em><br />
<em> and his body was wounded with bitter pains,</em><br />
<em> contemplate in your heart</em><br />
<em> the seven words that Jesus spoke.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-music-of-the-cross-on-good-friday/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week with Duccio: Washing the Disciples’ Feet</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-washin</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-washin#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 16:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39807</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[And during supper Jesus, knowing that the Father had given all things into his hands, and that he had come from God and was going to God,got up from the table, took off his outer robe, and tied a towel around himself. Then he poured water into a basin and began to wash the disciples’ feet and to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Washing.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-39855" alt="Duccio Washing" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Washing.jpg" width="510" height="490" /></a></p>
<blockquote><p>And during supper Jesus, knowing that the Father had given all things into his hands, and that he had come from God and was going to God,got up from the table, took off his outer robe, and tied a towel around himself. Then he poured water into a basin and began to wash the disciples’ feet and to wipe them with the towel that was tied around him.He came to Simon Peter, who said to him, ‘Lord, are you going to wash my feet?’ Jesus answered, ‘You do not know now what I am doing, but later you will understand.’ Peter said to him, ‘You will never wash my feet.’ Jesus answered, ‘Unless I wash you, you have no share with me.’Simon Peter said to him, ‘Lord, not my feet only but also my hands and my head!’ Jesus said to him, ‘One who has bathed does not need to wash, except for the feet, but is entirely clean. And you are clean, though not all of you.’ For he knew who was to betray him; for this reason he said, ‘Not all of you are clean.’</p>
<p>After he had washed their feet, had put on his robe, and had returned to the table, he said to them, ‘Do you know what I have done to you?You call me Teacher and Lord—and you are right, for that is what I am.So if I, your Lord and Teacher, have washed your feet, you also ought to wash one another’s feet. For I have set you an example, that you also should do as I have done to you.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">- John 13:1-14</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many New Testament scholars believe that the famous &#8220;kenosis&#8221; passage in Philippians 2:5-11 is actually an ancient hymn based on the events of John 13. It certainly brings out one of the great lessons of the footwashing account.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Let the same mind be in you that was in Christ Jesus,</em><br />
<em> who, though he was in the form of God,</em><br />
<em> did not regard equality with God</em><br />
<em> as something to be exploited,</em><br />
<em> but emptied himself,</em><br />
<em> taking the form of a slave,</em><br />
<em> being born in human likeness.</em><br />
<em> And being found in human form,</em><br />
<em> he humbled himself</em><br />
<em> and became obedient to the point of death—</em><br />
<em> even death on a cross.</em><br />
<em> Therefore God also highly exalted him</em><br />
<em> and gave him the name</em><br />
<em> that is above every name,</em><br />
<em> so that at the name of Jesus</em><br />
<em> every knee should bend,</em><br />
<em> in heaven and on earth and under the earth,</em><br />
<em> and every tongue should confess</em><br />
<em> that Jesus Christ is Lord,</em><br />
<em> to the glory of God the Father.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-washin/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Reconciliation Of The Cross</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-reconciliation-of-the-cross</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-reconciliation-of-the-cross#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 05:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39950</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So let’s get this clear: it’s for My own sake that I save you. I am He who wipes the slate clean and erases your wrongdoing. I will not call to mind your sins anymore. (Isaiah 43:25, The Voice) Tomorrow is Good Friday, the day we remember the Passion of the Cross of Christ. We will remember it [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Jesus-buried.jpg"><img class="wp-image-39953 aligncenter" alt="Jesus buried" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Jesus-buried-1024x768.jpg" width="602" height="452" /></a>So <i>let’s get this clear:</i> it’s for My own sake <i>that I save you</i>.</strong><br />
<strong>I am He who wipes the slate clean and erases your wrongdoing.</strong><br />
<strong>I will not call to mind your sins anymore.</strong> (Isaiah 43:25, The Voice)</p>
<p>Tomorrow is Good Friday, the day we remember the Passion of the Cross of Christ. We will remember it if we perhaps attend a Good Friday service. We may spend a bit of time meditating on the passages of Scripture that show Jesus being tortured and crucified. We may even watch Mel Gibson&#8217;s <em>Passion Of The Christ</em> again. We won&#8217;t spend too much time on the death of Christ, though. Death is boring. We want life&#8212;abundant life. We want the fun of the resurrection. Tomorrow we wear black, while Sunday is for bright colors and &#8220;He is risen indeed&#8221; greetings. Tomorrow we will not greet fellow believers with &#8220;He is dead. He is dead indeed.&#8221;</p>
<p>We rush past the death and burial of Jesus because there is seemingly nothing in it for us. If there is no resurrection, says St. Paul, we are just a bunch of miserable people. And so we are. We are lousy, miserable SOBs who turned our backs on our Creator and went our own way. And worse yet, we somehow have convinced ourselves that God felt really sorry for us and sent Jesus to die so we might maybe possibly come back to God. <em>See?</em> we think we hear God saying. <em>I love you so very much I sent my son to die for you. Now will you believe me? Please oh please oh please come back to me.</em> And now it is all up to us whether we can be bothered with this most Divine Act. We live life so bass ackward it is a wonder why we have eyes that look forward instead of to the rear.</p>
<p>I have some news for us all. The Cross is not for us. It is not about us. The Cross is about Jesus. It begins and ends with the Son of God. The crucifixion of the Christ was not a patchwork plan by the Father. It is not Plan B to make up for failed Plan A. The Cross was God&#8217;s plan from before the Big Bang. The death of Jesus is as much a part of creation as is the Horsehead Nebula or flowering redbud trees or ripe red raspberries. It was God&#8217;s plan all along for the Creator to become a creation and to die. He did this not for our sakes but for his.</p>
<p>And the question before us is this: <em>Why?</em> Why would God spin the entire magnificent universe into existence simply to end up dead on a tree that himself made?</p>
<p><span id="more-39950"></span></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get one thing straight right away. When Jesus died, he died. I think, since we know that he rose from the grave, we tend to think his death was no big deal. It&#8217;s like we think Jesus just took some time off. A three day weekend, as it were. But the Cross is not the Cross if it did not mean the end of the life God. When they took the body of Jesus down from where it had hung and bled, there was no longer any life in it. The resurrection is not a miracle if Jesus didn&#8217;t die. And if his body died, so did all of him. Where there once was a carpenter&#8217;s son named Jesus, there was now a lifeless and thoughtless body.</p>
<p>This is vital if we are to get even the smallest glimpse of God&#8217;s purpose in all of this. (I really don&#8217;t think we can get more than a tiny glimpse of the purpose of the Cross, no matter how long or hard we look at it.) Jesus&#8217;s thoughts ceased. Where there once was a mind, there was now simply a void in space and time, a black hole of nothingness. Do you see this? When Jesus cried out his last on that Good Friday the Temple veil was torn in two from top to bottom. There was another tearing, another rending in two at the same time. Where Jesus once held thoughts in his mind, there was now a parting of the sea of consciousness. A sea of terrible nothingness lay beyond that veil. And that is where God has cast our sin&#8212;into the sea of nothing.</p>
<blockquote><p> I am He who wipes the slate clean and erases your wrongdoing.<br />
I will not call to mind your sins anymore.</p></blockquote>
<p>Where did our sins go if they are beyond the knowing of the omniscient God? How can God wipe clean the slate of our wrongdoing? Isaiah says God will not &#8220;call to mind&#8221; our sins anymore. How can this be? Could it be that in the moment of his death God placed all of our sin&#8212;and his thought of our sin&#8212;into the void of the mind of Jesus? Could it be that in the rending of Jesus&#8217; thoughts our sins&#8212;all of our sins, past, present and future&#8212;were placed forever beyond even the reach of God in that sea of nothing? (This idea was birthed in me from Robert Capon in his book <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0802842224/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0802842224&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=goonewdai-20">Between Noon and Three: Romance, Law, and the Outrage of Grace</a><img style="border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=goonewdai-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0802842224" width="1" height="1" border="0" /></em>. He articulates it much better than I ever could.)</p>
<p>My sin, however, is not just a part of me. You can&#8217;t just lop off sin like scraping off a wart. My sin goes all the way to the very core of my being. If, then, my sin is cast away from God into this sea of nothingness, that means all of me is cast there as well. I and my sin cannot be separated, at least not in this life. It is the wheat and the tares. Rip up one and the other comes up as well. So in choosing not to call to mind our sins any longer, is God saying he is choosing not to hold us? Is he casting us away from his presence forever?</p>
<p>God casts our sins away from his thoughts, yet God holds everything. There is nothing beyond his grip, not even nothingness. Nothing is not beyond him. Thus for all eternity God must hold our sins in the dead mind of Jesus. For ever God will hold me as a sinner, as dead as Jesus on the Cross. God is reconciling all sin in nothingness, nothingness that could only be reached through the everythingness of the Cross. Thus I become nothing, as from before creation. In order to live I must be born again. And this is only accomplished in the resurrection. But for all eternity there is the death of sin in the mind of Christ. And for all eternity there is newness of life. There cannot be one without the other.</p>
<p>And so why did God do this? If he knew we would all sin and fall short of his glory, then it seems the Cross and the resurrection was just a charade for our entertainment. Something to make us feel better about ourselves, to lift our self-esteem out of the dirt. Really? Is that really why Jesus suffered and died? Was the Passion simply God playing a mulligan with us, his creation?</p>
<p>Or was there a deeper reconciliation going on? Is all of creation, every star, every galaxy, every black hole somehow pointing to something we cannot yet see? Is all of human history&#8212;every war, every civilization, every kingdom&#8212;somehow a part of a symphony only God can hear?</p>
<blockquote><p>So <i>let’s get this clear:</i> it’s for My own sake <i>that I save you</i>.</p></blockquote>
<p>Does God owe us, his creation, an explanation? He says he did this for his own sake. I don&#8217;t believe I will ever know why. If I can ever get my arms around God&#8217;s <em>why</em>, then I can be sure it&#8217;s not God.</p>
<p>Sunday will be here soon with candy and dyed eggs and spiral-sliced ham. But let us not rush past Friday with bitter wine and darkness and death. We do not see clearly now what God is reconciling through the Cross, be we can see God in the Cross. He is there. And he has rescued us from nothingness for his sake.</p>
<p>Happy Good Friday.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-reconciliation-of-the-cross/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week: Preaching as Good as It Gets</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-preaching-as-good-as-it-gets</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-preaching-as-good-as-it-gets#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 17:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39935</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nothing could have stopped this Pascal mystery of God and humanity. No amount of super-good discipleship or wisdom or hindsight would make a lick of difference to God’s determination to draw all people to God’s self through Jesus lifted high and on a cross. See, we are no different than the shouting crowds – those [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_39936" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 608px"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Giotto-Entry-e1364354887291.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-39936 " alt="Entry into Jerusalem (detail), Giotto" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Giotto-Entry-e1364354887291.jpg" width="598" height="376" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Entry into Jerusalem (detail), Giotto</p></div>
<p>Nothing could have stopped this Pascal mystery of God and humanity. No amount of super-good discipleship or wisdom or hindsight would make a lick of difference to God’s determination to draw all people to God’s self through Jesus lifted high and on a cross.</p>
<p>See, we are no different than the shouting crowds – those that do the right thing for the wrong reason or those who do the wrong thing for the right reason.  There is no better class of improved people.  There are just people.</p>
<p>And as soon as we think the good news is that we know better than those caught up in into the tragic events of that first Holy Week, we are mistaken. As soon as we think the good news is that we now know how to do the right things and for the right reasons we are mistaken.</p>
<p>Because it had to happen like this.   When the Pharisees told Jesus to stop his disciples from such an embarrassing display, he said that were they to stop even the stones would cry out. So there had to be crowds who shout praise  and friends who betrayed and followers who denied and women who wept and soldiers who mocked and thieves who believed. It would have happened like this even if the Jesus event were happening now instead of then.  Even if we knew everything in advance – were we the ones on the street we too would shout Hosanna and a few days later shout crucify him.  And <em>that’s</em> the good news when it comes down to it. Because these people of the Holy Week story are we people.  And we people are the likes of which God came to save. God did not become human and dwell among us as Jesus to save only an improved, doesn’t make the wrong choices kind of people. There is no improved version of humanity that could have done any differently.</p>
<p>So go ahead. Don’t wait until you think your motivations are correct.  Don’t wait till you are sure you believe every single line of the Nicene creed (no one does).  Don’t worry about coming to church this week for the right reasons. Just wave branches. Shout praise for the wrong reason. Eat a meal. Have your feet washed. Grab at coins. Shout Crucify him. Walk away when the cock crows.  Because we, as we are and not as some improved version of ourselves…we are who God came to save. And nothing can stop what’s going to happen.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><a href="http://www.patheos.com/blogs/nadiabolzweber/2013/03/palm-sunday-sermon-about-morbid-reflection-home-perms-and-fickle-crowds/"><strong>Palm Sunday Sermon about Morbid Reflection,<br />
Home Perms, and Fickle Crowds</strong></a><br />
<em>Nadia Bolz-Weber</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-preaching-as-good-as-it-gets/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week with Duccio: Christ Taking Leave of the Apostles</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-juda</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-juda#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39800</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;While Jesus is giving the new commandment to the apostles (now eleven), Judas betrays him for thirty pieces of silver. In Christ Taking Leave of the Apostles, his sideways position, shown up by the half-open door, is in contrast to the close-knit group of disciples. They are all turning the same way in thoughtful attitudes, the soft [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Christ-Leaving.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-39857" alt="Duccio Christ Leaving" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Christ-Leaving.jpg" width="510" height="446" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8220;While Jesus is giving the new commandment to the apostles (now eleven), Judas betrays him for thirty pieces of silver. In <em>Christ Taking Leave of the Apostles</em>, his sideways position, shown up by the half-open door, is in contrast to the close-knit group of disciples. They are all turning the same way in thoughtful attitudes, the soft drapery of their coloured robes animating the whole scene. As in the <em>Washing of the Feet </em>and the <em>Last Supper</em> Duccio has avoided halos since the conspicuous shape of the golden discs might have created an overpowering effect, besides taking up most of the space in the picture.&#8221; (WGA)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-juda/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week Hijinks…and Worse</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-hijinks-and-worse</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-hijinks-and-worse#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 04:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Circus Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39918</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Why is it that Holy Week seems to bring out the worst in American church culture? Ministries and church leaders that call anathemas down on venerable traditions that have stood the test of time and kept the faith alive throughout Church history have no problem adopting the cheesiest and most insubstantial gimmicks to get people [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Why is it that Holy Week seems to bring out the worst in American church culture?</p>
<p>Ministries and church leaders that call anathemas down on venerable traditions that have stood the test of time and kept the faith alive throughout Church history have no problem adopting the cheesiest and most insubstantial gimmicks to get people through the door during Easter season. Tetzel had nothing on contemporary pastors, who have wealth, technology, and media at their disposal.</p>
<p>Here is Pastor Rod (I have a really deep voice so you&#8217;d better listen to me) Parsley in his solemn Lenten best promoting his &#8220;Mission Possible&#8221; seasonal series by flying to the stage on a zip line, while the &#8220;praise&#8221; band plays the Mission Impossible theme.</p>
<p><em>Church du soleil</em>.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/0bDRFNlUvGk" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>If that were the worst of it, I&#8217;d just chalk it up to bad taste and shake my head. But what is worse, ministries like Parsley&#8217;s are actually promoting a dangerous, deficient message that has nothing to do with the season, the Cross, the Empty Tomb, or Jesus, and everything to do with money and power.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/c24NPEASv3s" height="315" width="420" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>I&#8217;m normally not given to anathemas, but I have to ask this question:</p>
<p><em>Is it time we start viewing these &#8220;ministries&#8221; as we do groups like the Mormons &#8212; good, conservative, moral people who conceive of a different God, acknowledge a different Jesus, proclaim a different Gospel, and practice a different faith than orthodox Christianity?</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-hijinks-and-worse/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>65</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week with Duccio: Last Supper</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-annunciation</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-annunciation#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 16:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39796</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Source: Web Gallery of Art &#8220;The Last Supper is dominated by the central figure of Jesus who, to the astonishment of the onlookers, is offering bread to Judas Iscariot (shown in other panels with the same features). An unusual experiment with space has been made with John, whose position is traditional: the head of the favourite disciple is painted [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Last-Supper.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-39848" alt="Duccio Last Supper" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Last-Supper.jpg" width="510" height="440" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Source: <a href="http://www.wga.hu/frames-e.html?/html/d/duccio/maesta/verso_1/verso03.html"><strong>Web Gallery of Art</strong></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8220;The Last Supper is dominated by the central figure of Jesus who, to the astonishment of the onlookers, is offering bread to Judas Iscariot (shown in other panels with the same features). An unusual experiment with space has been made with John, whose position is traditional: the head of the favourite disciple is painted in front of the figure of Christ, and his halo behind Christ&#8217;s shoulders. Wooden bowls, knives, a decorated jug and a meat dish, and the paschal lamb, are set on the table, which is covered with a simple tablecloth woven in a small diamond pattern.&#8221; (WGA)</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-annunciation/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week: Another Look at “Cleaning Closets”</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-another-look-at-cleaning-closets</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-another-look-at-cleaning-closets#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 04:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39904</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[NOTE: One of the traditions of Monday-Wednesday in Holy Week is spring cleaning, which goes back to the customs of Jewish families as they prepared for Passover. In honor of this tradition, here is another look at one of CM&#8217;s posts from July, 2010. And, heavens no, he is not actually doing any spring cleaning! [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/fibbers-closet.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-39907" alt="fibbers closet" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/fibbers-closet-234x300.jpg" width="234" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><strong>NOTE</strong>: <a href="http://www.catholicculture.org/culture/liturgicalyear/activities/view.cfm?id=1061">One of the traditions of Monday-Wednesday in Holy Week is <strong>spring cleaning</strong></a>, which goes back to the customs of Jewish families as they prepared for Passover. In honor of this tradition, here is another look at one of CM&#8217;s posts from July, 2010. And, heavens no, he is not actually <em>doing</em> any spring cleaning!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>I came home from a weekend away intent on cleaning out closets.</p>
<p>This urge occasionally strikes, and when it does, I’ve learned to lie down until it goes away.</p>
<p>Ridding home and life of clutter sometimes seems overwhelming, especially now, living in a house and at a time of life when most of it is out of sight. Motivation was easy when I had to look at the mess, and when we were tripping over it all the time.</p>
<p>The nest is now mostly empty, with seasonal lodging for our college students. Only the occasional visit from grandchildren leaves our floors covered with toys. It used to be that way a half dozen times a day. We have plenty of closet space, an attic that is big enough to be a third floor, and basement and garage storage.</p>
<p>And it’s all full.</p>
<p>My wife and I are certainly not hoarders, and though we lean toward the “pack rat” end of the spectrum, we don’t have an extraordinary amount of stuff. However, we have been married for more than three decades, had four children, are sentimental about our family memories, and are admitted book- and music-aholics. Our children live nearby or are in college, so lot of their stuff is still stashed at mom and dad’s.</p>
<p>Plus, we’ve been in school or ministry and traveling ever since we’ve known each other, so we’re always collecting articles, magazines, ministry tools, souvenirs and keepsakes. There are boxes of empty three-ring binders, boxes of stuff from our India trips, boxes filled with items from my desk and files at church, boxes of journals filled with six or seven pages of writing before I lost interest, boxes of old kids clothes, blankets, books, and papers we didn’t want to part with, boxes of stuff we retrieved from boxes of stuff at grandma and grandpa’s home when they cleaned their closets.</p>
<p>I’ve always loved taking pictures, and so we have a gazillion photos, a few photo albums and lots of bulging boxes. We’ve used a personal computer since 1988. What in heaven’s name do you do with all those disks, cords, adapters, manuals, drives, modems, scanners, cds, printers, cameras, and other equipment now collecting dust because they became outdated or replaced by newer stuff? We put it all in boxes and shove it in the back of the closet.</p>
<p>I’m not even sure what’s in all the boxes in the attic and basement. I’m sure I don’t want to know.</p>
<p>In traditional lingo, the metaphor of the <em>“closet”</em> implies that a person is hiding something. “Coming out of the closet” means making a public declaration of something you’ve been trying to avoid revealing. If you have “skeletons” in your closet, you’ve been covering up for a long time.</p>
<p>In the classic devotional story, <em><a href="http://www.ivpress.com/cgi-ivpress/book.pl/code=75">My Heart Christ’s Home</a></em>, Robert Munger uses closet imagery to discuss how Christ wants to penetrate every area in our life, even the areas we try to hide from him, in order to cleanse and transform us fully.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>One day I found Him waiting for me at the door. An arresting look was in His eye. As I entered, He said to me, “There is a peculiar odor on the house. Something must be dead around here. It’s upstairs. I think it’s in the hall closet.”</em></p>
<p><em>As soon as He said this, I know what He was talking about. There was a small closet up there on the hall landing, just a few feet square. In that closet, behind lock and key, I had one or two personal things that I did not want anyone to know about. Certainly, I did not want Christ to see them. I knew they were dead and rotting things left over from the old life. I wanted them so for myself that I was afraid to admit they were there.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>That’s a legitimate and, at times, convicting use of the metaphor. But it’s not really what I’m talking about here. We’re not hiding anything in our closets, at least as far as I know. That, in fact, would be self-defeating, since we probably couldn’t find said hidden treasure if we wanted to get our hands on it.</p>
<p><span id="more-39904"></span></p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-39910" alt="cluttered-closet-clothes-mess" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/cluttered-closet-clothes-mess-223x300.jpg" width="223" height="300" />No, our closets and attic and basement and garage and files and drawers are full mostly because I’ve neglected doing anything about them. I’ve ignored them. I’m lazy. Nothing has arrested my attention and compelled me to deal with the situation. This task has moved from the back of my mind to the back burner to somewhere in the outback. So, behind all those closed doors exists a hidden world of neglected remnants from our life.</p>
<p>This doesn’t make a lot of sense, given what I do. I am, after all, a hospice chaplain. I have conversations with patients and families every day about getting their affairs in order. I do bereavement care and hear horror stories of the messes entrusted to those left behind. It hits me regularly &#8212; I don’t want to do this to my kids. By the time I get home, the feeling has passed.</p>
<p>My grandparents and parents have set a good example for me. Over the years, they have shown a profound grace in ordering their lives, not only for themselves, but for their children. At times, I’ve thought them a bit OCD, but then I open my closet door and appreciate their ruthless purging.</p>
<p>Furthermore, it always feels so good when an organizing and simplifying task is completed! <em>“It is good,” </em>declared God with each step of bringing order to chaos at creation. Establishing a bit of harmony and symmetry is immensely satisfying. There’s a reason Feng shui has become so popular.</p>
<p>Why then the hesitancy? Why the perpetual procrastination? Why the inability to toe the line, to begin the task?</p>
<p>A long time ago, I read these words and knew that they were right:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Ultimately there is only one impediment [to spiritual growth], and that is laziness. If we overcome laziness, all the other impediments will be overcome. If we do not overcome laziness, none of the others will be hurdled.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>- M. Scott Peck, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Road-Less-Traveled-25th-Anniversary/dp/0743243153/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1279669361&amp;sr=8-1">The Road Less Traveled</a>, p. 271<br />
</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Peck points out that laziness is love’s opposite. For to love is to extend oneself to and for another. Unwillingness to do so is nonlove of the most serious kind. In her fine book of meditations on the deadly sin of <em>acedia</em>, Kathleen Norris reminds us that this word, usually referred to as <em>“sloth,”</em> means literally,<em> “the absence of care”</em>. The person who is ruled by this deadly sin is incapable or undesirous of caring.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>When life becomes too challenging and engagement with others too demanding, acedia offers a kind of spiritual morphine: you know the pain is there, yet can’t rouse yourself to give a damn.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>- <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Acedia-Marriage-Monks-Writers-Life/dp/1594484384/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1279671148&amp;sr=1-1">Acedia &amp; Me</a>, p. 3<br />
</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>One of the classic writers on this deadly state of mind, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Institutes-St-John-Cassian/dp/0809105225/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1279671196&amp;sr=1-1-spell">John Cassian</a>, teaches that acedia:</p>
<ul>
<li>Makes us disgusted with our current surroundings and circumstances,</li>
<li>Causes us to disdain others who are close to us,</li>
<li>Renders us immobile in the face of the work to be done in our lives,</li>
<li>Makes it impossible for us to concentrate and think clearly,</li>
<li>Makes us of little or no help to others because we’re always lamenting and complaining,</li>
<li>Prompts us to imagine that other places or situations would be far better,</li>
<li>Causes us to feel exhausted and wanting to take comfort in food and sleep,</li>
<li>Encourages us to take up other (easier) tasks and neglect our true duties,</li>
</ul>
<p>Open dictionary, insert my picture. In front of an open closet door.</p>
<p>When <a href="http://www.backtothebible.org/index.php/Gateway-to-Joy/Do-the-Next-Thing.html">Elisabeth Elliot</a> went back to the mission field after the death of her husband Jim, she was faced with many confusing circumstances and uncertainties. She took solace and instruction from an old Saxon legend that had been written into a poem. In old English, each stanza of the poem ended with the simple words, <strong>“Doe the next thynge.”</strong> The verses speak about trusting God, fearing not the future, being prayerful, reliant, reverent, resting in Jesus’ faithfulness. But above all, act on your faith and <em>“doe the next thynge,”</em> and do it immediately, leaving the results to him. In Elliot’s words, she tried to take this counsel to heart, and <em>“take each duty quietly as the will of God for the moment.”</em></p>
<p>Some people struggle more with trying to do too much for God, running ahead of him, substituting their ideas, plans, strategies, resources, and strength for the Spirit’s enabling energy and the Word’s quickening power. They produce impressive works but are lacking in fruit. They fulfill their agenda. Tasks get accomplished. Sometimes at the expense of people or other, more profoundly important matters.</p>
<p>Some people struggle more with a spirit of lethargy, sloth, acedia. They can’t find the moxie to simply <em>“do the next thing.” </em>They might find other things to do, and may indeed look busy. It’s a cover. They are neglecting the true thing, the important thing, the next thing. The loving thing. The thing that requires them to extend themselves for the good of others. What little they get done is ephemeral. And they remain alone.</p>
<p>In our weakness, we swing from pole to pole. We find it difficult to live in that place where we are <em>“walking in newness of life,”</em> (Romans 6:4), <em>“bearing fruit in every good work and increasing in the knowledge of God; strengthened with all power, according to His glorious might, for the attaining of all steadfastness and patience” </em>(Colossians 1:10-11), devoting ourselves to to God’s purposes and <em>laboring</em> to fulfill them, <em>“striving according to His power, which mightily works within”</em> us (Colossians 1:29).</p>
<p>Simply doing the next thing in him, his way, by his Spirit, for his glory, for the good of others.</p>
<p>I hear a closet calling.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-another-look-at-cleaning-closets/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week: Dinner with Him Once Dead</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-dinner-with-him-once-dead</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-dinner-with-him-once-dead#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 15:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39874</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Six days before the Passover Jesus came to Bethany, the home of Lazarus, whom he had raised from the dead. There they gave a dinner for him. Martha served, and Lazarus was one of those at the table with him. (John 12:1-2) * * * This story intrigues me. Normally, when reading John 12:1-11, we [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_39879" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 592px"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Giotto-Lazarus-detail.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-39879" alt="Giotto Lazarus detail" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Giotto-Lazarus-detail.jpg" width="582" height="338" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Raising of Lazarus, Giotto</p></div>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Six days before the Passover Jesus came to Bethany, the home of Lazarus, whom he had raised from the dead. There they gave a dinner for him. Martha served, and Lazarus was one of those at the table with him.</em> (John 12:1-2)</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>This story intrigues me. Normally, when reading <a href="http://bible.oremus.org/?ql=231155577"><strong>John 12:1-11</strong></a>, we focus on Mary&#8217;s act of anointing Jesus and Judas&#8217;s objection to what she did. But the narrative about Mary&#8217;s deed is framed with an emphasis on <em>Lazarus</em>. Twice it points out that Lazarus was the one Jesus raised from the dead. To set the stage for the story of the meal, John notes that Lazarus was present at the table with Jesus and that the dinner was given in honor of Jesus &#8212; presumably to thank him for restoring Lazarus to life. Then, following the anointing account, the text ends with these words:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>When the great crowd of the Jews learned that he was there, they came not only because of Jesus but also to see Lazarus, whom he had raised from the dead. So the chief priests planned to put Lazarus to death as well, since it was on account of him that many of the Jews were deserting and were believing in Jesus.</em></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever heard a sermon on what it must have been like to have dinner with someone who had recently been a corpse, dead and buried for four days. But that&#8217;s a genuine curiosity, don&#8217;t you think?</p>
<p><strong>What would American church culture do with this?</strong> Can you imagine? With our technological and marketing skills, Lazarus would have been a religious superstar of the highest order. Book and movie contracts. A tour of appearances and interviews. Given our hunger for the supernatural and the sensational, Lazarus&#8217;s &#8220;experience&#8221; would be first proclaimed and promoted, and then dissected and discussed and debated <em>ad nauseum</em>. I&#8217;m sure there would be a thousand questions about Lazarus&#8217;s &#8220;death experience&#8221; &#8212; what he saw and encountered on the other side. There would, of course, be doubters and those arguing that it couldn&#8217;t have happened as advertised because the experiential claims go against sound doctrine. Some would proclaim the event a clear sign that the last days are upon us.</p>
<p>The text itself (along with <a href="http://bible.oremus.org/?ql=231157980"><strong>John 12:17-19</strong></a>, the last mention of Lazarus in the NT) indicates that Lazarus and what Jesus did for him attracted crowds and generated enthusiasm. If true then, can you conceive of the media blitz that would accompany a happening like this today?</p>
<p><strong>Dinner with him once dead</strong>. Can we even imagine?</p>
<p>And then it struck me: if the Lord&#8217;s Supper is a true sacrament, if Jesus, our crucified and risen Lord is present, and if the baptized who come to the Table are those who <em>&#8220;have been buried with him by baptism into death, so that, just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glory of the Father, so we too might walk in newness of life,&#8221;</em> (Rom. 6:4), then each time we meet together for Communion, we are having dinner among the once dead.</p>
<p>The crowds may not come.</p>
<p>The event may not make the news.</p>
<p>It may, indeed, seem the very opposite of spectacle and enthusiasm.</p>
<p>But his flesh is true food and his blood is true drink &#8212; Jesus&#8217; dying love for the life of the world.</p>
<p>And we who come were once dead, but now live in the risen Christ.</p>
<p>A once in a lifetime experience for Lazarus has now become (at least) an every week event. And you are invited &#8212; Dinner with him once dead! With a whole room of people once dead!</p>
<p>Y&#8217;all come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-dinner-with-him-once-dead/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week with Duccio: Resurrection of Lazarus</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-lazarus</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-lazarus#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 04:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39789</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Source: Web Gallery of Art The Gospel reading for Monday in Holy Week is John 12:1-11. This tells the story of Mary, Lazarus&#8217;s sister, anointing Jesus&#8217; feet at a dinner in their home in honor of Lazarus, whom Jesus raised from the dead. That act of bringing Lazarus back to life is emphasized throughout the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Lazarus.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-39836" alt="Duccio Lazarus" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Lazarus.jpg" width="539" height="510" /></a>Source: <a href="http://www.wga.hu/frames-e.html?/html/d/duccio/maesta/predel_v/pre_v_i.html"><strong>Web Gallery of Art</strong></a></p>
<p>The Gospel reading for Monday in Holy Week is <a href="http://bible.oremus.org/?ql=231131052"><strong>John 12:1-11</strong></a>. This tells the story of Mary, Lazarus&#8217;s sister, anointing Jesus&#8217; feet at a dinner in their home in honor of Lazarus, whom Jesus raised from the dead. That act of bringing Lazarus back to life is emphasized throughout the text and was of such import that the officials decided they should not only kill Jesus, but Lazarus as well. Duccio&#8217;s panel portrays the event itself, which is recorded in the previous chapter, John 11.</p>
<p>Note the vivid colors, the intensity upon the faces of the characters, the depictions of Mary kneeling at Jesus&#8217; feet and Martha making her request, Lazarus himself tightly bound in the grave-cloths, and the lifelike, almost humorous portrayal of the man holding his nose for fear of the stench of death.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-lazarus/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic
Page Caching using disk: enhanced

 Served from: www.internetmonk.com @ 2013-03-29 00:02:31 by W3 Total Cache -->
