<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/" xmlns:creativeCommons="http://backend.userland.com/creativeCommonsRssModule" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>internetmonk.com</title>
	
	<link>http://www.internetmonk.com</link>
	<description>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 04:01:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
<!-- podcast_generator="Blubrry PowerPress/4.0.7" -->
	<itunes:summary>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:author>The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer</itunes:author>
	<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/monkposterx3.jpg" />
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer</itunes:name>
		<itunes:email>michael@internetmonk.com</itunes:email>
	</itunes:owner>
	<managingEditor>michael@internetmonk.com (The Internet Monk, Michael Spencer)</managingEditor>
	<copyright>2006-2009</copyright>
	<itunes:subtitle>...dispatches from the post-evangelical wilderness</itunes:subtitle>
	<image><link>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</link><url>http://creativecommons.org/images/public/somerights20.gif</url><title>Some Rights Reserved</title></image>
	<itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
		<itunes:category text="Christianity" />
	</itunes:category>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/internetmonk/SWqj" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="internetmonk/swqj" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</creativeCommons:license><feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">internetmonk/SWqj</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>Easter Monday Reflections</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/easter-monday-reflections</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/easter-monday-reflections#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 04:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40040</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[But on the first day of the week, at early dawn, they came to the tomb, taking the spices that they had prepared. They found the stone rolled away from the tomb, but when they went in, they did not find the body. While they were perplexed about this, suddenly two men in dazzling clothes [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/BLC2010a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40050" alt="BLC2010a" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/BLC2010a.jpg" width="560" height="352" /></a></p>
<p><em>But on the first day of the week, at early dawn, they came to the tomb, taking the spices that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">they had prepared</span>. They found the stone rolled away from the tomb, but when they went in, they did not find the body. While <span style="text-decoration: underline;">they were perplexed</span> about this, suddenly two men in dazzling clothes stood beside them. The women <span style="text-decoration: underline;">were terrified</span> and bowed their faces to the ground, but the men said to them, ‘Why do you look for the living among the dead? He is not here, but has risen. Remember how he told you, while he was still in Galilee, that the Son of Man must be handed over to sinners, and be crucified, and on the third day rise again.’ Then they remembered his words, and returning from the tomb, they told all this to the eleven and to all the rest. Now it was Mary Magdalene, Joanna, Mary the mother of James, and the other women with them who told this to the apostles. But these words seemed to them an idle tale, and <span style="text-decoration: underline;">they did not believe them</span>. But Peter got up and ran to the tomb; stooping and looking in, he saw the linen cloths by themselves; then <span style="text-decoration: underline;">he went home, amazed</span> at what had happened.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: right;">- Luke 24:1-12</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p><em>&#8220;He went home, amazed&#8230;&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Yesterday, the Gospel lesson for Easter Sunday from Luke traced the <strong>emotional journey</strong> of some of Jesus&#8217; friends early on the first Easter morning.</p>
<ul>
<li>The women went to the tomb <em>prepared</em> to deal with death.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Finding the stone rolled away, and the tomb empty, they were <em>perplexed</em> as to what had happened.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Confronted by &#8220;two men in dazzling clothes&#8221; who announced the good news of the resurrection, they became <em>terrified</em> and fell to the ground in fear.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>When the women rushed back and told the apostles and others, the disciples <em>did not believe</em> their report.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>After running to the site and seeing the empty tomb for himself, Peter went home, <em>amazed</em>.</li>
</ul>
<p>This was the first year I fully celebrated the Three Days (Triduum) and Easter Sunday with a congregation, and I felt something of this emotional journey as I never have before.</p>
<p>Thursday evening, we had a lovely <strong>Maundy Thursday</strong> service. By nature, this night is a time of mixed feelings. The meal we shared together brought joy. The practice of washing feet reminded us of our loving connection with our sisters and brothers. We had less formal music that night: piano, guitars, violins, and percussion, along with an ensemble of singers that led folk-style and contemporary hymns. Our youth put on a chancel drama reenacting the Last Supper, the footwashing and Jesus&#8217; teaching in the Upper Room. In the midst of our intimate fellowship, however, there was an sense of foreboding that erupted into word suddenly when, at the end of the service, a reader stood up and recited the words of <a href="http://bible.oremus.org/?ql=231780608"><strong>Psalm 88</strong></a>:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>O Lord, God of my salvation,</em><br />
<em>when, at night, I cry out in your presence, </em><br />
<em>let my prayer come before you;</em><br />
<em>incline your ear to my cry. </em><br />
<em> For my soul is full of troubles,</em><br />
<em>and my life draws near to Sheol.</em></p>
<p>As we silently reflected on this sorrowful lament, the pastor cleared the Table, removed its cloth, and put away all symbols of celebration. We arose in silence and went into the night.</p>
<p>The mood on <strong>Good Friday</strong> evening, of course, was somber. A simple service had been prepared, built around Heinrich Schütz&#8217;s <em>&#8220;Die sieben Worte Jesu Christe am Kreuz.&#8221; </em>To open, a hymn was sung, followed by prayer and an introductory homily by the pastor on the Seven Words. Then we moved into a pattern in which we alternated sections of the choral piece, the reading of the Seven Words, silence, chimes marking the Words, and prayers. The sanctuary was quiet, attentive, and reverent. The singing of Jesus&#8217; words in German along with the pipe organ and violins was deeply expressive and moving.</p>
<p>We had journeyed as far as Calvary.</p>
<p><span id="more-40040"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/8604373657_17fb502d0b.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-40052" alt="8604373657_17fb502d0b" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/8604373657_17fb502d0b-300x199.jpg" width="300" height="199" /></a>On Saturday we gathered outside around a fire in the cool of the evening for the <strong>Easter Vigil</strong>. We stood in front of the church and at sunset our pastor called us to a spirit of hope and expectation, lighting our candles from the fire and leading us into the dark sanctuary in procession. Lightened only by our candles, we found our seats and were called to worship. Again, we followed a simple repetitive pattern. The story of the First Testament was read from key passages, each followed by a sung psalm of response with cantor and congregation, followed by prayer. As the night deepened and we heard our family story recited, the light grew brighter. And then it was time to mark new birth. The entire congregation gathered around the font as a family brought their infant child to be baptized. After the rite, our pastor took a branch and sprinkled us all with water to remind us of our baptism, our passing from darkness to light in Christ. By then, the lights of the sanctuary were burning bright, and we sang hymns of resurrection and life in honor of Jesus, our risen Lord, giving thanks for his victory and our salvation. Gladly we came to the Table and shared the Feast together.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>At the Lamb&#8217;s high feast we sing</em><br />
<em> Praise to our victorious king</em><br />
<em> Who has washed us in the tide</em><br />
<em> Flowing from his wounded side.</em><br />
<em> Alleluia!</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Easter triumph, Easter joy</em><br />
<em> This alone can sin destroy!</em><br />
<em> From sin&#8217;s pow&#8217;r, Lord, set us free</em><br />
<em> Newborn souls in you to be.</em><br />
<em> Alleluia!</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><small>- Latin Hymn, 17th century<br />
Translated by Robert Campbell</small></p>
<p>After the service, the congregation came together for fellowship, complete with wine, champagne, sweets, fruits, breads and cheeses. The mood was festive, the conversations lively, smiles and laughter pervasive.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/easter_lily_wallpaper_free-e1364784588342.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-40055" alt="easter_lily_wallpaper_free" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/easter_lily_wallpaper_free-e1364784588342-300x283.jpg" width="240" height="226" /></a>And then came <strong>Easter Sunday</strong>. Rather than being a single day to mark Jesus&#8217; resurrection, I found myself experiencing the morning as the culmination of a journey. We arrived to share in the Easter brunch of pastries, fruit, and boiled eggs. The fellowship hall was packed with people wearing brighter colors, introducing congregation members to members of their families, delighting in the children, welcoming old friends not seen in awhile. The service was filled with solid celebratory hymns accompanied by pipe organ, brass, and choir. The altar was bedecked with lilies and spring flowers in bright pastel colors. It took much longer to commune all the people; the sanctuary was full. We exited in peace, set free to serve the risen Lord. We embraced and left to share special meals with our families, having celebrated Christ, having also remembered in prayer those who yet hunger and thirst and long for new birth.</p>
<p>I felt a bit like Peter. I went home, amazed.</p>
<p>A journey had ended. A new journey begun.</p>
<p>An Easter people had been born anew, raised to walk in newness of life.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s Easter Monday.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/easter-monday-reflections/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week with Duccio: Appearance behind Locked Doors</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-with-duccio-appearance-to-mary-magdelene</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-with-duccio-appearance-to-mary-magdelene#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 05:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39865</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Christ Jesus lay in death&#8217;s strong bands for our offenses given; but now at God&#8217;s right hand he stands and brings us life from heaven. Therefore let us joyful be and sing to God right thankfully loud songs of hallelujah! Hallelujah!  So let us keep the festival to which the Lord invites us; Christ is [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/duccio-appearance.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40027" alt="duccio appearance" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/duccio-appearance.jpg" width="580" height="428" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Christ Jesus lay in death&#8217;s strong bands</em><br />
<em> for our offenses given;</em><br />
<em> but now at God&#8217;s right hand he stands</em><br />
<em> and brings us life from heaven.</em><br />
<em> Therefore let us joyful be</em><br />
<em> and sing to God right thankfully</em><br />
<em> loud songs of hallelujah! Hallelujah! </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em id="__mceDel"> So let us keep the festival<br />
to which the Lord invites us;<br />
Christ is the very joy of all,<br />
the sun that warms and lights us.<br />
Now his grace to us imparts<br />
eternal sunshine to our hearts;<br />
the night of sin is ended. Hallelujah!</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><small>- Martin Luther</small></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-with-duccio-appearance-to-mary-magdelene/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week with Duccio: Deposition</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-deposition</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-deposition#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 22:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39862</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Faithful cross, true sign of triumph, be for all the noblest tree; none in foliage, none in blossom, none in fruit your equal be; symbol of the world&#8217;s redemption, for your burden makes us free. - &#8220;Sing, my Tongue&#8221; Venantius Honorius Clementianus Fortunatus (ca. 535-600) trans. by John Mason Neale]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Deposition.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-39863" alt="Duccio Deposition" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Deposition.jpg" width="510" height="472" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Faithful cross, true sign of triumph,</em><br />
<em> be for all the noblest tree;</em><br />
<em> none in foliage, none in blossom,</em><br />
<em> none in fruit your equal be;</em><br />
<em> symbol of the world&#8217;s redemption,</em><br />
<em> for your burden makes us free.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>- &#8220;Sing, my Tongue&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><small>Venantius Honorius Clementianus Fortunatus (ca. 535-600)<br />
trans. by John Mason Neale</small></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-deposition/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Footnotes on Holy Saturday</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/footnotes-on-holy-saturday</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/footnotes-on-holy-saturday#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 16:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship & Liturgy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=40006</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;It is rare to hear a sermon about Easter Saturday; for much of Christian history the day has found no place in liturgy and worship it could call its own within the triduum, or three-day festival spanning Good Friday and the Day of Resurrection&#8230;&#8221; - Between Cross and Resurrection: A Theology of Holy Saturday Alan E. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Holy-Saturday-e1364654989214.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-40009" alt="Holy Saturday" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Holy-Saturday-e1364654989214.jpg" width="581" height="250" /></a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>&#8220;It is rare to hear a sermon about Easter Saturday; for much of Christian history the day has found no place in liturgy and worship it could call its own within the triduum, or three-day festival spanning Good Friday and the Day of Resurrection&#8230;&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: right;">- <strong><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0802826784/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0802826784&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=goonewdai-20">Between Cross and Resurrection: A Theology of Holy Saturday</a></strong><img alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=goonewdai-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0802826784" width="1" height="1" border="0" /><br />
Alan E. Lewis</p>
<p>Here is the text of Alan Lewis&#8217;s footnote on that statement:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/between-cross-and-resurrection-a-theology-of-holy-saturday-193x3001.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-40003" alt="between-cross-and-resurrection-a-theology-of-holy-saturday-193x300" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/between-cross-and-resurrection-a-theology-of-holy-saturday-193x3001.jpg" width="154" height="240" /></a>There have, of course, always been special prayers and readings for &#8220;Holy Saturday&#8221; in church traditions with fixed liturgies and lectionaries. But torn &#8212; quite properly &#8212; between contrite memory and expectant hope, the church has often found it impossible to clarify any one particular theme or practice for worship and celebration on this day. Indeed, such is the ambiguity and anonymity of Easter Eve that it has sometimes lost its distinctive, if silent, place in the Christian calendar altogether, and been encroached upon liturgically by the other days of the Easter <em>triduum</em>, especially by Easter Day itself. Thus there persisted for centuries a Roman Catholic tradition of chronologically premature celebrations of the Easter Mass, held as early as the Saturday morning. This practice ceased in 1956. It is certainly better for the church to do nothing that is liturgically specific on the second day than to compromise the uniqueness of its position between cross and resurrection by absorbing it as simply an extension of Good Friday or an anticipation of Easter.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">The tradition of Paschal Vigil on Easter Eve, which goes back to apostolic times, has been preserved in both East and West, and is now enjoying something of a revival even in some Protestant circles, is a quite different matter, of course, and wholly appropriate. It preserves the integrity of the narrative, and indeed draws attention to its structure, by not anticipating Easter but waiting patiently, through the long, last hours of Saturday night, until the joyous third-day dawn&#8230;.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">In the theological tradition, as we shall see below, on the Greek Father Gregory of Nyssa has perceived much dogmatic significance in Holy Saturday, while Martin Luther daringly expressed the thought that after Good Friday God&#8217;s very self lay dead in the grave. In contemporary times, the great Roman Catholic theologian Hans Urs von Balthasar has alone, but profoundly, explored the meaning of Holy Saturday&#8230;.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Here is some good perspective on Roman Catholic understanding and practice from<a href="http://www.catholicculture.org/culture/liturgicalyear/calendar/day.cfm?date=2013-03-30"><strong> a helpful article on CatholicCulture.org</strong></a>:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/HolySaturday2.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-40013" alt="HolySaturday2" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/HolySaturday2-289x300.jpg" width="231" height="240" /></a>Holy Saturday (from <i>Sabbatum Sanctum</i>, its official liturgical name) is sacred as the day of the Lord&#8217;s rest; it has been called the &#8220;Second Sabbath&#8221; after creation. The day is and should be the most calm and quiet day of the entire Church year, a day broken by no liturgical function. Christ lies in the grave, the Church sits near and mourns. After the great battle He is resting in peace, but upon Him we see the scars of intense suffering&#8230;The mortal wounds on His Body remain visible&#8230;.Jesus&#8217; enemies are still furious, attempting to obliterate the very memory of the Lord by lies and slander.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Mary and the disciples are grief-stricken, while the Church must mournfully admit that too many of her children return home from Calvary cold and hard of heart. When Mother Church reflects upon all of this, it seems as if the wounds of her dearly Beloved were again beginning to bleed.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"> According to tradition, the entire body of the Church is represented in Mary: she is the &#8220;credentium collectio universa&#8221; (Congregation for Divine Worship, <em>Lettera circolare sulla preparazione e celebrazione delle feste pasquali</em>, 73). Thus, the Blessed Virgin Mary, as she waits near the Lord&#8217;s tomb, as she is represented in Christian tradition, is an icon of the Virgin Church keeping vigil at the tomb of her Spouse while awaiting the celebration of his resurrection.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>The mood of this day is somewhat different and more expectant, even joyous, in Eastern churches. Holy Saturday is called <strong>&#8220;The Great Sabbath&#8221;</strong> to commemorate Christ resting in the tomb, but it is also the day in which he, in spirit, performed <strong>&#8220;The Harrowing of Hell,&#8221;</strong> setting free those bound in Hades and lifting them up to Paradise. In some Eastern churches, the day is known as <strong>&#8220;Joyous Saturday.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Here is <a href="http://lent.goarch.org/holy_saturday/learn/"><strong>an informative overview from the teaching site of the Greek Orthodox Archdiocese of America</strong></a>:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Harrowing-of-hell-icon.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-40018" alt="Harrowing-of-hell-icon" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Harrowing-of-hell-icon-248x300.jpg" width="248" height="300" /></a>On Great and Holy Saturday the Orthodox Church commemorates the burial of Christ and His descent into Hades. It is the day between the Crucifixion of our Lord and His glorious Resurrection. The Matins of Holy Saturday is conducted on Friday evening, and while many elements of the service represent mourning at the death and burial of Christ, the service itself is one of watchful expectation.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">On Great and Holy Saturday the Church contemplates the mystery of the Lord&#8217;s descent into Hades, the place of the dead. Death, our ultimate enemy, is defeated from within. &#8220;He (Christ) gave Himself as a ransom to death in which we were held captive, sold under sin. Descending into Hades through the Cross &#8230; He loosed the bonds of death&#8221; (Liturgy of St. Basil).</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">On Great Saturday our focus is on the Tomb of Christ. This is no ordinary grave. It is not a place of corruption, decay and defeat. It is life-giving, a source of power, victory and liberation.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Great Saturday is the day between Jesus&#8217; death and His resurrection. It is the day of watchful expectation, in which mourning is being transformed into joy. The day embodies in the fullest possible sense the meaning of xarmolipi &#8211; joyful-sadness, which has dominated the celebrations of Great Week. The hymnographer of the Church has penetrated the profound mystery, and helps us to understand it through the following poetic dialogue that he has devised between Jesus and His Mother:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">&#8220;Weep not for me, O Mother, beholding in the sepulcher the Son whom thou hast conceived without seed in thy womb. For I shall rise and shall be glorified, and as God I shall exalt in everlasting glory those who magnify thee with faith and love.&#8221;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">&#8220;O Son without beginning, in ways surpassing nature was I blessed at Thy strange birth, for I was spared all travail. But now beholding Thee, my God, a lifeless corpse, I am pierced by the sword of bitter sorrow. But arise, that I may be magnified.&#8221;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">&#8220;By mine own will the earth covers me, O Mother, but the gatekeepers of hell tremble as they see me, clothed in the bloodstained garment of vengeance: for on the Cross as God have I struck down mine enemies, and I shall rise again and magnify thee.&#8221;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">&#8220;Let the creation rejoice exceedingly, let all those born on earth be glad: for hell, the enemy, has been despoiled. Ye women, come to meet me with sweet spices: for I am delivering Adam and Eve with all their offspring, and on the third day I shall rise again.&#8221; (9th Ode of the Canon)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Great Saturday is the day of the pre-eminent rest. Christ observes a Sabbath rest in the tomb. His rest, however, is not inactivity but the fulfillment of the divine will and plan for the salvation of humankind and the cosmos. He who brought all things into being, makes all things new. The re-creation of the world has been accomplished once and for all. Through His incarnation, life and death Christ has filled all things with Himself He has opened a path for all flesh to the resurrection from the dead, since it was not possible that the author of life would be dominated by corruption.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/footnotes-on-holy-saturday/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saturday Ramblings 3.30.13</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-3-30-13</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-3-30-13#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 04:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saturday Ramblings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39983</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is Holy Saturday, iMonks. It&#8217;s a day for quiet meditation, silence, solitude. It&#8217;s the day before The Day. And without The Day, we are eternally lost. Yet as you prepare for the joy of tomorrow, don&#8217;t let&#8217;s rush past the despair of today. Now that I have effectively driven all happiness from your day, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Rambler21.jpeg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-38060" alt="Rambler" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Rambler21-300x200.jpeg" width="300" height="200" /></a>It is Holy Saturday, iMonks. It&#8217;s a day for quiet meditation, silence, solitude. It&#8217;s the day before The Day. And without The Day, we are eternally lost. Yet as you prepare for the joy of tomorrow, don&#8217;t let&#8217;s rush past the despair of today. Now that I have effectively driven all happiness from your day, shall we ramble?</p>
<p>I have always been a big admirer of St. Francis. I was introduced to him in the 70s through the Franco Zeffirelli film Brother Sun, Sister Moon. I have read books about him, most notably Nikos Kazantzakis&#8217;s <em>Saint Francis</em>. Perhaps I&#8217;m being premature, but I think we may be seeing yet another St. Francis in this new pope, who wisely&#8212;or prophetically?&#8212;took my spiritual hero&#8217;s name. St. Francis caused great uproar in the established Church of his day through simplicity, poverty, charity. We are <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/pope-reluctant-pope-does-mean-223211212.html" target="_blank"><strong>seeing this now</strong></a> from Pope Francis.</p>
<p>He has decided, at least for the present, to forego the perks of his office, such as living in the well-appointed papal apartments, and will instead reside in a <a href="http://www.religionnews.com/2013/03/26/pope-francis-opts-for-vatican-guesthouse-instead-of-papal-apartment/" target="_blank"><strong>guesthouse</strong></a>. Imagine President Obama giving up the White House to live instead in a nearby Hampton Inn. (Well, ok, they do have really nice pillows &#8230;)</p>
<p>Then he held the <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/03/28/world/europe/vatican-pope/index.html?hpt=hp_c2" target="_blank"><strong>Maundy Thursday mass</strong></a> in a prison for &#8220;young offenders,&#8221; washing the feet of a dozen prisoners. He also spoke on Thursday to more than 2,000 bishops and priests, saying they should be &#8220;shepherds who have the smell of their sheep.&#8221; Are you listening, Protestants and evangelicals?</p>
<p><span id="more-39983"></span></p>
<p>Apparently one Catholic cardinal was listening. <strong><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/28/nyregion/cardinal-dolan-visits-maximum-security-prison.html?_r=1&amp;" target="_blank">Timothy Dolan</a></strong> mixed in with sheep in his home state of New York this week.</p>
<p>Still, not everyone is as thrilled with Pope Francis as I and others are. <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/03/29/opinion/avella-pope-francis/index.html?hpt=hp_t3" target="_blank"><strong>This priest</strong></a> is very pleased so far, while others are upset that he won&#8217;t support their <strong><a href="http://rorate-caeli.blogspot.com/2013/03/for-record-girl-among-12-inmates-whose.html" target="_blank">pet peeves</a></strong>. (Imagine being kind to a female convict. Just who does he think he is? Jesus?) Just remember, if you try to please everyone &#8230;</p>
<p>Well, I suppose I need to at least mention the fun debate before the Supreme Court this week. Not surprisingly, one lawmaker used a <a href="http://michaeloloughlin.religionnews.com/2013/03/24/mccaskill-cites-faith-in-marriage-support/" target="_blank"><strong>passage of Scripture</strong></a> to support her views of gay marriage. But it is surprising to some the direction she took it. You mean people on the other side might also know the Bible? Really?</p>
<p>It is not, as St. Paul Harvey would say, one world. We can buy and own and use and misuse Bibles in the United States all we want. But in several of the <a href="http://blog.christianitytoday.com/ctliveblog/archives/2013/03/bible-burning-spreads-to-another-former-soviet-state.html" target="_blank"><strong>former Soviet states</strong></a>, Bibles and other religious literature are being gathered and burned. And <a href=" http://blog.christianitytoday.com/ctliveblog/archives/2013/03/china_cracks_down_on_house_churches.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+christianitytoday%2Fctliveblog+(Christianity+Today+Liveblog)" target="_blank"><strong>house churches in China</strong></a> are coming under increased pressure from the Chinese government. Read both of these stories carefully. Do you see a connection? What size churches are being forced to close or submit to government regulation? Is it large or small gatherings? Which do you think these governments fear the most? Discuss.</p>
<p>Were any iMonks in Paris this week to hear the <a href="http://articles.washingtonpost.com/2013-03-23/world/37955533_1_bells-inaugurates-nice-sound" target="_blank"><strong>new bells</strong></a> of Notre Dame Cathedral? How do they sound? And wouldn&#8217;t the New Bells Of Notre Dame make for a great Christian worship team? (Oh great. I&#8217;ll bet we actually do see that now. Their first album will be hymns for Mass rearranged for electric guitar and two drum kits with samples of Gregorian chants &#8230;)</p>
<p>In this week&#8217;s scariest news, Liberty University wants to create <a href="http://blog.christianitytoday.com/ctliveblog/archives/2013/03/liberty-university-wants-to-create-tens-of-thousands-kirk-cameron.html" target="_blank"><strong>&#8220;tens of thousands of Kirk Camerons.&#8221;</strong></a> Holy crap. Does that imply they have somehow perfected cloning and are going to inflict this culture with thousands upon thousands of Kirks? What are they doing in Falwellburg anyway?</p>
<p>Finally, what do you do with your Peeps? No, not your entourage. Your Peeps. The little chick-shaped marshmallow treats you will get in your Easter baskets tomorrow. You don&#8217;t eat them, do you? Apparently there are plenty of people who don&#8217;t&#8212;or, at least, they wait until they use them to <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/magazine/peeps-pick-your-favorite-diorama/2013/03/26/50b0bb60-8b4b-11e2-9838-d62f083ba93f_gallery.html#imgid=eba8bb82-8b3b-11e2-9838-d62f083ba93f" target="_blank"><strong>create dioramas</strong></a>. Then maybe they eat them?</p>
<p>Happy birthday was sung this last week for Ric Ocasek; Moses Malone; Harry Houdini; Roscoe &#8220;Fatty&#8221; Arbuckle; Steve McQueen; Jack Ruby; Howard Cosell; Jim Lovell; Hoyt Axton; Aretha Franklin; Sarah Jessica Parker; Leonard Nimoy; Eric Idle; Bob Woodward; Diana Ross; Steven Tyler; Michael York; Dave Koz; Marlin Perkins; Sam Walton; and John Popper.</p>
<p>This week I thought I would share my favorite hymn with you, a hymn very appropriate for this weekend. Truly, because of the death and resurrection of Jesus, God and man at table are sat down. Enjoy, and Happy Resurrection Day.</p>
<iframe width="640" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/PWlUs5E7NpA" frameborder="0" type="text/html"></iframe><div style="text-align:right;"><a style="color:#aaa;font-size:9px" href="http://www.clickonf5.org/" title="IFRAME Embed for Youtube Free WordPress Plugin" target="_blank">IFRAME Embed for Youtube</a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/saturday-ramblings-3-30-13/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week with Duccio: Crucifixion</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-crucifixion</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-crucifixion#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39859</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am one who has seen affliction    under the rod of God’s wrath; he has driven and brought me    into darkness without any light; against me alone he turns his hand,    again and again, all day long. He has made my flesh and my skin waste away,    and broken my bones; he has besieged and enveloped [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Crucifixion.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-39860" alt="Duccio Crucifixion" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Crucifixion.jpg" width="548" height="720" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>I am one who has seen affliction</em><br />
<em>   under the rod of God’s wrath; </em><br />
<em> he has driven and brought me</em><br />
<em>   into darkness without any light; </em><br />
<em> against me alone he turns his hand,</em><br />
<em>   again and again, all day long. </em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em> He has made my flesh and my skin waste away,</em><br />
<em>   and broken my bones; </em><br />
<em> he has besieged and enveloped me</em><br />
<em>   with bitterness and tribulation; </em><br />
<em> he has made me sit in darkness</em><br />
<em>   like the dead of long ago.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">- Lamentations 3:1-6</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-crucifixion/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week: Music of the Cross on Good Friday</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-music-of-the-cross-on-good-friday</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-music-of-the-cross-on-good-friday#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 04:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IM Recommended Listening]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39966</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have the privilege of serving in a fine congregation in Indianapolis this spring as part of my ordination process. This church is filled with gifted musicians and the entire congregation has bought into the ethos of praising God through excellent music. For Good Friday, I will be joining the choir to sing &#8220;Die Sieben [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have the privilege of serving in a fine congregation in Indianapolis this spring as part of my ordination process. This church is filled with gifted musicians and the entire congregation has bought into the ethos of praising God through excellent music.</p>
<p>For Good Friday, I will be joining the choir to sing <a href="http://www.emmanuelmusic.org/notes_translations/translations_motets/t_schutz_swv478.htm"><strong>&#8220;Die Sieben Worte Jesu am Kreuz,&#8221;</strong></a> by Heinrich Schütz (<em>&#8220;The Seven Last Words of Jesus from the Cross&#8221;</em>).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bach-cantatas.com/Lib/Schutz-Heinrich.htm"><strong>Heinrich Schütz</strong></a>, a German composer and organist, is generally regarded as the most important German composer before J.S. Bach. He studied with both Gabrieli and Monteverdi, and is a figure who bridged the transition from Renaissance to Baroque music.</p>
<p>The following is a recording of the <em>Introitus</em>, or introduction, to <em>Die Sieben Worte</em> by the Ambassador Singers of Columbia International University, Dan Kreider, director.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/YyQcIjWz9Ro" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>While Jesus was on the Cross</em><br />
<em> and his body was wounded with bitter pains,</em><br />
<em> contemplate in your heart</em><br />
<em> the seven words that Jesus spoke.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-music-of-the-cross-on-good-friday/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week with Duccio: Washing the Disciples’ Feet</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-washin</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-washin#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 16:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39807</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[And during supper Jesus, knowing that the Father had given all things into his hands, and that he had come from God and was going to God,got up from the table, took off his outer robe, and tied a towel around himself. Then he poured water into a basin and began to wash the disciples’ feet and to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Washing.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-39855" alt="Duccio Washing" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Duccio-Washing.jpg" width="510" height="490" /></a></p>
<blockquote><p>And during supper Jesus, knowing that the Father had given all things into his hands, and that he had come from God and was going to God,got up from the table, took off his outer robe, and tied a towel around himself. Then he poured water into a basin and began to wash the disciples’ feet and to wipe them with the towel that was tied around him.He came to Simon Peter, who said to him, ‘Lord, are you going to wash my feet?’ Jesus answered, ‘You do not know now what I am doing, but later you will understand.’ Peter said to him, ‘You will never wash my feet.’ Jesus answered, ‘Unless I wash you, you have no share with me.’Simon Peter said to him, ‘Lord, not my feet only but also my hands and my head!’ Jesus said to him, ‘One who has bathed does not need to wash, except for the feet, but is entirely clean. And you are clean, though not all of you.’ For he knew who was to betray him; for this reason he said, ‘Not all of you are clean.’</p>
<p>After he had washed their feet, had put on his robe, and had returned to the table, he said to them, ‘Do you know what I have done to you?You call me Teacher and Lord—and you are right, for that is what I am.So if I, your Lord and Teacher, have washed your feet, you also ought to wash one another’s feet. For I have set you an example, that you also should do as I have done to you.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">- John 13:1-14</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many New Testament scholars believe that the famous &#8220;kenosis&#8221; passage in Philippians 2:5-11 is actually an ancient hymn based on the events of John 13. It certainly brings out one of the great lessons of the footwashing account.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Let the same mind be in you that was in Christ Jesus,</em><br />
<em> who, though he was in the form of God,</em><br />
<em> did not regard equality with God</em><br />
<em> as something to be exploited,</em><br />
<em> but emptied himself,</em><br />
<em> taking the form of a slave,</em><br />
<em> being born in human likeness.</em><br />
<em> And being found in human form,</em><br />
<em> he humbled himself</em><br />
<em> and became obedient to the point of death—</em><br />
<em> even death on a cross.</em><br />
<em> Therefore God also highly exalted him</em><br />
<em> and gave him the name</em><br />
<em> that is above every name,</em><br />
<em> so that at the name of Jesus</em><br />
<em> every knee should bend,</em><br />
<em> in heaven and on earth and under the earth,</em><br />
<em> and every tongue should confess</em><br />
<em> that Jesus Christ is Lord,</em><br />
<em> to the glory of God the Father.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/duccio-washin/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Reconciliation Of The Cross</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-reconciliation-of-the-cross</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-reconciliation-of-the-cross#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 05:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Dunn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Eastertide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Dunn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39950</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So let’s get this clear: it’s for My own sake that I save you. I am He who wipes the slate clean and erases your wrongdoing. I will not call to mind your sins anymore. (Isaiah 43:25, The Voice) Tomorrow is Good Friday, the day we remember the Passion of the Cross of Christ. We will remember it [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Jesus-buried.jpg"><img class="wp-image-39953 aligncenter" alt="Jesus buried" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Jesus-buried-1024x768.jpg" width="602" height="452" /></a>So <i>let’s get this clear:</i> it’s for My own sake <i>that I save you</i>.</strong><br />
<strong>I am He who wipes the slate clean and erases your wrongdoing.</strong><br />
<strong>I will not call to mind your sins anymore.</strong> (Isaiah 43:25, The Voice)</p>
<p>Tomorrow is Good Friday, the day we remember the Passion of the Cross of Christ. We will remember it if we perhaps attend a Good Friday service. We may spend a bit of time meditating on the passages of Scripture that show Jesus being tortured and crucified. We may even watch Mel Gibson&#8217;s <em>Passion Of The Christ</em> again. We won&#8217;t spend too much time on the death of Christ, though. Death is boring. We want life&#8212;abundant life. We want the fun of the resurrection. Tomorrow we wear black, while Sunday is for bright colors and &#8220;He is risen indeed&#8221; greetings. Tomorrow we will not greet fellow believers with &#8220;He is dead. He is dead indeed.&#8221;</p>
<p>We rush past the death and burial of Jesus because there is seemingly nothing in it for us. If there is no resurrection, says St. Paul, we are just a bunch of miserable people. And so we are. We are lousy, miserable SOBs who turned our backs on our Creator and went our own way. And worse yet, we somehow have convinced ourselves that God felt really sorry for us and sent Jesus to die so we might maybe possibly come back to God. <em>See?</em> we think we hear God saying. <em>I love you so very much I sent my son to die for you. Now will you believe me? Please oh please oh please come back to me.</em> And now it is all up to us whether we can be bothered with this most Divine Act. We live life so bass ackward it is a wonder why we have eyes that look forward instead of to the rear.</p>
<p>I have some news for us all. The Cross is not for us. It is not about us. The Cross is about Jesus. It begins and ends with the Son of God. The crucifixion of the Christ was not a patchwork plan by the Father. It is not Plan B to make up for failed Plan A. The Cross was God&#8217;s plan from before the Big Bang. The death of Jesus is as much a part of creation as is the Horsehead Nebula or flowering redbud trees or ripe red raspberries. It was God&#8217;s plan all along for the Creator to become a creation and to die. He did this not for our sakes but for his.</p>
<p>And the question before us is this: <em>Why?</em> Why would God spin the entire magnificent universe into existence simply to end up dead on a tree that himself made?</p>
<p><span id="more-39950"></span></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get one thing straight right away. When Jesus died, he died. I think, since we know that he rose from the grave, we tend to think his death was no big deal. It&#8217;s like we think Jesus just took some time off. A three day weekend, as it were. But the Cross is not the Cross if it did not mean the end of the life God. When they took the body of Jesus down from where it had hung and bled, there was no longer any life in it. The resurrection is not a miracle if Jesus didn&#8217;t die. And if his body died, so did all of him. Where there once was a carpenter&#8217;s son named Jesus, there was now a lifeless and thoughtless body.</p>
<p>This is vital if we are to get even the smallest glimpse of God&#8217;s purpose in all of this. (I really don&#8217;t think we can get more than a tiny glimpse of the purpose of the Cross, no matter how long or hard we look at it.) Jesus&#8217;s thoughts ceased. Where there once was a mind, there was now simply a void in space and time, a black hole of nothingness. Do you see this? When Jesus cried out his last on that Good Friday the Temple veil was torn in two from top to bottom. There was another tearing, another rending in two at the same time. Where Jesus once held thoughts in his mind, there was now a parting of the sea of consciousness. A sea of terrible nothingness lay beyond that veil. And that is where God has cast our sin&#8212;into the sea of nothing.</p>
<blockquote><p> I am He who wipes the slate clean and erases your wrongdoing.<br />
I will not call to mind your sins anymore.</p></blockquote>
<p>Where did our sins go if they are beyond the knowing of the omniscient God? How can God wipe clean the slate of our wrongdoing? Isaiah says God will not &#8220;call to mind&#8221; our sins anymore. How can this be? Could it be that in the moment of his death God placed all of our sin&#8212;and his thought of our sin&#8212;into the void of the mind of Jesus? Could it be that in the rending of Jesus&#8217; thoughts our sins&#8212;all of our sins, past, present and future&#8212;were placed forever beyond even the reach of God in that sea of nothing? (This idea was birthed in me from Robert Capon in his book <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0802842224/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0802842224&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=goonewdai-20">Between Noon and Three: Romance, Law, and the Outrage of Grace</a><img style="border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" alt="" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=goonewdai-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0802842224" width="1" height="1" border="0" /></em>. He articulates it much better than I ever could.)</p>
<p>My sin, however, is not just a part of me. You can&#8217;t just lop off sin like scraping off a wart. My sin goes all the way to the very core of my being. If, then, my sin is cast away from God into this sea of nothingness, that means all of me is cast there as well. I and my sin cannot be separated, at least not in this life. It is the wheat and the tares. Rip up one and the other comes up as well. So in choosing not to call to mind our sins any longer, is God saying he is choosing not to hold us? Is he casting us away from his presence forever?</p>
<p>God casts our sins away from his thoughts, yet God holds everything. There is nothing beyond his grip, not even nothingness. Nothing is not beyond him. Thus for all eternity God must hold our sins in the dead mind of Jesus. For ever God will hold me as a sinner, as dead as Jesus on the Cross. God is reconciling all sin in nothingness, nothingness that could only be reached through the everythingness of the Cross. Thus I become nothing, as from before creation. In order to live I must be born again. And this is only accomplished in the resurrection. But for all eternity there is the death of sin in the mind of Christ. And for all eternity there is newness of life. There cannot be one without the other.</p>
<p>And so why did God do this? If he knew we would all sin and fall short of his glory, then it seems the Cross and the resurrection was just a charade for our entertainment. Something to make us feel better about ourselves, to lift our self-esteem out of the dirt. Really? Is that really why Jesus suffered and died? Was the Passion simply God playing a mulligan with us, his creation?</p>
<p>Or was there a deeper reconciliation going on? Is all of creation, every star, every galaxy, every black hole somehow pointing to something we cannot yet see? Is all of human history&#8212;every war, every civilization, every kingdom&#8212;somehow a part of a symphony only God can hear?</p>
<blockquote><p>So <i>let’s get this clear:</i> it’s for My own sake <i>that I save you</i>.</p></blockquote>
<p>Does God owe us, his creation, an explanation? He says he did this for his own sake. I don&#8217;t believe I will ever know why. If I can ever get my arms around God&#8217;s <em>why</em>, then I can be sure it&#8217;s not God.</p>
<p>Sunday will be here soon with candy and dyed eggs and spiral-sliced ham. But let us not rush past Friday with bitter wine and darkness and death. We do not see clearly now what God is reconciling through the Cross, be we can see God in the Cross. He is there. And he has rescued us from nothingness for his sake.</p>
<p>Happy Good Friday.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/the-reconciliation-of-the-cross/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holy Week: Preaching as Good as It Gets</title>
		<link>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-preaching-as-good-as-it-gets</link>
		<comments>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-preaching-as-good-as-it-gets#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 17:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chaplain Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holy Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.internetmonk.com/?p=39935</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nothing could have stopped this Pascal mystery of God and humanity. No amount of super-good discipleship or wisdom or hindsight would make a lick of difference to God’s determination to draw all people to God’s self through Jesus lifted high and on a cross. See, we are no different than the shouting crowds – those [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_39936" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 608px"><a href="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Giotto-Entry-e1364354887291.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-39936 " alt="Entry into Jerusalem (detail), Giotto" src="http://www.internetmonk.com/wp-content/uploads/Giotto-Entry-e1364354887291.jpg" width="598" height="376" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Entry into Jerusalem (detail), Giotto</p></div>
<p>Nothing could have stopped this Pascal mystery of God and humanity. No amount of super-good discipleship or wisdom or hindsight would make a lick of difference to God’s determination to draw all people to God’s self through Jesus lifted high and on a cross.</p>
<p>See, we are no different than the shouting crowds – those that do the right thing for the wrong reason or those who do the wrong thing for the right reason.  There is no better class of improved people.  There are just people.</p>
<p>And as soon as we think the good news is that we know better than those caught up in into the tragic events of that first Holy Week, we are mistaken. As soon as we think the good news is that we now know how to do the right things and for the right reasons we are mistaken.</p>
<p>Because it had to happen like this.   When the Pharisees told Jesus to stop his disciples from such an embarrassing display, he said that were they to stop even the stones would cry out. So there had to be crowds who shout praise  and friends who betrayed and followers who denied and women who wept and soldiers who mocked and thieves who believed. It would have happened like this even if the Jesus event were happening now instead of then.  Even if we knew everything in advance – were we the ones on the street we too would shout Hosanna and a few days later shout crucify him.  And <em>that’s</em> the good news when it comes down to it. Because these people of the Holy Week story are we people.  And we people are the likes of which God came to save. God did not become human and dwell among us as Jesus to save only an improved, doesn’t make the wrong choices kind of people. There is no improved version of humanity that could have done any differently.</p>
<p>So go ahead. Don’t wait until you think your motivations are correct.  Don’t wait till you are sure you believe every single line of the Nicene creed (no one does).  Don’t worry about coming to church this week for the right reasons. Just wave branches. Shout praise for the wrong reason. Eat a meal. Have your feet washed. Grab at coins. Shout Crucify him. Walk away when the cock crows.  Because we, as we are and not as some improved version of ourselves…we are who God came to save. And nothing can stop what’s going to happen.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><a href="http://www.patheos.com/blogs/nadiabolzweber/2013/03/palm-sunday-sermon-about-morbid-reflection-home-perms-and-fickle-crowds/"><strong>Palm Sunday Sermon about Morbid Reflection,<br />
Home Perms, and Fickle Crowds</strong></a><br />
<em>Nadia Bolz-Weber</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.internetmonk.com/archive/holy-week-preaching-as-good-as-it-gets/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic
Page Caching using disk: enhanced

 Served from: www.internetmonk.com @ 2013-04-01 00:03:28 by W3 Total Cache -->
