<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>JoNova</title>
	<atom:link href="http://joannenova.com.au/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://joannenova.com.au</link>
	<description>Tackling tribal groupthink</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 06:10:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Lewandowsky, Prof of Psychology, thinks the Labor Government doesn&#8217;t benefit if he calls their opponents &#8220;stupid&#8221;.</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/lewandowsky-prof-of-psychology-thinks-the-labor-party-doesnt-benefit-if-he-calls-their-opponents-stupid/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/lewandowsky-prof-of-psychology-thinks-the-labor-party-doesnt-benefit-if-he-calls-their-opponents-stupid/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 15:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lewandowsky (Stephan)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Storms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Conversation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=28034</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Stephan Lewandowsky&#8217;s work is a case study in government funded inanity. Some Australians are sure that burning coal will make storms stronger. Others are not convinced. In November 2012 Lewandowsky&#8217;s intellectual contribution to science in Australia was to call the unconvinced &#8220;stupid&#8221;. If that&#8217;s not inane enough, at the same time he claimed that he didn&#8217;t recieve funding from any organisation that would benefit from his article.</p> <p>How many taxpayer dollars went towards funding that? No conflict of interest?</p> <p class="wp-caption-text">Are Australian Research Council funds used as a form of third party advertising for Labor Government policy?</p> <p>Writing in &#8220;A storm of Stupidity, Sandy, Evidence and Climate Change&#8221; on The Conversation, his reasoning is like this: some scientists reckon that a very bad storm called &#8220;Sandy&#8221; has &#8220;links&#8221; to man-made emissions of a trace gas. Lewandowsky reasons that because those scientists are called &#8220;experts&#8221;, anyone who questions them should be called stupid. (He thinks this article and that tweet were overdue). Though, in a twist, apparently he doesn&#8217;t actually think the unconvinced are actually stupid, he thinks they are ethically &#8220;disembodied&#8221; people who &#8220;mislead&#8221;. (As an aside, notice how he approves of news articles that call them stupid even though [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.3" /></div><div>Rating: 9.3/<strong>10</strong> (52 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/lewandowsky-prof-of-psychology-thinks-the-labor-party-doesnt-benefit-if-he-calls-their-opponents-stupid/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>69</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Monster has arrived. Thanks to friends&#8230; : &#8211; )</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/the-monster-has-arrived-thanks-to-friends/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/the-monster-has-arrived-thanks-to-friends/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 15:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Joanne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Site]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Admin]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=28040</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The Monster is in the house. I haven&#8217;t actually laid a finger on it, but I&#8217;ve been introduced.</p> <p>It is currently being fed with special monster baby food &#8212; heavy windows, slow drivers, stuff like that &#8212; it is pacified with shiny plastic discs and drip-fed digits from far-distant lands.</p> <p>At a hundred-billion-tera-flops a gargle-second, it&#8217;s learning fast. A lot seems to be going on.</p> <p>In the meantime, sorry for the silence. I&#8217;ve been working as fast as I could on a tiny coaster-sized array of pixels with unfamiliar software, no mouse, and no ability to load up pictures to my usual storage site, or read my usual emails (except one at a time with 14 keystrokes of complexity and a 20 second wait for the next &#8211; I gave up). I dream of graphs I can&#8217;t make. I reboot the old machine, and sometimes feel normal for a half hour. Then it goes.</p> <p>Space-time is being warped in my head. Things I used to do in five minutes take me all day.</p> <p>Some futurists have waffled on prophesizing about the coming integration of hominid brains and silicon chips, blah-de-blah. I always thought they were bonkers. But I was wrong. [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.1" /></div><div>Rating: 9.1/<strong>10</strong> (67 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/the-monster-has-arrived-thanks-to-friends/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>259</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Global gloom. Help. I need a new computer.</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/global-gloom-help-i-need-a-new-computer/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/global-gloom-help-i-need-a-new-computer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 13:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=28012</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In astrological terms, Jupiter must be passing through my technology zone. Yesterday the web-host was down for 15 hours. Today, my computer collapsed randomly into the blue screen of death. It can be revived, sort of, but the five-year-old-overworked-disc only springs to life for short bursts in between intermittent freezes. It&#8217;s been kind, letting me back up. But it doesn&#8217;t last &#8212; we are now stuck in an infinite degrading loop where it crashes, logs off and restarts, thoroughly error checking the full disc, and an hour later I can do another two minutes work, before the Goto-loop-from-hell starts over. </p> <p>Sorry to all the people who emailed me today, Robert, Horst, Jennifer and Jim I was about to reply&#8230; Tony, Mods, I&#8217;m working from  a lap top&#8230; my brain has shrunk from 2 x 30 inch, to 1 x 15.  Please be patient. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve lost emails, but I can&#8217;t see them right now.</p> <p>Five years! The blog-war-horse is gone. </p> <p>Donations gratefully received. A newer monster with more memory has been ordered&#8230;</p> <p>Right now these self funding academic researcher-analyst-commentators could do with support. Those billion dollar government departments don&#8217;t seem be in a hurry to fund [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.2" /></div><div>Rating: 9.2/<strong>10</strong> (84 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/global-gloom-help-i-need-a-new-computer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>374</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is the media waking up?  Global warming: time to rein back on doom and gloom?</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/is-the-media-waking-up-global-warming-time-to-rein-back-on-doom-and-gloom/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/is-the-media-waking-up-global-warming-time-to-rein-back-on-doom-and-gloom/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 15:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media Coverage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27979</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Tic, tic, tic. The sleeping MSM is stirring. Headlines no one could imagine seeing a few years ago are popping up on a regular basis. The backdown is beginning.</p> <p>For those who have not gone-over-the-falls and chained their reputation to a big-Green-rock, there is time to backtrack. This is a good moment to start mentioning that &#8220;things have changed.&#8221; It&#8217;s five years too late, but that&#8217;s better than being ten-years-too-late, and it still has a tiny bit of kudos for being ahead of stampede that is coming.</p> <p>The term du jour is &#8220;new evidence&#8221;. It&#8217;s the ticket back to reality, even though strong evidence has been there for a decade, and the lack of warming is just one more clue that the models are wrong.</p> <p>As far as I can tell, Geoffrey Lean is one of the commentators who&#8217;s been very much on the side of the global warming drive, but not a zealot. He allowed the odd caveat, he spoke of skeptics, but not of deniers. When the ClimateGate II emails were released, mostly he wrote about how they didn&#8217;t matter, were misrepresented, and the science was settled. Even then, there was a small caveat that &#8220;disturbing questions&#8221; remain, [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.8" /></div><div>Rating: 9.8/<strong>10</strong> (78 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/is-the-media-waking-up-global-warming-time-to-rein-back-on-doom-and-gloom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>252</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rupert Wyndham ponders the wanton hypocrisy of Paul Nurse and The Royal Society</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/rupert-wyndham-takes-on-paul-nurse-and-the-royal-society/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/rupert-wyndham-takes-on-paul-nurse-and-the-royal-society/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 06:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ad Hominem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Royal Society (UK)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wyndham (Rupert)]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27966</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 60px;">Rupert Wyndham is an eloquent treasure. For those who have not already seen this (and I&#8217;ve received many emails about it) &#8212; Enjoy! &#8212; His turn of phrase is something to behold: the damning indictments carefully understated, yet laid bare. That the Royal Society President has been reduced to ad hominem attacks &#8220;&#8230; demonstrates more clearly than anything else the loss of dignity it has endured and depths of corruption to which it has been reduced under your stewardship and those of your two predecessors. &#8220;</p> <p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 60px;">  &#8212; Jo</p> <p class="wp-caption-text">The Royal Society in better days: Boyle, Newton, Franklin, Jenner, Babbage, Wallace, Lister, Rutherford, Hodgkin, Shackleton. (From The stamp collection).</p> <p style="text-align: center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p> <p style="text-align: right;">31 March 2013</p> <p>Sir Paul Nurse, President, The Royal Society</p> <p>6-9 Carlton House Terrace</p> <p>London SW1Y 5AG</p> <p>&#160;</p> <p>Dear Sir Paul Nurse,</p> <p>Your reply to Lord Lawson dated 8 March has come to hand. It goes without saying that I make no claim to be responding on his behalf; he is more than capable of doing that for himself. Your letter, however, is such a singular juxtaposition of barely suppressed personal antipathy (malice even), blatant mendacity and [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.2" /></div><div>Rating: 9.2/<strong>10</strong> (153 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/rupert-wyndham-takes-on-paul-nurse-and-the-royal-society/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>216</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jobs and junkets are on the line. Abbott could axe Flannery and the climate commission</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/jobs-and-junkets-are-on-the-line-abbott-could-axe-flannery-and-the-climate-commission/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/jobs-and-junkets-are-on-the-line-abbott-could-axe-flannery-and-the-climate-commission/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 02:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flannery (Tim)]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27907</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="wp-caption-text">Tim Flannery</p> <p>No wonder Flannery and co. are playing double or nothing. While headlines have shouted for years that vested interests of the fossil fuel players dominate this debate, few journalists point out that the renewables industry, carbon trading markets, and the climate-scary-science-campaign have an all-or-nothing interest in propagating alarm. </p> <p>As I keep saying, those in private business who provide real goods to real voluntary customers will suffer from a carbon tax, but they still have a market. For them it&#8217;s a &#8220;dent&#8221; in profits. We&#8217;ll still be buying coal, oil and gas for decades to come. In contrast, those who make a living from government funds could lose everything in an instant. Their wealth and status depends on a forced payment and a decision from one Minister. It is far more ephemeral and subject to whim. The state-dependents are far more desperate. The stakes are higher.</p> <p>Gillard calls the &#8220;climate commission&#8221; an independent body, which is only true in the same sense that any parasite can be described as &#8220;independent&#8221; of the host while being completely dependent on it.</p> <p>This shows just how independent and apolitical the Climate Commission reality is:</p> <p> The Australian &#8220;Abbott says Tim Flannery&#8217;s job [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.2" /></div><div>Rating: 9.2/<strong>10</strong> (134 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/jobs-and-junkets-are-on-the-line-abbott-could-axe-flannery-and-the-climate-commission/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>283</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mafia caught laundering $1.7b through &#8220;renewables&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/mafia-caught-laundering-1-7b-through-renewables/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/mafia-caught-laundering-1-7b-through-renewables/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27952</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Real markets have real customers, who notice when things don&#8217;t add up. Fake markets are an invitation to criminals.</p> <p>The state forced payments from citizens for the wrong reasons, to solve a non-problem with the wrong method.</p> <p>In this case, state organized crime meets independent organized crime.</p> Mafia probe nets $1.7bn in clean energy assets <p>Italian police have seized assets worth 1.3 billion euros ($1.7 billion) from a Sicilian renewable energy developer in the biggest ever seizure of mafia-linked assets.</p> <p>The assets, including 43 wind and solar energy companies, 98 properties and 66 bank accounts, belonged to Vito Nicastri, a 57-year-old businessman dubbed the &#8220;Lord of the Wind&#8221; for his prominent role in the business.</p> <p>&#8220;This is a sector in which money can easily be laundered,&#8221; Arturo de Felice, head of Italy&#8217;s anti-mafia agency, told local media.</p> <p>&#8220;Operating in a grey area helped him build up his business over the years.&#8221;</p> <p>The anti-mafia agency in a statement said it was the biggest seizure of mafia-linked assets.</p> <p>This was not a free market, but a free-for-all.</p> <p>Italy&#8217;s renewable energy sector has been heavily infiltrated by the mafia because of once-generous state subsidies and lax controls, as well as the availability of [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.6" /></div><div>Rating: 9.6/<strong>10</strong> (92 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/mafia-caught-laundering-1-7b-through-renewables/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>IPCC plays hot-spot hidey games in AR5 &#8212; denies 28 million weather balloons work properly</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/ipcc-plays-hot-spot-hidey-games-in-ar5-denies-28-million-weather-balloons-work-properly/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/ipcc-plays-hot-spot-hidey-games-in-ar5-denies-28-million-weather-balloons-work-properly/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 02:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5AR (Fifth Assessment Rep)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hot Spot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPCC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Missing Hot Spot]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=26016</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="wp-caption-text">The classic hot spot prediction (A) compared to 28 million weatherballoons (B). Click to enlarge. You won&#8217;t see this in the new report.</p> <p>It was a major PR failure in 2007. The IPCC won&#8217;t make the same mistake again. They&#8217;ve dumped the hot-spot graphs. </p> <p>In AR4 they put in two graphs that show how badly their models really do. In the next report they plan to bury the spectacular missing-hot-spot images through &#8220;graph-trickery&#8221; and selective blindness. Each round of IPCC reports takes the spin-factor up another notch. It&#8217;s carefully crafted.</p> <p>See the draft of AR5: Chapter 9: Evaluation of Climate Models</p> <p>It&#8217;s hot-spot hidey games and PR tricks</p> <p>In the new extra-tricky AR5 version, the IPCC &#8220;quote the critics&#8221; and ignore them at the same time. That way they can say they include the McIntyre&#8217;s, McKitrick&#8217;s, Douglass&#8217;, and Christy&#8217;s: the words are on the page, but that doesn&#8217;t mean the information is used in the conclusions. The models have failed and they bury that undeniable result under the clutter.  (You&#8217;ll need to read the fine print). There is no acknowledgement that this issue of the &#8220;hot spot&#8221; drives more amplification of predicted warming in their models than any [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.1" /></div><div>Rating: 9.1/<strong>10</strong> (82 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/04/ipcc-plays-hot-spot-hidey-games-in-ar5-denies-28-million-weather-balloons-work-properly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>181</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Radi-Aid: Africa helps freezing children in Norway</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/radi-aid-africa-helps-freezing-children-in-norway-d/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/radi-aid-africa-helps-freezing-children-in-norway-d/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 04:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satire & Parody]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27802</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This is the Easter Spirit!</p> <p>Gotta love it. h/t Eric W</p> Rating: 9.3/10 (70 votes cast)<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.3" /></div><div>Rating: 9.3/<strong>10</strong> (70 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/radi-aid-africa-helps-freezing-children-in-norway-d/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>123</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lewandowsky, Cook claim 78,000 skeptics could see conspiracy survey at Cooks site where there is no link</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/lewandowsky-cook-claim-78000-skeptics-could-see-conspiracy-survey-at-cooks-site-where-he-didnt-even-put-up-a-link/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/lewandowsky-cook-claim-78000-skeptics-could-see-conspiracy-survey-at-cooks-site-where-he-didnt-even-put-up-a-link/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 06:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conspiracy Theorist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cook (John)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lewandowsky (Stephan)]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27883</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The MoonLanding paper is finally here. Eight months after Lewandowsky was so sure he had a &#8220;peer reviewed&#8221; conclusion that he announced his results in The Guardian and The Telegraph , the paper has finally been published.</p> <p>Lewandowsky et al claimed to show skeptics are nutters who believe any rabid conspiracy like the &#8220;moon-landing was faked&#8221;.  Their novel method for discovering the views of skeptics involved surveying sites frequented by those who hate skeptics.</p> <p>The survey questions included conspiracies likely to appeal to a small percentage of conservative or free market thinkers, and largely left out conspiracies that would appeal more to supporters of bigger government (like the idea that the rise of &#8220;climate denial&#8221; was a big-oil funded conspiracy). It studied big-government conspiracies and ignored big-corporate ones. There are gullible conspiracists who also believe in global warming, but there was no danger this survey would find them. The survey bias was so obvious, even alarmist commenters said they feared few &#8220;denialists&#8221; would take it. The results that were headlined in newspapers were based on a tiny sample of ten respondents to an anonymous online survey. Not surprisingly Lewandowsky&#8217;s university (UWA) received many complaints about ethics, methods, and the dismal quality [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.3" /></div><div>Rating: 9.3/<strong>10</strong> (157 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/lewandowsky-cook-claim-78000-skeptics-could-see-conspiracy-survey-at-cooks-site-where-he-didnt-even-put-up-a-link/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>164</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using disk: basic
Database Caching using disk: basic
Object Caching 673/678 objects using disk: basic

Served from: joannenova.com.au @ 2013-04-15 22:14:55 -->