<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>JoNova</title>
	<atom:link href="http://joannenova.com.au/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://joannenova.com.au</link>
	<description>Tackling tribal groupthink</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 13:56:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Labor downgrades &#8220;climate&#8221;. Makes Emerson minister of nearly everything</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/labor-downgrades-climate-makes-emerson-minister-of-nearly-everything/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/labor-downgrades-climate-makes-emerson-minister-of-nearly-everything/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 13:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australian Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27820</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="wp-caption-text">Dr Craig Emerson, Minister for Science, Weather, Inventions, Factories and Universities.</p> <p>After the leadership farce last week and the resignations of the more-sensible Labor ministers, Gillard has reshuffled again and the DCC (Department of Climate Change) is disappearing into a &#8220;super ministry&#8221;. It is a sign of the times.</p> <p>The P.M. has bundled the Department of Climate Change into a nightmare acronynm:</p> <p>The Prime Minister used her sixth ministerial reshuffle to merge the Department of Climate Change with the Department of Industry, creating a new Department of Industry, Innovation, Climate Change, Science, Research and Tertiary Education.</p> <p>Is that DIICCSRTE? </p> <p>Gillard appointed the former Woodside director, Gary Gray, to cabinet as mines and energy minister. The Climate Spectator is worried. Gray said something skeptical once in 1993: that the evidence linking human activity to climate change was ‘‘pop science&#8221;. Years later he apparently said he regretted the comments, but this was not enough to convince the religious that he has discovered the faith.  He made the mistake of saying there needed to be &#8220;intellectual challenge and debate&#8221;. These plain and sane words marked him as a confirmed skeptic. Only skeptics want debates. A true believer prefers not to mention [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=10.0" /></div><div>Rating: 10.0/<strong>10</strong> (12 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/labor-downgrades-climate-makes-emerson-minister-of-nearly-everything/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apollo 11 engines found and recovered from 4km deep</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/apollo-11-engines-found-and-recovered-from-4km-deep/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/apollo-11-engines-found-and-recovered-from-4km-deep/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 07:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27786</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160;</p> <p class="wp-caption-text">&#8230;</p> <p>Hey, Moon Landing Deniers&#8230; here&#8217;s an interesting tid-bit and an epic project. The historic engines that propelled Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin on their trip to the moon (with Michael Collins orbiting above them) have not only been found but recovered. These F-1 engines fell back to Earth at 5,000 miles per hour and sank four kilometers underwater in the Atlantic. (The Apollo 11 crew splashed down later in the Pacific on July 24, 1969.)</p> <p>It was not immediately clear when or where the objects might be displayed, but Mr Bezos said when he launched the project last year that he hoped they could be viewed at the Smithsonian&#8217;s National Air and Space Museum in Washington.</p> <p>The engines that rocketed astronaut Neil Armstrong and his crew toward the moon in 1969 were located deep in the Atlantic Ocean using sophisticated sonar equipment.</p> <p>These were recovered with private money.</p> <p>Mr Bezos used private funds to raise the F-1 engines from their resting places 4,267 metres below the surface of the ocean, even though he has maintained that they remain the property of NASA.</p> <p>NASA Administrator Charles Bolden welcomed the news.</p> <p>&#8220;This is a historic find and I congratulate [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.0" /></div><div>Rating: 9.0/<strong>10</strong> (46 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/apollo-11-engines-found-and-recovered-from-4km-deep/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>256</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What happened to &#8220;Earth Hour&#8221;? Celebrate: It&#8217;s the &#8220;Power Hour&#8221; tonight!</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/what-happened-to-earth-hour-celebrate-its-the-power-hour-tonight/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/what-happened-to-earth-hour-celebrate-its-the-power-hour-tonight/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 05:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earth Hour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27764</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="wp-caption-text">&#8230;</p> <p style="text-align: center;">Turn on your lights from 8.30pm-9.30!</p> <p>Remember all the fuss? What happened to Earth Hour 2013?</p> <p>It&#8217;s that time-of-year for the hour of Green Darkness. But how times have changed.  On Their-ABC, the only mention I can find is this: &#8220;Is Earth Hour dead?&#8220;  The Age and The SMH pay lip-service to Earth Hour with an article in today. But there is nothing like the hype of previous years. The Guardian puts on the best spin, but concede Lomborg might be right. Even the Huff Po is telling us it&#8217;s a waste of time.</p> <p>It appears Lomborg took the fun out of it by pointing out that Earth Hour was a waste-of-time token that produced more emissions than it saved.</p> <p>Earth Hour teaches us that tackling global warming is easy,&#8221; Lomborg writes at Slate. &#8220;Yet, by switching off the lights, all we are doing is making it harder to see.&#8221;</p> <p>How so? Well, for starters, Lomborg argues that more than a billion impoverished people around the world have no switch to flip, lacking the electricity that we take for granted. Earth Hour, he implies, demonizes a technology that has lifted great swaths of humanity from lives of [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.3" /></div><div>Rating: 9.3/<strong>10</strong> (101 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/what-happened-to-earth-hour-celebrate-its-the-power-hour-tonight/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>200</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>IPCC Lead Author calls Lewandowsky &#8220;deluded&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/ipcc-lead-author-calls-lewandowsky-deluded/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/ipcc-lead-author-calls-lewandowsky-deluded/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 07:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cook (John)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lewandowsky (Stephan)]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27768</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>People across the UK are rolling in the aisles in laughter.</p> <p>Lewandowsky&#8217;s latest paper, &#8220;Recursive Fury&#8221; (which has just reappeared),  categorized a comment by Richard Betts under the heading &#8220;Excerpt Espousing Conspiracy Theory&#8221; (in the supplemental data). But instead of being a comment from a rabid tin-foil-hat skeptic, Betts turns out to be Head of Climate Impacts at the UK Met Office and an IPCC lead author.</p> <p>When Betts was informed about this by Barry Woods, he tweeted &#8220;Lewandowsky et al clearly deluded!&#8221;</p> <p>Here&#8217;s the comment by Betts that Lewandowsky et al think demonstrates conspiracist ideation. Betts is pointing out how easily the authors of the original paper (claiming that skeptics-believe-the-moon-landing-was-faked) could have posted their survey link in places where skeptics were actually likely to see it. The Moon landing paper &#8212; after all &#8212; claimed to analyze skeptics but ended up getting results only from sites that were virulently anti-skeptic.</p> <p>Richard Betts: &#8220;The thing I don’t understand is, why didn’t they just make a post on sceptic blogs themselves, rather than approaching blog owners. They could have posted as a Discussion topic here at Bishop Hill without even asking the host, and I very much doubt that the Bish [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.0" /></div><div>Rating: 9.0/<strong>10</strong> (76 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/ipcc-lead-author-calls-lewandowsky-deluded/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>117</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who will be Australia&#8217;s PM tomorrow? (Answer &#8211; Gillard)</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/who-will-be-australias-pm-tomorrow/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/who-will-be-australias-pm-tomorrow/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 04:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australian Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27683</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>UPDATE: Rudd refused to contend. Gillard and Swan &#8220;won&#8221; uncontested. (The ALP loses.) QLD State Liberal Premier Newman calls for a federal election. &#8220;&#8216;The country cannot afford the waste of time; the paralysis we&#8217;ve seen.&#8217;&#8221; &#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212; It&#8217;s on. Finally.</p> Leadership ballot called for Labor Party at 4.30pm today. <p>[Skynews] The Prime Minister Julia Gillard has called a caucus meeting for 4.30pm (AEDT) to allow a ballot for the leadership of the Labor Party to be held.</p> <p>Ms Gillard made the announcement at the start of question time in the lower house on Thursday &#8211; the last parliamentary sitting day before the May 14 budget.</p> <p>&#8216;For the information of the house, I have determined there will be a ballot for the leadership and the deputy leadership of the Labor party at 4.30pm today.</p> <p>&#8230; Question Time has begun and Mr Abbott has called for a motion of no confidence in the Prime Minister.Mr Abbott then called for a suspension of standing orders in parliament to debate a motion of no confidence in Ms Gillard.</p> <p>&#8216;(This is) an incompetent and chaotic government which just gets worse and worse with each passing day, let alone each passing day,&#8217; he said.</p> <p>At one stage, [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.2" /></div><div>Rating: 9.2/<strong>10</strong> (30 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/who-will-be-australias-pm-tomorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>166</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Andy Hoffman admits they&#8217;re losing:  Fighting skeptics is like fighting slave traders</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/andy-hoffman-admits-theyre-losing-fighting-skeptics-is-like-fighting-slave-traders/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/andy-hoffman-admits-theyre-losing-fighting-skeptics-is-like-fighting-slave-traders/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 19:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27743</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Andy Hoffman has flown from Michigan to deliver the pop science solution to our atmospheric catastrophe.</p> <p>You may have thought it was about planetary radiation, or moist adiabatic lapse rates, but Hoffman is here to save you from the waste-of-time science debate. Discussing science with &#8220;climate deniers&#8221;  is like &#8220;talking to a wall&#8221; he says. We agree &#8212; anyone who denies we have a climate is thick-as-a-brick. Have you ever met one? No, neither have I. The mythical climate denier seems to be causing global warming through their inaction, but no one as yet, can name a single person who denies the climate.</p> <p>I&#8217;m sure Hoffman wouldn&#8217;t want to be loose and inaccurate with his words &#8212; so no doubt he will find an actual &#8220;climate denier&#8221; or start to speak English instead.</p> <p>Perhaps the debate he says he wants, will start when we speak the same language?</p> <p>It&#8217;s obvious the Great Global Warming Scare is unravelling when the losing team turn into sour-puss-psychologists &#8212; finding dark mental failings in those too stupid to understand their Gift with The Weather.</p> When it comes to pop-psychology anyone can play&#8230; <p>Hoffman thinks skeptics aren&#8217;t convinced because they are afraid:</p> <p>MANY climate sceptics [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.6" /></div><div>Rating: 9.6/<strong>10</strong> (75 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/andy-hoffman-admits-theyre-losing-fighting-skeptics-is-like-fighting-slave-traders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>183</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>FOIA, Government-Funded Climate Science and Hole-Digging</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/foia-government-funded-climate-science-and-hole-digging/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/foia-government-funded-climate-science-and-hole-digging/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 12:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JoNova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FOIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marohasy (Jennifer)]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27635</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p style="padding-left: 60px;">Here&#8217;s  a benefit FOIA probably didn&#8217;t imagine. Skeptical networks. For anyone who doesn&#8217;t know, Jennifer Marohasy has published one of the longest-running skeptical blogs in the world, and she&#8217;s one of the few other women on the front lines. I don&#8217;t know why we hadn&#8217;t spent a long time on the phone before. I&#8217;m delighted that we are in much better contact&#8230;</p> <p style="text-align: center;">&#8211; Jo</p> <p style="text-align: center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p> Guest Post By Jennifer Marohasy <p></p> <p style="text-align: left;">FOIA is a recognised shorthand for Freedom of Information Act.  Legislation by this name has existed in the USA since 1966, Australia since 1982 and the UK legislation was introduced in 2000.  It was climate scientists at the Climatic Research Unit, University of East Anglia, conspiring to evade the UK FOIA that probably inspired Climategate, with Mr FOIA, as the “hacker” calls himself, releasing over 220,000 documents and emails beginning in November 2009.  In a recent email he explained: “The circus was about to arrive in Copenhagen.  Later on it could be too late.”</p> <p>By providing public access to emails and documents from leading climate scientists, Mr FOIA exposed how tricks, adjustments, and corrections, were routinely applied to climate data to [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=8.9" /></div><div>Rating: 8.9/<strong>10</strong> (102 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/foia-government-funded-climate-science-and-hole-digging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>129</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Cyprus Moment: Steal money from ex-KGB deposits? Hello, Crunch-time.</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/the-cyprus-moment-steal-money-from-ex-kgb-deposits-welcome-to-the-new-economy/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/the-cyprus-moment-steal-money-from-ex-kgb-deposits-welcome-to-the-new-economy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 09:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiat Currency]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27708</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p style="padding-left: 30px;">UPDATE: Cash is being flown to British Troops in Cyprus. The banks will stay shut til Thursday. The finance minister has resigned. [SkyNews]</p> <p>Remember how the EU was supposed to promote stability?</p> <p>Sooner or later a central fund managed by central bureaucrats is going to fail in a &#8220;central&#8221; way. This isn&#8217;t it, but we are getting closer to the center.</p> <p></p> <p>Without competition between states on currency, Europe left itself open to be a case study in centralized stupidity. The bureaucrats needed to stop the waste of public spending, they needed to halt the corruption, increase competition. And their answer? Steal 10% of depositor&#8217;s funds from everyone in Cyprus. It seemed like a good idea at the time.</p> <p>We are now in new territory. In previous bank bailouts, if anyone took any losses it was the shareholders and the bond holders, and the depositors did not lose any money. In the Cyprus bail out, the bondholders and shareholders lose nothing but the depositors lose about 10%. (Any chance the bondholders of the Cyprus banks include the ECB or IMF?)</p> <p>Where is the natural law that makes sense in this decision? Don&#8217;t punish the shareholders, or the bondholders, [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.6" /></div><div>Rating: 9.6/<strong>10</strong> (54 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/the-cyprus-moment-steal-money-from-ex-kgb-deposits-welcome-to-the-new-economy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>67</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ocean plankton suck up twice the carbon we thought they did</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/ocean-plankton-suck-up-twice-the-carbon-we-thought-they-did/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/ocean-plankton-suck-up-twice-the-carbon-we-thought-they-did/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 17:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carbon cycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oceans]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27690</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="wp-caption-text">Hyperia &#124; Credit Wikimedia</p> <p>Despite the fuss about CO2 emissions, on a global scale no one is quite sure where a lot of it ends up. Those mystery &#8220;sinks&#8221; draw in a large proportion of CO2. Here&#8217;s a big sink that just got twice as big.</p> <p style="padding-left: 30px;">Science Daily  Mar. 17, 2013 — Models of carbon dioxide in the world&#8217;s oceans need to be revised, according to new work by UC Irvine and other scientists published online Sunday in Nature Geoscience. Trillions of plankton near the surface of warm waters are far more carbon-rich than has long been thought, they found. Global marine temperature fluctuations could mean that tiny Prochlorococcus and other microbes digest double the carbon previously calculated.</p> <p>The trouble started when someone made an assumption. </p> <p style="padding-left: 30px;">In making their findings, the researchers have upended a decades-old core principle of marine science known as the Redfield ratio, named for famed oceanographer Alfred Redfield. He concluded in 1934 that from the top of the world&#8217;s oceans to their cool, dark depths, both plankton and the materials they excrete contain the same ratio (106:16:1) of carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus.</p> <p style="padding-left: 30px;">But as any gardener who has [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=8.8" /></div><div>Rating: 8.8/<strong>10</strong> (51 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/ocean-plankton-suck-up-twice-the-carbon-we-thought-they-did/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>78</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Most of Earth covered with life powered on hydrogen. Living Rocks?</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/most-of-earth-covered-with-life-powered-with-hydrogen-living-rocks/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/most-of-earth-covered-with-life-powered-with-hydrogen-living-rocks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 17:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microbiology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27673</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>File this under: What don&#8217;t we know?</p> <p class="wp-caption-text">We just discovered slice &#8220;2&#8243; is alive.  &#124;1 &#8211; Continental crust &#124; 2 -Oceanic crust &#124; 3 &#8211; Upper Mantle &#124; 4 &#8211; Lower Mantle &#124; 5 &#8211; Outer Core &#124; 6 &#8211; Inner Core &#124; Image Credit: Dake</p> <p>You might have thought that photosynthetic life forms had the Earth covered, but according to some researchers the largest ecosystem on Earth was just discovered and announced last Thursday, and it&#8217;s powered by hydrogen, not photosynthesis.</p> <p>The Oceanic Crust is the rocky hard part under the mud that lies under the ocean. It covers 60% of the planet and it&#8217;s 10km thick. (The oceans themselves are a paltry 4km deep on average.) We&#8217;ve known for years that the isolated hot springs in trenches held life. But who thought that all the hundreds of thousands of square kilometers of basalt rock in between had its own life cycle? Last week a group from the Center for Geomicrobiology at Aarhus University, Denmark announced that they had drilled through crust that was 2.5km underwater and 55 km away from anything that mattered. They found life in the basalt.</p> <p>&#8220;We&#8217;re providing the first direct evidence of life [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.0" /></div><div>Rating: 9.0/<strong>10</strong> (38 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/most-of-earth-covered-with-life-powered-with-hydrogen-living-rocks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>49</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using disk: basic
Database Caching using disk: basic
Object Caching 659/670 objects using disk: basic

Served from: joannenova.com.au @ 2013-03-26 02:04:54 -->