<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>JoNova</title>
	<atom:link href="http://joannenova.com.au/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://joannenova.com.au</link>
	<description>Tackling tribal groupthink</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 07:27:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Who will be Australia&#8217;s PM tomorrow? (Answer &#8211; Gillard)</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/who-will-be-australias-pm-tomorrow/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/who-will-be-australias-pm-tomorrow/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 04:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australian Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27683</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>UPDATE: Rudd refused to contend. Gillard and Swan &#8220;won&#8221; uncontested. (The ALP loses.) QLD State Liberal Premier Newman calls for a federal election. &#8220;&#8216;The country cannot afford the waste of time; the paralysis we&#8217;ve seen.&#8217;&#8221; &#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212; It&#8217;s on. Finally.</p> Leadership ballot called for Labor Party at 4.30pm today. <p>[Skynews] The Prime Minister Julia Gillard has called a caucus meeting for 4.30pm (AEDT) to allow a ballot for the leadership of the Labor Party to be held.</p> <p>Ms Gillard made the announcement at the start of question time in the lower house on Thursday &#8211; the last parliamentary sitting day before the May 14 budget.</p> <p>&#8216;For the information of the house, I have determined there will be a ballot for the leadership and the deputy leadership of the Labor party at 4.30pm today.</p> <p>&#8230; Question Time has begun and Mr Abbott has called for a motion of no confidence in the Prime Minister.Mr Abbott then called for a suspension of standing orders in parliament to debate a motion of no confidence in Ms Gillard.</p> <p>&#8216;(This is) an incompetent and chaotic government which just gets worse and worse with each passing day, let alone each passing day,&#8217; he said.</p> <p>At one stage, [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.5" /></div><div>Rating: 9.5/<strong>10</strong> (17 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/who-will-be-australias-pm-tomorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>118</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Andy Hoffman admits they&#8217;re losing:  Fighting skeptics is like fighting slave traders</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/andy-hoffman-admits-theyre-losing-fighting-skeptics-is-like-fighting-slave-traders/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/andy-hoffman-admits-theyre-losing-fighting-skeptics-is-like-fighting-slave-traders/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 19:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27743</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Andy Hoffman has flown from Michigan to deliver the pop science solution to our atmospheric catastrophe.</p> <p>You may have thought it was about planetary radiation, or moist adiabatic lapse rates, but Hoffman is here to save you from the waste-of-time science debate. Discussing science with &#8220;climate deniers&#8221;  is like &#8220;talking to a wall&#8221; he says. We agree &#8212; anyone who denies we have a climate is thick-as-a-brick. Have you ever met one? No, neither have I. The mythical climate denier seems to be causing global warming through their inaction, but no one as yet, can name a single person who denies the climate.</p> <p>I&#8217;m sure Hoffman wouldn&#8217;t want to be loose and inaccurate with his words &#8212; so no doubt he will find an actual &#8220;climate denier&#8221; or start to speak English instead.</p> <p>Perhaps the debate he says he wants, will start when we speak the same language?</p> <p>It&#8217;s obvious the Great Global Warming Scare is unravelling when the losing team turn into sour-puss-psychologists &#8212; finding dark mental failings in those too stupid to understand their Gift with The Weather.</p> When it comes to pop-psychology anyone can play&#8230; <p>Hoffman thinks skeptics aren&#8217;t convinced because they are afraid:</p> <p>MANY climate sceptics [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.7" /></div><div>Rating: 9.7/<strong>10</strong> (64 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/andy-hoffman-admits-theyre-losing-fighting-skeptics-is-like-fighting-slave-traders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>150</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>FOIA, Government-Funded Climate Science and Hole-Digging</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/foia-government-funded-climate-science-and-hole-digging/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/foia-government-funded-climate-science-and-hole-digging/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 12:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JoNova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FOIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marohasy (Jennifer)]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27635</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p style="padding-left: 60px;">Here&#8217;s  a benefit FOIA probably didn&#8217;t imagine. Skeptical networks. For anyone who doesn&#8217;t know, Jennifer Marohasy has published one of the longest-running skeptical blogs in the world, and she&#8217;s one of the few other women on the front lines. I don&#8217;t know why we hadn&#8217;t spent a long time on the phone before. I&#8217;m delighted that we are in much better contact&#8230;</p> <p style="text-align: center;">&#8211; Jo</p> <p style="text-align: center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p> Guest Post By Jennifer Marohasy <p></p> <p style="text-align: left;">FOIA is a recognised shorthand for Freedom of Information Act.  Legislation by this name has existed in the USA since 1966, Australia since 1982 and the UK legislation was introduced in 2000.  It was climate scientists at the Climatic Research Unit, University of East Anglia, conspiring to evade the UK FOIA that probably inspired Climategate, with Mr FOIA, as the “hacker” calls himself, releasing over 220,000 documents and emails beginning in November 2009.  In a recent email he explained: “The circus was about to arrive in Copenhagen.  Later on it could be too late.”</p> <p>By providing public access to emails and documents from leading climate scientists, Mr FOIA exposed how tricks, adjustments, and corrections, were routinely applied to climate data to [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=8.9" /></div><div>Rating: 8.9/<strong>10</strong> (98 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/foia-government-funded-climate-science-and-hole-digging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>126</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Cyprus Moment: Steal money from ex-KGB deposits? Hello, Crunch-time.</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/the-cyprus-moment-steal-money-from-ex-kgb-deposits-welcome-to-the-new-economy/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/the-cyprus-moment-steal-money-from-ex-kgb-deposits-welcome-to-the-new-economy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 09:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiat Currency]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27708</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p style="padding-left: 30px;">UPDATE: Cash is being flown to British Troops in Cyprus. The banks will stay shut til Thursday. The finance minister has resigned. [SkyNews]</p> <p>Remember how the EU was supposed to promote stability?</p> <p>Sooner or later a central fund managed by central bureaucrats is going to fail in a &#8220;central&#8221; way. This isn&#8217;t it, but we are getting closer to the center.</p> <p></p> <p>Without competition between states on currency, Europe left itself open to be a case study in centralized stupidity. The bureaucrats needed to stop the waste of public spending, they needed to halt the corruption, increase competition. And their answer? Steal 10% of depositor&#8217;s funds from everyone in Cyprus. It seemed like a good idea at the time.</p> <p>We are now in new territory. In previous bank bailouts, if anyone took any losses it was the shareholders and the bond holders, and the depositors did not lose any money. In the Cyprus bail out, the bondholders and shareholders lose nothing but the depositors lose about 10%. (Any chance the bondholders of the Cyprus banks include the ECB or IMF?)</p> <p>Where is the natural law that makes sense in this decision? Don&#8217;t punish the shareholders, or the bondholders, [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.5" /></div><div>Rating: 9.5/<strong>10</strong> (49 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/the-cyprus-moment-steal-money-from-ex-kgb-deposits-welcome-to-the-new-economy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ocean plankton suck up twice the carbon we thought they did</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/ocean-plankton-suck-up-twice-the-carbon-we-thought-they-did/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/ocean-plankton-suck-up-twice-the-carbon-we-thought-they-did/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 17:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carbon cycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oceans]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27690</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="wp-caption-text">Hyperia &#124; Credit Wikimedia</p> <p>Despite the fuss about CO2 emissions, on a global scale no one is quite sure where a lot of it ends up. Those mystery &#8220;sinks&#8221; draw in a large proportion of CO2. Here&#8217;s a big sink that just got twice as big.</p> <p style="padding-left: 30px;">Science Daily  Mar. 17, 2013 — Models of carbon dioxide in the world&#8217;s oceans need to be revised, according to new work by UC Irvine and other scientists published online Sunday in Nature Geoscience. Trillions of plankton near the surface of warm waters are far more carbon-rich than has long been thought, they found. Global marine temperature fluctuations could mean that tiny Prochlorococcus and other microbes digest double the carbon previously calculated.</p> <p>The trouble started when someone made an assumption. </p> <p style="padding-left: 30px;">In making their findings, the researchers have upended a decades-old core principle of marine science known as the Redfield ratio, named for famed oceanographer Alfred Redfield. He concluded in 1934 that from the top of the world&#8217;s oceans to their cool, dark depths, both plankton and the materials they excrete contain the same ratio (106:16:1) of carbon, nitrogen and phosphorus.</p> <p style="padding-left: 30px;">But as any gardener who has [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=8.8" /></div><div>Rating: 8.8/<strong>10</strong> (51 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/ocean-plankton-suck-up-twice-the-carbon-we-thought-they-did/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>78</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Most of Earth covered with life powered on hydrogen. Living Rocks?</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/most-of-earth-covered-with-life-powered-with-hydrogen-living-rocks/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/most-of-earth-covered-with-life-powered-with-hydrogen-living-rocks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 17:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microbiology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27673</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>File this under: What don&#8217;t we know?</p> <p class="wp-caption-text">We just discovered slice &#8220;2&#8243; is alive.  &#124;1 &#8211; Continental crust &#124; 2 -Oceanic crust &#124; 3 &#8211; Upper Mantle &#124; 4 &#8211; Lower Mantle &#124; 5 &#8211; Outer Core &#124; 6 &#8211; Inner Core &#124; Image Credit: Dake</p> <p>You might have thought that photosynthetic life forms had the Earth covered, but according to some researchers the largest ecosystem on Earth was just discovered and announced last Thursday, and it&#8217;s powered by hydrogen, not photosynthesis.</p> <p>The Oceanic Crust is the rocky hard part under the mud that lies under the ocean. It covers 60% of the planet and it&#8217;s 10km thick. (The oceans themselves are a paltry 4km deep on average.) We&#8217;ve known for years that the isolated hot springs in trenches held life. But who thought that all the hundreds of thousands of square kilometers of basalt rock in between had its own life cycle? Last week a group from the Center for Geomicrobiology at Aarhus University, Denmark announced that they had drilled through crust that was 2.5km underwater and 55 km away from anything that mattered. They found life in the basalt.</p> <p>&#8220;We&#8217;re providing the first direct evidence of life [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.0" /></div><div>Rating: 9.0/<strong>10</strong> (36 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/most-of-earth-covered-with-life-powered-with-hydrogen-living-rocks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>49</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hottest summer record in Australia? Not so, says UAH satellite data</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/hottest-summer-record-in-australia-not-even-close-says-uah-satellite-data/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/hottest-summer-record-in-australia-not-even-close-says-uah-satellite-data/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 13:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australian temperatures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BOM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stewart (Ken)]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27633</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>There are probably only ten people in Australia who haven&#8217;t heard it was the Hottest Ever, Record Summer Downunder. And they were probably born yesterday.</p> <p>Summer here was so scorchingly awful it was Angry. But a funny thing happened on the orbit overhead. Check out the UAH satellite data on summers since the UAH records began.  The graph below (thanks to Ken) is the temperature data from the NASA satellites, processed by UAH (University of Alabama in Huntsville). Strangely there is a disparity between what the satellites recorded and the BOM.</p> <p>The satellite data shows that the summer of 2012-2013 was close to ordinary, compared with the entire satellite record going back to 1979. Not a record. Not even extreme?</p> <p class="wp-caption-text">According to UAH satellite measurements summer in early 2013 was not a record. Not even close.</p> <p>The graph data comes thanks to John Christy, Director, Earth System Science Center, Distinguished Professor, Atmospheric Science University of Alabama in Huntsville, Alabama State Climatologist and Roy Spencer. It was graphed by Ken Stewart at KensKingdom, and inspired by Tom Quirk at Quadrant. I was very happy to connect them this weekend. The data cover &#8220;average lower troposphere temperature anomalies for land grids [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.1" /></div><div>Rating: 9.1/<strong>10</strong> (71 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/hottest-summer-record-in-australia-not-even-close-says-uah-satellite-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>154</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unthreaded Weekend</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/unthreaded-weekend-9/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/unthreaded-weekend-9/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 15:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27555</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Who knows what might have turned up&#8230;</p> Rating: 7.7/10 (24 votes cast)<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=7.7" /></div><div>Rating: 7.7/<strong>10</strong> (24 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/unthreaded-weekend-9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>171</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Marcott Hockey-stick: smoothing the past and getting a spike from almost no data?</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/the-marcott-hockey-stick-blurring-the-past-by-smoothing-proxies-getting-a-spike-from-almost-no-data/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/the-marcott-hockey-stick-blurring-the-past-by-smoothing-proxies-getting-a-spike-from-almost-no-data/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 15:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hockey Stick Graph]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holocene]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marcott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paleohistory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27515</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The message to the world is unequivocal:</p> <p>“We are heading for somewhere that is far off from anything we have seen in the past 10,000 years – it’s through the roof. In my mind, we are heading for a different planet to the one that we have been used to,” said Jeremy Shakun of Harvard University, a co-author of the study.</p> <p>Source: The-world-is-hottest-it-has-been-since-the-end-of-the-ice-age–and-the-temperatures-still-rising.</p> <p>There are two factors in the new Marcott paper that are major red flags. For one, there is hardly any data in the modern end of the graph. Ponder how researchers can find 5,000 year old Foraminifera deposits, but not ones from 1940? Two: they&#8217;ve smoothed the heck out of longer periods. Marcott et al clearly say there is &#8220;&#8230;essentially no variability preserved at periods shorter than 300 years&#8230;&#8221; So if there were, say, occurrences of a warming rise exactly like the last century, this graph won&#8217;t show them.</p> <p>Some of the data has a resolution as poor as &#8220;500 years&#8221; and the median is 120 years. If current temperatures were averaged over 120 years (that would be 1890 to now), the last alarming spike would blend right in with the other data. Where would the average [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=9.3" /></div><div>Rating: 9.3/<strong>10</strong> (74 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/the-marcott-hockey-stick-blurring-the-past-by-smoothing-proxies-getting-a-spike-from-almost-no-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>178</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>ClimateGate III &#8212; the password is out</title>
		<link>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/climategate-iii-the-password-is-out/</link>
		<comments>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/climategate-iii-the-password-is-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 16:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Nova</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Global Warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ClimateGate]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joannenova.com.au/?p=27517</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>FOIA has been in touch with skeptics today. Here is the email below, sorry, without that password. There are 220,000 emails in the file. There may be private information which could cause grief that is not related to taxpayer funded work. Obviously that large file is not in a form that can be released publicly yet. I do hope people are very very careful with the password.</p> <p>This is your chance to understand why FOIA did what they did, and your chance to say thanks to the person who quite possibly saved us from a bureaucratic coup in Copenhagen in 2009. The draft treaty promised to take up to $140 billion from some and redistribute it to others. As Christopher Monckton revealed, sovereign nations would be ceding powers to a group of foreign officials, but the document did not have the words “election” or “democracy” or “vote” or “ballot”.</p> <p>To all those who think, post hoc, that Copenhagen was never going to succeed anyway, I say that in November 2009, when I asked the carbon traders which outcome the money was betting on. The answer was: we don&#8217;t know. The players are out of this market.</p> <p>You can leave your [...]<br /><div><img src="http://joannenova.com.au/wp-content/plugins/gd-star-rating/gfx.php?value=8.7" /></div><div>Rating: 8.7/<strong>10</strong> (147 votes cast)</div><br />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://joannenova.com.au/2013/03/climategate-iii-the-password-is-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>396</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using disk: basic
Database Caching using disk: basic
Object Caching 670/705 objects using disk: basic

Served from: joannenova.com.au @ 2013-03-22 09:46:00 -->