<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">
    <title>Mommy Shorts</title>
    
    
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/" />
    <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:weblog-86841840429078284</id>
    <updated>2013-04-04T08:08:27-07:00</updated>
    <subtitle>Funny bursts of wisdom in the battle of mommy vs. baby- new parenting stories, insights, and funny baby videos. Plus unique baby gift ideas, baby cool hunting, worthy giveaways and more.</subtitle>
    <generator uri="http://www.typepad.com/">TypePad</generator>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/MommyShorts" /><feedburner:info uri="mommyshorts" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://hubbub.api.typepad.com/" /><entry>
        <title>4 Reasons My Daughter Hates Me</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/MommyShorts/~3/DlVNJw19iNY/4-reasons-my-daughter-hates-me.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/04/4-reasons-my-daughter-hates-me.html" thr:count="35" thr:updated="2013-04-04T12:41:12-07:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9fa8442970d</id>
        <published>2013-04-04T08:08:27-07:00</published>
        <updated>2013-04-04T08:13:51-07:00</updated>
        <summary>There's a new dynamic in our house and it's this: ME: Hi, Mazzy. Want to play? MAZZY: No. ME: Okay. (sits down on couch near where she is playing) MAZZY: No! Go away! Leave me alone! ME: Don't worry, I won't try to play with you. MAZZY: I said— GO...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mommy Shorts</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="All Mazzy All The Time" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Warstories &amp; Rants" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Working Mom" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.mommyshorts.com/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9faa148970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="E759bd0693ba11e28e6622000a9f0a1a_7" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9faa148970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9faa148970d-800wi" title="E759bd0693ba11e28e6622000a9f0a1a_7" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9faa148970d-pi" style="display: inline;" />There's a new dynamic in our house and it's this:</p>
<p><strong>ME:</strong> Hi, Mazzy. Want to play?</p>
<p><strong>MAZZY:</strong> No.</p>
<p><strong>ME:</strong> Okay. (sits down on couch near where she is playing)</p>
<p><strong>MAZZY:</strong> No! Go away! Leave me alone!</p>
<p><strong>ME:</strong> Don't worry, I won't try to play with you.</p>
<p><strong>MAZZY:</strong> I said— GO AWAY!</p>
<p><strong>ME:</strong> Alright. See you later... (gets up to go to other room)</p>
<p><strong>MAZZY:</strong> DADDY!!! Will you play with me???</p>
<p>This has been going on for the past couple of weeks and it's only getting worse.
</p>

<p>Yesterday, I was able to come home from work in the middle of the day unexpectedly, and I thought Mazzy would be so excited to see me. Instead, I walked in her room as she was waking up from her nap, she gave me this really odd half-surprised/half-pissed-off expression and then called for Ruth, our nanny. </p>
<p>OUCH.</p>
<p>I know this is all par for the course in parenthood but I thought three years old was a little early to be demonstrating such animosity towards your own mother. </p>
<p>I wish I was the kind of person who could just let it roll off my back, but I find myself feeling genuinely hurt. </p>
<p>At first, I figured it was just one or two instances of Mazzy asserting her independence, but then as the behavior continued, I started to think about how much has changed at home over the last few months.</p>
<p>Here are the four possible reasons my daughter is not my biggest fan at the moment:</p>
<p><strong>1. I am back at work.</strong> </p>
<p><a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/the-weird-places-ive-pumped.html" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/the-weird-places-ive-pumped.html">I went back to work</a> about two months ago. Typically, as a freelancer, I work a few weeks full-time and then I have a few weeks off until the next project. But I have been getting consistent work and have not had any time off since I started working again. The effects of being back at work are cumulative. A couple of weeks back and all is well, but now Mazzy is beginning to realize this is more of a permanent change. I'm starting to feel the increased absence of time with her as well so we are both more sensitive when we are together. Mazzy needs to show me she is mad I am not around and at the same time, I want the time I spend with Mazzy to be that much more special.</p>
<p><strong>2. Our new bedtime routine gives us even less time together.</strong></p>
<p>About a month ago, <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/02/toddler-sleep-rehab.html" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/02/toddler-sleep-rehab.html">I started a new bedtime routine courtesy of a sleep consultant</a>. The consultant helped me realize that Mazzy was getting way less sleep than she needed and suggested we put her to bed earlier. After implementing the earlier bedtime, it became clear that she was right, but it also means that we cut the time we spend as a family practically in half. Mike and I usually get home from work between 5:30-6pm. The new bedtime routine dictates that Mazzy must be in bed before 7pm. At first, cutting out the extra 30-60 minutes of time together seemed worth having Mazzy wake up well-rested and in good spirits. But again, cumulatively, having that much less time with Mazzy (in addition to being back at work) has really taken a toll.</p>
<p><strong>3. I'm the bad guy.</strong></p>
<p>Every house has one. The parent that is more likely to say no and lay down the rules. I'm the one who won't let Mazzy watch TV before bed. I'm the one that tells her it's time to go to sleep. I'm the one who tells her she can't have a cookie for breakfast. My interactions with my child, in the little time I have with her, are all about saying no and making her do things she doesn't want to do. Someone told me yesterday that if your child likes you 100% of the time, you are probably not a very good parent. I think that's true. But if your child hates you 100% of the time, you are probably not a very good parent either.</p>
<p><strong>4. I'm always holding Harlow.</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/02/my-loves.html" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/02/my-loves.html">Mazzy loves Harlow dearly</a>. Even when she refuses to give me hugs and kisses, she is always eager to give Harlow affection. Because she took to Harlow so easily and fully, I thought we had avoided a lot of the new sibling resentment I had heard about. But now I realize that although Harlow's appearance in our lives didn't immediately have a negative effect, Mazzy now understands her beloved little sister diverts attention from herself. Mike is much better with Mazzy than he is with the baby so most often, when we are all home, I am the one taking care of Harlow. I have made a big effort to always hand off the baby to Mike so I can continue to be one who puts Mazzy to bed, but lately, Mike has been working late and I have been reading books to Mazzy while Harlow sits on my lap. </p>
<p>In fact, when I came home from work early yesterday and walked into Mazzy's room after her nap, I was holding Harlow. I think Mazzy needed to be held in that moment and her confused expression had to do with the fact that she was happy to see me but upset my arms were full. Then she called Ruth because she knew Ruth would be able to hold her.</p>
<p>So that's where we are. Lots of problems and I'm not sure if there is an easy solution to fix them. </p>
<p>But I did come up with something that Mazzy seems excited about. Today at noon, instead of running downstairs from work to grab a quick bite to eat, I am picking up Mazzy from school and taking her to lunch, just the two of us. </p>
<p>Last night, during bedtime routine, when I told Mazzy my plan, she told me she is going to have a turkey sandwich and I will be having soup. Then she retold this to her dad this morning and again when Ruth arrived.</p>
<p>So perhaps she doesn't hate me. She just needs some one-on-one Mommy/Mazzy time.</p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MommyShorts/~4/DlVNJw19iNY" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/04/4-reasons-my-daughter-hates-me.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>9 Tricks to Get Your Kids to Drink More Water</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/MommyShorts/~3/wtXP0euITjY/9-tricks-to-get-your-kids-to-drink-more-water.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/04/9-tricks-to-get-your-kids-to-drink-more-water.html" thr:count="27" thr:updated="2013-04-03T21:27:35-07:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0133f30ae399970b017c384d7fdd970b</id>
        <published>2013-04-02T21:33:11-07:00</published>
        <updated>2013-04-03T02:53:31-07:00</updated>
        <summary>The two main ways to keep your kids healthy is to make sure 1) they get lots of exercise and 2) they drink lots of water. Exercise is not problem for us. My daughter wouldn't sit still if she was duct taped to a chair with a fifty pound weight...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mommy Shorts</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Early Childhood Development" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Short Lessons in Parenting" />
        
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="how do i get my kids to drink more water" />
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.mommyshorts.com/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38378323970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Ginandtitonic" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c38378323970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38378323970b-800wi" title="Ginandtitonic" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38378323970b-pi" />The two main ways to keep your kids healthy is to make sure 1) they get lots of exercise and 2) they drink lots of water.</p>
<p>Exercise is not problem for us. My daughter wouldn't sit still if she was duct taped to a chair with a fifty pound weight on her lap.  </p>
<p>Water, on the other hand, is a bit of an issue. The only way I can get Mazzy to drink water is to mix it with juice. Or possibly force feed it to her in that whole duct tape scenario mentioned above, but it's not my favorite option.</p>
<p>So, if every week brings a new parenting challenge, this week I am determined to get my daughter to appreciate daily servings of H2O.
</p>

<p>I'm hoping that through a combination of fun products (sinking <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001GQ2SQ6/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B001GQ2SQ6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Titanic Ice</a> anyone?) and parental ingenuity (aka lying), I might have some success. But as with everything concerning a three-year-old, I'm sure there will be lots of trial and error, so take my suggestions with a grain of salt.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4265f752970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Trick-kid-into-drinking-more-water" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d4265f752970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4265f752970c-800wi" title="Trick-kid-into-drinking-more-water" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4265f752970c-pi" /><strong>1. Buy fun cups.</strong></p>
<p>I'll start with the obvious. Let your child pick out a special cup and then only let them use that cup when they are drinking water. Always leave the special cup of water where your child can reach it and have it on hand whenever you are on-the-go.</p>
<p><strong>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d427ca962970c-pi" style="float: left;"><img alt="Screen Shot 2013-04-03 at 12.04.42 AM" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d427ca962970c" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d427ca962970c-120wi" style="margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px;" title="Screen Shot 2013-04-03 at 12.04.42 AM" /></a>2. Make drinking water into a game.</strong></p>
<p>Challenge your kid to drink to a certain level of the cup. Like if it's the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B006V84JLG/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B006V84JLG&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Dora the Explorer Sippy Cup</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B006V84JLG" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" /> <em>(pictured left)</em>, say: "Drink until you reach the bottom of Dora's shoe!" </p>
<p><strong>3. Freeze some cool shapes.</strong></p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c384d98d4970b-pi" style="float: right;"><img alt="41E02t79KlL" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c384d98d4970b" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c384d98d4970b-120wi" style="margin: 0px 0px 5px 5px;" title="41E02t79KlL" /></a>Mazzy loves ice. Always has. Someone bought us a penguin-shaped ice cube tray and the other day when I tried and failed to get Mazzy excited about water, I suggested we put the penguin ice in the cup. SOLD! There are tons of fun alternatives— everything from <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0079MACFA/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B0079MACFA&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">mustaches</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B0079MACFA" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" /> to <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00262D282/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B00262D282&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">sparkly jewels</a> to <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0061O8PY2/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B0061O8PY2&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Hello Kitty</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B0061O8PY2" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />.</p>
<p><strong>4. Stick a slice of fruit in there.</strong></p>
<p>You never know what's gonna be exciting to a toddler so you might as well give this one a shot. Maybe it will be the greatest thing that ever happened or maybe she'll pluck that slice of lemon out and whip it across the room. It's worth a shot. You can also try freezing a raspberry in an ice cube. </p>
<p><strong>5. Suck it from a silly straw.</strong></p>
<p>When we were younger we had Crazy Straws. Of course, I remember drinking mainly chocolate milk out of those things but there's no reason why you can't use them to bring a little excitement to your child's cup of water. Chocolate milk is exciting on its own. There are also <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002DVJK14/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B002DVJK14&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Strawz Connectible Drinking Straws</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B002DVJK14" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" /> that work a bit like Tinker Toys. Or how about the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015MPDXG/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B0015MPDXG&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">magic wand ice cube tray</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B0015MPDXG" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />? You freeze a star at the end of a straw— genius! Just pray your kid doesn't get pissed when it melts.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9f0fd0b970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Icecubetrays18" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9f0fd0b970d" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9f0fd0b970d-800wi" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Icecubetrays18" /></a><strong /></p>
<p><strong>6. Teach your kid to serve herself.</strong></p>
<p>We've got a water dispenser on our fridge. It honestly never occured to me to teach Mazzy how to use it until I started writing this post. This morning I set up some cups in an accessible place and told her she was free to get her own water whenever she wanted. You would have thought I gave her the keys to our car.</p>
<p><strong>7. Be a water role model.</strong></p>
<p>"Yummmmm. Water is my favorite!!!! Tinkerbell LOVES water! So does Spiderman! You know what I could really go for? A glass of water! I'm going to chug a glass right now!"</p>
<p><strong>8. Create a Pissing Match.</strong></p>
<p>Yeah. Literally. Tell your kid you can tell how much water she is drinking by the color of her pee. Very yellow means not enough and pretty clear means you are winning at water. And who doesn't want to WIN AT WATER???!!!</p>
<p>If all else fails...</p>
<p><strong>9. Make a cup of juice the reward for finishing the water.</strong></p>
<p><em>Products in the graphic above: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001JRNLYU/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B001JRNLYU&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Alphabet Ice Silicone Rubber Ice Cube Trays</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B001JRNLYU" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004C7PYMQ/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B004C7PYMQ&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Plastic Fun Loop Straws</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B004C7PYMQ" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001JP9I5I/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B001JP9I5I&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Silly Straw Plastic Tubing Eyeglass Straws</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B001JP9I5I" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />
, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B006PTIILS/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B006PTIILS&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Sigg Water Bottle</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B006PTIILS" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002DVJK14/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B002DVJK14&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Strawz Connectible Drinking Straws</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B002DVJK14" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0061O8PY2/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B0061O8PY2&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Hello Kitty Ice Cube Tray</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B0061O8PY2" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013UESV8/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B0013UESV8&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Princess Plastic Goblets</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B0013UESV8" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />
, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003BXSED8/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B003BXSED8&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Bobble BPA Free Water Bottle Set</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B003BXSED8" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />, Ice Invaders ice tray, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001GQ2SQ6/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B001GQ2SQ6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Titanic Ice Cube Tray</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B001GQ2SQ6" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" /></em></p>
<p>-------------------------------------------</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9dd64cc970d-pi" style="float: left;"><img alt="Screen Shot 2013-03-30 at 9.58.04 PM" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9dd64cc970d" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9dd64cc970d-100wi" style="width: 100px; margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px;" title="Screen Shot 2013-03-30 at 9.58.04 PM" /></a>This post was sponsored by <a href="http://www.pediacare.com" target="_blank" title="http://www.pediacare.com">PediaCare</a> who asked me to write about ways to make staying healthy fun. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.pediacare.com/Products/pediacare-childrens-fever-reducer-plus-cough-and-runny-nose-with-acetaminophen.aspx" target="_blank" title="http://www.pediacare.com/Products/pediacare-childrens-fever-reducer-plus-cough-and-runny-nose-with-acetaminophen.aspx">PediaCare Children's Cough &amp; Runny Nose Plus Acetaminophen</a> is specially developed for kids (ages 4-11) and provides safe and effective relief for your child’s cough, cold and fever symptoms. All PediaCare's products are 100% child-focused with kid-friendly flavors and appropriate dosing restrictions. Check here for their <a href="http://www.pediacare.com/Products/pediacare-childrens-fever-reducer-plus-cough-and-runny-nose-with-acetaminophen.aspx" target="_blank" title="http://www.pediacare.com/Products/pediacare-childrens-fever-reducer-plus-cough-and-runny-nose-with-acetaminophen.aspx">dosing chart</a> which uses weight as opposed to height.</p>
<p><em>Disclosure: I am honored to be a 2012 paid brand ambassador for PediaCare. All opinions expressed are my own. For more information about PediaCare products, please visit their Facebook page: <a href="http://www.facebook.com/PediaCare" target="_blank">www.facebook.com/PediaCare</a></em></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MommyShorts/~4/wtXP0euITjY" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/04/9-tricks-to-get-your-kids-to-drink-more-water.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>First World Problems: Preschool Edition</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/MommyShorts/~3/EOMT9sENMrc/first-world-problems-preschool-edition.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/first-world-problems-preschool-edition.html" thr:count="39" thr:updated="2013-04-04T09:04:59-07:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0133f30ae399970b017d426e10e4970c</id>
        <published>2013-04-01T21:29:50-07:00</published>
        <updated>2013-04-02T06:55:25-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Awhile back Rants from Mommyland and I teamed up to do "First World Problems: Mommy Edition". Now, the hilarious ladies are back with the trials and tribulations of their privileged preschoolers. It's a tough job going to gymnastics class inbetween all those episodes of Team Umizoomi! Normally, I do a...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mommy Shorts</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="guest posts" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Leftovers" />
        
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="first world problems preschool edition" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="funny mom bloggers" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="mommy shorts" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="rants from mommyland" />
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.mommyshorts.com/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c3846ab38970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="First-world-preschool-problems-2" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c3846ab38970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c3846ab38970b-800wi" title="First-world-preschool-problems-2" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c3846ab38970b-pi" style="display: inline;" />Awhile back <a href="http://www.rantsfrommommyland.com" target="_blank" title="http://www.rantsfrommommyland.com">Rants from Mommyland</a> and I teamed up to do <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2011/11/first-world-problems-mommy-edition.html" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2011/11/first-world-problems-mommy-edition.html">"First World Problems: Mommy Edition"</a>. Now, the hilarious ladies are back with the trials and tribulations of their privileged preschoolers. It's a tough job going to gymnastics class inbetween all those episodes of Team Umizoomi!</p>
<p>Normally, I do a big set-up for guest bloggers but today, I'm just handing over the reins. I think the women who bested me in every mom blogging awards competition I've ever been in, can do just fine on their own. </p>
<p>I say this with the utmost love, respect, admiration and PURE UNFILTERED JEALOUSY. </p>
<p>Here they are!</p>

--------------------------------------------
<p>Hieeeee and waving! Guru Louise here, visiting from Mommyland. I’m
a big, huge, gigantic Mommy Shorts fan so I’m pretty excited to be here. I want
to move into the apartment above Ilana’s and exchange parenting tips as our
preschoolers play and hilarity ensues. It would be like a really awesome
sitcom!</p>
<p>It’s not creepy that I just said all that, right? <strong><em>(Note from Ilana: Yes, please! Move in the apartment above mine! Can you put an end to the constant need to drill holes in the floor boards during nap time??)</em></strong></p>
<p>
I’m here today because a couple weeks ago I wrote about my <a href="http://www.rantsfrommommyland.com/2013/03/10-first-world-problems-of-preschooler.html" target="_blank" title="http://www.rantsfrommommyland.com/2013/03/10-first-world-problems-of-preschooler.html">four
year-old’s first world problems</a>. Things like: her crayons all broke, and
she is expected to share the iPad with her little brother, and other various
injustices. </p>
<p>Lydia and I asked our readers what first world problems their
preschoolers have and holy crap, you guys, the responses were hilarious. We
waded through a couple hundred and selected the following as our favorites.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9e9bd04970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="First-world-problems-preschool-edition" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9e9bd04970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9e9bd04970d-800wi" title="First-world-problems-preschool-edition" /></a></p>
<p>Check out that awesome graphic!
I suggest you print it out and hang it on your fridge so you can remind
yourself that <em>it’s not just your kid.</em></p>
<p>xoxox</p>
<p>Guru Louise</p>
<p>------------------------------------</p>
<p>Alright, Mommy Shorts back now. Preschool versions of first world problems are just too fun to pass up. Anyone mind if I write a few for Mazzy? Guru Louise? (She says it's fine.)</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>FIRST WORLD PROBLEMS: MAZZY EDITION</strong></span></p>
<p>1. I have four blankies and all of them are in the washing machine.</p>
<p>2. My mom's making me eat lunch in the car on my way to the Hamptons which means IT'S COLD and there is no way to warm it up in the microwave.</p>
<p>3. My <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B006BIO0BA/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B006BIO0BA&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">FurReal Friends Dog</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B006BIO0BA" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" /> woke me up in the middle of the night due to its incessant robot barking.</p>
<p>4. My mom told me I had to stop watching shows on the iPad and play an iPad game instead.</p>
<p>5. My Winnie the Pooh cup is in the dishwasher and I refuse to drink my morning smoothie out of anything else.</p>
<p>6. I have over 100 books but I am not in the mood for any of them.</p>
<p>7. Netflix wasn't working so I had to watch regular television which is interrupted by something called COMMERCIALS.</p>
<p>8. There were twelve kids at my friend's birthday party but only four kids were allowed in the bouncy castle at one time. </p>
<p>9. MY CROWN WON'T STAY ON MY HEAD!!!!!!!  </p>
<p>10. My mother keeps trying to make me eat things that aren't bagels.</p>
<p>Okay— your turn!</p>
<p>----------------------------------</p>
<p><strong><em>Follow Rants from Mommyland on facebook <a href="http://www.facebook.com/RantsFromMommyLand" target="_blank" title="http://www.facebook.com/RantsFromMommyLand">here</a> and follow Mommy Shorts on facebook <a href="http://www.facebook.com/mommyshorts" target="_blank" title="http://www.facebook.com/mommyshorts">here</a>.</em></strong></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MommyShorts/~4/EOMT9sENMrc" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/first-world-problems-preschool-edition.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Easter Egg Hunt: Fantasy VS. Reality</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/MommyShorts/~3/hthI2Oi8290/easter-egg-hunt-fantasy-vs-reality.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/easter-egg-hunt-fantasy-vs-reality.html" thr:count="19" thr:updated="2013-04-01T21:24:20-07:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0133f30ae399970b017d426e605b970c</id>
        <published>2013-03-31T19:33:33-07:00</published>
        <updated>2013-04-01T03:41:17-07:00</updated>
        <summary>The only Easter Egg Hunts I have been to are in New York City. I imagine attaining Egg Hunt Perfection is a lot easier in the 'burbs. But just in case there are others like me who partake in communal neighborhood egg hunts instead of family hunts in their own...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mommy Shorts</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Holiday Hoopla" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Warstories &amp; Rants" />
        
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="easter egg hunts" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="fantasy vs. reality" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="kids" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="manhattan easter" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="parenting humor" />
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.mommyshorts.com/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d426e6f8a970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Easter-egg-hunt-fantasy-vs-reality" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d426e6f8a970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d426e6f8a970c-800wi" title="Easter-egg-hunt-fantasy-vs-reality" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d426e6f8a970c-pi" style="display: inline;" />The only Easter Egg Hunts I have been to are in New York City. I imagine attaining Egg Hunt Perfection is a lot easier in the 'burbs. But just in case there are others like me who partake in communal neighborhood egg hunts instead of family hunts in their own backyard— this one is for you.
</p>

<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>EASTER EGG HUNT FANTASY:</strong></span></p>
<p>Children in their Easter best gather on the White House lawn or some other lawn equally expansive. All eggs have been thoughtfully hidden in places that are neither too easy nor too difficult to find. When the hunt begins, the children know instinctively to spread out as much as possible so they don't step on one another's turf. There are enough eggs so all children are thoroughly occupied for at least thirty minutes time, with each child successfully filling their basket to the brim. When all eggs have been collected, the children gather together to open them up and see what they have inside. This is only a formality because, of course, whatever is inside the eggs, the children will be equal parts delighted and grateful. Afterwards, each child hugs and thanks their parents for showing them such a magnificent time.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>EASTER EGG HUNT REALITY:</strong></span></p>
<p>Your husband dresses your child while you are breastfeeding the baby and by the time you involve yourself in the process she is wearing pink leggings with a hole in them that she refuses to remove. They have paired those leggings with a forest green "Super Soccer Stars" t-shirt that is three sizes too big. You opt out of this battle because it's not like you are going to church and she'll be wearing a jacket anyway.</p>
<p>The one instruction you were given by the Egg Hunt Organizers was to bring your own basket. Between getting your three-year-old, your baby and your husband out the door with the necessary snacks, diapers and changes of clothes, you don't remember the basket until you have already left the house. Then you have to circle back, run upstairs with a baby strapped to your chest and find something ANYTHING to use. You settle on a beach pail. At least it's not a white plastic bag from Duane Reade.</p>
<p>The hunt takes place in a large courtyard between a few residential buildings. Due to lesson from last year (in which all the big kids overtook the little kids and left them with no eggs to find within a span of two minutes), the hunt has been split into two separate heats. At 11:30pm, all kids under three will search for eggs. At 12pm, all kids over three will search for eggs. You are also given strict instructions (again, due to last year) to only allow your child to take five eggs. You nod your head at these restrictions, thinking them very wise.</p>
<p>You arrive at the location at 11:45am, right when the little kid hunt is ending and the eggs are being re-hidden for the bigger kids. But, since your kid is exactly three (on the cusp of the little kid/big kid cut-off), she is not yet mature enough to undertstand why she must wait fifteen minutes for the hunt to begin. She sees eggs, she wants eggs, she was told she is here to hunt for eggs and so, SHE RETRIEVES EGGS. You then have to spend the next fifteen minutes convincing your child to put them back so that she can hunt for them again at the official time. A concept that makes no sense to her whatsoever. </p>
<p>When you have finally convinced your child to rehide the eggs (through a variety of threats, bribes and thanking her profusely for being SUCH A GOOD GIRL), you lead her to the group of kids assembling behind a rope. Your child runs under the rope making sure she is front and center and you avoid glances from other parents because perhaps they missed the whole premature-hunting-thing and won't realize she is yours.</p>
<p>At 12pm exactly, the rope drops, the kids squeal with excitement and take off. Unfortunately, they all focus their attention on the same bush. Hands are stepped on, parents yell to look elsewhere, THE PINK ONE is ripped right out from under your child's grasp. Uh-oh. You know that look. Tantrum will commence in 5, 4, 3— "It's okay, we'll find another pink one!" "I WANT THAT PINK ONE!!!!!!!" "Look, there's a pink one over there!" you lie. It works. She spots a tree, all the way in the back, makes a break for it. "I FOUND ONE!!!!!!" She picks up a pink one. You breathe a sigh of relief. Then a green one, a yellow one and a striped one, in quick succession. SHIT. This is too easy! You remember the "5 Eggs Rule". Oh no! How is this supposed to be enforced? "Make sure you leave eggs for the other kids!" you yell cheerily. She ignores you. Your husband begins removing eggs and throwing them back into the bushes when she isn't looking. She quickly finds twice as many to replace them. You overhear another mother, "Wow, she's got a lot of eggs..." "We're going to put them back!" you say a little too defensively. "No, no, I wasn't judging you!" the woman assures you. This is what's happening now. You're misinterpreting friendly banter at a neighborhood egg hunt. </p>
<p>You realize all the kids have tons of eggs. There seem to be more than enough. You relax. Your child is happy. She sits on the ground to open her eggs and see what is inside. A rubber bunny. A plastic ring. A cat tattoo. She doesn't stop until every last one is open. "Isn't this FUN?????" you say.</p>
<p>"But— THERE'S NO CANDY!!!!!!!!!"</p>
<p>Tears.</p>
<p>It's 12:02.</p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MommyShorts/~4/hthI2Oi8290" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/easter-egg-hunt-fantasy-vs-reality.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Ducks, Bunnies and Marshmallow Peeps</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/MommyShorts/~3/-OFF3eVIy78/ducks-bunnies-and-marshmallow-chicks.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/ducks-bunnies-and-marshmallow-chicks.html" thr:count="3" thr:updated="2013-03-30T13:59:51-07:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0133f30ae399970b017c382e1fc0970b</id>
        <published>2013-03-29T04:15:02-07:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-29T14:36:00-07:00</updated>
        <summary>As much as I make fun of the Jewish holidays, this week I remembered that matzah with butter is one of the greatest late night snacks in the history of late night snacks. Just don't eat too much— that shit is BINDING. Pun intended. Also, as predicted, I broke Passover...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mommy Shorts</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Product Reviews &amp; Giveaways" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.mommyshorts.com/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c382ebaa3970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="806d4191a750c917a01ed50" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c382ebaa3970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c382ebaa3970b-800wi" title="806d4191a750c917a01ed50" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c382ebaa3970b-pi" style="display: inline;" />As much as <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/thanks-grammy-for-horrifying-my-child-with-the-10-plagues-finger-puppets.html" target="_blank" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/thanks-grammy-for-horrifying-my-child-with-the-10-plagues-finger-puppets.html">I make fun of the Jewish holidays</a>, this week I remembered that matzah with butter is one of the greatest late night snacks in the history of late night snacks. Just don't eat too much— that shit is BINDING. Pun intended.</p>
<p>Also, <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/multiple.html" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/multiple.html">as predicted</a>, I broke Passover prematurely and completely by accident. </p>
<p>I'd been very good about staying away from leavened-bread-type-objects and then yesterday during a momentary brain malfunction, I ate a chicken sandwich for lunch. I continued my day, came home, ate Seder leftovers for dinner and then finally, at about 9pm, I was like— Oh wait.... oops.</p>
<p>So... since I messed up that whole keeping kosher thing, I'm gonna go back to talking about all things Easter.
</p>

<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d21683970d-pi" style="float: left;"><img alt="4146377622_74d3b552dc_o" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d21683970d" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d21683970d-200wi" style="width: 200px; margin: 0px 5px 5px 0px;" title="4146377622_74d3b552dc_o" /></a>One of my very best friends owns a very popular creperie/bakery/bar in Providence, Rhode Island called <a href="http://www.theduckandbunny.com" target="_blank" title="http://www.theduckandbunny.com">The Duck &amp; Bunny</a>. With that name, you might imagine they are open for Easter Sunday only, but no, they are open all year round. </p>
<p>My friend's name is Jessica and she's owned The Duck &amp; Bunny with her husband, Dan, ever since they fled NYC once everyone around them started having babies.</p>
<p><strong>FUN FACT:</strong> Every crepe on the menu is named after one of their friends' kids. The Mazzy Star (portobello, fontina with rosemary and truffle oil) is named after my daughter, Mazzy.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d3bbae970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="The-duck-and-bunny2" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d3bbae970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d3bbae970d-800wi" title="The-duck-and-bunny2" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d3bbae970d-pi" style="display: inline;" /><strong>ANOTHER FUN FACT:</strong> If Peeps were a cult of marshmallow extremists who would rather die than give up their right to pastel sugared chicks on the holidays, my friend Jessica would not only be a card-carrying member, she might kill someone to become their leader. </p>
<p>When I signed on to do <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/multiple.html#more" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/multiple.html#more">my Peeps post earlier this week</a>, I told them about my Peeps-obsessed friend, who's restaurant happens to have been awarded <strong>RHODE ISLAND'S BEST CUPCKES OF 2012</strong>. Peeps agreed to send Jessica a bunch of marshmallow chicks to let The Duck &amp; Bunny work its magic.</p>
<p>Here is the result.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d81b97970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Peeps-filled-cupcakes" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d81b97970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d81b97970d-800wi" title="Peeps-filled-cupcakes" /></a><br />I have not tasted them (although I am tempted to drive the 2+ hours just to do so) but having eaten many of The Duck &amp; Bunny's cupcakes before, I can guarantee they are delicious. </p>
<p>I'm particularly impressed with the Peeps buttercream filling which I'm told took multiple tries to get the consistency just right.</p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 12pt;">INGREDIENTS</span></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>2 cups (500 mL) sugar</li>
<li>4 egg</li>
<li>2 ½ cups (625 mL) all-purpose flour</li>
<li>1 cup (250 mL) milk</li>
<li>¾  cup
(175 mL) vegetable oil</li>
<li>2 ¼ teaspoons (11 mL) baking powder</li>
<li>1 teaspoon (5 mL) vanilla</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 12pt;">INSTRUCTIONS</span></strong></p>
<p>1. Preheat oven to 350 degrees F (180 degrees C).
Line cupcake pan with papers.</p>
<p>2. In a
large mixing bowl, with an electric mixer, beat sugar and eggs together until
slightly thickened, about 1 minute. Add flour, milk, oil, baking powder,
and vanilla and beat for another minute, just until the batter is smooth and
creamy. Don't overbeat. Scoop batter into paper lined cupcake pans.</p>
<p>3. Bake in preheated oven for 30 to 40 minutes or
until the tops are golden and a toothpick poked into the center of the layer
comes out clean. Let cool completely.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>FLUFF BUTTERCREAM</strong></span></p>
<ul>
<li>1 lb unsalted butter (room temperature)</li>
<li>4-5 cups 6x powdered sugar</li>
<li>¼ cup
fluff (peep colored and warmed slightly) x4</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong>INSTRUCTIONS</strong></span></p>
<p>1. In a stationary mixer with paddle attachment, cream
butter until smooth</p>
<p>2. Slowly add powdered sugar, one cup at a time, beating
about a minute between each addition</p>
<p>3. Beat until creamy and smooth</p>
<p>4. Divide buttercream to match the number of peep colors
you have</p>
<p>5. Add colored fluff to each buttercream and stir with
spatula until combined</p>
<p>6. In a round tip fitted pastry bag, scoop colored
buttercream and begin to insert into cupcakes about half way, filling it with
fluff frosting until it barely peeks out of the top of the cupcake</p>
<p>7. Make another batch of buttercream by using the first
two ingredients and a teaspoon of
vanilla.</p>
<p>8. Follow instructions 1-3</p>
<p>9. Pipe a round “doughnut” shape on the top of the fluff
filled cupcakes</p>
<p>10. Sprinkle
green colored coconut on top of the buttercream and place peep in center</p>
<p>11. Enjoy!</p>
<p><em><span style="font-size: 8pt;"><a href="http://www.theduckandbunny.com" target="_blank" title="http://www.theduckandbunny.com">The Duck &amp; Bunny</a> is on 312 Wickenden Street in Providence, RI. (401) 270-3300</span></em></p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>In addition to The Duck and Bunny's Peepcakes and my <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/multiple.html#more" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/multiple.html#more">Matzah Sch'meeps</a> from earlier this week, I had a lot of fun jumping around to all the participating bloggers in the Peeps campaign to see what fate they dreamed up for their pastel little chicks.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d20e46970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Stuff-to-do-with-peeps" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d20e46970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d20e46970d-800wi" title="Stuff-to-do-with-peeps" /></a></p>
<p>Here they are in no particular order:</p>
<p><strong>Rants from Mommyland</strong> made <a href="http://www.rantsfrommommyland.com/2013/03/i-rule-at-peeps.html#more" target="_blank" title="http://www.rantsfrommommyland.com/2013/03/i-rule-at-peeps.html#more">Mojito Peepos</a></p>
<p><strong>Naps Happen</strong> erupted a marshmallow <a href="http://www.napshappen.net/2013/03/25/the-eruption-of-mt-peep/" target="_blank" title="http://www.napshappen.net/2013/03/25/the-eruption-of-mt-peep/">Mt. Peeps</a></p>
<p><strong>Sometimes Sweet</strong> <a href="http://sometimessweet.blogspot.com/2013/03/food-family-traditions-peeps.html" target="_blank" title="http://sometimessweet.blogspot.com/2013/03/food-family-traditions-peeps.html">drowned her Peeps in hot chocolate</a></p>
<p><strong>Four Plus and Angel</strong> made <a href="http://fourplusanangel.com/2013/03/peace-love-and-sugar/" target="_blank" title="http://fourplusanangel.com/2013/03/peace-love-and-sugar/">No Bake Peeps in a Nest</a></p>
<p><strong>My Life and Kids</strong> played <a href="http://mylifeandkids.com/peeps/" target="_blank" title="http://mylifeandkids.com/peeps/">Peeps Pranks</a> on her kids</p>
<p><strong>The Underachieving Domestic Goddess</strong> created <a href="http://underachievingdomesticgoddess.blogspot.com" target="_blank" title="http://underachievingdomesticgoddess.blogspot.com">Peepster Sundaes</a></p>
<p><strong>How to Be a Dad</strong> made <a href="http://www.howtobeadad.com/2013/15949/7-abnormal-uses-for-peeps" target="_blank" title="http://www.howtobeadad.com/2013/15949/7-abnormal-uses-for-peeps">Peeps Proofing and Peeperpedic Pillows</a></p>
<p><strong>Hollow Tree Ventures</strong> failed at crafting an <a href="http://www.hollowtreeventures.com/2013/03/easter-hats-with-peeps-onality.html" target="_blank" title="http://www.hollowtreeventures.com/2013/03/easter-hats-with-peeps-onality.html">Easter Peepster Hat</a></p>
<p><strong>You Know it Happens at Your House Too</strong> poured herself <a href="http://youknowithappensatyourhousetoo.com/cake-in-a-glass-yes-please/" target="_blank" title="http://youknowithappensatyourhousetoo.com/cake-in-a-glass-yes-please/">Peeps in a Glass</a></p>
<p><strong>The Frugalista</strong> made <a href="http://frugalistablog.com/the-cult-of-peeps-onality/" target="_blank" title="http://frugalistablog.com/the-cult-of-peeps-onality/">Peeps-ka-bobs</a></p>
<p>and <strong>Baby Rabies</strong> <a href="http://www.babyrabies.com/2013/03/peeps-put-em-on-your-fireplace/" target="_blank" title="http://www.babyrabies.com/2013/03/peeps-put-em-on-your-fireplace/">Peeped Her Mantle</a></p>
<p>I think it goes without saying that any one of those things sounds like a lot more fun than playing with a <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/thanks-grammy-for-horrifying-my-child-with-the-10-plagues-finger-puppets.html" target="_blank" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/thanks-grammy-for-horrifying-my-child-with-the-10-plagues-finger-puppets.html">DEAD BABY PUPPET</a>.</p>
<p><em>For even more Peeps-inspired Easter ideas, check out this video:</em></p>
<p><iframe frameborder="0" height="264" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/z19P_u5JqB8" width="470" /> </p>
<p>--------------------------------------------</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>SWEET DREAMS GIVEAWAY WINNERS</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d4b28c970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="6a0133f30ae399970b017d41d68769970c-800wi" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d4b28c970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9d4b28c970d-800wi" title="6a0133f30ae399970b017d41d68769970c-800wi" /></a></strong></span></p>
<p>The two winners of a $60 <a href="http://babyjives.com" target="_blank" title="http://babyjives.com">Baby Jives</a> gift credit to use on an adorable handmade mobile <em>(like the ones above)</em> are @abbydunncarter on Instagram and Temami from <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/baby-jives-mobile-giveaway.html" target="_blank" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/baby-jives-mobile-giveaway.html">underneath the blog post</a>. Congratulations! Please email me to claim your prize.</p>
<p>For everyone that didn't win, Baby Jives is offering 15% off to all Mommy Shorts readers on both <a href="www.babyjives.com" target="_blank" title="www.babyjives.com">her site</a> and <a href="http://www.etsy.com/shop/BabyJivesCo" target="_blank" title="http://www.etsy.com/shop/BabyJivesCo">her Etsy shop</a> if you purchase a mobile before March 30th. Just use the code <strong>MOMMYSHORTS</strong> to get the discount.</p>
<p>If you are curious, Temami's name for her unborn baby was Zuzu, after the little girl in <em>It's a Wonderful Life</em>. More on all those oddly endearing in utero names next week.</p>
<p>Before I go, I've got an Easter tip. Take it for what it's worth since it's coming from a Jew...</p>
<p>Hide those eggs really really really well around your house. I suggest places like inside the urn on the top of your bookshelf or behind the impossible-to-move dresser. Than sit back, watch the full season of <em>House of Cards</em> on Netflix, while your kids spend the entire day trying and failing to find them. </p>
<p>Have a good weekend and Happy Easter!</p>
<p>— Mommy Shorts</p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MommyShorts/~4/-OFF3eVIy78" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/ducks-bunnies-and-marshmallow-chicks.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Crappy Pictures Made Me Some Crappy Pictures!!!</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/MommyShorts/~3/HZEXV4MTelg/crappy-pictures-made-me-some-crappy-pictures.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/crappy-pictures-made-me-some-crappy-pictures.html" thr:count="155" thr:updated="2013-04-04T09:23:13-07:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0133f30ae399970b017c382891b7970b</id>
        <published>2013-03-27T22:38:28-07:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-27T23:05:56-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Book Giveaway: "Parenting: Illustrated with Crappy Pictures " It seems a little silly for me to introduce you all to Amber Dusick. I'm pretty positive, if you are a parent with a computer, you are already well aware of her. But, just in case you are living in the back...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mommy Shorts</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Product Reviews &amp; Giveaways" />
        
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="mommy blogger books" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="mommy shorts illustrated with crappy pictures" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="parenting illustrated with crappy pictures" />
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.mommyshorts.com/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><em><strong>Book Giveaway: "<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0373892748/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0373892748&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Parenting: Illustrated with Crappy Pictures</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0373892748" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />"</strong></em></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38287f7b970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="FrontCover_ParentingIllustratedwithCrappyPictures_hires" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c38287f7b970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38287f7b970b-800wi" title="FrontCover_ParentingIllustratedwithCrappyPictures_hires" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38287f7b970b-pi" style="display: inline;" />It seems a little silly for me to introduce you all to Amber Dusick. I'm pretty positive, if you are a parent with a computer, you are already well aware of her. But, just in case you are living in the back of my coat closet in the storage bin that houses all the ski clothes I haven't worn since 1992, I will explain.</p>
<p>Amber Dusick writes an extremely popular blog called <a href="http://crappypictures.com" target="_blank" title="http://crappypictures.com">Parenting Illustrated with Crappy Pictures</a> in which she writes parenting stories illustrated with crappy pictures. If that doesn't sound like the funniest thing you have ever heard than you are not using your imagination. Check out <a href="http://crappypictures.com/last-monday-started-like-any-other-monday-except-the-boys-were-being-unruly-more-than-usual-i-mean-this-was-the-beginning/" target="_blank" title="http://crappypictures.com/last-monday-started-like-any-other-monday-except-the-boys-were-being-unruly-more-than-usual-i-mean-this-was-the-beginning/">"Going Viral, The Puking Kind"</a> and <a href="http://crappypictures.com/public-toilets-vs-girls-and-boys/" target="_blank" title="http://crappypictures.com/public-toilets-vs-girls-and-boys/">"Public Toilets Vs Newly Potty Trained Girls and Boys"</a> to fully understand the genius behind a badly drawn baby.</p>
<p>Amber came out with her first book this week (Congratulations, Amber!) called "<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0373892748/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0373892748&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Parenting: Illustrated with Crappy Pictures</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0373892748" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />" (obviously) and I could not be more excited to read it— my copy is currently en route.</p>
<p>To help promote Amber's book, I've got two things going on today.
</p>

<p>1) I'm giving away a copy! For a chance to win, leave a comment under this post.</p>
<p>2) Amber did me the supreme honor of illustrating Crappy Pictures for one of my old posts.</p>
<p>I must say, I'm feeling a little weird being all—<em> Amber is so hilarious! Now, read something of mine!</em> But a mom blogger must take thrills where she can get them and seeing myself and Mazzy illustrated in crappy pictures might be my biggest brush with greatness since Christain Slater autographed a playbill for me in the early 90's. (No, I was not wearing my ski clothes at the time.)</p>
<p>Amber chose the post herself (it's from just before Mazzy turned two) and I'm hoping that for many of you, it is your first time reading it. </p>
<p>Please notice Amber's attention to detail. Crappy Mazzy has a Crappy Bow in her hair.  </p>
<p>--------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">ARE YOU SURE THIS IS A KIDDIE PARK?</span></strong><br /><em>Written by Me, Crappy Pictures by Amber Dusick</em></p>
<p>I loved amusement parks as a kid (the scarier the ride, the better) so I was super excited to take Mazzy to her first kiddie park. I figured she was too small to go on most of the rides but at least she'd go on the carousel and kick some ass at Wack-A-Mole.</p>
<p>Then the ticket booth lady said Mazzy could go on ALL BUT TWO of the rides.</p>
<p>REALLY? Are you sure you are not mistaking my kid for the fourteen-year-old with the neck tattoo behind me?</p>
<p>Yes, she was sure.</p>
<p>We started easy with a train that went around in a circle at .00000002 miles per hour. I rode next to Mazzy with my arm laid over her lap just in case she tried to wriggle free from the seatbelt, jump out action-movie-style and scream “Thomas!” before running headfirst into the front car.</p>
<p>Miraculously, Mazzy sat still, tightly grasping the steering wheel for the entirety of the ride.</p>
<p>Next we moved on to a boat ride where Mazzy continued to surprise by not diving head first into one foot of water.</p>
<p>With two successes under our belt, we got more adventurous and tried the plane ride, the big slide and the mini roller coaster. Mazzy emerged smiling after each one and suddenly I had visions of future mother-daughter upside-down roller coaster rides, alpine slide races and sharing a tube in the Tunnel of Terror at Splish Splash.</p>
<p>I thought about how much different I was going to be from my own mother, who’d sit on the sidelines waving and snapping pictures no matter how much I begged her to come along. </p>
<p>“Go with your dad," she'd always say. "I belong on the ground."</p>
<p>At the end of the day, we had one more ride ticket left. After scanning the park, I decided to take Mazzy on a harmless looking apparatus with a cheerful sounding name. </p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9cb52c6970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Mommy-shorts-crappy-pictures-1" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9cb52c6970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9cb52c6970d-800wi" title="Mommy-shorts-crappy-pictures-1" /></a></p>
<p>We sat side-by-side as the "Happy Swing" started slow and steady. I yelled “whee!” on each downward motion, just in case Mazzy was unaware we were having fun.</p>
<p>Then the swing picked up speed. </p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d42574988970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Mommy-shorts-crappy-pictures-2" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d42574988970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d42574988970c-800wi" title="Mommy-shorts-crappy-pictures-2" /></a></p>
<p>Faster, higher, back and forth.</p>
<p><em>Hmmm. This seems a bit more dangerous than it did from the ground.</em></p>
<p>Faster, higher, back and forth.</p>
<p>I found myself gripping Mazzy’s leg to make sure she stayed put.</p>
<p>Faster, higher, back and forth.</p>
<p>Suddenly, I felt my stomach drop as if someone had just pushed me off the side of a cliff. </p>
<p>Faster, higher, back and forth.</p>
<p>My brain rattled inside my head as my fingers practically bore holes into Mazzy’s thigh.</p>
<p>Faster, higher, back and forth.</p>
<p>We were going to be thrown from the swing. I was sure of it.</p>
<p>Faster, higher, back and forth.</p>
<p><em>OH MY GOD WOULD THIS THING EVER END??!</em></p>
<p>I tried not to puke as I angled my head to make sure my baby wasn't crying. Then I offered her the only reassurance I could.<em><br /></em></p>
<p><img alt="Mommy-shorts-crappy-pictures-3" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9cb55d0970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9cb55d0970d-800wi" title="Mommy-shorts-crappy-pictures-3" /></p>
<p>Mazzy looked like she was in a state of shock— staring straight ahead, eyes wide as her hair whipped wildly above her. I was positive that if she survived the ride, this would be our first and last trip to the amusement park. She would forever be the little girl scarred by a crazy mother’s overzealous decision to take her on the most nausea-inducing ride in the park.</p>
<p>Finally, the swing began to slow and my hand loosened it’s grip on Mazzy’s leg. My stomach tried and failed to settle back into place as the ride screeched to it's upchuck-worthy end.</p>
<p>I looked at my poor 21-month-old daughter, prepared to plead forgiveness and assure her that this was the last time Mommy would ever place her in harm's way.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9cb573e970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Mommy-shorts-crappy-pictures-4" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9cb573e970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9cb573e970d-800wi" title="Mommy-shorts-crappy-pictures-4" /></a></p>
<p>Mazzy was expressionless, still staring straight ahead. I touched her leg gently.</p>
<p>“Mazzy, it’s over, I promise.”</p>
<p>Nothing.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9cb568f970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Mommy-shorts-crappy-pictures-5" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9cb568f970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9cb568f970d-800wi" title="Mommy-shorts-crappy-pictures-5" /></a></p>
<p><em>Oh my god. I'd killed her.</em></p>
<p>Then suddenly, her eyes sprang back to life and her arms flew over her head.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d42574d3a970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Mommy-shorts-crappy-pictures-6" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d42574d3a970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d42574d3a970c-800wi" title="Mommy-shorts-crappy-pictures-6" /></a></p>
<p>In that moment, I became my mother.</p>
<p><em>Go with your dad. I belong on the ground.</em></p>
<p>
--------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>GIVEAWAY RULES</strong></span></p>
<p>To win a copy of Amber Dusick's <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0373892748/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0373892748&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=mommshor-20">Parenting: Illustrated with Crappy Pictures</a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=mommshor-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0373892748" style="width: 0px !important; height: 0px !important; border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;" width="1" />, just leave a comment below. Winner will be announced next Friday. If you can't wait that long, you can purchase a copy by clicking the Amazon link below. </p>
<p>Big thanks to Amber for drawing me in slimming black with lots of hair!</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?t=mommshor-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as1&amp;asins=0373892748&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;fc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;lt1=_blank&amp;m=amazon&amp;lc1=01ACA6&amp;bc1=FFFFFF&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;f=ifr" style="width: 120px; height: 240px;" /><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MommyShorts/~4/HZEXV4MTelg" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/crappy-pictures-made-me-some-crappy-pictures.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Parent Sting Operation Catches Bedtime Bandit in the Act (VIDEO)</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/MommyShorts/~3/N6W1LruXXIM/parent-sting-operation-catches-bedtime-bandit-in-the-act-video.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/parent-sting-operation-catches-bedtime-bandit-in-the-act-video.html" thr:count="10" thr:updated="2013-04-01T14:12:34-07:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0133f30ae399970b017d42556d53970c</id>
        <published>2013-03-27T12:39:02-07:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-27T12:41:30-07:00</updated>
        <summary>Two year-olds are usually skilled in areas like feeding themselves and stacking blocks, which makes little Kyle's newfound skill all the more impressive. Kyle has mastered the art of 'LATE NIGHT BREAKING AND ENTERING'. According to his parents, Kyle had a habit of sneaking into his sister's room to steal...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mommy Shorts</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Funny Baby Videos" />
        
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="funny baby videos" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="kyle picks lock" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="toddler breaks into bedroom" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="two year old picks lock" />
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.mommyshorts.com/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d42556f2b970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Screen Shot 2013-03-27 at 3.40.17 PM" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d42556f2b970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d42556f2b970c-800wi" title="Screen Shot 2013-03-27 at 3.40.17 PM" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d42556f2b970c-pi" style="display: inline;" />Two year-olds are usually skilled in areas like feeding themselves and stacking blocks, which makes little Kyle's newfound skill all the more impressive.</p>
<p>Kyle has mastered the art of 'LATE NIGHT BREAKING AND ENTERING'. </p>
<p><a href="http://gawker.com/5992610/babycam-catches-toddler-picking-lock-on-sisters-bedroom-door-stealing-her-stuffed-animal?post=58591643" target="_blank" title="http://gawker.com/5992610/babycam-catches-toddler-picking-lock-on-sisters-bedroom-door-stealing-her-stuffed-animal?post=58591643">According to his parents</a>, Kyle had a habit of sneaking into his sister's room to steal her stuff. When Big Sis complained, they told her to lock the door. Did that stop Kyle? Nope. He just grabbed his kid-friendly nail clipper and used it to pick the lock. </p>
<p>What is possibly worth the risk of Kyle's midnight escapade? </p>
<p>Watch and find out. 
</p>

<p><iframe frameborder="0" height="353" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/8wk-qRfJQPM" width="470" /> </p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MommyShorts/~4/N6W1LruXXIM" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/parent-sting-operation-catches-bedtime-bandit-in-the-act-video.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Thanks Grammy, For Horrifying My Child with the 10 Plagues Finger Puppets</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/MommyShorts/~3/WykHqpgGTPs/thanks-grammy-for-horrifying-my-child-with-the-10-plagues-finger-puppets.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/thanks-grammy-for-horrifying-my-child-with-the-10-plagues-finger-puppets.html" thr:count="21" thr:updated="2013-03-28T18:37:03-07:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0133f30ae399970b017c3824464b970b</id>
        <published>2013-03-27T05:33:30-07:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-27T07:03:22-07:00</updated>
        <summary>This Passover, the main objective was to get my three-year-old to stay seated at the dinner table, which meant numerous family members came to last night's seder armed with various Passover-themed books and toys. None more disturbing than Grammy's gift of "The Ten Plagues Finger Puppets" (see above). Yep. That's...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mommy Shorts</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Holiday Hoopla" />
        
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="passover toys" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="ten plagues finger puppets" />
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.mommyshorts.com/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38243cf5970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Ten-plagues-finer-puppets-passover" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c38243cf5970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38243cf5970b-800wi" title="Ten-plagues-finer-puppets-passover" /></a></p>
<p>This Passover, the main objective was to get my three-year-old to stay seated at the dinner table, which meant numerous family members came to last night's seder armed with various Passover-themed books and toys. </p>
<p>None more disturbing than Grammy's gift of "The Ten Plagues Finger Puppets" <em>(see above)</em>. Yep. That's LICE, BLOOD and a DEAD BABY (aka the slaying the of the firstborn).</p>
<p>Are you having fun yet, Mazzy? What's that? You'd like a chocolate bunny and a basket full of candy? Sorry, babe! Now be a good little Jew and play with your DISEASED CATTLE puppet.
</p>

<p>In all honesty, the plagues were always my favorite part of the seder growing up (you get to dip your finger in the wine for each plague) and it wasn't until last night that I realized how horrifying this should be for a small child. </p>
<p>But Mazzy was fine and politely asked me to help her apply the BOILS sticker in her Haggadah workbook. </p>
<p>Someone else gave her a box full of the physical manifestations of the plagues (rubber locust, cup of blood, plastic frog), which caused her to wear an eye patch (DARKNESS) through most of dinner. </p>
<p>I gotta say though— Mazzy did look like she was having fun.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38245084970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Photo-223" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c38245084970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38245084970b-800wi" title="Photo-223" /></a></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MommyShorts/~4/WykHqpgGTPs" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/thanks-grammy-for-horrifying-my-child-with-the-10-plagues-finger-puppets.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Multiple Peepsonalities</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/MommyShorts/~3/Sb3siuvMV_U/multiple.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/multiple.html" thr:count="30" thr:updated="2013-03-29T18:32:46-07:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bf4f4e970d</id>
        <published>2013-03-25T23:54:49-07:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-26T05:55:44-07:00</updated>
        <summary>When I was little, I thought Easter-themed candies like Peeps and chocolate bunnies were forbidden. Along with colorful Christmas lights and gingerbread houses, denying myself fluffy chick-shaped marshmallow confections was part of the sacrifice of being a Jew. It wasn't until college that I ate my first Peep. You know,...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mommy Shorts</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Holiday Hoopla" />
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Product Reviews &amp; Giveaways" />
        
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="are peeps kosher" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="fun things to do with peeps" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="matzah peeps" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="peeps" />
        <category scheme="http://sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="show your peepsonality" />
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.mommyshorts.com/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfbb7a970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Photo-206" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfbb7a970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfbb7a970d-800wi" title="Photo-206" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfbb7a970d-pi" style="display: inline;" />When I was little, I thought Easter-themed candies like <a href="http://www.marshmallowpeeps.com" target="_blank" title="http://www.marshmallowpeeps.com">Peeps</a> and chocolate bunnies were forbidden. Along with colorful Christmas lights and gingerbread houses, denying myself fluffy chick-shaped marshmallow confections was part of the sacrifice of being a Jew.</p>
<p>It wasn't until college that I ate my first Peep. You know, as part of the rebellious coming-of-age phase when you first leave home, drink lots of alcohol, hook up with questionable boys, and eat pink sugared marshmallow. Everyone goes through that, right?</p>
<p>Since I was introduced to Peeps so late in life, I didn't realize that people were doing more with Peeps than just eating them straight out of the pack.</p>
<p>Apparently, there are many kinds of "peepsonalities" beyond the purists.
</p>

<p>There are those who cook with them.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424b5c44970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="7d87ad47ad0917a03b14ca86ee4e2362" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d424b5c44970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424b5c44970c-800wi" title="7d87ad47ad0917a03b14ca86ee4e2362" /></a><span style="font-size: 8pt;"><em><a href="http://thedomesticrebel.com/2013/03/19/peeps-candy-bars-spring-hop-along-peeps-party/" target="_blank" title="http://thedomesticrebel.com/2013/03/19/peeps-candy-bars-spring-hop-along-peeps-party/">Photo Source: The Domestic Rebel</a></em></span></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424b5c44970c-pi" style="display: inline;" />Those who decorate with them.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfce21970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="C85f8588889c9485ac032867a201f967" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfce21970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfce21970d-800wi" title="C85f8588889c9485ac032867a201f967" /></a><br /><em style="font-size: 8pt;"><a href="http://taloolakids.com/peep-wreath/" target="_blank" title="http://taloolakids.com/peep-wreath/">Photo Source: Taloola Kids</a></em></p>
<p>Those who think Peeps should exercise more modesty.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c381c7d0b970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Peep-1" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c381c7d0b970b" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c381c7d0b970b-800wi" title="Peep-1" /></a><br /><span style="font-size: 8pt;"><em><a href="http://blogs.babble.com/family-kitchen/2011/03/28/tuxedo-peeps/#" target="_blank" title="http://blogs.babble.com/family-kitchen/2011/03/28/tuxedo-peeps/#">Photo Source: Babble</a></em></span></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424b73e7970c-pi" style="display: inline;" />Those who destroy them.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9c14774970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Matzah peeps smores-3" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9c14774970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9c14774970d-800wi" title="Matzah peeps smores-3" /></a><br /><span style="font-size: 8pt;"><em><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e0OIxb3dJ3w" target="_blank" title="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e0OIxb3dJ3w">Video Grab Source: 10 Ways to Kill Marshmallow Peeps</a></em></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Those who are really upset about <em>The Office</em> ending.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10pt;">
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424d51e3970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Officepeeps" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d424d51e3970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424d51e3970c-800wi" title="Officepeeps" /></a><br /></span><span style="font-size: 10pt;">Those who like Downtown Abbey a little too much.</span></p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c381cab1c970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Screen Shot 2013-03-26 at 12.25.11 AM" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c381cab1c970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c381cab1c970b-800wi" title="Screen Shot 2013-03-26 at 12.25.11 AM" /><span style="font-size: 8pt;"><em /></span></a><span style="font-size: 8pt;"><em><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/magazine/peeps-show-vi/2012/03/27/gIQAswMmfS_gallery.html#photo=33" target="_blank" title="http://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/magazine/peeps-show-vi/2012/03/27/gIQAswMmfS_gallery.html#photo=33">Photo Source: The Washington Post</a></em></span></p>
<p>Those who think all great works of art should be edible.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424da4a3970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Screen Shot 2013-03-26 at 10.08.53 AM" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d424da4a3970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424da4a3970c-800wi" title="Screen Shot 2013-03-26 at 10.08.53 AM" /><span style="font-size: 8pt;"><em><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/magazine/peeps-show-vi/2012/03/27/gIQAswMmfS_gallery.html#photo=33" target="_blank" title="http://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/magazine/peeps-show-vi/2012/03/27/gIQAswMmfS_gallery.html#photo=33">Photo Source: The Washington Post</a></em></span></a></p>
<p>Those who make you nostalgic for children's books you previously found annoying.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bf6ab6970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="IMG_4733" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bf6ab6970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bf6ab6970d-800wi" title="IMG_4733" /></a><span style="font-size: 8pt;"><em><a href="http://pinkandgreenmama.blogspot.com/2010_03_01_archive.html" target="_blank" title="http://pinkandgreenmama.blogspot.com/2010_03_01_archive.html">Photo Source: Pink and Green Mama</a></em></span></p>
<p>Those who like to make fun of politicians on vacation.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c381e774b970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Screen Shot 2013-03-26 at 12.23.57 AM" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c381e774b970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c381e774b970b-800wi" title="Screen Shot 2013-03-26 at 12.23.57 AM" /><span style="font-size: 8pt;"><em><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/magazine/peeps-show-vi/2012/03/27/gIQAswMmfS_gallery.html#photo=33" target="_blank" title="http://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/magazine/peeps-show-vi/2012/03/27/gIQAswMmfS_gallery.html#photo=33">Photo Source: The Washington Post</a></em></span></a></p>
<p>Those who want to ruin Easter for children forever:</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424df066970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="542walkingdeadcloseup" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d424df066970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424df066970c-800wi" title="542walkingdeadcloseup" /></a><em style="font-size: 8pt;"><a href="http://www.comicsalliance.com/2012/04/06/peeps-dioramas-geeky-comics/" target="_blank" title="http://www.comicsalliance.com/2012/04/06/peeps-dioramas-geeky-comics/">Waking Dead diroama source: Comic Salliance </a></em></p>
<p>Those who fondly remember the '80s.</p>
<p><em style="font-size: 8pt;"><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c381ed252970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Peepbusters" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c381ed252970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c381ed252970b-800wi" title="Peepbusters" /><em><a href="http://www.comicsalliance.com/2012/04/06/peeps-dioramas-geeky-comics/" target="_blank" title="http://www.comicsalliance.com/2012/04/06/peeps-dioramas-geeky-comics/">Waking Dead diroama source: Comic Salliance </a></em></a><br /></em></p>
<p>And those who, if they weren't building elaborate Pixar-themed Peeps dioramas, could probably be saving the world or something:</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bf7f6a970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Peeps-house-up-eep" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bf7f6a970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bf7f6a970d-800wi" title="Peeps-house-up-eep" /><a href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c381e774b970b-pi"><em /></a><span style="font-size: 8pt;"><em><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/magazine/peeps-show-vi/2012/03/27/gIQAswMmfS_gallery.html#photo=33" target="_blank" title="http://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/magazine/peeps-show-vi/2012/03/27/gIQAswMmfS_gallery.html#photo=33">Photo Source: The Washington Post</a></em></span></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bf7f6a970d-pi" style="display: inline;" />What kind of "peepsonality" do I have?</p>
<p>The kind who, even as a grown adult, still feels a tad guilty publishing a Peeps post on the second day of Passover. You know, before I forget I'm keeping kosher for the week and eat a piece of pizza by mistake on Day Three.</p>
<p>So, when Peeps asked me to express my "peepsonality" today, I deicided to pay homage to my heritage and make what I call "Matzah S'meeps". Or maybe "Matzah Sch'meeps"? That's the Peeps version of a s'more with a little Jewish twist.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>WHAT YOU NEED:</strong></span><br />Peeps<br />Matzah<br />Chocolate<br />Fire <br />Someone Who Does Not Care that Peeps Aren't Kosher </p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfbf9b970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Matzah peeps smores" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfbf9b970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfbf9b970d-800wi" title="Matzah peeps smores" /></a></p>
<p>I'd offer actual instructions but that's probably not necessary. I will say to use two Peeps for each Sch'meep with the chocolate smashed between for maximum melting.</p>
<p>Aren't they pretty? Delicious too.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfc2c7970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Photo-210" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfc2c7970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9bfc2c7970d-800wi" title="Photo-210" /></a></p>
<p>Now, someone tell my daughter she doesn't have to wait until college to eat one.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424bbede970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Matzah peeps smores-2" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d424bbede970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424bbede970c-800wi" title="Matzah peeps smores-2" /></a></p>
<p>For more ideas of what you can do with <a href="http://www.marshmallowpeeps.com" target="_blank" title="http://www.marshmallowpeeps.com">Peeps</a> over the holdiays, check out the adorable commercial below. It's the extended version of the one you might have seen on television, except each craft/recipe/activity mentioned has an annotated link that you can click on that tells you how to make it. For instance, if you've never heard of "Peeps Jousting" before, I highly suggest you click the link and find out.</p>
<p><iframe frameborder="0" height="264" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/z19P_u5JqB8" width="470" /> </p>
<p>And Happy Pesach! </p>
<p>Peepsach?</p>
<p>Oy.</p>
<p>--------------------------------------</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 8pt;"><em>This is a sponsored post by Peeps but the thoughts and opinions are my own.</em></span></p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MommyShorts/~4/Sb3siuvMV_U" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/multiple.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Antidote to Second Child Syndrome</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/MommyShorts/~3/RgP5G4_1y3U/the-antidote-to-second-child-syndrome.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/the-antidote-to-second-child-syndrome.html" thr:count="18" thr:updated="2013-03-26T19:56:44-07:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243b135970c</id>
        <published>2013-03-24T21:07:18-07:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-25T07:04:39-07:00</updated>
        <summary>My photographer friend Jenny Sherouse (who took our family pictures when Mazzy was two and again when Harlow was just born) asked me if she could do a yearlong series on Harlow, which would mean taking pictures every three months. I said, "Gee, I don't know, Jenny... I'm really busy...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mommy Shorts</name>
        </author>
        <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="All Harlow All the Time" />
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.mommyshorts.com/"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38149d28970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="LksNPsHJzdagZ6PEZFdR6n_4Syvg7WXrP9pJ0yDAVIo,NC8IoRwBDm3JbY6LxLqKA_a2trjYPKJHIZ-7OB2tyOc" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c38149d28970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38149d28970b-800wi" title="LksNPsHJzdagZ6PEZFdR6n_4Syvg7WXrP9pJ0yDAVIo,NC8IoRwBDm3JbY6LxLqKA_a2trjYPKJHIZ-7OB2tyOc" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38149d28970b-pi" style="display: inline;" />My photographer friend <a href="http://jennysherousephotography.blogspot.com" target="_blank" title="http://jennysherousephotography.blogspot.com">Jenny Sherouse</a> (who took <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2011/12/is-there-a-toddler-wrangler-at-this-photo-shoot.html" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2011/12/is-there-a-toddler-wrangler-at-this-photo-shoot.html">our family pictures when Mazzy was two</a> and again <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2012/12/happy-holidays-from-mommy-shorts.html" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2012/12/happy-holidays-from-mommy-shorts.html">when Harlow was just born</a>) asked me if she could do a yearlong series on Harlow, which would mean taking pictures every three months.</p>
<p>I said, "Gee, I don't know, Jenny... I'm really busy and this sounds like it might eat into my weekends." </p>
<p>Or maybe, I said something more like, "SERIOUSLY??!!! THAT WOULD BE AWESOME!!!!! Especially since I have SECOND CHILD SYNDROME and ADULT HARLOW is going to be PISSED when she sees her LACK OF QUALITY DOCUMENTATION!"</p>

<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b7d490970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="R87kaZwR5UfyLrqTiiV2BXnjZeXVrEkO7XrvxJ1ikb8,mJ4kOUdUt0fCaEQ4eq1RQSYUwzzC5GTFbk3h3tZCcaI" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b7d490970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b7d490970d-800wi" title="R87kaZwR5UfyLrqTiiV2BXnjZeXVrEkO7XrvxJ1ikb8,mJ4kOUdUt0fCaEQ4eq1RQSYUwzzC5GTFbk3h3tZCcaI" /></a></p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243d6c5970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="OgWdcLN2Xdj7A1gpUnickJNQbVjelaj_QDz9vr6-K9A,j2E3es8grgv6uPbFcl_an8Kaa6iKfdFe5-8zcVl0tyY,fCrrvV-QgFJTmuCRtCVHPb8UGXFjcQVg7c59AsnlWeE" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243d6c5970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243d6c5970c-800wi" title="OgWdcLN2Xdj7A1gpUnickJNQbVjelaj_QDz9vr6-K9A,j2E3es8grgv6uPbFcl_an8Kaa6iKfdFe5-8zcVl0tyY,fCrrvV-QgFJTmuCRtCVHPb8UGXFjcQVg7c59AsnlWeE" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243d6c5970c-pi" style="display: inline;" />Right before Mazzy was born, Mike bought me a DSLR camera for my birthday and we used that constantly for Mazzy's first two years. Now, I'm sad to say, it seems like a pain to lug around and is buried deep in our coat closet. </p>
<p>Almost all of the photos we have of Harlow are taken on our phones.</p>
<p>As much as I love Instagram <a href="http://instagram.com/mommyshorts" target="_blank" title="http://instagram.com/mommyshorts">(follow me-- @mommyshorts!)</a>, those photos don't usually hold up very well if you blow them up to print.</p>
<p>Adding insult to injury, I have no videos of Harlow. It didn't even occur to me to take them, because she doesn't DO anything.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243cb47970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="FNkPeW9OnvkJVgNtE8oV7U838CBDnFC2AKYIqAvZAhA,a68IIpAPIMB1jhop_5FdeiC8hYnN6VpuFmgf1H_AYXY" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243cb47970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243cb47970c-800wi" title="FNkPeW9OnvkJVgNtE8oV7U838CBDnFC2AKYIqAvZAhA,a68IIpAPIMB1jhop_5FdeiC8hYnN6VpuFmgf1H_AYXY" /></a></p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c381500b3970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="MaM07NUbvINkTzkU7VViEvlaTPqFaZsTrSh1zk54JtE,Fn5-WppWUTYAkU0roD-vecW9SP3j3BVCP45btIyQTa0,RFkFedcgaHwb3mbDetLlmQy-p2MbVGVzn2AGRKEHpXM" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c381500b3970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c381500b3970b-800wi" title="MaM07NUbvINkTzkU7VViEvlaTPqFaZsTrSh1zk54JtE,Fn5-WppWUTYAkU0roD-vecW9SP3j3BVCP45btIyQTa0,RFkFedcgaHwb3mbDetLlmQy-p2MbVGVzn2AGRKEHpXM" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b83a6a970d-pi" style="display: inline;" />Not that 'lack of doing anything' mattered when CHILD #1 was born. I took video of Mazzy constantly. I have hours and hours of footage of Mazzy lying on different surfaces in various outfits... propped up in chairs, getting baths, having her hair combed, looking at herself (also not moving) in the mirror. I have videos of Mazzy SLEEPING. </p>
<p>CHILD #2 has one video that is about five seconds long. I stopped recording when I realized nothing was happening and it was just going to take up storage space.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b7f269970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Harlow-mommy-shorts-2" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b7f269970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b7f269970d-800wi" title="Harlow-mommy-shorts-2" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b7f269970d-pi" style="display: inline;" />Sad, because all those videos of 'nothing happening' was how I created <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2011/01/still-here-me-too.html" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2011/01/still-here-me-too.html">Mazzy's First Year Video</a>. It's called <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2011/01/still-here-me-too.html" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2011/01/still-here-me-too.html">"Life Thus Far"</a> and it's probably my favorite thing on earth.</p>
<p>It's also how I created <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2010/11/home-video-is-boring-even-mine.html" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2010/11/home-video-is-boring-even-mine.html">the video of Mazzy rolling over for the first time</a>— a full two minutes chronicling countless rollover attempts before she finally completed the manuever at 6 months. </p>
<p>You know who rolled over a few weeks ago?</p>
<p>Some baby named Harlow.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243ea8b970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="BQbqf4pr_HST1Qdipv14hUamiCG_OfTFXpRwxlvoxZU,nlVQaC_62b5CYyUZ4CEKnAoONr7YaBpJC7AdjbUytzs,kwRS_P8A_YH19VY4-73Gb6UOaYXkp5BpJpVnswvjQSw" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243ea8b970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243ea8b970c-800wi" title="BQbqf4pr_HST1Qdipv14hUamiCG_OfTFXpRwxlvoxZU,nlVQaC_62b5CYyUZ4CEKnAoONr7YaBpJC7AdjbUytzs,kwRS_P8A_YH19VY4-73Gb6UOaYXkp5BpJpVnswvjQSw" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243ea8b970c-pi" style="display: inline;" />What does she have to show for it? </p>
<p>MEMORIES.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243ec68970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="XpAavYATF_gu4Ew3wGpezyKycJVXbgnag4jAoMYCjf4,zYd6m4tXV2_ZQyEKx8RUSrHEUNROBapy8POz1-Tx_3M,uCvg4Fv2tX6DtGX9WhuFxpCZIXyYmak1El2dqC86DBc" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243ec68970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243ec68970c-800wi" title="XpAavYATF_gu4Ew3wGpezyKycJVXbgnag4jAoMYCjf4,zYd6m4tXV2_ZQyEKx8RUSrHEUNROBapy8POz1-Tx_3M,uCvg4Fv2tX6DtGX9WhuFxpCZIXyYmak1El2dqC86DBc" /></a></p>
<p>Granted, Harlow rolled over successfully after her first attempt, whereas Mazzy spent three months propelling herself to one side without completing the task. We demonstrated, offered incentive, egged her on. There was frustration, determination, crying, laughter— the stuff home videos are made of!</p>
<p>But Harlow?</p>
<p>She was just like, "Yeah, I wanna roll over. There I did it. No big deal." </p>
<p>All beginning and ending, NO STORY ARC.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424441cd970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="E93F6iNWmhqDxqlpGQLIECCulNoj7wX-ynHW_N7qgpI,jAOGCO5FnUxS_8Engq9fBRwq8sUwblLbkjPun6uEl7Q,XyKxKS3Q4JZ-COSMHWam-zn_eq8QWrUj-odO7TP5Mj0" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d424441cd970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424441cd970c-800wi" title="E93F6iNWmhqDxqlpGQLIECCulNoj7wX-ynHW_N7qgpI,jAOGCO5FnUxS_8Engq9fBRwq8sUwblLbkjPun6uEl7Q,XyKxKS3Q4JZ-COSMHWam-zn_eq8QWrUj-odO7TP5Mj0" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d424441cd970c-pi" style="display: inline;" />But at least, Harlow's premature rollover makes me think Mazzy is not going to walk all over her baby sister like I always imagined. Nope, little Harlow, flipping over at a mere three months, <a href="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/01/the-evil-faces-of-harlow.html" target="_self" title="http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/01/the-evil-faces-of-harlow.html">shooting looks that kill</a> at anyone who dares to glance her way...</p>
<p>CHILD #2 IS NOT WALKING IN ANYBODY'S SHADOW.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243efca970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Harlow-mommy-shorts-low" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243efca970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243efca970c-800wi" title="Harlow-mommy-shorts-low" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243efca970c-pi" style="display: inline;" />And thanks to <a href="http://jennysherouse.com" target="_blank" title="http://jennysherouse.com">Jenny Sherouse</a>, fifteen years from now, when Mazzy shows off her carefully curated first year video, Harlow can whip out her year of professional photo documentation, and EVERYBODY WINS.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b81be1970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="3dtgrOSQBFnY-5K1Ci7X9GlrG23wXkfXewxjmZk0QaY,v0iiSU6Es4qA-SXPV0FLZN6QTXj0wvRWQUZ0vAsOms0,DeNT4X79RT_7PQhkeyFR-MQO75mX404Ld7CkK4CGUBY" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b81be1970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b81be1970d-800wi" title="3dtgrOSQBFnY-5K1Ci7X9GlrG23wXkfXewxjmZk0QaY,v0iiSU6Es4qA-SXPV0FLZN6QTXj0wvRWQUZ0vAsOms0,DeNT4X79RT_7PQhkeyFR-MQO75mX404Ld7CkK4CGUBY" /></a></p>
<p><a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b81be1970d-pi" style="display: inline;" />Plus, Harlow will actually have a few photos with MOM. Something you can't get when you're taking all the pictures yourself.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c3814d64f970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="UQqf1CPm7d64VMagZ57gyBXb36AbCED4LSbFPmIbygA,RpTti4ZWldVsLJ4EcrewSZ05Exrb979zdboLiJ5_ifg,BOj904f36y9HVb80ZupRBeej6aV35Ec3mBR6cyLMJlU,xm4t_rnOvVquKtWvGpd83JMKsU75ES8A6-mrB4siUGk" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c3814d64f970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c3814d64f970b-800wi" title="UQqf1CPm7d64VMagZ57gyBXb36AbCED4LSbFPmIbygA,RpTti4ZWldVsLJ4EcrewSZ05Exrb979zdboLiJ5_ifg,BOj904f36y9HVb80ZupRBeej6aV35Ec3mBR6cyLMJlU,xm4t_rnOvVquKtWvGpd83JMKsU75ES8A6-mrB4siUGk" /></a></p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b83e03970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="CHtgBMbOXLZ16T2uOxcU3HdeBLMx-YykKF-YtZCLjCE,0BLNW6gsJ5yKxZ19Z8YcILJp6hveLrtaEWh4fJTu5AQ,ea7zaSneb9mtnP_W7Jc1SsXRgy-XtzI2MHD_amQmawY" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b83e03970d image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017ee9b83e03970d-800wi" title="CHtgBMbOXLZ16T2uOxcU3HdeBLMx-YykKF-YtZCLjCE,0BLNW6gsJ5yKxZ19Z8YcILJp6hveLrtaEWh4fJTu5AQ,ea7zaSneb9mtnP_W7Jc1SsXRgy-XtzI2MHD_amQmawY" /></a></p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243fff0970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="XEMhz255R1ZasK_27JBm9pWfrUu3wZMH7LHNoTnPoss,ybr9SkjngFZ6q-RwtETeYF483SAx0hRMiWX8_d28DIg,0vTCAYx06El13EHmJ1il6RW-mpd82efxxWA1-U1uwdc" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243fff0970c image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017d4243fff0970c-800wi" title="XEMhz255R1ZasK_27JBm9pWfrUu3wZMH7LHNoTnPoss,ybr9SkjngFZ6q-RwtETeYF483SAx0hRMiWX8_d28DIg,0vTCAYx06El13EHmJ1il6RW-mpd82efxxWA1-U1uwdc" /></a></p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38150c0b970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="AAY739o1tMfv-G6N5rCuQ8Ek_36Bedj3Hr0KHbQm4n0,xtw_igw2rO_CdR7aTjNDX7Sd6SQndmpH5Dc7l_fw-RI,GLOym61iuKp9Xb6VnG817-fHkJk7_Gzv4FREdwaO6V0" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0133f30ae399970b017c38150c0b970b image-full" src="http://themommyproject.typepad.com/.a/6a0133f30ae399970b017c38150c0b970b-800wi" title="AAY739o1tMfv-G6N5rCuQ8Ek_36Bedj3Hr0KHbQm4n0,xtw_igw2rO_CdR7aTjNDX7Sd6SQndmpH5Dc7l_fw-RI,GLOym61iuKp9Xb6VnG817-fHkJk7_Gzv4FREdwaO6V0" /></a></p>
<p>If anyone would like to use Jenny Sherouse to take pictures of their family, I cannot recommend her highly enough. Hopefully, the proof is above. You can contact her <a href="http://jennysherouse.com" target="_blank" title="http://jennysherouse.com">here</a>.</p>
<p>I, of course, am indebted to her FOREVER.</p><xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MommyShorts/~4/RgP5G4_1y3U" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>



    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.mommyshorts.com/2013/03/the-antidote-to-second-child-syndrome.html</feedburner:origLink></entry>
 
</feed><!-- ph=1 -->
