<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Pawcurious: With Pet Lifestyle Expert and Veterinarian Dr. V.</title>
	
	<link>http://pawcurious.com</link>
	<description>Healthy living advice from veterinarian and busy mom Dr. V</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 22:14:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.2</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Pawcurious" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="pawcurious" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><image><link>http://pawcurious.com</link><url>http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/themes/pawcurious/pc_feedburner.gif</url><title>Pawcurious</title></image><feedburner:emailServiceId xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">Pawcurious</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>OMG SALMONELLA RUN FOR YOUR LIVES</title>
		<link>http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/omg-salmonella-run-for-your-lives/</link>
		<comments>http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/omg-salmonella-run-for-your-lives/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 09:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. V</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[don't panic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natura]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recalls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salmonella]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pawcurious.com/?p=16901</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You know, I can&#8217;t tell you how many times I had to sit in an exam room with a weeping child, explaining to them over the listless puppy in front of them that I was so sorry, the test came back for Salmonella and the prognosis was grim. Wait, that&#8217;s parvo. Salmonella, while demonized in [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You know, I can&#8217;t tell you how many times I had to sit in an exam room with a weeping child, explaining to them over the listless puppy in front of them that I was so sorry, the test came back for Salmonella and the prognosis was grim. Wait, that&#8217;s parvo.</p>
<p>Salmonella, while demonized in the media to a bogeyman of epic proportions, is mostly known as an irritating member of the Diarrhea Duo, a pest more than a demon scourge of canines. And yet, with every recall, the anger, the indignation, and the fear rolls in, predictable as a rush on flu vaccines after the first case of the winter.</p>
<p>I get it. Trust me, I get it. The 2007 melamine recall put us all on edge- and rightly so, I might add. That was a terrible event, one I hope never to see happen again in my career.</p>
<p>There are several factors that went into that event that made it extra awful, mainly the scope, the deception on behalf of the suppliers, and the number of deaths assumed to have resulted from the whole debacle. There is no excuse for deliberately adulterated ingredients to make their way into the pet food supply, ever. And now here we are, with yet another Salmonella recall- on a food I&#8217;m currently feeding Brody. And am I indignant? Disappointed? Filled with righteous fury?</p>
<div id="attachment_16903" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 582px"><a href="http://pawcurious.com/?attachment_id=16903" rel="attachment wp-att-16903"><img class="size-full wp-image-16903" title="salmonella" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/salmonella.jpg" alt="" width="572" height="480" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Salmonella typhimurium, courtesy NIH.</p></div>
<p>No, not really. But in order to get that you have to understand the ubiquitous nature of Salmonella.</p>
<h4>Salmonella: The scourge of veterinary medicine (except when it isn&#8217;t)</h4>
<p>Let&#8217;s put it this way: if dogs were a preschool, Salmonella would be that runny nose snotty kid always wiping their fingers on everything. It&#8217;s just kind of there, it&#8217;s not there on purpose, but it just kind of happens, and you manage it the best you can. You can peruse pubmed and the various studies on the topic if you want- in fact, NC State is doing research on the very topic of the prevalence of Salmonella in dogs as we speak- the older papers are all over the place, finding 11% to 66% incidence in dogs. A 2002 <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC339295/">Canadian paper on asymptomatic dogs fed the BARF diet</a> found 30% of those dogs tested positive for Salmonella, and, as BARF enthusiasts themselves regularly point out, they are not, as far as anyone can tell, keeling over dead of Salmonellosis in any discernible numbers. This despite the fact that in this study, 80% of their diet did test positive for the bacterium.</p>
<p>So why does the CDC hunt it down like Snape chasing Harry through the halls of Hogwarts? Are they that concerned about the comfort and well being of our canine companions? (hint: no.)</p>
<p>They care because <em>people</em> get Salmonella. The final tally from last year&#8217;s <a href="http://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/newpetfoodrecalls/brand_list.cfm?Trade_Name=Diamond&amp;pet=Dog">Diamond incident</a> was that 49 people were sickened, 10 hospitalized, none dead. The CDC stats, when they have them available, average out to about 35 or so people a year getting documented cases of Salmonella from pet food. 35 out of the 42,000 reported cases a year. That&#8217;s <strong>0.08%</strong> of the documented cases being due to pet food, for those keeping score. The actual number of Salmonella cases, most of which are never reported (how many of us had one of those &#8220;OMG I ate bad Taco Bell&#8221; mornings and never reported it?) is estimated to be about 29 times higher. Death rate from acute Salmonellosis? Less than 1%, actually quite a bit lower than even that unless you are very young ,very old, or immunocompromised.</p>
<p>I know you all love infographics. I&#8217;m too cheap to hire a graphic designer, but nonetheless I made you all a pie chart because I know everyone loves a good pie chart.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/omg-salmonella-run-for-your-lives/pie-chart/" rel="attachment wp-att-16907"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16907" style="border: 2px solid black; margin-top: 4px; margin-bottom: 4px;" title="Salmonella pie chart" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pie-chart.jpg" alt="" width="744" height="360" /></a></p>
<h4>We swim in a sea of Salmonella</h4>
<p>We know, we know and this is well documented, that raw meat is a common source of Salmonella. That is why my mother freaked out, loudly and with great horror, if there was any chicken juice on the counter not promptly blown into oblivion with bleach. &#8220;SALMONELLA!&#8221; she would scream, wielding Lysol like Excalibur against the foe. But as we&#8217;ve seen with a recall from The Honest Kitchen earlier this year, it&#8217;s not just meat that can be the problem- their recall was actually due to a batch of parsley that tested positive. It&#8217;s in the raw ingredients for pet food and the raw ingredients for our own foods. Peanut butter. eggs. chicken. milk.</p>
<p>So what&#8217;s the deal? If you want to make a list of the affected brands in the last 5 years, it goes far and wide. Almost everyone has been affected at some point or another. Is it that every single manufacturer, regardless of their commitment to quality control or lack thereof, is just gross and negligent? In certain cases, like the Diamond recall, where there was a well documented failure to maintain adequate facility standards at the manufacturing plant over several months, I would say yes- they screwed up royally.</p>
<p>But in most cases? I would argue that many manufacturers- at least the ones who do it all in house and are transparent enough to invite journalists in &#8211; follow very high levels of quality assurance. The testing process in a plant following adequate GMPS is thorough; the production process is extremely effective at getting rid of pathogens during the cooking process. And even with that, even with everything done properly, sometimes Salmonella happens, just like sometimes you get an infection post-op even when your surgeon followed meticulous sterile procedures.</p>
<p>In yesterday&#8217;s Natura case, we are talking about one single sample that tested positive.</p>
<h4>So now what?</h4>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for an excuse to stop feeding commercial food and this seems like a convenient one, go forth with my blessing. Please find someone who knows that they are talking about (I love the nutritionists at <a href="https://secure.balanceit.com/">BalanceIt)</a> to help guide you.</p>
<p>If you, like the vast majority of the pet owning population including myself, have decided to take your chances with this vile scourge, this baleful bacterium, I give you this long and complicated process to minimize your risks of contracting Salmonella:</p>
<p><strong>1. Wash your hands after touching pet food.</strong></p>
<p><strong>2. Don&#8217;t buy your kid a live chick for Easter.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_16902" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 511px"><a href="http://pawcurious.com/?attachment_id=16902" rel="attachment wp-att-16902"><img class=" wp-image-16902 " title="salmonella-poultry-poster" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/salmonella-poultry-poster-835x1024.jpg" alt="" width="501" height="614" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: CDC (http://www.cdc.gov/salmonella/)</p></div>
<p><strong>3. A<a href="http://www.foodpoisonjournal.com/food-poisoning-watch/conagra-salmonella-pot-pie-plant-shuts-down/#.UUf6S1t4ZU4">void pot pie</a>,<a href="http://www.cdc.gov/vitalsigns/foodsafety/"> mind the beef, don&#8217;t eat cookie dough with raw eggs</a> (screw that, I&#8217;ll take my chances), don&#8217;t be old.</strong></p>
<p>The end!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Disclaimer: I&#8217;m not a CDC public health expert, nor do I pretend to have the vast reservoirs of knowledge that many food safety pros do. That being said, I&#8217;m going out to dinner tonight with my good buddy, veterinarian, MPH and CDC employee Dr. Carrie, so I can pass on any questions to her you might have. </em></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=S-lGt9uW_Jk:Nye6lRs6efM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=S-lGt9uW_Jk:Nye6lRs6efM:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=S-lGt9uW_Jk:Nye6lRs6efM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=S-lGt9uW_Jk:Nye6lRs6efM:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=S-lGt9uW_Jk:Nye6lRs6efM:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=S-lGt9uW_Jk:Nye6lRs6efM:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=S-lGt9uW_Jk:Nye6lRs6efM:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=S-lGt9uW_Jk:Nye6lRs6efM:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=S-lGt9uW_Jk:Nye6lRs6efM:I9og5sOYxJI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/omg-salmonella-run-for-your-lives/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gaming the system</title>
		<link>http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/gaming-the-system/</link>
		<comments>http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/gaming-the-system/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 09:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. V</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mother of the Year]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad mommy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brody]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pawcurious.com/?p=16890</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Raising kids is a lot like raising dogs. There&#8217;s a lot of responsibility, a lot of poop, ridiculous amounts of cleaning, and no small amount of frustration. Regardless, the benefits far outweigh the costs, and with a little consistency and training, it&#8217;s all good. Training being the key component. My son likes Legos and chihuahuas, [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Raising kids is a lot like raising dogs. There&#8217;s a lot of responsibility, a lot of poop, ridiculous amounts of cleaning, and no small amount of frustration. Regardless, the benefits far outweigh the costs, and with a little consistency and training, it&#8217;s all good. Training being the key component.</p>
<p>My son likes Legos and chihuahuas, two things I kind of like but wouldn&#8217;t really say are my &#8220;thing&#8221;. He is his own kid. I realized he was fascinated with mechanical devices more than biological creatures, so I built enough mystique around the Keurig: &#8220;oh no, it&#8217;s MUCH TOO HARD for a kid to work&#8221; etc etc until he insisted- insisted!- that I teach him how to use it, and now he delivers me coffee every morning.</p>
<p>My daughter likes Barbies and Golden retrievers, which, for those of you who know me, you will know must be genetic. So when she came home with an assignment to &#8220;write a presentation on the &#8216;How To&#8217; topic of your choice,&#8221; she announced she wanted to do it about dogs.</p>
<p>&#8220;What are you going to instruct your class in?&#8221; I asked.</p>
<p>&#8220;How to groom a dog,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>So she sat down and typed up her outline. &#8220;Get the dog wet, shampoo the dog, dry the dog&#8221; and so on and so forth.</p>
<p>I looked at the presentation software they were supposed to use.</p>
<p>&#8220;Did you know you can put pictures in here?&#8221; I asked.</p>
<p>&#8220;No,&#8221; she said. &#8220;That wasn&#8217;t part of the assignment.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;But you want to go ABOVE and BEYOND, right?&#8221; I asked. &#8220;I mean, you want to knock this out of the park! Right?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh!&#8221; she said. &#8220;I do. Absolutely.&#8221; She paused. &#8220;But I don&#8217;t have any pictures of me grooming Brody.&#8221;</p>
<p>I paused, looked at the ceiling as if deep in thought, and then said, well, if this is <em>really</em> important to you, I bet I could find a camera.</p>
<p><a href="http://pawcurious.com/?attachment_id=16894" rel="attachment wp-att-16894"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16894" title="L1060075 (2)" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/L1060075-2.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="374" /></a></p>
<p>And that is how I conned my kid into not only washing Brody, but blow drying him, brushing him out, cleaning up, and thanking me for the opportunity.</p>
<p>Maybe I can pay the teacher off to repeat this assignment once a month through the end of the school year. <img src='http://pawcurious.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=obV5UIk6Jvs:Pmf-qQV0uwc:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=obV5UIk6Jvs:Pmf-qQV0uwc:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=obV5UIk6Jvs:Pmf-qQV0uwc:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=obV5UIk6Jvs:Pmf-qQV0uwc:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=obV5UIk6Jvs:Pmf-qQV0uwc:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=obV5UIk6Jvs:Pmf-qQV0uwc:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=obV5UIk6Jvs:Pmf-qQV0uwc:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=obV5UIk6Jvs:Pmf-qQV0uwc:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=obV5UIk6Jvs:Pmf-qQV0uwc:I9og5sOYxJI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/gaming-the-system/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>I want to go where they went</title>
		<link>http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/i-want-to-go-where-they-went/</link>
		<comments>http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/i-want-to-go-where-they-went/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 21:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. V</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cancer sucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mulan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pawcurious.com/?p=16882</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I do not profess to know what happens to us after we die. Even those who have strong faith in what will happen to us after we go are sometimes unsure of what happens to our beloved pets. And to them, I quote the great Will Rogers: &#8220;If there are no dogs in Heaven, then when I [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I do not profess to know what happens to us after we die. Even those who have strong faith in what will happen to us after we go are sometimes unsure of what happens to our beloved pets. And to them, I quote the great Will Rogers: &#8220;If there are no dogs in Heaven, then when I die I want to go where they went.&#8221;</p>
<p>When someone close to me passes on, be it person or pet, I have a dream about them a week or so later. I don&#8217;t know why, if it is a quirk of my subconscious or an actual visit or who the heck knows; the theologians can debate it all they want, but these particular dreams always stick with me long after I wake and give me a good deal of comfort. And yes, I had a dream about Kekoa a week or so ago, right before the funeral service in our backyard arranged by our daughter and very kindly attended by all four grandparents.</p>
<p>But last night I had a different dream, and regardless of what it means it really struck me because it&#8217;s the only time I&#8217;ve had one like it. Those of you who have been around for a while may remember me <a href="http://pawcurious.com/2010/09/little-earthquakes/">speaking about my grandmother Mary</a>, who passed away several years ago and is the person, I believe, who most set me on the path I am on today as a veterinarian. You may also recall my <a href="http://pawcurious.com/2012/03/elegy-for-carl/">grandfather John</a>, who passed away just under a year ago. It was from him, I later learned, that I got my obsession with adventure and the dream of climbing Mt. Meru, which I accomplished last year.</p>
<p>So in this dream, I am driving around on a grassy hillside and I pull into a driveway, quiet and remote. Another car pulls up, and it&#8217;s my grandmother.</p>
<p>&#8220;Open the window so I can see your face,&#8221; she says. &#8220;It&#8217;s been so long.&#8221;</p>
<p>But I get out instead, and look in her backseat. And there is my dog Mulan, who died of melanoma in 2009, right before I started the blog.</p>
<div id="attachment_16883" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 645px"><a href="http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/i-want-to-go-where-they-went/img_5327/" rel="attachment wp-att-16883"><img class="size-full wp-image-16883" title="IMG_5327" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5327.jpg" alt="" width="635" height="423" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Not Brody! This is Mulan and Emmett, in 2008.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;Is she doing better?&#8221; I ask, reaching in as she licks me.</p>
<p>&#8220;Of course!&#8221; Mary says proudly. &#8220;I know how to take care of animals. She is doing very well.&#8221;</p>
<p>I peer into the drivers seat. &#8220;Is my grandfather up there?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Yes,&#8221; she laughs. &#8220;But he doesn&#8217;t want to come out.&#8221; Which is typical.</p>
<p>I pat Mulan, and I start to cry.</p>
<p>&#8220;What&#8217;s wrong?&#8221; she asks.</p>
<p>&#8220;I just lost another dog,&#8221; I said. &#8220;She had bone cancer.&#8221;</p>
<p>My grandmother takes my hand, and says, &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry.&#8221; She kisses me and I wake up with a wet pillow.</p>
<p>You know how some dreams are. Some are bizarre flights of fancy, some dreadful chasms of dark worries come to fruition. And others, in those rare and brief moments, sweep you up in their elusive beauty and show you something that stays with you long after you wake. They feel real. And of all the people for Mulan to find on the other side, my sweet dog who was abandoned by an owner who didn&#8217;t feel like treating her flea allergies and wanted me to euthanize her instead, I&#8217;m so glad that at least in my mind, she found Mary.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know what it means, or if it means anything. But I am so glad it was a dream I got to have.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=ckiAg9lYF9Y:Kns2Tti2FOg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=ckiAg9lYF9Y:Kns2Tti2FOg:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=ckiAg9lYF9Y:Kns2Tti2FOg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=ckiAg9lYF9Y:Kns2Tti2FOg:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=ckiAg9lYF9Y:Kns2Tti2FOg:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=ckiAg9lYF9Y:Kns2Tti2FOg:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=ckiAg9lYF9Y:Kns2Tti2FOg:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=ckiAg9lYF9Y:Kns2Tti2FOg:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=ckiAg9lYF9Y:Kns2Tti2FOg:I9og5sOYxJI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/i-want-to-go-where-they-went/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dr. V, Mega Commuter and Expert Snake Avoider</title>
		<link>http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/dr-v-mega-commuter-and-expert-snake-avoider/</link>
		<comments>http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/dr-v-mega-commuter-and-expert-snake-avoider/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 09:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. V</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brody]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rattlesnake]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pawcurious.com/?p=16868</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I read in an article on CNN the other that that a scant 8% of the population is comprised of &#8216;mega commuters&#8217;, that unlucky club whose commute consists of 90 minutes each way, three hours on the road a day. I felt sorry for them, until I realized I was one of them. When we [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I read in an article on CNN the other that that a scant 8% of the population is comprised of &#8216;mega commuters&#8217;, that unlucky club whose commute consists of 90 minutes each way, three hours on the road a day. I felt sorry for them, until I realized I was one of them.</p>
<p>When we moved in December, in search of better schools and a better commute for my spouse, I hadn&#8217;t taken into account what we would do if our home school district didn&#8217;t have space for us. Of course they would, right? Except they didn&#8217;t, and the best they had to offer was another school nearby until the fall. Which would have been ok except for the fact that I already moved the kids&#8217; school once last September, when we thought our house wouldn&#8217;t sell, and the thought of four schools in a year and a half was just more than I could bear for them. I&#8217;ve already put them through enough this year.</p>
<p>So, until this school year ends, despite the move and the promise of a new day and blah blah blah, I&#8217;m dragging my butt up and down one of So Cal&#8217;s most congested freeways four times a day. To school, back home. To pick them up, back home again. 45 minutes each way, 90 minutes roundtrip x twice a day. And I hate driving to begin with.</p>
<p>I tell you this not to elicit sympathy, though if anyone is wondering if California&#8217;s public school system is really as broken as you&#8217;ve heard the answer is an unequivocal &#8216;yes&#8217;. I tell you this by means of explanation as to why I&#8217;m not here, writing. I probably could type in the car, I spend enough time in it just kind of sitting around, but I imagine that sort of thing is frowned upon. So I listen to the radio and think to myself, how lovely it is for my husband that he now has such a short commute, and he better hand over that Sirius subscription stat.</p>
<p>In between driving, and driving some more, I&#8217;m doing all the same sorts of things I&#8217;ve always been doing, it&#8217;s just I no longer seem to be able to find a good 2 1/2 hours a day I used to have for documenting it. So much to say, between Koa&#8217;s funeral and working at Helen Woodward and oh yes, this:</p>
<p>Last weekend we took Brody to a much needed rattlesnake avoidance refresher course:</p>
<p><a href="http://pawcurious.com/?attachment_id=16870" rel="attachment wp-att-16870"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16870" title="K32C4278" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/K32C4278.jpg" alt="" width="508" height="635" /></a></p>
<p>Normally I&#8217;d have lots and lots of pictures, and some video, and a long explanation of the difference between a good course and a useless course, but in my current state all I have to offer is this one photo. Oh, and a picture of a rattlesnake muzzle, in case you were wondering what one looks like:</p>
<p><a href="http://pawcurious.com/?attachment_id=16869" rel="attachment wp-att-16869"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16869" title="rattlesnake" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/K32C4345.jpg" alt="" width="635" height="423" /></a></p>
<p>We shot that from some distance, by the way. The snake&#8217;s mouth is being held shut with a humane snake muzzle (NOT duct tape!) though that doesn&#8217;t make me any more inclined to come closer than 30 feet. I hope someone makes a reality show about these trainer guys someday. They&#8217;ve forgotten more about snakes than I learned in 4 years of vet school.</p>
<p>The short version of an explanation, for those who are wondering, is that we are fortunate in San Diego to have a very professional and well educated team called <a href="http://socalrattlesnakeavoidancetraining.com/">Natural Solutions</a> who offer a top notch rattlesnake aversion course.</p>
<p>There are terrible rattlesnake courses. I know people who have gone though them. I&#8217;ve read about the people who use mops instead of snakes or the wrong snakes or don&#8217;t know how to to properly use the collars or use them on dogs who are just not proper candidates for this type of program. If you&#8217;re wondering how this group works, I encourage you to read their <a href="http://socalrattlesnakeavoidancetraining.com/TrainingProcess.php">FAQ</a> and see why I trust them with Brody. I trust them so much I wrote to my city council lobbying to allow them a venomous snake permit for use within city limits (it was granted, fortunately).</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve already seen some snakes out and about on our walks, and this training gives me an added layer of comfort. Though considering I&#8217;m in my car most of the day, if I see one I can simply, you know, drive away.</p>
<p>On the plus side, last day of school is May 31. I&#8217;m throwing a party and you&#8217;re all invited.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=Ka90o-4U9Zg:nSHbrYMoi9s:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=Ka90o-4U9Zg:nSHbrYMoi9s:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=Ka90o-4U9Zg:nSHbrYMoi9s:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=Ka90o-4U9Zg:nSHbrYMoi9s:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=Ka90o-4U9Zg:nSHbrYMoi9s:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=Ka90o-4U9Zg:nSHbrYMoi9s:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=Ka90o-4U9Zg:nSHbrYMoi9s:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=Ka90o-4U9Zg:nSHbrYMoi9s:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=Ka90o-4U9Zg:nSHbrYMoi9s:I9og5sOYxJI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pawcurious.com/2013/03/dr-v-mega-commuter-and-expert-snake-avoider/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spay Day, that Golden study everyone’s talking about, and why I still happily remove testicles.</title>
		<link>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/its-world-spay-day/</link>
		<comments>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/its-world-spay-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 09:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. V</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Be The Change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pawcurious.com/?p=16851</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s the day- 2013 Annual World Spay Day! I have to tell you, it doesn&#8217;t tickle the old joy centers quite the way, say, Ben and Jerry&#8217;s Free Ice Cream Cone Day does, but it&#8217;s here and I&#8217;m glad it exists. Now, two things to note before I give my thoughts: 1. Although it&#8217;s called [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s the day- <a href="http://www.humanesociety.org/issues/spay_day/">2013 Annual World Spay Day</a>! I have to tell you, it doesn&#8217;t tickle the old joy centers quite the way, say, Ben and Jerry&#8217;s Free Ice Cream Cone Day does, but it&#8217;s here and I&#8217;m glad it exists.</p>
<p><a href="http://pawcurious.com/?attachment_id=16852" rel="attachment wp-att-16852"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16852" title="spayday" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/spayday.jpg" alt="" width="685" height="187" /></a></p>
<p>Now, two things to note before I give my thoughts:</p>
<p>1. Although it&#8217;s called &#8220;Spay Day&#8221;, the event encompasses both spay and neuter. Nobody&#8217;s trying to leave the fellas out, I think it just rolls off the tongue better this way.</p>
<p>2. Yes, I know it&#8217;s a Humane Society of the United States initiative and that is making at least five of you raise your eyebrows. That being said, I do think it&#8217;s important to recognize and support good initiatives no matter where they originate, and this is one. Lots of other organizations, such as PetSmart Charities, Petfinder, and the ASPCA, agree enough to be an official part of the event.</p>
<p>This question of whether to spay and neuter has become somewhat controversial as of late. And to that I say, let&#8217;s talk about it. Politely, please. As long as it took me to perfect my gentle tissue handling skills I really take issue with being accused of ripping uteri out of unwitting pets willy-nilly for no good reason.</p>
<h3><strong>I Spay</strong></h3>
<p>I am a spay/neuter advocate. Anyone who has worked even a little in a shelter environment becomes one really fast- because when you are faced with the reality:</p>
<p>Of 10,000 faces.</p>
<p><a title="walle3 by pawcurious - visit http://www.pawcurious.com, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pawcurious/5527965011/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5257/5527965011_b02f3e8898_z.jpg" alt="walle3" width="640" height="559" /></a></p>
<p>No, wait, that&#8217;s not 10,000.</p>
<p><a title="walle2 by pawcurious - visit http://www.pawcurious.com, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pawcurious/5527962611/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5219/5527962611_378ff7c49f_z.jpg" alt="walle2" width="640" height="558" /></a></p>
<p>No, wait. That&#8217;s not 10,000 either. THIS is 10,000:</p>
<p><a title="walle 10,000 by pawcurious - visit http://www.pawcurious.com, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pawcurious/5528551292/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5136/5528551292_c9c7f7833f_z.jpg" alt="walle 10,000" width="640" height="558" /></a></p>
<p>10,000 faces A DAY euthanized in US shelters, makes it hard to argue against anything that will help reduce those numbers. Which is why I will support low cost spay/neuter clinics, even if it cuts into my own professional workload (though it never seemed to, even in my lower income area of practice.)</p>
<p>My clinic referred people all the time; our surgery protocol was absolutely top notch, but it came with an appropriate pricetag. Given the choice between a subsidized clinic down the road or no surgery at all, we knew what was the right thing to do. Money&#8217;s tight these days. I get that. I am glad there are resources around for those who need it.</p>
<p><a href="https://spaydayportal.humanesociety.org/spayorneuteryourpet/us/">Spay Day</a> has an <a href="https://spaydayportal.humanesociety.org/sd_findEvent_US.aspx">event locator</a> for people to find local Spay Day events. As an example, h<a href="https://spaydayportal.humanesociety.org/sd_findEventDetails.aspx?eventId=1768">ere&#8217;s an event from my neck of the woods</a>: $10 to fix any pet whose owners reside in a particular school district. I can&#8217;t compete with that, but truth be told, I probably never was in the running for most of the business to begin with. Whatever the outcome, one less litter in the Sweetwater shelter is OK by me.</p>
<h3>But gonads are good! Don&#8217;t you deny it!</h3>
<p>But WAIT! I know what you&#8217;re going to say. You are an educated, informed pet owner and you know all about the research showing that sex hormones do have health benefits and spaying and neutering may not always be 100% a positive thing. You&#8217;ve pored over the latest <a href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0055937">Golden Retriever neutering and cancer study</a> (I did too. Putting 2 Goldens down in 6 months is not a fun thing.) And you ask:</p>
<p>Why must I be forced into this surgery for my pet? <em>Why is no one admitting that testicles and ovaries have a purpose and are best left attached to the animal from whence they sprouted?</em></p>
<p>To this I say: I agree.</p>
<p>And to that I add: Will you at least concede, being an educated, informed pet owner, the sad truth that many, many people are not? And while I can say with utter sincerity that I believe you are not letting your pet run amuk impregnating the neighborhood, your less conscientious streetmates are?</p>
<p>We need to look at the conversation on two different levels: Individual health and population health.</p>
<p><strong>I believe</strong> individual owners should have the right to decide when and if their pets are spayed and neutered. It&#8217;s my job to help you evaluate the risk/benefit analysis and decide for yourself what is right for you, what the consequences of that choices might be, and how to proceed. Should you make an <em>informed</em> decision not to spay and neuter, I will support you. I know you people exist. I&#8217;ve met you. However:</p>
<p><strong>I also believe</strong> that from a population standpoint, in the absence of an owner who makes that level of commitment to understanding the complexity of the issue- or any issue regarding their dog, really- the default recommendation should be: spay and neuter. If you got your cryptorchid puppy off Craigslist and waited three months to bring him in for his first parvo vaccine, I&#8217;m going to recommend neutering him. If you are a local news personality and you Tweet me asking me whether you should buy a dog with an umbilical hernia if you intend to breed her&#8230;.not that that happened&#8230;OK, it just happened&#8230;but do you see what I mean? There are a lot of people out there making, as I explain it to my children, &#8220;poor decisions.&#8221;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 19px;"> </span><br />
<a title="Untitled by pawcurious - visit http://www.pawcurious.com, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pawcurious/8201799702/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8478/8201799702_6ff8281064_z.jpg" alt="Untitled" width="640" height="427" /></a></p>
<p>Nowhere is the benefit of spay/neuter more apparent to me than in Granada, where World Vets started performing the surgeries half a decade ago. You might have walked through there in 2002 and marveled that the stray dogs all seemed so young and vibrant, but here&#8217;s the truth: that&#8217;s because they usually died, starving or in pain, by age 4.</p>
<p>Those people who live there will tell you, with awe in their voices, how much healthier the overall animal population is. How much nicer it is to walk down the street and not see a dead starved dog in a ditch. Those of you educated enough to appreciate the benefits of an intact pet are certainly educated enough to appreciate in the big picture, that might not apply. If not, come on down to Granada and I&#8217;ll show you a<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transmissible_venereal_tumour"> TVT</a>.</p>
<p>You can&#8217;t evaluate the necessity of spay/neuter campaigns in a vacuum; so to sum up, here you go:</p>
<h4>TLDR: If you choose not to spay or neuter your dog because you&#8217;re responsible and educated enough to have decided that is right for you, I&#8217;m here for you. And while I will support you in that I hope you will also acknowledge that for millions of animals out there, spay/neuter IS the best choice, so do me a solid and don&#8217;t undermine my efforts to alleviate significant suffering in spheres outside your own. Deal? Group hug.</h4>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=-_VaQ7LR4Vw:YycJhiPZHpA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=-_VaQ7LR4Vw:YycJhiPZHpA:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=-_VaQ7LR4Vw:YycJhiPZHpA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=-_VaQ7LR4Vw:YycJhiPZHpA:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=-_VaQ7LR4Vw:YycJhiPZHpA:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=-_VaQ7LR4Vw:YycJhiPZHpA:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=-_VaQ7LR4Vw:YycJhiPZHpA:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=-_VaQ7LR4Vw:YycJhiPZHpA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=-_VaQ7LR4Vw:YycJhiPZHpA:I9og5sOYxJI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/its-world-spay-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Muscle Memory</title>
		<link>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/muscle-memory/</link>
		<comments>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/muscle-memory/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 10:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. V</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cancer sucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Picks of the Litter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer sucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kekoa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Koa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loss]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pawcurious.com/?p=16844</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Scientists have long been fascinated with the concept of &#8220;muscle memory&#8221;, that subconscious part of our brain that controls movement without us having to think about it. It&#8217;s what allows us to do complicated tasks such as riding a bike or typing &#8220;the quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog&#8221; without having to stop [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have long been fascinated with the concept of &#8220;muscle memory&#8221;, that subconscious part of our brain that controls movement without us having to think about it. It&#8217;s what allows us to do complicated tasks such as riding a bike or typing &#8220;the quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog&#8221; without having to stop and say, OK, I need to contract my left hamstring while extending my right quadricep and all those tricky things that go into motion. It&#8217;s what allows me to tie a knot during surgery without the laborious thought process that takes place during learning &#8220;around the forceps from the front? or the back?&#8221; After a while, it just happens.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s funny how it pops up in the most unexpected places. For the past 3 years, Kekoa has been my footrest. I literally could not sit in the house without her wedging herself beneath my feet. Now, my feet head toward the floor, expecting a mass to bring them to a halt about 12 inches off the ground. I don&#8217;t think about it or calibrate their momentum, they just go with the intent that they will hit fur. Without her there, they crash repeatedly into the floor, each time a jarring reminder of what is no longer there.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s odd to me how strong those tangible physical reminders can be. For some reason, I can&#8217;t remember the exact timbre of my individual dogs&#8217; barks- and I know they were all quite distinctive- but to a one I can tell you how their heads felt in my hands. Taffy, light as a feather, ready to nip at the slightest provocation. Nuke, needle-nosed and gently, resting into your palm. Emmett, like a solid football, sturdy and reassuring. Mulan, like a brick, wide and solid.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/muscle-memory/koa1/" rel="attachment wp-att-16846"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16846" title="koa1" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/koa1.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="410" /></a></p>
<p>Kekoa&#8217;s head was disproportionately small compared to the rest of her body. She looked somewhat like an engorged tick, but in a nice way. She would lumber over and plop on your feet, her manticore tail smacking into the wall with such force you&#8217;d think someone was cracking a whip on the drywall. She never seemed to notice. Such was her excitement that she would hover over you, massive, looming, and then with the gentlest motion ease her tiny head into your hands and cover them with kisses. You&#8217;d try to push her head away when you had enough but then she&#8217;d kiss that hand too, so eventually you&#8217;d just give up. Her tail wouldn&#8217;t stop wagging the whole time.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/muscle-memory/koa2/" rel="attachment wp-att-16845"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16845" title="koa2" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/koa2.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="410" /></a></p>
<p>She had a terrible wail. A piercing bark so heartbreaking and eardrum-wrenching that she lost two homes because of it. We used our baby monitor to listen in while we were away, and eventually I had to stop because it was too much to listen to.</p>
<p>That sound I can&#8217;t bring up. Already, I&#8217;ve forgotten it. But the sound of her tail hitting the cabinet, and the feel of her head in my hand- those will be with me forever.</p>
<p>Are there any strangely strong memories you carry with your pets who have moved on?</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=VklMixVyQBo:Ubjmp6PDfEc:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=VklMixVyQBo:Ubjmp6PDfEc:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=VklMixVyQBo:Ubjmp6PDfEc:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=VklMixVyQBo:Ubjmp6PDfEc:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=VklMixVyQBo:Ubjmp6PDfEc:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=VklMixVyQBo:Ubjmp6PDfEc:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=VklMixVyQBo:Ubjmp6PDfEc:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=VklMixVyQBo:Ubjmp6PDfEc:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=VklMixVyQBo:Ubjmp6PDfEc:I9og5sOYxJI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/muscle-memory/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Dogs are Better than Boyfriends. :)</title>
		<link>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/why-dogs-are-better-than-boyfriends/</link>
		<comments>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/why-dogs-are-better-than-boyfriends/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 22:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. V</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Life]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pawcurious.com/?p=16839</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Two of my favorite forces- The Honest Kitchen and Lili Chin from Doggie Drawings- teamed up for this awesome little V-Day nugget. Enjoy!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Two of my favorite forces- The Honest Kitchen and Lili Chin from Doggie Drawings- teamed up for this awesome little V-Day nugget. Enjoy!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/why-dogs-are-better-than-boyfriends/whydogsarebetterthanbfriends/" rel="attachment wp-att-16840"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16840" title="WhyDogsAreBetterThanBFriends" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/WhyDogsAreBetterThanBFriends-1024x791.jpg" alt="" width="614" height="475" /></a></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=fRivNmj_CsA:5s-21iqYnpg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=fRivNmj_CsA:5s-21iqYnpg:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=fRivNmj_CsA:5s-21iqYnpg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=fRivNmj_CsA:5s-21iqYnpg:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=fRivNmj_CsA:5s-21iqYnpg:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=fRivNmj_CsA:5s-21iqYnpg:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=fRivNmj_CsA:5s-21iqYnpg:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=fRivNmj_CsA:5s-21iqYnpg:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=fRivNmj_CsA:5s-21iqYnpg:I9og5sOYxJI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/why-dogs-are-better-than-boyfriends/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tip Number One in the Grieving Process: Get Takeout</title>
		<link>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/tip-number-one-in-the-grieving-process-get-takeout/</link>
		<comments>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/tip-number-one-in-the-grieving-process-get-takeout/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 17:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. V</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer sucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kekoa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pawcurious.com/?p=16831</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Everyone processes grief differently. From those who wear it all on their sleeve to those who bottle it in and let it slowly eat them up inside to those who tackle an entirely unrelated project with distracted abandon, being sad is a universal condition we all have to figure out how to deal with. I [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Everyone processes grief differently. From those who wear it all on their sleeve to those who bottle it in and let it slowly eat them up inside to those who tackle an entirely unrelated project with distracted abandon, being sad is a universal condition we all have to figure out how to deal with.</p>
<p>I grew up in New England. We&#8217;re taught from an early age not to show sadness. Or happiness, or anything, really, other than a mild general irritation with other human beings. &#8220;Be like a cement pillar,&#8221; they said, or something along those lines. At my grandfather&#8217;s funeral, we drove up to the gravesite two seconds before the priest arrived, stood there for 2 minutes while he mumbled something in Latin, then got ushered back to the car and whisked away to a Chinese restaurant before anyone could respond to the fact that we were at a funeral. Ta daaa! All you can eat won tons! SSHHHHH AND EAT THE WONTONS.</p>
<div id="attachment_16833" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/tip-number-one-in-the-grieving-process-get-takeout/chinesefood/" rel="attachment wp-att-16833"><img class=" wp-image-16833 " title="chinesefood" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/chinesefood.jpg" alt="" width="529" height="362" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Bury your emotions, people, deep under a pile of Mu Shu pork where they belong.</p></div>
<p>Food is an important part of the New Englander grieving process, I&#8217;ve realized. It explains so much about my family. Yesterday, I wandered through the grocery store for an hour mulling life and the universe and wound up spending 3 hours making a complicated three course gourmet everything. &#8220;What was the inspiration for this?&#8221; asked my husband as he surveyed the 500 dirty pans in the sink. &#8220;Kekoa,&#8221; I said. &#8220;Here, have some goat cheese arugula salad with pear vinaigrette.&#8221;</p>
<p>I <em>try</em> to be a good New Englander, but it&#8217;s a struggle. My day is divided into wide swaths of being OK, punctuated by unpredictable moments of destitute tears triggered by something that reminds me that oh yes, I just lost an important part of my life. That&#8217;s how it is for most of us, I think. We muddle through the best we can.</p>
<p>The day Kekoa died, my husband correctly assumed I would not be in the mood for cooking. He then incorrectly assumed that going out to dinner would be a good distraction and a solution to our problem of what to have for dinner. My daughter had suggested we maybe consider takeout, but he persevered in his attempt to get us out of the house.</p>
<p><a href="http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/tip-number-one-in-the-grieving-process-get-takeout/snl-pepper-boy/" rel="attachment wp-att-16832"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-16832" style="margin: 8px 9px;" title="snl---pepper-boy" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/snl-pepper-boy.jpg" alt="" width="320" height="180" /></a>We wound up in an Italian restaurant, one of those places with extremely attentive waiters who are by every two seconds to make sure you are having the time of your life. &#8220;How are you?&#8221; crooned the hostess, the water boy, AND the waiter, all of whom needed to be addressed in an appropriately cheery tone. And don&#8217;t even get me started on the pepper boy.</p>
<p>They left us with a pile of menus and some crayons, all the better to scribble on the paper on the table. My son started drawing a robot. My daughter, on the far side of the table, started in on her masterpiece.</p>
<p>&#8220;Look,&#8221; my son said. &#8220;A robot looking up at the universe.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Very nice,&#8221;  I replied.</p>
<p>&#8220;Don&#8217;t you want to see what I drew?&#8221; asked my daughter, pushing aside the salad plate to reveal a house, watched over by a small black dog with angel wings and a triumphant angel choir.</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh,&#8221; I said, and started crying, just as the solicitous waiter appeared with more garlic bread.</p>
<p>My daughter, thinking I didn&#8217;t like her work, started crying too, and as the waiter tried to carefully place the food around the table and pretend he wasn&#8217;t hearing anything, my son went back to work on his bit.</p>
<p>&#8220;Check out the constellation,&#8221; he said, &#8220;I made Sirius.&#8221; A big dog, outlined in stars. Soon, the entire table was covered in memorial drawings and soggy wet paper.</p>
<p>The manager was most distressed at the fact that our family seemed to be having difficulty enjoying the meal. &#8220;Is the spinach not to your liking?&#8221; she asked in a worried manner, rubbing her hands together.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s fine,&#8221; my husband replied. &#8220;Can I get another glass of wine?&#8221;</p>
<p>Sitting in a restaurant with the waxy proof of your children&#8217;s grief staring you in the face while you try to eat is, if anyone is wondering, <em>not</em> the most effective distraction from your sadness.</p>
<p>Cookies, on the other hand, will save the day every time, and thank goodness they figured that out.</p>
<p>But yeah, next time we have to go through this- pizza it is. And for the love of God, do not <em>under any circumstances</em> rent Frankenweenie.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=-tiA_DJVfgE:1pzuYOzYwVU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=-tiA_DJVfgE:1pzuYOzYwVU:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=-tiA_DJVfgE:1pzuYOzYwVU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=-tiA_DJVfgE:1pzuYOzYwVU:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=-tiA_DJVfgE:1pzuYOzYwVU:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=-tiA_DJVfgE:1pzuYOzYwVU:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=-tiA_DJVfgE:1pzuYOzYwVU:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=-tiA_DJVfgE:1pzuYOzYwVU:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=-tiA_DJVfgE:1pzuYOzYwVU:I9og5sOYxJI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/tip-number-one-in-the-grieving-process-get-takeout/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Please God, let me go with my face in a plate of chocolate chip ice cream</title>
		<link>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/please-god-let-me-go-with-my-face-in-a-plate-of-chocolate-chip-ice-cream/</link>
		<comments>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/please-god-let-me-go-with-my-face-in-a-plate-of-chocolate-chip-ice-cream/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. V</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cancer sucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Picks of the Litter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer sucks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kekoa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saying goodbye]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pawcurious.com/?p=16815</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Friday things were getting bad, Kekoa&#8217;s leg was aching. So you know, it&#8217;s time to go, But not without some bacon.   Saturday was super great, All day long we ate and ate, Venison, rabbit, gator too, All day feasting through and through. &#160; And when Sunday came around, Gray and rainy, under cloud, I [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Friday things were getting bad,</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Kekoa&#8217;s leg was aching.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">So you know, it&#8217;s time to go,</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">But not without some bacon.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <a href="http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/please-god-let-me-go-with-my-face-in-a-plate-of-chocolate-chip-ice-cream/photo-feb-10-9-22-58-am/" rel="attachment wp-att-16826"><img class="wp-image-16826 aligncenter" title="Photo Feb 10, 9 22 58 AM" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Photo-Feb-10-9-22-58-AM-e1360533960833-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" width="461" height="614" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Saturday was super great,</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">All day long we ate and ate,</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Venison, rabbit, gator too,</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">All day feasting through and through.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">And when Sunday came around,</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Gray and rainy, under cloud,</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">I sat down and then I cried,</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Cause it was time to say goodbye.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">When the doctor gave the shot,</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">My dear dog, she felt it not</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Because she had &#8211; don&#8217;t get me wrong-</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">In her paws, a treat filled Kong.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">As she slipped away to dream,</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">She was slurping down ice cream.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Chocolate chip with bacon too.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">When I go, I want that too.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <a href="http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/please-god-let-me-go-with-my-face-in-a-plate-of-chocolate-chip-ice-cream/photo-feb-10-10-25-09-am/" rel="attachment wp-att-16827"><img class=" wp-image-16827 aligncenter" title="Photo Feb 10, 10 25 09 AM" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Photo-Feb-10-10-25-09-AM-e1360534036154-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" width="461" height="614" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">I am sad and I will cry.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">No one wants their dog to die.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">But this gift I had to give-</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Before she died, she really lived.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/please-god-let-me-go-with-my-face-in-a-plate-of-chocolate-chip-ice-cream/k32c4152/" rel="attachment wp-att-16818"><img class="size-full wp-image-16818 aligncenter" title="Koa" src="http://pawcurious.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/K32C4152.jpg" alt="" width="635" height="424" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Sweet Koa, in our family for <a href="http://pawcurious.com/2010/02/rescue-stories/">three wonderful years</a>, in our hearts forever.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Feb 10, 2013</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=UwQI0743P1g:hdoPALp5Dp8:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=UwQI0743P1g:hdoPALp5Dp8:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=UwQI0743P1g:hdoPALp5Dp8:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=UwQI0743P1g:hdoPALp5Dp8:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=UwQI0743P1g:hdoPALp5Dp8:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=UwQI0743P1g:hdoPALp5Dp8:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=UwQI0743P1g:hdoPALp5Dp8:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=UwQI0743P1g:hdoPALp5Dp8:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=UwQI0743P1g:hdoPALp5Dp8:I9og5sOYxJI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/please-god-let-me-go-with-my-face-in-a-plate-of-chocolate-chip-ice-cream/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>80</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buckets of food: GATOR!</title>
		<link>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/buckets-of-food-gator/</link>
		<comments>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/buckets-of-food-gator/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 08:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. V</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alligator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biscuits by Lambchop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bucket list]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckets of food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kekoa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pawcurious.com/?p=16799</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I haven&#8217;t been posting about Kekoa&#8217;s culinary adventures every day, but trust me, she has turned into a regular Anthony Bourdain. When I first said I was doing this Foodie Bucket List for her, my good friend Annette at Biscuits by Lambchop decided to do something very special for us, and I wanted to share [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I haven&#8217;t been posting about Kekoa&#8217;s culinary adventures every day, but trust me, she has turned into a regular Anthony Bourdain. When I first said I was doing this Foodie Bucket List for her, my good friend Annette at <a href="http://biscuitsbylambchop.com/">Biscuits by Lambchop</a> decided to do something very special for us, and I wanted to share it with you all:</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/gEzXfVGrMeU" frameborder="0" width="640" height="360"></iframe></p>
<p>It really meant a lot to both of us that you did that. Thank you Annette. <img src='http://pawcurious.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif' alt=':D' class='wp-smiley' />  And they smelled really good, too.</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=UsPt_nhjiho:ZiPtrk6a0io:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=UsPt_nhjiho:ZiPtrk6a0io:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=UsPt_nhjiho:ZiPtrk6a0io:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=UsPt_nhjiho:ZiPtrk6a0io:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=UsPt_nhjiho:ZiPtrk6a0io:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=UsPt_nhjiho:ZiPtrk6a0io:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?i=UsPt_nhjiho:ZiPtrk6a0io:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=UsPt_nhjiho:ZiPtrk6a0io:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?a=UsPt_nhjiho:ZiPtrk6a0io:I9og5sOYxJI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Pawcurious?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"></img></a>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pawcurious.com/2013/02/buckets-of-food-gator/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
