<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0"><channel xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><title>Band Back Together</title><link>http://bandbacktogether.com/feed/</link><description>A contributing community group blog of support.</description><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright (c) 2011, Band Back Together Project</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BandBackTogether" /><feedburner:info uri="bandbacktogether" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>BandBackTogether</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item><title>How To Take Care Of Yourself When The World Seems So Messed Up</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/BDRD0p2C_uo/</link><description>Self care is important when dealing with the troubling events in our world.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3799/</guid><category>Things That Suck</category><category>Violence</category><category>Shock</category><category>How To Cope With Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder</category><category>Help With Trauma</category><category>Project Self-Care</category><category>With The Band</category><category>Grief</category><category>Loss</category><category>Anxiety</category><category>Post Traumatic Stress Disorder</category><category>Feelings</category><category>Anger</category><category>Fear</category><category>Sadness</category><category>Trauma</category><category>Emotional Shock</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something awful happened yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suddenly looking through my Facebook and Twitter feeds I found out that there had been several explosions at the Boston Marathon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explosions. Injuries. Fatalities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfathomable situations to consider.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="vertical-align: middle;" src="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/04/Prayers_For_Boston.jpg" alt="Prayers for Boston" width="640" height="280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social media is incredibly informative. We learn news in the blink of an eye, but just as quickly we can receive misinformation and find ourselves giving out incorrect details because we want to share and we want to help.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social media can also be terribly triggering when it comes to disasters such as these. Sometimes we cannot handle what is happening in the world. Stories such as this horrible tragedy in Boston trigger dark thoughts for many of us. We get stuck in that mindset and can't push it down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are perfectly normal reactions to a tragedy such as this one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;But it's also totally okay to WALK AWAY.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We want to remind you that it is perfectly acceptable and often REQUIRED to walk away from the news stories.&lt;/strong&gt; YOU are most important here. Yes, it's a horrible thing. Terrible. Emotional. Anxiety-provoking. But you need to know that if you are overwhelmed with the news you do not need to watch it, read it or listen to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don't look for it. You'll hear it all eventually. It's not critical for you to know immediately what is happening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nobody will judge you for not participating. Nobody will ask you if you watched the Anderson Cooper show or read the latest AP News information. There will be no quiz here.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social media IS amazing. But sometimes people just jump feet first without actually thinking or researching. And pictures that do not need to be seen get tossed about. Horrible. What for? Nobody needs to see that. Especially you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are a parent, you are probably protecting your child(ren) from these things. There's no harm in protecting yourself, as well. I would recommend you do it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I remind you, because I know that in times like these we often forget, that taking care of you is most important here. Avoid triggers. Close the laptop. Take a walk. Play with your kids. Eat something chocolatey. Dance around your living room. Sing your favorite song. Buy yourself a fancy coffee. Cry if you think it will help. But don't hole yourself up with the footage. It's not healthy and it's not necessary. Because we want you to take care of you. We want you to remain safe. And we want to help keep you that way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself looking for answers or resources, please consider reviewing some of these Band Back Together resource pages. And if you need to, reach out. We're here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="PTSD Resources" href="../../../../ptsd-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Trauma Resources" href="../../../../trauma-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;Trauma Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Fear Resources" href="../../../../fear-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;Fear Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Emotional Shock Resources" href="../../../../emotional-shock-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;Emotional Shock Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Anxiety Resources" href="../../../../anxiety-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;Anxiety Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We, The Band, keep the people of Boston in our hearts today and in the coming days as they face the aftermath of these horrible events.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3799/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Dose Of Happy: With The Band</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/qjm_PIQH8RI/</link><description>Getting to meet a coworker made her happy this week.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3798/</guid><category>A Dose of Happy</category><category>Friendships</category><category>With The Band</category><category>Happiness</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/02/Dose_Of_Happy_Monday.jpg"&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/02/Dose_Of_Happy_Monday.jpg" alt="" width="337" height="174" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;textarea id="textarea" style="height: 150px; width: 150px; margin-top: 10px;" readonly="readonly"&gt;&amp;lt;a href="http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3798//"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/02/Dose_Of_Happy_Monday.jpg"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Last week was really special for me. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been With The Band for more than a year now but I&amp;rsquo;ve never gotten a chance to meet any of my Bandmates in real life. That changed last week when I got to meet Fallah, one of my fellow Team Leads, while she was in town for work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img style="vertical-align: middle;" src="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/04/FallahNatalie.jpg" alt="" width="424" height="450" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;We had such a good time! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We went to the Riverwalk and ate at a British pub that actually had a vegetarian menu, and discovered the joy that is curry mayo. I was nervous about meeting her, but we got on like a house on fire.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;I hope that sometime this year I&amp;rsquo;ll get to meet more of my Bandmates because I just know we&amp;rsquo;ll have fun together too. I also hope I can figure out how to make that curry mayo because it was a happy all on its own.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;**************************&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;What's your Happy?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don't think you have one? Look harder. Something will make you smile today.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We want to know!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Share it with the world on your blog and then link up below, tweet it out (hashtag #DOHMonday #WithTheBand) or share it on Facebook. Whatever you want to do, do it. Just find a bit of happy in this Monday!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src="http://www.simply-linked.com/listwidget.aspx?l=40df419f-8a6f-4e31-bb07-d87ad08a36da" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3798/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Take Back The Power: Because I Am You</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/_7RcVRmHcZ0/</link><description>She shares how she took back the power in her life.</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3789/</guid><category>Relationships</category><category>Friendships</category><category>Take Back The Power</category><category>Anxiety</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most  of us, well, we've been through some garbage in our lives - and  we've  given power to a lot of people who simply don't deserve it. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;April is &lt;a href="../../../../How-To-Help-Someone-Heal-From-Sexual-Assault/" target="_blank"&gt;Sexual Assault Awareness Month&lt;/a&gt;. We here at Band Back Together  are shining the spotlight on ALL survivors. Depression, Abuse, Trauma.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's time to take back the power.&amp;nbsp;Tell us how YOU have taken the power back in your life!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone always says, "You are your own worst critic. You are your own worst enemy." I suppose this is quite true. For as long as I can remember, I've been harder on myself than anyone else has ever been.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking back on some of my past thoughts and actions as an objective third party is easier than looking back and seeing that person as myself. Putting that distance between the "main character" and myself helps me see how I hurt other people, but it really makes me see how much I really hurt myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've always known how I look, or at least how I &lt;em&gt;think &lt;/em&gt;I look - what I see in the mirror has never been close to what other people see. I wore baggy clothes while trying to blend in with the walls. I let my anxieties control me. Thoughts of never being smart enough or pretty enough or [fill in the blank] enough consumed me. I can't say that I never had thoughts of the world being a better place without me in it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm not speaking of things from my adolescent years. I'm speaking of things from my adult years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those thoughts and &lt;a title="Anxiety Resources" href="../../../../anxiety-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;anxieties&lt;/a&gt; are what kept me bouncing from guy to guy, almost all of whom were liars, &lt;a title="Infidelity Resources" href="../../../../infidelity-relationships/" target="_blank"&gt;cheaters&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a title="Abuse Resources" href="../../../../abuse/" target="_blank"&gt;abusers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I let myself take my own power. I let those relationships take my power. Until one day when I had a conversation with a concerned friend: "Do you really think I don&amp;rsquo;t know you? I know everything about you. I know you because I am you. I have been where you are."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her words are what helped me finally break the cycle of negative thoughts and actions; it is because of her words that I was finally able to be enough and strong on my own as a woman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has taken quite some time, and I'm still working on it. But I have taken my power back from my anxieties and thoughts. I have taken my power back from those who would use it to hurt me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3789/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Some Mom...</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/u-SsJLvBNBw/</link><description>She doesn't believe she's a good mother.</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3794/</guid><category>Parenting</category><category>Self-Image</category><category>Self Esteem</category><category>Suicide</category><category>Self-Loathing</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some mom I am...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am the worst kind of &lt;a title="Parenting Resources" href="../../../../parenting-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;mother&lt;/a&gt;. I have given up on life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;How many times have I &lt;a title="Suicide Resources" href="../../../../suicide-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;tried to end it&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;One is too many. But three times was not enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Third time was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;the charm...)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, I am just content for survival's sake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just content. Not happy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I do things simply because I have to. Because it's what's best&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my family.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I justify, I explain, I&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have simply settled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because I know I am nothing now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm no example. No role model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't even pray anymore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I simply don't know what else to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am not the mom I want to be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not the mom they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some mom I am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3794/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Ask The Band: When Does Being Sober Get Easier?</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/bke2Zs8orGQ/</link><description>She's struggling to stay sober and is asking The Band for help.</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3795/</guid><category>Parenting</category><category>Help With Addiction</category><category>Ask The Band</category><category>Addiction</category><category>Alcoholism</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here at The Band, we believe in kicking stigmas to the curb,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title="Glitter Flinging Resources" href="../../../../flings-glitter-resource-page/" target="_blank"&gt;flinging glitter&lt;/a&gt;, and shining a light into the dark. And now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your bandmate needs a sounding board.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's time to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title="Ask The Band Category" href="../../../../category/ask-the-band/" target="_blank"&gt;Ask The Band!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Alcoholism" href="../../../../alcoholism-resources-2/" target="_blank"&gt;I quit drinking seven months ago&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actually, it was 217 days ago if you want to get specific.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wasn't a fall down drunk all the time. I reserved my drinking for the evenings and the weekends. I usually waited until my child was in bed. I usually drank with other people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I graduated both high school and college with honors, all while drinking. People knew I attended classes hungover but no one ever said &lt;a title="Addiction" href="../../../../addiction-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;I had a problem&lt;/a&gt;. I have successfully held down jobs all while drinking. I had more than my fair share of liquid lunches and still managed to not get fired. My happy hours after work went on too long and by sheer luck I never hurt myself or someone else or had a run in with the law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I stopped drinking when I found out I was &lt;a title="Pregnancy" href="../../../../pregnancy-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;pregnant&lt;/a&gt;. As soon as I was done nursing I started drinking again. I was sober for about a year. Aside of that year, I hadn't been sober that long since I was 14 years old.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last summer, I made a complete ass of myself with my drinking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took risks I shouldn't have. I drank alone often. Most mornings I'd think about how long it would be until I could drink again. I'd wonder if I could drink during the day and be okay to pick my son up from day care. I came dangerously close to drinking at lunch. I arranged sitters so that I could drink to excess and not have to worry about parenting getting in the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started to scare myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought about drinking and wanted to be drunk all the time. The only thing that stopped me is the shame of everyone finding out that I'm an alcoholic. I can barely type those words; I have yet to say them out loud to anyone. But it is who I am and it was getting really hard to keep hiding it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Recovery" href="../../../../recovery-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;So I quit drinking&lt;/a&gt;. Cold turkey. Just like that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I miss it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I miss being drunk. I don't know if I can do this for the rest of my life. I want to drink so badly tonight it hurts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't know how to live sober.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm afraid to tell people just how bad my drinking was because they will think I'm a &lt;a title="Single Parenting" href="../../../../single-parenting-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;bad mother&lt;/a&gt;, a bad person. Or they won't believe me because I seem put together. Or &lt;a title="Loving An Addict" href="../../../../loving-an-addict-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;I'll be held accountable&lt;/a&gt; and be judged if I slip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Substance Abuse Relapse" href="../../../../substance-abuse-relapse-resources-2/" target="_blank"&gt;And I really, really feel like I'm going to slip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought I'd be less scared of myself if I got sober.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why am I still so scared?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When is this going to get easier?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3795/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Life Is Better</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/7Qbw9Q0R3YM/</link><description>We ask what makes your life better.</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3796/</guid><category>With The Band</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="vertical-align: middle;" src="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/04/Life_Is_Better_When_.jpg" alt="Life Is Better When I" width="640" height="415" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;My life is better when I take time for myself. I notice the difference when I get that time and when I don't.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Big things. Little things. &lt;strong&gt;What makes your life better?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3796/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Take Back The Power: I'm A Survivor</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/oLuamECAj-0/</link><description>She has taken back the power from the man who raped her.</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3791/</guid><category>Intimate Partner Rape</category><category>Rape/Sexual Assault</category><category>How To Cope With Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder</category><category>Love</category><category>Survivor</category><category>Take Back The Power</category><category>Post Traumatic Stress Disorder</category><category>Trauma</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most  of us, well, we've been through some garbage in our lives - and  we've  given power to a lot of people who simply don't deserve it. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;April is &lt;a href="../../../../How-To-Help-Someone-Heal-From-Sexual-Assault/" target="_blank"&gt;Sexual Assault Awareness Month&lt;/a&gt;. We here at Band Back Together  are shining the spotlight on ALL survivors. Depression, Abuse, Trauma.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's time to take back the power.&amp;nbsp;Tell us how YOU have taken the power back in your life!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;April is Sexual&amp;nbsp;Assault&amp;nbsp;Awareness Month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a survivor, April is the month I join with others to spread awareness and education. I firmly believe that not only do we need to teach our girls to be strong and show them the signs to recognize an unhealthy relationship, but we also need to raise our young men to treat everyone with respect. If we can do this, we can raise young people that have healthy relationships and who respect each other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, I wrote about&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title="How Had She Gotten Here?" href="../../../../post/3495/" target="_blank"&gt;my intimate partner rape&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;I also wrote about&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title="Recover, Healing, Survival" href="../../../../post/3528/" target="_blank"&gt;learning to be a survivor&lt;/a&gt;. These two stories are important pieces of me. Even more important is this story of how to survive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="Rape/Sexual Assault Resources" href="../../../../rape-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;Rape&lt;/a&gt;, in any form, leaves scars. Those scars will never go away, though with time they will fade. Like any &lt;a title="Trauma Resources" href="../../../../trauma-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;trauma&lt;/a&gt;, rape can cause the survivor to struggle with &lt;a title="PTSD Resources" href="../../../../ptsd-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;PTSD&lt;/a&gt;. Triggers and flashbacks are a very real likelihood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the years right after I left my &lt;a title="Intimate Partner Rape Resources" href="../../../../intimate-partner-rape-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;abuser,&lt;/a&gt; I had frequent flashbacks. It seemed everything was a trigger. A green semi truck on the road, men who walked or talked a certain way, a song on the radio, even certain foods or restaurants. I struggled each time something triggered me. It would take all my strength to stand my ground and not go running.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over time, some of these triggers have faded. The flashbacks are less frequent. So infrequent, actually, that it takes me a few moments to recognize them for what they are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week while napping with my fiance, something triggered me. Whether it was the feel of a rough sheet under my cheek or the way the air brushed my hair across my face, I don't know. All of a sudden, it was a different voice whispering &amp;ldquo;I love you&amp;rdquo; in my ear, it was a different hand that rested on my hip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I froze.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the memory faded, and I could once again see the here and now, I was left near tears. My fiance held me as I tried to make sense of what had just happened. And as he rubbed my back, all of a sudden, it didn't matter. I realized those flashbacks only had power if I gave it to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="vertical-align: middle;" src="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/04/I_Am_A_Survivor.jpg" alt="I Am A Survivor" width="640" height="150" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am a survivor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have overcome so much, surely I will not allow a bad memory to bring me to my knees. I have someone who truly loves me now, who will never hurt me. His love and understanding give me strength to stand up to those memories of my past and shove them away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have the power over how I allow my past to affect me. And I refuse to allow my abuser to have any place in my life, not even in my mind. He is nothing and he no longer has any power over me. This is part of my path of healing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am in charge of me. I've taken back the power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3791/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Sound-Check Wednesday - April 10, 2013</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/RO_9AwF6FOg/</link><description>SuperTeala is checking in with The Band in the Sound-Check Wednesday post.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3793/</guid><category>Sound Check </category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh! It's Wednesday. That means it's time for...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/02/Sound_Check_Wednesday_1.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="userContent"&gt;We all have a story to share. Maybe it's  something no one knows about you that you'd rather keep anonymous but  you feel a need to share it - here, you can post anonymously. Maybe it's  something you want to share so that you don't feel quite s&lt;span class="text_exposed_show"&gt;o alone in your journey - that's what sharing your story and leaving comments are for.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In April, we're focusing on our Take Back The Power World Tour topic. Because why?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Most of us, well, we've been through some garbage in our lives - and we've given power to a lot of people who simply don't deserve it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;April is&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="../../../../How-To-Help-Someone-Heal-From-Sexual-Assault/" target="_blank"&gt;Sexual Assault Awareness Month&lt;/a&gt;. We here at Band Back Together are shining the spotlight on ALL survivors. Depression, Abuse, Trauma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;It's time to take back the power.&amp;nbsp;Tell us how YOU have taken the power back in your life!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps that's not really your cup of tea. We always welcome posts from older World Tours. &lt;a href="../../../../category/i-am-me/" target="_blank"&gt;The I Am Me Project&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a great one; it helped me tap into my core and to accept myself as a whole. &lt;a href="../../../../category/letter-i-cant-send/" target="_blank"&gt;A Letter I Can't Send&lt;/a&gt; is a way to let out those words that you just can't say to someone. In&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="../../../../category/a-letter-to-my-younger-self/" target="_blank"&gt;A Letter To My Younger Self&lt;/a&gt;, you could write the words you needed to hear or give your younger self advice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;What else might work?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, almost anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Where do you find your power? How do you use it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;Are you where you want to be in your life? In your career? In your relationships? In the world?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;If not, why not?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;If you are, how did you get there?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;What was your very first date like?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;What makes you happiest?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;What is your most favorite memory?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Share your stories in this place without fear of being stigmatized or ridiculed.&amp;nbsp;Band Back Together is a place where we can come to find support and resources. Come share your story with us in this warm, supportive place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;------------&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you like to volunteer? You should totally volunteer and get With The Band!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know would like to volunteer with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="../../../../brains-band/" target="_blank"&gt;Brains Behind The Band&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;email volunteer@bandbacktogether.com.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;------------&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let us know if you have questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For technical (site related, password, etc) questions, email teala@bandbacktogether.com.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anything else can be sent to bandbacktogether@gmail.com, and we'll make sure to get your question in front of the right eyes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;------------&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Band is everywhere:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Follow us on Twitter&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/bandback2gether" target="_blank"&gt;@bandback2gether&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and our behind-the-scenes account&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/BrainsofBB2G" target="_blank"&gt;@BrainsofBB2G&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re also on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/b/104232050024052727774/104232050024052727774/posts" target="_blank"&gt;Google Plus&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://bandbacktogether.tumblr.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/bandback2gether" target="_blank"&gt;The Facebook&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/company/band-back-together?trk=hb_tab_compy_id_2120610" target="_blank"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/bandback2gether/" target="_blank"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Band has a new&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/106979540267623889962" target="_blank"&gt;community of GooglePlus&lt;/a&gt;. Join us because you're rad!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;------------&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;And now, I'm off to write a post of my very own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3793/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Little Cabin In The Winter Woods</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/IEUB9aPpXw4/</link><description>She shares a memory of her childhood sexual assault in the hopes that other survivors will know they are not alone.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3787/</guid><category>Abuse</category><category>Child Abuse</category><category>Child Sexual Abuse</category><category>Rape/Sexual Assault</category><category>Adult Children of Childhood Sexual Abuse</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One in five girls is a victim of child sexual abuse, leaving scars that will last a lifetime.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is her story.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;One winter when I was ten, under the guise of a group father-daughter weekend camp out, my Dad took me to a secluded cabin in the woods. It was beautiful there. Snow, pine trees and a frozen lake were right there outside the windows of the cabin. But inside there was nothing but hell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;By this time my Father had been &lt;a title="Child Sexual Abuse Resources" href="../../../../incest-child-sexual-abuse/" target="_blank"&gt;abusing&lt;/a&gt; me for about seven years so I knew what was in store, even though I wished I could be such a good girl he wouldn't assault me this time. In the past though, it was single encounters; one &lt;a title="Rape/Sexual Assault Resources" href="../../../../rape-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;rape&lt;/a&gt;, one act of sodomy or one forced act of oral sex committed in the middle of the night in my bed or in the tent on a camping trip. Then I would have sweet peace until the next time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;This time it was an entire weekend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;Repeated violations for hours and hours. And I didn't have my primary coping tool with me. At home I had drawn crayon pictures above my bed so when my Father came into my room I would fly up into them and escape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;Here, there were no crayon pictures, no means of escape as I didn't yet have the tools to dissociate without the help of those pictures. I was fully present for all he did, something I hadn't been for years. That is, I think, the primary reason why this weekend was so damaging, and why the memories of it visit me so often.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;I don't remember sleeping. The pain and &lt;a title="Fear Resources" href="../../../../fear-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;fear&lt;/a&gt; were too significant. But I do remember lying on a sleeping bag in the dark night staring at the fire in the fireplace while my Father slept next to me. I recall begging the fire to envelop me and take me away. But it did not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;That weekend was the most frightening time in all the years my Father assaulted me. And it was also the most confusing. I wanted him to love me so badly. I craved the love of a Father who would accept and care for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;He said all the right words. He told me he loved me. He told me I was his special little girl and that I was such a good, good girl. That made me very happy. But at the same time he hurt me, excruciatingly so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;My mind couldn't make sense of it except to determine I was a bad girl who wasn't appreciative of her Father's affections. It was a weekend of profoundly felt pain&amp;mdash;both physical and emotional. The emotional was the worst because I felt like a failure. I came home an even more broken little girl than I left, hard to imagine given what I had endured the seven years before, but incredibly true.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;&lt;img style="vertical-align: middle;" src="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/04/Know_You_Are_Not_Alone.jpg" alt="Know You Are Not Alone" width="640" height="471" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;Why am I sharing this memory? For two reasons. The first reason I share my story, in the details that I did, is to educate all of those people who tell sexual assault &lt;a title="Adult Survivors of Childhood Sexual Abuse Resources" href="../../../../adult-survivor-sexual-abuse-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;survivors&lt;/a&gt; to &amp;ldquo;Just get over it.&amp;rdquo; I would be rich if I had a nickel for every time someone told me that. &amp;ldquo;It happened so long ago, why can't you just put it behind you?&amp;rdquo; Read my story, people who think I am faulty in my processing of the sexual assault.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;Put yourself in my shoes&amp;mdash;just for that one weekend, knowing it was only one weekend in eight years of assault for me. I challenge you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;Imagine the rape, the sodomy, the forced oral sex as if you were a ten year old little girl who wanted nothing more than to please her father and earn his love. Feel the pain, the confusion, the shame, the helplessness and the hopelessness. Focus on it for 24 hours, the amount of time I had to endure it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;Now, just get over it&amp;mdash;in a finger snap, just like that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;Second, I want those who have suffered sexual assault to know they are not alone. One of the most horrible aftereffects of being sexually assaulted is that as victims we feel so &lt;a title="Social Isolation Resources" href="../../../../social-isolation-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;isolated&lt;/a&gt; and alone. Some of that is because of the &lt;a title="Shame Resources" href="../../../../shame-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;shame&lt;/a&gt; of what happened, some of it is because we look around and no one else seems to be suffering like we are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;But read my story and know YOU ARE NOT ALONE in what you've suffered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;I have been there&amp;mdash;to the depths of hell riding on the back of the devil himself. On the dark nights when all you can do is relive the memories, know you are not alone. On the days when &lt;a title="PTSD Resources" href="../../../../ptsd-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;flashbacks&lt;/a&gt; and emotional pain seem to invade every aspect of your life, know you are not alone. Others have endured what you have and we are there in the darkness with you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;Our energy is there with you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;Our &lt;a title="Love Resources" href="../../../../love-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;love&lt;/a&gt; and our strength are there with you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in;"&gt;Several times during the day you pass another one of us who have endured what you did. My worldly eyes may not see you but my spirit sees you. And as we pass I send out love, strength and acceptance. &amp;ldquo;You are known&amp;rdquo;, my spirit tells yours. &amp;ldquo;You are loved. You are worthy. &lt;strong&gt;You are not alone&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3787/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Demo Tape: Reintegration Is Hard Work, Yo</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/nv41m88zMoE/</link><description>She shares her story of reintegrating into society after prison and how she adjusted to life on the outside. A Demo Tape is a mixture of a resource page and a post from someone who has been in a situation.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3784/</guid><category>Incarceration</category><category>Loved One In Jail</category><category>Reintegration To Society After Prison</category><category>Demo Tape</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;While we, at The Band, work tirelessly to bring you expert resource pages, sometimes the best advice is from someone who has been where you're standing. What follows is a mixture between a resource page and a post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; I introduce to you, The Band, a Demo Tape.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Take what you need and leave the rest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="../../../../post/3694/" target="_blank"&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="../../../../post/3730/" target="_blank"&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's face it: the odds are stacked against ex-offenders as soon as the paperwork is signed and they're dropped off at the front gate of the prison. Without assistance of some sort, the chances of &lt;a href="../../../../successful-reintegration-incarceration/" target="_blank"&gt;reintegrating into society on their own become exponentially more difficult&lt;/a&gt;. Setting aside all the challenges of trying to find a job and a place to live, paying their fines and parole fees, struggling with physical and mental health issues, and &lt;a href="../../../../Loved-One-in-Prison-Resources/" target="_blank"&gt;trying to re-establish relationships&lt;/a&gt;, ex-offenders have to heal from the actual experience of being in prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Often, people fresh out of prison do things that seem weird or random, or they have strange hang-ups about ordinary things. It's because we no longer take those things for granted, or we are learning new things, or overindulging in things we were deprived of. It&amp;rsquo;s all part of the healing process and it takes time. Eventually some of those weird, random habits will disappear, but some may not. Prison changes a person. Period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I first got out, I remember doing things that many people probably thought were crazy as hell. Sitting outside at night, just because I could (you can&amp;rsquo;t go outside at night in prison). Sunshine did that, too &amp;ndash; he&amp;rsquo;d sit out and stare at the stars for hours. I remember spinning in circles in the rain, because I had not felt rain on my skin in so long. Forcing my friends to watch hours and hours of &lt;em&gt;Blue Man Group&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Cirque de Soleil,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;What Not To Wear&lt;/em&gt; on TV, because the one TV in the prison dorm was usually playing soap operas and sports, or that movie about The Temptations (great music, but for a time I knew every damned word of the movie). I would listen to all kinds of weird new music because the detention facility had such sucky choices in radio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I got out, I was worse than OCD about my clothes. In prison, there are no high heels or cute sundresses; there is no starch or irons. I really went buck wild with the fashion choices for a while, and I was anally retentive about the laundering process and the ironing. I would make my friends take off their clothes so I could iron the wrinkles out before we went out, because A) I could iron and B) after all the wrinkled monotony, I couldn't bear wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't buy or wear white shirts to this day; in prison, whites stay white for exactly one washing. All whites in prison turn grey in about 3.2 seconds. I also will NOT wear a sports bra or any type of wireless bra. Underwire bras were forbidden in prison; I still hate sports bras with a passion. I hate orange clothes now. I love a beautiful citrus-y orange, but I won't wear it. It is too similar to the orange jumpsuits we had to wear. Horizontal stripes? Forget it. Sneakers and flip-flops (aka shower shoes)? Hell no. Heavy cotton twill (or anything polyester)? I will not put it on my body. I love pattern and will take a risk with it as long as it isn't stripes. I won't wear sweats or thermal underwear. I had to wear those garments under my prison orange clothes just to stay warm. I will walk around cold as hell before I'll wear sweats or thermal underwear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went through a phase where I only ate things that started with the letter P the first couple of weeks I was out. I don't know why, but I ate only pop-tarts, pringles, and pizza. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t like I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get those things in prison because the commissary had chips and pop-tarts, and we occasionally had pizza at meal-times; maybe it was that I could actually CHOOSE FOR MYSELF WHAT TO EAT. I also became addicted to Dr. Pepper (and later Diet Dr. Pepper) because in jail there is no soda. Sunshine said he desperately wanted a real cheeseburger first thing when he got out, and REAL pizza. Maybe the few weeks I spent eating only foods that started with the letter P isn't as random as it first seemed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen cash in so long that it was a novelty. I would hide my cash in the circuit breaker box at my loft apartment; because in jail, we&amp;rsquo;d hide our small contraband items in the electrical outlet in the cell. Speaking of electrical outlets, Sunshine spent almost a year after he got out the first time lighting his cigarettes with the electrical outlet. (It is possible to do this, trust me.) I hate when I have less than half a pack of cigarettes, and I hoard lighters. I will have to admit that I hoarded lighters well before I did time, but I would let myself get down to my last cigarette before I'd go to the store. No longer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I still have a hard time taking super long showers. We only had two minutes to shower in the &lt;a href="../../../../successful-reintegration-incarceration/" target="_blank"&gt;facility where I did my time&lt;/a&gt;. I got good at getting clean really fast. If I stay in the shower a long time now, it is because I am either so achy I can't stand it, or I am so filthy from work that I need extra time to get the dirt off me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Loud noises and bright lights are bothersome to this day. The first night in my new loft apartment, my friend Daniel and I laid on the floor in the living room, talking all night, watching headlights play across the ceiling and walls through the mini-blinds, listening to the sounds of the city. Both of us would jump out of our skins and cringe any time somebody went in or out of their apartment, because the doors were very heavy; when those heavy doors slammed and the noise echoed off of all that concrete in that wonderful building, it sounded like a cell door slamming. Sunshine said he couldn't sleep without a towel wrapped around his head for almost a year after he was released. Even at night, the lights don't go out in prisons and jails. I quit being afraid of the dark because I spent so much time in places where the lights never went out. Sunshine still gripes that the Christmas tree lights are too bright and he can't sleep, so I have to unplug our tree at night during the Christmas season. He hates it when I only close the privacy shade and leave the second layer of blinds up, he says it is too bright.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t watch movies set in prison. I just won't. Except those stupid-ass Snake Pliskin movies with Kurt Russell - because those aren't prison movies, they're doomsday apocalypse movies. I did watch &lt;em&gt;Shawshank Redemption&lt;/em&gt; once, and I could identify with Morgan Freeman's character, who, after release, had to ask his supervisor at the grocery store for permission to go to the bathroom because he just could NOT pee if he hadn't asked permission. I hate The Price is Right because the prison supplies (mattresses, pillows, uniforms, toothpaste, hygiene supplies) are "Bob Barker" brand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you just have to let freshly-released people do things that look crazy to you. It WILL pass; rain will again become a nuisance, the dark will cease being a novelty, and our diets DO eventually level back out somewhat. Give us some time to adjust to the little things, too, while we&amp;rsquo;re trying to tackle the big things. We&amp;rsquo;ve got a life to rebuild from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3784/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Ask The Band: A Start</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/GMDwA5008mE/</link><description>They ask The Band how to be able to trust again after being raped.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3783/</guid><category>Date/Acquaintance Rape</category><category>I Am The Face Of Rape</category><category>Rape/Sexual Assault</category><category>How To Help A Friend After A Rape </category><category>Ask The Band</category><category>Trust</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here at The Band, we believe in kicking stigmas to the curb,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title="Glitter Flinging Resources" href="../../../../flings-glitter-resource-page/" target="_blank"&gt;flinging glitter&lt;/a&gt;, and shining a light into the dark. And now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your bandmate needs a sounding board.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's time to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title="Ask The Band Category" href="../../../../category/ask-the-band/" target="_blank"&gt;Ask The Band!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;My name is Eddie and I'm a &lt;a title="Rape/Sexual Assault Resources" href="../../../../rape-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;rape victim&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been having a hard time  sorting things out in my head. I guess the hardest thing I am dealing  with is being able to &lt;a title="Trust Resources" href="../../../../trust-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;trust&lt;/a&gt; a friend again. Mainly because the only true &lt;a title="How to Help Someone Heal from Sexual Assault" href="../../../../How-To-Help-Someone-Heal-From-Sexual-Assault/" target="_blank"&gt;friend&lt;/a&gt; I had is now the reason I've stumbled across this site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do I learn to trust again, The Band?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3783/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Dose Of Happy: Survivors</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/XAhJ1JGQs6I/</link><description>Survivors taking back the power in their lives is her dose of happy today.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3792/</guid><category>Rape/Sexual Assault</category><category>A Dose of Happy</category><category>Survivor</category><category>Take Back The Power</category><category>Happiness</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/02/Dose_Of_Happy_Monday.jpg"&gt;&lt;img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/02/Dose_Of_Happy_Monday.jpg" alt="" width="337" height="174" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;textarea id="textarea" style="height: 150px; width: 150px; margin-top: 10px;" readonly="readonly"&gt;&amp;lt;a href="http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3792//"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/02/Dose_Of_Happy_Monday.jpg"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;April is Sexual Assault Awareness Month and we here at Band Back Together are celebrating survivors who are taking back the power in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Why is this my happy?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Because I am also a survivor. And through my work with The Band, I've met fellow survivors who share their strength with me each and every day. Alone? I may just be one person. Together? We're a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;One survivor speaking out is a powerful, glorious thing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;All of us speaking together?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;We're turning heads. Changing the world. Saving lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;And what could be happier than that?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;**************************&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;What's your Happy?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don't think you have one? Look harder. Something will make you smile today.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We want to know!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Share it with the world on your blog and then link up below, tweet it out (hashtag #DOHMonday #WithTheBand) or share it on Facebook. Whatever you want to do, do it. Just find a bit of happy in this Monday!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src="http://www.simply-linked.com/listwidget.aspx?l=93b000d3-b332-45df-8db9-e6203e5c274c" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3792/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Ask The Band: Emotionally Abusive Relationship?</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/OlOafsVtuf4/</link><description>She asks The Band if her recent relationship was abusive.</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3778/</guid><category>Abuse</category><category>Domestic Abuse</category><category>Emotional Abuse</category><category>Breakups</category><category>Heartbreak</category><category>Relationships</category><category>Help With Domestic Abuse</category><category>How To Cope With Domestic Abuse</category><category>Ask The Band</category><category>Love</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here at The Band, we believe in kicking stigmas to the curb,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title="Glitter Flinging Resources" href="../../../../flings-glitter-resource-page/" target="_blank"&gt;flinging glitter&lt;/a&gt;, and shining a light into the dark. And now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your bandmate needs a sounding board.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: right;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's time to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title="Ask The Band Category" href="../../../../category/ask-the-band/" target="_blank"&gt;Ask The Band!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I sincerely hope you will take time to read my story. I hope you can give me some help or advice. I am completely heartbroken. I'm feeling worthless and &lt;a title="Loneliness Resources" href="../../../../loneliness-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;lonely&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When my boyfriend (let's call him Steve) and I met for the first time I was not ready for a &lt;a title="Romantic Relationship Resources" href="../../../../romantic-relationship-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;relationship&lt;/a&gt;. I was at a point in my life where I was completely happy alone and I wanted to stay that way. I also thought he was &lt;a title="Substance Abuse Resources" href="../../../../substance-abuse-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;doing drugs&lt;/a&gt; on weekends and was a dealer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, I thought he was beautiful and that I could get to know him. We would be friends with benefits but nothing more. I would not let myself be emotionally attached to him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We met twice and he was wonderful, not what I had expected. He was so much fun and cute. The third time, we slept together. Soon afterward, I got drunk while out with a friend and had a one-night stand that I didn't tell him about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were sleeping together for a couple of months. I was in denial that I wasn't in love with him, but I really was and I knew he loved me too. We kept "just sleeping together," but we also did many things that couples do. We officially started our relationship seven months after we met for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few months afterward, he asked me if I had had a one-night stand and I told him yes, it had happened a few months before we met. A couple of months later, I could not bear to hold the truth in any longer. I felt like if he would &lt;a title="Forgiveness Resources" href="../../../../forgiveness-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;forgive&lt;/a&gt; me and accept me for what I did, we were meant to be together and would be able to conquer all. If not then maybe we should not be together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I decided to tell him what had been on my mind for so long. I told him the truth that it had happened after we (Steve and I) had met three times and slept together once. He flipped. He said at first that he could not be with me anymore but he would think about it. When we talked together the next day we decided to make it work.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four months after I told him he went on a weekend away with his friend to another country where he got really drunk and kissed a girl. He told me she kissed him and that he went away as soon as he figured out what had just happened. I was devastated, completely crushed. I felt betrayed by the love of my life.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided to be with him anyway because he was so sorry that he cried and told me it was a mistake. I never screamed at him once for this and never called him any names, I was just sad and cried. We stayed together and made it work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For eight months after I told him when my incident had happened &lt;a title="Emotional Abuse Resources" href="../../../../emotional-abuse-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;he called me a whore&lt;/a&gt; almost every day. Every time we fought it was because he was thinking about that incident. He told me he hated me, that I deserved nothing good, that I didn't deserve him, that he was a much better person than me, that he should be with a girl that didn't do such a thing, that I was disgusting, that I was a whore, that I should fuck off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whenever we fought about this I was scared to death. Three times he grabbed me by the neck, one time he lifted me up on the neck from the floor. Sometimes he grabbed me by the arms and shook me. Many times he held his fist up against me like he was &lt;a title="Domestic Abuse Resources" href="../../../../domestic-abuse-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;going to hit me&lt;/a&gt; but he didn't. He told me "I'm so close to fucking hitting you right now you disgusting whore." About four times he pushed me so hard I fell.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whenever I mentioned I was &lt;a title="Sadness Resources" href="../../../../sadness-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;sad&lt;/a&gt; about the incident that happened on his trip, he always managed to turn it against me. What had started with me being sad about what he did ended with him screaming and me being scared to death, holding my arms around my head in fear of him hitting me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every time after we fought I comforted him. I said everything was going to be okay and that I forgave him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was never allowed to be sad. He would scream "Why are you crying, you whore? You don't deserve to cry." I was crying because I was scared, because I was sad and felt like I was going crazy. I was also crying because I did not like remembering the one-night stand and he kept on reminding me.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two days ago &lt;a title="Relationship Breakup Resources" href="../../../../relationship-breakup-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;we split up&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;He told me he could never be with a girl that did such a thing when we had already met. He didn't care when I tried to tell him that it was the biggest mistake I ever made and that I was never going to be emotionally involved with the other man.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we split, he did not scream at me. We were just sad to be splitting. I asked him whether he thought a &lt;a title="Therapy Resources" href="../../../../therapy-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;therapist&lt;/a&gt; would help or if he could ever forgive me. He said that he thinks that a therapist wouldn't help with this, that I disgust him and he will never forgive me.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was okay with ending things with him because I had been telling myself that I deserved better, that he may have been abusing me emotionally and physically during our relationship. So now come my questions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="vertical-align: middle;" src="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/02/Ask_The_Band_3.jpg" alt="Ask The Band" width="640" height="150" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you think a therapist would have been able to fix this &lt;a title="Anger Resources" href="../../../../anger-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;anger&lt;/a&gt; and his thoughts about this incident and that it could have worked out for us?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you think I'm crazy for asking this question because I am not supposed to want to be with a guy that breaks me down, has destroyed my &lt;a title="Self-Esteem Resources" href="../../../../self-esteem-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;self-esteem&lt;/a&gt; and has complete power over me?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Was I &lt;a title="Abuse Resources" href="../../../../abuse/" target="_blank"&gt;abused&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="How to Help With Low Self-Esteem" href="../../../../how-to-help-low-self-esteem/" target="_blank"&gt;How can I fix my self-esteem&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Right now I only remember the good things and can't seem to remember the bad things. It is only when I describe this to someone that I realize that this was kind of sick. I never said anything to him when he screamed at me. I was desperate - and still kind of am - to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The people I have told say that he is not good for me and that I should be happy to be out. But why do I not feel it? Why do I only want to be with him and make it work? I am still so in love with him, even though I am not as crazy about him after all this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can you help me in any way?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3778/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Broken </title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/ej9xc85i-Ws/</link><description>She's struggling through the grieving process following the loss of her sister.</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3756/</guid><category>Help With Loss</category><category>Helping Someone Who Is Grieving</category><category>Grief</category><category>I Am The Face Of Loss</category><category>Loss</category><category>Sibling Loss</category><category>Sadness</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grief takes a different form for everyone, and coming to terms with a sibling's death can take some time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is her story.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not going to lie, &lt;a title="Grief resources" href="../../../../grief-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;grief&lt;/a&gt; is one tricky bitch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The past month has been the worst for me grief-wise. Little triggers have happened and when they do all I want to do is cry, cry, and cry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some days are better than others, I&amp;rsquo;m sure all of you know this. If I can get through the day without tears I find it a victory. However it&amp;rsquo;s not long before something reminds me of my sister and I shut down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The whole process is a total nightmare. Never in a million years did I think &lt;a title="Sibling Loss Resources" href="../../../../sibling-loss-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;losing my sister&lt;/a&gt; would make me into a broken, hot mess. I am usually - to quote Phil from Duck Dynasty - "&lt;a title="Happiness Resources" href="../../../../happiness-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;Happy, Happy, Happy&lt;/a&gt;" despite that what has happened to my family is &lt;a title="Sadness Resources" href="../../../../sadness-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;sad, sad, sad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;At church not long ago, we sang "Jesus Loves Me" during communion and for some reason it got to me. It reminded me of Jenny so I cried, which made dad cry too. Good one, Mags.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later at lunch dad told that Jenny&amp;rsquo;s main caregiver, the one who had been with her for 20 years was diagnosed with the early stages of &lt;a title="Alzheimer's Disease Resources" href="../../../../alzheimers-disease-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;. Fuck. We can&amp;rsquo;t win, can we?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following Tuesday I had choir practice and since it was nice out, I decided a quick trip to the cemetery was in order. I was concerned about the flowers I had put out since 11 inches of snow was dumped on us. The flowers were fine along with the solar light dad had gotten but the pretty pink pinwheel didn&amp;rsquo;t survive thanks to the high winds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I pulled up the pinwheel from the fresh ground, I noticed the death date plaque was put in place. Cue the waterworks. I stood there a few minutes then went to toss the pinwheel. I noticed the pieces of the pinwheel were strewn about not far from where Jenny was buried. In fact, one was near where my grandpa was buried just a few feet from Jenny. I collected them in order to try and fix them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went home and sat in the rocker that used to be in Jenny&amp;rsquo;s room and cried. I felt silly to be crying over something so ridiculous as a dollar pinwheel that can easily be fixed or replaced. I blame that time of the month for that one. I was extra emotional then. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;What triggers my emotions and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t is another funny thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A week ago I went into Jenny&amp;rsquo;s nearly empty room. I felt that heavy feeling you get when you&amp;rsquo;re sad but it quickly vanished. Later when I got home and heard a song on the radio, boom, it hit me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following Friday I was at the store when I ran into someone who once again expressed their sympathies (another thing I am tired of). Then I ran into one of Jenny&amp;rsquo;s longtime &lt;a title="Caregiver Resources" href="../../../../caregiver-resource-page/" target="_blank"&gt;caregivers&lt;/a&gt;. After we exchanged hugs and hellos she told me it gets harder and harder every day. Then she dropped an unexpected bomb on me. Jenny&amp;rsquo;s room was painted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I knew this would happen because eventually Jenny&amp;rsquo;s room would be given to another client who needs it. But to paint it so soon? After a month, when we were told to take all the time we needed? Granted, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much left but how am I to go there now and not see the cheery yellow room that was Jenny&amp;rsquo;s? It was too much. I ranted at my dad about it later because I was &lt;a title="Anger Resources" href="../../../../anger-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;angry&lt;/a&gt;, and when I got home I was exhausted again. I cried.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was told by a friend of mine that I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a title="Compassion and Empathy Resources" href="../../../../compassion-compassionate-empathy-resources/" target="_blank"&gt;empathetic&lt;/a&gt;. I feel more than most people; births, marriages, sicknesses and especially deaths have more of an effect on me. "Lucky me," I replied sarcastically. They told me it was a good trait to have and more should have it. Then how come I feel like shit and cry at the drop of a hat?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m tired of being sad, crying at any given moment. Tired of complaining to people about it when I&amp;rsquo;m sure they&amp;rsquo;re tired of me too. I used to be so strong. It took a lot to get me to cry but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll have that strength again. I heard that Dad said I was his backbone through all this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some backbone. I feel spineless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know it takes time to heal. I get that, but it just seems endless. I&amp;rsquo;ve considered going to a grief support group in April. It&amp;rsquo;ll be hard with my schedule but I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to work it out because I think it just might help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I enjoy writing on here, I&amp;rsquo;m glad there&amp;rsquo;s understanding for what I&amp;rsquo;m going through.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3756/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Where Do You Find Your Power?</title><link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/BandBackTogether/~3/YLAORYdSFCQ/</link><description>We ask where you find your power.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3781/</guid><category>With The Band</category><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="vertical-align: middle;" src="http://static.bandbacktogether.com/media/images/2013/04/Where_Do_You_Find_Your_Power.jpg" alt="Where Do You Find Your Power" width="640" height="410" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We often give power to people or things in our lives that do not deserve it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do you do when you realize you need to take your power back?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where do you find your power? How do you use it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><feedburner:origLink>http://bandbacktogether.com/post/3781/</feedburner:origLink></item></channel></rss>
