<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Americana the Beautiful</title>
	<atom:link href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://americanathebeautiful.org</link>
	<description>One state and wacky festival at a time</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 19:53:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>What I Did on my Spring Sabbatical</title>
		<link>http://americanathebeautiful.org/what-i-did-on-my-spring-sabbatical/</link>
		<comments>http://americanathebeautiful.org/what-i-did-on-my-spring-sabbatical/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 19:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Americana the Beautiful</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[channel islands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chess]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disneyland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dolphin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feeding frenzy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goofy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[it's a small world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muscle beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mussel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pelican]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[route 66]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sabbatical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa monica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sea lion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snow white]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space mountain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starfish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whale]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://americanathebeautiful.org/?p=4143</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Full-time travel is no vacation&#8211;we&#8217;ve explored this topic before. Laundry and planning and writing and chores&#8211;plus amazing immersive experiences. While incredible, I found myself over-stimulated and in need of a break. So I headed for Los Angeles&#8211;not a place folks usually think of for a rest. Therefore, why there? a campground on the beach lots [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Full-time travel is no vacation&#8211;<a title="Sabbatical from my Sabbatical" href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/sabbatical-from-my-sabbatical/" target="_blank">we&#8217;ve explored this topic before</a>. Laundry and planning and writing and chores&#8211;plus amazing immersive experiences. While incredible, I found myself over-stimulated and in need of a break.</p>
<p>So I headed for Los Angeles&#8211;not a place folks usually think of for a rest. Therefore, why there?</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">a campground on the beach</span></li>
<li>lots of friends in the city</li>
</ol>
<h3>What a Special Campground!</h3>
<p>They do excellent marketing because they neglect to share that it&#8217;s directly under the LAX flight path and downwind from an oil refinery. Sneaky. Verrry sneaky.</p>
<p>It does have a visiting sea lion. Awww. And a modest inventory of shells, which makes the ones found all the more treasured.</p>
<p>I arrived at the California coast juuuust as the sun was setting. <em>From sea to shining sea! </em>Click the pic to advance the slideshow.</p>
[[Show as slideshow]]
<h3></h3>
<h3>Sure, I&#8217;ll Watch</h3>
<p>Santa Monica is a study in contrasts. Chess players across the walkway from Muscle Beach.  The end of Route 66 adjacent to stands selling maps for Homes of the Stars and Hollywood Crimes.</p>
<p>The chess players sparked my imagination. Have the two players competed against each other before? Did they arrange to meet at a certain time? Or are they circumstantial opponents? I love that the intensely mental game is now social.</p>
<p>As for muscle beach&#8230;<br />
WHEN [on muscle beach]<br />
IF [you're an exhibitionist]<br />
THEN [I'm a voyeur]</p>
<p>This was my first venture intentionally without my camera. I felt naked, which may have been apropos for Santa Monica. So unless I&#8217;m in it, the picture is courtesy of Flickr. Click the pic to advance the slideshow.</p>
[[Show as slideshow]]
<h3></h3>
<h3>Whale Watching Trumps Seasickness&#8211;Every Time</h3>
<p>Two Dramamine are not enough. At least not for me. I endured the pitching and heaving (and that was also in the ocean, not just my stomach) with as much grace as I could muster. AKA I found a bench, laid down (layed down?), and only got up when the captain announced an animal sighting. The adrenaline lasted almost as long as we gawked at the critters, and then quickly back to my prone position. Let me just say, I don&#8217;t know why folks voluntarily have a colonic&#8211;seasickness is far less invasive.</p>
<p>Playing dolphins; a feeding frenzy when a pool of unsuspecting fish was trapped and brought to the surface for dolphins, sea lions, and birds to gorge themselves; sun bathing sea lions; and humpback whales! Holy cow! They&#8217;re fascinating, gorgeous, enormous.</p>
<p>Fun facts:</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Dolphins are playful in <em>all sorts of ways</em>&#8211;if you know what I mean, wink wink&#8211;the only other species besides humans to be so. </span></li>
<li>Humpback whales are 60 feet long, and bigger than any dinosaur. When you see their tail, it means they&#8217;re diving down for a snack&#8211;anywhere from 1-20 minutes.</li>
<li>Dolphins, sea lions, and whales are all mammals&#8211;so all that jumping and prancing we enjoy at the water&#8217;s surface is actually breathing. Plain and simple.</li>
<li>Sea lions keep warm by keeping one flipper in the air!</li>
<li>Dolphins have a complicated language of sounds, and each dolphin even has its own sound, like a name!</li>
<li>When a pelican dives to feed, it goes as fast as 40mph and as deep as 20 feet. Its mouth is bigger than its stomach, holding twice as much. Why&#8230;?</li>
</ul>
<p>Click the pic to see the slideshow. The pics are awesome because I found Flickr people who weren&#8217;t seasick!</p>
[[Show as slideshow]]
<h3></h3>
<h3>The Happiest Place on Earth?</h3>
<p>Disneyland is indeed magical, but I still assert that the happiest place is the<a title="America’s Favorite Color is Blue: Lessons from the Crayola Factory" href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/americas-favorite-color-is-blue-lessons-from-crayola/" target="_blank"> Crayola Factory</a>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s charming and full of memories you didn&#8217;t know you have. It&#8217;s a Small World brought me back to being a girl on my first visit to the Orlando location. Space Mountain is just as awesome as it was when my brother and I went on it at least two times, maybe three.</p>
<div>Disney is universal&#8211;amazing how people with such divergent styles all flock here: redneck and alternative and soccer moms all wear disney gear proudly. Click the pic to advance the slideshow.</div>
<div>[[Show as slideshow]]</div>
<div></div>
<div>In three weeks, only three excursions. Otherwise, walks on the beach, naps, discovering that they don&#8217;t exaggerate LA traffic, reading, and trifling projects.</div>
<div></div>
<div>***</div>
<div>What have you been up to?</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://americanathebeautiful.org/what-i-did-on-my-spring-sabbatical/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Folk Art with Found Objects</title>
		<link>http://americanathebeautiful.org/folk-art-with-found-objects/</link>
		<comments>http://americanathebeautiful.org/folk-art-with-found-objects/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 13:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Americana the Beautiful</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://americanathebeautiful.org/?p=4121</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While I&#8217;m on sabbatical, AKA watching back-to-back episodes of Law &#38; Order, hopefully you&#8217;ll find inspiration in this art and messages. **** Soul-Moving Folk Art in Alabama Original post June 7, 2012 I&#8217;ve never really liked Folk Art, so was surprised at myself for having two stops in one trip. Perhaps it&#8217;s their subjects, or [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I&#8217;m on <a title="Sabbatical from my Sabbatical" href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/sabbatical-from-my-sabbatical/" target="_blank">sabbatical</a>, AKA watching back-to-back episodes of Law &amp; Order, hopefully you&#8217;ll find inspiration in this art and messages.</p>
<p>****</p>
<h1>Soul-Moving Folk Art in Alabama</h1>
<p><em>Original post June 7, 2012</em></p>
<p><a href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/Joe-Minter_post.jpg"><img title="Joe Minter bowling balls" alt="Joe Minter bowling balls" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/Joe-Minter_post-1024x731.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve never really liked Folk Art, so was surprised at myself for having two stops in one trip. Perhaps it&#8217;s their subjects, or I&#8217;m evolving. Doesn&#8217;t matter. These are more than folk art; they&#8217;re history and passion (and a bit of obsession).</p>
<h3>Joe Minter&#8217;s Yard</h3>
<p>An acre-ish, abutting a cemetery. From the street it&#8217;s a cluttered mess. Actually, even from within it&#8217;s a cluttered mess. Take a breath and look at the trees within the forest, so to speak. There&#8217;s whimsey with smiley faces made of pot lids. And there&#8217;s history with replicas of slave ships.</p>
<p>Knock on the door and Joe will come out, pose for a picture, tell you a story, and leave you be. It was the best art &#8220;gallery&#8221; I&#8217;ve ever been to!</p>
<p>The majority of the work in <a title="Joe Minter's Yard" href="http://www.flavorwire.com/112231/folk-art-paradise-joe-minters-african-village-in-america" target="_blank">Joe Minter&#8217;s Yard </a>(Birmingham, AL) is about African American history. He presents it bluntly and juxtaposed with scripture passages of love and peace. Over time his work has evolved to commemorate his reactions to world events like Tsunamis and local like a district plumbing issue.</p>
<p>Walking through, it became more of a garden to me, each lesson he learned planted for others to reap. It reminded me of the <a title="Secret Life of Bees wailing wall" href="http://www.bookrags.com/essay-2005/11/3/222838/437" target="_blank">wailing wall from the book the Secret Life of Bees.</a> This is a place for him to express what pains and inspires him.</p>
<p>Watch the slideshow for a sampling of the experience.</p>
[[Show as slideshow]]
<h3>Ave Maria Grotto</h3>
<p>Who knew Monks did folk art? With shells? In Alabama? (meanwhile, who knew there were Monks in Alabama?)</p>
<p>Brother Joseph Zoettl worked on the <a title="Ave Maria Grotto" href="http://www.avemariagrotto.com/" target="_blank">Ave Maria Grotto</a> for 46 years. He built 125 miniatures of churches and Catholic monuments, as well as the Seven Wonders of the World, the Leaning Tower of Pisa…whatever caught his fancy.</p>
<p><a href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/DSC_0027.jpg"><img title="Ave Maria Grotto" alt="Ave Maria Grotto" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/DSC_0027-1024x687.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></a></p>
<p>The architectural detail is stunning. The scale and precision. And all of this without ever having visited any of these places and working only from photos for reference.</p>
<p>Then comes the whimsy. Shells from Florida, glass floats from Maine, gifts from all 50 states to incorporate into his work.</p>
<p>It was like a doll house city. A miniature city on a hillside. Not everything was to my taste, but you can’t deny the artistry and dedication.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Watch the slideshow for a sampling of the experience.</p>
<p>What kind of art do you like? Where do you think Folk Art fits within the world of &#8220;gallery art&#8221;?</p>
[[Show as slideshow]]
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://americanathebeautiful.org/folk-art-with-found-objects/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hang Gliding over the Outer Banks</title>
		<link>http://americanathebeautiful.org/hang-gliding-over-the-outer-banks/</link>
		<comments>http://americanathebeautiful.org/hang-gliding-over-the-outer-banks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 13:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Americana the Beautiful</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://americanathebeautiful.org/?p=4119</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While I&#8217;m on sabbatical, AKA working out at Muscle Beach, enjoy this old post. *** Hang Gliding when you’re Afraid of Heights Originally posted February 10, 2012 Hang gliding was amazing! I didn’t do the kind where you run off the mountain – I am afraid of falling on my face, crushing my legs on [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I&#8217;m on <a title="Sabbatical from my Sabbatical" href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/sabbatical-from-my-sabbatical/" target="_blank">sabbatical</a>, AKA working out at Muscle Beach, enjoy this old post.</p>
<p>***</p>
<h1>Hang Gliding when you’re Afraid of Heights</h1>
<p><em>Originally posted February 10, 2012</em></p>
<p>Hang gliding was amazing! I didn’t do the kind where you run off the mountain – I am afraid of falling on my face, crushing my legs on landing, and being able to fly the thing. No, I didn&#8217;t create irrational fears about this <em>at all</em>&#8230;</p>
<p>Instead I went tandem, which involves a plane.</p>
<p><strong>Forced Itimacy?</strong><br />
The instructor lays on the bottom, suspended. I step into overalls of sorts, that are cushiony and have a built in ledge for my feet. When I stretch out my feet, my while body is now suspended horizontally. I’m free floating above the instructor, so my fear of smothering him was moot.</p>
<p><strong>Up, Up, and Away</strong><br />
We’re connected to a bi-plane that takes us up to 2000 feet then disconnects the cord and we glide on our own for 15 or so minutes.</p>
<p>The ride up was easy and smooth. Just, liftoff. I squealed with joy.</p>
<p>When we disconnected from the plane there was a roller coaster dip, which was fine, but I wasn’t prepared to see the cord disappear and I screamed and then laughed and laughed from the adrenaline.</p>
<p><strong>Smooth Operator</strong><br />
He offered to let me steer the glider. I had an extreme need to hold on, so passed. There are options while in flight: tricks or smooth. I opted for smooth. Surprised?</p>
<p><strong>Earth, Sweet Earth</strong><br />
The landing was spectacularly not terrifying! I know, I should be in sales.</p>
<p>He describes it as an escalator and I told him that’s not romantic enough for something as amazing as this. We descend seven feet forward and one foot down, hence his analogy.</p>
<p>It’s MUCH smoother than a plane landing, which always makes me a bit ill. And it’s literally like floating. It’s a combination of ideal ocean waves where it’s serene and you coast over them (but not that movement, just the sensation of being suspended), and then a new feeling of literally floating in air.</p>
<p>The landing was insignificant. The glider has wheels, so no running required. No chance of a broken leg. Phew.</p>
<p><strong>Where was this Adventure?</strong><br />
Currituck in the Outer Banks of North Carolina with outfitter <a title="Kitty Hawk Kites website" href="http://reservations.kittyhawk.com/Info.aspx?EventID=+1" target="_blank">Kitty Hawk Kites.</a></p>
<p><a title="Click to see the slideshow" href="https://picasaweb.google.com/105940220298076191656/Hanggliding?feat=email#slideshow/5705435962887461634" target="_blank">Click here</a> to see the slideshow.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://americanathebeautiful.org/hang-gliding-over-the-outer-banks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Moonpie Festival</title>
		<link>http://americanathebeautiful.org/the-moonpie-festival/</link>
		<comments>http://americanathebeautiful.org/the-moonpie-festival/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 13:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Americana the Beautiful</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://americanathebeautiful.org/?p=4118</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While I&#8217;m on sabbatical, AKA reading trashy novels, enjoy this blast from the past. **** The Most Creative Festival Contests I’ve Ever Encountered Originally posted June 17, 2012 The Best Festival Ever The fine people of Bell Buckle, TN know how to throw a festival. The Moon Pie Festival was a blast! A bare-chested band who can&#8217;t [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I&#8217;m on<a title="Sabbatical from my Sabbatical" href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/sabbatical-from-my-sabbatical/" target="_blank"> sabbatical</a>, AKA reading trashy novels, enjoy this blast from the past.</p>
<p>****</p>
<h1>The Most Creative Festival Contests I’ve Ever Encountered</h1>
<p><em>Originally posted June 17, 2012</em></p>
<h3><a href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/MyPublisher-6172012-91429-PM.bmp.jpg"><img title="Moon Pie Festival signs" alt="Moon Pie Festival signs" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/MyPublisher-6172012-91429-PM.bmp.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></a></h3>
<h3>The Best Festival Ever</h3>
<p>The fine people of Bell Buckle, TN know how to throw a festival. The <a title="RC and Moonpie Festival" href="http://www.bellbucklechamber.com/" target="_blank">Moon Pie Festival</a> was a blast!</p>
<p>A bare-chested band who can&#8217;t sing performed for folks who sat on bales of hay. Members of the general public who could sing rocked it at a karaoke stand.</p>
<p>It was barely integrated, but diverse in their fried food. And all the flavors of pies&#8230; who knew you could combine them in so many disgusting ways?</p>
<p><a href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/2.jpg"><img title="Eating Moon Pies at the Moon Pie Festival" alt="Eating Moon Pies at the Moon Pie Festival" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/2-1024x731.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></a></p>
<h3>Every Town Needs a Parade</h3>
<p>&#8230;so the politicians can sit in convertibles and wave.</p>
<h3>A Match Made in Heaven?</h3>
<p>RC Cola and Moon Pies. I had no idea. I&#8217;d never had either&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/1.jpg"><img title="RC Cola at the Moon Pie Festival" alt="RC Cola at the Moon Pie Festival" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/1-1024x731.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></a></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;" align="center">The Moon Pie Toss</h3>
<p>The name really says it all. Take a pie, still in wrapper, stand in an impressively long line, and wait your turn to throw that pie as far as you can. The winner gets a ribbon the size a horse could wear. The end.</p>
<p><a href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/moon-pie-for-post-005.jpg"><img title="Moon Pie Toss" alt="Moon Pie Toss" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/moon-pie-for-post-005-1024x731.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></a></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;" align="center">Walk with an Open RC Cola on your Head</h3>
<p>Why it&#8217;s the most obvious thing to do. Open a can, balance it on your noggin, and start walking. First with one can, then the winners stack two. And then (drum roll), three! Only two people made it to the final round.</p>
<p>The concentration was intense. The cheering maniacal. And the spilled RC Cola hot and sticky.</p>
<p>Welcome South.</p>
<p><a href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/moon-pie-for-post-006.jpg"><img title="RC Cola on Your Head at the Moon Pie Festival" alt="RC Cola on Your Head at the Moon Pie Festival" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/moon-pie-for-post-006-1024x731.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></a></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;" align="center">The Hula Hoop Challenge</h3>
<p>Here&#8217;s the deal: eat a whole Moon Pie and drink an entire RC Cola &#8211; all while keeping a hula hoop in rotation. Those pies are mealy and the soda warm; it&#8217;s harder than it seems. The winner: the boy.</p>
<p><a href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/moon-pie-for-post-004.jpg"><img title="Hula Hoop Challenge at the Moon Pie Festival" alt="Hula Hoop Challenge at the Moon Pie Festival" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/moon-pie-for-post-004-1024x731.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></a></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;" align="center">Watermelon Seed Spitting Contest</h3>
<p>You&#8217;d be surprised at how many people want to spit in public. And not just in public, but on display. And then there&#8217;s the confounding factor of which projection is yours vs his.</p>
<p>Honor among seeds.</p>
<p><a href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/moon-pie-for-post-001.jpg"><img title="Watermelon Seed Spitting Contest at the Moon Pie Festival" alt="Watermelon Seed Spitting Contest at the Moon Pie Festival" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/moon-pie-for-post-001-1024x731.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></a></p>
<h3>The Largest Moon Pie</h3>
<p>You knew it was coming&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/DSC_0437_5052447263_o.jpg"><img title="Largest Moon Pie at the Moon Pie Festival" alt="Largest Moon Pie at the Moon Pie Festival" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/DSC_0437_5052447263_o-1024x683.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></a></p>
<p>Which festival have you loved the most?</p>
<p><em>Disclaimer: I went to this festival in 2010, but launched the blog in 2011, so saved the post to coincide with the 2012 festival, which was this past weekend.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://americanathebeautiful.org/the-moonpie-festival/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oh Goody: Bugs!</title>
		<link>http://americanathebeautiful.org/oh-goody-bugs/</link>
		<comments>http://americanathebeautiful.org/oh-goody-bugs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Americana the Beautiful</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://americanathebeautiful.org/?p=4115</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While I&#8217;m sabbatical, AKA shifting my sleeping patterns, enjoy this walk down memory lane. **** A Bug’s Life…Is Short When It’s Inside My Trailer Originally posted June 21, 2012 Disclaimer: if you don&#8217;t believe in killing bugs when they&#8217;re in your home, then you won&#8217;t like this post. That&#8217;s your prerogative. It&#8217;s mine to kill [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I&#8217;m <a title="Sabbatical from my Sabbatical" href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/sabbatical-from-my-sabbatical/" target="_blank">sabbatical</a>, AKA shifting my sleeping patterns, enjoy this walk down memory lane.</p>
<p>****</p>
<h1>A Bug’s Life…Is Short When It’s Inside My Trailer</h1>
<p><em>Originally posted June 21, 2012</em></p>
<p><em>Disclaimer: if you don&#8217;t believe in killing bugs when they&#8217;re in your home, then you won&#8217;t like this post. That&#8217;s your prerogative. It&#8217;s mine to kill as many as I can.</em></p>
<p>Got ready for bed, turned around and the bug exhibit from the zoo had inhabited my trailer.</p>
<p>They were miniscule, but they were still bugs. (How did they get past the bouncer?) I don&#8217;t know many species there were&#8230;perhaps ALL of them?</p>
<p>They were concentrated around the lights over the bed, which made killing them easier, but less fun for the reality of when their corpses fell. Oh yes, I channeled Bruce Willis and took on the enemy. With a vengeance.</p>
<h3>What Awful Rhythm You Have</h3>
<p>Like a drummer playing to her own beat, I hit the wall and ceiling for each and every bug. Sometimes I had to search = pause. Sometimes it was in succession = staccato. Regardless, it couldn&#8217;t have sounded good: erratic slams and tiny bug screams.</p>
<h3>The Guest List</h3>
<p>A spider was hanging from the ceiling. I am absolutely serious.</p>
<p>Black, hard-bodied #$%^% that look like a pumpernickel seed and that required me to bisect them with my nail in order to die. Good times.</p>
<p>Seemingly freshly hatched moths, according to my years of entomology study, who have superb reflexes, little buggers.</p>
<h3>You Lookin&#8217; at Me?</h3>
<p>After an obsessive amount of time ticking them off one by one, I stood back, hands on my hips and said (out loud), &#8220;Alright, who&#8217;s left?&#8221;</p>
<p>Now we came to the matter of how they got in. They were all tiny, so some gap in the screen? No fresh air tonight.</p>
<p>The next challenge: opening the screen door to get to the real door to close both&#8211;all without letting in the flock of large bugs vying for entry. Deep breath. I squirted the screen with mosquito spray and hit it with the fly swatter. That stunned them enough to get the doors closed with only one (naive) big bug getting in. As it flew past I screamed like the girl that I am and then promptly killed it.</p>
<h3>A Good Night&#8217;s Sleep?</h3>
<p>Instead of lovely nature sounds and fresh air, I slept with an air conditioner as subtle as a plane engine. At least it drowned out the frantic wing flapping of the bugs trapped between the door and screen door.</p>
<p>Plus there&#8217;s the matter of bug blood on the bed and ceiling. Blech. Thankfully not on the sheets. Guess who&#8217;s doing laundry in the morning? AND cleaning the ceiling. Have YOU ever cleaned the CEILING&#8230;?</p>
<p>Seriously, have you ever cleaned the ceiling? Why?<br />
And/or what&#8217;s your favorite bug story?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://americanathebeautiful.org/oh-goody-bugs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Videos: Living in an RV</title>
		<link>http://americanathebeautiful.org/videos-living-in-an-rv/</link>
		<comments>http://americanathebeautiful.org/videos-living-in-an-rv/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 13:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Americana the Beautiful</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://americanathebeautiful.org/?p=4114</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While I&#8217;m sabbatical, AKA doing yoga uncomfortably close to other trailers, enjoy this post from the past. ****** Living in an RV originally posted October 2, 2012 You asked, and finally I deliver. We have video upon video about towing the trailer, setting it up for travel, setting up utilities at the campground, and a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I&#8217;m<a title="Sabbatical from my Sabbatical" href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/sabbatical-from-my-sabbatical/" target="_blank"> sabbatical</a>, AKA doing yoga uncomfortably close to other trailers, enjoy this post from the past.</p>
<p>******</p>
<h1>Living in an RV</h1>
<p><em>originally posted October 2, 2012</em></p>
<p>You asked, and finally I deliver.</p>
<p>We have video upon video about towing the trailer, setting it up for travel, setting up utilities at the campground, and a tour of the space.</p>
<p>Go make some popcorn, this is going to take a while.<br />
I&#8217;ll wait. Go ahead.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re likely thinking, &#8220;How long could this really be?&#8221; Thirty minutes &#8211; seriously. It takes me nearly an hour to set up and another to pack up &#8211; for every leg of the trip. So consider yourself lucky with this abridged version. Another thing to be grateful for: while the film quality is feeble, YouTube has a magical &#8220;stabilize&#8221; button &#8211; otherwise you&#8217;d also be sea-sick.</p>
<h3>Hitching the Trailer to the SUV</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s truly incredible that 1. a single hitch tows 5,000 pounds of weight, and 2. that I can do all of these connections. At the beginning it took <em>forever</em> to undo a single clasp &#8211; now, it&#8217;s easy peasy.</p>
<p>I bought a gardening cushion, thinking I would sit on that vs the ground. Ha! A waste of money. Maybe if I encounter mud, but now I can do this without having to sit. Progress.</p>
<p>Now that it&#8217;s no longer 100 degree days, I don&#8217;t &#8220;glisten&#8221; quite as much as I did during set-up. But since I have to do this twice in one day: leaving campground A and going to campground B, I don&#8217;t shower that morning. Too much information? If you got grimy and your hands looked like a mechanic&#8217;s, you would wait, too.</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='614' height='376' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/Qgp87-_0f8I?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<h3>Bringing Civilization to Camping</h3>
<p>Each and every campsite has hookups for potable water, electricity, and plumbing. Glory be!</p>
<p>Plus you need to stabilize the trailer &#8211; think of adding training wheels to a bike. Otherwise the trailer would be a rockin&#8217; and no would come a knockin&#8217; when all you&#8217;re doing is washing dishes.</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='614' height='376' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/VuXsrLyPqCo?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p>Curious about the Mummenschanz reference? <a title="Mummenschanz" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=lPHYpiR4JuM#!" target="_blank">Watch here.</a></p>
<h3>Prepping the Trailer for Towing</h3>
<p>Stuff goes flying when on the road. Think about exits off the highway that are round. There are signs (that you likely ignore) calling for 25mph. I follow those signs now. Tipping, shifting &#8211; these are not good words.</p>
<p>Railroad tracks: I hate them. Road construction with unfinished roads: not only are they cruel to my bladder, they also make things bounce in the trailer.</p>
<p>So before a trip, batten down the hatches. After one, look to see what fell and put it away. This is why I use plastic dishes &#8211; they can&#8217;t break.</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='614' height='376' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/OpDA5ZO-Lkg?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<h3>More Room with the Touch of a Button</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s enough to tow 19 more feet; I don&#8217;t also need a &#8220;wide load&#8221; scenario. Enter the slide room. It&#8217;s compact for driving and when extended, adds much needed space.</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='614' height='376' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/9KCv7ThwwG4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<h3>Living in 184 Square Feet</h3>
<p>It feels much more spacious than that &#8211; perhaps because of the convex roof, the excellent use of storage, or pure denial.</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='614' height='376' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/OUCuRBQCFGQ?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<h3>Trailer Sweet Trailer</h3>
<p>There you have it! It&#8217;s work, but it&#8217;s worth it. You commute, I pack up to tow. You wear fancy clothes, I have the option not to shower. You live in blissful ignorance about plumbing, I am unfortunately intimate with mine.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>How does this reality fit with what you had in your imagination?<br />
Share your thoughts in the comments below.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://americanathebeautiful.org/videos-living-in-an-rv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NASCAR</title>
		<link>http://americanathebeautiful.org/nascar/</link>
		<comments>http://americanathebeautiful.org/nascar/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Americana the Beautiful</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://americanathebeautiful.org/?p=4112</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While I&#8217;m on sabbatical (AKA at the beach), enjoy this re-run. **** What&#8217;s a Jewish Girl Like You Doing in a NASCAR Place Like This? originally posted June 12, 2012 It’s mandatory to visit something NASCAR when in Charlotte. My friends who live here weren’t aware of this rule, but I gleaned it from the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I&#8217;m on <a title="Sabbatical from my Sabbatical" href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/sabbatical-from-my-sabbatical/" target="_blank">sabbatical</a> (AKA at the beach), enjoy this re-run.</p>
<p>****</p>
<h1>What&#8217;s a Jewish Girl Like You Doing in a NASCAR Place Like This?</h1>
<p><em>originally posted June 12, 2012</em></p>
<p>It’s mandatory to visit something NASCAR when in Charlotte. My friends who live here weren’t aware of this rule, but I gleaned it from the tourism website that fixated on the sport.</p>
<h3><strong>NASCAR According to Paula</strong></h3>
<p>It’s admittedly odd that I chose to spend the day exploring the <a title="NASCAR Hall of Fame" href="http://www.nascarhall.com/" target="_blank">NASCAR Hall of Fame</a> and <a title="Charlotte Motor Speedway" href="http://www.charlottemotorspeedway.com/" target="_blank">Charlotte Motor Speedway</a>.</p>
<p>First of all, because I’m interested in sports about as much as I am in cultivating roach colonies.</p>
<p>And secondly, because my understanding of NASCAR is this: people drive super fast around an oval before massive crowds. Some fans are infield, where they can’t see anything but don’t care because they’re drunk. The drivers make gobs of money because they have cluttered sponsor stickers on their cars and jumpsuits. Women like this sport more than any other, and many have a crush on someone named Junior.</p>
<p>So why am I here? When in Rome… and Americana, baby!</p>
<h3><strong>It Doesn’t get more Americana than Moonshine</strong></h3>
<p>During Prohibition, folks made their own alcohol. No shock there. In the South it was called &#8220;moonshine&#8221; and the men who drove it to destinations and (hopefully) evaded police were &#8220;bootleggers.&#8221;</p>
<p>A successful bootlegger had to modify his car to be fast. Eventually the idea was borne to hold races among the bootleggers&#8230;the origins of NASCAR.</p>
<h3>The Thrill of the Race</h3>
<p>Forty-three cars drive 1.5 miles for 200 laps. The majority of the time they&#8217;re going 200 mph, then slow down to zero at the pit stop for 10 tire changes and re-fuels per race and rev back up again. The pit stop: 12.5 seconds. My average pit stop: 15 minutes. Unless of course, I have to<a title="When Putting Air in your Tires Becomes a Herculean Feat" href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/when-putting-air-in-your-tires-becomes-a-herculean-feat/" target="_blank"> put air in my tires.</a></p>
<p>Some intentional hits of other cars (boys will be boys), but mostly incredible maneuvering on a track that alternates between flat and pitched at an angle of 24%&#8211;three stories high. We drove that pitch in a Chevy van going 80 mph with no one else on the track. It was a rush, it was sideways, it would be insane with others on the track, too.</p>
<h3>How does this Apply to the Real World?</h3>
<p>I&#8217;m not good at math. Anyone surprised? No?</p>
<p>I have vivid memories of high school where I&#8217;d wonder how some formula or parabola would apply to the real world. NASCAR is a perfect example of how math does. The physics, geometry, and pure algebra are visible everywhere.  If only schools would find examples that fit interests, we could learn math so much better.</p>
<p>The car doors and the track walls are both made of Styrofoam so the cars bounce instead of absorb energy on a hit. Fewer casualties and injuries. Physics, anyone?</p>
<p>Cars go faster with less air in the tires, but too little air and there&#8217;s a blowout. You have to consider air pressure when cold vs hot&#8211;both of the tire in use and of the air temperature. Formulas.</p>
<p>Math at work in the real world.<br />
Where have you been impressed to find math in places you wouldn&#8217;t have thought it to be?</p>
<h3>Boom Town</h3>
<p>Concord NC, host to the Charlotte Motor Speedway, becomes the state&#8217;s third largest city on race day. The influx of staff and spectators is that significant! 160,000 people come to watch.</p>
<p><a href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/IMG_0001.jpg"><img title="Charlotte Motor Speedway" alt="Charlotte Motor Speedway" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/IMG_0001-1024x684.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em> Thank you to the friends and their colleagues who facilitated my complimentary ticket to the NASCAR Hall of Fame.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://americanathebeautiful.org/nascar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joshua Tree National Park</title>
		<link>http://americanathebeautiful.org/joshua-tree-national-park/</link>
		<comments>http://americanathebeautiful.org/joshua-tree-national-park/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 21:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Americana the Beautiful</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bloom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boulders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joshua Tree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mormon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yucca]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://americanathebeautiful.org/?p=4126</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yes, I&#8217;m officially on Sabbatical. BUT there were three experiences still to share. This is the last one&#8230; Up next: retro posts revisted. *** Not a U2 fan, I hoped that Joshua Tree National Park would still hold relevance for me. It did. Phew! What&#8217;s in a Name? For starters, it&#8217;s not a tree or [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, I&#8217;m officially on <a title="Sabbatical from my Sabbatical" href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/sabbatical-from-my-sabbatical/" target="_blank">Sabbatical</a>. BUT there were three experiences still to share. This is the last one&#8230; Up next: retro posts revisted.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>Not a U2 fan, I hoped that <a title="Joshua Tree National Park" href="http://www.nps.gov/jotr/index.htm" target="_blank">Joshua Tree National Park</a> would still hold relevance for me. It did. Phew!</p>
<h3>What&#8217;s in a Name?</h3>
<p>For starters, it&#8217;s not a tree or a cactus&#8211;it&#8217;s a yucca.</p>
<p>Why named for Joshua? Mormons came upon the &#8220;tree&#8221; in the desert, with arms held high, and thought of the Biblical Joshua who went to Canaan at Moses&#8217; request to scout the land for settling after the 40 years awander in the desert. The tree looked like it was praying, as Joshua did, and now we have a name.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4132" alt="joshua tree arms raised" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/joshuas-arms-raised.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></p>
<p>Enjoy some more pretty Joshua Trees. Click the pic to advance the slideshow.</p>
[[Show as slideshow]]
<p>This flora reminds me of a muppet. As the yucca grows, the leaves on the trunk and branches dry out, leaving a crispy, shaggy texture.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4134" alt="joshua tree as muppet" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/tree-as-muppet.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></p>
<h3>I&#8217;ll See You Where the Deserts Meet</h3>
<p>Within the National Park, two deserts meet: the Colorado, which is dry and full of cacti; and the Mojave, which is where the Joshua Trees grow. Interesting to think about deserts having boundaries and merging with each other. But I suppose bodies of water do, too.</p>
<div id="attachment_4130" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 624px"><img class=" wp-image-4130 " alt="desert progression at joshua tree national park" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/desert-progression.jpg" width="614" height="461" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Watching the desert landscape evolve throughout the park. Cacti and barren and then forests of Joshua Trees.  </em></p></div>
<div id="attachment_4135" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 624px"><img class=" wp-image-4135 " alt="yucca bloom" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/yucca-bloom.jpg" width="614" height="461" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Cactus blooms!</em></p></div>
<h3>What Big Boulders You Have!</h3>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4128" alt="boulders at joshua tree national park" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/boulders.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></p>
<p>These boulders basically erupted from the ground! Molten liquid oozed up while the Earth&#8217;s crust moved and now there are clusters of rocks that appear&#8230;right there. They&#8217;re massive and daunting, and Flinstone-esque.</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='614' height='376' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/KIC7a-s1UyQ?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4131" alt="flintstones" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/flintstones.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></p>
<p>The regular ole rocks that litter the mountains remind me of the movie <em>The Neverending Story</em>. Think this is where pop culture drew inspiration?</p>
<div id="attachment_4133" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 624px"><img class=" wp-image-4133 " alt="joshua tree boulders and neverending story" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/neverendingsotyr_flickr.jpg" width="614" height="461" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Photo courtesy of Flickr</em></p></div>
<p>I was excited to see the Joshua Trees, but didn&#8217;t know anything about the boulders. I actually enjoyed them more&#8211;for their variety and grandeur.</p>
<p>****</p>
<p>Which nature experience reminds you of a pop culture reference?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://americanathebeautiful.org/joshua-tree-national-park/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saguaro National Park</title>
		<link>http://americanathebeautiful.org/saguaro-national-park/</link>
		<comments>http://americanathebeautiful.org/saguaro-national-park/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 13:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Americana the Beautiful</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[arizona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cactus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saguaro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tucson]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://americanathebeautiful.org/?p=4092</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yes, I&#8217;m officially on Sabbatical. BUT there were three experiences still to share. This is number two&#8230; **** Saguaro National Park is dedicated solely to one magnificent species of cactus. Pollinated by bats and doves (intriguing), they&#8217;re also inhabited by woodpeckers and owls. The woodpeckers abuse the plant until it heals itself with a liquid [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, I&#8217;m officially on Sabbatical. BUT there were three experiences still to share. This is number two&#8230;</p>
<p>****</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4100" alt="DSC_0135" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSC_0135.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></p>
<p><a title="Saguaro National Park" href="http://www.nps.gov/sagu/index.htm" target="_blank">Saguaro National Park</a> is dedicated solely to one magnificent species of cactus.</p>
<p>Pollinated by bats and doves (intriguing), they&#8217;re also inhabited by woodpeckers and owls. The woodpeckers abuse the plant until it heals itself with a liquid that the birds turn into a hardened cocoon. Once the woodpeckers abandon the nest, owls roost in the holes!</p>
<div id="attachment_4095" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 624px"><img class=" wp-image-4095" alt="bird nest in saguaro" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/bird-nest.jpg" width="614" height="461" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Left: a woodpecker hard at work; Middle: context for height; Right: postcard of an owl setting up home. </em></p></div>
<p>The largest cactus in the U.S., the saguaro takes a looooong time to grow. They start as seeds the size of a poppyseed. The odds are against them, though. In a 150-200 year lifetime, one plant might produce 40 million seeds. Nature is against the seeds, with only ONE likely to live to maturity!</p>
<p>To help that seed along, &#8220;nurse plants&#8221; protect from the elements and the critters. At some point it gets a little crowded.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4104" alt="nurse plant" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Slide13.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></p>
<p>Thirsty little suckers, they can absorb 200 gallons of water in a single rainfall&#8211;which satiates all year. That&#8217;s quite prudent since the desert only gets 12 inches of rain a year. The accordion pleats let the plant expand with water. By the time they&#8217;re 50 feet tall (as tall as they get), the reality of consisting of 85% water means that they can weigh 16,000 pounds!</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4098" alt="up close look at a saguaro cactus" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/up-close.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></p>
<p>The spines do more than protect from predators&#8211;they also shade the saguaro&#8217;s skin!</p>
<div id="attachment_4101" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 624px"><img class=" wp-image-4101" alt="DSC_0153" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/DSC_0153.jpg" width="614" height="461" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Roots expand as far as the tree is tall. Imagine the congestion in a forest like this. </em></p></div>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='614' height='376' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/7iD9EvCXEKY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p>How long does it take to grow?</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">1 year = 1/4 inch</span></li>
<li>15 years = 12 inches</li>
<li>30 years = flower and fruit (local American Indians consider the fruiting as the beginning of their new year)</li>
<li>50 years = 7 feet and it starts to grow arms (more surface area for photosynthesis and flowers, more flowers means more seeds)</li>
<li>100 years = 25 feet</li>
<li>150 years = 50 feet and 16,000 pounds</li>
<li>200 years = oldest they live</li>
</ul>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='614' height='376' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/msinvSIKURU?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4094" alt="saguaro with arms" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/arms.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></p>
<p>One in 200,000 saguaros grow in a curly fan. Scientists don&#8217;t know why, but know that it&#8217;s from sort of damage. I think they&#8217;re rather pretty.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4103" alt="saguaro curled at top" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Slide12.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></p>
<p>***</p>
<p>What question do you want to ask? <img src='http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://americanathebeautiful.org/saguaro-national-park/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Airplane Boneyard</title>
		<link>http://americanathebeautiful.org/airplane-boneyard/</link>
		<comments>http://americanathebeautiful.org/airplane-boneyard/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 13:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Americana the Beautiful</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[arizona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airplane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boneyard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tucson]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://americanathebeautiful.org/?p=4084</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yes, I&#8217;m officially on Sabbatical. BUT there were three experiences still to share. This is number one&#8230; **** Where do military planes go to die? Tucson Arizona. Specifically, the airplane boneyard at Davis Monthan Airforce Base. I&#8217;ve wanted to come here ever since seeing the 1987 &#8220;hit movie&#8221; Can&#8217;t Buy Me Love. In the Beginning After [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, I&#8217;m officially on Sabbatical. BUT there were three experiences still to share. This is number one&#8230;</p>
<p>****</p>
<p>Where do military planes go to die? Tucson Arizona. Specifically, the <a title="Airplane Boneyard" href="http://www.pimaair.org/view.php?pg=16" target="_blank">airplane boneyard</a> at Davis Monthan Airforce Base.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve wanted to come here ever since seeing the 1987 &#8220;hit movie&#8221; <a title="Can't Buy Me Love" href="http://youtu.be/taS5VBhF7J4" target="_blank"><em>Can&#8217;t Buy Me Love</em></a>.</p>
<h3>In the Beginning</h3>
<p>After WWII, the government faced a quandary: what to do with all the planes? One bomber came off the plant every 30 minutes and now they were back home.</p>
<p>Enter a storage facility in Arizona: chosen for the weather and soil. The hard-packed clay is rich with calcium, which means the planes can sit on the desert floor.  At its peak, the facility housed 6,000 planes after Vietnam.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4088" alt="airplane boneyard" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_1662_499188661_o.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></p>
<h3>Life in the Boneyard</h3>
<p>With 3,800 crafts on site, they&#8217;re here for three purposes.</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Flyable Hold&#8211;20% of the planes here will fly again. They&#8217;re simply in storage. The Vipers will be sent to <a title="A Most Terrifying Museum" href="http://americanathebeautiful.org/a-most-terrifying-museum/" target="_blank">White Sands Missile Range</a> and the Gulf of Mexico, transitioned to drones for &#8220;blank&#8221; missiles to have target practice. </span></li>
<li>Parts Reclamation&#8211;stripped as needed to repair operational planes.</li>
<li>Disposal&#8211;once fully stripped, they&#8217;re cut into parts. Those parts are melted and used to make circuit boards! The military base used to sell the carcass to nearby scrapyards, but policies changed after 9-11 and now they&#8217;re disassembled on-site.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Protection from the Elements</h3>
<div id="attachment_4086" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 624px"><img class=" wp-image-4086" alt="cover seems" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/cover-seems.jpg" width="614" height="461" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Spray latex protects against the sun, wind, and rodents. All seams are covered. </em></p></div>
<h3>Military Precision</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s incredibly well organized, and beautiful in the patterns and repetition. The planes are parked with precision&#8211;valets would be very happy.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4087" alt="airplane boneyard from the sky" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/from-the-sky.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></p>
<p>A star on a plane indicates that the crew shot down an enemy aircraft. Earn five stars and you&#8217;re called an &#8220;ace.&#8221;</p>
<p>The planes are gorgeous and terrifying. Some sleek, some massive. Some slow, some <em>stealthy, </em>flying 15 miles above ground, at night, undetectable. It&#8217;s a sea of grey with sports of color, stars, and patriotism. Click the pic to advance the slideshow.</p>
[[Show as slideshow]]
<h3></h3>
<h3>What Do Aircraft Do?</h3>
<p>Transport and bomb, test and train, search and destroy. Each plane has a letter that tells you its mission.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4090" alt="aircraft abbreviations" src="http://americanathebeautiful.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Slide1.jpg" width="614" height="461" /></p>
<p>***</p>
<p>Have you ever been to a junkyard or boneyard? What did you learn?</p>
<p>Disclosure: these photos are from Flickr. My tour wasn&#8217;t allowed to leave the bus, I had an aisle seat, and the windows were shaded with an appliqué that still had air bubbles.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://americanathebeautiful.org/airplane-boneyard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
